[Music]
yeah right as the show starts I look
over and Spencer's just giggling welcome
to episode number 50 of the grow from
your heart podcast your source for
Cannabis News education and conversation
dude I'm excited I can't even talk I'm
so excited
I everybody made it on time everybody is
here welcome to episode number 50 guys
we're just going to introduce everybody
to the left we got white Mike what's up
everybody to the further left we got
Jesse hey what's up everyone uh kind of
to the front we got Maddie what's up
y'all me in the face with a
mic we're already off to a great start
so holding holding a microphone over
there is Spence from garden of Weeden
hello uh Spence and Maddie are sharing a
mic they're holding it and uh we're
going to attempt to share the mic I
think that every time it's madd's turn
to talk she's going to get punched in
the head with the microphone for sure
this is going to be fun I do not endorse
domestic violence but uh no not at all
but it's really cute the way it's
happening it's not it's not violent it's
cute uh over here to my right at the
3:00 position we got Mr Adam gas cans
how you doing bro what's up man number
44 in the house absolutely welcome back
number 50 man number 50 thanks for
coming everybody made it I'm excited
thanks a lot you guys you're welcome
everybody just nodded and smiled nods
and smiles don't [ __ ] work on podcast
you got
[Music]
hear all the resin rocks in your head
rattling around oh so everybody brought
some on out everybody uh Jesse brought
some great prizes from H gr indoor
growing supplies here we're just going
to do this weird we're just going to do
it just like this we'll jump and do
speaking of high gr indoor growing
supplies this podcast is brought to you
by hyro indoor growing supplies uh super
huge shout out to hyro uh they have two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store 6271 Beach Street or of
course our favorite I can't even speak
today our favorite pbl location at 618
East forth Street in PUO Colorado don't
forget if you're listening to the grow
from your heart podcast all you have to
do is tell them you listen to the show
and you will get commercial pricing when
you check out at Hy grow dude support
them if you listen to the show you will
hear about some kickass prizes they
brought today uh it took two men two
boxes of [ __ ] to carry it into the house
and then I added more to it when they
got here so huge shout out dude Jesse
thanks a lot bro for sure I tried to
save that for the show so thank you man
a lot that's really cool of you yeah
Adam thanks for carrying it yeah thanks
man but if for real Jesse I'm we have a
podcast we can give them away on I mean
yeah yeah dude I'm I hear about Maddie
said that one of the listeners actually
showed up at the store to meet Maddie
and say hello the other day so shout out
to that person do you remember their
name microphone I don't remember his
name but I will see him very soon
because I have an order for him cool
cool dude thanks for listening to the
show thanks for shopping uh hopefully
one time I bump into you at the store
there that'd be pretty cool cuz I shop
the store kind of frequently I'm that
kind of guy that never goes and gets
everything I need I'll go buy a bunch of
[ __ ] and as soon as I get home I'll go
oh yeah I needed
ogt you too that one thing that you
needed and you always forget always yeah
and I try to stand around in the store
and look around like what is it what is
it what is it what is it I think we all
do the same thing cuz I literally go and
just people ask me can I help you up
like no I'm just looking I forgot do you
need anything yeah yeah this shelf here
and everywhere over that way I remember
I was thinking about cutting clones it's
got to be in the cloning area I could
use about six of those you needed clone
X and you went home without clonex right
was the only thing you needed all right
I do need to send a big thank you shout
out to the Mystic Roots band for letting
me use their music on the show thanks to
cat coot and the entire Mystic Roots
crew the stay positive Productions crew
it's really awesome they let me use
their song on the show I appreciate that
that was the most important uh paper I
had to get through um Mike brought up a
really interesting topic we were going
to do some giveaways and [ __ ] but I got
a couple things to talk about before we
get into there Mike brought up a really
interesting topic I saw it you guys
might have seen it on TMZ I saw it
online this morning uh Ralphie May came
to Colorado and had himself a little
accident with some edible
right before a performance apparently uh
the police had to be called to quiet the
the pissed crowd when Ralphie was way
too zoned to even finish a sentence they
showed video of Ralphie May being
escorted out of the back of the comedy
club by the police because the crowd was
so pissed off at him they were demanding
their money back and he was just smiling
and like I love you guys I don't know
what happened you wouldn't let me do my
bits and he was waving like he was a
princess or some [ __ ] was really [ __ ]
funny I've seen
[ __ ] before and I have never seen
Ralphie May that high he talks about
doing a lot of drugs you got to read the
labels people read the labels yeah they
didn't fun don't mean Fun
Size read the label yeah well you know
it's Ralph E may he probably ate
something and went damn this is
delicious and just started eating all of
them did that have sometimes the arm
eats for you you don't even know you're
doing it he's kind of a big dude so he
probably thought a th milligrams ain't
[ __ ] for me oops his brain is just the
same size as everybody else's
all right shout out to Ralphie May this
episode won't be out for like two weeks
so that'll be old news by then but we
read it today we thought it was freaking
hilarious Ralphie May you're the new
Morino Dow I hope you work that into
your next bit I hope that's funny at
some point that's good yeah um tonight
it'll be too late but uh the new Ari
shaffir comedy special is on at midnight
tonight I'm going to catch that yeah uh
paid regular with Ari one of my favorite
comedians uh when Spence was here last
time we talked about the best [ __ ] of
the year 2014 and we left out something
super duper freaking important what was
that we didn't even mention live resin
oh
[Laughter]
[Music]
yeah yeah well only reason we probably
didn't talk about it is cuz it's nothing
new to us yeah but it was like the thing
for 2014 it was something we definitely
should have talked about we talked to
people today that were like I still
haven't seen any live resin and then
just Joe Blow like pulls some out of his
pocket like yo I got some right here you
know and it's just like the gu's just
like oh oh he's wanting you know to
enter some [ __ ] to a competition and
it's
like you just won yeah yeah no live res
is definitely a big pickup um something
new uh especially with you know the
addition of Clos Loop it kind of really
came about shout out to emotech yeah
shout out to Giddy emotech K bill that
whole crew that kind of you know put the
put the forward push yeah uh live resin
did a lot for you of course it did a lot
for emo and giddy it did a lot for hanky
B and The Greener Side kind of um as a
residual it actually your win in the
secret cup boosted up my Instagram
following it made me more known so yeah
live resin kind of boosted us all up in
the in the scene a little bit yeah for
sure I me I can't believe we forgot
about live on the year review episode
yeah that was big yeah huge Maddy's
shaking her head all flabbergasted I
can't believe we did either that was
such a big part of the end of our year
especially with the secret cup so and it
was awesome to win The Secret Cup
regionals that was awesome met a lot of
people in Denver through that yeah uh
and people still talk to me like I'm
part of your crew like you grew that
well and I'm like I didn't grow it dude
that's they grow it they [ __ ] pop the
seeds they shatter it they blast it it's
all them so I have to correct people and
I I let them know that you grew that I
never take credit for your guys' grow I
didn't grow that stuff you guys it was
them soil to oil yeah actually the stuff
for uh I may have grown a couple of
theirs but I I've taken credit for those
so this is kind of a random note a lady
messaged me on in Instagram and kind of
called me out uh she said that in and
I'm sure I said this but I don't
remember the exact words in an older
episode I kind of tried to cover my ass
legally with a disclaimer like if you
live in an illegal State don't grow weed
follow the rules and all that [ __ ] I got
to say that kind of [ __ ] to cover my ass
uh I don't know technically if I come on
the air and I say hey if you live in
Florida [ __ ] all the rules grow all the
weed you can I don't know if I'm going
to get in trouble for that so to cover
my own ass I just say follow the follow
the rules you guys but I think that you
should grow your own cannabis if you're
smoking cannabis if you're consuming
cannabis if you like it recreationally
if you like it medically grow the [ __ ]
out of it everywhere that's my new
stance on it overgrow the government
they can't arrest us all they might
arrest me for saying that but if they do
somebody else make a badass podcast and
keep this going for me and and I mean if
you are going to do
it illegally you know if you do it
somewhat responsibly and you're willing
to go to court for that then so be it I
mean you may be the change that your
state or your community yeah your
community is needed so plant more seed
you guys grow more weed I can't be a
hypocrite I grow a lot of cannabis I
think you should too but also know the
risks if you've got kids in the house
you can lose the kids
when they're going to shoot your dog
most likely when they come in the door
think about that kind of [ __ ] it's going
to be traumatizing it's going to [ __ ] up
your life if you're prepared for that if
you can handle that if you're a man
Andor woman enough if you're transgender
enough I'm not trying to exclude anybody
I'm trying to include all of you if you
are person enough and you can handle
that [ __ ] grow cannabis do your thing
just know what the risks are there we go
I'm not being a hypocrite uh if you're
yeah she also called me out for dabbing
in the car and telling people not to uh
I'm a professional lady I could dab in
the car if you find yourself to be a
professional dab in the car the people I
was talking [ __ ] to were not
professional I'm a professional car
Dabber right she yeah we've got a nice
little system in my car absolutely I've
been I've been there with him and it's
always parked in very certain locations
where it's like this is dab approved I
know good spots yeah there we're not
pulling up next to the park like hey see
those kids on the swing over there
no it ain't happened like that and I
understand certain places between here
and like Boulder Longmont Broomfield
Fort Collins uh that I know to pull off
like I can pull off right here there's a
little gas station with a car wash I
love to go in the car wash at the gas
station and get my car wash and take a
DA that before but now that you've said
that I I have to try it and nobody can
see you your car is covered at all
angles and you're just in there dabbing
you have the Master Shake too that's a
perfect little car rig it's hard for the
car uh Master Shake is 10 there's no way
to hold it in the car there's to put it
it just Falls over when you drive so
this is mostly the
Hitman the cou fit in the coup well okay
yeah yeah so the this is Colorado I've
seen more than one enail set up in a car
shout out to Otis dabs big shout out to
Otis is always driving with the p nail
in the car uh you see that dude dabbing
in strip clubs he also dabbed on an
airplane did he really take the dab or
did he just show off the rig I didn't
the da he took a real dab on the plane
hey win winner winner winner vegan
dinner with a torch or a with with a
torch and took a dab in the bathroom and
blew it out took a video it was on
Instagram I don't know if it's still
there I don't know if it's still there
or not but TSA had a problem with that
would have jacked it security so so
shout out to that lady that kind of
called me out I guess I might have been
hypocritical but honestly encourage any
of that I was just trying to cover my
own ass is all I'm trying not to go to
jail and trying to keep this podcast
going I can't tell people in [ __ ]
Texas to grow weed and not think that
I'm going to get in trouble but guess
what if you're in Texas grow some
[ __ ] weed dude grow it grow it with
all your heart I would I would think
it'd be easy to uh figure out what our
opinion was but right yeah I don't think
you really off a role model Vibe is more
or less you want to put the correct
information out there for people yeah
yeah well she called me out and I I
guess she was right because I did say
don't do this and I I guess I can't be a
[ __ ] about it just want to man up to
that one um where was I going to go from
there do we want to start this big old
list of shout outs I'm only like 11
minutes into the show I do have one more
thing I have to do I just look down uh
this podcast is brought to you by
Nature's green remedies.com check out
our friends Natures green remedies.com
for good deals on gag green genetics
Lata lab Sin City RAR dankness mile high
can Adventure the Cali Connection iy
genetics and a whole bunch more trusted
brands use coupon code IE 2015 for 15%
off any order and you always get free
shipping at natur Green remedies.com I
don't know when that coupon code will
end we'll just keep it going probably
all the way through Valentine's Day so
check those guys out also check out tree
Thugger dcom if you want to read about
uh dude you guys probably don't care but
the Grateful Dead is playing at Soldier
Field in Chicago with Trey Anastasio on
guitar I'm sure there will be articles
about that on tree Thugger dcom so check
out tree Thugger dcom live music uh live
music lifestyle magazine yeah sorry for
stumbling through the ads I just want to
get them done I promise I'll do those
for people just wanted to throw that in
there you know it's what I got to do
also if you're interested in sponsoring
the show send me an email it's grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you
all that info that's all the technical
stuff for now we're not going to do any
more of that um all right let's read
this big old list of shout outs I'll let
you guys go first if you guys uh Mike if
you got anybody that you want to shout
out or say anything to because this is
episode 50 it's kind of time for like a
celebration before we start giving away
prizes and [ __ ] everyone's looking at
their phones like shout out to you bud
50 is huge right well thank you guys for
coming all of you guys are Clinton Sean
should be here but there aren't enough
chairs dude if I had two more chairs
Shawn and Clint would have been my next
options to have here I want to save
Shawn for win uh it's just kind of
focused we could talk about some [ __ ]
and Clint would just derail the whole
[ __ ] team kind of be kind of fun just to
have them both on and he just Clint sit
there and poke fun at him the whole time
and he not know what to do keep going
bro I'm sorry I totally interrupted you
bad host that's uh that's all I got
right now it's Yeti OG dabs wait a
minute I wasn't expecting to to be put
on the spot people be yeah definitely 50
is huge man I've been looking forward to
this for a while thanks for the
microphone oh man thanks for coming on
and you keep us updated with our local
politics and the local [ __ ] that we need
to be aware of and I think that
reminding us about our local stuff
teaches our listeners that they can
participate too and it gets them off the
couch which is what we need you can be
an activist in so many ways but you got
to off the couch to do be ready to do
local political work if marijuana is
getting legalized in your state as soon
as it's legal at the state level all
sorts of nightmarish work begins at the
local level with the city and county
level and if you don't have somebody in
your crew ready to step up on that it's
not going to go the way you want it to
and you're looking at local bands like
Colorado Springs I'm impr with how uh
friendly you have become with some City
Council Members we'll be hanging out
taking dabs in the phonal ring and he be
like oh that's this city council member
excuse me for a minute and I'm like bro
you're at my house taking dabs listening
to Ree and you're going to excuse
yourself to go talk to the city council
manager okay they uh they're people too
bro like if you call them they call you
back their job is to keep the
constituents happy and it doesn't matter
how often you dab you're a constituent
it's pretty killer I like that you've
developed that relationship for us cuz I
know it's not my spot uh it's it's it's
fully my cross to bear I can see why
it's like my wheelhouse and honestly I
don't see myself knowing what you know
about growing or knowing what Spence
knows about blasting it's just I know
about
zoning so not sex we need someone like
that it's all good me doing your job
speaking of zoning both of you looking
at me going thank [ __ ] god you're
here cuz I'm going to [ __ ] do it yeah
everybody need someone like you I go to
City Council meetings occasionally and I
I know I don't go enough but I've I'm
intimidated it's well it's like going in
like hi I'm the pot grower and it just
feels weird yeah like yeah you get some
looks yeah oh some looks Jedi stared for
half the session last time the dude with
the Stars on his chest was like I don't
like holes in my shirt Jesse that's a
killer Shirt By the way shout out to
heavy 16 for all the goodies that we get
to give away from them uh do you got
anybody to thank or any shout outs for
the for the show um I know we're only
like 11 minutes but uh Yeti OG live
resin I agree with all that
uh my beautiful wife there you go
congrats on the wedding this year yeah
that was one of the coolest weddings I
if not the coolest wedding I've ever
been to it was by far the drunkest I've
ever been out a
wed Maddie and I got to give out live
res dabs to everybody all night that was
kind of fun full on dab bar fullon dab
bar she doesn't have a mic but most of
you guys probably caught that from the
echo in the room I had someone ask me to
plan their reception for him the other
day actually does that mean we get to
go you got a hire Rock it's pretty easy
you just uh yeah show up with a bunch of
hash and [ __ ] ton of beer starting
another impr compan now oh Jesus hey hey
hash
weddings all right uh so Maddie just
grabbed the mic from Spence it looks
like she's prepared you got any shout
out I want to give huge shout out to our
crew from NC in Colorado they have
really stepped up their game this year
and all learned how to grow some killer
weed granted they have some you know
good friends to help them learn but our
friends really stepped up and started
growing some amazing cannabis this year
they deserve a big shout out for that
good genetics go a long way also I've
seen a lot I was I'm kind of going to
brag on that yeah shout out to all those
guys because a lot of them you guys have
passed on I gentic seeds to a lot of
that crew and they are freaking killing
it on Instagram so you're totally right
Abol we love to suggest iy genetics it's
a great place to get reliable reliable
genetics from well thank you yeah no
problem um yeah I wish I could give
unfortunately you guys there aren't any
seeds in the prize packages because of
legal reasons these prizes are available
uh to almost anybody in the United
States unless you're here at the table
or you're too closely affiliated with
the show by the way I make the [ __ ]
rules and they can change any time I
decide they change mad jealous for that
the prize packs are sick guys I don't
even remember where I was headed with
that yeah anyway anybody can get the
prizes um yeah so there can't be seeds
in there that's what I was saying there
can't be seeds in there I'm sorry I will
make a Colorado local contest where I
can put some I seeds in there eventually
I just got to figure out how to do that
it'll just be a local thing so yeah big
shout out to all those guys dude MD you
sound great on a microphone you are you
need to be podcasting all the time thank
you yeah you're nice well I have a we
have a discussion table every night when
we take dabs we usually just have a
session sit down and talk for an hour or
two and just [ __ ] and honestly it
could be on a podcast so that's why I've
said it before on the show that your
table is part of what inspired this
podcast
uh your guys's friend uh I won't say his
name he used to come and pick my brain
for 2 hours at a time at your table and
then I thought I should record all this
a write it down and just refer him to my
recordings I wish I could just bring
thoughts back that I have like I
remember something we were talking about
but I don't remember the specifics uh
one time on an older podcast that I used
to do uh shout out to 719 the blocks uh
on that podcast we had a recording issue
and our whole recording got lost and we
decided let's just try to redo it and
mimic it about 10 minutes in we're like
this feels so fake there's no way to
bring back those thoughts in that
conversation so we just gave up we're
like no so remaking a talk isn't it's
not the most legit thing we've sat here
and tried to make a podcast four or five
times in one night and it just didn't
work time and time was about episode 13
or 15ish around that area was cut
everything's better when it's not forced
yeah I just I wasn't feeling it like it
was time to record and I just wasn't in
the mood and now I'm I'm way more
comfortable at it so did 5050 episodes
in on this show and then I did a about
50 with another show also so I've had
some time to get comfortable yeah I've
only been a host for 50 episodes I feel
like I've only been a host for about 30
episodes to tell you the truth it took
me 20 25 to get there it flew by yeah
yeah uh I'm thinking about doing more
frequent episodes because we get more
listens when they're more frequent but I
don't want to bore people also I don't
want to be that podcast information
disappears for three months and then
comes out with the show and then comes
out and so few of those apologizes but
then I also don't want you to have to
listen to me four times a week like Jo
Rogan cuz I don't even have time to hear
all the Joe Rogan stuff Joe Rogan's a
busy dude yeah yeah all right Spence
just grabbed the mic for Maddie he
smacked her with it violently
[Music]
uh it's a cute violence when they do it
uh how about you Spence you got any
shout outs for the year uh let's
see
um shout out to all the people who breed
seeds and give me freed seeds St bro I
appreciate that um and the people that
hooked me up with um
legit genetics you know there's I've had
genetics from California Seattle so
shout out to all the people out there
that have passed on genetics you know
it's kind of now it's kind of something
that should be done now is you know kind
of share the genetics for people um
there's always going to be Cuts people
are going to hold that's just how it
works but you could still share at the
same
time sharing is um great
here no it's all good I just tried to
step in somebody was had to do something
here but go to take a dab and all just
look atly for my carb cap was clogged so
I was [ __ ] choking on it too that was
weak good man I'm going clean that out a
little bit the sharing is good here in
Colorado got to keep clean yeah try not
to be a a clone hoarder and I know
that's hypocritical because I'm a
breeder and I'm kind of a clone hoarder
everybody's going to keep your special
genetics but everybody's got those
couple that if you got something that's
high in CBD or is really good Med out
it's medicine share well cuts are one
thing seeds are another yeah yeah seeds
are available like I think seeds should
be getting get given out uh that's part
of why you guys are frustrated with me
there's not a lot of stuff at Natures
green remedies.com it's because all my
locals are getting it um there is
obviously a markup when you go through a
dealer a distributor and I'm skipping
that markup and getting the seeds to my
locals at wholesale prices cuz it feels
good doing that uh sorry that you guys
didn't get a lot on Nature's green
remedies you'll get the next the whole
batch will probably go to you cuz my
locals are served up everybody's fed and
and I mean nine times out of 10 that's a
lot of times H 90% you would say would
go to Nature screen remedies and only
like 5% stays here yeah and then all my
friends are like where are the seeds and
I'm like you have to go online like
everyone else and it feels rude that was
kind of our Christmas this year yeah
yeah sorry we're all going to take turns
joking because the dads are going around
the circle uh was that your shout outs
you concluded with the the sharers the
people that share yeah you look your
eyes are as red as your microphone
really really really high everybody in
this room is quite
dab uh we showed up here everyone showed
up right about 710 and it's just now 810
so we took a little pre preparing
session Adam how about yourself bro you
got any shout outs thanks you brother
like you've I've only been here a year
and I mean I met you quickly but man you
know like without you I wouldn't be in
the scene that I'm in Jesse you know you
fed my family brother like straight
up Mike thanks for doing doing the
work you man next year appreciate it he
pointed at spit for that one yeah sorry
the microphone can't see it but next
year I I got your back I know what
you're capable of brother thank you
so man it's good to have you yeah
definitely welcome welcome to Colorado
welcome to the crew like it's definitely
and right could be any place happier and
I mean my wife for putting up with my
wife yeah dude she she's struggling this
is my wife you know but
chrisy what's up Christie you you'll be
you'll be all right I'm doing everything
for the fam so it's it's it'll come
around it's got to be hard you guys move
from another state and she doesn't have
anybody in she's not just look at us we
did it two years ago know but she's not
a social butterfly like us she's really
she's kind of Shyer than we are so I
understand why she's having a hard time
she can't just talk to people like her
job and [ __ ] so it it's it's been kind
of you know what she I'm proud of her
for quitting her job to tell you the
truth I am to steing away from Nightmare
she grabbed her balls and she [ __ ]
used them and proud her she's been there
for 4 years it's not like she hasn't put
up with enough Pizza Huts [ __ ] hey
Christy I pick on you bro but I'm proud
of you for quitting that job because
that [ __ ] was treating you like [ __ ] and
you deserve better and not only that but
like I said the other day in the in the
Facebook post that she walks the kids to
school every morning in snow you know
she's never dealt with snow at all so
you know props to her and everything
that she does yeah shout out to all the
moms out there shout out to all the moms
what's up Mom shout out shout out to my
mom yeah everybody here has got a pretty
good
Mama all right I've got a big list of
got a big list of shout outs I want to
give here dude thanks all the people
that said thanks to me thanks it makes
me blush it makes me feel honored uh you
can't be uh somebody taught me that you
are the sum of the five people that you
surround yourself the most on purpose uh
five people sitting at this table with
me so that's that's an honor dude for
real yeah you know nice yeah so uh I
don't remember who taught me that it may
have been
uh Cliff ravenscraft is where I heard it
but somebody else taught him it might
have been Michael hayatt it doesn't
matter but uh yeah that's the five
people that you surround yourself with
the most on purpose are who you become
and there are five people sitting around
me that I I'm inspired by all of you
every day just a little bit MD's looking
at me like you're inspired by me [ __ ]
yeah no your friends have a big
influence on you so I completely
understand that absolutely and I I
completely agree with that same
statement I've never really thought
about it like that before so that's why
I was staring at you I was like hm I'm
sitting trying to think of my five and
most of them are at this table so yeah
friends are always been my family
explain why under R for the last two
years yeah uh and of course Angela would
be if there was another person to be
here that would contribute to who I have
have been lately Angela would be uh if
you two count if MD and Spence were a
person as we put that couple just Garden
of Weeden yeah if they were Garden of
Weeden then Angela would probably be
number five shapes my uh my stuff so D
I've got a huge huge freaking list of
shout outs that I want to give here I'm
looking to see how much time I'm into
this episode cuz I don't want to take
like 4 minutes doing shout outs but I'm
going to to do prizes yeah right uh
that's cool that's probably the next
part here um so let's see I said it
first angelish keeps me smiling and
inspired Maddie dude you're the first
woman on the show that's awesome thank
you congratulations dude thanks for
coming again Spence dude you keep me
supplied with the dankest dabs I could
ever imagine smoking uh I smoke a lot of
hash you guys and Spence keeps me going
uh he's actually in the process of
teaching me how to make my own hopefully
tomorrow we'll get on that again big
shout out to Big Mike what's up bro uh
you're like family Michael you're like
family what up big Mike White Mike
sitting next to me family sloppy what's
up my ninja slop Dizzle big shout out
big shout out to Phil Phil we don't get
to hang out enough bro you're kind of
quiet but know that I think about you
that you're part of the crew over here
Adam what's up dude you already know I
said what's up Jesse dude you're quiet
and you're shy but I love having you on
the show man you're loosen it up you're
becoming a great [ __ ] podcast guest
for sure a hell of a dude I know that if
some [ __ ] goes wrong I can always call
you uh Jesse can build a house with his
hands his bare Man Hands yeah so if some
[ __ ] goes I know I can count on him dude
it's sick I know it's the beard is it
the beard that does it it's the man
power power it's a super power uh King
Cola shout out bro Clint shout out super
big shout out to hunt grimy Gatsby and
the turpack crew uh 719 nugs big shout
out there extra large shout out to hyro
tree Thugger Nature's green remedies oil
slick big super warmed up to the perfect
temperature shout out to highly educ
educated in task Rock how about this one
a shout out to Robert Craig Vegas Matt
and Matt from the spot uh Twitter
listeners frivolous Road Runner Mr omnio
El Roo from Facebook how about Fred
Garvin how about my good logo designer
Bender what's up buddy people that let
me use their music cat and cot from the
Mystic Roots band DJ nick uh task list
me use his music too shout out for that
the guy that taught me so much about
podcasting and has no idea that I even
have a podcast and has never listened to
my show will not hear this shout out but
huge shout out to to Mr Cliff
ravenscraft the podcast answerman if you
guys are trying to make a podcast dude
totally Google the podcast answerman
check his [ __ ] out he will teach you so
much uh if you're looking for some
highgrade no wait if you're looking for
some mid-grade cannabis big shout out to
my friend Vigor lover shout out hash
mids uh shout outs to Jake and
Emily super huge shout out to Giddy Up
and emotech Shout out to hanky b and a
super special shout out to my good
friend Doug Benson and also Joey Coco
Diaz
and a shout out to everybody that made
it here to the show was kind of I was
kind of wondering if you were going to
forget him or not but that's that's cool
no [ __ ] suck I ain't going to forget
Joey Diaz I knew you could uh I listen
to his episode the other day was amazing
Joe Rogan and Diaz No the not I haven't
even listened to that one Doug Benson
and and Coco Diaz where they I haven't
seen that one the little uh Filipino
girl in between them and he's just like
oh yeah sweet little Peach there little
Filipino girl who is that Amy or Emily
coup or some Margaret Cho no no no not
Filipino just wondering how racist
you're getting you are on on a show
saying that to people all right so uh
man I want to thank all the listeners
super huge shout out from from my heart
I grow from my heart and I thank you
from my heart thanks for listening to 50
episodes we get like 6,000 listens on a
huge episode when Sean comes on we get
6,000 people to hear this that's [ __ ]
insane people yeah I had no idea it was
that high of a number when you said that
earlier I was hoping you were going to
mention it now because I I had no idea I
if you knew what my guess was it was
nothing close that that was awesome I
thought maybe like
1,500 that's what I was thinking but I
did I mean I don't think about the fact
that it's the it's the web anybody can
listen to it anybody anywhere I sent
print ads to Nature's green remedies and
so everybody that bought seeds for like
3 months got my ad in the mail with
their seeds that was very smart around
the world yeah as soon as I get the new
logo figured out and everything I plan
on printing up a new logo and bombing
the world with new newsletter ads and
stuff nice will drop them every I wonder
what our what our craziest location uh
listener is I can probably tell you by
looking at the uh the logistics on my
website it tells me where yeah I could
see where everybody's IP address is but
the problem is if people cheat on their
IP addresses CU they can't be looking at
certain [ __ ] where they're from so they
got to go in somewhere else and then
come back to your site yeah but uh like
we're Listen to In Like Prague and
Russia and like yeah places where they
don't even speak English uh
anytime I've done any kind of social
media video chat I've always pumped that
and I was I told Mike before like those
are my listens I'm glad you said that uh
shout out to all the people on bong TV
uh I got I got a nice little group that
I hang out with there on bong TV the
snower Army it's fun uh doe what up bro
I know we've been arguing but it's a
friendly argument uh shout out to doe
trip uh I can't list them all I forget
people D's uh all of them what's up guys
shout out to Bong that do with the
dreadlocks that's me bro
dread J dread 420 the other guy I think
that's General dread oh okay I think
shout out dud with with the other
dreadlocks there are a couple guys on
with dreads lately you know which one
I'm talking about though yeah all right
so what I was getting at is that I love
all the listeners and to show that
appreciation uh we've got some killer
prize packages and we want to give them
away we sat around here for a few
minutes trying to think about ways to
give them away so I think this is what
we're going to do I will post pictures
and I'll read the prize packs here in a
minute but I want to tell you first to
keep you excited I will post pictures of
the prize packages on Instagram and
Facebook uh the prize packages there
won't be there'll be individual prizes
the prices that are on Facebook are only
there on Facebook the prizes that are on
Instagram are only available on
Instagram so that people that are on
different social medias have options to
get in on this I'll post pictures on
whichever site I'm posting it on uh what
you have to do is follow on Instagram
you have to follow where is it you have
to follow iy genetics you have to follow
gr peblo and you have to follow Garden
of Weeden on Instagram if you want to be
in the Instagram contest you have to
follow those people then you have to
comment on a photo of the Prize Package
that you want because I don't want you
if you want a t-shirt don't like comment
on the nutrient packages because there's
nutrient packages and [ __ ] that I want
those to go to people that are going to
grow if you want a nutrient package
comment on that if you want a t-shirt
comment on that if you want this sweet
ass pendant that Maddie and Spence
brought comment on that so that we can
give these prizes to people that want
them so comment on the prize that you
want using #g grow fromyou heart
giveaway on Instagram and then comment
on that picture and tell me why you
think you should win that prize so it's
pretty easy you got three things to do
you got to follow three people you got
to comment using a hashtag using hasag
grow fromy heart giveaway and then
you've got to put in a little message
there and tell me why you think you
should win that specific prize um you
can enter once on each picture uh and
that includes Facebook and Instagram you
can do all of the contests once
uh don't enter don't leave two comments
on the same picture uh I'll probably
delete both of your comments at that
point uh just trying to keep it fair you
know I just don't want a bunch of people
spamming the [ __ ] out of my stuff follow
the rules yeah yeah uh I make all the
rules as they're going I'm going to try
to be as Fair as possible but I do have
the right to change the rules if I feel
like you cheated or you're being a
douche I can just [ __ ] block you that's
my thing I hold that heavy banhammer and
every single prize like I would I would
great prizes dud Jessie and hyro killed
it when they showed up with they brought
four killer bags all right let me read
you what's in this bag here's the big
I'll go from the bottom um the smaller
prizes are from our good friends at
Highly Educated titanium there will be
one Highly Educated t-shirt it's a size
extra large and there is one iy genetics
sticker pack in there which is a license
plate sticker a regular logo sticker and
an iHeart dab sticker so that's the
Highly Educated prize pack there are
four
iy genetics t-shirts and sticker packs
available I'm writing down sticker pack
on there cuz I didn't put that part on
the start so be four iy genetics
t-shirts and sticker packs available uh
there's a variety of sizes there are
three black and one white uh I'll list
them all on social media sites there'll
be probably two land on Facebook two on
Instagram uh we'll list those up there
so you got four options I'm going to go
ahead and add there are two hat pins two
iy hat pins one for uh IG and one for
Facebook damn there's a lot of cool ass
prizes now man damn yeah we're just
going nuts getting even better yeah um
I'm only shipping this [ __ ] to the
United States you guys I'm not shipping
this stuff out of America you got to be
in the United States of America if you
win these prizes and you want to pay for
the shipping and you're in France or
wherever else out of the country you can
pay for the shipping and I'll mail it to
you but uh it's already going to be
expensive enough there are right for
that grand prize it's going to be like
40 bucks even if it goes like to Denver
yeah yeah that's coming out of my pocket
so shout out to I mean everybody threw
down sweet prizes so I I don't mind
shout out for Jeff for paying for the
shipping what you brought way outshines
my shipping cost shout out to hro shout
out to Jeff you guys rule Garden of
Weeden there is a prize package from the
the lovely Folks at Garden of Weeden
there's a t-shirt what size was it extra
large yep yep uh extra large t-shirt
there's a sticker a garden of Weeden
sticker and a cool ass pendy it's like a
honeycomb uh I think it's a honeycomb
it's made by the real ghost cat glass
artist and it's pretty sweet I told them
that it wasn't making it to the prize
pack and they looked at me like I was a
dick and told me I had to give it away
so you guys are lucky you're getting it
all right so those are kind of the
smaller prizes which aren't even that
small we got t-shirts we got t-shirts
and sticker packs we got a pendy we got
a sticker and a shirt I want out of the
pile we got hat pins so here's where
we're getting fancy um there are three
of these available there are it's a big
of those sweet tote bags like you get at
all the events uh there's a bunch of
heavy 16 nutrients like a heavy 16
nutrient pack shout out to heavy 16 good
[ __ ] you'll grow some heavy herb with
that uh there's a bottle of plant
Catalyst there's a bottle of tap rooot
uh there's some stickers and then
there's probably a Humbolt hempwick and
maybe some random [ __ ] in there just a
little bit of Swag in that bag so there
are three of those little nanolux
flashlight oh yeah little nanolux a
green flashlight for your grow room the
green light won't bug your plants yeah
yeah those have been a favorite around
the people lately around the job site y
yep and then uh the grand prize uh
brought to us again I got to mention Hy
gr indoor growing supplies in poblo and
Denver uh check them out mention the
show you'll get sweet deals uh hyro
indoor growing supplies has donated a
bag of Gro Kashi a bag of ogt a big
bunch of heavy 16 nutrients a big bottle
of plant Catalyst a bottle of Tap Root
there's a lighter some stickers uh
there's a probiotic Farmers Alliance
button there's a gauge green genetics
button uh there's a Bronco T-shirt with
some other stuff on it uh I don't think
that Bronco logo is used with li proper
licensing it's a house and garden
t-shirt okay there's that shirt in there
and then there's probably uh stickers
and there's going to be other random
stuff in that one that is our big super
number one bonus prize pack uh that grow
Kashi is going to improve your grow by a
whole bunch that ogt is going to improve
your grow a whole say all that will make
you into a damn near Great Gardener yeah
yeah all you need now is a good pack of
seeds and some soil and a good light and
you will be crushing it decent good
living soil and [ __ ] yeah yeah if you do
it right that'll put you through the
first one casting really nice to try
some new teach you damn whatever I did
that time I need to do again yeah I uh I
actually got a sample pack of that heavy
16 and I will use it on something really
soon I've got so many projects coming up
that uh I've started another Perpetual
cycle instead of doing large rooms all
at once I've got a perpetual and that
gives me more options to run different
NES so uh I really like the Perpetual
better it just keeps me going yeah keeps
me I don't know seems like I get
stagnant when I just have a long a long
grow all right so guys get in on these
prize packages here are the rules again
I'm going to take pictures of every
Prize Package and I will try to show
everything that's in the package in a
nice little pile it's going to take me a
minute to get all these up uh I will
post the pictures to Facebook I will
post some of the pictures to Instagram
what you've got to do is go and follow
oh yeah I didn't say who you had to
follow on Facebook you have to follow
the grow from your heart podcast you
have to follow high grow indoor growing
supplies and you have to follow the
garden of Weeden on Facebook and then
it's the same thing you have to comment
using hashtag grow fromy yourheart and
you have to tell me why you should win
the prizes so I will post the pictures
on the I genetics on Instagram and the
grow from your heart podcast on Facebook
is where you'll find these pictures
right I said that right right everyone
yeah cool I'm just making sure I'm not
[ __ ] anything up I just want
everybody to be on the same page as me
because my notes are really scattered on
and I would imagine all this information
will be in the post with the picture and
yeah yeah I'll put the rules the sizes
for the shirts folks we made sure to get
a selection that's the kind of stuff I'm
talking about sizes so check the photo
that you're looking at don't comment on
the extra small shirt when you want the
extra large shirt yeah the extra medium
the medium it'll look good on it'll look
good my size is that what you weum tall
and skinny mhm yeah dude you look funny
in aium they'd be like a little mini
halter top on you Spence is like 6'4 65
it's the curse of the tall guy yeah but
you're also the skinny guy so you get
doubly
bad yep yep I remember one time I went
to what was it big and tall one of those
thinking I could get some just regular
tall but no you got to be like size 40
and tall at the same time it's like
Jesus you can fit in one pant L what you
got there it's big and not big comma
yeah should be I forgot to do a shout
out to Greenworks big shout out to
Greenworks they changed the game this
year a little bit for a few people yeah
shout out to Greenworks I got indoor
outdoor tree trunks growing inside it's
ridiculous I've seen the pictures check
out Spence's Instagram make sure you do
if you're trying to win some prizes
you're going to have to like some stuff
on Spence's Instagram if you're
listening to the show go through there
and check it out these follows if you
aren't already you will enjoy yeah
listen to episode 50 I think that needs
to be a rule just not applicable to you
know at this moment but yeah once it's
on social media it's they're definitely
uh if they want to know all the rules
they probably listen to number F yeah
please just listen to the podcast guys
tell your friends we're getting yeah
we're definitely hitting 4,000 listens
on almost every episode which is pretty
cool the better episodes get 6,000 uh
the standouts are getting 5,000 listens
there are some that are still like the
episodes with just me we don't nobody
listens they listen to about and I can
see on the website if you listen like
for 40 minutes of the episode or 40% of
the episode it shows me how far you drop
out and people just get tired of me
rambling by myself but tell your friends
about the show if all 5,000 of my
listeners told one per told two people
about the show cuz one person's going to
ignore you and one person might listen
that'll probably get me at least another
thousand listeners podcasting is still
kind of new yeah it's it's catching on
very quickly but you tell people hey man
do you listen to podcast and they're
like what what's a podcast yeah or
they're like yeah I do man what shows
are you jamming they either know or they
don't so if you tell people when more
people listen moves my show up in the
ranks in Stitcher and in iTunes and then
that shows it makes it available to more
people they just see it and then more
people grow better cannabis and that's
my goal just more better more better
weed all over the world all over tell
youa to listen to the show yeah tell
whoever's responsible for growing your
cannabis to listen to The Grow from your
heart podcast and maybe we can get you
some better weed no mids no mids I I
tell people all the time all the time
about it so and we have kind of gotten
way off topic on the past few episodes
cuz uh we had Christmas and New Year and
then I was sick as [ __ ] and these guys
came over and did a rescue episode for
me I don't know if that's even out yet
no that hasn't been posted as as of this
time so I don't know how many listens
that got but it was a great episode it
was funny the last episode Stoners that
are ahead of schedule
yeah but uh we are going to get back
onto the track of doing those great
episodes where there's a lot of grow
lessons and a lot of great guests you
guys are going to learn more [ __ ] it's
not just going to be my high ass
rambling uh I've actually got the next
like 10 episodes kind of outlined I know
what the topics are going to be I can
scroll through my phone and read off
points but I'm not going to do it
learning is what 2015's all
about remember that Adam said that that
was not my motto at
all so y'all going to learn from Adam
yeah no not from me I'm learn 44 get in
on those contests guys man get in on it
that highly Shir it's one of the smaller
prizes but it's so dope is that from me
Miss Maddie Miss matd just scooped me up
wa what scen did you just give me Yeti
OG
oh you uh you are close to that mic all
right somebody's got to talk while I
take a dab all right well um yeah go for
it Adam you always have a good start
yeah have a good ramble um well we
learned today that uh getting hit in the
face with the ball pisses people
off um shout out to fish you know he's
he's he's doing it uh you'll survive
buddy yeah yeah even if it's a total
accident he really wanted to come you
know tonight
but he I'm sorry bro yeah the table is
really full no it's crowded there's
seats Tak it's not us being a dick
there's literally you'd have to Mike and
Jessie are kind of cuddling yeah Mike
and Jesse are pretty damn close to each
up just to make room for I don't have
any more microphones you're here in
thought yeah the third time I hit him in
the face with the ball was totally an
accident it was it was clearly an
accident and it was clearly the straw
that that broke
but I I think taking out of that job
site it as fast as you can with all
Wheels spin in towards that very very
thin and steel framed gate is just going
to be something we all do at least twice
I've done it several times yeah sounds
like you guys have fun at work we do uh
zero fun is allowed at work looks like
you're breaking rules yeah yeah when a
bunch of males of the same age are left
to just stand around for like a National
Geographic description yeah bizar [ __ ]
happens that dab just made my face kind
of today it was t-ball that do weird
[ __ ] yeah like made my eyes get to some
injuries and property damage sorry
sorry softball so good that's that was
the that was the kind of fun of today
you know I've been made fun of a couple
times but I can't even remember who you
they make fun of you at
work this where you J comes back these
guys didn't work together until recently
I think it's partly my fault that these
guys all kind of built a construction
company together on accident and it's
fun to see all my Bros just hanging out
talking about what they did cuz before
they were all off doing their own
separate [ __ ] and now it's they all have
a good story together now we all mingle
pretty much so yeah conversation
sometimes right so Adam said that 2015
is the year of learning does anybody
else have something that 2015 is for
them the year of
what um cashing in hopefully cashing in
I knew that answer I knew that answer
I'd like some of my really hard hard
work to pay off and it will so it will F
show yeah right I was thinking the 2014
is the year of like getting the
construction in the foundation in 2015
is actually seeing some [ __ ] succeed and
get
finished sounds nice I finally got hired
on at a large facility so I've got over
200 lights to work with now that's kind
of what my year is going to be about
you're going to have fun with that buddy
blowing it up bro blowing it up get more
shirts made get them on the shelves at
the spot get more hoodies made get them
on the shelves at the spot
some hats dude I'm glad you said it
because Robert if you're listening to
this episode bro some hats are necessary
we need spot hats and we need iy
genetics Grassroots might as well call
Grassroots right there I will prepa for
my hat I'm saying it right now I'm a
poor [ __ ] and I will give you
$40 out of money I don't have PR for my
hat gr Grassroots Colorado Grassroots
California ruga Ryan if you're listening
to the show brother I would love a
sponsorship I'll do ads for a year in
exchange for iy genetics hats audence we
got audience to 5,000 listeners we
weekly episodes that's a lot that's 52
episodes a year at least with 5,000
people here in your ads this podcast is
brought to you by your good friends at
Grassroots California if you're looking
for a dope ass hat look no further stop
in at something something Lamer in
Denver and pick yourself up a fad ass
Grassroots hat I don't know it's 22
sample yeah he already knows the address
I got a Grassroots hat on right now
so at the table yeah I got about 10 more
on the shelf downstairs out to my friend
hand made my hat [ __ ] y'all yeah
yeah I just can't decide which
Grassroots hat I like the most so I just
keep buying the new fresh one that I see
yeah one yet that's like kind check out
M's purple forever flowering Grassroots
hat that is fresh dude that purple is
purple and baby blue I like that I like
thaty genetics hat got a iy hat pin on
there make it official I think I got iy
hat pin on here no most of my hats have
it but oh this one's already got the
Colorado FL on there enough so I don't
put that on there light.com that's like
one of the coolest websites I've ever
heard of yeah shout out they don't they
don't even pay for that but shout out to
Forever flowering green houses uh if
you're looking for uh if you're it's
dude if you're poor and broke don't even
try but we're not trying I don't have
one on folks so if you got an advanced
grow and you're looking for a nice
outdoor Greenhouse forever fling greenh
houses is the way to go if you can yeah
that'll take your [ __ ] to the next level
I'm trying to sell one for you guys get
at me
yeah you go on vacation and put plants
in and have killer PLS for my efforts
you got to name your company so we can
start shouting it out yeah big shout out
to Jesse's
grow what's up Grammy Gatsby I'll build
that [ __ ] for you I saw those pictures
yeah shout out to hunt dude we're going
to
get [ __ ] yeah me and Gatsby has have
you know relayed messages five or six
times and it's like it's your turn to
come see me bro I know I've never said
that to the
come to the we'll do a podcast we'll get
Garden sh turack and the hunt on the
show all at once it'll be awesome us and
we'll protect you yeah come on down bro
no hunt can take care of himself he
don't he ain't worried about [ __ ] it
ain't that bad it Ain it is a dangerous
city in Colorado though so isn't that
funny though we just live hereid every
day I haven't seen a damn bit of it I'm
sorry but I actually kind of love this
place people are like why do you still
live there and I'm like dude I I I
didn't grow up here but I became who I
am here and I feel like I kind of owe it
to this town to stay here and be who I
am and support the movement here and be
part of this scene here how many times
have we defended it in Denver you know
like yeah and then we beat the [ __ ] out
of the people that were talking [ __ ]
about fck stabbed switch blades took all
their money and their Nikes I'm just
kidding probably the one of the least
violent people I
know all right we have gone almost 50
minutes we should put about another 10
minutes into this show anybody got
anything smartass or great to say
oh what are some of your favorite
moments we've had on this podcast so far
I know remember that night we s here we
talked about it earlier we sat here you
sat across the table from me and we
tried to do a show for like three hours
and I don't know if it was the dabs or
if it was just the the
unfocused of the group but yeah there
was no podcast to that night you know
like in the middle of the podcast he
just walks up in the room starts yelling
and screaming and it was D it was weird
so there's it didn't really happen but
it kind of really did happen happen you
know but that was that was definitely a
funny moment that was funny we I had a
recording error to where I didn't delete
one of the pre-recorded tracks from
another recording session and when it
came around to that that recording
dropped into while we were talking and
it was perfect it was perfect it was
like cuz the guy goes hey it's me man
what's going on it just starts
talking and we like but you're not even
in the room how the hell did you just do
that I thought Jeff was a vental acquist
at that point in time and I was like wow
this isir really weird yeah 3:00 a.m. I
think I need to go home man that's like
some for track
a moment that I really really remember
is when I ate the 350 migr edible on the
podcast I remember I don't remember the
whole hour show but I kind of remember
doing it I sat here holding on to my
chair just tapping my feet as hard as I
could woo I'm flying right now those
things those things you do not want to
come to Colorado and eat
okay may a brownie but that's 350 Mig of
sit the [ __ ] down read theam lab
whatever you're doing yeah if you guys
come to Colorado e Edibles be careful
please luckily that's a medical only but
you know yeah I think they can only sell
100 G Edibles at the recite now what
Incredibles are yeah they're 100 so I
mean yep you can buy like seven of still
Marine Dow 70 of them I don't remember
yeah like it's read the [ __ ]
label like that's what that was the big
lesson of 2014 is what happens if you
legalize wheed oh is it turns out people
don't read labels for [ __ ] anything
ever we just assume people that don't
even take pot like they don't even well
if you think about it do you all
remember the chips that gave you anal
leakage like they were looking for fat
free and it made your [ __ ] drip that
had to be on the front of the bag and
they still sold everywhere and it's
because people don't read labels and
with Edibles that leaves you to hugging
a pair of weird jeans in a hotel room
and then writing about it for the New
York Times Orie may try not to [ __ ]
himself on
stage you know the meme with the little
black kid that always says you mean to
tell me that blah blah blah and blah
blah blah but you mean to tell me there
was some [ __ ] chips that caused anal
leakage and people were still buying it
I forgot that y'all were probably on T
fish tour when this hit the shelves cuz
it's the those timelines line up butra I
think was the special oil they found a
special oil and you could eat chips that
you didn't get any calories from the
side effect was your butt was leaking
yeah all that fat your body didn't
absorb was dripping out your ass so no
I'll pass I will pass America was about
it I don't need a snack I have to eat on
the toilet see Jesse's a fellow eat
anything at the gas station kid you know
what the [ __ ] up no I remember making
fun of my cousin for eating those yeah
remember reading the package I'm like
it's right on the front of the bag May C
anal said anal on the front of a bag of
chips and they still sold all over the
country this is definitely a record time
for the word anal being so so when it
says 350 mli they're in a jar
for people just don't even see it they
think 350 Mig huh that seems like a lot
for a fun Fun Size Snickers edible they
chew that [ __ ] back and 20 minutes later
they think they're in space they're
really just sitting in the hot tub of
their hotel room just splashing in three
inches of water 35 to 45 minutes isn't
enough time seriously give it two or
three hours yeah give it some time to
kick in it's got to be broken down and
processed into your blood and it takes a
while bad Ralphie bad ralie every person
is different hey spenc are you going to
enter any contests in 2015
um hopefully I'd like to I'd like to uh
travel to Oregon and Seattle again this
year and go enter up there
um maybe California but like High Times
cannabis cups or uh hopefully cannabis
cups um
cup maybe what next when is that next
November again or something like that I
think so yeah yeah maybe maybe some I'd
like to get out and kind of the best
thing about going to cups is it's like
vacation but there's weed yeah yeah you
know what I'm saying like you don't have
to like worry about trying to find weed
cuz you're going to a weed event so it's
there you guys got your uh Denver
Cannabis Cup tickets yet um don't know
what we're doing yet so I don't know if
I want to buy tickets or go through the
vending route oh yeah okay I got my
three-day pass I'm just working on
booking a hotel room I've actually got a
ticket to see Doug Benson on 420 at 9:00
b a house it's just me I just roll solo
and just do the backpack thing it's so
much easier get in the car and leave
when I want go I want just going to be
me doing the backpack in the car yeah
all right as soon as I get extra money
um I've gone with a crew of people and
I've gone by myself and it's easier for
me to just go and meet you honestly I I
like going I don't know I like going
with the crew but I like to especially
me when I'm trying to like talk to
people kind of it's kind of hard having
you guys 15 people when you're trying to
all go get tired of hanging out with me
at the Cannabis Cup cuz I'm not even
trying to be egotistical but people walk
up and want to talk to me they know who
I am so if you're hanging out with me
you're just hanging out by yourself
pretty much so I roll solo just go by
myself and yeah easy you can you can do
a lot of [ __ ] by yourself yeah yeah and
you don't I don't have to say hey Mike
do you want to do this are you hungry
Mike these events are so crowded and so
well attended that trying to I'm just
trying to picture one of you walking
with like 15 I mean I'm going to call
them ducklings it's it does it's not
intended as insulting as that sounds I
guess trying to walk down the aisle like
that like you got to lose all your
duckings and then you end up at the end
of the road going well [ __ ] them I got
business do yeah pretty much and that's
the big thing for me this year's
business I'm trying to take care of
business no more no more playing games
and being nice and none of that I'm
trying to come out and take some cake
there you go I'll be trying to talk to
somebody like hanging out with MAA and
then the people with me don't even know
who Mila is no clue who she like do you
know who that was like no I'm [ __ ]
bored like dude that was you should have
got in on that conversation you should
have said hello yeah I should have got
your picture taken he should have gave
her a hug give her some oil or something
yeah yeah I pretty much learned that
quickly that when you're excited I
should be excited when you take me
places when you're pumped that yeah
there's something I should be paying
attention to and even if I don't
understand right now it'll probably be
explained later with this guy even lunch
can be a mild Adventure where famous
people just appear yeah you just got to
accept it it's bizarre you just got to
know how to put yourself in the position
and uh line yourself up to meet the
people you want to meet without being
creepy and realize they're just [ __ ]
people too and if you open with the
right lines they're just humans too and
they realize that you're not a stalker
and they want to talk to you absolutely
I dude I am nobody perfect and I'm sure
I'm not everybody's cup of tea but I
kind of I'm a nice dude that tells the
truth most of the time I felt giddy when
DNA genetics walked up to me and shook
my hand because they recognized me and
my logo from Instagram they're like hey
I know who you are man and they said
what's up to me and gave me props for my
work that kind of put a smile on my face
I got a hot nail somebody talk while I
dab I mean you got you got a great email
set up for him from him you know uh and
Shout out for that we use that thing
every day we used it right before the
show um oh shout out to the Gil I
thought that earlier and then I forgot
it again I'm sorry shout out to OG um
but yeah the gnail is a beautiful
invention these dabs are available that
are on the table anybody can dab out of
that I'm not trying to be stash but just
send it around again yeah here go for it
MD will start helping out too all right
big shout out to dabs yeah big shout out
to
dabs a lot of those early podcasts might
not not have been put together at 3:00
a.m. 3 a.m. yeah don't tell everybody
those happen at like sunrise and [ __ ]
half asleep trying to do a podcast we
weren't half asleep we're just
that's I'm so much more comfortable on a
mic now I just swing the mic in front of
me I don't even edit the shows anymore
I'm just like what's up Podcast time I
feel better putting some of me into the
show instead of just being all
information I feel like I've made a lot
of friends know and from listening to uh
I listened to Nerdist and I listened to
Doug Benson and now when I see those
guys like I saw Nerdist uh Hardwick at
Red Rocks and it was like watching one
of my friends achieve a goal it was so I
feel like maybe my listeners feel like
I'm one of their buddies especially the
people that interact with me on Twitter
and [ __ ] I know I'm their friends like
if I met Mr omnio he lives in the UK If
he showed up he'd bring the doorbell
he'd come in and take dabs and hang out
dude I'd make a cup of your mam mate and
we'd chill out and he'd be my bro and
just because I have a podcast so that
guy's my friend now from that Fred
Garvin would probably show up and come
take dabs we just killed Mike with the
dab there he goes shout out to Mike I'd
really like to for you to get
uhon uh who was on show number two um
Addie Addison deor yeah get him back
you've been asking and asking and asking
but big shout out to Addison I should
have given a shout out to that guy he's
been on the show uh Addison Big D hunt
all the Denver crew Nick shout out shout
out oh don't do that that would be the
most horrific thing ever I know he's
been beating you up the microphone MD's
about to blast Spence's Natty beard
slash dreadlock mess torch to the Dome
torch to the
Dome uh somebody should hold on I'm
going to yell you guys so it be cool hey
Mike are you alive all good y Mike is
alive you guys we did not kill him very
borderline but he made it all right does
anybody else have anything to say we're
down to two minutes I'm going to ear
down to a minute try to keep this about
an hour do your stuff do your stuff
alive and well people nice we did not
kill M dude I Ser I've said it a couple
times but I sincerely want to thank all
you guys for coming to the show you guys
are Adams made jokes about a team and B
team and [ __ ] but this is my crew right
here uh I know if something went wrong
in my life this would be the first five
people I could call to help me out I
really appreciate everything you guys
taught me this year and all together
throughout the times that I've known you
Jeff especially you taught me a lot
since I've moved here from col from
North Carolina now I feel like I'm from
Colorado yeah oh goodness welcome home y
dude thank you I'm uh I didn't realize I
taught you so much I didn't realize you
absorbed so much of what I taught you uh
I learned from you guys too it's not
just me teaching you guys I come and
parrot a lot of [ __ ] that Spence says
just in my own language you know what I
mean I learn [ __ ] from you guys every
day so thank you guys too thanks that
means a lot to me no
problem that goes for both of you guys
like Spence like and Sean yeah Sean and
even Clint and Mike Mike's taught me
grow [ __ ] on accident just uh not just
refreshing your mind not everything
about growing is about growing there's
simple [ __ ] in your grow room that Mike
may go why is that turned that way if
you turn that way you'd get better air
flow and I'm just giving random examples
uh there's like physics and [ __ ] to be
done in the grow room shout out to Tony
also sorry I ski that one he keeps the
website going he keeps the feed going
and he's one of the when I said physics
I thought of Tony right away he knows
about air flow and a lot of that [ __ ] so
guys even if your friends aren't the
best Growers you can learn accidentally
about HVAC you can learn Plumbing like
all that [ __ ] comes in handy so don't
ever take anybody for granted shout out
to vau yeah yeah and Scott and Scott
they'll never listen to this probably
but they they at least deserve the big
love and Ralph SW we're listing people
yeah what's up I learned a drywall
already this year you're a learning [ __ ]
douchebag way to [ __ ] name
it and uh yeah big shout out to Ralph
who Tau me how to drywall 44s method of
learning we'll get you far places all
right yo fish I'm sorry I was uh dissing
you on the other show bro I'm sorry man
yeah no he's also shout out to Dreadful
Jay I haven't giving her a shout out in
a while she listens shout out for impact
resistant glasses this show should just
be called episode 50 mad shout outs
earlier when you're shouting out it
reminded me of 40 o to Freedom that's
kind of what I was going for honestly uh
your mom called she said take a nap
that's kind of what I was going for
goddamn thing about Miami or whatever
I'll try to put some music in the
background of that [ __ ] so I just put
that music in there see if you can find
it get sued bro I'll get I can't I don't
I won't get sued but iTunes will take it
down yeah
cover they've never taken down you're
telling me you can't go down there and
make a dub version somehow like of every
single instrument back in the day I used
to play like Marlin Asher and popular re
and they never flagged any of my shows
but I only had like a 100 listens back
then so nobody that shit's funny
bro thanks chi chi you mean that song
good job Barney Stinson all right uh
thanks for listening you guys uh I
promise the episodes are going to get
better I promise the guests are going to
stay high caliber everybody that's here
is just
hi now he's a smartass after that dabby
took everybody that's here is invited
back whenever they'd like to be back I
promise I'll have everybody here again
um we're going to do maybe get some more
ladies on the show um it's harder to get
ladies on the show there aren't as many
ladies guys have more [ __ ] to talk about
because we're kind of egoists you know
what I mean you hang out with a bunch of
badass dudes uh so I've got a squad of
guys around me all the time that's what
I'm saying I saw that picture you posted
like all these dudes protect me hell
yeah we all have your back dude that was
yeah definitely I'm standing in the back
there with a big old smile like I got
her back forever that was a Merry
Christmas P I mean I know there's other
Growers like in the scene and Instagram
and all that stuff but you're the only
one here locally that's at least known
for producing killer stuff so lady
Growers uh [ __ ] ladies that want to be
on the podcast that have something to
contribute about cannabis if it's your
opinion I know very very few female
Growers that I have a lot of respect for
yeah but hopefully some will step up
come be on the show if you want uh we
are in poblo Colorado on the South Side
all you got to do is uh send me an email
you can call me you can Instagram you
can Facebook me uh it's grow fromy
yourheart hotmail.com I'm on Instagram
at IR gentics that was a big old Dad it
was Spencer just gave me a fat dab and
he got up and left he did it he took it
off somewhere didn't want no part of
that the enail is in the other room
turned on so that could be where he went
there wasn't any room on the table for
the enail tonight with all the the it
was such a fat dab it started coming out
of my nose I it's called an angry dragon
isn't
it this is this is the terminology
people all right on that note we're
going to wrap up the show I love you
guys thanks for listening everybody that
came everybody that's listening everyone
that download the show everyone that
contributes hey also uh a little bit of
pandering I added we added Tony
technically added at the request of
myself a donate button on the iy
genetics website if you go to iry
genetics.com find the grow fromy heart
podcast Tab and there is a donate button
at the top um if you feel like this show
was worth a couple of bucks and you want
to make a slight contribution you can
make a donation to the show uh I will
thank you on the show if you'd like me
to or you can tell me not to say your
name um I'm not begging for money but a
couple of people said that if I had the
donation button they would throw
donations in there and why not take a
donation if someone's trying to offer
absolutely so much of your time and
effort into this you deserve it and not
only that but you can put it back into
the podcast for necessary I'll buy
another microphone you can also we can
potentially have more giveaways you can
also put it as an anonymous so you don't
even need to know you know it it's just
three bucks that came from nowhere and
then I learned about something else that
I may try to do in the future um it's
called a money bomb is what this guy
called it uh if you listen to a lot of
podcasts you may already know about it I
don't want to tell you too much about I
haven't uh paid too much attention to
how to do it but it sounds like a great
idea to where it will give me money to
give away to my listeners and also help
fund the podcast a little and like
Maddie said I do put some time into this
uh they everybody here spent about an
hour with me before we even recorded
putting this show together uh I was
thinking while you were talking what it
would cost to get all of us in a room
uhhuh uh sa for like a two-hour
consultation with the
business and it's in the thousands oh
yeah I'm expensive for that kind of
thing if you get all this at the table
being up is upfront and honest as we are
at the podcast and I'm sitting there
thinking about the content over the last
50 episodes and if you go back and
cherry pick say like the outdoor grow
lesson episodes or and the growing and
curing and harvesting
episodes
that's like job training if you pay
attention to take notes no you could
fully have a career based on that
information if you put a couple of years
of practice into it and do your own
independent research that's the found
that's like a bachelor's degree in
weed like not even [ __ ] around a
little that's legit and Jesse's outdoor
lessons this year basically walked me
through my outdoor this year you know
like there was there was Cure episode
got your weed dried and cured absolutely
and then sea came and talked to you
about Organics and taught you how to not
go buy bottled nutrients anymore and I
mean just yesterday I mixed up grok
Kashi you know what I'm saying like H
look out so here for a year mixing grok
Kashi right I want to get an extract
artist on here that will teach us how to
make hash but at the same time that's
risky because uh we can't teach you how
to open blast cuz that's not legit and
then uh nobody wants to give away their
clothes sit around and tell you how a
whole bunch maybe we'll get someone to
come teach us how to make water hash
we'll get Fred Morris or somebody to
come teach you how to make water hatch
it's a very good idea yeah Fred Morris
if you listen to the show hit me up bro
please i' want you to come on and teach
us how to make water has you know uh so
long cross the table there doesn't know
knows quite a bit about water hash as
well he's keeping his head down but you
know uh you know he also knows who Fred
Morris is so he knows why I'm saying
Fred Morris I'm not I'm not trying to
call you out just saying that you know
I've smoked it and it was very
impressive you know maybe I haven't had
that much bubble has but I do all right
Spence got add he had to go charge his
over there to High man you can't give
him that many dabs for a podcast it's
all good that's just how we roll all
he's thinking about is damn Amy
Donuts dude it's 9:00 they're closed
what I thought they closed at 700 they
closed at 700 we would have so stopped
stopped on we yeah they yeah I thought I
said it's 9: they're closed no you told
me the other day they closed at 7:00 I
better hurry up yeah they they Clos at
7:00 that's what I'm saying it's 9: and
they are closed oh okay okay I thought
you made it as they were open till n
first rule Amy's Donuts is you don't say
anything about Amy's Donuts so you just
to Amy I've never had to go to a dut
place and be like nothing with bacon on
it please like that's weird for me I'm a
vegetarian I don't want bacon Donuts is
is the vanilla cheesecake ones that you
like it's absolutely my favorite fella
cheesecake is top I'm that I'm not what
what I banana something got
ban yeah the Elvis was good the peanut
butter and J original glaz come be on
the podcast come get some Amy's Donuts
enjoy P we trying to get smoke fat D the
green chili one is banging all right
let's wrap up this show you guys big
shout out to everybody that listened if
you made it an hour and 10 minutes into
this podcast I love you every day
YouTube search the grapest
Spence is packing up he's stretching you
going to the gym after this bro he's
going to leave me it looks like he's
to run up out of here let's finish this
up before MADD has to walk home here we
go uh now that the show is over please
go to iTunes Andor Stitcher go to the
iTunes Store to the stitcher main page
and search for ulture grow fromy Heart
by the time this comes out it better be
fully switched to grow from your heart
I'm going to get that logo speed rush
made um I've got to do a couple things
I'm working on another company also so
that I've got multiple logos to work
with but don't worry uh Bender I
appreciate your logo and I need it also
keep it coming but I've got another idea
that I want to use uh so I need that
logo been home to talk to him he doesn't
reply to my emails either so it's cool
uh search for the show find the review
section give me a festar rating after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comments on the show if you think I
completely suck at podcasting you can
say that if you think I've got a shitty
Voice or an awesome voice you can say
that too just tell me what you think and
I will try to improve and make you happy
or I might just ignore you and block you
uh don't forget the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every episode will
always be archived on iy genetics
color.com and don't forget about that
donation button yeah it goes right to my
PayPal um my daughter's trying to go on
this uh Adventure in Hawaii an
educational adventure and most of the
money will probably go to that to tell
you the truth not trying to kiss your
ass but that's probably what I'm going
to do with it truth make sure you follow
us on Twitter and Facebook to search for
grow from your heart uh please follow iy
genetics on Instagram if you want to win
those prizes you know what you got to do
follow iy genetics if you interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like us to review send me
an email it's scart hotmail.com and I'll
get you all the info you need big shout
out to my ninja Spence who is higher
than giraffe [ __ ] in the corner walking
around in my house over there he's like
exploring your
home glass collection that's cool he's
been through the dab breaks prize packs
and he's just having a b his eyes were
as red as that microphone cover when the
show started part 15 minutes they'll
have breakfast ready I guarantee [ __ ]
we'll let him keep roaming around the
house
um with bacon please shout out Spence
shout out bro thanks for coming hope you
uh got some food somewhere
close I know that's what I'm thinking
about too thanks for everybody that
showed up starved starved everyone's
dying we're going to go get some food
before we die everybody oh uh thanks for
again for listening check us out on
episode 51 until then take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
me first place in the race hand raised
with the torch get the paper you don't
get the paper from the porch I used to
get my flavors from my neighbors to the
north now C runs the valley hence forth
for first place in the race hand raised
with the torch get the paper you don't
get the paper from the porch I used to
get my flavors from my neighbors to the
north now C runs the
valley L with the bumping track let me
get another pack on the butter so you
know the [ __ ] back ouru is
gifted and we lifted like a hover crap
Lumberjacks coming for your trees and we
run the back
all my friends creating gold from a
bunch of SCP we set the trends break the
mold then we run it back people thaning
me for showing them the way to go like
way to go B made it on the radio give me
a Dabber and a skill it in L or a mic
cuz I'm a rapper who can kill it as well
entrepreneur man building the wealth ill
is in so cool I only chill with myself
yeah so if you Woll I would bet it's
probably cuz you want to be following my
footsteps if you're a fan then it's
likely a pioner you can look back on
this and