[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
and it is time for episode 567 of the
grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10
while checking out at seeds here now
dot com you know i like to start the
podcast off by talking about what i'm
smoking
today i've been taking dabs of coin
style
live batter from green dot labs this is
a blend of sugar town express and lemon
g13
on the package the flavor is described
as a coin style
margarita on the rocks unfortunately or
maybe fortunately
i don't know what a coin style margarita
on the rocks tastes like i'm not an
alcohol drinker
i don't consume any alcohol so i haven't
had a margarita in at least 10 or 12
maybe 15 years
don't remember what that tastes like
couldn't tell you if that's an accurate
description or not
what i can tell you is it's [ __ ]
delicious if that is an accurate
description a coin style margarita
tastes [ __ ] delicious it is very
lemony it is very citrusy
it's got a little bit of a funk to it i
can actually really taste the lemon g
that is in the
blend here but that sugar town i think
is giving it a really nice
sweetness one thing i do really enjoy
about this concentrate
is it kind of [ __ ] me up it makes me uh
like it puts on some blinders it gives
me like a tunnel vision
it is the kind of concentrate that you
may sit down thinking you're about to
record a podcast next thing you know
you've checked your emails for 35
minutes
time has flown by you didn't even know
any time it passed and you wake
you look up from the computer and you're
thirsty as [ __ ] you got to get back to
work
you didn't even know you've been wasting
35 minutes so
that is the coin style live batter from
our friends at green dot labs
i really enjoy this concentrate on the
back of the package it says it contains
65.58 thc i think the rest of that is
straight up terps because this is so
tasty it is very potent it leaves a nice
flavor on the tongue
nice lingering aroma in the room i
obviously enjoy
the coin style live batter from green
dot labs so shout out to our friends at
green dot for the delicious concentrate
i'll show the camera the concentrate
here
of course you can see i took a big
dollop out of that gram delicious
beautiful texture beautiful color great
work from green dot
all right let's move into the show in
this episode i'm going to do a couple of
updates
from previous episodes then we're going
to read some patreon messages
before we get to that part let's do some
shout outs to the members of
the 710 club of course the 710 club for
the folks who support the show
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher on patreon
so with no further ado let's do some
shout outs let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to miss karen crawford
let's send another thank you shout out
to canner reaper i want to send a big
thank you shout out to prospect
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for craig compton i need to
send a big thank you shout out to north
terps what up north i see you pop up a
lot
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for tommy i want to send a huge
thank you shout out to ned denver
i want to say thank you to steven d
smith i also want to send a giant thank
you to lefties farms what's up bro hope
you're doing well
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to ross decay also a big thank you to
kent
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to our friend
victor big thank you and big shout out
for all of the continued support
if you are not already supporting the
show on patreon and you would like to
learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need
will be right there on the screen
all right i did say i was going to do
some updates in this episode uh in a
previous episode
i talked about grafting i read a message
from a patreon supporter about grafting
cannabis plants
and i said that i feel like the genetics
may move around if we
graft multiple plants onto one branch i
said a lot of
uh maybe slightly negative things in my
opinion about grafting that were very
uneducated and i was
very clear that those were my opinions
and i had no education i'd never done it
and i said it seemed silly to me
i was corrected if i make a grafted
plant those genetics will not move each
branch
apparently will stay true to that
genetic somehow the genetics don't move
around i don't understand that part
i am willing to admit that so i got a
lot of great corrections and updates
grafting seems to be a viable practice i
apologize for bashing that
the genes don't move around uh we
wouldn't have good apples if grafting
wasn't a common practice
now let's move into another update uh we
had a blind grower
send us a message shout out to our
friend david in brazil uh send us a
message
saying that they think their plans may
be finishing
too early as soon as that episode went
out i got a lot of great
feedback so let's do some updates most
of the feedback came from the youtube
channel
and they were great ideas one listener
or viewer since it was from youtube one
viewer
suggested that since this uh grow is
possibly in brazil
that maybe the equatorial location
is giving those plants super intense sun
and they are finishing
earlier simply because they are getting
more sun more sun is more energy for the
plants
you've heard me talk about turning my
light cycle onto 18 6 at the end of
flower the last 10 days
that way it'll beef up the buds because
they get more light of course more light
is more
energy so yes maybe they are finishing
more quickly because of that intense
mountain sun breeders steve talks about
some plants
finishing earlier i think he's in south
america can't remember i think he said
colombia
that may be where he is breeder steve's
plants finish sooner
uh in near the equator so that may be a
thing you may be getting that
brighter sun that equatorial sun the
environment is just right
maybe that is one of the reasons why our
friend is getting earlier
finishing plants another thing that we
thought of
is maybe perhaps the and our friend is
blind so he's got a helper who is
helping them
maybe that helper is not looking at
trichomes they stated that the trichomes
were brown
maybe perhaps we have thought that maybe
they're not looking at trichomes and
perhaps they're looking at
pistols because pistols do turn brown
however pistols are not the indicator of
ripeness when it comes to a cannabis
plant
pistols are basically the sex parts for
a cannabis plant
and when a cannabis plant passes its
prime time for being bred the pistols
simply shrivel up
also pistols will shrivel up from
disruption from moisture from foliar
sprays
from you touching it from an insect
crawling on it from wind
a lot of things will cause pistols to
curl up and basically wither and die
so possibly we assume we think that
possibly
this assistant is looking at pistols and
not trichomes
so we need to clarify the difference
between a pistol and a trichome
the things that everybody calls a red
hair those are your pistols
those are the parts where the pollen
will land the pollen will go down that
into an ovule and create a seed inside
of your bud
that's what that is for a trichome is a
completely different part of the plant
it is the part that everybody calls the
crystals so you got hairs and crystals
those are now pistols and trichomes if
you want to keep up
the trichomes are what indicate ripeness
we are smoking
ripe trichomes we just happen to have
those trichomes delivered to us on a
green
leafy matter when we make concentrate we
basically remove the trichomes from the
green leafy matter that's why we get
more lit more easily
there's not as much green stuff to smoke
everything you're smoking is basically
extracted trichomes and the oils from
those trichomes
so we need to make sure that the
assistant is looking at trichomes and
not looking at pistols that is a huge
difference
the mushroom things that you see on the
plant all over the plant the crystals if
you look at them with the scope with the
magnifier they look like mushrooms
they got a stock they have a bulbous
head on them those are the trichomes
those are what we are looking for
we want those in most cases with most
cultivars with most growers for most
ideal
conditions i can't say all the time
because there's never an all the time in
cannabis
uh but most of the time most growers
want to harvest when those trichomes
appear to be about 30 percent amber so
if you can get a hundred trichomes in
your view
or if you can look around and see about
a hundred trichomes you want 30
of those 100 trichomes to be turning in
amber color you will see clear trichomes
you'll see trichomes that have turned
like a milky white color you'll see
trichomes that are almost a baby blue
they've got like a silver and bluish
tint to them then you will also see some
that are starting to turn like a
brownish color on the inside
then you'll see some trichomes that look
like they've got dr pepper or soda on
them
those are the ripe trichomes right when
you start to see those
dark ones are probably a little bit past
your peak point but
if you've got 30 percent amber trichomes
the rest of the trichomes you've got 70
percent that are going to be right where
you want them to be
so we want to harvest at 30 percent 25
30 percent amber trichomes
again we need a scope a magnifying glass
to see the color of the heads of the
trichomes
but that is when we should be harvesting
i think most of the growers here have
listened to my determining ripeness
podcast
so again look at the trichomes not the
hairs that is another thing that we
think
may be happening in this situation and
again i'm not accusing or making
judgments
these are just ideas that myself and
other growers think may be causing
this issue and it's not really an issue
if the plants are finishing
too early that means you're getting buds
too early you get to harvest too early
you get your crop
earlier you're not going to risk a lot
of problems in colorado right now
it was 85 to 100 degrees for a month
straight
everybody was looking sunburnt and
looking burned out and sweaty and tired
from the heat
then last night it got to 32 degrees
right now i'm looking at my
a little indicator to show me the
temperature it is 36 degrees outside
in the next few days it is going to go
back up is going to go back up to
probably 80 or 90
degrees all of these giant temperature
swings give us opportunity
for huge problems in the grow here in
colorado a lot of crops were lost to a
surprise
snowstorm here at the start of september
we usually don't expect snow until
around halloween
on september 8th and 9th we were hit
with snow a lot of crops were
destroyed outdoors so those people that
have early finishing plants that finish
too early
maybe you're going to get lucky and beat
that early snowstorm you probably don't
have a snowstorm coming in brazil but
you do have something coming
maybe police maybe robbers maybe animals
maybe there's something out there that
could destroy your crops so if it's down
too
early that means it's down too early uh
in colorado
we got a lot of crops destroyed by snow
storms in california
crops are getting destroyed by wildfires
there is a very good likelihood that
when harvest time comes
maybe only half to a third of the
expected crops outdoors are going to be
cut down
and brought to the market this year so
there's a very good opportunity and
potential
that prices will rise at the end of this
year and the start of next year so
people that are used to paying
that low price for their cannabis [ __ ]
may go back
up because of all these natural things
happening the snowstorms ruined a lot of
money
the fires are burning down a lot of
money we're going to lose a lot of
cannabis farms to these fires we're
going to lose a lot of genetics we're
going to lose a lot of important [ __ ] so
while i'm thinking about i want to send
some love to all the people suffering
through
these [ __ ] fires and snowstorms right
now uh my heart goes out to
everybody but uh big respect and big
love to all the farmers losing [ __ ]
all right i need to get myself back the
[ __ ] on track uh
your crop may be finishing early uh
because of
your equatorial location also you may be
looking at pistols
not trichomes see i'm getting myself
back on track it is working
another theory that we think may be
happening in this grow
is you were saying that the plants are
finishing about 21 days too
early maybe perhaps you are judging
the first day of flower at the first
sign of
pistols and not actually the first day
the plants go into flower
if you are seeing pistols and you're
considering that the first day of flower
i would recommend backing your calendar
up about two weeks
it takes about 10 to 14 days to see
pistols on a flowering plant
in most cases i can't say all the time
every time when it comes to cannabis
there are always going to be anomalies
most of the time in cannabis we can see
pre-flower
we can see sex in about 14 days so if
you're
judging the day one from the time you
start seeing those pre-flowers those
pistols pop
up you can adjust your calendar your
schedule by about two weeks and you can
say they've been in flower for two weeks
longer than what you've been saying
which may
put you right on the schedule that the
breeders recommended on the back of
those packages
so those are the things we think may be
happening you may be uh getting a faster
finishing plant because of your location
on the equator
you may be looking at pistols and not
trichomes and you may be
judging by the wrong start day of flower
you may be judging day 14 as day one
somewhere around day 10 to 17 you may be
mistaking that for day one
maybe i'm not in your grow like i said i
can't accuse you or blame you on
anything these are just theories that we
think may be happening and we're trying
to help you out so we're sharing ideas
uh check on these three things
see if these three things can be causing
your not problem problem
i don't think it's a problem so there's
nothing to correct here
but maybe like i said before if you were
looking at
pistols and not trichomes we may want to
let these plants go a little bit longer
so if you're not
looking at the right part of the plant
to judge maturity maybe you can improve
your crop you didn't say you were happy
with it maybe you could be even happier
uh send me another email let me know if
i helped you out thanks for all the
great feedback thank you for the great
interaction
and i do look forward to hearing back
from you also big thanks to all of my
friends who left a comment on the
youtube video or sent me a message
with their theory or their idea of what
they think could be happening in this
person's grow
i do come on this show and i get all of
the credit for putting this show
together
but i've got to give you guys credit a
lot of people gave me feedback input
advice and information on
this exact topic and without you guys
this episode wouldn't have been what it
is
so thank you i also appreciate all of
the emails and interaction because i
love
getting emails and knowing that the
questions i read are actually helping
somebody
i'll write shows about random topics uh
re-vegging or drying and curing i know
that stuff will go well
sometimes i get ideas and i'll do a show
and i'm like i wonder if anybody even
needs this advice
so when you send me a message and you
say hey help that really helps me out so
thank you guys
for all the participation the feedback
the input that [ __ ]
means a lot to me i'm gonna quit
rambling i'm telling you this coin style
live batter it will
[ __ ] your brain up you'll get a lot of
stuff done but it won't be any of the
[ __ ] you intended to do
let's get back on track here i've got a
patreon message this one comes from our
friend xavier
what's up bro good to hear from you this
one goes
a lot like this it says yo what's up
rasta jeff i really want to thank you
for your hard work
thank you bro i'm glad you notice it it
says creating all of your killer
genetics
oh it says i want to thank you for all
of your hard work creating all of your
killer
genetics i'm glad you find my genetics
killer uh i want to see pics of your
grow
it goes on to say your amazing podcast
helped me get through my third grow with
ease and confidence
thanks so much for that i appreciate it
i love hearing that i'm making your grow
easier and making you more confident
that's the idea i want to make you more
comfortable more confident in your grow
so that you can make decisions on the
fly you don't panic when [ __ ] goes wrong
that's my goal here so i love hearing
that i'm hitting the goal i love hearing
that you're getting toward your goal
with my help also that means a lot
i should continue it says i've just
harvested some lemon jeffrey orgasm
bebop
and the cream you've got a nice
selection the lemon jeffree's got those
lemon terps the orange
gasm of course the orange terps bebop
has got that cushy possibility if you
get the right phenotypes
and the cream is unique in its own it's
got that root beer cream soda sort of a
terp to it and if you're making
concentrates the cream is the boss
anyway it goes on it says these plants
blew my freaking mind i
love hearing that they put on some
insane harvest weight
uh this is good advertising i did not
write this message it says all i had to
do was make sure that all of my girls
were nice and comfy in a trellis netting
with lots of plant steaks for extra
support i'm going to interrupt you
um if you did the trellising
properly you won't need those extra
supports i'm not trying to dog you not
trying to diss you we're going to
improve your grow right now
where you think you had to add extra
headed i said had it i did that again
not even editing it we're going to keep
moving i say weird [ __ ]
if you uh if you had added i think
that's what i meant to say if you had
added a third net
or to hold those buds up or if you had
worked those
uh branches into that net properly you
wouldn't need needed
my words are all [ __ ] up we'll get
back there in a minute you would not
have needed stakes the idea when you're
making a trellis is to get that canopy
nice and even
so the ones that are sticking up that
you needed a stake for probably again i
can't see your grow dude i don't know
what's going on
but you probably could have worked those
branches in just a little bit more and
kept the canopy nice and even
if you've got a few sticking up or you
needed a few stakes i would have put
another
layer did i say it again i don't know i
would have put another layer of trellis
net
to keep all those branches in there but
i don't know what you're doing
send me some pictures i think you did
i'm going to look at your pictures and
see if we can help you out
anyway let's continue with this email
just wanted to talk about the trellising
get them even the idea is to get a nice
even canopy get those sticks out of
there
of course if you need them that may be a
good thing i can't see your grow
let's stay focused since i dialed my in
my environment and i feed all of my
girls
uh the feed just went as wild as i
wanted them to do
they fattened up all the way up till
harvest but i was not able
to get all of my plants to yellow and
flush
all right so the grow went great it
sounds like everything went well
but during the flush phase the plants
did not yellow
as expected i don't find that to be a
problem
but it goes on to say i was literally
flooding them for two weeks and i only
got a couple of plants to yellow
if some of my plants didn't yellow at
all
even though i flushed the [ __ ] out of
them does that mean i still have a lot
of nutrients trapped
in my buds i was growing in soil with
1200 ppms in flowering by the time i got
done with my flush my runoff was very
low for soil
i think 110 ppms and this is combined
runoff from multiple plants that were
flushed all right this is a very good
and unique question a lot of people when
they flush their plants they expect and
want to see
the plants start to turn yellow they
think we're flushing the nutrients out
of here
these plants should turn yellow they
should start fading and showing me their
fall colors they're about to die
that is not always necessary you do not
have to get yellow dead crispy looking
plants at the end of your grow they can
be nice and green and lush
they don't have to be yellow and crunchy
and faded
it's really cool it looks really nice i
love taking pictures when they start
turning
like a little bit of golden colors at
the end they get those red hues the
purples start coming in
but they don't have to fade some
genetics will not fade no matter
i guess they all fade no matter what you
do to them they'll run out of nutrients
eventually
but some they just look happy right up
to the end
um how's the smoke that's what meant
really matters did you cut them down
have you dried them and cured them
how do they smoke uh the dry and cure
process is really going to play a huge
role in this but
does it smoke well does it smoke harshly
does it smoke smoothly
does it taste good does the ash burn
white is the ash chunky
if you roll it into a joint or pack it
into a bowl and take a few hits off of
it
does the part you smoke turn into like a
charcoal briquette or does it turn into
a white
flaky soft ash that's really the way to
judge
if it was flushed properly or not and if
you dried and cured it those two things
are going to come into
interplay together at the end here so
it's all about how's the smoke
you say you were trying to uh get all of
the nutrients out does it mean you still
have nutrients trapped in my buds
i don't there's a lot of controversy
around
flushing and not flushing right now and
i'm trying not to pick a side i'm trying
to stay open-minded as somebody who
teaches and shares
information i can't pick a side i can't
be biased in this topic because i don't
have enough information
but when i think about flushing i think
that i'm trying to clean out
the soil or the medium to get that clean
so that the plants don't have any more
to eat just they're gonna
they're going to simply quit eating
there are nutrients and sugars
stored throughout the plant mainly in
the leaves but the stuff in the buds
i feel like that has been metabolized
and converted into
buds it's no longer nitrogen phosphorous
potassium aluminum calcium magnesium
boron
several other nutrients and elements it
is now bud material
like today i nobody cares what i ate i
had food today
that food is not food inside of me it is
now in my blood it's becoming
muscle tissue skin not much muscle i'm
[ __ ] skinny but it's trying
uh it's making muscle tissue it's making
skin it's making my blood move it's
providing me vitamins
those so there's vitamin c and iron in
my food today
uh i am not i'm not iron and vitamin c
right now there's a lot of those things
that have turned into parts of me that
have become part of me
and i when i go pee or poop it's not
going to be
vitamin c and iron that comes out it's
not going to be like that
i don't think i i know i got way off
track on that but i don't think that the
buds are the nutrient they've converted
into buds now it's not just nitrogen and
phosphorus and potassium so you can't
really
wash that out of the buds in my opinion
i don't have science behind this i'm
trying to explain my theory so that
stuff has turned into
you you mixed up a and b and now you've
got c and you can't wash a and b
back out or you would just lose c and i
understand that you want to rinse the
nutrients out so the buds burn
cleanly but i think if you flushed and
even if they're not showing you that
they're angry
you're not going to smoke the leaves so
the leaves don't need to change colors
as long as the
the plants are flushed and they've
stopped eating they've metabolized all
the stuff in there
and turned anything that was in the
plant system into smokable buds
that is my theory i don't have science
behind that
i can't prove that but that's what i'm
thinking you're not going to smoke those
leaves
so why are you watching for the leaves
to change colors other than it looks
[ __ ] great
it's really beautiful and you've got a
nice row of plants and they've got that
fall colors
that's my fall color [ __ ] photograph
right there if i was going to make a
postcard for somebody it'd be
fall color cannabis leaves but um you're
just trying to get the plants to stop
eating and use up the stored food
you can't remove that part from the
plant in my opinion i don't have science
behind this i am still learning you guys
just like you guys
i'm still learning i may be learning on
a different level and learning different
things
but i am still learning i don't feel
like i know it all i'll never know at
all
that's one of the great things about
cannabis when i learn something i go oh
that's really cool
and then i realized that that makes me
able to learn
two more things and when i learn those
two things i gotta learn
three more [ __ ] things to understand
those two things to be able to put those
three things with the first two things i
learned back with some old school [ __ ]
and then i go oh man
my head explodes and i just learned 12
new [ __ ] things on accident
it's like an epiphany every day in the
grow for me i love learning you guys and
i'm glad that you want to learn with me
and from me
i'm [ __ ] high as [ __ ] from that coin
style live batter so i'm gonna get
myself
back on track here i think your plants
will be great you flushed for two weeks
uh your runoff and your ppm was very low
so your plants aren't eating
they've cannibalized themselves they've
eaten all the nutrients that were left
over
now i want to know how was the smoke
i've seen pictures of the grow
i've gotten a report on the grow i know
that you flushed
this message came in a little bit ago i
want to know how
did this crop turn out also i owe you an
apology because it took me a long time
to get this message on the show
and the last episode i did say i think
i'm caught up on patreon messages
and our friend xavier said hey bro
you're not you skipped me so i found
your message
here you are i apologize for taking a
while i'm pretty sure you've cut that
down
smoked it by now let me know what it
tastes like how it burns and if you're
satisfied
and then let's see what we can improve
in the next grow
all right xavier i want to thank you for
the great patreon message i want to
thank you for the continued support
i want to move into one more email
for this episode and this one goes just
like
this it says hey ross to jeff thanks for
being extremely
an extremely positive force during the
times we all
face much appreciated thank you for
noticing
um i'm not always super happy and
positive but when i come on a camera or
a microphone i gotta be in a good mood
trust me some days i wake up and i go ah
there's some bummers in my life
sometimes but
what are we gonna do we're gonna be
bummed out all day are we going to have
a bummer moment and you take a dab and
[ __ ] realize that you got a lot of
other good [ __ ] going on
you got one bummer moment and like 9 000
good moments every day
i'm going to embrace those 9 000 good
moments so i try to stay positive
especially during these weird [ __ ]
times
uh having an audience that are basically
my friends and backup family
that really helps so thank you guys it
goes on
it says i have a few questions for you i
recently listened to episode
404 grow lessons part four
man you are way behind but thank you for
listening it says i heard you talk about
the shine a few times uh one of my
questions is on the shine so shine is a
product
from uh it's hydroponic research they
make the veg bloom line
i recommend the shine it's a great
product that says i'm wondering what
weeks of bloom
do you recommend using the shine i know
you said
using it a week before a flower should
help stop initial stretch
also used during the first five days of
flush i also heard you mention that some
kind of enzyme would be good to add
at the end with the shine i'm using
advanced nutrients
so what i need to use scentsy zyme as my
enzymes there's a lot of good stuff to
talk about here and this
so let me back up what weeks of bloom do
you recommend
shine and they remembered that i
recommend using it
uh the week before you start flower to
help stop initial stretch
shine is not a cheap product it's got a
good price tag on it so
a lot of people use shine sparingly or
as needed
i use shine extra and i find that if
i've got plants that are super stretchy
at the beginning of flower if i give
them a product called shine
right before flower and through the
beginning of flower they do not stretch
as much give them half of the
recommended dose or the recommended dose
which i think is a gram or two per
gallon of water
uh start off small you don't need to
give it a lot just have the presence of
shine in there at the beginning
and they'll say oh we're going to get
fed real well i don't need to stretch
real hard there's plenty of nutrients i
don't need to go crazy
they don't stretch as much also like i
said before the product is not free
it's a little bit spendy if you don't
want to start early
and spend an extra three or two weeks
using the shine
that is when you start at the beginning
of week three you can start a week two
or week three
the earlier the better in my opinion but
get it in there by the start of week
three that is when you need it
in there uh before flower will help
reduce stretch
having it in there at the beginning of
flower will help reduce stretch having
it in there early
will help start trichome development
earlier start packing on thicker denser
buds
so um it's kind of up to your budget and
how many
things you want to be mixing in your
ppms your growth style
that's kind of what it's up to how much
shine do you have access to what's your
budget i said that already
but that's how i use it if you want to
go early it will
help stop with the stretch also to help
stop with stretch crack and twist those
plants
i talk about popping and twisting you
basically grab it one spot
grab another twist your hands opposite
directions kind of gently until you hear
a pop it should sound like
should sound like a knuckle popped once
you hear that sound just move up do it
again
do that all over the entire plant give
it knuckles burl it up real well
that plant will spend most of its energy
fixing those broken knuckles
and it's not going to slow down anything
other than the vertical growth we're not
making buds yet
the plant is still realizing oh it's
flower time i need to transition
from vegging to flower so the hormones
are moving around the plants trying to
figure out what to do
it'll get into flour in about 14 days
crack it pop it twist it
just before flower right at the start of
flower and then about week three
then keep going if you want to that'll
stop your stretch from getting too out
of control so add the shine
and then crack and twist it says also
use during the first five days of flush
yes if you're in coco
and you're gonna flush for about 14 days
you can add shine
with your flush but make sure you flush
hard at the end to get that out of there
that is kind of a uh
a more advanced grower technique some
beginner growers may burn the plants or
have a shitty tasting product
if they try to go too hard at the end
but if you're flushing
you can use about two grams of shine for
the lat for the first five days of the
flush cycle
if you're going to flush for 14 days do
that if you're you got to add time to
the flush phase
so just clean water and shine then i
said that i could add some kind of an
enzyme to the flush phase
uh yes i like enzymes during flush again
this is kind of budget
uh according budget friendly if if
you've got an unlimited budget and you
can buy some enzymes
if you've got a big grow enzymes get
expensive if you have a little tiny grow
enzymes aren't that expensive you could
buy a bottle of hydrozyme or scentsy
zyme
and they'll go a long way if it fits
your budget flush with some enzymes for
the first week or so
what that will do is the enzymes get in
the root zone and break down all the
[ __ ] and help clean out that root
zone so as you're flushing you're
getting out
everything you guys that recycle your
cocoa or soil that's a really good idea
to make sure that all the small roots
all the dead stuff all the decaying
matter in there
gets broken down and cleaned out of your
root zone before you recycle that
so i do recommend an enzyme in there i
like enzymes
a lot in my grow it really helps out
does a lot of things keeps the soil
safe and healthy a little bit of enzymes
a little bit of plus life together your
soil will be really happy lots of
microbes in there with that obviously
every time
but i do like enzymes the next part of
the question is i'm using advanced
nutrients
so what i need to use scentsy zyme as my
enzyme no
absolutely not there's no need to stick
with that brand specific nutrient
just because you're using advanced
nutrients does not mean you have to use
scentsy zyme
uh you can use any enzyme product out
there that fits your budget fixture
fits your growth style or is simply
available at your local grow store some
products are harder to get
some people don't like to shop online
they don't want amazon showing up
i ordered a carbon filter and they
brought me a carbon filter
with no like wrapping around it it was
just said carbon filter and i was like
[ __ ] i didn't need that delivered here
but it came that way so i don't like to
order some things from amazon
here's a trick if you're going to order
something from amazon like a carbon
filter
there's a box that says this order this
item is a gift
click it as a gift and they'll wrap it
for you now when it shows up at your
house
it's [ __ ] wrapped and it's not
showing that this is a carbon filter
this is a box of nutrients
that'll help you out get that [ __ ] gift
wrapped all right
uh where the hell are we in this message
i lost my place
um i remember where we are i was just
about to say
you don't need scentsy zyme you can use
there are a lot of enzymes out there i
don't even need to list them get the one
that's available for you then i was
gonna say
thank you for the great message i wanted
to check and see if you left the name on
here but you did not leave a name
i don't know if you want your name said
so you know who you are thank you for
the great message
thank you for all the good support i'm
[ __ ] rambling
from those dabs i should wrap it up but
since i'm so rambly we're gonna go ahead
and read one more message
big shout out to all of our patreon
supporters this one comes from north
north terps
on patreon what up north i see your name
pop up a lot thank you for the support
this one goes hey rasta jeff i still
think that should be a song
then it says great great shows thanks
for always answering my questions
you're a real blessing to have around i
learn a lot of practical knowledge
i love how punctual you are um i didn't
realize how punctual i am thank you
uh that's because i can set shows to
come out at a certain time when they pop
up
i don't know that i'm sitting here at
the time all these shows come out that's
uh that's pre-programmed stuff
unless you mean the uh the instagram
live every monday around 7
10 i'm here i need to keep going with
this email because i'm [ __ ] rambly
it says with that being said you talked
about how well organized
you are your spreadsheets and how you
love them
and i was wondering if i can get an
empty copy of these
so that i could implement this into my
life i'm organized only in my head but
my add in my bad handwriting does not
allow me
to do the best i can also as i have half
a
thumb on my writing hand and i haven't
been able to write well
so if you could help me that would be
dope also shout out to white mike what's
up dude
i like seeing you on the show more mike
got a shout out what's up bro
uh big shout out to north terps who did
not use
a single piece of punctuation in this
whole message that's why it was hard to
read
just picking on your north you don't
have a thumb so uh you're you're missing
your punctuation thumb it looks like
nothing but love for you um
north realizes that i'm organized and
i've said that i keep all a lot of my
information on spreadsheets
and north is asking for a copy of my
spreadsheets
i don't really have a template that i
use i open up a google
document and i make a custom document
for
anything that i'm doing so right now
i've got a document that says
room a and then that's a column and then
on the side it's just the date
and then on the date i will put uh so on
right here it's like september
first second third fourth and then in
room a i've got the
ph and ec of the water going into the
plants
and the next graph is the water coming
out of the plants so it's uh room a
and roommate out and i just know that
the google doc is actually labeled room
a
and the first two columns are in and out
and then every day i just know that in
and out that's what's going in and out
of those plants
and i just make and create google
documents that work for my mind for my
grow style for my brain for my phone for
my ipad
i just build them like that they work
for me so i don't really have
custom spreadsheets or anything i guess
they're all just custom for me
so my advice is learn how to use google
documents a lot of businesses a lot of
the future is on google docs so
learn how to use google docs get that
figured out and just create your own
custom spreadsheets you'll or open uh
what is it google spreadsheets google
docs
you learn to use both of those and
you'll start utilizing it to the best of
your ability uh you're gonna have to
get your thumbs figured out because it
does require a little bit better typing
in those small boxes but
i think you'll be able to figure it out
the add
doesn't make it easier by using a google
doc because you go to open your phone
and now you've opened your phone and
then you see that i put out a new show
and now instead of making a google doc
you're watching my next podcast
but i think you'll figure it out bro
i've got faith in you i'll just open up
a google document or a google
spreadsheet
start poking around it's free you can't
[ __ ] it up it may be easier for you on a
computer you can also
share the same document if you log into
google docs with your email address
whatever it is north north terps at
[ __ ] north terps.com
log in on your computer log in on your
mobile device you can get the same
spreadsheet on the same on your both
devices
it's much easier to do the spreadsheets
on the computer sometimes especially if
you're missing a finger
i may help you out so i wish i had more
templates or more advice for you but
honestly i just create my own google
spreadsheets and google docs and
write what i need to write uh not a lot
of it happens on paper anymore because
like yourself
i've got scribbly handwriting and also
uh paper just
makes piles and gets [ __ ] a mess in
the grow so most of it's in google docs
google spreadsheets
and then it's there forever and then
it's in my computer it's in my ipad it's
on my iphone
and then if i go to another computer if
i go to another facility and i want to
look at something
all i have to do is get a computer log
into my google account
open up my google spreadsheets and i can
look right there also you can share
those documents and spreadsheets
so if i've got i've got a couple of guys
that run a grow on a weekend
and i'll have questions and i'll be like
hey did you do the to-do list and
instead of asking them
i can open up a to-do list and see if a
guy has put his initials
next to the task because that's what i
have to do put your initials next to it
tell me if it's done correctly or wrong
i know who the praise are [ __ ]
kicking the balls
so it's got their initials i did it i
did it and i can see
i don't even have to bug anybody we
share those google documents together i
can edit it they can see the edits in
real time
so i can put hey you guys go to lunch
you've been working too hard and they'll
get a notification that the document has
been edited they'll go oh boss said go
to lunch he's watching us on camera
they'll go to lunch then i'll put
something funny in there when they're at
lunch when they come back they'll check
the document again
they'll find out who got to clean the
toilets at the end of the day because i
watch them stand around on camera
so google documents uh google
spreadsheets they're free
they're super easy uh customize it for
yourself if you've got add
my documents may not work for you make
those documents yourself
make it work for your brain if you have
to bro just write it on paper
as long as you're taking notes and
making some sort of documentation
maybe get a calendar maybe an old school
calendar maybe that may be the way to go
but uh i'm just doing custom my own
custom tailored
google docs and spreadsheets basically
rows and columns bro the information
that you need
and the date that you need it and fill
in the blanks all right north north
trips i want to thank you for the
continued patreon support and for the
great message
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
would you like to make a financial
contribution of the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen
and i did include a link in the show
notes to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends you guys i've got
to wrap up this podcast i've been going
for a little bit longer than anticipated
it was well worth it once again shout
out to green dot labs for the
delicious coin style live batter
really got me chatty and rambly for the
episode uh also
don't forget to check out my sponsor at
seeds herenow.com use coupon code gfyh10
uh while you're checking out that will
save you ten percent if you're getting
one pack of seeds that'll cover the cost
of shipping if you're getting multiple
packs
that'll buy you another pack go get more
seeds you just saved a bunch of money
uh what else do i got for you if you
have any questions concerns or
corrections i would love to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy also leave those comments
on youtube if you've got an update or
correction
i will find that on the youtube channel
the best way though
is the email address i want to thank you
guys for hanging out thank you for being
here thank you for being a great
audience thank you for being faithful
and loyal
i look forward to seeing you in just a
few days i want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy kurt z
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me