[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back hand is community it's time
for episode number 102 of the girl from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
decide if you're new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff sitting across the table from
me today is our good buddy white Mike
how you doing bro man how are you I am
great good I may have fallen asleep on
the couch for a couple hours so when you
got here I may have been a little bit
groggy but I think I've got my [ __ ]
together by now naps are good for your
health naps are really good for you take
a bunch of dabs eat a bunch of food then
you wake up on the couch order and we're
time went right feeling all refreshed ah
we're good we're back in the game so I'm
doing great man thanks for coming today
bro yeah happy to it so I think the
listeners like having you one cuz we get
a lot of listens when your hair nice you
guys before we get too far I want to
give a big THANK YOU shout out to the
mystic roots band
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew they let me play their
music on my show they don't ask me for
anything in return
that's super kind of them make sure you
guys support mystic roots in my opinion
Katherine Ramirez is the most beautiful
woman and reggae so make sure you check
that out big shout out to the coot or
the mystic roots cat and coot from the
mystic roots band shut up so we've got
some cool [ __ ] lined up today to talk
about but first I want to kind of brag
about my good-ass weekend Thursday I
think I recorded uh since this Thursday
I saw Israel vibration right yeah we
talked about that so uh Saturday my
phone is too close to the recording
equipment it's making throw that there
we go yeah by phone get out of here we
don't need you for a minute
Saturday we I went up to Comedy Works to
go see our good friend Doug Benson again
for probably the 15th or 20th ish time I
went to work full disclosure well thanks
for uh keeping the shop on lock and
holding everything down while Rasta Jeff
was up seeing Doug Benson somebody gotta
hustle
yeah this truth so uh I didn't have
anybody to go with me Saturday I thought
I had some plans they didn't work out
the person I wanted to go with me was
unable to go Saturday so I went up there
and I had two tickets and I walked up to
the line and there was another dude by
himself walking up to the line looked
kind of confused holding like his
printed ticket and [ __ ] I could tell he
was a noob to comedy works that he'd
never been there and he was trying to
figure out the Comedy Works lifestyle so
I watched him fumble around and I
started conversation with him he lit up
a blunt we smoked a blunt there in the
part in the line at comedy works and
then he goes man he asked me a question
about comedy works I don't remember what
he said specifically and I go oh no
worries man you could totally do that
here you'll be just fine and as we
walked in uh he went to get his ticket I
go man you don't even need your ticket
you're gonna sit with me tonight he goes
what do you want to sit front row bro
and he goes no you're [ __ ] me and I
go yeah man I got two front row passes
let's go sit in the front row and so
anybody that knows me that listens to
the show I'm gonna brag a little bit
I've got two lifetime preferred seating
passes for Comedy Works in downtown
Denver all I've got to do is let them
know that I'm coming and I will be
seated in c12 which is the front two
seats right there in front of the stage
right where the comedians are spitting
and drooling and sweating and staring
you in the face and make it funny and
putting you in part of the show at the
be part of the show section I get made
fun of every time I sit there if I sit
there so it's great so uh I take this
brand-new strangers all working in the
front row yeah huge dreadlocks and a
huge cheesy smile yeah they love me down
there in the front they love to make fun
of me so I took this new dude that I'd
never met until that day he was having
kind of a bad day up until then I was
like Brooks come with me we'll go sit
front row and he sat front row in here
the time of his [ __ ] life dude he
laughed his ass off he gave me a hug and
[ __ ] at the end of the night that was so
cool thank you
shout out to my buddy Merlin if you're
listenin bro it was good meeting you man
that was a good time so after the show
we go meet Doug Benson I get stoned uh
hang out with Doug Benson actually it
was really cool because it was a Doug
loves movies podcast and Harlan Williams
was a [ __ ] guest Harlan is one of my
favorite comedians that was [ __ ]
awesome
Pete Davidson or Davison from Saturday
Night Live was another guest and Doug's
friend and a comedian I've seen several
times Jeff Tate was the third guest nice
so uh hung out got stoned with Jeff Tate
doesn't smoke pot but he hung out with
and Doug Benson definitely smoked got
snowed with a whole bunch of cool ass
people in the crowd and then I drove
back to Pueblo actually at the mellow
mushroom and then it was still hungry so
I also ate at the chee behind because
I'm a pothead and I'm a fat [ __ ] so that
[ __ ] was delicious drove home and when
you're in food country you got to stop
and get some yeah when you drive past
both of those restaurants you're like
well I'm eating here there's just no
stopping it shout-out to my friend
Tiffany over at the mellow mushroom
thanks for a delicious meal that was
awesome he took good care of me
great waitressing I liked it ah so
Saturday Sunday did it all over again I
had a beautiful date Sunday she was able
to go with me Sunday went up there and
saw Doug Pinson do stand-up comedy he
tore it the [ __ ] up that was amazing ah
he made fun of me a little bit both
nights so that was cool two days of Doug
Benson hanging out with Doug Benson the
second night he treated me it was not
even like some celebrity and his fan
hanging out Jeff Tate walked up to me
and asked me a question he had a
question for me because I I was part of
the show at the end of the show they
play games and they play a game called
the last man standing
the thing is somebody in the audience
names an actor and then the participants
in the game have to name movies that
that actor has been in until they run
out you know we just keep going back and
forth until one was a I dunno mom yeah
and so uh Doug knew that I listened to
the podcast so he's like Rasta Jeff will
definitely have a name for us we'll go
to him for a name in just a minute so he
let me give him the name and when it
came time to it I said I have two names
in my head do you want me to give you
two of them any pick one he goes nope
just give me one and we'll do it I was
like alright so the name I gave them for
the game was Philip Seymour Hoffman
because I mean he's got a lot of [ __ ]
movies and they should know a lot of oh
that's a good one it was really good
they liked it they had a lot of fun with
it
so after the show Jeff Tate walked up
and he's like who was your other name
bro and it's funny because I always
forget the guy's [ __ ] name and I had
it like in my head right at that moment
for when he asked what I forgot NYX I
knew my time was up and I go I forgot
dude
you know and I go yeah but I always
forget his name and I said he played the
president in mocking and before I could
say Mockingjay he goes oh [ __ ] Donald
Sutherland dude and hit me on the
shoulder
so that dude knows his [ __ ] movies
Jeff Tate knows his movies real well
shoutout to Jeff day they made me feel
like a friend like these guys treat me
like I am a homie now when I walk
through comedy works I get high fives
I didn't even walk me to my seat anymore
like you're you know where your [ __ ]
seat is go have a seat enjoy your night
right yeah do comedy works is awesome I
used to go there on college that's I
mean I love going to music shows but
some music crowds are [ __ ] yep the
crowds have evolved into [ __ ] that
want to shove their way to the front and
spill their beer on you and just be a
disrespectful dick and don't appreciate
the show and they kind of ruin some
concerts for me I started enjoying
sitting in the back and getting high as
[ __ ] a long time ago right getting older
but comedy shows they don't allow any of
that pushing and shoving [ __ ]
they'll kick you right out if you heckle
so you're sitting down the whole time
and you can order food and they bring it
to you so if comedy shows have been kind
of my new go-to thing for a date or for
some fun it's really great stink girl
out and see a pretty girl smile at a
comedy show shout outs my date I don't
think you listen to the show but you
know who you are I had a great time with
you do support local comedy shout to the
wild cousins comedy shout out to all the
Pueblo comedy crew much love much
respect alright we've been talking about
everything but cannabis on this podcast
for the past 10 minutes I'm for some we
let's talk about cannabis actually let's
not talk about weed let's [ __ ] smoke
some with me bro gorilla glue or Girl
Scout cookies know what's let's take a
quick second here do you realize what I
just asked you I do there are people in
places they were probably just smacking
their smdh smacked my damn head right
now yeah when I first saw it but uh
there's somebody just where this
[ __ ] got Girl Scout cookies and
gorilla glue just sitting there ready to
smoke yes you guys and it's not even
flowers it's the most beautiful hash
you've ever seen we're we are spoiled
here anyway Mike yes for legalization
while we're on it yes but when you do
make sure that you include some sort of
law or it allows you to have some sort
of consumption place where everybody can
gather and smoke cannabis because that's
what we missed here in Colorado and
right now we're struggling to get those
types of rules in place if you like some
wonderful nurse I would like yes dude
enlightened me but before you do let's
make a decision here would you like the
Girl Scout cookies or would you like
this is gonna go with the gorilla glue
only because right before we started
recording we did sample the Girl Scout
yes we did all right
it was quite wonderful but I coughed for
quite a bit so I'm hoping the gorilla
glue will be slightly less choking for
me I'm gonna give you a little dab
Mike's kind of Mike why don't I no shame
people take the dab you want that's the
truth you guys yeah you don't have to
dab like I do take a DAB that's
comfortable for you Mike just said that
he had some news to share I'm gonna make
Mike share his news before he takes this
dad because I talked about he's gonna
cop for 30 seconds and then this dad
will be your reward for a quick coffee
just thinking about it yeah this damn is
your reward that is waiting for you and
I'm gonna dad while you tell us about
your news so I got a text a few days ago
from a local friend of mine in the
industry down here he's always been kind
of a step removed like he's not an owner
of a dispensary or anything like that
but he got me a text and he had a
licensing hearing he needed he wanted me
to attend and he received his special
use permit to open a cannabis museum
slash consumption location here in
Pueblo County is this somebody that I
know yep cool is it the person I think I
know probably okay cool we'll talk
specifics off the shadow greener side
Empire talking about old school greener
side Empire what up hanky B hope you're
doing well homie it's not it's not what
up shorter dude with curly hair so look
for that comment
so a cannabis museum during the
licensing hearing his description of it
would be a marijuana themed Hard Rock
Cafe would be the closest business that
he could relate it to that everyone's
familiar with so when you sit down at
your your booth with the marijuana
product you bring yourself there will be
stuff on the wall that's like marijuana
was originally outlawed and about like
historical stuff and they've hired local
historians like professional historians
that do this for a living
Wow and are currently researching
cannabis because there isn't a local
historian who expert
word lost my mind who focuses who
specializes cannabis history majors I
suppose I could qualified but I didn't
know that was us we could they need to
come to somebody all the schooling will
be great and useful but then they need
to come to somebody involved in it right
to get it I'm sure they've got a college
it I like us on the team and if they
don't I'm gonna be that person on the
team for them if at all possible Abba
Rock Cafe if you will I'm sure it's got
a name but I don't I don't honestly
remember it but yeah that should be
coming here earliest estimates first of
the year knowing how these things go
sometimes I'm gonna say bye in the
spring we should have a place to go and
enjoy some cannabis out in the public
you know what what was in a business
that members only but that be in the
city of Pueblo or in the county of just
into the county just into the county all
right come on city of Pueblo you guys
want that damn tax money but you won't
let us have anything in the city the
Pueblo County passed rules and regs for
public consumption shops a while ago
there's only been one other applicant
that I know of to try and they [ __ ] it
up so hard it was painful a lot I think
I remember hearing about that huh I was
really pissed that they did it because
that said everybody back it's like six
months
ouch all right guys see you heard it
here first our buddy Mike reported on it
Mike is our correspondent now suddenly
reporter Mike live from the field Mike
you in a DAB you want a free dab for
such a wonderful report on the show here
there will be a show prizes marijuana I
like the word cannabis there will be a
cannabis museum in the county of Pueblo
here before too long that is really cool
Mike said something about public
consumption I am going to humble myself
I'm going to eat a little bit of crow if
you will on this show never said eat
crow before I get the phrase and now
that I've said it I understand where it
comes in perfectly I've never said that
I've heard it and thought that's a weird
phrase but it just came in perfectly so
shout out to the phrase eat some crow
it's got its place well recently I've
had I've had beef with a couple of
people personal issues uh childish
[ __ ] that's stuck in my mind and
they recently
through a harvest festival here in
Pueblo Colorado and their event was
completely [ __ ] successful they
crushed it they had a public consumption
event three blocks from my house on the
Main Street of our town our town is
called pueblos this should happen on
Pueblo Boulevard they smoked hash and
weed and had a miniature cannabis cut
basically in their parking lot four
minutes from my house I did not attend
it because like I said I was seeing Doug
Benson and that was my priority I was
working but a number of people um then I
know we're there they said I went off
huge aah Spence and Jessi cleaned house
Spence won six awards and Jessi won
first place Jessi's outdoor grape OG
beat I don't know if I'm supposed to say
that that [ __ ] was outdoor but Jesse's
possibly outdoor grape OG green house
beat a green house properly beat a bunch
of indoor weed so shout out to Jesse for
his victory shout out to Spence for six
[ __ ] awards dude home runs boys nice
you know what I've got I have had
personal issues with those people and
it's my choice over possibly business
issues that we're legal involving a
store but even though we've got a little
bit of beef we don't get along we don't
see eye to eye on [ __ ] everything
we're all in the same community they
pulled it off and proud of them I'm
gonna give them a shout-out right here a
shout out to Terry shout out to [ __ ]
Ryan you guys did it you see that big
old [ __ ] played a crow right here at
the [ __ ] girl from the heart a
podcast I'm [ __ ] feasting on it you
guys I'm saying it out loud they did it
I'm proud of him nice work you guys
no sarcasm like I'm a smartass and I'm
[ __ ] I'm straight face right here
good work you guys
I hear that turnout was way bigger than
they were expecting I'm gonna go to the
next row like I've never gone to one of
their events for personal normal
personal stupid [ __ ] uh and I'm a
stubborn [ __ ] something in me if I
don't like you for something you've done
in the past I'm probably not gonna like
you in the future but I see them trying
to make progress I've tried to work with
those people before and we just butt
heads and so I've kind of separated
myself but I'm gonna get over it and I'm
gonna go there next eBay because they
crushed it this time all right so I
demand up there for a minute
I feel better all right Oh Mike you look
perplexed you've got a weird look on
your face nerds
[Music]
I wish they would have gone to that like
that when I heard how well it went I was
bummed that I had to work all weekend
right yeah I kind of wish that I would
have gone that's fully the first time I
felt about one of their events and they
finally did it right from what I hear
I'm gonna try haven't heard about any
blowback from it either
nothing happens really nothing nothing
wrong went on it went smoothly without
yeah yeah well it's been several days
it's Wednesday now it's about to be
Thursday so nothing's gonna happen I'm
probably okay all right so I was gonna
say I was gonna try not to miss any Doug
Benson shows at comedy works I'm gonna
try to get as many as I can because I if
you tweet Doug Benson he will read your
tweets during the first 20 minutes of
his show that's what he does he just
reads tweets and makes fun of people and
so uh I just tweeted at him hey Doug
front row again feels like home and so
he read a bunch of tweets and he goes
this guy back here says where's whatever
my tweet her name and he's I'm over here
it was his tweet says I'm Way too high
hahaha and go speaking away to hi raasta
Jeff's in the front row again that's
well those people [ __ ] much here dude
they clapped and [ __ ] and he goes Rasta
Jeff's been in the front row in that
seat for the last 18 Doug Benson shows
he hasn't missed a show yet it was so
funny I'm gonna try not to miss any -
it's gonna be a good time if the
listeners out there want this experience
the way to do it is amazing we don't
tell - every Doug Benson show it's just
the gut the slide Denver's taken like
there's a way to do this go bananas I
think that's the club in Cincinnati
maybe if that's see like I almost want a
google at you let's I'm gonna take
[ __ ] 30 seconds we might pause it we
might not let's see we're gonna have
Siri do it yeah I've been a duck fan for
a long time we'll see I just ask Siri
where's the club go bananas live
stand-up since a [ __ ] nati bro I'm
such a comedy geek go bananas
you listen to a lot of podcasting things
I alright because we've been rambling on
for like 20 minutes let's get on to a
topic here we've got a couple of things
in the news that we could talk about um
I read an article I'm not gonna read you
the article because it's forever long
it's way too many words
long but I found this article on a
website called The Guardian Mike also
read it so we'll be able to discuss it
without reading it here on the show and
we'll be able to paraphrase a little bit
for you guys and tell you what it's
about essentially um they're talking
about an influx of people coming from
across the country to Pueblo Colorado
because Pueblo Colorado for the size of
the city that we are and for our
economic development and the amount of
cannabis jobs available we are the most
affordable place to land when you come
from out of state would you agree with
that Mike um we routinely ranked is like
the cheapest city in Colorado for our
size and size yeah right if you went to
anywhere smaller you're pretty much
[ __ ] like the next move there's not
like you have to have a shitload of
money to live in nowhere land yeah and
this is there's a hundred thousand
people here which is just about perfect
for coming to a city that's not too
expensive trying to get a new star it's
not right he's one of the cheapest
cities in the u.s. recently it's it's
yeah we're gonna bring that up later
Denver can spit some people out Denver
can chew you up a little bit you well
there's a lot of there's a lot of lot of
reasons people are moving to pueblos
right now legal marijuana is definitely
one of them yes but let's dive into the
story because I'm about to talk about a
bunch of it's like a pulling the [ __ ]
on the chains on your I've been a part I
was a part of this story in like a back
room since I've met with all the players
about this topic but don't spill too
many of those beans I won't so they're
saying that all of these people moving
to Pueblo Colorado are beginning to put
a burden on our resources here we have a
resource called Posada which is a
nonprofit organization that helps
families get there some themselves on
their feet if something happens to
somebody here in Pueblo they can go to
Posada
for example there's a guy in this news
article that hurt his foot something
fell on him and broke his foot and he
can't work for a little bit so he's
going to Posada to get a little bit of
help maybe I don't know what they're
given and possibly some food probably
some cheese I'm saying just to keep him
on his feet while he's unable to work
but they're saying that
those resources at Posada are being
strained and the people are coming from
all over the nation to come work here
and they're not prepared like you look
like you got something on your mind
already you're stewing but no it's so
what they're getting at is that legal
marijuana is creating a huge homeless
problem in Pueblo Colorado right and
it's not like causing good hardworking
Americans who got hooked on marijuana to
become homeless it's attracting homeless
people in other areas to pueblos
apparently and the article goes on to
say people that work at Posada and a
couple other agencies in town saying
that they've had huge increases in
people seeking services from them
whether it's housing vouchers or food
stamps or medicine bank medicine
vouchers or help with medical problems
Posada especially has been pretty vocal
with the press down here in Pueblo and
then it's spiraled nationally when the
anti pot groups picked it up and started
pushing it other newspapers started
picking it up that one of the problems
caused by amendment 64 is more homeless
people coming to Colorado because of our
marijuana laws and just that idea never
really made sense to me until I realized
that it's not illegal to be homeless
most places but it is illegal to have
pop most places right and homeless
people have huge rates of substance
abuse and if if you're homeless
consuming substances is a way to deal
with some of the miserable conditions
and that lifestyle absolutely so if you
can move to a place where they're not
going to chase you around and throw you
in jail for having some weed why not be
there and when that's combined with a
number of other things that are
happening at the same time like legal
marijuana here everybody's talking about
how many thousands of people are working
in the industry and how much money it's
making no one's talking about what it
takes to get an Emmy D badge
so that's something I was gonna touch on
in a few minutes when you're homeless
and there's a new booming industry
I mean it's humans been doing it since
humans started doing anything we move
for to where there's work especially
when there's no work and we're just
coming out of a depression like a
national depression where works hard to
come by everywhere especially in our age
demographic yep remember all those
articles about people than their 30s
that moved home after college right
degrees had a no I'm still not saying me
but a lot of them got degrees unlike
internet stuff those jobs are all taken
up that [ __ ] kind of failed but not
failed but I mean it's just gotten so
much easier to make a webpage that that
guy that used to know how to do it isn't
and I have a theory that that's gonna
happen to the weed grower to I'm gonna
do a whole report on that here on the
podcast in the future so yeah those
those people are now in the weed
industry rankings making a pretty solid
living yeah so there's a lot of reasons
homeless people are at our people on the
brink of being homeless or moving to
Colorado and I mean I've said it a
countless times like come if you want to
come here that's great but come prepared
right like look come prepared is one of
the seriously that's the iton on this
[ __ ] paper come prepare them that's
huge and a lot of people didn't like
winning your kind at the end of your
road financially an opportunity wise
wherever you live and you hear about
Colorado and everything that's going on
here all the stores all it grows I mean
you figure out at least I can get a job
trimming right I can sit in a room and
cut Leafs off buds all day I can surely
do it in scrubs like I'll move there and
do it but no one knows what that takes
right you guys if you're going to cut in
ah come prepared that's definitely the
thing come here with a little bit of
money cuz it's gonna take a minute to
get a job in the weed industry you have
to get before you even come here
research a Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division support badge if
you're coming here for work in the
industry definitely know what it takes
to get a job in the end and you're not
gonna get a job trimming for you may get
a job trimming for your cousin
whatever but that shit's not gonna last
long it's not gonna that's not going to
sustain you it may sound a fruit full
right now but trimming for your buddy or
trimming for whoever's got this grow
option option for you it's not gonna
work unless it's illegal like unless
they own a business there's a lot of a
lot of people that have lived here or
have recently moved here with kind of a
plan and gotten a job that are growing
their legal six plants and they need
help trimming and they'll call you and
you can trim for them for like ten hours
once every 90 days right yeah yeah you
need you need to work for like five of
those people if you want to try to pay
rent that way right and you're not gonna
find for others right when you move here
I hate it that the trimmers I use go
trim for other people I mean it's
expected but I hate that [ __ ] but yeah
if you're not trimming if you don't need
a mad badge that's probably not a job
that's gonna last for very long
right now they're cleaning up illegal
grow operations they're getting rid of
all of that [ __ ] here in Colorado it's
going away so when things are legal the
illegal stands out like a sore thumb
true very true that's something we've
talked about on the show so research
getting your marijuana Enforcement
Division support badge if you've got any
drug felonies in the last ten years
don't even think about coming to
Colorado to get a job in the industry
they're not gonna give you a badge if
you don't have the badge you can't walk
in the door we can't let you behind the
counter you can't go in the gross space
you can't trim you can't deliver you
can't sweep the parking lot like I swear
to god he's ready to get on the website
it takes two seconds google colorado
meed badge and it'll come right up our
security guards are badged with their
security service like train with their
security they wear their security guard
badge and their shirts for their
security and their gun all day long but
they are also wearing a marijuana and
they have to have that [ __ ] to work
there so they had to go spend an extra
it's like a hundred and fifty bucks for
that badge yep just to work there so you
guys if you can't afford a hundred and
fifty dollar badge and if you can't
qualify for that badge don't come here
please because I'm not talking [ __ ] to
you I'm not saying don't come here
you're just gonna be stuck you're not
gonna be able to get in the industry
you're gonna be relying on resources
here and you're gonna make it it just
kind of makes it look shitty
if you can come here and do something
you're invited come on if you're if
you're able if you're willing if you're
ready if you can trim if you're able to
get the badge
we'll take you but honestly the silikal
here while we're on it the big four
requirements are no drug felonies in ten
years no felonies period in five it's
kind of [ __ ] up that you could have
like killed someone and like with your
car or something five years ago five
years ago and get your badge before the
guy who got busted with it out or what
is it two grams of concentrate in most
places yeah
[ __ ] up world I yeah it really is but
so no drug phonies in ten years no
felonies in five and your student loans
and your child support need to be in
order yes now what in order means is you
it you means you have to call them and
set up a payment plan and make one
payment if you're already paying on it
you're legit if you're already paying
paying on it and everything's in good
order you're fine but if you've been
ducking child support for urge student
loans for a while you got to stand up
call Sallie Mae and start making
payments you know all they want is a
receipt and tip that you're paying I had
to do it like I had to go show them that
my student loans were in good order I
had to do is get a thing from both loan
companies it was really easy I filled
out I printed the application online I
printed it at home I filled it I took me
like 30 minutes to do it whatever you
know it's just like a thick job
application but really thorough yeah and
then they give it to the FBI who checks
it so you can't just lie and while
they're checking a better smartest [ __ ]
they take your paperwork and start
running it then they call you back while
it's being ran and they fingerprint you
and they take their sweet [ __ ] time
fingerprinting you so that if there is
anything wrong with your paperwork and
they if you're illegal if you've got
warrants they'll come and get your ass
right there I I wondered why it took so
long it seemed like the tech was brand
new and yet it took her 74 tries to get
my index finger oh yeah that finger
funny thing that laser reading finger
printer is hard it feels like right you
know I've actually come to rest in case
it had warrants while they were there
yeah they don't [ __ ] around so one thing
I was gonna say and this is gonna sound
like really rude as [ __ ] go and take
cash when you go to the licensed place
oh yeah they do not take a check or a
money order you gotta go to if you go to
the credit
its 151st I don't even want to quote the
prices right now because they change all
the [ __ ] time yeah I paid 150 for
mine without a big echo I didn't hear it
okay I've got these headphones on it's
thought I heard echo long as we're not
going in the recording oh you guys I
know it sounds great to pack up your
whole wife and come to Colorado and
enjoy the dispensary and smoke some
legal cannabis and it is it's amazing I
have a plan have a plan it's not as
complicated as it sounds ah I'm gonna
use an atom as an example is you're a
deep-sea fishermen we've got your
[ __ ] job here too Adam thought he was
gonna come here and grow some paw and be
the king [ __ ] of the [ __ ] world and
I'm not talking to [ __ ] about Adam Adam
is making it but Adam is not buying
whatever CD came out last week
he's Adam is not going with us to dinner
I work construction with him all winter
exactly yeah and I'm not trying to Adam
I love you bro I'm not talking showed up
realize that that wasn't gonna play out
and immediately got to work and survive
and make it yeah if you fight for it you
can make it but come here with a plan
save up some money find a job find a
place or two that you want to see to
rent like you have a plan yes or don't
just show up here with a u-haul truck
into three dollars in your pocket
cuz you will be homeless in like four
days or my option for you which I
recommend what you're gonna think I'm a
dick but ah save the energy that you
were gonna use to move here and use that
energy to fight for legalization where
you are just push that over yeah just do
that right where you are just gather a
bunch of people uh get a bunch of
like-minded folk it'd be cool if you can
get all the smokers around but I
understand a bunch of potheads sometimes
you don't want the pot heads to go to
City Council with you there's a couple
guys you just want to leave we've
definitely had more than one walk up and
shoot themselves and everybody else in
the foot and it sucked yeah some some of
those guys you just leave behind but try
to get an intelligent group of people
put an ad on Craigslist in your area say
hey I want to fight to legalize cannabis
let's start a legalization group and you
guys get together and you make a
petition and you make a petition and you
try to get it put on the ballot for your
community that hey we want to make a
medical marijuana legalization movement
it's easier than that there's already
three groups if you're listening to this
in the US there's already three groups
in your state town and city working on
it you just have to find them normal
find normal the normals for the Reform
of Marijuana Laws
the project policy the Marijuana Policy
Project yes see I think I know how I'm
reaching for I just [ __ ] I have that
ad D and then who's our third friend
the third one three of them no I wasn't
thinking of three specific there's there
are three there's [ __ ] one and maybe
Google cannibal cannibal cannibal dozen
states are voting on advocacy groups for
your areas what you want to find and
then join that [ __ ] do what you can
everybody's got their own gift in life
and if you want to fight for
legalization you have to find where you
fit in find what you can do my niche is
this podcast my niche is making seeds my
niche is growing like a [ __ ]
my initials taking care of my patients
and paying attention to what works for
them medicinally and adjusting my gross
schedule and micronutrients and my gross
strains to work for my individual
patients medical needs which is an art
to tell you the [ __ ] truth to grow
enough weed from Mike and enough weed
for Doug and other people that I supply
and have the right strains at the right
times for these people it takes a little
bit of scheduling and a little bit of
foresight so whatever you do if you're a
construction worker and you're looking
to move here and do construction and
smoke weed and the evenings have as much
of a [ __ ] plan about what you're
gonna do in life is Jeff just laid out
right there is like what he does is his
niche like at least that much you should
be getting online and like oh you know
I'm a car salesman find a dozen car
dealerships looking for employees before
you even consider moving out here yeah
call them contact them send them your
information let them know you'll be here
whenever looking for a job yep long
before you move out here the people that
moved out here with just the hope and a
prayer most of them have had to beg
people for money so that they can haul
their ass back home and that has to suck
unfortunately a Colorado has become
be not what you know but who you know
state if you want to be in the cannabis
industry right now there's just so many
rules and regulations and the tiniest
[ __ ] can cost the shop ten thousand
two hundred thousand bucks that he can
lose their licensing because you did
something that half the people that walk
in our doors every day assume we're
doing constantly so gaining that level
of trust and a job interviews a
[ __ ] absolutely um and if your
main sales pitches that you've been
hired for a decade like just don't try
like come here and do whatever you've
been doing to make a living if it's
selling weed don't move here because we
got stores that do that now I get to
look at a lot of job applications
because anything that goes for the grow
department the job applications get
passed to myself and another guy you
would not believe some of the verbage
that I see in job applications like list
your skills dog I could grow the
sticky-icky fire dog I got hydros skills
with the Z and [ __ ] and we honestly we
throw those applications away I bring a
resume look professional it is the weed
industry but it is called industry its
business we're trying to better our
business we need to make money so we can
improve our business we can open more
stores
it's just how business [ __ ] works
don't come trying to talk like you're a
cool gangster and try to impress us be
professional you know legal comes with
rules regulations and expectations
you're gonna be wearing a lab coat if
you work next to me in the grow I know
that sounds ridiculous we were at a lab
coats bro we've got a different lab coat
for each room I need to know that you're
responsible enough to wear this lab coat
in room a and know that you need to take
that son of a [ __ ] off and put on
another lab coat before you enter room
be aware enough to actually care about
cross-contamination yeah yeah we need to
know that you can read the warning signs
when we use a pesticide and we put up a
certain do not enter sign or whatever
gear is required to enter this room we
didn't know that you can read that kind
of stuff even the salespeople if I make
a real simple mistake I can get the shop
shut down yeah oh yeah anybody anybody
that works there pretty much with the
badge if we do the wrong if we say the
wrong [ __ ] the store can be closed yep
any minute yeah
and we're under camera you guys you guys
think we can hang out smoke pot and be
chill no it's busy as [ __ ] all the time
there's no chairs where I work there are
no chairs in my work area I'm always
standing up but also we're under camera
from every angle and all times you're on
two cameras no matter where you are in
that building there are two cameras
covering that area I cannot scratch my
ass in that building without being seen
if you do something really funny you can
go to the office and ask for the footage
like immediately
cuz it's available I've had security
that was three rooms away make fun of me
for butt crack yeah thing is on camera
to the point where they can read number
on my car outside a parking lot with the
camera yeah that's how [ __ ] smooth
those cameras were they were reading VIN
numbers on cars like people really don't
understand the level of regulation the
scrutiny that the industries on those
cameras go about a hundred feet all the
way around the perimeter of the building
all the way like a hundred feet
seriously I'm not even kidding they go
all the way to the street and [ __ ]
that's why you hear about a dispensary
getting robbed in Colorado you hear
about the arrest the guy who did it like
an hour and a half late right yeah oh
boy and it's funny because if somebody
smokes anywhere near the building are
security guards damn near run outside
with their gun in their hand you cannot
smoke on our premises but if you cannot
smoke anything anywhere near our
dispensary you guys we can't have I've
mentioned this before excuse my burping
we cannot have I'm a medical marijuana
patient and I cannot have my any of my
medical marijuana products in my private
vehicle on my work shift in my car
parked in the parking lot at the
dispensary I have to wait till I get
home I have to drive home and dab hard
after work because I can't have the [ __ ]
there anything that might be seen as
anka say consumption could cost the shop
its license right we can't carry our
beverages ah I can't as uh as a guy that
works in the back I can take my bottle
mine but my Dr Pepper after lunch I can
take that back to the back of the
building but they will not let me take
my drink into the bud room when
visit Mike when I'm chatting him up when
I'm taking a pee break like if Mike's my
can I hardly ever see each other at work
but when we do it's like hey buddy no
open containers in the bedroom if you
say you were a customer and you spilled
that [ __ ] in a jar we'd
I couldn't even charge you for what you
just ruined because I can legally only
sell you an ounce or an ounce where your
license says you're from that's shitty
um and so if you're from Texas and you
spill your your water into a jar weed
that's got eight ounces a weed in it
this shops gotta eat a lot of money and
that's where that's my job
ouch so can you take your water bottle
back there anything only if it's got a
lid okay just a water bottle and then
like keep it well the [ __ ] away asking a
pretty sure I've seen a couple of water
bottles back by that window well the
window edge is where they go that's
where they're safe
yeah the window ledge all right cool so
yeah it's strict you guys what I'm
getting at is there is no hanging out
smoking pot being lazy having fun the
only time I get to groove and have a
good time is when I'm pushing a broom or
a mop like I will catch myself shaking
my ass cuz I got me we played we played
loud music in the back and there's good
music up front most of the time so
there's good music going on is one of
the best parts but the only time you get
to chill out and have fun is on lunch
breaks or sometimes we have a little
team meetings and [ __ ] which are fun but
it's hard work working at a dispensary
you guys if you're coming here to work
in the industry be ready to put it away
put in work yeah don't you get serious
it never stops
yeah should I go in and 9ish just
depends on the day somewhere between
eight and ten just depends on honestly
how busy we're gonna be what I've got to
do I know what I've got to do right now
how much time it's gonna take but
sometimes we will leave there we've left
at seven o'clock before we've done it at
9:00 in the morning now we've got an
8:00 and left at 7:00 I've worked you
can't close up there until the time in
the back we can pretty much work but we
just got to finish the job there's a lot
of [ __ ] to do with it sometimes it's
just what happens in the legal industry
like there's work to be done and it's
got to get done by somebody and pot
takes a lot of work a lot of planning
yep planning for us in the back
people come here with just the craziest
expectations and it's [ __ ] a lot of
people if you're one of those guys that
quits a job all the time if you're one
of those guys who can't show up on time
if you're one of the guys that makes
excuses you're not gonna make it in the
marijuana shirt come dinner time like I
knew yeah yeah you gotta look
professional you gotta take care of
yourself here oh you guys this may sound
like [ __ ] but this is the truth
for every one dude that is hireable
there are seven women that are hireable
that are way more attractive than you so
if you're a dude and you're trying to
get a job in the industry you gotta get
your [ __ ] together because you put a
real resume together beautiful women
sell more weed so it's already a an
uphill battle for a lot of you dudes
clean up yeah always
resume resume are you [ __ ] um let's see
we've been going for 40 minutes holy
crap um we're so big this is like the
longest news article summation we didn't
even read so many different places with
this I like this podcast it felt right
um so just to get slightly back on topic
let's do it the thing that pisses me off
the most about this whole legal pot
causes an increase in homelessness
nonsense is like one of the big reasons
Puebla is experiencing a lot more
homeless people right now looking for
services or people on the brink of being
homeless looking for services is because
all of the cities around us
currently bus homeless people out of
that area that's the only way they've
got to deal with it if Posada could have
anything they wanted right now it would
be millions more funding so that they
could send everybody back home and
there's a small reason for that like if
you send everybody home hopefully
they've got family friends people in the
community that they know and can make
contact with to help them get back on
their feet like somewhere where they're
tied to the community a little bit
rather than here where they're strangers
to everybody right but most places are
just like hey guess what I hear this
place it the way that you probably can't
get back to without a lot of help is
banging you should go there here's a bus
ticket there for free bro they've got
like everything you need
um I had a guy asked me for a ride that
one day and I probably would have told
him no except the place he was asking to
go was like a block and a half from
where I was headed
and I took a look at him and he looked
totally [ __ ]
but like recently like his clothes were
clean but he looked like he had the
worst day after the worst month ever and
I was like alright dude I can give you a
ride to where I'm already going I've
like got like 150 pounds on you even if
you pull like a real [ __ ] loaded
weapon on me I've got this especially in
a car like if I can reach you it's I win
and his little story just wrecked me
like he had a serious medical condition
he was in Albuquerque and they were like
dude didn't you hear Pueblo got it for
you they've got like free services for
you with your [ __ ] and I'll take real
good care of you and the community is
gonna love you and they'll get you a
house and a job and [ __ ] get you on
your feet and this is Pueblo they're
talking about we don't got [ __ ] off for
anybody yeah unless you're looking to
invest a couple of million dollars in a
numerical arm like what I don't got what
you're looking for it's cheap to live
and I bet nobody highest on hold in
Colorado yeah we've got the Colorado
unemployment rates like four point
something it's one of the lower and the
lowest in the nation but Pueblo is
unemployment rate is like five and a
half or six like a good point and a half
higher than the rest of the state and
when you magnify that times the amount
of people that are in the state like
it's a huge huge chunk of the jobs like
there's a lot of people that came here
looking for work that are just [ __ ]
[ __ ] out of luck now yeah cuz they came
with no plan but we're trying to pin it
on legal pot when there's like thirty
different reasons homeless people and
people about to be homeless ready to
pueblos you can Trancas the cheap like
the third cheapest city in the US and
expect that [ __ ] not to have
concentrations which varies in every
newspaper in the country you know what I
did not plan poorly huh this dab no get
it let's do this you guys I'm gonna hit
the dab I'm hitting it
and hitman the sampson hitman combo
collab reg with a highly-educated d nail
on it that runs to the gmail from emo
tech shout out to giddy up
there's dougie I like shout out to task
let's do this you don't might keep going
while I damn don't worry about posada Oh
Posadas I don't have anything against
Posada except they're being nuts on this
issue they're getting national press
talking about how it's all marijuana's
fault and then if you read the article
you'll get about 3/4 of the way through
when they mention like other cities bus
and homeless people here and straight
lying to them when I put them on the bus
town on phobos great and app level being
ranked the cheapest city in the u.s.
tons of people moving here sure that 3
or 4 of them are gonna get jobs in the
marijuana industry only to find out that
we don't take felons I mean multiple
multiple that they just don't publicize
any of the requirements anywhere outside
of this podcast basically right yeah so
that's your public service announcement
you guys make sure you google that [ __ ]
make sure you can find out if you're
even qualified to work in our industry
and if you're going if you're coming
here to run in a legal industry I'm not
even trying to be a smartass I was deep
[ __ ] into the illegal cannabis industry
I can admit it now I could talk about
that you know what I had to get away
from it because it wasn't gonna work
much longer I was gonna go downhill
trying to stay on that side of the world
now I've got a steady job everything is
legit it's much easier you guys it's
much easier and that the illegal
industry is going away you can see it
crumbling here those people that are too
stubborn to come to the light you can
see them struggling and dwindling and
falling off I saw it a couple of years
ago the people I knew that we're living
right on that the edge but between the
black and the white market like the what
you'd call the gray market
the more stores that opened up the
harder it was to compete with them I
mean the guy that had one strain for you
in March come July would show up a seven
by December there was a selection hash
in his bag too and by January it was
just too much of a [ __ ] hassle
regardless of the selection because you
could just go to a store and pick right
like you never had to hang out and not
seem like foot traffic or any of that
meet somebody somewhere how much how
many episodes of How It's Made would
never have been watched if we could just
buy weed in stores Deadliest Catch what
I've never been viewed Yeah right
viewership on a lot of [ __ ] would go way
down if you didn't have to hang out with
your weed dealer for two hours so you
didn't seem like you were there buying
wheat
this dude's just really really bored and
a lot of his friends come to visit for
two hours at a chunk I guess yeah like
it's just so much more convenient even
when you get to the shop and you're like
really that's the price [ __ ] taxes
like you start wondering how much your
time's worth like how many hours that I
spend sitting on the couch listening to
[ __ ] because I was there to buy a
bag of weed and that was the best weed
in town yeah cuz every weed dealer wants
to show you his new thing that he bought
with your money but you did you redo man
anything but more [ __ ] Deadliest
Catch listen to this song cooking that
sure I like that yeah I don't know why
used to get stoned to watch the [ __ ] out
of Deadliest Catch that's really weird
hey it's it's fun wonder which one's
gonna get squashed by a crab cajun eggs
I'm gonna write myself a note here this
is not show related watch more Deadliest
Catch no I record another podcast and I
was a Deadliest Catch story that I want
to tell on that podcast there's an
episode where Jeff sent people no no I'm
kidding to tell this weird ass dream
story on this podcast I mean this is
almost a [ __ ] hour-long here just reg
install these people so let's talk about
this one time I got my wisdom teeth
removed and they gave me vicodin then I
took too many of them and I fell asleep
watching Deadliest Catch okay that's
like the main setup here I woke up in a
dream that I would caught somebody
trying to kill people on The Deadliest
Catch boat and I murder
him cuz he was trying to kill me and in
self-defense I killed him on the [ __ ]
cuz he killed everybody else on the boat
but then I realized everybody on the
boat is dead but me and they're gonna
think I did this [ __ ] and I'm all
covered in blood in the boats all
covered in blood so I gotta get the [ __ ]
out of here then I wake up and since I
took too many vicodin before I fell
asleep when I woke up I didn't really
wake up I was still dreaming but I was
physically sitting up in real life but
in dream life I was still in my boat and
I saw blood all over my house and it
took me a good I don't really know but
I'm gonna say like three or four minutes
of like shaking my head around and
walking around my bedroom going why is
there blood everywhere what the [ __ ] is
happening and then finally the blood
faded away and I woke up don't too many
of I don't do too many vicodin kids
that's my it's my [ __ ] theory but I
had my wisdom teeth taken out they
[ __ ] hurt dude that [ __ ] sucks okay I
was kind of listening but while I was
listening I had a thought okay let's
hear this has been rambling as [ __ ]
uh-huh so if you're still listening I'll
go ahead and pay to send you a sticker
pack or some [ __ ] umm if you tweet me I
like it when you ramble all right you
guys and then tag [ __ ] grow from your
heart podcast in it as well so you have
to if there's a whole bunch you a whole
bunch of people still listening and I
get a shitload of tweets about it I'll
we'll pick like three and I'll pay two
so we get t-shirts
we got stickers we got plenty of
stickers I don't know that though what
they'll be but we've got stickers I've
got so many sponsors and vendors and
friends that we I've got something
really cool yeah some grassroot stickers
I read genetic stickers I Heart dab
stickers we got plenty of stickers right
so it's Nemo Punk 15 you have on Twitter
you have to tweet at Nemo Punk 15 and @g
fyh podcast yep with hash tag I like it
when you ramble yep and then I will
contact you to get your mailing
information yep alright you guys don't
freak don't forget to do that [ __ ] you
can just its stickers it's free stickers
it's free stuff for listening this long
because this kind of went everywhere it
did go everywhere but I like it that
sometimes dads take you fun places yes
they do well since Mike's uh Mike's
giving away [ __ ] I'm gonna wrap up the
show before he starts giving away more
[ __ ] who wants a microphone no don't do
that what the [ __ ] are you doing wants
of pizza I want a pizza
I wanted a Pete there this is
gotten way off course you guys Mike
thank you for coming over brothers have
been a lot of fun happy too man yeah man
we uh we may record someone here in just
a minute
you guys only thank everybody for
listening episode 102 you guys holy [ __ ]
102 in the can yeah don't put it in your
can
there's no can anymore put it in your
pipe and smoke it yes I'll be back in
another week with that so number 103
right ring whoa this is getting weird
you guys we need some sponsors for the
show if you want to sponsor the podcast
or if you have a product you'd like me
to review data to oil slick no Noah for
very good reason I've got a table sighs
oil slick pad from our friends at oil
slick they're the [ __ ] keeps the table
protected I like it also shout out to
hit man glass they do not sponsor the
show but you know what they keep me dab
the [ __ ] out since we're doing shout
outs like that also shout out to highly
educated titanium task rock what's up
homie big old fist bump and also since
we're there shout out to the burnisher
company for the emails also shout out to
emo tech for the other email those all
those companies together keep me Dad the
[ __ ] out you guys that's I use I use
those companies products on a daily dose
of Pelle case Pelle case yeah the
Pelican case we're less than fun [ __ ] in
the room dr. pepper you know they don't
pay us dude stop none of those people
pay us for any of that but they're
delicious and without them we could not
do this that's true sure that's a little
baby how's that yeah buddy
all right so you guys are if you want
sponsored upon a product review what I
would like you to do is send me a
product that you want us to review we
want to send it back to you if you want
if you want us to keep it pure as [ __ ]
will don't worry but I'd like you to
send us some products Mike and I will
unbox it here on the show we will review
it and we'll talk about it on the show
we'll be honest we'll check it out we'll
smoke hash there well smoke weed through
it
well we'll read the instructions you
surprise intended that is the truth will
and we'll let the world know what we did
some limitations and then we'll send it
back to you if you want not only knows
how big and wide this audience range is
right they could be neat send us your
products guys mostly looking for
cannabis related stuff but will pretty
much review anything you want to send us
that is true that is true we like hats
and shirts - [ __ ] - I will definitely if
you got some pennies that you need worn
and seen on
shoutout to ghost cat glass this just
became the [ __ ] shout out sounds like
[ __ ] the bTW wards over here I like
it when you ramble ramble hit me up you
guys its roar from a herd at hotmail.com
find me on all this goddamn social media
sites i'm on twitter it's @g f YH
podcast i'm on facebook girl from your
heart on instagram you guys it's at I
read genetics we're almost to 19,000
followers get up on it get up on it um
don't forget you guys the shows
available on iTunes the show is
available on stitcher and every single
episode is always and forever archived
on I read genetics Colorado dot-com that
is my website they'll never take that
away from us
let me apologize about the quality of I
read genetics Colorado calm that is
under construction my friend is a
college student we work on that when
he's not in college let the man get an
education that's first and when he's not
there he'll come over and we'll work on
the website go to school Tony do your
thing don't worry about it we got your
back bro we're on it if you're in a
position to hire somebody who needs to
work like a couple of weeks a year hire
a college student he's alive get through
school I like it when you ramble yep all
right you guys I'm gonna wrap up this
show thanks again to Mike for coming
thanks to everybody for listening what
the hell does tickle my arm that's a
spider thumping guy that's scared that
one reach over there that was weird is
so high your body cares about your
dreadlocks again just tickled that was
strange
anyway you guys weird AB the [ __ ] out I
hope you had a lot of fun with us
hashtag I like it when you ramble get
your sticker pack C's was not a good
idea big shout outs made in to Spence
thanks again for listening guys until
next time take a fat dad and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you