yeah what's up podcast world it's your
boy Rasta Jeff coming to you live from
the car on Interstate 25 that's right I
just left the champs trade show I
thought it'd be a good idea to jump on
the microphone and do a little bit of
recording while it's still fresh in my
mind so today I went to the champs trade
show in Denver it was a beautiful Drive
it takes me about two hours to get up to
Denver it took me about another 20
minutes to find a good parking spot
anyway I got a good parking spot I
messaged a good friend of mine who had a
pass for me we met up and he got me a
pass for champs he gave me a high-five
and told me to have a good time he had
[ __ ] to do so he sent me on my way and I
headed into the champs trade show you
guys I am failing you right now because
I seriously don't know what champs
stands for champs is an acronym for
something I don't know what it means
ch am PS it means something about glass
and tradeshow because what it was was a
trade show based on glass cannabis and
it's some of that [ __ ] said for tobacco
use only but tobacco and cannabis
smoking accessories I saw so basically
it's all your [ __ ] that is available at
all the head shops that you go to
depending on the quality of your head
shop but it was all there all that
plastic shitty Chinese smoking
accessories stuff was all there all the
shitty Chinese knockoff glass was there
all of these shitty knockoff nail
companies were there but also some of
our good friends were there you guys I
got to visit the Hitman booth if I was a
man if I didn't walk away from the
Hitman booths today I was going to spend
a lot of money with hitman they had two
rigs that I was really interested in
they had the mini they have the new I
forget what they call Nokomis sundae
stack or something like that it's not
the sundae cup but it's this little
stack thing the mini stack holy [ __ ]
they got bad water in it they let me
pull through it that thing felt like it
would hit like a champ unfortunately you
guys there was no consumption in this
venue we were not allowed to smoke any
type of cannabis we couldn't dab
there was actually somebody pressing out
rosin dabs he had a rosin press if you
know about rosin it's made by squishing
your buds between two heated surfaces
using parchment in the middle is a way
to catch your hash he was pressing out
rosin right there for you so you could
bring your nugs and get him squished as
what they were calling it some people
were taking dabs of that right after
they would squish it although it was
frowned upon and if you got caught they
would escort you out of the building so
anyway I met up with the hitman crew I
fell in love with a couple of rigs they
had a mini sidecar rig with a blue label
the blue label was beautiful it's my
favorite color
my exact favorite color blue
unfortunately I just bought the same rig
with a yellow label so I could not bring
myself to spend another 150 dollars on a
rig although a hundred and fifty dollars
on that rig was a steal I just didn't
want to buy a copy of a rig that I have
already got did not make sense to me
anyway so I had to walk away before I
bought the sunday stack and before I
bought the blue mini sidecar they had a
bunch of great rigs at the Hitman booth
also I made friends with a bunch of
people i also got to bump into our crew
with oil slick josh moil slick and the
oil slick crew was there in full force
they sent me home with the sample of the
I forget the official name of it I've
been calling it the bond condom it's
actually a it's basically a condom you
put on the mouthpiece of your bong so
that if you're at a large party or an
event you can swap those out so that not
everybody has to get the that we call it
the cup cough or the look flu so they
gave me a couple of those to check out
right across from our friends at oil
slick was our good friends at handmade
apparel big shout out to the entire
handmade and oil slick family thanks for
coming out to Colorado thanks for
showing everybody how to run a booth hit
champs cuz you guys do it right you guys
are great people great people in the
industry great service so you guys make
sure you support oil slick and handmade
apparel and also hit man glass also I
made a little stop at the highly
educated titanium a little booth there
and I picked up a couple of highly
educated titanium products task was not
in the building but he had his uh his
cronies working form they do a great job
so shout out to those guys make sure you
support highly educated titanium I know
it sounds like a big bunch of shoutouts
but
I was at an event where there are a
bunch of vendors you guys so these guys
took care of me there are products that
I support so shout out to all them so uh
it's basically you guys have to be a
swap meet of supplies that for your head
shop and I saw every kind of pipe in
bong and hash rig and nail you could
imagine every type of hash container you
could imagine there was not a lot of
growing accessories or gross supplies or
anything like that it was all basically
aimed at supplying your head shop with
good quality glass so I've got a list of
people here that I got to hang out with
today before I even open up the list I
don't even need to think about it as I
walked out of my car I walked up to no
soon as I walked into the event I was
greeted by a guy by the name of Scott
reach he walked up to me and shook my
hand asked how I was doing you guys that
is rare dankness one of the most popular
seed companies in the world right now
for Scott to walk up and know who I was
kind of blew my mind to tell you the
truth I got a few feet into the building
and then I ran into the man himself the
kosher stoner adam mca' doshas our good
friend adam hill big shout out to Adam
mill it was good seeing Adam Hill I got
to hang out that him for a few minutes
have a quick conversation adam was
hungry so he took off we were supposed
to link up for turps later we'll talk
more about that I ended up having to
drive home I don't I didn't have to
drive home dinner was at 7:00 it was
seven o'clock we're still at Hunt's
house taking dabs I figured we want to
go in to dinner till 7:30 which means I
would have been there until 8:00 I don't
know I've been there until 9 maybe 9:30
it's a two-hour drive from there they
would have put me home around 11:30 or
midnight I couldn't deal with that I've
got to work in the morning so I had to
split out from dinner but anyway shout
out to John Hunt shoutout to animal shot
at Oh Carly
big shout-out to everybody who invited
me to dinner I apologize for not being
able to make it next time guys for sure
I went to champs today on a whim I
wasn't even supposed to go to champs
this was a poorly planned trip but I'm
gonna call it a hell of a success you
guys so I was walking through champs and
I spied one of the most beautiful women
I have ever laid my eyes upon the lovely
Miss Charlo Greene was in the building
if you guys don't know who Charlo Greene
is she is a cannabis activists activists
from Alaska and she's actually
lady who was known for saying [ __ ] it I
quit on the news she was at champs she
was here in Denver oh my gosh you guys
usually I am cool calm and collected I'm
a smooth [ __ ] I'm not afraid to
talk to anybody I'll walk up to anybody
and say hello I'll walk into the
restricted access area and act like I
own that [ __ ] I'm not a shy guy but for
some reason when I shut saw miss
Charlotte green something inside of me
[ __ ] melted ah you guys charlo is
more beautiful in person than she has
ever looked online on Facebook on the
internet on Twitter on Instagram
whatever you saw her on she is even more
beautiful in person and her personality
is sassy and stunning
so I'm walking toward her and she
spotted me and she reached out and put
her hand on my shoulder and said hey you
and she knew who I was which was kind of
weird I've stalked her on Facebook and
said hello but she has no reason to know
who rasta Jeff is so I was a little
excited by that that made me a little
spellbound it made me feel like a high
school boy so I stopped and I asked her
if I could give her a hug and she said
oh of course and we talked for a couple
of minutes and you guys I went stupid I
did not have [ __ ] proper to say to that
beautiful lady I couldn't decide if I
wanted to just be like a normal dude and
talk to her or if I wanted to go into
like business guy mode or if I wanted to
be podcast guy and my brain fluttered
that woman is beautiful oh my god so big
shout-out to Charlo Greene if you listen
to this yes I'm gushing over you you're
the most beautiful damn woman I have
seen in a long time holy [ __ ] blew my
mind honey she's tall you guys I'm six
foot five of course she was wearing some
heels but she is tall hold on there's a
copy right next to me he might pull me
over yes I am talking into a microphone
while driving down the interstate this
cop is right next to me you guys he's
like staring at me he's like what are
you doing
I didn't pull me over that was awesome
okay anyway Charlo Greene I'm six foot
five Charlo Greene of course was wearing
some heels but she was nearly as tall as
me I posted a selfie to Instagram and
you guys will be able to see if you
check that out check it out it's a Tyree
genetics on Instagram she is tall and I
said damn honey you were tall and I put
my arm around her we took a selfie cuz
I'm a big girl and I love it and I said
me too and I went silent I was like well
I've got a shot
Pueblo you should come check that out
and if I see you at the party later
tonight we'll dab and of course I'm not
going to the party because I do have to
work in the morning I was really
thinking about going to the party but uh
I can't it'll kill me I will hate life
tomorrow and I've got to be a productive
dude I've got [ __ ] to handle trying to
be a grown-ass man so let's see I've got
a list of people that I wanted to make
sure I gave a shout out to we covered
hunt hunt john hunt you're a bad
[ __ ] you are the Terp gatherer
you are may you're the brother dude here
the man I like it
big shout out much respect to John hunt
the Grammy Gatsby that's my boy that's
my partner in crime
I like hangin out with that dude he he
kind of encouraged me to come up to
chimps he let me hang out he kind of
encouraged he kind of made it happen
it's your fault you let me hang out at
the house afterward and stop and take
some tabs at the Terp station
thanks for let me come to the dojo bro I
appreciate it shout-out to hunt
also shout it to animal if you guys
don't know Adam hill you got to learn
about Adam ill Adam ill he had a podcast
I don't think he's doing that he's now
working with be real on be real TV
so Adam ill the guy that goes whoa make
sure you check him out he's cool that's
my homie shout out to Adam Hill Terp
champ who else we got on the list I'm
driving you guys we got hit man we got
oil slick we got handmade apparel we got
highly educated titanium we gave a big
shout-out to Charlo Greene god I just
want to take a second to think about
that one shoutout Charlo all right also
big shoutout to Tim and Zak and the
entire crew from New Mexico you guys my
friend Tim is from New Mexico he's part
of the New Mexico medical marijuana
movement my friend zach is a patient
today I met their grower and another one
of their friends I can't remember both
of their names one dude was named cedar
the other guy his name is left my head
it was a normal guy name honestly
possibly Tyler but it's been a while and
I've taken a few dabs his name is left
my head I apologize it's [ __ ] rude
but shout out to those guys they were a
lot of fun to hang out with they got me
into the event we got to hang out for a
little bit and I will probably see them
on their way home because I live between
Denver and New Mexico so stop in and
take some dabs you guys I can't wait
let's see dude I bumped into a young man
by the name of Tim Martin Tim Martin is
the host of the John Doe radio show if
you don't listen to the JD our John Doe
radio show give that a listen yes I am
shot
another cannabis podcast but we are not
competing we're friends we do totally
different shows they're from Denver I'm
from Pueblo we have different views on
things we agree on a lot of things but
I'm just saying it's two totally
different shows there's no competition I
fully support what Tim Martin is doing
Tim Martin's a great dude
Tim and I actually talked about doing a
couple of shows together so in the very
near future I will be traveling back to
Denver I will be on the John Doe radio
show stay tuned for that I'll let you
know what it happens you can listen also
we will get Tim Martin to come be on the
Grove from your heart podcast you guys
know that I've got the zoom h6 I feel
like I can take the show anywhere I did
not record anything today I felt rude I
didn't even think about taking my gear
in there because it felt rude walking
around I just wanted to say hi to my
friends and hang out and not be that
interview guy in the future I will do
that if there's a two-day event I'll
walk around one day and be friendly I'll
walk around the next day with the
microphone there's more fun just
catching up with the crew this time you
guys so big shout out to Tim Martin make
sure you guys support John Doe radio I
don't know where to tell you to go look
for that it's probably on iTunes the
conversation that him and I had today
leads me to believe that his podcast is
on iTunes all right who else do we own a
show a shout out to you guys I bumped
into a glassblower he's my friend he's
from North Carolina he now resides in
the great city of Pueblo Colorado he is
a glassblower that is on the rise on
Instagram he is known as at barefoot
glass his name's will he's a great dude
make sure you support that guy I am
going to get him and his friend Blake on
the podcast we were gonna talk about
glassblowing the glassblowing industry I
plan on having that dude on the show
that is going to be great so big shout
out to my buddy will at barefoot glass
for hanging out with me entertaining me
for a few minutes at the event that was
a good time always good to see will what
up well I hope you listen bro shout out
shout out to your bro that I met also I
want to remember that his name was Blake
but like I said earlier that was several
two hours and several dabs ago I'm
trying to get you guys my review of
champs well it's a little bit fresh in
my head and it's also filled with
shoutouts one more important shout out I
was walking through the event and I came
across a young man who calls himself Fox
extracts what up Fox I hope you listen
to the podcast it was great meeting you
and your lovely girlfriend and your
puppy big
to the puppy on their tummy scratch that
dog um Fox is a lot of great [ __ ] coming
up with CBD you guys we talked about
something for about a minute and it had
me completely intrigued Fox is now in
Colorado he's in Colorado Springs one
time this week and I am going to do my
best to link up with him and get him to
talk into a microphone for you and share
you some ideas that he's got he's got
some amazing [ __ ] happening I cannot
wait for you guys to get to hear it so I
think that's all of this shout outs I've
got a guy gave me an edible to try but
I'm not going to do a shout out on that
or any review until I'm able to sit down
and look at the packaging and eat it
right now I'm driving on Interstate 25
going about 70 miles an hour there's
nobody else out on the interstate it's
just me it's a Wednesday night it's
pretty mellow I'm actually driving
through Monument right now shout out to
the city of monument and shout out to
that cop that didn't pull me over a few
miles back I'm full on talking into a
microphone and that cop did not pull me
over
that's pretty killer so let's see I
think I've done all these shoutouts I
apologize if I missed anybody it's
nothing personal big shout out to Adam
hand for throwing me a pin big shout out
to everybody that I hung out today I
apologize if I skipped you I want to
move on to this next part you guys I was
gifted from a vendor a Jeep in mini
disposable is called the Jeep in
disposable vaporizer it's got a battery
already in it you're supposed to use it
until it dies and then you're supposed
to throw it away so it's got
instructions of press the button five
times to turn it on unscrew the
mouthpiece lows load with your desired I
think it said essential oil is what it
said on the packaging and then it said
screw on the cap and then it said press
the button and inhale so I was gifted
this it's a yellow Jeep in disposable
it's the concentrate version I have
followed the instructions i unscrewed I
loaded I turned it on I screwed it back
together now you guys we were going to
press the button and we're going to
inhale and we're going to see what kind
of drawers we get off of the Jeep in
disposable let's check it out right now
here we go
so it's dead silent I know it's shitty
for podcasting but I loaded it with New
York City diesel live resin that I got
from Spence from the garden of Weeden
big shout out to Spence and it tastes
really good but honestly I didn't get a
bit of smoke it's lighting up like it
should let's try this again let's give
it another pull
so honestly I just got some hash in my
mouth which tastes really good but
there's no smoke and it's not working
the way that you would really expect a
hash pin to work I packed it down
properly it comes with a little uh a
little pokers he can uh yeah live resin
in my mouth I gave it a little poker so
that you could pack it down in there and
it's packed down in there it's pressed
against the coil I've used plenty of
hash pins in my day and this one so far
two hits in I'm ready to throw it out
the [ __ ] window if I hadn't loaded it
up with some decent New York City live
resin it would be out the window the car
by now so what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
hold it up right to where the hash will
melt into the coil when I press the
button and I'm gonna let it melt for a
couple of seconds I'm doing that it's
lit up it seems to be doing its thing so
now I'm hoping that I've melted the hash
down gravity wise into the coil and I'm
gonna hold it to where it you know what
I mean right it's where the [ __ ] hash
is melting into the coil while I hit it
I'm gonna give it a give it a third try
and we're gonna see how this goes so
excuse me for one second you'll get more
silence but I'm gonna try this hopefully
we don't end up with hash down my throat
while I'm driving
no smoke and a little more hash in my
mouth so we will try this again on an
episode at home when we're in the house
to where we're not driving in the car
trying to do this but so far the
disposable Jeep in I find it to be a
fail I think you press it five times to
turn it off let's see one two three four
or five they flashed and went off I'm
gonna set that in the seat next to me
next to the microphone case and we're
gonna say fail on that for now you guys
gotta take a quick drink so I have a
bunch of chunks of wax stuck in my teeth
no live resin in my mouth so we've been
going for a few minutes give me just one
second I'm gonna set down the microphone
I'll edit this out but I need to take a
drink hold on I got because of that pen
I've got melted wax in my teeth hold on
here we go
all right I might add it a few seconds
of that out I apologize guys that take a
drink there's nothing like having hash
smeared across your two front teeth I
was weird alright so where was I I was
talking about the champs trade show
right you guys champs trade show was at
the Denver Convention Center it was free
they make it seem like you need to be
some sort of a vendor or have some sort
of a license to get in there but
honestly I don't have well I do I have
an LLC in ship but I walked up and said
hey I'm here and they said what company
are you with
and I said I was with my buddy Tim and
he didn't even say anything I said I'm
with organic ax and they looked at Tim
and Tim to Thorg antica and so they said
what's your name and I said Rasta Jeff
and she wrote my name on a little tag
and handed it to me no questions asked
it didn't cost me anything champs is a
free event if you're in the industry if
not all you gotta do is have a good
reason to be there and tell them that
that's why you're there if you have like
a wholesale license or something like
that you can definitely get in if not
you've got a friend that has a way to
get you in the Champs if you want to
good want to go um it's free which is a
good thing because it's not really worth
a whole bunch of money to walk through
there if it was like a five dollar
ticket I wouldn't complain I was a cool
event there's nowhere to sit down
it's illegal to medicate in the building
it's illegal to consume cannabis in the
building you can't even hit a vape pen
they did not like that of course like I
said there were a couple of people
taking a couple of rosin dabs but they
would have been escorted out had they
been caught um it was a great event it
was fun I had a good time the best part
for me honestly was linking up with a
bunch of people from the industry I
would up Anthony what up Johnny be sorry
I forgot you guys I did not mean to skip
you I apologize we spent some time
together hanging out I almost [ __ ]
spaced it you know why because our
conversation was just friendly and
natural wasn't something that had to be
documented it was just a good
conversation which I love
so shout out to also ah Jonathan Kent
yeah Jonathan dude and and Dan that's
who was with John yeah eh a whole bunch
of people saw me I was I saw them it was
fun hanging out that was my favorite
part was meeting up with people and
shaking hands and seeing everybody was a
really really good time so it's a great
place to go if you're in the industry
and you know a few people you can buy a
lot of great glass at very great
discounted prices
I saw some beautiful beautiful glass but
you guys honestly I'm not into buying
really artful glass lately I've been
buying what they call production work
and functional glass is just clear and
hits like a champ I hate it when I spend
hundreds to a thousand dollars on a nice
rig hold on I gotta put the microphone
down here cuz the car just gonna be one
second alright I just didn't want that
car to see me talking into the mic I
hate it when you spend a lot of money or
your friends spend a lot of money on a
rig and you can only put like a really
certain amount of water in there because
one drop more it splashes in your mouth
and one drop less it doesn't perk right
I found that to be really annoying on a
custom-made piece so I buy production
pieces that are clear and I think they
hit like a [ __ ] champ you guys I
think there's nothing wrong with having
a clear rig you don't even need to spend
a lot of money on a rig you guys you
could have spent 40 bucks on a really
nice rig today and been set up you could
have got a highly-educated titanium male
and a carb cap for a really good price
champs is a great place if you're
looking to come up on a rig or two or if
you've got a wholesale license it was
really the place to buy a whole bunch of
[ __ ] alright so also shot it's a
grassroots grassroots was they're set up
in style yeah so for a free event it was
really a good time it was a great day in
Denver it rained a little bit but that
didn't slow anybody down
most of the vendors that I really
appreciated seeing will be at the
Cannabis Cup in Denver or excuse me I'm
burpin they'll be at the Cannabis Cup in
Denver in April if that happens there's
rumors that that may not happen I'm not
gonna start talking [ __ ] about it on the
show but there have been rumors if that
won't happen let's hope that it does
most of those vendors will be available
and present at the Cannabis Cup in full
force if there's a cannabis cup in your
area I bet those vendors will be there
make sure you look out for oil slick get
an oil slick pad keep your table from
getting all [ __ ] sticky check out hit
man glass hit man makes really good
glass that hits like a truck every
[ __ ] time when you get new glass what
do you need you need a new nail who do
you go for for that you go to highly
educated titanium you get yourself a
nail I like a domeless nail and a carb
cap I think that's the way to go then
you need some cool ass t-shirts who do
you get your t-shirts printed through
you go to handmade
peril there's another car on the highway
let's just get behind him and cruise for
a little while so they don't see me
talking into a microphone yeah guys I am
driving on the interstate we're now
approaching Woodman Road in the
beautiful city of Colorado Springs
Colorado let's see I've been recording
for 22 minutes I should pay attention
more to the road and the recording but
I'm the only one out here other than
this guy in front of me I'm gonna get
passed by a truck here we go all right
so yeah I've got a bunch of great [ __ ]
planned for more episodes you guys I'm
just gonna put this out as a Thursday
episode or oh yeah bonus Thursday
episode this will not be your Monday
primary episode I just wanted to ramble
for a little bit while I was driving see
if I could actually do a car podcast
never thought of that before now that
I've got this nice gear I felt it would
be necessary you guys I've got an
episode coming up Monday I think Monday
we are going to talk about ways reasons
why your cannabis is not top-shelf in
ways that you can improve your cannabis
and make it top-shelf I wouldn't take a
whole lot foremost do you guys just
upgrade your grow just a little bit it
won't cost you money it will cost you
more time energy effort and attention
which we all should have I've got an
episode about CBD planned I think I have
an episode with Fox planned I have an
episode about blowing glass and the
glass industry coming up with our friend
will and I'm going to try to get a whole
bunch of grow lessons planned out forgot
some great [ __ ] in my mind you guys are
gonna love it I want to thank you guys
for listening to this short car episode
I'm gonna get off the microphone I don't
have anything else left to say I
appreciate you guys I love you guys
every day like my own adopted children I
will be back Monday with the full
episode don't judge me by the quality
this episode you guys have recorded this
in the car while driving after the
champs trade show in Denver so until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
you