[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 104 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber here at cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friend is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my show
big thanks to kab the entire mystic
roots crew
back in the studio you guys and I
putting this episode out as a regular
Monday episode so good morning hope
you're having a great Monday
sometimes Monday's can be a real [ __ ]
so I hope I make it a little bit better
with the fresh episode of the girl from
your heart podcast if it's not Monday
for you whenever you're listening to
this I hope you're having a great day I
hope you've got a fat joint rolled hope
you got a blunt roll I've got a DAB
ready have you got a bowl packed
hope you got the vaporizer filled up I
hope you got something going on maybe
you're eating some edibles maybe you're
using some cannabis lubrication or
possibly a cannabis suppository whatever
it is I hope it's working great for you
I hope you're working in the garden hope
you're driving in the car whatever
you're doing I'm hoping that I'm making
your day a little bit better thanks for
joining me you guys I'm back in the
studio last time I was on I did an
episode from the car and I did a review
on the Jeep in slim disposable vaporizer
I used the concentrate version you know
when I was in the car I gave this thing
kind of a shitty review but let me tell
you that was a preemptive strike I got
home and I looked at it a little bit all
I had to do was patch pack the hash in a
little bit harder I press it down and
heat it up a little bit and it actually
gave me quite a few fat rips so I'm
going to AH what is it called withdraw
my my shitty review of this product and
I'm going to update it I'm going to give
it like 4 out of 5 stars for a vape pen
that's disposable this is probably the
best quality we're gonna find so like 4
out of 5 stars because for a DAB or a
wax hit or a concentrate hit I prefer a
rig you need a rig for 5 stars but it's
a good product if you're in Colorado and
you're picking up some concentrates and
you need something to smoke it through
these little yellow vape pens that
you're gonna throw away when you're done
I think these are an affordable and
economical deal so I apologize for the
shitty review my updated review says
it's a quality product alright so I want
to give the whole nation a shout out
everybody in America this is for you you
guys
Halloween just passed and guess how many
people reported finding cannabis laced
candy and their children's Halloween
basket nobody that's right there were
zero reports of cannabis laced can be
given out for Halloween this year so a
big shout out we did the same shout out
last year but I wanted to do it again
because you're doing a good job you guys
please don't ever give children animals
anybody can
this infused candy without their
knowledge if your pets using it for
medicine do that with discretion I can't
judge you there they do make medicine
for your dog now it's infused with
cannabis but don't do it just to get
your dog [ __ ] up that's rude
you guys keep us on a good Street keep
the recreational cannabis going well for
us
all right so shout out so you guys I was
at the chance trade show if you listen
to the other episode I'm sure you heard
about that
but I was at the champs trade show over
the weekend I was actually during the
week and I noticed something there is a
really tight-knit really close little
community that travels around to all of
the cannabis shows and they set up their
booths and they take great care of the
customers and the community and they
really represent the cannabis movement
the cannabis product movement the
cannabis industry in a positive light
and I just want to give a big shout out
to all those people they know who they
are I don't need to point them out
specifically if you were part of that
cannabis movement that comes to the
events that goes to the events that is
part of the product development the
advancement of the products if you're
there show in your face if we see each
other and high-five each other and don't
even have to talk you're part of the
crew that I'm talking about if we see
each other and just nod at each other
because we've seen so many tons seen
each other so many times you're part of
the crew I'm talking about you guys make
these events happen and we kind of rely
on you I've noticed a bit I find myself
hovering and lingering at those boots
that you're there all the time because
we've become comfortable we've become
friends and you guys are also leaders
and you're teaching the other boots and
the other vendors how to do it so a big
shout out much respect to the family
that travels around and does all of the
events and supports each other supports
the movement it's really great to see
you guys every time you show up you're
welcome in Colorado all the time if you
ever need anything when you're in
Colorado let me know and I will do my
best to accommodate you fully much love
and respect to the whole cannabis
community and industry and also big
shout out to all the people that come
and learn and meet me at greet me and
shake my hand and high-five me and ask
me questions and thank me for my
breeding a big shout out to all those
people I really enjoy going to those
events it's really a refreshing time all
right so you guys let's get down to
business here is the topic for the show
today
I've been bumping into people and
they've been talking about
why some people are able to take their
cannabis to the next level and some
people are stuck growing it's not mid
grade but it's still not stellar
cannabis so I thought that I would write
down some of the reasons why your herb
not yours but some herb is not what we
would consider top-shelf product and
then we could talk about a few ways on
how to improve that and get your herb up
to the top shelf so let me work on my
list here I got a couple things written
down all right you guys the main reason
I find the cannabis is not able to be
considered top shelf product is because
it has been over fertilized a lot of
people are thinking that they can add
more fertilizer and feed it more and
you're gonna get better product but
actually what you're doing is you are
pumping it full of nutrients that are
gonna affect the flavor it's gonna be
harder to flush that stuff out in the
end everything that you put into your
plants will affect the flavor another
big reason that I find a lot of cannabis
is not able to be considered top shelf
product is that it was not properly
flushed you guys your cannabis plants
need to be flushed for a minimum of ten
days preferably two full weeks before
harvest so 10 to 14 days before you plan
on cutting down your plants you need to
start watering it with just clean water
pH and about six five get in there and
just fill every pot fill the whole pot
with water so that it's dripping out of
the drain holes a little bit do that 14
days before harvest and then let it dry
up just like you normally would and when
you're gonna water again make sure you
water it until it drips out of the pot a
little bit and you don't want to give it
any nutrients for the last 14 days if
you're an experienced grower there
aren't a few things you can add at the
end there but I wouldn't recommend too
many things unless you really know what
you're doing that's this is where you're
really going to start affecting your
flavor so be careful at the end make
sure you flush for at least 14 days you
can go longer you I don't think you can
over flush if you feel like you start
flushing about 14 days before you think
you're gonna harvest and you feel like
those plants can go a few more days
don't worry let them go a few more days
they'll be just fine and they will taste
even better let them finish up let them
ripen up let them flush out let all the
nutrients come out and you'll be okay
you guys you may see some yellowing
hope for some yellowing that means
you're flushing it properly that means
that you're getting all the excess
nutrients out of the leaves that are
stored in the plants and you're gonna
flush that right on out that means that
there aren't extra nutrients left in the
soil that the plants eating it means
it's eaten all of its food and it's
getting cleaned up and it's almost time
for harvest now I want to take a step
back and say over fertilization and not
flushing are both possible even when you
were using organics you guys organic
nutrients can still burn your plants
organic nutrients can over fertilize
your plants be careful when using
organics you can add the wrong I mean
think about the way that stuff smells
when you're working with some organics
it literally smells like a pile of [ __ ]
if you over fertilize it they can make
your butts taste like a pile of [ __ ] it
is very possible also not flushing I
hear a lot of people say they don't have
to flush because they used organic
nutrients you need to flush if you're
using if you're using your own like
super soil and you know that you don't
need to flush because you've been
flushing the whole time you're an
experienced grower and you understand
that but if you're using a bottled
nutrient or some sort of organics or
most amended soils you're going to need
to flush you guys so make sure you flush
even with organics make sure you don't
over fertilize even with organics and
this can make your cannabis better if
you're using a bottled nutrient start
with about half of what they recommend
on the bottle about half of the dosage
rate and then if you see that you have a
deficiency move up you can correct you
can always add but you can never
subtract from what you've fed your
plants all right so don't over fertilize
and do flush the next thing that I see
that makes cannabis not able to be top
shelf is a really poor trim job you
would not believe how much very well
grown cannabis I have seen that would
have been top-shelf
if the grower would have taken just a
little bit more time to make sure to
take all those little tiny leaves off
you guys we don't want to see any leaves
when we're looking at the buds we want
to see trichomes we want to see resin we
want to see just just buds we don't even
want to see any stick at all just a
little tiny stick that sticks out of the
bottom of the bud that's all that we
need so when you're trim and make sure
you take off all those little tiny
pointy leaves get in there
clean that [ __ ] up cut all the little
sticks out cut your sticks off of the
big gigantic buds and trim your weed to
look like just buds look at a magazine
look online look what good quality bud
looks like and trim it up like that if
you can see an obvious leaf on there get
in there with your scissors and clip it
off get in there to thumbnail and knock
that off trim your we'd like connoisseur
grade weed and it will be top-shelf
alright and also wear rubber gloves you
guys when you're trimming your cannabis
make sure that you wear rubber gloves
and in my opinion top-shelf herb is hand
trimmed and not machine trimmed if
you've got machine trimmed bud that one
a cannabis cup I'm impressed ah let's
see what rubber gloves you guys whenever
you're touching these buds whenever
you're touching a product that
somebody's going to smoke make sure you
wear rubber gloves we do not want to
smoke your skin oils I don't want to
hear your skin oil or your skin moisture
sizzling my dab that's just so gross
so trim your weed wear gloves and use
scissors not a trim machine is something
I want to stress alright so another
thing that quite often deters people's
cannabis from being top-shelf product is
a very poor cure a lot of people are
trying to speed dry their cannabis you
guys the slower your buds dry the better
they are going to taste the better they
are going to smoke think about your goal
your goal is to eventually grind up this
bud and either roll a joint out of it or
pack a bowl or stuff it in your
vaporizer or most of us in how days are
going to stuff it into a tube and turn
it into BHO or a lot of your gonna
freeze it and turn it into ice wax or
something but anyway let's think about
what we're trying to do eventually most
of us are gonna grind up this herb and
roll a fat joint out of it now when you
smoke your joint you want it to smell
good you want it to taste good you want
it to get you nice and stoned but
something that you really want it to do
that you don't think about is that you
want it to burn nice and smoothly you
want it to burn evenly you want it to
burn and make a nice white ash you don't
want it to burn into this hard black
charcoal looking thing that hard black
charcoal that's in the bottom of your
bowl when you're done or that your joint
turns into that's nutrients that weren't
flushed out of the plant
ah anyway I'm backing up a little bit
but a lot of times a bad cure will make
your buds not burn properly when you're
curing your buds you are removing excess
chlorophyll from the plants you are
removing a water molecule from the THC
which makes the THC more psychoactive
you are also pulling chlorophyll which
is making the plants taste better
making your buds taste better so a
proper cure and not a speed dry is very
important of proper cure will definitely
affect the way that your buds burn
slowly drying your buds will suck out
all of that chlorophyll and it will suck
the moisture out slowly and your buds
will burn very nice and smoothly they'll
be nice and sticky and they will burn
very very well I've got an episode all
about drying and curing I'm gonna pause
right now and go see exactly which
number it is it's either 35 or 36 let me
pause for one second and go see what it
is so that I can tell you to listen here
we go okay guys it's episode number 35
go listen to episode number 35 of the
girl from your heart podcast and learn
all about properly drying and curing
your cannabis
actually when it was episode 35 it was
called iGrow culture but it's still on
the same feet he guys it's episode
number 35 and it's titled number 35
drying and curing so go check it out
it's a the formerly known as agriculture
podcast that now known as the girl from
your heart a podcast it's in the same
feed go check it out
I feel like I'm way off topic let's get
back in the game here we are talking
about a poor cure is what makes your
buds not top-shelf because they don't
taste good and they do not burn properly
you guys it is very possible to have
nice sticky buds that are properly dried
and cured that will burn like a champ
stink up the whole [ __ ] neighborhood
and get you high a [ __ ] that's your goal
so listen to the episode learn how to
properly dry and cure the buds um
another thing don't try to speed dry
your weed you guys do not speed drive
cut it down hang it upside down and let
it dry properly that's what that's gonna
give you a huge advantage also here is a
major contributing factor to why I feel
like a lot of people's buds are not
top-shelf you guys people really love to
cut their buds way too early let that
[ __ ] grow let it finish just because the
packaging on your seed package says that
those seeds will be done in 60 days does
not mean that you have to cut them down
in 60 days get yourself a nice scope get
some sort of a scope where you can
magnify the size of your trichomes to
where you can see how many of them have
turned opaque how many of them have gone
cloudy and how many of them are amber
when you start seeing about 30 percent
amber trichomes is when it's time to
harvest you guys a lot of people are
just cutting weed down way too early
they're trimming it like [ __ ] there's
speed drying it and then they're trying
to get top-shelf prices for it and they
feel bad and they feel let down when
they're not able to sell their product
for a top-shelf price you've got to let
it finish you have really got to let it
finish it doesn't even taste right it
doesn't get you high enough and you're
not even getting the right weight if you
don't let it finish that last week or
two is really where it starts packing on
weight on a lot of strains so let the
weed grow longer quit cutting it too
early and it will really improve the
quality of your buds like I said get a
scopes
aren't watching the trichomes quit
paying so much attention to your
calendar and pay a little bit more
attention to the plants I understand
you're on a schedule but the plants are
the boss here and if you want a Plus
top-shelf buds this is what you're gonna
have to do alright so don't cut too
early now also you're going to have to
pay a lot more attention to the room we
can tell I can tell by looking at the
finished product if the room got too hot
or if the room got too humid or if you
had some sort of bug infestation or if
there was some sort of struggle a
professional grower can tell by looking
at your finished but what the problem
was off your buds are airy and fluffy
you probably got too hot in there if the
buds have this weird texture to them it
probably got too humid in there I can
spot bug damage on those leaves that
you're not cutting off I can see the
spider mite marks on those leaves you
guys so pay a lot of attention to the
room get good control of your rooms it's
all about the environment you have to
set up that room to have proper air flow
you need air exchange you need to get
the old stale air out of there and you
need to get fresh air in so that that
plant can breathe you don't want to be
trapped in a stale humid ass closet all
day neither do your plants so and they
also don't want to be too hot if you get
the plants too hot they start Fox
tailing the buds start getting wispy
it's just like in the summer time you
guys you guys you know what I'm talking
about when it gets all hot your junk
starts swinging down all low it's just
trying to cool itself down the plants
will do the same thing it starts
spreading its legs all far so that it
can get some air and it starts Fox
tailing that's from too much heat you
guys so if you get your grow room under
control
you will be able to produce better
cannabis get the bugs under control you
guys if you don't have bugs on your
plants your plants don't have to spend
all their energy fighting off these
predators and they're able to use all of
their energy into producing delicious
tasty trichomes and resin terpenes let
the plants focus on what they're
supposed to do
all right so um pay attention to the
room get the room under control is the
point of that part right there so
another reason why a lot of cannabis
that I see cannot be considered
top-shelf cannabis is because the grower
basically forgot the general rules of
growing he forgot to think about his
lights his air his water or his soil he
just kind of got it
sometimes as growers we get complacent
we get cocky we get egotistical we get
overconfident we get ahead of ourselves
that [ __ ] happens and sometimes that's
when you start worrying about something
that is really obscure and then you
forget about something that was really
basic you're trying some new trick
that's really gonna improve the crop
right this new trick is gonna make
everything [ __ ] magical it's gonna be
amazing but as I did that I forgot to pH
the nutrient solution before I watered
it something stupid like that you guys
just pay attention to the basics pay
attention to your lights pay attention
to the air pay attention to your water
and pay attention to your soil and
everything should be cool of course pay
attention to the plants look at the
leaves every day for bugs do all that
stuff but remember the basics you need
good lighting if you don't have good
lighting you can't grow quality buds you
can grow quality bud under a small lamp
I wouldn't go you know you can use it
250 you're not gonna grow cannabis cup
winning buds underneath the 250 watt
light you may do OK under a 4 you've got
potential under a 6 but I really think
if you're gonna grow cannabis cup
winning top-shelf a great buds you need
at least a thousand watt light at least
1000 watt light and you don't want to
try to put more than about a 4x4 or a
5x5 floor pattern worth of plants
underneath there you want your canopy to
be nice and tight under that thousand
watt light the light is the main
nutrient for your plants that's what the
plants want more than anything so have
enough lighting and also make sure you
have the right spectrum that's super
important don't forget about that ere we
sort of discussed err before ah don't
have too much humidity don't have too
much heat try to find a way to replenish
the co2 by replacing the air in the room
very often your water
mentioned this make sure your pH in your
nutrient solution before you're feeding
it to your plants make sure you're
checking your ppm s make sure you're
using good quality water if you can
start with reverse osmosis water that
would be ideal make sure you remember to
check the pH you guys a lot of people
simply have overlooked pH balancing
their water before they add it to the
solute to the plants you want that about
six five ish depending on what strains
you're running depends on how far into
flour you are but make sure you've got
your nutrients measured properly you're
not over feeding the plants and you've
got them pH adjusted your soil you guys
you got to use a good quality soil you
can't be packing your dirt too tight you
need some aeration you need some air in
there you need some drainage in there
use good soil don't overlook that type
of stuff those are the basics that you
guys need to pay attention to that you
may have forgotten that sometimes I
forget I'm guilty of this as well this
is all small things that I'm trying to
remind you about so don't forget the
basics of growing and we can always
refer to the old rule called laws lights
air water and soil never forget those
and then of course you got to add love
in there because I think plants grow
with a lot of love you gotta love the
plants so another way to improve your
cannabis and this is gonna sound like
I'm just trying to make a sales pitch
here but you need good quality genetics
you guys unless you've got a top-shelf
cultivar and I'm gonna I'm gonna branch
here you guys quit saying strands it's
not a strand we don't smoke different
strands we don't grow different strands
we grow different strains and if you
really want to be difficult and
technical they are known as varietals
and then if you really want to be an
[ __ ] you would call it a cultivar so
a specific phenotype of a specific
strain would be a cultivar but I digress
use good genetics you guys grow a good
strain if you're stuck on growing that
strain and you can't get it to be what
you want it to be maybe it's time to buy
a pack of seeds and run those seeds and
find the one in there that does what you
need maybe you're simply held back by
the quality of the clones you've got
that could be your issue so use good
genetics do some research get some seeds
from a reputable breeder I am not
sponsored by the dank team.com
currently they do not pay for
any ads but I can fully recommend my
friends at the dank team.com they have
reliable seeds I used to say it all the
time you can get rare dankness mile hike
an adventure Sin City sour seeds those
are just a few of the people that I
would recommend of course I read
genetics if you can get your hands on it
get yourself some good quality seeds
from a reputable breeder do a Fino hunt
find the best one out of there for you
and maybe that will help you improve the
quality of your cannabis maybe it's just
that clone that you're growing isn't
going to get any better maybe it's got
maybe its potential is only 17 percent
THC no matter what you do to it it's
just a genetic thing my genetics say
that I'm not gonna be able to jump six
feet high no matter what I do I can't
jump high I'm a white I'm a white man
they can't jump it's just my genetics
sometimes these plants aren't gonna go
much further than their potential so get
good genetics hey you guys we talked
about lights air water and soil but what
we got to think about is do not overlook
the vegetative stage of growth from day
one when you get those clones when you
crack those seeds from the very
beginning of the grow you are working on
the quality of that cannabis you may
just say hey it's a veg I can just put
it under these weak lights I don't need
a lot of good air I don't need to feed
it good soil good nutrients but really
good teenagers and good kids make good
adults so why doesn't the same [ __ ] work
with plants I think you need to take
really good care of those baby plants
because that is the beginning of
everything
you need to create a nice root zone you
need to create a nice thick stalk you
need a nice node structure you need nice
strong supported branches
you need nice topping you need nice a
nice canopy you need nice pruning just
take very good care of the plants in the
veg phase and you will be very prepared
for happy healthy plants when you go
into the flowering stage so pay more
attention to the veg phase I think a lot
of people overlook the vegetative stage
of cannabis growing so that's a way that
you could definitely improve the quality
of your cannabis alright guys I've got
one more thing that I really think would
help improve the quality of your
finished product and it will also help
improve the quality of your concentrates
if you're a hash maker something you
really need to do is clean your grow
room okay make sure that the floor is
clean make sure that the tops of your
light reflectors are dusted off make
sure that the air conditioner gets
cleaned make sure that all the blowers
and the carbon filters the tops of them
sometimes they collect a little dust
clean those make sure that your carbon
filter covers get cleaned occasionally
hey guys you got to go in there and
clean up ah if you've got a shop vac
with a good filter on it get in there
and shop vac the corners clean the [ __ ]
out of that grow room because every
piece of dust and particulate that is in
the air will end up sticking to your
plants if you've ever taken a picture of
a cannabis plant and there's a little
hair in there you understand exactly how
bad anything and everything will stick
to your cannabis plants while they're
growing you'll never be able to get the
hair out of it you'll never be able to
get the dust out so clean up the grow
room if you've got long hair if you've
got a beard think about keeping that
[ __ ] out of the plants to do what you
can I can't talk too much [ __ ] I've got
dreadlocks that go almost to my knees
I've got to wear a big-ass hat just to
go in the grow room so try to be
sanitary try to be clean try to be dust
free try to clean up all that [ __ ] all
of that stuff is going to stick to your
buds all that stuff is going to end up
in your finished product all that stuff
is going to end up in your concentrate
so just think about all the dust and
whatever that is its soil and whatever
else you're dragging around in the grow
room that's all going to end up in your
finished product
all right you guys so I'm gonna do a
quick recap I've gone through my list
let's go real quickly if you want your
buds to be a little bit better than they
are maybe you could uh pay more
attention to your feeding maybe you
could flush a little bit better you
could possibly trim up your buds a
little bit better you could probably
improve the quality of your drying and
curing method which all you'd have to do
is listen to episode number 35 and
that'll give you huge steps on how to do
that you could probably let your plants
grow a little bit longer pay attention
to the harvest date that would help you
out
you could probably pay more attention to
the room and dial the room in a little
bit better you could probably work on
not having bugs another good way to
improve the quality of your cannabis is
to remember the basics and remember the
fundamentals of growing another huge way
to improve the quality of your grow is
to use quality genetics from a reputable
breeder another good way is to not
overlook your veg phase and of course
clean up the grow room and then of
course we've got a little side note here
that says good lighting so make sure
you're using proper lighting and also
you guys good nutrients good quality
nutrients will get you a long way make
sure your plants are properly fed um
there are a few things that I think
would work with every feed regimen if
you wanted to add dehydrated coconut
water and also yucca extract those
things will definitely improve your
cannabis with almost any feed regimen if
you're going hydro you're gonna have to
figure out how to add those to your
hydro regimen it's a little bit
different but if you got a soil mix
going on those things that definitely
make your plants taste better if your
plants are burning and making black
ashes you're probably over new training
/ nutrient tting over feeding over
fertilizing that's what I think I'm
trying to say and you're not flushing
properly so work on those things you
guys that's all I've got for this
episode I'm gonna start wrapping up the
show I will be back in about I'm not
gonna do a midweek episode so I will be
back Monday for you I've got a couple of
few things planned I'm trying to link up
with our friend Fox he's in Colorado
right now he is a busy man he is elusive
I've chased him down for a day and it
was hard to find him so he did not
record with him yet but we will in the
future if everything goes my way you
guys I'd love it if you found me on the
social media I am on Twitter it's at Gia
by each podcast we are on Facebook it's
grow from your heart on Instagram I use
the I read genetics Instagram page we're
almost at nineteen thousand followers to
be really cool if you clicked on that
and put me up there at nineteen thousand
followers that'd be really cool
so follow I read genetics on Instagram
you guys I think that's all I've got for
you this week I want to thank everybody
for listening I want to give a big shout
out to my ninja Spence
until next time you guys take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
want you to marry me
just oh let it be
I'm so contagious or let it be
herb smokey I say
[Music]
no reprisal a blue jacket water don't
applaud to know what this is
[Music]
I just saw that he'd be
don't want you to know marry one
I just saw let it be hey this is not
everyone abusing a message from the ones
that use it don't abuse it
my name's Johnny now one do what they do
how are they
[Music]
[Applause]
open your eyes
[Music]
but in a medium
I just saw let it be
oh geez
I just let it be
herb is the lifeline
[Music]
tada
you