[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 105 the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation god I'm already coughing
through the intro I want to thank
everybody for joining me you guys
sitting across the table from me is my
good buddy well how you doing bro good
man how you doing dude I'm doing great
thanks for joining me you guys I
apologize for coughing right away on the
intro I blew the intro but it's alright
we're gonna have a great show you guys
my buddy will is here he's a glassblower
he's also known as at barefoot glass on
Instagram are you on Twitter because
make sure you check him out on Instagram
go look at his post while you're
listening to this podcast it's at
barefoot glass he's a UH kind of an
up-and-coming glass artist kind of a new
guy how long you been going started in
July so late you're really new yeah
coming up on four months holy [ __ ] right
on well congratulations I thank you
doing hella good well appreciate it
he gave me a you gave me a dabber
several months ago yeah it is why it's
taken a couple of tumbles and it has not
broken yet knows what he's doing well
thank you man oh for sure man I
appreciate you being on the show I'm
looking for the news article that I had
tagged here but of course I refreshed
and now it's gone so this it'll come
back up it can be the best and it can be
the worst thing on the planet
well dude thanks for coming to the show
I've got a news article I can't find out
on my computer I'm not getting it going
here I promise you but I don't even need
the news article talk about it something
weird happened here recently in Colorado
Snoop Dogg has signed a deal with live
well a dispensary he'll appear in
Colorado to produce a strain of cannabis
and market this cannabis under the Snoop
Dogg name at live well now that sounds
like a really cool thing but wills
looking at me and shaking his head kind
of to the side kind of like yeah if you
guys have heard the show in the past
we've reported about Live Well putting a
whole bunch of shitty-ass pesticides in
their cannabis if you come to Colorado
and you shop it live well you'll be
disappointed because it's pretty much
like going to the shittiest street
dealer you can ever find
and buying the shittiest dirt weed you
can find for way too much money and it
always seems old like old weed
yeah yeah just old and it's probably
because they're using pesticides and low
quality grow times so I think it's
really weird that Snoop has come and
done a deal with the shittiest like
they've got the reputation for being the
shittiest dispensary in Colorado soups
publicist or publishing or public people
should have done a lot more research on
this [ __ ] this is a fail on publicists
yeah it's their fault that guy failed
they should have done a little more work
and I'm also curious I am NOT a law
expert but snoop is not a Colorado
resident how is snoop able to
participate in a Colorado cannabis
business I'm very curious about that so
if you guys have some insight on that
Mike if you're listening please tweet me
or come be on the show and we will talk
about how snoops able to do this this is
this is kind of wack you guys soup
signed up with the shittiest dispenser
here in Colorado and I'm not just
talking [ __ ] if you're in Colorado and
you go to live well and then go to
almost any other dispensary go to the
spot dispensary go to green and healthy
wellness when they reopen here in about
two weeks I you will see quality
products fare to live well very quality
yeah green and healthy is only a Terp
station is only medical so I apologize
alright so I wanted to talk about that
for a second we got past the Snoop Dogg
part we did not even need any help from
the news article ah snoop big fail bro
if you need some good weed come hit me
up for the dispensary and I'll show you
how to grow and I'll show you how I grow
and will produce some quality buds for
you will do it will make a strain for
you called doggy style
alright so wills a glassblower let's
talk a little bit about blowing class
dude you brought some great looking
pieces with you man the piece right in
front of me is is that called Illuminati
or is that this is haterade alright very
special okay that's a good that's a good
random question where did these names
come from big blast night the color of
the glass yeah whoever the company that
makes it or the person that pulls it
okay each one there's like glass alchemy
mountain glass arts and then tapi tubes
en el burro here in Denver okay just
bunch of different companies that pull
different colors and they name it
whatever they
there's a few that go across the board
like blue Stardust is one that every
company most likely has okay but then
there's a few I can't think of any off
the top of my head but that are just
specifically a company made them okay so
is this a common color or is this poor
it's a pretty common one yeah all right
all right so what's the difference
between haterade slime and Illuminati
Illuminati is UV reactive Illuminati
have to just like hater a pretty much
little bit more on the yellow side
probably but is UV reactive so when you
hit it with the UV light he glows
it's hope it's pretty neat I've got a
little Pandey from shout out to ghost
cat glass with some UV in it all right
and then slime of course is a little
it's like white in it sometimes how you
stretch it and pull it all right so you
guys we're already learning we learned
the difference Illuminati glasses really
cool you guys it's real hip if you're
not it's not in the glass seen this some
of this episode may go over your head
but you're gonna learn a whole bunch
today yeah the glass scene has got its
own scene happening here in Colorado
it's got its own glass scene in
California is everywhere Florida yeah
the East Coast has got a glass scene
popping up it's everywhere there are no
glass galleries all over the place it's
really funny I go to glass events and I
don't even will and I hang out
we are friends through the garden of
Weeden we don't really hang out in on
our own but we always bump into each
other at illusions glass galleries we
ran into each other at champs Oh who's
calling you daddy good what maybe that's
the best person that could call right
now hey Maddie come be on the podcast
again we get so many listens when you're
here but we run into each other at glass
places glass events all the time so
we're birth both huge glass enthusiast
which is kind of great so does this rig
have a name who blew this one this is
whitey glass whitey glass yeah whitey
glasses his name I don't know his actual
name but whitey glasses Instagram why do
you don't even know there's an
underscore anything but you look up
whitey glass you'll find him you'll find
it real good he's healing the climb
maybe this Klein game yes see these
pieces with this weird spout on the back
that's called the climb yeah this is a
client Klein that's like a recycler it's
the new kind of cool recycler that
everyone's liking as opposed to the old
triangular shape shape recyclers is more
of an internal one even though it's not
technically internal with the the drains
and the drain in the back everything I
really like the way those types of rigs
hit I've got a little Klein and I love
the way that they're awesome they're
awesome
all right so shout out to whitey glass
that's a sexy piece dude
tell me more about this rubber ducky
looking at this little birdie right here
this is a calm burgling this is number
38 in the series just kind of a little
of how many I'm not sure on that number
38 sweet it came with a little tin but
you can see over there it's like got a
little drawing on the top that side and
everything that's fresh yeah it's pretty
cool
but yes a little series calvin Mickle's
or calvin Mickle is his name
calm combo on instagram he makes really
cool Birds one of the simpler ones kind
of a productions kind of a puck type
base which is hollow and functional
that's where the perk is sitting s la
he's got a donut which functions as the
basically the head of the bird Atwood
it's got a beak what color's the beak
the beak looks like green Stardust I
think it's women Stardust all right and
then he's got a couple of white wings
that are attached to the base and then
now you got a little club banger on
there nice little little quartz banger
we're gonna talk more about the bangers
here in just a few minutes one of my
notes is all about the banger remind me
the artist on that one that is a calm
combo combo
alright so shut up the combo glass you
guys make sure you check out all these
artists on Instagram we're gonna talk a
lot about artists make sure you go check
them out i'll list off some of my
favorite artists towards the end of the
episode I'm gonna ask will some of his
favorites also so we will definitely
give you some [ __ ] to look at so next up
is a glorious piece with have I what is
this piece here on the front call this
disc collection it would be called a cab
when it's connected like this
alright it's a little die crow iguana
cab this piece is made by mongrel glass
okay Jack Jack is his name Jack Alba
shark good good friend of mine from
actually back in North Carolina North
Carolina there are people left you guys
didn't bring everybody from North
Carolina no he's out here guys that's
funny because Maddie and Spence moved at
her close to two years ago and then
everybody else from the town of Dixie
came out here then all of the
surrounding areas all the cool stoners
are just moving to Colorado
everybody from North Carolina is coming
out here and it's really funny to see
but I love it you guys are so in the
North Carolina people are some of my
favorite friends
they're they're a different breed of
folk they're more open they're kinder
their more polite they got more time
southern charm but not that southern I
don't know the trailer park exactly all
right let's do this piece what is going
on with the pco2 this is my favorites
this is called the Safari special okay
it's a really big really big bass with a
tiny little mouthpiece we'll try it out
in a minute
oh yeah he did it's like it's kind of
hard to talk about it over the
microphone without you people seeing it
but it's got this giant basically shower
head perk in it it's got like seven
holes it's [ __ ] Frost like oh they
can hear that yeah yeah it's got a nice
function couple of Leafs on the inside
with some flower implosions attached to
the perk it looks like somewhere that
Ariel The Little Mermaid we wanna catch
exact it totally looks like it's got
some ah so it this is this a banger
hanger with this officially beautiful I
would call a banger okay yeah alright
well we're on that subject about banger
hangers I'm gonna give it another
shout-out to [ __ ] glass here because he
was one of the first in my opinion to
start using this and he even posted
about it a while ago I was when before
even bangers were a thing it was emails
when he nails were a big thing he was
one of the first people to start going
back to the original female joint as
opposed to the male joint that people
were using for dabbing because he
noticed the trend of people using
attachments and dramas and stuff and
everything so he I remember him making a
post about it everything about you know
I'm thinking about making transition
back to just this blah blah blah and he
was one of the first people in my
opinion to really you know I was
completely do that when I first saw him
going back to the female joints I was
like what's happening here how do I put
my nail in this [ __ ] and like this is
new and when I saw the bangers the club
bangers we're gonna have to talk about
bangers in the middle after defined
bliss I write that here I wrote down the
word banger remember to talk about that
a little bit so this piece we're talking
about you guys I know we've been talking
about this piece for a long time it's
got a really fat bass and then it's got
what did you call this one again cab die
crow cab with an iguana a super colorful
iguana on the front seat of life in the
back of the seat of life sacred geometry
in the back
and then when you spin it around in the
back there's like a mid with the flower
and two leaves around it and then it
seals up and coming out of the clear
sealed part is three pieces of bamboo
the taller pieces the mouthpiece and
then it's got to beautifully detailed
leaves go just one one beautifully
detailed leaf coming up the side it's
pretty fresh looking piece that's that's
a really stylish looking rig yeah it's
one of my favorites for sure I can see
why yeah does it hit well with that
skinny mouthpiece oh yeah phenomenally
cool sounds like a champ yeah so we got
to give shoutouts to mongrel to combo
and I forgot one guy whitey I forget why
people called me whitey all the time I'm
writing these names down so that we can
give a huge shout out at the end make
sure all these glassblower just get a
bunch of love alright so what are these
three of your favorites in my collection
yeah oh yeah these are probably three my
favorites of my collection for sure I've
got a couple more Klein's got a couple
more pieces by him I've got the wyoming
angler but these are like my daily
drivers one of the anglers yeah I guess
check those crazy some of the teeth make
me nervous about a sharp yeah scares me
I work with more the functional clear
prototype class for myself it's more my
thing so since we're talking about your
glass I'm gonna brag about my new rig
I've got this Hitman over here it's
actually hitman Sampson collab
it's got basic hitman yeah yeah it's got
a basic hitman sidecar design but then
it's got this sweet girl what do you
call that color greenish turquoise
definitely a custom sort of things I've
never seen lately I really love that I
like the clear glass that's made by like
a like a brand that's known like hitman
because I have nothing against these
rigs but when you buy one of these the
functions sometimes is questionable
definitely I've seen friends of ours
spend thousands of dollars on a rig and
if you put four milliliters too much
water in it you're gonna get in your
mouth and if you put five milliliters
too short you get a dry dab and you
choke for days and I love that these
production rigs that are made the same
all the time I love that I know what I'm
getting when I buy them and if I break
it I can write I don't want to break it
but if I do I can replace that fairly
easily just go to the hitman store which
is illusions around here
just grab one off the shelf exactly
you're not out $1,000 right right and if
you break this this is artwork this is
art as well but this is this took much
this is a proto art well this one is a
only one the only Safari special that's
out there gorgeous gorgeous that's a
great piece you guys I'll take a picture
of it and I'll put it on my Instagram I
just promised that so I have to do it
which means you guys need to check out
my Instagram I'm running down insta so
you guys gotta check out my Instagram I
read genetics there are pictures of
these rigs on there why am i ringing
that's so weird that the MacBook is
ringing decline that [ __ ] alright so if
you're on a podcast put all your [ __ ] on
airplane mode that's that's my advice to
you where the shits were why I was
talking about rigs right all right dude
right on for bringing thousands of
dollars worth of glasses and table that
is freaking awesome I'm gonna have to
grab a torturers let's talk about the
bang so everybody I talked about dabbing
off the nail you guys I like the nail
because I can hook the titanium nail up
to the email the nails that I use are
usually titanium they go on to a male
joint that points up you drop the nail
on to there or you put your other dome
type nail inside there like our buddy
was talking about this dude decided to
flip back to the female joint because he
saw the trend of accessories and what
we're calling bangers coming out so
there's a guy everyone calls him qwave
but I think it's actually pronounced
khwab and I don't I'm not even sure if I
go back and forth on it on how I hear
you so qwave is more comfortable khwab
sounds a little fancier yeah so anyway
there's a guy named quad who made what
we call the banger it's got a male joint
that goes into your rig it's got a
female joint and then it comes straight
up and then it curves out to there are
multiple different angles available you
get it at 90 or 45 probably other angles
as well but then it's got just a basic
it looks like a small it looks like the
lid to your chapstick but it's clear
it's made out of quartz and so you heat
that [ __ ] up and then you let it cool
and you drop your dab in there and the
theory and I believe it is that the
quartz is giving a much cleaner more
flavorful hit
yes compared to the titanium and I
really agree with it my problem is I'm a
little clumsy and I I'm gonna break that
and you got to keep that a little bit
cleaner it's definitely more that
maintenance having a banger with a tie
you know you can get it real dirty and
then just get it hot and hit it with a
little brushes for the grill even almost
as little steel wool steel wool type
things right and get it fresh and clean
but with a banger once it gets dirty
it's a it's dirty and if you want to
keep it clean you got to do the it's got
to keep q-tip in it every time for every
youth q-tip Texans worth so that's a
banger you guys basically a banger is
made out of quartz a lot of were made
out of glass I don't see a problem with
davon Adam the glass piece but it's not
gonna taste as good it's not gonna last
as long it's gonna break after heating
and cooling so long the quartz is better
quality you can use anything quartz art
I definitely one of the two yeah and if
you're getting maybe ceramic the Halen
honey holes are great if you're going
for something made out of quartz the
Halen troughs are amazing and those are
also the quaff banger banger knockoffs
are cool if you trust your artist
neither vendor trust where your stuff is
coming from China / China that's where I
was heading up no China glass it's made
by little kids that aren't using proper
protection is there a difference in the
glass um it's really hard to tell but
yeah there is a definitely a difference
in there's quartz qualities and the
Chinese manufacturers are definitely
gonna be using much lower quality cords
as cheap as they can face cheap as they
can find because it's just some douche
over here trying to make money just
exploiting the market right and you're
definitely gonna find lower grade
Chinese made quartz is gonna be much
lower rate than american-made just like
titanium exactly because they sound like
a bunch of snobby douches when we talk
about getting a quality nail but that's
your health you're heating this product
up to I don't even know how many degrees
I don't have to burn the [ __ ] out of
yourself and you're putting your
medicine on there you're putting your
hash on there and you're smoking
directly into your lungs so whatever's
in that you're you're gonna dab it if
it's something that puts off some sort
of gas or has an oil on it or some kind
of [ __ ] you're gonna dab that right
along with your Earl so get a quality
nail that's super important to me
definitely yeah so q-tip tank kids have
done dabbing with your banger
you gotta heat that [ __ ]
clean it out with a q-tip right well you
don't even heat it the the in theory is
that if you get the good you get a good
temperature where it's not too hot so
you're done dab and you get your good
temperature you got to do it pretty much
immediately after you grab a q-tip you
wipe the inside there should be like a
little bit of a not a puddle but some
wetness in there you get it quick enough
it'll clean it out look good as new
you're good to go you don't even got to
heat it up like this nail for example I
was trying to do it this good nails
couple weeks old now all right you know
it's still yeah but on this one you can
see I have it in the q-tip check exactly
yeah that's always in there heating that
sure yeah if you take it out then you
can heat it up right after you dad
thought I work too but that's not gonna
that's also gonna like burn it and heat
like it burns it a little bit so the
q-tip tech is definitely like the ideal
I guess it's just okay so it's catching
on I saw you saying something on
Facebook about q-tip tech the q-tip
thing I'll have a problem the q-tip tech
it's these new q-tip holders as well I
find hilarious $300 glass to hold it in
there's there's some janky ones you'll
see going for like a hundred and fifty
dollars and it's literally it's
literally a shot glass for you people um
it's a shot glass that a glassblower
made and put some color on and some of
these guys are putting absolutely no
time into it you can tell and they put
him up Rotch and they go for like 150
there was one I will say the one that
started the whole hype on it was a a
two-stroke and sleek lab that they
posted and I think they kind of posted
it as a joke originally and then they
and then they got a ton of hype behind
it and so they decided to auction it off
and they went for $2,200 holy SH and I'm
not don't get me wrong I mean this [ __ ]
was amazing these two-stroke and sleek a
phenomenal glass artist and her work
goes I mean their work is expensive but
at the end of the day it was it was a
shot glass q-tip holders what they were
selling is the thing to hold q-tips you
know saying and yeah exactly but this
whole q-tip holder thing blew up
overnight it's insane you can do
something with that kind of money you
can do a lot of snow communities well
he's only $2,000 so 2222 okay 2200
though you can still 20 200 200 change
your day Oh change a week a lot of
people listening right now though fix
their whole damn car car would not I
have 2200 I would be straight right now
right
oh yeah I'm doing okay and I take 20
yeah all right so how long ago did you
make your first q-tip holders before
they got popular uh honestly like I
didn't make it as a q-tip holder when I
first started uh probably my first after
a month about being on the torch I was
working with shaping to make mini tubes
and I started making shot glasses slash
little nugs are things that was what we
what I was calling him and my shop mate
was calling me again nug jars you know
yeah yeah which is what they are and
then I took it home and I was like oh
look I can put q-tips in these haha it's
a q-tip holder it's a heady q-tip holder
and I had a buddy come in town and I was
showing him was like hey dude hoodie
q-tip holder haha and we joked about and
this was a solid two months ago maybe
month and a half even like and I have a
there's a bunch of my Instagram five
weeks old on my Instagram you can see it
on the table its I'm not lying
look YouTube's not trying to be that guy
but you know um and we me and my buddy
joked about it like oh that's so stupid
like haha like Hettie q-tip owner that
would never sell like that's just
another like if it did haha and sure
[ __ ] here we are a month and a half
later with $2,200 q-tip holders man
talking about another podcast whatever
you can still make them people are doing
it I just I hate jumping on the hype
train like that I'm just not I don't
like doing that and yeah but it's
whatever
hashtag q-tip Tech hashtag q-tip holder
Tech $2,200 oh he's gonna have to go
YouTube in and Instagram and so much
[ __ ] after this uh-huh so much stuff
alright so we talked about q-tip Tech I
should have asked you a long time ago
but the conversation was fun whose are
some of the glass bowlers that inspired
you that got you into glassblowing
uh this guy right here mongrel ass okay
definitely like my biggest he was my
biggest help getting involved in
everything personally oh yeah we're from
where he went to high school we didn't
go to the same high school but we in the
same County and I had a lot of mutual
friends in high school didn't know each
other in high school we both ended up
living in Asheville after high school
and I hit him up so I knew he was blown
glass oh hey man I'd love to come check
up studio cool you know blah blah blah
and he was like yeah sure went down the
studio a couple times hung out with him
hung out them at his house a couple
times you know got to become pretty
decent friends with him
bought some flats from him and then he
ended up moving out to Gunnison with
Brian's
don't know as I said preserve her glass
preserve glass he's working with
Berserker who was phenomenal and he's
he's a beast you guys definitely ought
to look at Berserker and check out the
dogs that he makes the bully animals
blitzkrieg blitz yes you're right really
close my bad yeah it's okay it's same
but let's be as bees and crazy noises
yeah but he Jack showed me a bunch of
things on the torched a couple years ago
it's about pie
three or four years ago now I guess kept
and touches them over the years then I
wanted to start doing it and he gave me
all the information I need to do has let
me come out to his studio here check him
out
so he's deadly my biggest he sold me my
first torch actually um biggest Hughes
done my biggest help getting into
glassblowing and as far as guys that
like you know inspire me and motivate me
and everything I mean you seen you seen
going he's definitely she's phenomenal
he's one of my favorites calm right here
definitely my favorite like sculpture
artist or I guess he's sort of school
for all artists but his birds are just
phenomenal I loved him I was real big
into elbow for a while when the elbow I
mean I was on the elbow bubble for a
while but everybody was everybody was
huge and it definitely I don't say it
pop but it definitely deflated a little
bit salt of course he was one of my
favorites back in the day you guys check
out salt that's not crazy dirty [ __ ]
yeah yeah and then um one of the books
my gosh I cannot remember the name of
right now I'm tripping slipping these
two books they're uh yeah it's really
before glass was a thing that he just
put smoked smoked out smoked Volume one
and two okay they're books full of glass
artists and everything it was before
there was really a glass scene type of
thing it was just kind of like this was
how you found there was no Instagram
this was later these were the heavy
artists at the time and anybody in that
book to I can't really member anyone
specific this was a while ago but that
but those books definitely were like
whoa this is kind of sparked you a
little bit stuck in your mind all right
yeah alright and degenerate art the
documentary that was the biggest I think
I watched that my freshman year in
college and I was already into glass
that's what we watched it but we were
more into me my roommate had a bunch of
roars we had like roars and 51/50 AMG's
much straight tube ok rippers exactly
what it was
and then we were like oh dude there's
movie but glass on here let's watch it
and that movie honestly I would say like
I'm gonna like change my life I didn't
opened me up to my eyes to the scene of
glasses I had no idea even existed I was
like holy hell this is crazy like this
is nuts did you get to meet Bob
Snodgrass at champs yes Bob Snyder's
that was really cool cool for me shut up
Bob Snodgrass man he's the man he's the
do G yeah you got father of modern day
glassblowing for sure it kind of did it
on accident oh yeah you know how he did
it yeah that's crazy yeah definitely
check out degenerate art if you have any
any interest in glass or art or just
culture in general anymore it's just a
really it's just a great great film if
you're into cannabis culture and yeah
looking for something that you want to
watch that's not just we like if your
girlfriend's coming over and you want to
watch something else that's a good one
that it's not just another weed movie
it's awesome and it's really cool with
that one because that was only four
years ago that that documentary was like
produced and made and um let out and
it's just crazy to see how far they've
last industry the market has come from
2011 to 2015 where in 2011 you know kind
of this underground scene that like
right there was nothing on it really
until this documentary came out and then
um you know like at the time in the
documentary I believe Scott Debbie his
most expensive piece at the time was
$18,000 like that's that's a crazy
amount of money obviously for a piece
but now Scott Debbie is selling pieces
for I mean 18 of 23,000 I mean that's
nothing that's everyday yeah he's got a
hundred thousand dollar pieces going out
so so what I wanted to ask you what
makes the market do that kind of [ __ ]
what makes an artist and the market jump
up and down and then like we said
earlier elbow the guy that makes a dyno
rigs he shot up huge for a little while
and then one day everyone's just selling
their elbows on Instagram for stupid
Chia
what makes [ __ ] go like that in the
glass market well I definitely think
what happened what Instagram definitely
helps I mean Instagram is a huge part of
like who's doing you know what who's
what in the glass world I guess if
they've got you know lots of followers
on there people are gonna think they're
like oil brothers for example Matt Bogle
and he's he's good he's really good but
his first rig that he put up for sale it
was a little coil pot of green mini rig
and it sold for like eight hundred
dollars at auction and it was like his
first rig that he ever sold
cuz yeah the hype thing but um I guess
with the market what happened was like
everybody all of a sudden started
getting into it and it built really fast
like it went from nothing to something
like in a year mothership prices were
quadrupling just because I really don't
know what it was it just become like it
people started finding out about it I
guess it wasn't all of a sudden an
underground thing that it was like you
know people had instagrams they get to
show their stuffs people were buying
more stuff okay and then everyone when
the market peaked everyone was like oh
man like kind of like a stock market
almost it's like a stock market crash if
you want to think about it like that
where you know everyone's like oh go
sell sell sell buy buy buy right yeah
and you know when mothership is like
now's the time to sell the mother ships
and so everybody sells their ships or I
guess elbow in this example everybody
had the bronto's and they were like my
number I bought mine for two thousand
dollars for example I bought it from
illusions two thousand dollars brand-new
sold it about six months later for
seventeen hundred dollars and I
struggled selling it for that you know
sand yeah and it was usually like knit
before that had no problem I definitely
bought mine at the peak of the the peak
of the height yeah it was like right
when I came down for vacation for the
first time a little rig yeah sweet
definitely loved that thing
yeah but uh but I think definitely
people they see what the rigs are going
for retail wise and so they're like okay
that's retail I'm gonna they put a high
price on it and it goes for a little bit
more and then eventually it's gonna
build up to a point and then people are
gonna be like [ __ ] that I'm not paying
that anymore
so the price will start going down and
then all of a sudden everybody starts to
sell their rigs trying to oh [ __ ] I got
rid of this now while they're still
still worth something
and then that and itself decrease she
appreciates the value a little bit yeah
so it's a little interesting it's funny
to see the mothership hype I saw the
mother ships girls roller coast one rig
the same rig went from 12 to 18 to 24 to
28 to 32 and now they're about 18 dude
there was a time when you could get I
mean clear clear ships we're going for
like 9 K at 1.5 K holy hell are you
kidding they're new ships one just sold
for $35,000 for the new trifecta it's uh
so mothership is known for the Klein the
Taurus and the fab egg and they combined
all three into one rig sandblasted it
and put some crazy logos on it sort of a
35,000
so sure Scott Debbie yeah he's doing all
right oh he's dealing big shout out to
the mothership if you want to see some
crazy glass you guys excuse me I'm all
choked up I'm getting something in my
throat here now if you want to see some
nice crazy glass some high-quality glass
go I just hit hashtag mothership
mothership appreciation mothership glass
any of that mothership glass you find it
will impress you that's amazing [ __ ]
especially those elites these and
everything the clear ones you guys are
three thousand dollars each
eighteen to 3018 hundred to three
thousand dollars the colored ones are
starting off about for one of the minis
you can get a mini four uh little minis
for twelve yeah yeah just the mini with
a little swing on it yeah
anything that's not a fixie you're
looking at twenty eight hundred eighteen
hundred minimum and up yeah so yeah that
does look like 1800 for just the rig no
buckets wink at nothing like that and
it's just all hype on names too oh yeah
holy crap how long is it gonna take for
you to climb your way up to the top
there oh I don't even know that's like
it if I ever get up there that would be
awesome but uh it's just really a matter
of I mean with the glass it's kind of
one of those who you know what not it is
definitely a lot of what you know but it
is a little bit of who you know to and
who you can sell to and I'm lucky enough
we're starting out I have friends from
like cuz I used to manage a shop back in
North Carolina a headshot back in North
Carolina for a little bit and so I've
made a little bit of connections through
that and I have a friend who just opened
up a shop in North Carolina transparent
dreams on Instagram check about you guys
North Carolina I think let's check it
out and then some of my old co-workers
have opened up shops so I've had outlets
to put my glass into nice from from from
the get-go which is really nice cuz I've
had one of my shop mates you know he's
he's definitely he said super ex shot me
it's not shot me anymore
he had some trouble selling his glasses
he's been doing it for two years and
he's like you know he struggled selling
cases and I'm here like two months in
and I was flipping flipping mini tubes
out the door and he's just yeah it's
just a lot of uh getting networking and
marketing for sure I got to hit one of
your mini to banger hangers the other
day little shredders yeah one of the
first ones you made an active mic over
there yeah yeah picture what's his new
Instagram name he's got a new name on it
team Wheaton 710 now yeah check him out
you guys teammate the 710 that's our
buddy Big Mike he's a good dude make
sure the whole garden of Weeden crew
time through team we deny mates yeah
that's a nice shirt I like that through
team Whedon I made so many good friends
oh yeah so much so yeah family I mean
that's how I met you nice all right guys
we've been going for over there over 30
minutes now um dude thank you for taking
some time out of your day to stop let's
start wrapping this up and then we're
gonna take some dad is it before we go
let's give some shout outs and talk
about some of my favorite glass blowers
I'm I don't buy it I like to look at it
let me be clear about that I don't pay
the money but I do appreciate the art
coil holy Shi is definitely one of my
favorites there's a his monkeys and his
little bananas that whole little series
is just very very cool very nice I don't
say simplistic but some of some of the
more simplistic stuff that he does is
some of my favorite stuff it's awesome
also if you're into that simplistic [ __ ]
if you like that real it's real stylish
but real simple SD Rhino or wine oil
condenser on Instagram check out SD
riots at SD rhino on Instagram one of my
favorites and also Bertoni yeah you can
tell I like that real bold color real oh
yeah that's the kind of stuff that I
like and of course there's Darby home
and like that yeah so I'm gonna go back
down this list we gotta give a shout out
to mongrel glass mongrel at mongrel I
think it's mongrel glass on Instagram
there you go and then combo is they just
called over there hundred scores in
there as far as I know it's just calm
but I think it is and whitey glass and
then if we're gonna talk about glass you
guys make sure you check out hit man
glass Dougie support hit man glass those
are some homies of mine berserker
blitzkrieg you Xin elbow salt and of
course Bobby Snodgrass you guys check
out Bob snob Snodgrass started at all if
you want to blow glass if you want to be
a glass blower you need to go check out
anything to do with Bob Snodgrass yeah
make sure you check out the movie the
name is leaving my head regenerate are
degenerate hearts he knew that I wanted
to see portal hustler for somebody that
was not it pipe classic movies on
YouTube to pipe classic on YouTube you
guys
is there a good YouTube channel or a way
for people to go learn how to blow glass
there's a great one Revere glass on
Instagram I'm sorry on YouTube they have
a whole channel and that is how I got my
start into it that's how most people
these days are getting started they have
like like 50 something videos and each
one's a little how-to video to do a
different little you know different
technique or something and they're
they're pretty cool dudes
Dustin Revere and Kevin foot I'm
actually does it do it heard of the
chair didn't realize that that's what
they did yeah they have a couple
different things they do and they're
it's pretty cool big shout out thanks to
those guys for teaching people all the
[ __ ] that they know cuz that is a huge
art oh yeah I want to give a big shout
out to somebody who will never hear this
but my buddy Ian ah I'm not even gonna
say his real name but he's in he's a
glassblower he's not on Instagram he's
not even like that he's kind of he
doesn't want notoriety he just wants to
make glass and be a glass artist but uh
that dude tried to teach me how to blow
glass and it wasn't his fault that I
couldn't learn it was totally my fault
there I'm good at several things and
blowing glasses is definitely not one of
them
I got a fiberoptic burn I burned my foot
I don't know how I burned my foot I
don't know what burned me inside and
burn my damn foot I am NOT meant to blow
that's all the people that can a
shout-out to Ian for trying to teach me
and shout-out to the raging glass crew
that tried to tolerate my dumb ass it
only took me like two attempts to
realize this is not for me yeah it's hot
you guys if you want to blow glass you
better yeah and you got to get in that
fire yep just get in there you gonna get
just there's no you can't hesitate no
stopping you keep going keep that
respect I understand why glass is so
expensive do an excellent all glass to
it in itself is expensive too that's a
big thing that people a lot of things I
think a lot of people don't think about
is sometimes you can get like a rod of
slime like a just a couple ounces of
slime just a single little color rod can
cost like 15 bucks or just a little
wrong yeah yeah and then how many Rhino
they break in they killed sometimes when
you make of those how many what
percentage of your work will break in
the kiln you know on a good day like
I'll get like 20% breakage but on an
average day it's like 50% it'll just be
like not as like in the kiln but it'll
like it'll break while I'm making it or
it'll some a piece of it'll break
to make a new piece like my bass will
break cuz acute angles will kill ya if
you have an acute angle on glass when it
when it cools down it cracks if the
seals not perfect there's air pockets
there's just so many little little
things that go into it right cools down
quicker than one piece if it's too thick
it's crazy those little details are the
things that the china glass that right
yes work exactly they were proper anneal
cycles they don't lose proper seal so
you could you know some of their seals
you could just push it with your thumb
and it'll fall off oh [ __ ] by American
glass you guys if you can support
American glass if you can support a
local artist support a local artist I
know I buy a hit man glass but there's a
reason for that Dougy is my homie they
kind of support what I do I support what
they do and they support the community
yes that's the he puts back in the
community so yeah he does support the
chalice festival it's gonna be freakin
huge this year's gonna be awesome
shout out to Doug for everything he's
been doing for the community I love it I
support it supports us it's also dude
cool ah man so let's wrap up the show do
don't think you can for coming do you
have anybody you want to give a shout
out to anything you want to say while
you're up is recorded and being put on
the sloppy told me to tell you to give a
give his mom a hug or you gave your mom
a hug like that there's that force
lobbying said he told me to tell you
that one big shout out to sloppy wood
okay call me coming back on the podcast
bro you were invited make sure you guys
follow oil Limpy and glass arts Mon nice
he is a sloppy is now taking a business
venture in the glass game so if you
doing quite well too who's got a solid
little bit of a head ease for sale nice
yeah yeah glass you guys check out our
buddy slop support the community
definitely tell him that you heard about
him to the girl from your heart podcast
and see if I can earn some Commission or
something on this what up yeah but out
to my buddy Blake my shot mate Blake
stay cheesy glass on Instagram he's been
a huge huge help ever since I started
blowing glass guess I should have talked
about him earlier but he's taught me a
good bit ever since I got into the
studio here in Pueblo nice yes big shut
up like I mentioned the champs you seem
like a cool bro I wish you could've been
here but that sounds like you're having
fun
he's doing it's doing it
I heard it
awesome well uh dude thanks a lot for
coming to talk about crass next time
we'll get you on and maybe you'll be
able to tell us a little bit about how
to love to do that nice nice you heard
it from him you guys so we'll get him
back here in a couple of weeks we'll set
up another podcast here in two or three
weeks while I'm talking about how to
blow glass just 30 minutes basics you
know we're not gonna get too in-depth
you guys if you burn yourselves I'm not
responsible either as well either is
we'll just make sure you know that you
get the burn cream fire somehow oh there
you go a chef want me to rub mustard on
it that s how it works sure maybe it's
just a what's that called a [ __ ] cool
Zeebo it works and it works if it works
it works there you go rub some mustard
on it I don't think everybody for
listening make sure you support all the
social media stuff make sure you follow
it find me on instagram under I read
genetics make sure you follow at
barefoot glass as if you want to see a
whole bunch of great glasgow fall all
the people I mentioned before I'm sure I
said it several times you're probably
done hearing it um I'm not gonna read
all that stuff that I normally read
because you're probably tired of hearing
it you probably know it all by now so
I'm just gonna wrap it up like this you
guys thanks again for listening I want
to give you a huge shout out to my ninja
spins shot it's my guest for joining me
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
right
you got me
[Music]
yeah
you got
[Music]
my friends and family we got my sister
my brother
ride on
[Music]
my brother ride on the Duggar buses
we gotta help my sister
my brother
[Music]
you