yeah what a podcast world it's your boy
Rasta Jeff coming to you with episode
number 106 of the girl from your heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation you guys I'm
coming to you with another show from the
car you guys have been traveling back
and forth between Colorado Springs and
Pueblo quite a bit lately and it's an
hour drive each direction so I've had a
lot of time to think and I have
definitely had some time to do some
recording so here I am on the microphone
traveling on the interstate it is
Wednesday November 18th I plan on
putting this episode out on Thursday the
19th so this is just gonna be a bonus
episode and I hope you guys enjoy it I
want to make a very special announcement
while I'm here
you guys as of yesterday around noon I
am no longer involved with the spot
dispensary I have severed all ties with
the spot dispensary I'm not employed by
them I am not affiliated with them and I
am not advertising for the spot in any
way any longer so I want to say goodbye
to the spot dispensary I don't work
there anymore it was fun but I've got to
do other things with myself um I have no
hard feelings or ill-will or any hatred
anything toward the spot I just need to
move on sometimes there are other
options in life that you need to follow
or need to pursue and that's what I'm
going to do with myself so that being
said let me make one more huge
announcement as of today around noon I
am officially the lead cultivator at
Green and healthy wellness in Colorado
Springs Colorado that's right you guys I
quit a job yesterday and I've got a new
job today so big shout out to hunt and
the Grammy Gatsby and the green and
healthy wellness crew a few weeks ago as
about two weeks ago when the owner of
green and healthy wellness gave me a
call and he said hey bro do you know
anybody that would be qualified to run a
large grow and I said yeah what you need
and he gave me a nice description of the
job and he told me what would be
required and I said you know I think I
want that job and he was like no way and
I was like not for real I want the job
because I'm not happy with what I'm
doing so we talked about it for a couple
of weeks I drove up and checked out the
grow I've spent a lot of time in the
grow a lot of time with the crew and it
is a go you guys this is where I need to
be I need to be working at Green and
healthy wellness
with hunt with damsel with Randall's I
need to be there it's part of the team
so team dreadlocks is getting a little
bit stronger shout out to green and
healthy wellness for having faith in me
and giving me the opportunity to be the
lead grower you guys I'm going to be the
one producing all of the medicine for
their medical marijuana shop and
Colorado Springs so if you're a medical
patient look forward to we should have a
harvest coming down mid February ish is
what I have planned in my vision
so around March around March first to
st. Patrick's Day ish we should have
some Rasta Jeff grown flowers available
for the medical patients at Green and
healthy wellness in Colorado Springs
Colorado now I want to kind of elaborate
here you guys I want to let you know why
I quit the spot and let you know what's
going on cuz I don't want you to think
that I hate the spot or than anything
shitty happened I've been at the spot
since the middle of July and we have
been building and getting things
finalized and there is no sign of having
plants in that building for at least
another month or two and I am not I'm
not a plumber I'm not a construction
worker I can do basic things but I've
been trying to find stuff to keep me
busy for 40 hours a week in the spot for
the past month and there's nothing to do
and without plants in there I've been
going crazy you guys the building is not
ready for plants they're not ready to
cultivate I was expected to be there and
perform so it was hard to be there
everyday with nothing to do it was
making me super anxious I was making me
bored I was spending way too much time
on social media because I was bored at
the shop so when my buddy hunt called
and said hey we need help here at green
and healthy it felt like the right thing
to do to jump on and be part of the team
at the spot they run hydro it's a big
huge hydro set up I am NOT a hydro
grower I am a soil farmer at the green
and healthy grow we're running three
gallon pots of soilless mix with plants
already in the building they're our
plants they're waiting for me so Friday
I'm going to move plants to the
flowering room and I'm going to give
them a little bit of time to veg in the
flower room in their new home
in about 10 to 14 days after that I plan
to flower the first crop for green and
healthy wellness so I'm leaving a
facility that will not have plants until
my first harvest at my new facility is
finished is what it feels like and I'm
in it to grow you guys that's what I'm
here for I want to grow and produce
quality cannabis so I had to make a move
I had to make a huge move this is an
hour drive to and from work every single
day but you know what it's a soil garden
with my homies with a grimy Gatsby and
dude it's damsel and John Randall's jr.
so in my mind this is the right decision
sometimes you gotta just you got to make
a move that scares you you got to make a
move that puts you on the spot you got
to make a move that breaks you out of
your routine and I feel like my life has
really been routine for the past couple
of years and shaking myself up like this
really puts it lights a new fire under
my ass so to speak it puts fresh ideas
in my head I find a new inspiration I
meet new people I go new places I really
improves my life overall when I put
myself in a uncomfortable position when
I break out of my comfort bubble and put
myself in a position where I'm not
exactly sure how this is gonna play out
it always works very well for myself so
if you guys are scared to do something
if there's something you're thinking
about doing if there's a big change in
your life that you're thinking about
making all I can say is grab your balls
and do it just do it don't be afraid
success is scary but once you succeed
and you see what it's like to succeed
and not fall down from that all you're
gonna do is want to succeed more and
more and more your goals are gonna get
bigger your dreams are gonna get bigger
your abilities to reach those dreams
will get bigger right alongside all of
that so if you're afraid of something
don't be scared you guys you can [ __ ]
do it and what's gonna happen you're
gonna try and you're either gonna
succeed or you're gonna fail if you fail
you're gonna be right where you are
you're not gonna go backwards by failing
because trying something is going to
give you skills you're gonna at least be
trying something you're gonna feel
better and if you succeed holy [ __ ] you
just succeeded it's something you just
opened a new door to your life you just
have a new thing you can do or somewhere
else you can go and what is that gonna
do that's gonna be a building block for
the next places you can go and the next
things you can do so if you're scared if
you're stuck in your comfort zone if
you're stuck in your little bubble you
guys all
I can say is snap out of that and try to
do some new things I have some faith in
the world have some faith in yourself
have some faith in life even if you're
not a spiritual or a religious person
you can have some confidence you can
have some some I guess faith is what you
need to have and don't have fear of
failing your life if your life is good
right now and you try something and you
fail you're still gonna have the life
you've got nobody's gonna take it away
from you because you messed up trying
something new and anybody that does talk
[ __ ] to you and disrespects you because
you tried something new and you failed
they are not your friend
your friends are gonna support you
through your failures your friends are
gonna say man that looks like a
challenging task to try to do and I'm
proud of you just for getting off your
ass and trying it because 75% of the
people that are out there wouldn't even
have gotten off their asses to attempt
what you just failed at so don't be
afraid to fail you got to try some [ __ ]
you guys I guess that's my inspirational
talk for the day that was my
announcement for the day I am driving
down i-20 five on a beautiful damn
Wednesday it is so gorgeous out here
there's not a cloud in the sky I can see
for a hundred miles I can see Pikes Peak
I can see the wet mountains it is such a
gorgeous day so guys get outside suck up
some sunshine the winter is coming we
should talk about how to prepare your
Grove for the winter I guess pretty soon
here so that's some good [ __ ] to talk
about you guys I'm getting out of here I
feel like I'm rambling into this
microphone I hope everybody has a
wonderful day
smoke some great cannabis smoke some
good hash love one another don't be
afraid to reach your goals and until
next time you guys take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]