[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back Han of his community
it's time for episode number 107 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right appear a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're an old-school smoker or a
hardcore dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or someone who's just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you I'm
your host my friends call me Rasta Jeff
want to thank you guys for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band a big shout out to cat kun
and the entire mystic roots crew what's
up everybody hope you guys are having a
wonderful evening a wonderful morning
wonderful afternoon whatever time it is
no matter what no matter where you are
no matter what your gonna hope you're
smoking something tasty hope you got a
fat dab I hope you got a joint rolled
hope you got something like that going
on we're coming to you on November 19
sitting across the table from you
joining us again is our good buddy white
Mike how you doing today bro doing good
man good thanks for asking I'm gonna put
this microphone a little more at your
face there you go just get the words
into it a little more get back in our
rhythm yes yes I'm gonna drop this music
out a little bit and we will get down to
business how you doing today bro don't
all right thanks for coming thanks for
taking time away from the new youngster
to come see me he's sleeping right now
so I get some away time
I hear he's had a little head cold so I
hope the little dude gets better really
soon yeah he's on the mend I hope you
didn't share it with everybody
all right you guys if you're listening
take your vitamins so that you don't
take your vitamins take some emergency
wait nobody pays me you take take those
yeah if you have a vitamin company that
would like to sponsor a podcast do you
know how to find me shoutout to not
getting sick
yes shoutout to good health you guys
take good care of yourself make sure you
hydrate if you're dabbing and smoking a
bunch of cannabis or a bunch of hash or
eating edibles or whatever you're doing
you need to hydrate drink more water
most of us are dehydrated anyway
skip that soda drink a bottle of water I
know it sounds crazy it's ludicrous
hydrate it's good for you it's really
good for you all right you guys I need
to mention something I put out an
episode number one
six went up on stitcher on Thursday we
actually went up today Thursday the 19th
and for some reason stitcher is failing
on picking it up it's only got one
second of the show posted so I've
emailed stitcher and let them know that
there's an issue usually stitcher just
goes and corrects it really quickly the
show is it's available on iTunes it's
available on my website I read genetics
Colorado com
for some reason it did not work on
stitcher it's stitchers problem I can
tell because it's playing on my iPhone
it's playing on my computer I just will
not play through stitcher so I apologize
if you guys did not get to hear episode
106 I made a very special and a very
important announcement I recorded the
podcast from my car while I was driving
so it's one of those and you do want to
listen to it
so if you're a stitcher listener and you
have not gotten to hear episode number
106 with a very special announcement I
encourage you to either go to my website
or go to iTunes and check out episode
number 106 it's I read genetics Colorado
com click on the girl from your heart a
podcast tab and it'll be right there
number 106 very special announcement
give that a listen I think you will
appreciate what I had to say I do
apologize for stitcher not picking up
the episode I've emailed them I just
gotta wait for them to fix it that's
pretty much what we can do all right I
got to reach for my phone I've got one
more thing I want to talk about before
we start getting down to the heart of
the show guys I got a screenshot of
something um so we put a lot of work
into this podcast I take time out of my
day to take time out of my life Mike
takes time away from his family to come
over here and record Mike works 40
something hours a week in the spot so
getting him to come over for an hour is
actually a little effort I got an email
that makes all of our time all of our
effort worthwhile these are the emails
that really make it worth putting in the
energy so this came from somebody will
just call it Mike oh and he says the
podcast is great best show I've listened
best show and I've listened to them all
hoping you will do more shows with
longer content like the earlier episodes
I would like to see a pest management
episode and more BHO shows I'm in
Michigan and took a 10-year hiatus from
growing after cloning the [ __ ] out of
super skunk seed smuggled back from
Amsterdam in 93 [ __ ] sure changed since
oh four had to learn about hair he lists
a bunch of stuff he had to learn about
and then he keeps her going for a minute
he says I've listened to
all the grow shows Adam Dunn dude grows
Kyle kushman and then he says yours is
the best by far great mix of knowledge
humor and irreverence in a very easy to
listen to style I'm almost done re
listening to the entire series again
great job brother man I'll do a dab for
you signed Mike dude good thanks Mike
that's awesome that is awesome he says
we are the best podcast I'm not trying
to compete with anybody but if I'm being
called the best then that is [ __ ]
awesome I appreciate that Mike thanks
for listening to the podcast the email
is turned off over here this email coil
needs to be replaced but when we do it
dab the next tab that we do is for Mike
and I've got I get plenty of emails like
that but it was time to read one on the
air and say dude check this out this is
what comes I probably get an email or a
text message or an Instagram message or
a Facebook message once a day saying
thanks for the podcast so that kind of
stuff makes it all worth the time and
energy and effort that we do to put in
this podcast thank you guys real listen
that's what I'm trying to say it thanks
for the email if you want to send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear what you
have to say what I would really
appreciate is if you go to iTunes go to
the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast find the review
section give me a five star review and
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show that would be really
cool what that does is moves us up in
the ranks and iTunes and that exposes us
to more listeners and then more
listeners will grow better ganja more
people will help us liberate cannabis
it's a good thing so give me a little
review let me know what you think I
would appreciate that I'm gonna sneeze
didn't happen we talked about it scared
it away alright so we do have a real
topic we want to talk about here but I
want to talk about one more thing since
uh since Mike is a little familiar with
this region of life I got the privilege
on Monday morning of going to jury duty
at 8 a.m. on a cold ass Monday yep I got
lucky the last time I to do it was
during the summer at least I wasn't cold
right yeah you gotta be there bright and
early and it's [ __ ] cold and wet it
was so windy was one of the windiest
days of the year that's crazy you had
jury duty I'm really nasty yeah it was
weird because the the courtroom has
skylight sort of windows that are kind
of tinted behind the judge and they were
changing from black to baby blue to
black
with the weather every like 10 minutes I
was like holy [ __ ] what's going on
outside that was crazy
so I had jury duty and obviously I was
not selected I have never selected to be
a part of the jury I get down to when
they start asking questions and they're
like oh you can go home but uh I went in
there with a certain thing in mind of
what I was going to see and experience
and how I was gonna handle [ __ ] and it
was nothing like what I expected no it's
it's not at all like it appears on
television exactly and the chairs are
just isn't comfortable as they appear on
television if not significantly more so
but other than that very few
similarities it was like they were mad
at us and made us sit in shitty church
pews it when you're in them it feels
like it was designed to punish everyone
that was selected significantly yes so
Wow the thing that stood out the most to
me I'm afraid of judges just straight-up
a judge can say you are going to jail
and you get to do some time in jail you
get to go get but poke for a little bit
and there's nothing you can do about it
yeah the judge that resided over that
courtroom was cool as [ __ ] like I don't
know the judge personally but he
presented himself fairly I didn't feel
like he was passing judgment on anybody
by the way they looked he treated the
guys in suits and the lady in her sweat
pants exactly the same he was kind
everybody who was respectful and he was
a human about things I figured it was
gonna be rigorous in like the time
everything would be on a certain time
schedule and stuff and he went for a
little bit of time and he goes does
anybody need to use a restroom or
anything can we wait another 15 minutes
and everyone's like I can wait 15 he's
like okay we'll go in 15 minutes you
guys don't worry and he looked up the
clock oh sorry it's been about 20
minutes you guys let's go use the
restroom we'll take 15 and like he was
actually pretty cool so you know they're
at this point for the most part it runs
like it should like it's much more
functional in I don't know human that a
lot of people assume I know judges like
I've met many of them is right there are
people too and that's what I said Mike's
a little more in that realm Mike has
experience in that side of life and I uh
I'm the dreadlock I I've got dreadlocks
to my ass I got red eyes
I smell like cannabis most of the time I
try to avoid those types of folks but
you know now things are
engine I'm gonna have to mingle and rub
some elbows with those types of people
but the judge was very fair I did not
feel intimidated I didn't feel afraid it
was really cool it may have given me a
touch of faith in our system maybe a
touch more it's nice to know that
there's at least humans involved like
we've seen it from just the juror
selection part they didn't kick us out
they didn't kick out the rejected jurors
until all of the jurors had been chosen
so that they knew that there were enough
in the pool and I got to watch the
selection process and I got to watch all
of the jurors to be interviewed and then
at the end of that the two lawyers the
prosecutor the prosecution and the
defense pass back and forth a piece of
paper and they agree on which people are
gonna be the jurors and I was laughing
is like it's like fantasy football for
the Warriors or something yep and
they're like I'll trade you the angry
white guy for the passive white lady and
like I could just see him negotiating I
knew who was gonna go home I was like
they're gonna get rid of that guy like
he's too angry and he's too mad he wants
this guy to go to jail before he's even
heard the case we the last two times I
went the the first time I got let go
before any of that started even I never
even made it to the courtroom they
called it all but like 20 of us and like
the rest you know like just no ceremony
but we didn't have to sign out or
nothing they don't care the first time I
went that's what happened there was a
case that we were gonna see that day and
the lady that was supposed to be in that
case committed another crime and it been
reading to jail and was gonna be retried
for all of her [ __ ] so yeah she got me
at a jury duty that day but she [ __ ]
up her life and then the last time they
uh they got down to like 30 people that
they liked and they just waved that the
rest of us when I go home and so we all
got to go home at lunch which was nice
but it's oh my god had friends that have
selected and served on juries and it's a
hell of an experience you know since uh
you guys if you did not listen to
episode number 106 I no longer work at
the spot dispensary I just wanted to put
that out there I quit the spot I know
work at Green and healthy wellness in
Colorado Springs quick update yeah quick
update just since 106 may have been
unlistenable on some devices um yeah I
quit the spot guys I'm sorry I had to do
that I work at Green and healthy
wellness I'm now the grower there it's
in Colorado Springs we're gonna crush it
check out to hunt but I was in jury duty
and I'm sitting here thinking
I don't have to work tomorrow ain't got
[ __ ] to do I wouldn't mind being
selected for a case it would have been
kind of fun it would have been a very
learning experience for myself yeah I
hate to imagine it but now if I'm ever
in court I know how it goes yep and I've
got a little experience it's I'm not
gonna [ __ ] my pants the first time um I
want to invite Mike while he's sitting
here in friend me we'll get a commitment
out of him you guys I want you to come
to an episode with me about how to deal
with you how to conduct yourself with a
law enforcement oh sure whether you're
being pulled over whether they come to
your home whether you're in public
whether you're at a smoking event I'd
like to get you and we'll get somebody
else on the show too I have a good idea
of who we're gonna get on the show I
think we're gonna get sloppy and you on
the show because that's that that'll
make for a really interesting show
that's for sure yes sloppy you're
invited we have such different exactly
experiences with law enforcement yes
yeah yeah and I want to get both you
guys on the show and we can talk about
how to deal we'll talk about how to deal
with the law enforcement and not get
your ass thrown in jail all right guys
so I must have blown a couple of dabs
into the computer because as I was
saying that part about the judge it
totally just quit recording here here we
got too high the computer is too dabbed
out something went wrong that means that
we're gonna have to start running an
auxilary output from the the USB down
here or the mixer into the h6 and do or
record this [ __ ] in case that happens
again and then I can just keep recording
the h6 would have kept going nice yeah
or we'll go get a little Roland handheld
recorder and use the headphone out on
the mixer and then just run that into
the handheld recorder and that just
records onto an SD card so there's no
failure the age six would work
the handheld would work we'll do
something like that as a back-up plan or
we can just take a DAB when it fails and
come back a couple of minutes later and
explain that we just had a major
technical failure here yeah I like the
third option that seems simplest it's
the cheapest y'all were wondering like
what kind of equipment we're doing the
show with Jeff's got a pile of equipment
that's larger than your car well this is
the home setup this is where this is so
that you can get the voice like there is
a cast that's that's what that's what is
for all this but home based versions
pretty elaborate yeah yeah yeah the to
go version is the size of a big cell
phone basically yeah when you hear me
recording the Morrises cell phone maybe
yeah Zack Morris is older cell phone
that's the truth we just went [ __ ]
Saved by the Bell on this [ __ ] all right
you guys the program crashed we had to
restart it I just give you the trash
didn't had to restart that's the truth
that is the truth
I just given a shout out to the judge
that resided over that courtroom I felt
that it was fair I liked the way he
treated people I don't know how much of
that got recorded but I went to jury
duty you guys it wasn't that bad that
judge was cool it was fair I wanted to
move on from that and keep going while
the computer is working that email said
that they wish I'd do more girl lessons
ah that'll come you guys I'm working on
it I don't know if that got recorded in
the part before so we may have just
don't talk to that part if my girl
lessons are coming yes
um so let's get to the beauty of us and
ask us what you want us to talk about
[Music]
the appropriate people I don't know if
we're double talking so I don't know how
much that made it to the recording but
that's the truth you guys gonna find out
if you want more grow lessons all you
gotta do is let me know what you want to
learn about send me an email to grow a
free heart I'll calm you can tweet me
it's @gf wih podcast you can find me on
Facebook you can send me a text message
you can that's all one memory file that
was funny did you like how that went
yeah almost like a Tourette's spasm
footage I'm sorry I don't mean to make
fun of people
so I've got you guys want more girl
lessons and should I understand you guys
would like the listener that sent me the
email said that he would like more
lessons on BHO and he was like a
pesticide issue or episode we will get
our friend Sean over here as soon as I
can get him back and we will do an
organic pesticide management episode and
then I need to find ourselves some hash
experts and we will do some hash
episodes I'm not a hash expert you guys
said it's not me
Spence is a busy [ __ ] so getting
him to come over here is gonna cost me
like 50 bucks an hour to get him to come
record all the time but we'll get a hash
expert we'll get him to come on the show
let's get down to the point of the show
you guys we're gonna go in for 15
minutes and all we've done is talk a
bunch of nonsense um we've been covering
this a little bit lately I've got three
news articles I'm going to read the
headline two and then we're gonna skip
all of that and then we're gonna go to
the main article that I want to talk
about but this is kind of a little bit
of a build-up on the on the website
called the cannabis twitch is where I
find a lot of my news big shout out to
David McCoy and Ricardo Baca for
supplying the world with up-to-date
cannabis news from Colorado I found an
article this one was written on November
13th and it says pesticide edict ensures
fate of recalled
for pot products the byline is nearly
30,000 marijuana infused products
recalled over pesticide concerns will
likely be destroyed after Hickenlooper
says their public safety risk here's
another article just in the headline you
guys is all I'm gonna read this one once
again was in the cannabis that says
denver-based lab 710 recalls pot
products / pesticides and then the
byline is in the state's eighth pot
recall in 10 months lab 710 concentrates
calls back two thousand three hundred
and sixty two packages of marijuana
concentrates and then here is the third
one that I want to read the headline -
it says denver issues this one was
written on November 18th once again by
Ricardo Baca and David McCoy of the
cannabis it says denver issues ninth pot
product recall in ten weeks then the
byline is edibles company guys garden
issues its second voluntary recall in as
many weeks after banned pesticides are
detected in products you guys this is an
upsetting trend we've been seeing here
in colorado in the commercial growing
industry I do not depends on your
perspective okay is it's I'd I really
hate that we're finding pesticides and
final product but I'm so thrilled that
we're finding pesticides and final
product like it's this weird duality yes
this is regulation working this is when
you you go to the store and you buy a
product you know there's not pesticides
in it and now that cannabis is legal
we're a year or so from having all of
that testing in place so that you know
there's no bug [ __ ] there's no pesticide
there's no mold or mildew you're just
getting delicious concentrates so it
sucks that they're fighting it's but
it's awesome that they're finding it
right because now we can stop it we can
start teaching the growers and the grow
facilities have to stop using these
products I much in the future I predict
that the Department of Agriculture is
going to create a pesticide class for
the cannabis industry they're gonna have
to do it yep it's gonna have to happen
they're going to have to make their own
regulations because that's who's doing
this they're gonna have to tell us what
we can and can't do they kind of are now
all that stuff from the ground up like
it exists in every other industry but
we're not allowed to access any of the
components that
do this for like cantaloupe or tobacco
or right beer because cannabis is
federally illegal so we're not allowed
to federally test so no we can't find
all over labs that are doing the testing
were created by the demand the medical
industry created here like all of the
labs that are up and running around the
state came from the Medical Marijuana
days and they weren't state mandated the
industry demanded them and created them
on their own and when they do testing
labs want to apply for DEA licensing
like they should they all got raided so
they stopped applying for DEA licensing
and just ran a testing lab anyway with
just without that federal certification
meaning that they can't do like organics
testing or certifying or anything like
that because that's all federal right
shot at this detail halen Labs yep
actually I don't think organic testing
is actually federal I've been
regulations for using that word are okay
that makes sense recently if you're a
legal marijuana business and you had
organics in your name you had to change
a little bit yep what you guys gonna do
alright so let's talk about this article
a little bit you guys it seems to be a
trend in Colorado that a lot of the
commercial growers are using pesticides
that have been banned and that sounds
ridiculous but oftentimes these products
were sprayed on the plants 70 days ago
and these rules came into effect 20 days
ago so you can't retroactively lis
unsprayed your plants you can't go back
and that's basically what we're seeing
plants that were harvested six months
ago and turned into other Earth's sold
off and turned into other products like
edibles and concentrates you know I
didn't come in two more months ago I
didn't account for the time from so
you've got to grow these plant they got
a veg they've got to flower you're
looking at 90 to 120 days there it's got
to be harvested they've got to be
trimmed and dried and cured you're
looking another two weeks there is your
140 days ish somewhere between 120 and a
hundred and fifty days by now yep right
that's engineer math right and then the
product has to be picked up by the
infusion company the mips whoever's
gonna turn it into something the
processing facility like it I mean then
you've got drying and curing too so
that's what that's what got us to about
150 but like yeah we're still rolling on
almost 200 days for
today's 250 - yeah before it's even
processed okay but I mean it wasn't
standard practice for the company buying
the product - lab test it again right
and that's one of the things that these
recalls are starting to create is the
first company to really fail that was
the first big policy change they
announced was we're gonna test
everything that comes in now because
that's how this happened yeah they
process really nasty stuff and we
probably dab some of it it could happen
and you guys a lot of people did none of
these recalls have been issued because
people got sick or anything like that
it's right industry-wide they're all
voluntary when they're going through and
doing lab testing when one of their
products fails they just do a massive
recall on anything with that serial
number which is admirable because that's
a lot of money that these guys are
losing that's tons of money tons of
money I just measured money and weight
tons of money yes dollar amounts and
weight so these plants could have been
sprayed 200 days ago and these rules
just were put into effect whenever 30
days ago 45 days ago and so it's not
like people are [ __ ] up on purpose
it's not like it's ignorance it's just
it's just timing of laws in a lot of the
places something that I want to mention
is all that we do used to smoke back in
the day before we had dispensaries it
was being sprayed with some [ __ ] there
was something at worse than what's
happening in these dispensaries on your
weed you've smoked it before it's
quality control is one of the first
things legal marijuana created as a side
industry and it's been a beautiful thing
you know I saw a quality go when medical
came real popular around 2010 quality
skyrocketed yep there was a huge
competition for quality buds and then
around 2013 2014 the quality started
going away and the quantity started
popping up now everything looks the same
everything looks real similar yep I'm
gonna try to uh to make that different
in a green and healthy wellness we've
got some fun we got we got fire genetics
and I know how to grow so I'm gonna try
to bring that quality back to the Shelf
cream and healthy wellness I can't wait
yeah I keep looking back at the
recording software to make sure we're
getting what we're saying because we
can't afford to try to do this all over
again that was weird right
alright so we're talking a lot about
these
tainted products this brings me to an
email or an email a news article I wish
there was an email that would've been
great this one Mike sent this to me from
The Denver Post right on Mike for
finding us the good news the headline is
Hickenlooper issues executive order to
declare a tainted pot a threat to the
public the byline is any marijuana grown
with unapproved pesticides would be
removed from commerce and destroyed once
again the articles from David McGowan
and Ricardo Baca and it goes a little
bit like this I need to take a drink
because I am dried up then I'll read you
the article Mike say something
impressive oh okay basically this story
just to save Jeff the effort of reading
a long letter from the governor any
marijuana grown with an unapproved
pesticide is now a threat to public
safety just sort of by default so any
but any grow that's got a not unapproved
pesticide use going on and that grow is
currently scrambling to figure out new
pest management protocols because the
rule in this that's gonna really throw
shockwaves through the industry is right
now cannabis is federally illegal and to
sell a pesticide in the United States
you need a federal certification and
approval I mean your product has to be
tested for all kinds of stuff because
it's being sprayed I'm God knows what
around God knows who so it every
pesticide comes with a lot of really
specific rules about how they can and
can't be used and what they can and
can't be used on and cannabis right now
isn't on any of those labels and what
the governor just said was if cannabis
isn't on the label specifically you
can't use it to grow marijuana legally
in Colorado and nobody's gonna put
marijuana on there or cannabis or they
got just because it's illegal yeah there
is a caveat there's some some pesticides
have they're super safe you can use them
on anything and they have it a
standardized phrase for that that'll be
on the label and if the pesticide
carries that specific use designation
then it can be used on cannabis so it's
not like we can't use anything
in this industry but I guarantee there
are countless grows around Colorado that
have been using stuff that's perfectly
acceptable for tobacco or flowers or
food and has been used on cannabis for a
decade or more around the country
everywhere just as common practice right
that are scrambling right now to figure
out what they're gonna replace that
product with it's gonna make a huge
difference for a lot of growers so
there's a timeline here and I will read
part of the article you guys I might try
to sum it up for us but I'll read a
bunch of it there's a timeline off to
the right of the artist a lot that's
what I was thinking about thank you
thank you I needed a little bit of
hydration so that helped out there's a
timeline here and it says on September
7th months after marijuana holds post
post tests find pesticides in products
and that was on September 7th September
8th Denver recalls mahatma pot extracts
containing unapproved pesticides and
then on the 18th denver issues two more
recalls and it keeps going ah let's see
colorado proposes stricter rules pot
products made with unapproved pesticides
recalled on October 18th Colorado puts
what that's not a real word
it's just abbreviated stuff on industry
to use pesticides that are safe on pot
and then on the 21st Nature's Cure of
Denver recalls pop products containing
pesticides then it just keeps going you
guys so there are a bunch of incidents
of these pesticides on cannabis we're
gonna keep seeing it and then they think
it'll taper off in the middle of next
year
it should by summer of next year by
spring of next year all this [ __ ] should
be settled everybody should be
well-educated on what they can and can't
use all the tainted herbs should be gone
some of the problem here is we don't
have enough testing labs so if you're
looking to invest in a fun sized but
side business call us we want you to be
able to test for residual solvents and
hash we need you to be able to test for
pesticides and flowers we need you to be
able to test for molds and pathogens and
our flowers we need ecoli testing in the
buds yeah all we need all the to potency
testing reliable potency testing yep we
need it all alright let's read part of
the article I know Mike tried to sum it
up but it goes like this
Governor John Hickenlooper on Thursday
issued an executive order telling state
agencies that any marijuana grown with
unapproved pesticides is a threat to
public safety and should be
moved from commerce and destroyed the
order is hickenlooper x' first word on a
months old controversy over pesticide
used to grow cannabis and a more
aggressive approach to then half a dozen
recalls by denver health officials have
put on thousands of contaminated
products some of it later allowed back
into commerce sorry you guys that was
hard to read there's a really long
sentence that whole paragraph is one
sentence and i didn't have a good rythm
sorry I made it walking for you the tech
issues are the dad's after but it
definitely [ __ ] with my rhythm little
from column a that's the truth the
article goes on to say the order
effectively immediately was the result
of a collaboration with officials from
several state agencies the Department of
Agriculture Revenue and Public Health
and Environment among them and provides
much-needed clarity on the use of pet
use of pesticides and how agencies
should treat them according to a joint
announcement a joint announcement right
haha it says when the pesticide is
applied to a crop in a manner that is
inconsistent with the pesticides label
and the crop is contaminated by that
pesticide it constitutes a threat to
public safety the order says the order
says agencies agencies should use all
investigative and enforcement authority
to end the threat including but not
limited to placing contaminated
marijuana on administrative hold and
destroying contaminated marijuana
pursuant to existing law industry
spokespersons spokespersons got my words
are hard industry spokespersons could
not be immediately reached for comment
late Thursday the order comes from
Denver Post stories that showed how
potentially harmful pesticides barred
for use on cannabis we're still being
applied and fought at high
concentrations in products sold to
customers if the Denver Post is taking
full credit for this executive order
that's what yeah that's what that
sounded like
thanks for point a pers love it when
they can say we reported something and
then change happened at a state level
because of it and so this is a huge
feather in their cap
they've just been buying up random
product to dispensaries and taking it to
testing labs who's gonna say that the
westward started that part of it they
the westward in the Denver Post both
hammered the edibles industry a couple
of years ago
over potency issues and then they
started doing contaminants tests or the
poster - doing contaminants testing and
it's definitely sent shockwaves through
the industry it's definitely caused
change to state level so they're running
around like they scored because they
[ __ ] scored and they kind of did um
and it's been a good smack for the legal
industry I think like there was a little
bit of shenanigans like we brought a lot
of the black market stuff with us and
eventually we were gonna step up enough
to where we had to play by the same
rules everybody else did and we've
passed that point in Colorado now
significantly and so a lot of the things
that happen at every employer now could
be happening throughout the marijuana
industry and some of that lab testing
some of that's recalls and it's about
time it happened it is it is alright
I'll keep going with the article it says
where was I I wanted to give a shout out
to Claude the Candyman we're talking
about edibles shots - Claude the
Candyman dude you're on an adventure of
a lifetime you're probably not gonna
hear this podcast but uh Claude is
taking a personal vacation and I've seen
his facebook pictures the dude has never
had a bigger smile he's making a life
change and Claude a proud Ebro big shout
out support sweet stone candy that's
what made me think he needs a shout-out
on the show so it goes on to say the
post also identified how state laws that
barred use of certain pesticides were
not enforced and the testing
requirements for pesticide residues were
set aside and then it says a threat to
safety
Thursday's bulletin specifically
mandates state agencies to determine any
off-label use of a pesticides a threat
to public safety and ensure that the
contaminated products are quarantined
and destroyed oh that's a bunch of hash
and pot you're just gonna watch it just
destroyed I'm wondering how high the
animals to landfilling Amanda I think
you just gonna burn it like back in the
day the fire department used to just put
all the bales of weed in the fire they
still do that all over the place and
every now and then they [ __ ] it up and
get the whole town really high yeah but
I don't know maybe I think it's just
gonna get blended with dirt is what it's
probably gonna happens with it that's
kind of what happens at a dispensary if
you run a soil grow and you got to throw
leaves away
you do like lasagna you do leaves dirt
leaves dirt just mash it up yep all
right
the article goes on to say Thursday's
bulletin specifically meant in a way I
just read that part that is that is a
stiffer approach in the quantity
quarantines and recalls Denver health
officials have put on marijuana products
contaminated with unapproved pesticides
in most cases the products were allowed
back into commerce once tests confirmed
pesticide residues were at levels lower
than what's allowed on other consumable
crops Hickenlooper zorder appears to
leave no room for trace amounts and
recalls for the destruction of the
affected plants and any derivative
products zero no trace elements so if
they used any pesticide they find it on
there pretty much bye-bye to your whole
product line if they use some of this
stuff I mean years ago they could be
destroying breeding stock or I mean how
many this is most of the recalls are
stem from a couple of bigger grows that
wholesale off dried flower to other
companies to make edibles or hash with
and so that's it's the people that
bought it that are now issuing recalls
is they go through and they're like wait
[ __ ] we bought 80 pounds of that and we
make chocolate bars so we threw that 80
pounds in with a thousand other pounds
we bought and we made butter out of that
and then we've made edibles and now
we've got to recall all the edible
batches with those serial numbers on
those it's huge ripples through the
industry ouch we're gonna see lab
testing at every level we're gonna see
the labs triple or quadruple the number
across the state to handle all the
testing that's gonna have to take place
I wouldn't be surprised to see little
spike in price of a buck or two for
whatever price all this [ __ ] cost
because yeah it's gonna play into a bit
more crime I'm happy to buy stuff in the
legal industry because I know that this
stuff's coming out yeah yeah I don't
have to worry about what's being sprayed
on over what's still in it man you just
made the greatest argument for legal
prostitution yep yep that applies yeah I
didn't just study legalizing weed and
clean than it's
better than getting some dirty hookers
all right we've gotten sidetracked I'm
gonna continue the article here it goes
on to say a company could destroy any
affected marijuana voluntarily or face
administrative actions by the state to
force the destruction according to a
policy statement issued by the Chiefs of
the three state agencies involved there
is no pesticide specifically approved
for use on marijuana because the
chemicals are regulated by the US
Environmental Protection Agency and
cannabis is illegal under federal law as
a result there have been no tests to
show how pesticides used on marijuana
could affect consumers or whether their
use is safe but state agricultural
officials have allowed certain
pesticides to be used on marijuana crops
only if it would not violate the
restriction on the products label it is
a violation of federal law
to use a pesticide contrary to its label
you guys this applies to you and your
home Gro this applies to you and your
greenhouse grow any pesticide wants to
be a dick it can be an extra charge yep
yep all you got to do when you buy your
your spray products your pesticides peel
off that little booklet that's on the
back and read it there will be rules on
there there will be what you should
really pay attention to is the interval
of reentry if it says not to go in this
braid area for 4 hours you should
probably stay out of there for 4 hours
take that seriously you're not gonna
notice that you're getting sick from a
pesticide until you start twitching in
five years
right like you really want to read those
labels yeah so where the heck was I
despite the prohibitions the Post
revealed in its own testing that a
number of marijuana infused products
contained high levels of pesticides not
allowed for use on cannabis what
followed were a number of recalls issued
by the Denver Department of
Environmental Health after
investigations into business is
connected with the Post's findings we
were at the last paragraph you guys go
ahead Mike it's a downplay the other
half of their findings they found they
tested eight samples two of them came
back pretty dirty but the other six came
back cleaner than the lab testing dude
had seen anything in a while nice so but
that's not news well it should be it
should be but there's no scare tactic
involved in that right like it's it's
really unfortunate that the there's a
dirty product out on store shelves but
at the same time it's all being recalled
because we've got
labs no one else has it's kind of a
beautiful thing I'm such a [ __ ] up way
though all right you guys I will try I'm
gonna make myself a note a list of
approved all right I want to find a list
of approved pesticides which I need
anyway for the shop
we just need we use basically one or two
products at the shop we've got a pretty
good pesticide regimen going on there
but uh I will get a list of approved
pesticides we'll talk about that on the
show when we do the pest management
episode that I need to work on I've got
a lot of episodes of like halfway
written you guys I just need to put them
together things have been really chaotic
in my world I've been driving the
springs like three times a week to talk
about getting a job and now I've got the
job so it's gonna be a lot of fun let's
get on to the last paragraph of this
news article so that we can get Mike
home to his little baby
it says although state officials have
been battling around pesticide rules for
more than a year there was no
enforcement until Denver health
officials quarantined more than a
hundred thousand plants it said were
improperly grown with pesticides the
state said could not be used the
quarantines came after Denver fire
inspectors found potentially hazardous
pesticides and marijuana growing
facilities during routine inspections
this year and reported it to health
officials because I mentioned this on
the show they found a eagle 20 in there
and when Eagle 20 is an eagle 20 or
might its Eagle 20 when Eagle 20 catches
on fire and burns the off gas that comes
from Eagle 20 is cyanide so that's when
the firemen Fire Department doesn't want
that in your grow because people yeah
like know what you've got in your grow
know you've got in your house this is
all gonna do Long's
yeah you should read the label on any
product you're using any way all the
time you should kind of be aware of what
you're putting into yourself and your
plants into your food feeding your dog
read the label alright last paragraph
you guys last small sentence in the
paragraph the state isn't in rulemaking
that would strictly limit the pesticides
that can be used on marijuana only to
those whose labels allow for unspecified
crops that can be used in greenhouses
and that are not prohibited from human
consumption pesticides allowed in
tobacco cultivation also would be
approved alright so any pesticides found
in any test of cannabis equals your
cannabis is
being destroyed yep that's a huge move
that's Mike said it a minute ago it's
gonna make prices go up if the I mean
it's gonna send big ripples through the
industry there's not everybody was
growing with the stuff that's being
banned or was banned a couple months
back so it's not like everyone has to
change up but every company that buys
product does like it's it's only a
matter of time before shops our lab
testing everything that comes in just as
a matter of policy let alone extract
companies edible companies just think of
a product like chief would chew or dick
ceilings he came to the new Snoop Dogg
you know how much stuff they buy and
process right or snoops new line or
Rihanna's new I know like there's
freaking every honest new line yep
wooden I thought might have just been a
meme on Facebook I don't know I'm high
and I scroll through a lot of news
yeah but Willie's know Willie's got a
brain coming out like I just came out
cuz you're mildly famous for marijuana
you've got a [ __ ] brand of marijuana
coming out well since we're on the topic
song store you know what I was gonna say
is I want to see since snoop and I'm not
dissing you snoop snoop Dogg I [ __ ]
love you bro Snoop Dogg I'm from
California but I grew up my cousin lived
in Long Beach I spent a lot of time in
the LBC Snoop Dogg actually went to
school with my cousin I'm not dissing
Snoop Dogg he might be how do you know
snooping smoking a blunt listening to
the girl from her I listened to the GGN
he should listen to the girl from a
heart unrest prostitutes nice but yeah
but Snoop bro you signed up with the
shittiest [ __ ] dispensary in Colorado
like they are known to be the shittiest
the most loyal right yeah they're the
[ __ ] dispensary that got or is
accused of handing out [ __ ] edibles
at the goddamn stage yeah they just keep
[ __ ] up left and right
so they also had a lot of pesticide
issues in the past I'm curious to see if
snoops products have residual pesticides
from when they were made back in the day
who knows yeah Wow yes and you did that
and since we're talking about like
celebrities and things that are gonna
have strains coming out let's go ahead
and toot some IRA genetics horns here
over the past two nights I have been
harvesting the lovely damsels dank and I
actually got harvested a few nights ago
it was finally dry enough to finish
through the final trim so damsels dank
you guys is jarred up and the curing
process has begun there will be a
tasting party the first weekend of
December it's a private party I would
invite you but uh I can't have all you
guys showing up say it's taken yeah all
the seats are fully guys but I will let
you know how it goes I'll try to get
damsel on the show shortly after that so
that she can talk about her new strain
that I made for her she likes it I can't
wait till this process is over so I can
finally get some details because all
I've seen is three jar samples flashed
in front of my grandpa's and some jar
samples is pretty much what I've what
I've shown anybody right and I want to
dig through all of those jars there's a
whole bunch of them over there there are
ten if it made it to the final round for
damsel to choose from so whichever one
of those tins she likes the best
we will work with she's human and she
may reject all ten of them that may not
be what she wants so when this might
just be round one yeah exactly
and if that's the case then I just did a
really cool Fino hunt I found at least
three keepers had a pension right like
there's some stank and there's some
stank over there you never end up bust
after a good fee no that's the truth you
know huh you guys listen to the episode
I did about Fino hunting I don't
remember which a number it is but make
sure you check the website look it up
there you go it's super easy to do yep
go to iTunes go to draw eye region etixx
Colorado calm look for the girl from
your heart podcast tab scroll through
every episode is there you'll find it um
so we've covered the Hickenlooper
article you got anything else you want
to say while we're on the air bro not
especially you just like shout out to
everybody there's a lot of changes with
people in my life this week like you
change jobs but you're not alone there
I've talked to a whole bunch of people
that are going through a big change
right now so shout out for people trying
to do someone make them that's gonna
make him happy yeah that's the truth
don't be afraid of a little bit of
success that's what I said on episode
number 106 that nobody got to listen to
because stitcher failed us I apologize
yes so let's start wrapping up to show
you it's been 40-something minutes -
whatever I have to edit
because a little tech issue in the
middle email a specific Gro questions
yes please do that if you want to learn
stuff about anything email it to me girl
from your heart at hotmail calm you can
tweet me it's at G fyh podcast find me
on Facebook check out the Instagram you
guys I use I read genetics on Instagram
we've got 19,000 followers when I get to
20,000 I'm gonna start doing some
giveaways so get on there follow me
join that [ __ ] do it do it I like it I
like it when you ramble people will get
you here next week yeah that's uh I was
since I've got Mike here Mike you have
got to scroll through Twitter and find
that I've got it there were like four
people who who has tagged this
appropriately within the timeline so if
you were taken care of if you count how
many people there are
we'll put envelopes on the table and
then we'll email them or they need to
send us their addresses so that we can
mail them stickers yeah if you're
listening again tonight you know who you
are direct message me or at Nemo Punk 15
or or you can get grow from your heart
to at Rasta Jeff for 20 yep just direct
message that in Twitter or over Facebook
or whatever and we'll get you your
sticker back mail that yeah we'll get
your stickers to you we didn't know if
you guys are awesome I got such a big
grin every time one of those came
through it's a good hour of just smiling
hashtag I like it when you ramble um so
hope you guys too what's up let's put it
into that now so that people can't jump
on no mas No Mas that is over you guys
ones this drop in this will come out
Monday which will be the twenty-third
ish Monday there's something something
yeah but Monday come on calendar you got
to go faster 23rd I was correct so
Monday the 23rd the hashtag I like it
when you ramble sticker packs off
sweepstakes sweepstakes is no longer
offer but if you really want some
stickers send me a tweet send the tweet
to I'm giving you so many different
Twitter addresses to talk about now send
the tweet to @g fyh podcast follow the
podcast we'll figure out how to get you
some stickers one way or another we may
make you do something for him but it
won't be anything real crazy take a fad
something like that yeah I'll probably
make you follow me on Instagram
all seven of my Twitter accounts or
something right I don't really I do
alright where does rambling hashtag I
like it when you ramble speaking of
being November 19th tomorrow is my mom's
birthday my mom does not listen to the
podcast my mom doesn't grow weed but
happy birthday mom you gotta send her
love either way um I guess that's a good
way to wrap up the show right yeah you
guys make sure you follow us on all the
social media I'm sure you've caught all
the the names and places by now make
sure you follow up Mike it's at Nemo
punk 15 on Twitter search him out follow
him do you want to advertise your
Facebook group what we're here yeah
might as well I haven't mentioned it
until now but [ __ ] it follow me on
Facebook if you like its Pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws just punch that
into your search I'll come right up I've
been getting a lot of feedback on that
lately shit's been blowing up lately
because anti-pop people have taken
notice and are starting to get really
pissed when I link their stuff and
debunk it and it's led to some really
hilarious little prohibitionist I don't
know attempted trolling I supposed a way
to describe it it's it's funny cuz it's
sort of like if a small child decided to
lecture calculus at you like it doesn't
matter how passionate they are like
they're never gonna get it right you're
not gonna learn anything useful it's
just this weird thing that I mean to be
against pot at this point in history is
to have failed to do your homework
and that's just where the argument
starts yeah poor Randy oh poor poor
Randy Randy i slayed you so much so much
passion so little information report a
little troll Randy and I done slayed you
so many times and you just keep coming
back for more I need someone who likes
to make memes I don't have time to do
this [ __ ] dude I need somebody to help
me reply me we have got trolls on this
podcast that listened religiously so if
you need a meme you call them to action
and we will get you some memes right
yeah yeah the anti pot community learn
to meme like a week ago and it's stuff
that makes you want to put your head
through a wall yeah you guys are gonna
have phones away so that you can help
them with the meme
yep I just don't have the energy all the
time to [ __ ] debunk nonsense cuz
there's a lot of nonsense this is we're
way off topic you guys but I a hashtag I
like it when you ramble and I hope you
guys were listening still shut it if you
are around Facebook has murdered me over
the past week with all of the change
your profile picture to a French flag
and all of this and everybody talking
about who's a terrorist and who is not
that has burnt me the [ __ ] out I didn't
even look at Facebook the past week I
find myself shunning news and social
media after events like this just
because of all that like the event
itself is bad enough all the hate in the
fear and the idiocy and the ignorance
that led up to it's bad enough but then
the [ __ ] that comes after it's just so
much worse right yeah yeah Facebook just
makes me want to smash my head into the
wall lately so I've been avoiding that
sorry if I haven't been returning your
facebook messages and all that stuff for
the past week you guys but once all this
stuff stops on Facebook once we go back
to talking about football games and
stupid [ __ ] I'll be back yeah it's a
little too intense right now
I have to go unfriend people because of
some of the [ __ ] that I see dude I'm not
gonna tolerate some of it like I'm not
gonna get all political and get my
opinion going too much on here this is a
weed podcast but goddamn some people get
really really ridiculous really really
quickly when people are afraid they do
really really crazy insane things and
that's what's going on right now is is
there's a lot of fear out there and
people are just diving into it because
it's easy there is a lot of fear you
guys don't buy into the fear find the
truth you know I know that's hard to do
in the world right now there are a lot
of clouds plus the ones weren't blowing
but you got try to find the truth search
for the truth the truth will set you
free
yeah and calm the [ __ ] down that way
about half of the people that I see I'm
like you know dad chill pill been the
main thought going through my head the
last two weeks is just like dude calm
the [ __ ] down yeah like you need to dabs
in a nappy nap like that's what your
life needs hey Bernie if you're
listening to the podcast bro we're
sourcing a nappy-nap Bernie you need a
dab in a nap but we're still friends bro
even though we had a band out the other
day no real Oh have you tuck him in no I
just gave him a couple dives and sent
him home and hit
plaid or sent me a message like 12 hours
later that was like got super high I
went home with sleep do you drive around
in your kids new car seat nope sorry
Bernie I had to bro if you guys didn't
catch on
Bernie's about three foot two I think
he's like five foot he's a great guy
that's why I don't feel bad picking on
him cuz he's actually a good dude and
that's why I'm giving him a shout out
and saying even though we had a heated
conversation on Facebook and we totally
disagree on some [ __ ] I agree that we
disagree and you're still my bro
politics he's a marine and so he's done
[ __ ] in the combat vet yeah thank you
thank you and all the combat vets cuz
they if we didn't have vets that signed
up to go do [ __ ] or people that signed
up to be Marines and army guys and Air
Force guys you and I would get drafted
bro because we're big a lot like even
when I was a teenager and I had friends
that really could think I'm gonna go
sign up for the Air Force I was like I
would die twice like that's so not me
bro you've played black ops with me you
want to be in the military with me nope
if I throw if I get flashbang 90% of the
time it's cuz I threw the flashbang too
tight pants lots of running that so not
me it doesn't set the desert the desert
nope not me I don't look good weapons
are loud
I'd miss everybody on purpose bro like
there's a terrorist and I'd be like just
kind of fake aim and Adam shoot next to
him to scare him away
you sure the sirens just now did that
was crazy
I came through my headphones alright you
guys we are totally rambly we're totally
off topic I said happy birthday to my
mom that was last note that I had we're
gonna start wrapping up the show and I
thank everybody for a listen and Mike
dude thanks for coming hae-jin if you
listened to the show thanks for let me
borrow your husband for an hour or two
sorry I sent him home highest [ __ ] but I
appreciate you letting him come over and
spend some time with me and record a
podcast the listeners really appreciate
him on here hey Davey if you listenin
but I hope you're feeling better get
well little man yeah all right so we're
wrapping up to show you guys if you want
to visit the website and hit the PayPal
donation button that would be super
awesome but I'm not gonna beg you for it
what I'd really rather you do is follow
me on Instagram it's a vital piece of
equipment is down right now y'all when
you just step up and how about the show
yes the coil on the Jesus
[ __ ] so if you want to send a donation
go to I read genetics Colorado comm
click on the girl from a heart podcast
tab on the top right there's a PayPal
logo click on that PayPal logo it'll
take you to PayPal you can throw a
donation my direction I would totally
appreciate it and give you a shot on the
show it's not necessary this show is
always going to be free free free
freedom I want to share my knowledge my
love for cannabis with you for free but
if you want to make a donation I'd love
the [ __ ] out of you we would buy a new
coil for the Gmail things would work out
and you'll never have to hear the torch
coming through the microphone you notice
we uh we didn't dab because the torch is
just so this is what it's um when you
dab with the torch
taking off that's what you guys are
missing sounds like a plane taking off
exactly all right we're on rambled the
[ __ ] mode so we're gonna turn off the
mics we're gonna take some more dabs
we're gonna hang out be Bros for a few
minutes I want to thank everybody for
listened to this super long episode I
want to give a shout out to Danielle
good luck in Denver hope everything goes
your way good luck girl yeah good luck I
want to give a shout out to hey uh chefs
dispense and Mattie baby hit me up this
afternoon like what you doing fool and I
was like I'm gardening I'm like you want
to go to lunch and I was like you know I
want to go to lunch so we went had faux
there's [ __ ] delicious quality little
shout out too yeah shut up the Spence
and Manny and shout out to faux it was
really good on that note big shout out
to manager Spence until next time you
guys take a fat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
music wow sometimes the things that
means in life maybe that's all the time
it's gonna be easy
I solve it - Mariana and get stay up
over the weekend
I'm very good about myself a belonging
feeling good damn that's there from
there my smoke the marijuana yet se
llaman Toby kids
Oh
[Music]
yeah
stay a Bon Jovi kids and flower
[Music]
[Applause]
stay up on the weekends I'm
I'm feeling very good about myself big
insane feeling Gouda well and that's the
problem I smooth the marijuana half yet
boom the we kids
I went I got problem might um
domestically on my ladies one a query
wouldn't is my Ramana
still your bum the wicked
the day you gotta find it I'm a big
Madonna behind
[Music]
you