[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 110 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right if you're a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a veteran
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shot up to my friends in the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my show
big thanks to cat coop and the entire
mystic roots crew what's up everybody
hope you guys are having a great evening
afternoon morning whatever time it is
wherever you are
hope you're hanging out getting some
turps in your head hope you're smoking a
fat joint hope you got a vaporizer
packed up hope you got a DAB ready hope
you get the email turned on you're
eating some edibles you might be smoking
a blunt that's like not my favorite but
if you're smoking a lot more power to
you do what you got to do get it in your
head get them Terps in your mind set
yourself free you guys this is gonna be
a great episode this is the episode that
I recorded in Colorado Springs from the
dude it's Gatsby Invitational there are
a lot of great folks in this episode
this episode features the grimy Gatsby
this episode features Chris from the
clear concentrates and it definitely
features a whole bunch of lovely ladies
before we get to that this podcast is
brought to you by our great friends at
Hitman glass that's right hit man glass
you guys there I'm sitting over there
hitting the Hitman mini sidecar with the
hammer head I grabbed this one because
it's got a yellow label on it and I
haven't seen a lot of hit man with a
yellow label I really liked it that it
looked fresh the hammer had Perkin this
thing you guys oh my god this thing it's
like a [ __ ] boss you know what I'm
talking about it I'm gonna heat this up
for a second here wha more rambling
about hit man glass let's see what else
do I have to say but I'm gonna eat the
supper and take a fat dab to some
gorillas what is it it's a gorilla glue
live resin from the garden of Weeden so
let's take a DAB here but this podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
Hitman glass when I'm shopping for a
raki guys I want to
that I know is gonna hit like a truck
it's not gonna splash water in my mouth
and I also want a rig made by an
American in America and not made by some
Chinese kid without protective eyewear
with no shoes and not getting paid so
you guys I represent hitman glass my
glass made in America
hitman glass is a huge part of the
cannabis and hash movement make sure you
check out www.montgomeryvillenissan.com
they shout out to hitman make sure you
guys support the hitman crew thanks a
lot to dougie and the entire hitman fam
for supporting the podcast you guys I
don't have a lot else to say let's get
into the episode let's a time travel
back a few days to Colorado Springs
because it was a lovely snowy afternoon
there were a bunch of lovely ladies in
the house or a bunch of Turkey dudes in
the house there was a table table
covered in great food and good hash and
good weed so as a party let's let the
music take us right into that part of
the episode and then I'll be back to
wrap up the show after that all right
what's up ladies and gentlemen it's your
boy Rasta Jeff I am here in beautiful
Colorado Springs looking out a giant
window looking at a lovely day it's
snowing like a son-of-a-bitch it's
gorgeous out there sitting across from
me you guys I am here at the the dude
it's Gatsby Invitational and sitting
across from me is the lovely dude it's
danzel how you doing today it sounds it
looks like the weed that I grew is
working for the whole house silly for
four days now nice I like that I like
that well our friend Britney is joining
us she's known as dude it stands on her
real name is Britney hey thanks for
being on the show I appreciate that
yeah of course man anytime she brought
four or five I can't even count how many
lovely ladies there are she brought four
beautiful model friends with her I'm
just gonna go from the left and
introduce all the ladies sitting to my
left is Miss Amanda what
they call you on Instagram Ackley rocks
are a wks there you go guys make sure
you follow her thanks for joining us
we're gonna talk to you a little bit
more later too oh you've got a mic
nevermind I give you a mic sitting right
in front of me sorry guys I'm really
high too I just hide it better sitting
in front of me is my new friend Shayna
hey just Shayna you don't have an
Instagram you want a shout-out
okay awesome she's a great photographer
you guys she has taken some great
pictures this weekend hopefully we'll
talk more about that I'm gonna give
everybody a heads up make sure you check
out Instagram a hashtag dude it's Gatsby
and look at some of the pictures that
are posted there you might enjoy some of
those so sitting at my position here is
Tristan how you doing I'm doing good
good good what's your Instagram handle
so people can stalk you while they're
listening oh man Tristan Renee is my
Instagram all right and you how do you
spell Renee at the end there I know it's
different re na RL special you are
special we like it alright sitting way
to my right ish is the shy girl do we
call you Jacqueline do we call you
Jackie Jacqueline please all right
what's your instagram honey hello my
name is underscore Jacqueline all right
make sure you follow her guys
she's taking some great pictures this
weekend thanks for joining me ladies I
really appreciate it yeah we're super
steps over here who's got to grab his
mic blow out his dad get his [ __ ]
together cough a little bit this is my
buddy John hunt how you doing brother
what's going down hanging out man this
is my buddy the grimy Gatsby this is the
man the myth the Turk gather the legend
thanks for joining me man this show will
be filled with cops that's no problem
thanks for coming out bro dude thanks
for having me this is a gorgeous house a
gorgeous location some gorgeous friends
and family also in the room you guys
we're gonna do another podcast after
this and we'll feature this these guys
but also in the room we got Jordan from
turf X we got our buddy Dan from CCC
4:20 and to my left my new friend Chris
from the clear the clear scientist dude
thanks for joking in the show with all
these guys here in just a minute we may
get the guitar out again if you guys
remember what happened on that episode
they got a little turf sloppy yeah we
might do that so I've got a bunch of
notes here in the phone I should
probably open that stuff up and start
getting on it first before we get too
far I need to learn a little
bit about the dude it's Gatsby
Invitational you guys want to tell me
all about that I'm sure so I've kind of
been organizing these like shoot fests
for a few years I used to do it for a
different company I'm gonna bring a
bunch of girls and photographers to
different locations and we would make a
whole bunch of art and have a really
good time and there was kind of an
excuse for all of us to get together
even though we are spread across the
country and I thought why not do that
for cannabis products and for businesses
and so we kind of jet I kind of ran the
idea pass went and he was like that
could actually happened it was kind of
just an idea wouldn't it be cool I
really just wanted an excuse to bring my
friends somewhere and watch them run
around naked but he said that we could
make it a real thing and and lots of
hard work and planning and some sweet
sponsors later and a lot of these guys
here teaching me how to be a boss you
already knew that to be a boss before I
met you well maybe I mean I think
lifestyle marketing and kind of like
content creation in general is something
that numerous businesses whether big or
small are utilizing in different aspects
and so with you know the the GG fam and
different kind of aspects and I actually
met damsel at one of those shoots before
giving cannabis class until like the
photo shooting and kind of doing some
cannabis consulting but with the people
that are in the room now there's a
massive imprint and footprint so to
speak on like how social media and
social engineering and lifestyle
marketing comes to be very effective and
so it was kind of a double-edged sword
with bringing the right people together
but also getting the right brands
together to be able to like represent
what damsel does really well and what we
can put together and what brands were a
part of the event this time is this the
first event guys have done like this
first one the first so who joined on for
this one I can I mean I can rattling off
pretty fast
they'll deserve a shout-out yeah we have
we have all kinds of different companies
came to be obviously IRA Genetics had it
had a nice part with some of the stuff
we've been putting in the air for the
week Apothic came Papa Canada came
through with a bunch of great holistic
topicals that we've been using sponsor
as well as they're huge you know Chris
coming out in person is a blessing in
general just having out the scientists
the Matt I mean like Matt's that can
cover that coffee table right there that
we're staring at green and healthy
wellness we had some places there that
we shot at and saw what was going down
with that there are a huge success we
brought out a bunch of veteran models
and a veteran photographer and girls
that are really used to like pitching in
and doing their shirt at work and
helping out and we all get along really
well but we know how to work really hard
to get the job done so it was a lot of
work and a lot of play and we just had a
you know a really great group of girls
that are really good friends spread
across the country and when we get
together it's like nothing changed so
it's been awesome we keep talking about
friends from across the country where is
everybody in the room from I'm formerly
okay machinae I'm from Boston bow
opposite into the country nice meeting
in Colorado
I'm from Long Beach nice it's kind of my
neighborhood from Bellflower I'm from
Chicago but just moved to Phoenix three
months ago
oh wow how's that for a change I love it
nice to ride your bike more yes it's a
Harley and she looks awesome doing it
alright so one of the things that we
really such a big shout out to the the
dude that's hard for me to remember the
dude it's Gatsby Invitational that's a
lot of words for my stone as to remember
but Jennifer letting me be a part of
that look the snow is coming down again
this is such a great view shadows the
people that let us use this house yeah
yes the dope house so one of the things
that really made this weekend special
miss Danville actually we're gonna blame
this mostly on hunt a few months ago
hunt put me in touch with Miss damsel
and she asked me if I would breed a
strain for her so a lot of what's been
going on this weekend is we have all
been smoking what will become or
possibly not become from what the talk
has been some things that may become
damsels dank so you've got a little
notebook in front of you have you guys
decided which is your favorite and least
favorites and such I mean I think the
overwhelming favorite is what ladies
before before okay all right all right
so before is the winners great stuff for
us to all flavor I have a veteran rule
in doing this but the one that's gone
first there's always the true the one
that everybody's smoked was gone fever
was gone first this time with the house
nice I've got some more before in the
car huh throw some on the counter yeah
all right so for the people that didn't
get a chance to smoke it can you
describe what you thought of before
since you got your notes right in front
of you yeah so I thought it smelled a
little bit like pineapple with a hint of
citrus but the taste was a little bit
more
I was so high when I did this I drew a
campfire floral with the hint of birch
and then it was nature II I said it kind
of tasted like camping okay
and it was you know had some nice orange
hairs it was frosty and yeah we have
been really enjoying it there's lots of
giggles lots of good times the [ __ ]
love before the [ __ ] can I call you
guys the [ __ ] for the length of the
show and I'll stop right after I found
my boundary all right so did anybody
else in the room get a campfire or just
tastes like camping aroma I'm just
curious about that totally all right
aren't you a chef you've been cooking
the entire time I've been here that's
the first time you haven't been cooking
yeah well thank you I appreciate it and
you caught you say it does kind of taste
like campfire in a good way yes okay all
right because when I think you can't
fire I think like when you go camping
and your hair smells like campfire not
like that that's yes is hey what kind of
dreadlock joke is that mama grab a mic
if you're gonna talk but it heard you
all right so before I was there a
runner-up yeah I also really enjoyed the
a 383 all right which I thought it
smelled like fruity pebbles
a little bit like black cherry but it
tasted a little more diesel II but that
one had super sparkly chirps on it and I
described the overall highest sway feels
you know and you like get super high and
you just like start swaying in the
kitchen nice just kind of leaning yeah
this Way's all right so does anybody
want to know what was in these crosses I
know all the boys tell me what's in
there
yeah this was fun to mess with everybody
did anybody try any of the number the
letter C did any of that get tasted it
was no good that's why there were three
that were from that selection I didn't
bring them so the way I did this I ran I
think I started with 20 seeds of three
different strains and I narrowed it down
through the veg phase and through flower
I ended up with three of letter A and I
just labeled the seeds so that nobody
knew what they were I've just this is
Brandi this is Brandi this is Brandi I
had three of letter A four of B and
three of C Cesar Dukey just got rid of
them we don't need that it's crap I'm
not even gonna grow any more of those
seeds throw it all the way a C was a
transformer two-day breaker from gage
drain genetics transformers inferno haze
and Kim D and then the what's the other
one I said it is sorry I'm lost now Kim
D that's inferno haze' and Daybreaker
Daybreakers Kim D and Joseph Oh G
all right yeah so many genetics in my
head that I get confused but the winners
are PIRG I am kind of a Terp nerd I'll
take that a is space Queen crossed a
grateful dog I used a female space clean
and a male a reverse male grateful dog
so it's a feminized seeds space
yeah space cleaned a grateful dog is
what that is so it's my space cool or am
i grateful dog that I made two sub cool
space Queen a real tall stretchy
phenotype of the space Queen that's
where that fruity funky moldy smell
comes from as a space Queen and it's the
Romulan that makes it grow those orange
real orange pistols the real fingery
calyx is that's from Romulan okay so be
the one that everybody loves
everybody's guessed it so many times
accurately its lemon skunk from Arion
its greenhouse seeds lemon skunk its
ourian's from lemon man and then it's
crossed to the day breaker from gage
brain genetics with the joseph OG and
the chem D in there so that's what that
one is lemon skunk and day breaker needs
a good name if it's so what I've heard
you might not decide that this is gonna
be the keeper you know they were all
super super good but I feel like there's
just another strain that I compared all
of my eyes to
don't say the name of it cuz we're gonna
keep I think we should try to put that
in the mix and maybe do the process over
but there were so many good what was the
b1 that was another really really good
one that's the lemon skunk Daybreaker
cross so all of the bees will be lemon
skunk today breaker and all of the A's
are grateful dog in space Queen Holy
See's were trash okay so the ones that
you guys really liked we're gonna work
on getting those on the shelf at green
and healthy wellness it'll take a while
yeah that's the a3 a3 we'll get that
there before and before maybe even be
one boys are across the room and when I
said b1 I got two thumbs ups on the b1
so there will be some new stuff showing
up the green and healthy wellness you
guys that'll be a little bit be a couple
harvest but we'll make it happen
I mean it all got smoked it's great yeah
really high it's when they don't smoke
like the Colorado folk do they come and
get rekt and it's pretty entertaining
not making funny you I love it the
turkey boys have just been smoking all
the B 1 and B for like champions what
you feel and just for appearance she
wrote green she's all blushing that's
cute I like it I have more notes a week
ago over unless anybody has more stuff
to say about this weed what so talk to
us about what's up with that fee know
how long is before how high does it get
so B 1 and B all of the B's were very
very similar
ok growth you could barely see a
difference in them they kind of stretch
the limits gunk make some stretch pretty
well
they grow real dense they grow real
chunky they take they could take 70 days
these went 63 I think it could have gone
another week but I was pressed for time
what about top the a was done at eight
weeks finished at 8 weeks one of them
started to herm you could probably see
it if you guys are experienced weed
growers and if you got one of the top
buds you could see her flowers in there
it was just yeah Mon so I can't I can't
work I don't remember which one it is I
took pictures and mark it down to the
photos and stuff but I don't remember
off the top of my head but I marked down
which one was a herb that one brought in
the most the most flower yeah be one
well be one brought in just yeah there
was most of them there are little plants
they harvested about an ounce and a half
B one was about two and a half ounces
yes yeah yes
I got another roster on the microphone
that's always nice yeah you know what
your favorite strain is basically
D'Angela you figured that out we're
gonna cross something of mine to that
strain some of our friends in the room
actually have a clone of your favorite
strain they're gonna they've given me
blessings to work with that so I'm gonna
play with it and we're gonna make you a
new strain we'll do this all over again
when you ladies coming back I hope this
is gonna take me 120 give me about a
year not even like because I know what I
want to do I need to get the clone that
you want me to work with and then I'm
going to reverse it I'm going to make it
a boy it's a girl I'm gonna turn it into
a boy I'm gonna collect pollen from it
I'm gonna put pollen on another clone of
the same plant then I'm also put pollen
on like nine other [ __ ] in the room
and then we're gonna smoke all we're
gonna grow those out then we'll smoke a
bunch of those we'll do this all over
again it's gonna be a minute plus some
carrion
yeah and we're gonna have a whole bunch
of stuff groaning can't rush perfection
that is the truth and we want to find
your strangest for you I appreciate that
man what are we smoking right now which
one is this microphone benign benign
okay mm-hmm it's got a cotton candy it's
very sweet that's the Daybreaker that
gives it the musky Daybreakers got some
real og cush influence to it shout-out
to gage Green genetics I feel it's real
important to give shoutouts to the
people that let me breathe with theirs
rains gauge completely encourages me to
work with his stuff so thanks dude the
whole gauge green genetics cruising I
just one person it's a group of people
so if you guys ever done a tasting party
or anything like this before
all the girls said no all the ladies
said no how about you guys over their
tasting party you ever done something
like this nice well thanks for being
involved with it
fist bump for putting me in this
position we've revealed the winner I
told you what everything is we're gonna
do it again yeah all right so I wrote
this down hey miss um and I see you got
your phone over there you've got a book
coming out a cookbook you talked about
it you want me to just cut that part out
I was gonna give you a chance to shout
out your cookbook I I am finishing a
cookbook that I've been inspired by this
trip to quickly finish stay tuned
what's your cookbook called it's gonna
be called eat yourself thin and you said
it's mostly for women it's I you know
it's it's gonna be for everybody I think
that everyone should know how to cook
clean and simple so I know my budget so
that's all it's gonna be so whether you
cook for your boyfriend a girlfriend or
significant other husband wife it's for
those people awesome
so you'll have it finished by the end of
the year and then how long to get it out
we'll do a Skype interview when it comes
out because you've cooked for the house
and I and I drove home like a satisfied
man so thank you thank you I was awesome
I had to make sure to shout out your
book she's also catered to like
vegetarians or allergies dairy allergies
gluten allergies I mean we have about
five different food allergies in this
house and she's managed to cater to
every single one of them normally I
won't heat at somebody else's house but
when she was talking to hunt about his
gluten allergy and she said there's no
egg in this and this is like this lady
knows what's up yeah good job thanks for
feeding everybody nice I could tell you
just live in the kitchen you're just
comfortable as much
it's awesome I love it so Brett what do
you do when you're not being a
supermodel not a supermodel
I'm a supermodel thank you I am the
general manager for green and healthy
wellness so I you know you manage yeah I
manage I mean today I recently started
helping out in the garden I have a new
appreciation for the plant that I've
been smoking for the past ten years
because it is a lot of work got my hair
got in oh that's the worst yeah sticky
flytraps and you know sore back and like
there's something about Mary so yeah it
was a really humbling experience and a
really good experience I've enjoyed it
but I really enjoy interacting with the
patients most and you know getting to
develop relationships with them and
building that trust so that's definitely
where I think oh god how long have I
been in customer service now how old am
I
thirteen years of customer service
experience probably serves me well in
the front of the house but uh so I do
that and I am I'm married and I have a
dog and we like to stay home and smoke
weed and shout out the pub likes the a
shout out to Penelope and puggle make
sure you follow her on Instagram the
sweetest dog on IG she so yeah it's the
you know I just I live the the weave and
Colorado lifestyle and I've been here
since April so I'm just
enjoying the altitude in the mountains
and welcome home thank you this view
here is awesome it's known so perfectly
I like it you guys found the greatest
spot I'm glad we did a podcast right
here all right miss Shayna
can I ask you what you do in your normal
everyday life when you're not being a
model okay so I bet it's much easier for
you ladies to pose and feel comfortable
in front of a lady photographer instead
of some creepy dude I contend with our
best experience she really you know
shoots each photo to the models body and
she's really good at directing and
working with her we were I'm so stoked
about all of the shots that we got from
this weekend and more real stoked to put
up the lip book cuz Shana killed it
I saw the unedited shots and the
lighting is great you made these ladies
look great good job they make it look so
easy
miss Tristan I'm game
what do you normally do normal life we'd
watch some Netflix and chill perfect yes
all right miss Shire I'm gonna ask you
next what are you doing your normal
day-to-day life um I'm a bottle service
girl on the weekends what do you do that
uh this bar called bar Smith and monarch
theater I know people gonna stalk you I
might cut that out
no I posted on Instagram post about it
too yeah so that's about it and then I
ride my bike and I hike your motorcycle
your Harley yes tell us a little bit
about the Harley I'm curious
1200 Knights der it's my first bike and
I've had it for just about a month now
nice it looks good on you
thanks for not being shy for a minute oh
she passed the mic so quick
hold it off you nailed it though you
nailed it that was perfect hey people
that stole your car yeah yeah my car got
stolen yesterday morning and you talked
about the irony of this welcome to bring
up the fact that I got paid to be a car
thief model for the Department of police
and DMV about identity theft and getting
your car stolen and that was on every
red rock ticket in every DMV Department
banner for like a year or so so how many
Facebook and Instagram and text messages
did you give oh yeah so like five
o'clock in the morning I started my car
whatever in these guys got it while I
was coming out the front door and I
chased them and all this other [ __ ] that
occurred and then three or four hours
later we got our car back so that was a
double Mike in him all this stuff I
think the day yesterday yeah so two days
ago whenever it happened on Thursday I
think I got about like 15 to 20 text
messages of some sort of image of myself
as a car thief saying that your car was
easy to steal and taking your identity
was even easier and there's one that's
like a really big close up with me and
it just says did like you know something
about me taking your ID or some [ __ ]
so I'm mad at myself for not making the
first me situation that's all credit to
dad back there yeah that was the turkey
boys come with the turkey boys pointing
over here at Amanda so they that's a 55
heard you guys complimenting each other
yesterday it's a 50/50 yeah that all
happened yesterday I don't really have
much of a I don't think I have like my
real life is like you know grimy Gatsby
in four pieces and wellness and the grow
that you know you and I work at and know
what you're doing when you hired me
you're like I don't know how to grow
weed I need you bro you got it under
control I shouldn't tell you that too
much because I mean
out of a Johnson you got another control
bro we do an alright job over there we
try to keep the Terps coming you look
like you know how to go yeah I don't
know about a real life yet I think I did
I sleep from like 11 or 12 until like
5:00 in the morning and the rest of the
time as you all know my phones on and
we're going you guys there's a bed at
the shop if that tells you anything
about life there's a bed at our shop
where we yeah I've slept in it already
I've only worked there for less than a
month and I've crashed out in that bed
yeah I can't I can't
well we have a we have a mattress at our
girl in case that's necessary nice all
right so I feel like we've gone about 30
minutes most people listen for about 35
minutes before they get burned out I'll
put a little intro and an ending at the
end of this show at the start and end do
you ladies have anything you want to say
since you got a microphone in your hand
a chance to say something to the world
[Music]
all right we talked about your crew like
your gang the WPC WPC could stand for
the ladies thanks for letting me invade
your privacy for a few minutes I really
appreciate you being on the show Brit
thanks for giving me the honor of being
the dude selected to can't wait for us
to find the winner yeah we're close you
guys and team green and healthy thanks
for letting me be a part of that you
guys that's awesome I'm honored
definitely I come down to West 4:30
Colorado Avenue and buy a bunch of Terps
and hang out and kick it and see the new
shop or something I think we'd bye Jeff
on the Shelf - yeah about February March
ish there'll be ganja grown by Rasta
Jeff you guys can always come meet Miss
damsel she's there a lot kimete damsels
430 West Colorado we'd love to see you
yeah go say hi to Hali also oh it's it's
medical only patients but you know will
expand soon and we'll see you there it's
coming you guys yeah Colorado Springs
has to wake up and let us do
recreational cannabis this is not cool
smoke chirps
that's true all right well since that's
starting we're gonna wrap up this one
we're gonna start a show with the turkey
boys over there cuz let's throw on the
vibe now ladies thank you so much for
joining us I appreciate it thank you
we're gonna get you guys on the show
again big shout out to Haley since she
couldn't be here also big shout out to
Jon Randall's jr. all right you guys
hope everybody enjoyed that episode I
want to thank you for listening I want
to thank everybody for participating in
that episode I want to send a huge shout
out to hunt and Daniel for making me a
part of the dude it's gatsby
invitational i also want to thank damsel
for giving me the opportunity to create
a strain for her and also a huge shout
out to the entire green and healthy
wellness crew for trusting me and giving
me the opportunity to grow the product
for the shop
you guys are trust me with your lives in
your livelihood I do understand that and
I appreciate the opportunity and I'm
honored to be the new lead cultivator of
your place all right so you guys helped
me back in another week with another
episode don't forget to check out our
sponsor hit man glass if you're looking
for some new glass for your collection
if you want a glass rig that hits like a
truck a glass ring that's not gonna
splash water into your face a reliable
rig make sure you check out hit man
glass comm make sure you follow my
friend hit man glass Dougie on Instagram
if you guys are interested in sponsoring
the podcast all you've got to do is send
me an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com and I will get you all of
the information that you do need you
guys not that the show is over please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the girl from your heart podcast
find a review section give me a 5 star
rating and type in a little comment and
let me know what you think of the show
and I will read your comments on a
future episode you can also check us out
on all the social media we are on
Facebook it's a girl from your heart
we're on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
and we're on Instagram until they take
us down again under Irie underscore
genetics so I read genetics on
instagrams where we are they took down
the original page hopefully they don't
take me down again I'll do my best
you guys don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
don't forget about that donation button
on the podcast page you guys if you feel
like this show is worth a couple of
bucks of your time go to the I read
genetics Colorado com website click on
the girl from your heart podcast tab at
the top right there's a donation button
it looks like a PayPal logo
click on that throw in a few bucks that
goes directly to my PayPal account you
guys I will never charge you anything
for this podcast this will always be a
free show but if you'd like to make a
contribution
I would definitely appreciate it I'll
give you a shout out if you got
something you want me to say if you want
me to shout out an organization I'll do
that for you so I'd appreciate that I
already told you to check us out on all
the social media I think that's all I've
got for you once again big thanks to the
green and healthy wellness crew they
shadows to the Terr packs crew that's
all I've got for you guys shut up man
into space thanks again for listening
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug
[Music]
the colorist all
waiting for the stars
[Music]
as it grows
into your eyes
[Music]
yeah
boss not
and cover us all
yeah with snow
[Music]
you