[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 111 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower here a new smoker or a veteran
daddy if you're a cannabis activists
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you again for joining me
as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic Luke's band for letting me use
their music on my show
big thanks to Kat key and the entire
mystic roots crew
to turn down that music a little bit
make sure you guys support my friends in
the mystic roots band you guys up
everybody's having a great holiday
season this will be the Christmas
episode Opie forgot all your Christmas
shopping done maybe you're listening to
this while you're driving to the mall to
grab that last-minute gift or whatever
you got to do anyway no matter what
holiday you're celebrating this season I
hope you have a great holiday if you're
surrounded by friends and family and
some good food and most importantly if
you're surrounded by some good turf so
if you got a fat joint nope you got a
good dad maybe some edibles you know how
we do it here the girl from your heart
podcast I hope you were getting baked
out of your mind this holiday season you
guys this episode is part 2 of the dude
it's Gatsby Invitational this is kind of
the guys episode last week we had the
ladies this week is gonna be the Bros
this podcast actually features our
friends from turf X and our friends from
the clear concentrate but before we get
to that part of the show there's podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
Hitman glass hey man glasses made in
America by Americans you guys when I'm
shopping for a rig I like to know that
what I'm paying for is gonna give me a
nice fat dad and I know that I can rely
on hitman glass don't trust your dad to
a rig made in China by a Chinese child
without proper eye protection or
adequate pay you guys buy glass made in
America by folks who dab just as hard as
you and I hey man glass is not only a
glass company you guys hit man dougie is
a huge part of the cannabis and hash
movement support hit man glass and be
sure to check out the chalice festival
in California
go follow hit man glass on Instagram
search for hit man glass Dougie and give
them a follow and be sure to visit
www.madamebridal.com bari and the Clear
concentrate crew from the dude it's
Gatsby Invitational so let's take a dad
and I will be right back
alright guys actually hit record so
behave yourselves for just a couple of
seconds we're back we're here at the
house at the dude it's Gatsby
Invitational this will be round 2 this
time it's more of the Bros the ladies
have gone downstairs to quote unquote
take shots [ __ ] is what I think I
heard was gonna happen down there so I
take like two shots between the five
probably 300 pounds of people down there
yeah all right so sitting to the left
Kocher Daniel on Instagram view on a
stalk him
it's condor underscore Daniel I known
you first from CCC 420 is where I think
I first discovered you yes yes coming
back on the CCC 420 the Triple C 420 I
hear you're coming back make any a
reemergence we actually are yeah we're
shooting for January actually forgot
about that forgot about it he was he was
a little bit distracted the last few
days let's just put it that another
success like the first go-around nice
well congrats on coming back up see you
back on YouTube yeah the YouTube misses
you all the weed reviews all the dab
reviews since he's over here talking to
my right it's my buddy Jordan how you
doing brother here at this beautiful
house and springs on the top of a
mountain I can see all of Colorado
Springs through the fog donkey guys so I
hope you're prepared for this is gonna
be a very interesting episode if you
guys want to follow my buddy Jordan he
is I remember its GDP Inc on Instagram
granddaddy purple incorporated Randy
purple incorporated I don't know why
you'd rep that strain that is one of my
least favorite strains ever bro well
shows what you know I love you guys
alright and over here speaking on the
phone who was our on the phone why did I
say phone that's how high I am over
there on the microphone the guy that I
just met last night he's coolest [ __ ]
this is the guy we called the clear
scientist my buddy Chris how you doing
brother I'm doing excellent I am high as
[ __ ]
we're all altitude well thanks for
joining me on the show here comes a
beautiful damsel sneaking through nice
nice here's a guy I just met today this
guy's name's Brian he's got a really
fantastic all you my friend you like
people to stock you on while they're
listening to the show
no now you're low key alright gonna like
a low-key kind of dude I hear you're
into some cool [ __ ] so we may open the
doors to talk about some of that stuff
here in the near future I do like cool
[ __ ] nice nice you guys I hear that you
too Chris and Brian are like the the
hash mad scientists the product that I
heard about a minute ago the mother's
milk can I ask you guys about that are
you ready to talk about that in a
podcast or that's something we have to
keep on the down-low what they can okay
yeah yeah yeah you know if I ask too
many questions just tell me I matter one
and so you can make the solution to say
oh this this has got 5 or 10 milligrams
per milliliter of solutions and you have
a little a little test tube or some some
volumetric flask or somethin and measure
out exactly how its potent and it works
yes we all want to try some of that hunt
likes likes the doctor and dr. pepper
mix I was like to drop some in my dr.
pepper I hear it hits you with in like
15 minutes
it does sooner yeah it's definitely the
24th flavor and their consensus I mean
if you can stay awake did you like to
testify on this matter all right we're
gonna bring to the my car buddy hunt the
Grammy Gatsby he's hanging out in the
room
let's tell us a little bit about what
happens when you have consumed the
mother's milk how do you like this stuff
is a from the teat it is a smokeless
immediate type of effect we're like
literally after like three or four sips
or like a couple straws worth you can
feel it and if the drink is potent
enough within five to ten minutes you're
at you know pretty much euphoria and it
also can pounds itself are some sort of
like multiplier where it's like if
there's 60 milligrams in the cup it
really feels like 200 milligrams when
you drink it and some batches in the R&amp;D
phase were extremely chirpy and
unpleasant and other batches have been
refined into perfection very nice very
nice well thanks for your testimony kind
sir if you ever want to grab the mic
just jump in dude I know you're hanging
out over there and enjoy yourself squat
up nice so I guess the golden question
is over an hour drive home and it's
snowing and it's gonna be a bobsled ride
getting down this mountain where we are
this place is beautiful but getting down
tonight in the dark dude how about the
deer anybody else experience the deer
yes the deer that was some crazy [ __ ] I
don't know I grew up in a grew up in
Ohio lived in Colorado here for a couple
years and when we looked down here in
Colorado Springs I mean I always knew
the deers to be pretty damn friendly and
fearless but this [ __ ] was
trying to get in on the cypher or some
[ __ ] cuz you like back down like eight
of us came over startled us walk back to
the house he's like literally backed us
into a corner into the door we pulled up
into the driveway the cars and let this
at us like you got the pass or what and
then he came up to my window like ten
bucks
look at me in the eye you know bet bet
down to put the blonde out and like yeah
that's what you've bent over for right
got in he got ready to charge
he was ready he's like a four point four
point big boy what do you guys serious
about I'm gonna get him by the horns
comes back tonight I'll do it I know
jiu-jitsu man I'm gonna get them I can
play the spoons and the washboard to
jiu-jitsu don't work on dear bro I can I
even ask you about the clear am I
allowed to ask what can you tell me
about the clear a lot of my listeners
this is listen to people have listened
to by people from all over the world not
just people in Colorado or Kali's it's
up a lot of the people listening have a
hard time finding pot so the clear if
you just want to tell them kind of
basically they know if they probably
know about shatter and basic hashes from
listening gonna give them an update on
what the clear actually is that'd be
awesome
so clear is is a brand of product that
we in California and it was sort of the
first like I guess popularized a
purified cannabis oil that it was always
a nice high clarity and like low color
and you know kind of we're one of the
first quote solvent-free companies so
people have their own ways of making
these activated cannabinoids decolorized
and stuff and so we don't really speak
to how we do it just keep it always a
secret much respect so other people do
it and tell you how they do it but as
far as us we we kind of stick to just a
purification method and we have our own
particulars as to what machines we use
we build a lot of our own machines and
have our own processes and things like
that so it's kind of just particulars
and we have our own like unique flavors
that we then blend back in all natural
flavors that can range from cannabis
type flavors that have high doping
content to like you know your standard
your grape and you know we have sort of
a flavor department that we we know pump
out just flavors and try to keep our
those flavors derived from cannabis or
other products so they're all derived
from other products okay everything's
natural and none of them are like
everything you know for instance the
terpenes that we use are steam distilled
and all the flavors we use are you know
high grade and are all you know based
off of like a lot of essential oils and
we try to make sure things I've talked
to you for a couple hours and I trust
you I trust your judgment on that kind
of product so far there's a lot of you
know great uses for products like this
we can use them for topicals and edibles
and vapor cartridge isn't anything you
can really want to you know formulate so
it's kind of cool right I hear a lot of
good things about the clear we'll have
to get our hands on some I think that's
your department yeah it's out there a
few people that have it it's just in
Denver not in the springs yet so I got
to drive to Denver to get it greener
green and healthy wellness is interested
I think the boss is behind me laughing
he's like hey wait how can you say that
you do the grow I'll do the managing you
shut your face all right Jordan what's
up with her packs bro hey dude thanks
for the weight on the clear I appreciate
that
you got it I appreciate it what's up
with the turn packs brother oh we are
you know we're doing recreational
processing up in Denver right now we're
still doing medical process and down
here in Colorado Springs and have a
pretty large growth
is about to be up and running for our
medical wholesale gonna have a lot of
really awesome flavors that we're gonna
be making out of there everything that
gets grown in that facility has to be
extracted so you know have a lot of
really really awesome tips on what has
to be extracted full plant herbs then
also you know it's gonna be a pretty
exciting month we are going out to
Illinois in the middle of this month and
we are doing some consulting out there
with one of the first operators to get
up and running for medical cannabis in
Illinois we're gonna be going out there
to extract their crop and you know help
get their processing operation going
help them with some of the you know
processing preparation expand the brand
that's awesome we're not that's not
really a brand situation you know the
market and and Illinois is very small
that's more of like a consultation help
you know kind of do like a Cobra and
private label type situation where we go
out there and help create their brand
which is you know one of the first you
know they'll have some of the first
infused products available in the
Illinois medical cannabis market and
probably you know be some of the first
legal butane extractions to be dies in
that state if not the first we're also
going to be getting up and running in
Las Vegas within the next month which
exciting so that'll be right about when
this comes out this will probably come
out in about two or three weeks so right
when this drops
well yeah hopefully that would be right
around the time around the first of the
year where we're getting up and running
in Las Vegas that will be you know two
packs branded products that we're gonna
be nice on wax shatter vape pens things
like that throughout the Las Vegas
market are calif you know we originally
came out here from california and
they'll be pretty awesome because now
california patients will have access to
the products that we make again because
nevada has reciprocal medical marijuana
laws alright anybody
yeah reciprocity reciprocity shut up to
Dan for going to English classes grammar
Vegas and you have a California medical
marijuana card you can shop at a Vegas
dispensary you shop at a Vegas
dispensary Reno any Nevada Medical
Marijuana Colorado card there as well
yes sweet all right you guys are that go
to Vegas and take your medical marijuana
card go shopping get some herb yep they
are up and running out there so go get
some tur packs at the first of the year
dab it out definitely let you guys know
where the drops are happening how much
of that so you guys are talking about
nug runs all of the room you're growing
has to be made into Earl what percentage
of that and if I'm out of line just let
me know and I won't ask the question how
much of that product will actually be
sold as smokeable Earl and how much is
it will be sold to a vendor and turned
into something like a topical or an
edible or something I would say a
hundred percent of that will be sold as
smokeable oil you know it's we you know
we take pretty we take pretty good steps
in the grow to make sure that you know
we have really high quality we were able
to let people you know experience the
flowers but the fact that we can take
all that high quality flower product and
turn it into extract you know we want to
get as much of that branded tur PEX
awesome dog run flavor on the market as
possible so I would say most of that
product will be sold as smokeable oil if
we start delving into other products and
find that you know it's more beneficial
to do things that way you know maybe
we're working to that now but right now
the plan is to just make grandma dad or
wax live resin maybe some bubble 5 resin
you want to talk about wive resin for a
minute I heard you say something to a
client earlier the bottom line bro what
makes it live resin and what doesn't
just I've said this on the show and
people call me a hater well it makes it
live resin the fact that it's a live
plant that's cut down and then frozen
before it is dried then what machine do
you run it through we personally use an
emo tech at our Colorado operations as
well as the ones that we'll use and
and Illinois see guys I didn't even say
I didn't bait him we just let him say
his thing and he backed up everything I
have said nice thank you bro so what the
question really comes down to there are
some like little small distinctions and
like live resin some people will dry
like a slight bit and then freeze versus
like a full dry how do you feel do you
consider that any drawing it's the
immediate cut and freeze because some
people complain about like tubes o'clock
for two you know the live resin process
I'll just you know because because of
the way everything gets clogged and
everything like that I just would never
recommend doing it fresh frozen ice
water instead alright so if I do it
through like a sweet leaf am I still
making live resin is it gonna come out
the same
you know what machine you just gotta
compensate for to try to get the end
product that you're looking for you know
if the machine operates a little bit
differently just try to compensate make
you know it's a process you know I don't
really think you know live resin is what
do you guys prefers where's like type of
now grown here fresh dried yes there's
certain strains that come out amazing as
live resin that you know really tastes
awesome but I think those are looks like
the tangi tan geez yeah all those ones
taste amazing I was live resin but all
of those taste amazing
dry I think the main reason why people
like live resin so much is because the
color yeah totally
coming brings out a lot of flavor but
certain types of certain flavors get get
muted down by like this kind of watery
but certain strains in live resin the
Terps are amplified and other strains I
feel like it yeah others I feel like it
takes like a nice like dry and cure to
really bring out the chirps - they're
like maximum true aesthetically pleasing
as if it's cut down early frozen and
extracted true in the form you know it's
gonna look yellow yeah so yeah I've
learned to take the plants a little bit
early if I know they're gonna be oil the
actor looks so much better
it's definitely a definitely a tactic
that a lot of growers use all right
these days I just want to go around the
room what's your favorite train to smoke
as a flower and favorite to dab that's
funny I was just talking to Chris about
this my favorite was always the SF vog
and I haven't had it in quite some time
but uh that's my that's the ultimate in
flower and dad from the San Fernando
Valley
Oh G cush it's gonna I'm gonna if I ask
a lot of people if I asked 100 people I
bet 50 of them would say the SF vog it's
awesome and probably 40 of them didn't
smoke the real one Oh Chris is speaking
about it already you want us to skip you
all right Brian favorite strains I
really like smoking Jack Herer flower
okay and really any any African sativa
just love okay I think it's 10 lean is
the common terpene there's I really like
those get up and do things during your
day when it's done right it's done it
can be done so well I want to assume
that Turpin alene is a terpenoid it is
correct
Chris I want to hear about one of the
isomers of Terp Terp anine I can't
remember ed believe it's gamma and
[Music]
has a very distinct smell and is
attributed to like the jack and XJ type
smells and a lot of times can be a very
like overpowering note in like a lemon
haze or silver haze or something like
that very fairly common in like
hybridized definitely yeah Dutch treat
in there as well
you can really that's I think like if
you're gonna get into turbans that's
when you're gonna be able to pick up
more than a little different okay what's
your favorite stream yeah
and is that flower that's gonna flour
and lemon strain we got that we call
Lemongrab and we got apparently you know
just passed down through a number of
people through arm farms up in Seattle
and it was apparently some 20 year old
lemon from soma and it is just a killer
strain it just makes this like just
intense lemon and has no no no lean
taste and it's a lot different than you
know the common lemons I think we talked
about yesterday a much different than
that yeah lemon strain we had a nice
harvest that we grew in-house and so
nice it's all you my friend I mean a
good you know flower and a burrs uh
that's a flower you know just one
swisher Sweets a granddaddy purp
today but you know granddaddy perps
probably a favorite but you know mainly
more you know I really love Oh g-good Oh
Gigi cut oh geez my particular foodie
palette over here most of the room one
for the oh geez yeah I would say the oh
geez and Kim's yeah and definitely camp
I've been going really heavy on like
some chem DS and candy ones lately but
mainly you know g-code OG flowers dad
I'll cook it up from not from time it's
a unique thing yeah if there's no
cookies distinct break it up and you get
a little something different you know
you guys compared the number fours with
s ones we got from the Prophet out in
California we have not popped those just
yet now that we've got this new
warehouse far enough I think we're gonna
check them out and we have the cut of
the GG for so I've grown a ton of GG for
so I'll be able to recognize it a little
bit so we were talking about the
granddaddy purple and I said it's not my
favorite I'm gonna kind of diss your
strain here but then I've got the two
guys in the room that are gonna be able
to explain to me why I don't like it
when I smoke granddaddy purp snow matter
and it's a lot of purple buds do this to
me when they're dried and cured they
taste like they are still wet is that
have you experienced adders that make
sense to you that it's taste like
there's moisture in the bud or I don't
like the flavor of granddaddy perps the
moisture content shouldn't be affected
directly I don't think it's actually
moisture it just tastes like wetness or
perps and my floral these are just
different sort of like floral top notes
terpenoids things that are like a little
bit less like elucidated I would think
you like the Cannabis sort of spectrum
relative to like the symbol turban so
you've got like a situation where like
how they age and how they oxidize is
kind of dependent so you may get that
effect but some people might identify
that physical frog [ __ ] every time even
when it's dried and cured properly you
know Grandaddy perps a fickle fickle
lady you know what I mean the purple
Oracle there's different fee knows and
cuts I feel like there's definitely one
that's like a little bit heavier I'm
like the cardboard which may be kind of
what you're talking about a little bit
it kind of swell you know it kind of
smells like maybe it was cured in a way
that being said though I don't know
where you're getting a lot of your GDP
from but what I said true dat but yeah
GDP you were growing or was this GD you
know I've never grown it because I'm not
if I've never been a fan GDP was hugely
mass produced rain out of California for
quite some period of time and was one of
the you know massive commercial-style
grow warehouses where they're sending it
across the country I'll grow the [ __ ]
out of it I'll trim it myself purple
leaves not purple trichomes affirm from
that mistake different color bubble
coming out and I'm pretty sure I promise
taking those make roasted purple leaves
right and not in the trichome how it's
done you can have green
you know yeah nice yeah the black shirt
oh go for it bro I talk a lot say green
grapes in my favorite they'd like purple
leaves but all right
the black cherry Kim is well known for
its purple but one of those green
phenotypes is amazing it's one of the
keepers yeah that's my only and it's way
out of the purple range is that black
sure you came it grows purple but it
doesn't taste like anything else purple
all right hey I wanted to ask you what
happened to why did the original Terp ex
Instagram get the kibosh what happened
their suits came in and said it's time
to clean it up few weeks
yeah they got so far as to get ahold of
somebody over there and they you know
told us oh really any sort of pricing
information no contact I'm opening my
Instagram right now to see if I've got
contact info on there because they shut
me down at 50 was it 19 K and I'm at
like 1500 and I feel dumb well
Oh
[Music]
catchy Instagram why do you suck
we just wanna take nice pictures of weed
and slabs it's not too bad
[Music]
Celie needed xanax on their pages you
should really be worried about them and
not us - I've got crack DM me for info
I've got lean DM me for info I'll get
you whatever you need
yeah Instagram we're coming for you and
would not take it no for an answer we
will post pictures of our slabs and our
glass and our weed [ __ ] you indeed yeah
I just wanna post that was the Instagram
song ladies and gentlemen do you guys
have a band name are you just the
terpene yard sock butthole in the brown
stock butthole yeah that's a great segue
now I think what has been demanded miss
damsel just walked by and wanted to hear
the butthole song is there such a thing
as the butthole song that happens
between you two what would it take to
get you boys to riff a little bit of the
butthole riff here on the show for me I
think you would probably take those we
might have to pause real quick and come
back once we get the whole yeah that's
not gonna happen
whole riff and we'll see if we can tempt
this young man to sing some butthole
jams for us here we go ladies gentlemen
butthole Jam Volume one live on the girl
from your heart podcast brought to you
by dandy rolling from our hearts right
now remember this is what you guys do
did for
your life is less important than the Sun
have you ever seen a cute little
butthole
it's highly inappropriate that you just
wanted to maybe paint a picture of it
and maybe do some other things as well
[Music]
like
put your tongue in the butt
yeah you know that we like to lick lots
of butthole
it tastes so good it tastes so sweet
tastes kind of like a coconut meat hey
Jeff when was the last time you ate but
more recently than I care to admit its
what a lucky guy
to have those bottled Terps for dinner
every night I'm sure she won't fight
[Music]
it shines like a diamond when you're
done cause it's so damn clean making but
is serene
if I don't like it for a while I get
mean
[Music]
we gotta blow off some steam keep it
clean
you know my favorite strain is Blue
Dream
[Music]
Blue Dream kinda tastes like a strippers
ass crack
I am piney
[Music]
strippers love to dream strippers love
the dream if there's one thing I know in
my years in this game blue dream make
strippers go insane blue dream and some
glitter on your butthole that's how you
know you are smoking that strippers
delight dream
[Music]
yeah here first the butthole song segue
into a little bit of a movie I haven't
heard that performed in at least as long
as he's been a part I heard Jimmy played
that back [ __ ] Jimmy [ __ ] kills it
man yeah he's better than tre way better
man all right so we've got we've gone a
long time and I want to reward my
listeners everyone that's made it
through the butthole song that's made it
all the shenanigans let's talk about
hash we've got some amazing hash artists
here in the in the room everyone's nice
relaxed are all comfortable we're all
friends now what's coming up with hash
what's gonna be next we've got clear
Hersh
we've got dissolvable dr. pepper Terps
that's the truth everyone's talking
Terps everyone talks Terps they don't
even know it herbs means yeah most
people don't know what a team flavor
gonna call the flavor components and the
flavor is
terpenes and flavours turps and I think
you know got some people out there doing
some little terpene isolettes stuff like
that but I think the game's gonna be you
know sort of just keeping the essence of
cannabis so that everyone can experience
it and all the different formulations
you know it's like a kind of more of an
art and cannabinoids they're a little
bit more stable and flavors are kind of
like our you know perfumers and people
who do that sort of extraction but you
know doing it for their own methods and
I think cannabis hasn't quite matured to
that level of science and it's kind of
getting there just now been given the
freedom we were a little we were
prohibited from doing that
experimentation all right so you feel
like Terps are next do you look like you
got something important to say good me
we definitely have not been okay and so
some people have been doing some
research on unter beans for a while I
mean aromatherapy that's a lot of people
on that but it's
that's real because it's one of the
things that gets us I the way that we
want to use it for people using lavender
oil and stuff like that just in there is
it bedside steamers and stuff like that
or whatever the essential essence so if
I mean it's definitely real and so
incorporating that in the cannabis is
pretty cool yeah keeping keeping that
original essence and so coming up with
the different extractions and trying to
get just the terpenes and then get
plants that produce a lot of terpenes
and there's there's pretty neat
information out there in theories on how
you can influence the terpene levels by
soil management and like environmental
controls and stuff like that you know
this isn't the only industry where
turbines are prevalent or where people
want the turbines from what they're
about different things they want to be
able to extract those these other
industries and follow their lead you
said that environmental factors play a
lot into my terpenoids and my soil I
know you're not you're more on the hash
side than you are the grow game from
what I understand about you could you
give myself and my listeners one hint on
how we could improve our Terps in our
garden one thing that we could just stop
doing or start doing that would correct
our Terps I've got that all right sounds
good to me you guys you heard it here
he's gonna read that and find it look
like you got some to say Jordan rosin
breath slowly rosin bro Triple Threat a
lot of my friends listen to this podcast
I've tasted one person's rosin that I
liked everything else tastes like burnt
popcorn I get a lot of the burnt popcorn
yeah I had one guy my buddy Tim came
through and he had some properly made
rosin I think he made it himself he was
the only one who had rosin
I liked about that low temp high
pressure rosin from salt you don't want
that [ __ ] you don't want the cuticle
waxes all the stuff even if you did like
half a fish and rice if for any kind of
gets you away from that bulk of the
plant material and that's going to
increase your resin quality you're gonna
get a lot less of the the resin stuff in
the plant material and overall just
gonna be more of a pleasant experience
just kind of come up with a reasonable
sipped dry I sift or you know if you can
keep the moisture away you know people
are building out cold rooms doing do go
in the fold the full-length and so if
you can break that material down get
away from all that leaf there it is okay
so oh man that's a lot of work for a
home grower sometimes what's your what's
the most recommended way of getting some
dry sift out of that to work it into
rosin I mean I think you can just kind
of promptly break down
you know they got wrote at Machine okay
they've got ways of sniffing material
that can that are pretty efficient if
you just can I rosin my Keefe yes oh
yeah I see a bunch of head not come out
it tastes like burnt popcorn or since we
didn't use plant matter did it taste
right I mean it definitely tastes better
than what comes out of the flower you
know she didn't [ __ ] out as a classic
and always when it comes to any process
true that if it's key for not like
bubble like oxidation and plants been
through what should I be doing with my
reclaim I've got a drop down that's
probably got thrown it away just throw
it away CBN okay make sleepy time
sleepy time CBN heat it up make it in
and then just dab it again or be edibles
with it
it alright dabbing it'll have very
little psycho activity but you probably
find a calming sleepytime effect from it
we've got I've got a video going they
said can we season our nails with
reclaim yeah yeah why couldn't you bro
yeah you totally could buddy if you're
kind of like upset with your buddy you
know take some of his like oil and just
kind of use cleaning it brings the flame
in one thing one thing I've seen
recently I saw a picture on the internet
the other day of someone who had smashed
their fingers it was a girl because
there's girl fingers super you know low
temp high pressure situations and didn't
get their fingers out of the way and it
was not a pretty sight it looks like you
ran over a banana yeah yeah it was
terrible yeah most of you guys are you
stole your girlfriend's hair
straightener they're not using a
hydraulic press or anything be fair that
as goofy and stupid as it works actually
flower and a hair straightener is the
first time we tried it what was that
from the gorilla glue I remember I don't
remember your rosin virginity
unfortunately I think we're gonna run
into just like any of these other
extracts is that with some plants will
be better suited for PHS absolutely for
rosin you get certain heats intention
with certain turbines no bueno and
certain ones are fine so I think it's a
matter of like where do these if it's
all going towards oil then there's five
or six ways to make oil and that's gonna
leave different spectrums of which
plants get turn in the GDP maybe he gets
pressed and doesn't taste like so right
so whatever or maybe it's like you
really taste better when you get it
first I like the way you think my friend
yeah we got to get some Jesus key and
press it and then blast it and then make
bubble out of it and see if we can
convince me that I like that flavor
I think you're gonna think it's best in
flower form them all right let's get it
I'll grow it will smoke it me too me too
all of us we're in agreeance with that
just crawl me on over call me over
awesome alright so we've been going for
a long time our listeners have probably
checked out around the Blount whole song
so I hope a lot of people enjoyed that
extra bonus hash talk if you're paying
attention that's your bonus that's a big
shout-out to you cuz these guys are I've
got some of the hash mad-scientist the
forefront hash guys in the room here oh
I wish I would have been more prepared
but I have no idea these cats were even
gonna be here so this is pretty awesome
thanks for being on the show you guys
thank you Chris looks like he's got more
stuff brewing up if you've got more
knowledge you want to drop on these
listeners bro I will never stop you
[Music]
alright so I think it's time to wrap up
the show would you guys like to wrap us
up with another song would that be
possible let's just do some some dad
talk and some grown from your heart
maybe talk about boobs a little all
right all right well you guys start the
riff and I'm gonna say thanks everybody
for joining me I appreciate everybody
for being on the podcast you guys on
periscope I'm gonna close the video
thank you for watching oh you know what
let's just leave it on so you guys can
hear the song point it over at this guy
you can hear a song thanks for watching
on periscope good thank you for joining
me playing guitar
fist bump bro before you get going dude
mental fist bump from across the room
thanks for joining me follow the clear
scientist made a new friend in Brian
tonight learned a lot of great [ __ ] from
you already cannot wait to try the
mother's milk mother's milk
water-soluble THC that won't taste like
anything you just caused me hi
yeah I could use a nap sometimes then of
course Jordan thanks for coming on the
show and singing anytime you're my
favorite choirboy you know take what the
Lord gave you I appreciate each and
every one of you
the Jewish one the Jewish one you was
gonna go there thank you so I'll be back
I'm gonna let these guys sing a little
song when they wrap it up I will be back
to wrap up the show and say goodbye in
the official way I'm gonna set my
microphone down to take a DAB and enjoy
the song you guys thanks for listening
thanks for having us man oh dude thanks
a lot I appreciate the hash knowledge I
want you guys back soon enjoy the song
guys
[Music]
we are growing from our hearts busted
Jeff his Jets are as long as I'm tall
[Music]
and it takes lots of Debs Buster Jeff he
is growing Terps
for the created healthy shop these days
[Music]
while Kaku Daniel plays guitar
I need a DAB
I needed app so big and strong out of my
bog
Jeff wanted me to sing about boobs those
are my favorite days
[Music]
there's about 10 hot titty city
in this house
but unfortunately they won't let me take
off your blouse
[Music]
they're kind of
but they still have nice titties
[Music]
we got a drop from our heart
grow from your heart
[Music]
grow from your heart grow from your
heart
from your heart draw from your heart
we are growing from
hearts smoking dabs written parts
growing from
[Music]
alright guys if you stuck around that
long I want to give you a huge shout out
and I really want to thank you for
listening also a huge thanks to Jourdan
Dan Chris and Brian and also a huge
shout out to hunt from the Graeme Gatsby
and also damsel from green and healthy
wellness you guys threw a great party
and thanks again for letting me be a
part of that and also thanks for being
on the podcast
alright everybody I'll be back in
another week with another episode don't
forget to check out our sponsor hit man
glass make sure you follow hit man glass
on Instagram it's at hit man glass Dougy
also check out their website it's hitman
glass calm they have tons of great glass
available if you were interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review send
me an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com
I'll get you all the information that
you do need now that the show is over
you guys please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for grow from your
heart find the review section give me a
five star rating and after that type in
a little comment and let me know what
you think in the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode you
guys I'd love it if you follow me on all
of the social media you can find me on
Facebook it's a girl from your heart
podcast you can find me on Twitter it's
at G fyh podcast I'm on Instagram i am
at ireon der score genetics on instagram
you guys I had to restart the account
I'm sure if you follow the show you know
what happened I had like 19,000
followers I woke up one day and I did
not have an account anymore so I started
a fresh account the Terp x boys say that
if you don't post contact information
that you should be cool and your page
won't get deleted so I am going that
route and hopefully I get to keep my
page at this time so make sure you
follow me on Instagram I post a ton of
great cannabis related photography you
guys don't forget to the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always and forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
don't forget about the donation button
if you go to
genetics Colorado comm click on the
podcast tab at the top right there is a
donation button that goes directly to my
PayPal account you guys I'm never going
to charge you for this show this show
will always be free this podcast is my
gift to you
but if you feel like the show was worth
a couple of bucks and you want to make a
contribution
I would definitely appreciate it and if
you'd like I will give you a shout-out
on the show if you make a contribution
and you would rather me not give you a
shout-out make sure you type that in the
notes or email that to me because I will
give you a shout out automatically if
you do throw down on the PayPal so let
me know if you want to be anonymous I
want to send a huge shot it's my friend
Jessica hey Jess thanks for listening to
the show it was great to learn that you
listen that closely I definitely
appreciate it big shout out to Jessica
and her crew you guys I think that's all
I've got for you this week I want to
send a huge shout out to my ninja Spence
thank you again for listening and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
so
I'm calling onyx can do it alone
[Music]
even in this form is that Jesus can sit
down just a few words bring a fire in
that room that I send my seekers but I
can do it
[Music]
and execute
here comes the
[Music]
they're coming they're coming