[Music]
[Applause]
yeah Happy New Year cannabis community
it's time for episode number 113 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write up your new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a veteran
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots brood
yeah Happy New Year everybody hope you
guys had a great new year hope you've uh
made some new year's goals if you
haven't made some goals for the new year
you should grab a pen and a paper and
you should just write down a few things
that you want to accomplish in 2016 and
when you get that feeling of
accomplishment you're gonna want to
accomplish bigger goals so just write
down some goals and get that [ __ ] done
guys and also if you had some [ __ ]
in 2015 now is the time to shake it off
and leave it all behind if you haven't
forgotten about the [ __ ] of 2015
it's time to take a big old fat damn
smoke a big old fat joint smoked a fat
blunt hit the vaporizer however you do
it I'm gonna take a big old fat dab and
we're gonna blow out all the [ __ ] of
2015 we're gonna start fresh here in
2016 so we're gonna do that out of my uh
my brand new hit man short stack shot up
to the hit man crew you guys know me why
buy a rig I like to buy an American rig
something made in America by an American
so I buy a hit man glass
hit man glasses made by dabbers these
kids dab as hard as you and I do hit man
dougie is a dad enthusiast he's a
supporter of the hash movement he throws
a festival every summer in California
called the chalice festival make sure
you check that out you guys I'm gonna
hit my brand new hit man short stack I
don't think there are words to describe
this rig other than [ __ ] amazing so
I've got the email hooked up I've got a
big old glob of cactus cooler from Terp
X on the dabber you guys take a DAB with
me and then we will get on the show
let's inhale some positivity and love
and freshness and then we exhale we're
gonna exhale all the [ __ ] from 2015
let's take this dab together you guys
[Music]
all right well all right well I'm
heavily medicated now this will be a fun
podcast so shout it to the hit man glass
screw you guys make sure you follow hit
man glass go to hit man glass calm also
make sure you you follow dougie on
instagram at hit man glass dougie
support hit man glass glass made in
America by Americans made by guys who
dab just as hard as you are this music
will get off the show because I also
wanna make a huge announcement green and
healthy wellness is now open for
business we are a medical marijuana
facility in Colorado Springs Colorado we
are at 430 West Colorado Avenue if you
have a medical marijuana card we would
love to see you drop by pick up some
turf backs I pick up some Apothic and I
pick up some top-shelf flowers we'd love
to see you in there
a big shout out to Britt Carly
hailey buzzy and especially hunt the
entire crew a big shout out forgetting
that place going I'm proud of you guys
drop in give us a visit
what else do we have for business um
these sticker packs remember a few
episodes ago we did a hash tag and
everybody who messaged us on Twitter and
used that hashtag they are going to get
a sticker pack a couple of nights ago
Mike and I sat here and addressed
envelopes and I will be stuffing
stickers into those envelopes and they
will go out Monday morning so when this
uh podcast drops those stickers will be
in the mail one day the same day so by
the time you hear this the stickers are
on the way to you I've only got let's
see how many do I have here they're
addressed I've got one I've got two and
the third person already got there so
I've only got two so if you were
involved in that and you need to send me
an address similar address to grow from
your heart a hot meal calm and remind me
that you deserve stickers from the hash
tag I like it when you ramble sticker
giveaway remind me I'll get to your
stuff what else do we got in I need to
give a big shout out to my buddy frosty
I bumped into my friend frosty at the
candy Canyon dab Club the other day
frosty I smoked that cush bud that you
gave me [ __ ] dude I was high that was
awesome thank you I smoked that this
morning was the first thing I smoked and
made my eyes a little droopy made me
want to be nice and lazy for the day
good Weber I appreciate it it's always
wonderful to receive
gift of cannabis from friends it's super
great when your friends tell you that
they listen to your podcast and learned
how to improve their cannabis from
listening to the show and then they give
you buds that they grew so shot at the
frosty that's super good weed dude I
really appreciate it you did a good job
well flushed well cured and super
bleeped rimmed I like your work man I
gotta give a shout-out to everybody at
the canna Canyon I dropped into the
candy Canyon and everybody there is
super kind you guys when I walk in
everybody's like dab this dab this try
this I tried some live resin I tried
some butter tried some shatter smoked a
little bit of everything I had some
solvent lists at some fool mill had a
little bit of everything the last time I
was there I really appreciate the way
they treat me there and shine that's all
my friends at the candy Canyon a shout
out to Camille shoutout to everybody
over there I'll be doing an episode from
there really soon that features our
friend Fox tracks so keep your ears open
for that one alright guys so let's get
to the point of the show I've been
telling you that I was going to make a
checklist of things that you should be
taking care of in your garden so I did
that for you I've got a list of things
you should do daily weekly monthly
things you should do after each harvest
and also things that you should do
yearly there are a couple things on that
list so I think I'm gonna take a DAB and
a drink while you guys listen to a
couple of seconds of reggae music and I
will be right back and we will get into
this checklist
[Music]
choppy bottom easy go evil uncle file
when we try the 9000 haven from done try
them last night
easy boy o'clock even one time said it's
not that easy
alright guys I am back and I am ready to
get into this checklist I hope you guys
think it's a bad low I was taking dad's
I just hit some cactus cooler from turf
backs if you've ever a cracked open a
can of cactus cooler or taking a drink
it's exactly what this hash tastes like
it's kind of got my mouth watering you
ever taken a DAB that made your mouth
water usually your mouth goes dry excuse
me for coughing into the microphone I
was listening to a podcast today and the
co-host was just coughing into the
microphone err I really wanted to turn
off the damn show so I apologize for
coughing into the mic anyway on this
check list here we go this is stuff that
I feel you should be doing every day
some of this stuff will vary if you've
got a hydro garden some of this stuff
will be different if you've got a soil
garden some of this stuff will be
different based on the size of your
garden some of this stuff will have to
be done over a course of a couple of
days some of this stuff will have to be
if you've got a little garden this stuff
is just things it'll take you two
seconds so here is what I've got for
your daily checklist daily visually
check each plant for bugs moulds or
signs of deficiencies or over
fertilization and correct if necessary
oh you got to get in there I walk in and
I just pick a random plant and I just
pull a random leaf off of a random plant
I flip it upside down and I look at it
and I make sure there's no bugs
I feel the leaf I can tell by feeling
the leaf how healthy the plant is I can
kind of rub on the leaf and tell but I
like to pull leaf off look for bugs look
for molds I look around the room see if
any of the leaves are yellow or crispy
or crunchy or if anything's happening if
you've got anything weird going in there
work on correcting it something I should
add anything that can be done today do
it today don't wait until tomorrow
you've got plenty of [ __ ] to do tomorrow
whatever you can do today do it or you
just keep adding [ __ ] up for tomorrow
and then tomorrow never comes and then
one of these days you're gonna have a
big-ass list of [ __ ] that you never did
you're gonna find problems and you're
gonna in your grow and you're gonna know
why it's because you didn't do that list
of [ __ ] that you should have been
keeping up on so try to stay on top of
your chores you guys that's what I'm
saying so check your plants every day
you should be touching every single
plant you should be putting your eyes on
every single plant get in there and love
them so the second thing on my list here
check to see if the plants
water you can check visually I can see
if the plants look droopy at all if
they're starting to lean over if the
leaves are kind of hanging down they
need water or lift up the pot and check
the weight the standard way to do this
is think about it this way water your
plant water until it's full freshly
watered pick it up and see how much it
weighs that's its full weight when it
weighs half of that it's ready to be
watered again you need to pour in water
and get it wet again so second thing
check to see if the plants need water
the third thing I would do every single
day pull any dead leaves and put them in
a trash bag or a trash can that gets
removed from the garden area I don't
like to leave my trash bag or my trash
can in the garden that doesn't make
sense to me I want to get that out of
there um one of the reasons being I
apologize for all the coffee and
cleaning over the throat that'll end
here pretty soon took a couple of fat
dabs ah the reason I like to get
yellowing leaves out of the room is buds
are attracted to yellow leaves bugs see
yellow leaves as a perfect opportunity
the outer layer of the leaf has been
softened and they can bite in and get to
the juicy insides of the leaves a little
more easily and bugs know that so
they're attracted to yellow leaves
that's why your sticky traps are yellow
so get all the yellow leaves out of
there put them in a trash can put them
in a trash bag and get them out of the
room because those are gonna attract
bugs so get that [ __ ] away from there
the next thing I would recommend check
the clones in the domes for moisture I
checked the humidity levels in your
clones and check for roots and if you've
got roots to transplant them put them
into the next uh if they're going into
the next size Rock we'll put them into
there if they're going into cups with
soil throw them into there I think they
got roots do whatever you need to do if
they need moisture or humidity adjust
that [ __ ] get in there and fix it you
can fix the clone domes really easily so
the next thing to do check the temps and
the humidity of the room and adjust that
if necessary you guys try to aim for
forty to sixty percent humidity during
your bloom phase and then during the veg
phase you can be around sixty to seventy
percent humidity I wouldn't go any
higher than seventy percent humidity and
trying to have some airflow along with
that or you will get some issues try to
keep the daytime temperature around
seventy to seventy seven degrees I
really like 74 degrees plants really
like 70 for some of the sativa is like
to get up to 77 during the
cycle during the night cycle try to stay
within 10 degrees of what your day cycle
is so if during the day you're getting
77 at night you want to be at 67 or a
little higher don't go more than 10
degrees swing from day to night so
during the day 72 77 during the night 60
to 65 degrees during your night cycle is
what I try to aim for another thing that
you need to do that a lot of people
forget to do and I can tell by your
Instagram photos sweep the damn floor
all you gotta do is get a broom and a
dustpan and a bucket and sweep the floor
scoop up that [ __ ] that you just swept
up into a dustpan dump it into the
bucket get it out of there and put it
into a trash can and get it out of the
house all that [ __ ] on the floor first
of all it looks terrible why do you want
that [ __ ] on your floor in your grow
room it looks like [ __ ] get the leaves
off there get the dirt off there get
that uh the UH I can't think of what
that shit's called right now that white
stuff that sucks the step on the perlite
get the perlite up off the floor ah just
sweep up you guys it's not that hard
every leaf on the floor every little
piece of debris that's a good spot for a
bug to hide if you've got a problem with
white flies fungus gnats spider mites a
fidex that's another spot for a bug to
hide one little tiny bug can hide under
a leaf and lay so many eggs don't give
him the opportunity you guys fight the
battle at your advantage don't give
these bugs a place to go so sweep the
floor ah
the next thing I would do check any
equipment check your hydro pumps Chuck
the EZ cloner pumps check your
dehumidifiers if you're running hydro
check your mix pump in your reservoir I
know a lot of guys have a big res filled
with nutrients you just put a pump in
there to shoot the nutrients around
check that pump make sure it hasn't
gotten clogged up those pumps have
little filters on them they like to get
gunky if you're using any kind of feed
system check that thing make sure your
sprinklers haven't gotten clogged up if
you've got an EZ cloner check the water
level in that as well and refill it and
adjust the pH ah
so the next thing you should do check
the pH in ppm levels if you're running
any hydro if you've got a flood and
drain kit if you're doing buckets or
whatever check your pH also check your
ppm you need to adjust your pH you need
to adjust your PPM's almost every day
I've seen large hydro Gardens need to be
topped off every day if not twice a day
because of
evaporation and plant productivity and
every time that water evaporates and you
add more water you've got to adjust the
pH so check that [ __ ] out all the time
every day if you can twice a day if you
can on that if you're running hydro
hydro guys may have a little bit more
work to do than our soil guys but we've
got a lot of soil and dirt to deal with
so the work will kind of math out I
guess I'm not sure I'm gonna run a real
hydro garden myself so I can't speak
correctly on that but it seems like you
have a lot of cleaning and a lot of
maintenance to do on a hydro grill so
what's next
prune and train the plants and shape
them the way you want them for your grow
space that's something you can be
working on every single day keep in mind
how you want those plants to be shape if
the architecture correct so that you
have sturdy plants try to use up as much
canopy space as you can with each plant
so prune and train your plants take off
all the shitty leaves take off any
little sucker leaves that are happening
just get rid of that crap make the plant
cells alright excuse me
so the next step lollipop any small crap
while you're in flower all those little
tiny buds that are happening on the
bottom just crap cut that crap off
you can Wally pop all the way up through
week four I've done it up into week five
once you get the hang of it you can
really get carried away you'll know what
to cut off you'll know what to leave so
when you're new at it only do it for the
first couple of weeks I guess until you
get the hang of it and then once you've
gotten a few crops under your belt that
you've ollie popped you'll be able to do
it up in a week four or five without
pissing the plants off I've done it too
late and caused from aphrodite that's
why I warn you to go light and then
learn how to do it so lollipop stuff
take off all that small crap and flower
pull off any funky leaves while you're
there so the next thing that you can do
every single day you guys take notes on
everything you do everything you do just
write down what you do I run a large
grove for green and healthy wellness
basically the owner of green and healthy
wellness has put me in charge of the
grow what I say goes he doesn't ask me
any questions as long as at the end of
the harvest
there's our goal weight of quality flour
nobody's gonna [ __ ] with me and I'm
gonna reach that goal
but the OCD person in me the person that
likes to be accountable I make notes of
everything I do all day every day if I
open up my phone we could read exactly
what I did not exactly probably but I'm
pretty close to every step I did today
from walking in and checking the Clones
walking the roads and checking each
plant fixing the sprinklers like I write
down what I do every day just to keep
accountability and to keep myself
reminded of what's been done so that if
something goes wrong I can look back on
that and go oh look who's right here
when I makes this stupid [ __ ] together I
messed up also you guys a good reason to
take notes this industry is expanding
rapidly and we're gonna have marijuana
available in every state before too long
when states start legalizing cannabis
and it's time to hire professional
growers you guys that took good notes of
all your grows you guys are gonna have a
portfolio basically an application or a
resume right there on paper you can see
look I took notes so that shows that
you're organized it shows that you're
accountable it shows that you're
planning it shows that you're thinking
it shows that you're serious all the
other guys are gonna be able to say well
I grew this much weed in my mom's
basement and they're not gonna have any
pictures or any notes or anything like
that
so you guys are taking notes you're
gonna have the advantage there so take
notes on everything you do I talked
about that a lot but it's something that
I think is really serious in a cannabis
grow what if you do something different
this time and it comes out perfect
you're gonna want to know what you did
the only way you're dumb high ass is
gonna remember is if you wrote it down
cuz you're smoking too much good weed
cuz you're growing too much good weed so
write [ __ ] down and that is my weekly or
my daily to-do checklist I'm now gonna
move on to weekly so this is stuff that
you should be handling once a week I
like to pick Mondays and just kick
Monday's ass I get all the chores done
on Monday and then through the rest of
the week you can just focus on the
plants and keeping everything clean and
doing all that stuff so every Monday
this is what I would do I would start
each week with a well plan to feed in
each room if you've got a clone area if
they've got water in trays or in a
cloner dump that water out put fresh
water in there fresh nutrients whatever
you're using if you're using a and B in
the cloner or if you're using rapid
start or if you use a clone X whatever
put fresh solution in your clone er get
it going fresh on Monday or whatever day
you choose to start but once a week
clean that sucker out and get it going
fresh also water all of your
vej plants feed your veg plants with a
strong nutrient solution on Monday if
their little babies maybe just some a
and B if they're getting a little bigger
maybe throw a little liquid karma in
there if they're getting even bigger
maybe they want some potassium silicates
and maybe some cal-mag in there you
should definitely be feeding your veg
plants a little bit of ruin oculi also
get those roots going so also feed your
flowering plants a well-planned feed
each week if it's time to flush you need
to start flushing and that's another
good reason to take notes then you know
when to flush if you guys need help
planning your feeding I did an episode
all about feeding your flowering plants
so episode number 69 will give you a
weekly planning a weekly schedule of
what to feed your plants while they're
in flowers so if you want to check that
out that may be useful for you so every
week feed your plants a well feed a
well-planned feed ah the next thing I
would do every week is dust all of the
fans you guys those fans get dirty
I just dust the backs of them off if you
want to take off the screen and clean
the blades every week that would be
super cool of you your room would
appreciate it all of that dust is going
to end up in your dabs if you don't
clean the fan think of it that way the
next thing I would do
check the timers for proper time and
function be there when the lights come
on a couple of times a week I know you
can't be there all the time when the
lights come on but if you can try to be
there if the lights come on at nine
o'clock just be standing outside of the
room like 857 so that when the lights
click on you can hear it go click and
then you can open the door they can make
sure the timer is working and then be
there again when the lights go off so
just check the timers for proper time
and proper function every week I would
calibrate your meters if you've got a pH
meter you should have one of those
calibrate it get the 4 the 7 and the 10
solution and just calibrate that thing
once a week if you're a small time
grower and you have a hydro short hydro
store near you that you frequent they
will probably calibrate your pH meter
for you they'll be nice and do that as a
courtesy so calibrate your pH meter you
should also have a ppm meter calibrate
that as frequently as you can at least
once a week that can make a huge
difference in the quality of your
flowers if you're measuring something
and your meter is telling you that it's
at 7 but it's actually at 5 and you're
adjusting to get to 6 5
you're actually gonna be justing down
into the fours and you're really gonna
cause problems so calibrate your meters
you guys the next thing I would do at
least once a week is check all your
blowers and fans and make sure that
they're not clogged or restricted in any
way most of the time this you can be
done visually you can look around the
room and see that everything is working
maybe put your hand if you've got a big
vortex blower just put your hand on the
outside of the vortex blower and feel it
vibrate listen to it you'll know if some
shit's wrong but just pay attention to
that stuff if it's clogged up that could
be a fire hazard if it's clogged up that
is going to cost you electricity because
that fan is spinning and you're not
getting blowing out of it but you're
using electricity because it's spinning
and trying to break free from that hair
clog or whatever you've got in there
those leaves that are clogged in there
so just check those out guys before you
go sticking your fingers and any blowers
unplug them and give them a long time to
quit spinning they spin for a long time
and just the the natural force of those
fans spinning on their own weight that's
enough to put a nice cut on your finger
so watch your [ __ ] fingers those
blowers I've cut myself on a blower
before it sucks more than you would ever
know take it from me there's blood sweat
and tears in my garden and that's where
the blood came from so the next thing
you guys visually check the ductwork and
make sure that everything is sealed up
were blown a lot of pressure through
these ducts
where the ducting connects to the lights
where the ducting connects to the blower
where the ducting runs out of whatever
room you're using just make sure that
all that stuff is sealed also clean your
air stones if you're making any kind of
tees or running any hydro or if you've
got cloners with air stones or if you've
just got water sitting there to get
bubbled to get the chlorine out clean
the air stones you guys those things get
murky sometimes you might just want to
throw them away and replace them they
are not that expensive if you've got a
few bucks just go buy new ones
the next thing clean your dehumidifier
or humidifier filter in Colorado we
probably don't even have a dehumidifier
in most rooms we use a humidifier in
some places but clean those filters they
get funky that [ __ ] gets dirty anything
that has water running through it
frequently needs to be cleaned it'll get
gross just clean your [ __ ] if you're
running hydro clean out your reservoir
every week to ten days and start with
fresh water and fresh nutrients well
like I keep saying water that sits
around that gets old it gets gross shits
able to grow in there things can
colonize in there you don't want that
you
fresh stuff if you're running easy
cloners do the same flush out those easy
cloners I talked about that a minute ago
just dump it out fill it with fresh
water fresh nutrients pH it and get it
going all over again your plants will
love you for it you don't want to drink
old funky water do you like you don't
even leave your dog's bowl sitting there
for too long without putting fresh water
in it don't do that to your plants love
your plants they're family too so
something you're gonna need to think
about weekly you need to you need to
dispose of your grow room trash
carefully when the trash man comes
you're gonna wanna I would wait until
the morning and take the trash out till
you when you know he's coming don't
leave that trash sitting out there on
the curb overnight if it's out there on
the curb your trash is accessible to the
public and it is legal for police
officers neighborhood kids hungry
homeless people curious neighbors
whoever private investigators anybody
can walk up to your trash and look
through your [ __ ] and they can take it
if they want those guys stole my trash
yeah they can do that they really can't
sir if you don't know what I'm talking
about I apologize that was kind of
cheesy ah but your trash is fair game if
it's out there on the curb and if you've
got a whole bunch of leaves in there and
you live in a state that is not legal to
produce cannabis you could have a crime
that could be evidence of a crime right
there so be careful dispose of your grow
room trash very carefully if you're
doing a large grow take it to the dump
yourself the guys at the dump don't give
a [ __ ] just take it to the dump have it
in big trash bags just go drop it off
they don't care that you're dropping off
wheat leaves those guys have their own
business going on so uh dispose of your
grow room trash carefully another thing
I would recommend doing weekly look
around the grow room look on the walls
and the ceiling and the floors and look
for any mold or moisture if you've got
condensation happening somewhere figure
out why that's happening correct it if
you've got any mold I've seen blue mold
form on the walls and grow rooms I've
seen a little green mold form on the
walls and grow rooms clean that [ __ ] up
get rid of it use h2o to use bleach use
peroxide use something strong if you
want to go organic do that do your thing
but clean that [ __ ] up that is unhealthy
for you it's unhealthy for the plants
figure out why it's happening and
resolve the issue to make it not happen
once you've cleaned that you've got to
figure out what caused it and stop it
from happening or it'll just come back
mold is a [ __ ] you can clean mold I saw
somebody clean mold off of a wall they
had a spot
this is about the size of a quarter
maybe a 50-cent piece and she scrubbed
the mold with bleach and hot water and
she called me the next day and she's
like come over here I want you to see
this and I walked into Matt mold had
formed into like a four by four square
it just grew that much in like 24 hours
it was so ridiculous so if you've got
mold figure out what's causing it clean
the [ __ ] out of it you may need to call
a professional eventually don't ruin a
rental home growing weed god I apologize
for clearing the throat so much in this
episode but I've got a whole bunch of
good dabs from the Terp station so I'll
shut up the Terp acts you can blame all
the throat clearing on Jordan that
sounded grosser than it was meant to but
there we go
so that's everything that you should do
in my opinion stuff you should do weekly
I'm gonna move on to things that you
should do monthly if you're running
hydro or if you have a feed system I
recommend that you clean the lines out
some way um who recommended it to me I
remember who said it Shane it was our
friend Shane Shane recommended that you
use an air compressor to clean out the
lines of your hydro system to blow any
clogs so if you've got a feed system
he's got a hydro system clean that [ __ ]
out if you've got little sprinklers
clean those out if you've got rippers
clean those out just you might have to
hand poke them you might have to get
something pokey then just hand poke each
little hole out by hand but you need
them clean so clean the [ __ ] out of
those monthly clean your air conditioner
filters that's something that needs to
be done monthly also test your smoke
detectors you should have smoke
detectors in your grow rooms yes you
don't want that [ __ ] burning down if it
catches on fire you want a heads up so
test your smoke detectors replace the
battery if necessary that should be
obvious there's nothing like hearing
beep beep all the time when you're
growing and batteries trying to die it's
the worst sound ever I don't know how
anyone can live with that another thing
you should do every month clean the
glass in your reflectors you guys this
may need to be done more or less often
depending on your style if you're
spraying and there if you're using a
foliar spray that shit's gonna probably
end up a little bit on the reflectors
unless you're careful if you're spraying
bug sprays it's gonna end up on the
light reflectors clean that glass just
clean it out if you can slide the glass
out clean the inside sometimes your
carbon filter blows a little bit of
carbon in there just clean that stuff up
you're paying for the light to shine
it's taking electricity the light is
shining don't put a dirty lens between
the light and the plants that you're
trying to put the light on it just makes
more sense to clean it you're paying
full price no matter what you do so
clean that [ __ ]
and speaking of paying full price the
next step these may sound like no
brainers but pay your electricity and
water bills every month you guys you
should be okay running a whole bunch of
electricity and use it a whole bunch of
water but the first time you miss a bill
they're gonna come [ __ ] with you they're
gonna knock on your door they're gonna
want their money and that's when [ __ ]
can go wrong so pay your bills don't
ever try to ditch out on a grow bill
don't ever steal electricity don't ever
steal water just pay your bills should
be a no-brainer most of the people who
listen to this show should already be
doing that but don't ever steal if you
do get caught stealing electricity or
water the government I think here I was
told that they're able to charge you
threefold for what you use so if you use
a hundred dollars in electricity and you
get caught stealing it they can charge
you 300 dollars just because you stole
it so pay up front don't be a dick it's
well worth it all right that's my stuff
you should do monthly I'm gonna move
into things that you should do every
harvest every harvest you're going to
need to dispose of your sticks and
leaves that you have leftover there's
gonna be a bunch of sticks and a bunch
of leaves and a bunch of trim I'm not
the small trim you want to make a shout
of that but like a bunch of trim crap
that you don't want laying around you
need to get rid of that like I said
don't go throw-in that in the trash and
just leaving it out there you might want
to wait for the trash guy to come you
might want to find a friend who has a
construction site and get permission to
throw your trash in there don't go using
someone's dumpster because if you get
caught doing that bill that's a fine for
throwing your trash into somebody else's
[ __ ] and then they'll want to see what
you threw in there and then this cops
looking at you and your big-ass bag of
weed leaves and then you're trying to
figure out a story so figure out a
clever way a safe way a smart way to get
rid of all your sticks and leaves also
dispose of or compost or recycle all of
your soil carefully you don't want to be
in the backyard dumping out your old
pots and then your backyard ends up full
of perlite and it's all white and
speckly and the dirt doesn't look right
you can't be that guy so you have to
figure out a way to either dispose of or
recycle all of that soil that you use
recycling soil isn't as hard as you
would imagine it just needs to be
remanded and kind of stir
and then you can definitely use that
soil again so I figure out a way to do
that I've done a little bit of talking
about that on the show I'm still
experimenting it with it myself so once
I get good at it I'll do a full episode
on recycling soil I made a little note
about that so you're gonna have to learn
how to get rid of a bunch of dirt you're
gonna have sticks and stuff get rid of
that you're also if you're running hydro
you're gonna have rock wool cubes or
you're gonna have those hydroton clay
pellets I hate those things
you're gonna have to get rid of that
[ __ ] too somehow I'm pretty sure you can
recycle the rock wool cubes the hydrogen
pellets you can rinse them off and use
them again E and clean them but
eventually you got to throw those away
because they get funky so don't just go
throw don't go throwing those into your
trash make sure you get rid of those
safely and smartly smartly a word I
think so it is now also cleaner pots you
guys every harvest you should clean your
pots you should also clean your hydro
trays if you've got a 4x4 botanic care
tray or one of those 4x8 trays you
should clean those things you're gonna
think I'm crazy but here's how I
recommend you do it I throw in the truck
and just take them right to the car wash
and just line the pots up against the
wall and just spray the [ __ ] out of them
it's Colorado here everybody knows what
you're doing just go spray your [ __ ]
down nobody cares the hydro trays lean
it up against the side of the truck
spray the [ __ ] out of it throw in the
back of the truck take it home if you're
in another state that may be kind of
weird but if cannabis is legal just take
them to the car wash and hose them down
don't use any soap don't use the car
washing soap don't wax them just use hot
water on them with the high-pressure
thing just spray the [ __ ] out of them it
works really well so once you got your
pots cleaned I recommend you clean the
room thoroughly from top to bottom I
said earlier use h2o to use bleach use
hydrogen peroxide there are a thousand
other products I could say to use but
use something to get in there and
sanitize the room don't just clean it up
sanitize it our good friend Mike helps
me out when it's time to clean the room
Mike and I dress up in our little let's
get clean suits it's basically just our
shittiest clothes we have put bandanas
on our faces put our hair and crazy hats
go down in there and just clean
everything and by the time we're done
you can eat off the floor of my grow
rooms when they're freshly started it is
so gorgeous in there since I'm talking
about Mike I only give him a shout out
we recorded a podcast last night and the
recording sounded like
[ __ ] something went wrong in the
recording software and everything
sounded like robots sound like r2d2 and
Darth Vader and b8 having conversations
so I just deleted that I apologize to
Mike for that podcast never making it to
the air but you know he'll be back Mike
you'll be back bro I'm sorry that did
not work but you'll get over you got to
come dab and hang out anyway
so thanks for coming and let's get back
into the show sanitize your room every
harvest that's what I was saying I also
clean the floors and the walls in the
ceiling you guys wipe them down scrub
them down the ceiling gets funky you're
in there that's you it's humid you're in
there spraying pesticides are in there
Spring foliar sprays so that puts
moisture everywhere then it gets humid
water rises the ceiling is gonna get
funkier then you're gonna assume so just
scrub it you'll think it's clean you'll
hit it with the rag and you realize it
is not clean the walls obviously same
thing with the foliar spray same thing
with the humidity and the floors
everything lands on the floor you
spilled nutrients there even walk in
there it's just filthy clean mat [ __ ]
also inspect any seals you've made if
you've sealed up any windows or doors or
anything like that if you've put
caulking somewhere recaulk it if you've
taped it retaping also if you've put up
I put up hepa filters so if I've got a
wall between two rooms and I'm pulling
air from one room to the other I just go
to Lowe's and buy those little square
hepa filters and I just cut them kind of
close to the shape I want just staple
them to the wall I replace those every
time every harvest also I try to because
they get dusty they get dirty but they
keep all the funk out of the room so
just go ahead and replace those that's
always a good idea just those little
square hepa filters you can find them at
lowe's if you can't find those just use
like a any kind of filter will work for
it's just better than having the hole
where the air is moving open you just
want to put a filter over there to catch
the dirt or any bugs or anything that
may be trying to move around trying to
migrate from place to place
alright so yearly here are a couple of
things that I think you should do every
single year as a grower oh I forgot to
mention every harvest um that little
sleeve that goes around your carbon
filter take that off and clean it and
put it back on and good luck not getting
carbon everywhere the next time you turn
on your carbon filter there are tons of
tricks on that here's what I'm talking
about when you use a carbon filter every
time you move it you jar the carbon and
and then you put a blower on there you
plug in the blower to start blowing the
air through the filter just to use it
and then all that carbon you've just
stirred goes flying through all of your
lights and into your grow room you've
got to get you got to figure out a smart
way to catch that carbon what I do is I
blow it into a I've got a it's a what is
it I know what it is I can't think of
the Brants a Crown Royal bag because the
Crown Royal bag will let the air out but
it'll catch all of the particulate
that's coming through so I just put the
ducting into a Crown Royal bag and hold
it and plug it in and it blows into
there for a couple seconds and then I
just pull that off and seal it up and
I've caught all the carbon in there so
that's a trick a really weird random
trick to keep all the carbon from
blowing out when you got a new carbon
filter so take that little cover off you
guys it comes with the sleeve take that
off clean it it looks like [ __ ] when
it's all dusty anyway you want that
white and clean clean it up put some
OxiClean in the water get that sucker
wide again so yearly here's where we are
yearly replace your carbon filter the
guy at the hydro shop swears to me that
my carbon filters are gonna last two
years they do not um there was a guy
replacing I what's it called a
transformer in my backyard a couple of
weeks ago and he told me sir smells like
you got a skunk back here there were no
skunks back there that was a little bit
of grateful dog crossed a space clean
and it was sneaking up the whole
neighborhood because my carbon filter
needed to be replaced I've got a new one
sitting there now as soon as I rebuild
the room I'll have a fresh filter the
neighbours will quit smelling the candy
scented skunks so replace your carbon
filter they only last about a year
another thing that you should do every
year you guys have your fire
extinguisher checked and replaced or
charged they've got a little red yellow
and green gauge on them you want it all
the way in the green if it starts to get
too yellow it's not reliable anymore and
you need a new fire extinguisher you
neither you either need to go get it
charged or just buy a new one they sell
them at Lowe's they sell them at Home
Depot they're not expensive there
hopefully you never need it I really
hope you never need it but if you do you
want it fully charged I always have a
fire extinguisher near your Dro I've got
one I've got a veg room I've got a
flowering room there's a fire
extinguisher hanging on the outside of
my flowering room have it on the outside
if something goes if you hear that smoke
alarm and they're going off grab the
fire extinguisher check the door for
heat if it's stupid hot you have a
decision
to make do you want to open that door or
not open that door hit that [ __ ] with
the fire extinguisher that you've
already got in your hand you don't want
to open the door and run in there and
find the fire extinguisher in the smoky
hot fiery room so have it on the outside
and I really I prayed a job that you
never have to use your fire extinguisher
but I'd rather you have it and it work
and I'd rather you be safe then this
thing fail on you so I've got another
fire extinguisher right just outside the
bedroom also just that's where [ __ ] can
go wrong there are a lot of why it's a
lot of electricity just want to be a
responsible grower try to be responsible
so get your fire extinguisher inspected
and replaced once a year and I think
that's all I've got for the checklist
you guys I really want to thank all my
friends on Facebook I posted to Facebook
asking for some updates and a lot of
people contributed so many of you that
I'm not even gonna try to list everybody
so shout out to my facebook community
that helped out I truly appreciate that
there are some things I did leave out I
understand that things got left out here
you'll need to work on a pest management
system you'll need to integrate that
into this checklist somehow if you don't
see any issues you can simply spray once
a week with an organic application
whatever you want to use I use as a max
if there's no problems I just use it
like since I travel from so many Gardens
I hit my plants once a week with that as
a max when they're in veg just to make
sure that I don't bring anything home
from all the other Gardens I play in if
you see any issues in your garden you
may need to increase the frequency and
the potency of whatever you're spraying
maybe change the active ingredient to of
something a little bit stronger
hopefully you don't get any pests if
you're doing something preventative but
that's something you'll have to work
into this regimen here as well there's
also gonna be a point in time where
you're going to need to change your
lightbulbs we did another episode on
that every bulb is different every
garden is different we talked about
swapping out your thousand watt HPS
bulbs about every one two three harvests
I've heard people using them for a full
year I've heard people using them for a
while it's like I said earlier when your
bulbs start diminishing your eyes won't
notice it but your plants will and
you're still paying for all of the
electricity if you've got a thousand
watt bulb and it's like six months old
it's probably only putting out 60 to 70
percent of its output but you're paying
for one hundred percent of that thousand
wants to be running so go upgrade your
bulbs it
it cost that much money if you think
about how how much herb you're gonna
grow from a fresh bulb the difference
the cost of that bulb should definitely
be worth it so that's what I've got for
you on a checklist of things that you
should be doing in your garden don't be
shy to send me things that I missed if
there's something you want to add to
this if there's something I did wrong
let me know I want to hear from you no
matter what you've got to say send me an
email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com you can find me on twitter
it's at g f YH podcast you can hit me up
on Facebook it's simply grow from your
heart podcast if you know my personal
facebook you can find me there if you
know me you can text me you can call me
tell me whatever you want to tell me
about the podcast but I'd love to hear
what you think of this garden checklist
if there's something I missed let me
know we'll do a part to make sure you
guys check out the next podcast
it will feature kabuki Jay Fox and it
will be recorded live from the Canon
Canyon so big shout out to kabuki Jay
Fox of Fox tracks and the canna Canyon
in Colorado Springs don't forget to
check out our sponsor you guys hit man
glass big shout out to hit man glass
I've got a brand new hit man short stack
I really can't do this justice if I
destroy if I try to describe it with
words on a microphone it's five disc
perks stacked on top of each other and
they are welded together with what's
called a Jesus seal there are three
Jesus seals holding each perk together
the disks are actually donuts and there
is a tube that goes down the middle and
it's got a hammer head so there's a down
stem that goes into the rig it's got a
hammer head perk when you smoke through
it the water goes up through each disc
and then it goes to the top disc where
there is a drain that goes down back to
the bottom through the sinner I know I
just confuse the [ __ ] out of your head
but I will post a picture of the stands
to Graham so that you can check it out a
huge huge shout out to my friends at hit
man glass make sure you follow them on
Instagram I'll let them know that you
heard about them from the girl from your
heart podcast we would all appreciate
that you guys know that show's over I
would appreciate it if you go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart podcast find the review
section give me a five star rating and
after that type in a comment and let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode I know I haven't done that in a
while trying to save up a couple and
once we've got enough there I'll go and
read three or four or four or five
comments and we'll share that with you
so I'd appreciate if you go and do that
what that does is that exposes the show
to more people it'll move us up in the
rankings more people will see the
podcast more people will listen more
people will grow better cannabis and
that's the main goal here just get more
people to grow better cannabis um yeah
you guys don't forget to the shows
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm don't forget about the donation
button on the website you guys on the
top right if you go I read genetics
Colorado calm click on the girl from
your heart podcasts tab at the top right
there is a donation button that goes
directly to my PayPal account I've said
it before I'm never gonna charge you for
this podcast this podcast is always
going to be free but if you'd like to
make a contribution I would truly
appreciate it if you're curious where
your contribution goes it goes to paying
for the hosting of my website it goes
for things like new microphone covers I
try to have microphone covers for the
guests because they do this kind of
stuff here that they rub their faces all
over the microphones when they're
talking because they're new so I try to
have a cover for each guess if they
don't have to go rub in their face on
another person's mic cover I just think
that that's gross water bottles for all
of the guests but mostly it goes to
covering the Bluehost
website which is where I host or the
Bluehost hosting fee which is where I
have my website which is where I host
this show there's a hundred and thirteen
episodes up there so it does take a
little bit of bandwidth anyway I'm just
letting you know where that goes I'm not
begging if you'd like to contribute I
would definitely definitely appreciate
it I'd give you a big shout out on the
show send you a couple of stickers let's
see what else do I have for you make
sure you listen next week you guys will
have foxtrax on I think that's all I've
got please follow me on Instagram Irie
underscore genetics on Instagram I don't
give a huge shout out to my ninja spins
thanks again for listening and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
Oh
you