[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 114 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I want to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band for
letting me use their music on my show
big shout out to Kat kun the entire
mystic groups crew I also want to send a
huge shout out to my friends at Hitman
glass this podcast is brought to you by
our friends at hitman glass hitman glass
made in America by Americans you guys
know what I like to say when I'm
shopping for glass I like to buy
something that I know is gonna give me a
big fat rip and it's not gonna put water
in my mouth when I try to hit it I like
to buy a hitman glass you guys support a
hitman glass to visit hitman glass comm
make sure you follow my friend dougie on
Instagram it's at Hitman glass dougie
make sure you send him a little message
let him know if you learned about hitman
glass from the grow from your heart a
podcast he would appreciate that
and so would I so big shout out to
hitman glass today I'm sitting here
dabbing off of my semi-new it's fairly
new to me be a short stack from hitman
glass this thing hits like a champ I got
the short stack here it's the little one
with the 14 millimeter joint on it I've
got a highly-educated duality nail on
there
we have been pulling dabs of lemon G
from turf X and it has been a wonderful
day so big shout out to hitman glass I
appreciate the support make sure you
guys check them out so this episode is a
wonderful episode you guys this episode
features my friend kabuki Jay Fox
he has a company known as Fox Trax he's
known for the hashtag run CBD we're
going to talk a whole lot about CBD so I
think you guys should get out a notebook
because you might learn some [ __ ] and
I'm gonna let the music play for a
couple of seconds oh you know what
before I get that far I want to give a
huge shout out to my friends at the
canon
this podcast was recorded live at the
canna Canyon the candy Canyon is a
private social club if you've got an ID
that says you're 21 and over and you've
got a few bucks you can drop on into the
Canon Canyon sign up sign a member
agreement and you can hang out take some
dabs with us you can smoke some flowers
with us it's a really chill environment
the place is classy as [ __ ] I will have
Kamil the owner of the business on the
podcast here real soon in the meantime
check it out you guys it's at 1507 West
Colorado Avenue in beautiful Colorado
Springs Colorado there's a sign out
front it says the can of Canyon I will
be easy for you to find go check it out
all right I'm gonna fade out the music
for a couple of seconds and I will be
right back with our friend kabuki Jay
Fox all right welcome back ladies and
gentlemen we are here at the canna
Canyon in Colorado Springs we find the
address we are at 1507 West Colorado
Avenue in Colorado Springs we are at a
really cool place you guys this is a
place where adults 21 and over if you've
got an idea in a few bucks at the door
you can come in and you can hang out and
you can take dabs there are people from
Colorado here that are kind of heads in
the scene some a Colorado's finest is
here Colorado Springs is finest is here
and actually we've got people here from
Texas hanging out taking dad's being
beautiful there are ladies here there
are dudes here there are more ladies
than men here yeah it is pretty rare for
a cannabis club so big shout out to the
hey take care of yourself leaving the
club right now is my good buddy Jason
Margulis have a great day buddy be safe
on the road he's out of here so sitting
to my right I'm gonna introduce the man
the myth the legend mr. kabuki Jay Fox
how you doing brother I am great I'm
excited to have you here I'm excited to
be at a club in Springs where we could
just take some dabs we're gonna be doing
shows from here oh wow I feel like
because this place has a great vibe
shout out to Camille for inviting me
here after the whole do they treat me
like a VIP when I show up I haven't
turned a doorknob here every time I show
up somebody opens a door for me they
carry
Goody's informing it's a great place big
shout out to the club so uh our friend
Fox here I know you mostly as Fox I'll
probably call you foxy most of the show
that's for a month you are who I refer
to as my CBD expert if I've got a CBD
question I usually call you up so Wow
I guess what I should start with this
can you tell my listeners a little bit
about what CBD is okay
CBD just like THC is a compound
cannabinoid in cannabis that is non
psychoactive so let's say tea is a
psychoactive compound which obviously
gives us a great feeling CBD is a
non-psychoactive cannabinoid that has
different qualities that THC doesn't
have okay yes and I mean it's it's one
of 138 found in cannabis and it's like
you know we're [ __ ] 138 couldn't have
annoyed 113 oh wow I only know of maybe
12 or 13 yeah II was sitting down with
me and I was just like so THC is the one
that we all love it gets us high because
it displaced you said there is no
psychoactive effects to CBD no there's
more like a euphoric effect right you
know in high doses you can get kind of
like an elevated euphoria but it's
nothing like a psychoactive effect where
you feel high percent right I've smoked
a lot of CBD being in Colorado we're
blessed to have absolutely Biddy
available I'm not I don't smoke a lot of
CBD myself it doesn't do anything for me
I am a medical marijuana patient but I
don't need the CBD so I try to save it
for the patients trip we did talk about
it on one episode I will talk a little
bit later about the effect that had on
myself
yeah but I want to hear more about so
why are we going for the CBD it what
does it really do for you why are you so
enthusiastic about CBD if it's not
psychoactive okay well my story with CBD
is a little bit it's long we've got
plenty of time okay so in the long terms
of it when I was
young you know I'd lost a child to
epilepsy and so your own child
yeah I'm sorry but I never knew that no
yeah it's fired brother um that's that's
why I'm here and that's why raise
awareness
I lost my second child epilepsy I was
very young what happened I had no idea
about epilepsy at the time literally it
took me by storm there was a good
seven-year period where I had one - a
very confused place it puts strain on
every relationship around me all that I
continued to focus on at the time was
cannabis and I had no idea that it would
bring me round circle - something that I
dealt with and not really knew about
what had gone on until I met a parent
going through something similar with
their nonverbal autistic child who was a
cannabis patient in their state they
started telling me all about the wonders
of how CBD is working for them but they
have problems getting at problems
obtaining at the CBD that they were
getting was tainted and making their
child sick had random [ __ ] in it
absolutely terrible yes we didn't know
much let's say this is two years ago
that I you know contacted other parents
oh we didn't know what we know now and
what is available now it definitely
wasn't them yeah I've seen you come a
long way I've seen you uh the hash that
you brought today is amazing how much of
that did you make oh absolutely
only one of these actually the rest of
them are from companies that I love to
support you know all right you can shout
them out if you feel absolutely I've got
a little bit of a craft concentrate as
well as viola live resin and some
wonderful full mouth extractions from
natural mystic caregivers blueberry
cherry CBD you know I like to mix it up
man
you know usually with I run something
it's out of my garden and its first
donate to the patient so it's very
limited on the you know right batch
drops that I have so it should be so I
rather just you know I luckily in a
great place where a lot of our friends
there in the community in the industry
and they're killing it at what they do
so I'm happy to support any of them I
like the way you do things I've been
watching you on uh we should let people
know how they can follow you on social
media how can they find you on Instagram
and Facebook on Facebook I am kabuki GA
Fox and on Instagram I am at Fox Trax fo
x TR ace TCS go check him out while
we're talking you guys go make sure you
stock him a little bit excuse me I'm
coughing into the microphone he gave me
a big ol fat to have some solve unless a
few minutes ago and I'm still uh went a
little bit from it before though we got
to give a shout out to Bear Mountain
glass for the gorgeous what colors
exactly are those that is my Mountain
Studios custom one of one raindrop and
purple lollipop climbed up
it's a Cline but it's kind of a climb so
he calls the decline dose so that's what
I've kind of been calling it it's
gorgeous
thank you so much I get a lot of
compliments sort of peas almost an egg
sort of a feel to it as well with the
way that it's hollow there yeah
absolutely
almost like a hollow honey jar of sorts
yeah opals really if you guys follow me
on instagram its Irie underscore
genetics I will post a picture that I
took a nice picture of you guys and I'm
sure you can find it on Fox's Instagram
yeah we'll take it we'll take a pic of
that and take a pics of pic of us
together so man that's why you've got
the passion now I understand what put
passion into you that's why you came out
of nowhere and you're winning also
congrats on the cannabis cup thank you
so much it's funny that Jason who is
actually here
it was my material that I grew he ran it
we ran it together on a you know
wonderful unit that he had I think a
sweet leaf or something I think so and
then okay Caleb over there I got the oil
and cranked it out into the
award-winning chocolate bar that it was
so funny that you had all those people
in the room at the same time I'm kind of
in a room full of rock star
good work you guys for sure definitely
give a little shout out shimmy bars man
he's definitely cooking with the CVT
working to the Shumate Barzeh you cannot
there are a few left on the shelf down
there at the can of canyon come by
they'll tell you how you can get ahold
of those definitely try the peanut
butter it's very yummy my favorite was
the banana what was that a banana
something he gave me yes yeah that was
the the entry okay
the banana cream that was so delicious
walked around just slow for the rest of
the day it put a little slowness on my
day you know the oil that we used for it
it came back testing out at 71.3% CBD
okay ten point nine five percent THC so
really strong seven to one so when we
cranked out and did the math that he
dosed it out it came out to like 160
milligrams to that bar and I mean it was
almost the perfect ratio for just
literally having the calmest day we come
we gave some and donated stem to some
autistic patients that were having some
rage issues pediatric nonverbal so
obviously you know it's hard to gate
stuff like that and the results that we
were getting back from the parents were
almost immediate saying just from a few
chips of this chocolate bar they were
getting calming soothing effects and it
was really helping with those oh I could
see there's no way that I could be
rageful or angry after eating that thing
I was walking around day two of the
cannabis cup just in mellow bubble
around me it was beautiful
yeah alright so you said that really
helped the autistic children with their
rage what other things to CBD help with
okay these guys speed-sew CBD is a new
york protectant anti cancer so let me
pause for a second when I say anti
cancer we all know that THC kills cancer
cells CBD freezes the cancer cell in its
tracks so it can't progress or grow any
further but it will not kill it so anti
cancer is freezing it at bay it's best
it basically causes cell death in the
mutated cells and so that the tumors
can't grow anymore but there they still
exist if they're okay if you use a
conjunction of a high CBD heights
tht regimen with cancer you're bound to
basically stop kick fries and kill those
mutated cells and you know get back to a
healthier you know way of living yes so
CBDs in your protection so obviously
it's very popular with epilepsy and
other neurological diseases Asperger's
autism children on the spectrum
Crohn's PTSD anxiety it kind of goes on
it's almost anything that an adult would
be suffering from pretty much for my
headaches I don't even take any form of
aspirin or any I mean I have completely
separated all that with different
regimens of CBD and THC in just a
healthy cannabis regimen you know okay
Vina endocannabinoid system is very
important and we all as medical patients
have our own deficiencies in those
systems CBD is one of those all-around
protectants it's it's the vault it's the
multivitamin of the cannabis you know
world I like that you make a sticker out
of that yeah Centrum sticker it does so
much and in different variations and
ratios it can help so many different
things I mean Parkinson's cerebral palsy
nerve damage it goes it goes on and on I
mean it literally the in CBD itself
there's other spectrum of cannabinoids
cbn CBG cbc you know that all have
different medical attributes that aren't
psychoactive gets run hot kind of things
these are one of these is an
anti-inflammatory one of these is a
antibacterial one of these is a bone
regenerate you know I make a CBG cream
for a couple of patients that have this
rare disease called keen box disease
which is where your wrist is basically
dying and I came up with a salve that
literally supplies immediate relief for
people that have had the surgery have
that pain
I'm trying to make that more readily
available that's amazing that's amazing
that should definitely sway some of the
people I encourage people that don't
know a lot about cannabis to listen to
my show so that should sway them to
believe a little bit more in medical
marijuana and the uses as practical uses
and then we're not just in this just to
get as high as we possibly can yeah I
mean a lot of us are yeah take fat dabs
and get rekt but there's medicinal value
in actively use CBD and part of my
regimen all the time I don't just
advocate it or you know do what we do
with the genetics and you know the
breeding and just everything in general
I need you know I literally I know I'm
happier with it I'm calmer I'm a much
more productive person I don't have
going through some of the things that
you know I've gone through at a young
age you know that kind of you know it
weighs on you a little bit you know and
so it it gets hard sometimes literally
as soon as I started enriching my
cannabis diet with CBD I've noticed a
wide spectrum of problems that I was
having day to day really kind of just
have more control over I don't really I
don't let it get to me anymore and I
just find myself being incredibly more
productive I feel the same way about THC
yeah exactly see and I'm glad that we
can sit here and talk about that because
like yourself you're obviously a
wonderful advocate for THC one of my
friends team Landon thank you guys on
Facebook yeah he cured his leukemia with
THC strong cannabis though he started
with the realm of caring which is
obviously known for Charlotte's Web and
the yeah but the CBD oil which he
actually wasn't even using for the most
part I mean they used it as a supplement
because they noticed it was stopping
what the chemo is doing but they made it
very they were very adamant the TV is
what killed
his leukemia and you know shoot it's
been I think over six months since he's
had a clean you know ability yeah
absolutely no four state chemo anymore
state for scheme oh I'm sorry no more
all the tests have come back completely
negative you know there's no signs he
still maintains a healthy regimen Sierra
maintains as his caregiver and we
oversee you know all that and I've seen
what both sides of it does so at the end
of the day though we advocate for our
different compounds are different
cannabinoids whole plant cannabis is
what I think is the full spectrum yes
the synergistic effect yeah so shout out
to team Landon that's good play this
episode for me guys put it put them up
by the the iPhone I let him hear this
Judy I want to be here doing well yeah
it did Colorado Springs is so neat we
were talking a minute ago about how the
medical community here has United
because we don't have recreational so we
don't have the there's not as greedy of
a vibe in cannabis here it's beautiful
they're a bunch of people just hanging
out in line just waiting to get a DAB
and it's all peaceful no one's got a
problem we got people up there whipping
up dabs for them they're pressing up
rosin and everyone's just hanging out
it's so peaceful it's great I love it
you guys come on down to the candy cane
and get a dab with this one of these
nights so earlier you told me we talked
a little bit before we hit record you
guys we hung out and got comfortable
took a bunch of dabs together but you're
telling me that you made extracts before
you even grew yes just being a process
you process I hate saying I mean I gonna
devalue is what you're doing but where
we were whatever the case was it started
one way and it started becoming clear
that we couldn't control you can only
control so much of what she make because
it's all in your starting material
absolutely and I wanted to start
controlling the type of medicine that I
was making instead of just processing
other people's material I mean because
it's hit or miss you have some people
that put their love and their everything
into their material and it shows when
you end up pulling it out and sometimes
not the case flora my and everything
else into the oil absolutely exactly
what you mean that's the most
wonderfully nice way yeah so you know
start processing the oil found out that
I kind of really love doing it it got
back to you know my roots in chemistry
and just little things like that and and
seeing what people are doing with
distillation even a few years ago and
and things like that yeah I'm seeing how
we're coming along I mean we're still a
budding baby
industry in the can of chemistry world
oh yeah I agree with that yeah it's
amazing to see what we're doing now with
technology that's been around for a long
time and now we have these wonderful new
ways and freedoms to apply these new
applications so it's great to see what
these guys are doing and people are
coming out with new extraction
techniques whether it's in the solvent
list world or whether we're using you
know solvents or whatever the case is
and it's exciting to see you know what
are some of the things you make I've
seen you make a bunch of different types
of CPL products let us do the list of
what you can do so we've made
suppositories for some patients we've
made dogs CBD biscuits we've also made
one-to-one treats for the cancer you
know some older you know some of our old
canine friends have you know fatty
tumors or whatnot dog absolutely you
know so we do what we can and started
coming up with solutions solutions to
try to help those patients yeah yeah
those those people you know those two
that we love
you know I have a few myself so from
there SABS bombs different ratios of
capsules for a wide variety of ailments
from you know everyday
cannabis regimens you know for a normal
medical patient to an extended hospice
patient where what we do at that point
is make them as comfortable as we can
and we're you know these patients are in
the excess of taking anywhere from a
thousand to three thousand milligrams of
cannabis a day to make them comfortable
you know because that's what you can do
so and you're able to produce then
reliably for the people absolute let's
come in that we do we make per patient
it's specifically per so there's nothing
- the sad that I've talked about the CBG
salve and then any collaborations that
we've done with friends like Caleb or
anything like that are things that are
even close to being mass-produced
everything is small-batch everything is
individually made per patient very we've
done saline and cannabis saline
infusions as well as for those children
that have DeFede through G tubes oh wow
we've done - thinking of everything yeah
we've done some medicated lubricants as
well we've done those work yeah
absolutely
shoot obviously different concentrates
water extracted butane extracted what's
the white CBD stuff I've seen yeah I my
friend's team Landon have a company
called Landon south Hut and they work
with the lab here in the states that
produces this hemp derived 99.5 seven
percent I CBD isolate Wow and at first
she started telling me about it and I
was very skeptical and I wanted more
information and then we got in touch
with the lab and I found out that they
were using you know American sourced
hampt and they you know they kind of
walked us through the process of you
know do dis elating and then you know
crystallizing
you basically you know it's I know just
made it sound like it's a simplified
process but it kind of is you know it's
just a matter of getting the right
material we said you're gonna you've got
a chem background so absolutely I skim
the pond with the rocks of time but what
catches really catches and through a lot
of trial and error you you learn that's
what this industry is all about
absolutely trial and error is your
friend and I mean that's how I do
everything and I really you know we try
to focus and don't get anything out
until it's right and we in the series of
things I can really only think of one
little thing that we've ever gone
through and you know you're making
edibles for someone I learned my
mistakes and putting flaxseed in there
because some people are very susceptible
to that allergy but other than that like
I can't think of you know what we make
has really helped a lot of people across
the board for all the different ailments
we stay away from alcohol extractions as
far as our so any alcohol infused
tensions or anything like that just
because we mostly started with pediatric
epileptic patients the trace amounts of
alcohol could the medications that they
have to take for the most part even
trace amounts of that kid effect and
totally just give them a huge variety of
complications with their medication and
I've seen it you know it's also it's
very hard on their digestive systems and
so yeah children that are going through
chemo children that have autism children
that have epilepsy all have compromised
immune systems and compromised digestive
systems in their own way so one of the
problems that I've seen with pediatric
patients using our so is that they have
problems holding down that medicine so
start going around and promoting you
know different carrier oils different
you know ways of taking this you know
non solvent or solvent extract and
decarboxylate and you know putting it
into a healthier carrier oil for these
children what's an example maybe co-op a
bottle coke
oil in kind if someone is diabetic and
they want to try a healthier route
there's always ham seed oil which is the
healthiest I mean it's protein juice
it's it's absolutely wonderful for you
so I always say hemp seed oil first if
not avvocato Isle grape seed oil is
another wonderful example of something
you can use those in coconut oil but you
know a lot of people are very happy with
coconut oil if it works and you know it
works a lot of people are on the coconut
oil cake it seems to be real popular
definitely my first questions with that
is if they're Crohn's patient or
diabetic I asked them right away and you
know we just I transparency is
everything you know true knowledge
you know this knowledge is all open
source so the more you can be open with
the patient and explain it to them the
more they leave knowing at the end of
the day the better it is in the long run
you know have you thought about going to
dispensaries and maybe to medical shops
and teaching the bud tenders this sort
of stuff or do you think they Dave I
absolutely think there's a really
important part and people bartenders
specifically getting some form of
Education because a lot of them I'll be
very blunt I say this a lot of them look
at is just a job you know a lot of them
come in looking at is the retail job
there's a lot of retail aspects to what
it is because it is a peel a
point-of-sale system but the other day
you're dealing with medical patients and
what you're providing what you're
helping sell is we want to be taken
seriously like a medical industry like
we're trying to actually take the time
with the medical patient like is
required I don't think anyone ever got
too mad at a bun tender for knowing too
much like proper information about their
meds
I've been a budtender and I've annoyed a
few people with my weed nerd skills
people just don't care but you you tend
to feel them out and people that are
just there for what they want are there
for just what they want but there's
curious patients that come in and they
have genuine like like real questions
about things that they don't know Joe's
wonderful to have somebody there that
knows that they're talking yeah I can
just make them feel more welcome and
more often than not you build
wonderful business relationships with
your patients and they feel comfortable
coming back and getting you know their
medicine from people that actually know
and care about what they're eat at the
restaurant where the guy remembers me
and remembered oh you like this last
time you just want to go back when you
build a relationship and aren't treated
like customer number seven for today
yeah yeah so you said you don't make a
Rick Simpson oil type of product now you
have an alternative I do I literally
will infuse I mean the oils that we make
in comparison are either infused with
hemp seed oil the Tincher percent okay
or we crank the ratios out with raw
vegan egg hemp seed or grapeseed oil or
coconut oil and we'll use that as the
carrier and we've seen I can get the
dosage almost down to similar to what it
would be and your body's gonna love that
black tar that black sludge is super
hard for about oh yeah you get nauseous
and change colors some people still eat
that stuff wrong I don't understand how
they can do it it's you know so we're
just trying to find better ways of
easier ways for this to get into our
system and healthier ways Rick Simpson
was an innovator for what he did but
right now knowing what we know about
NASA and the process and I mean you were
we're at a different place now medically
so we know better and we should provide
that to our page right like your
integrity on that know we kind of got
sidetracked we're talking about you you
started making hash before you started
growing yep so how did you end up
because you weren't satisfied with the
material that was around right pretty
much okay in Cali and the bay was kind
of people are on that cookies trip a lot
of the CBD fire that was coming out was
looking like grass clippings or it was
really bad I'm not sure plants are hard
to grow no the CBD heavy plants are not
as easy to grow as some of the more THC
or sativa or indica
as a breeder in a grower I recognize
that heavily I don't like ced dominant
plants so here's the thing as a grower
that started out just girl you see we D
dominant plans the first time I pop some
seeds that would cheesy dumb and I was
like this is really easy oh yeah alright
you'd have the curve now and yeah I took
off the training wheels the curves that
I had to deal with for CBD for growing
the CBD or not what I was dealing with
it growing you know some very wonderful
TC genetics that I had been gifted and I
was just like oh my god
[Music]
your ratios will be affected severely if
there's any sort of stress during the
vegetative state whatsoever because that
CBD is already there in the vegetative
state before before it's been flipped or
anything you so glad you said that
people often completely overlook their
veg state people will build a growl I've
watched people build $10,000 flower
rooms and spend six or eight hundred
bucks just fixing up a shitty old
bedroom to make a bed space I'm like
come on let's do that cuz that's like
you said that's where the plants start
starting stage of life you're growing
from seed you obviously want to wax your
tapper you want to make you strong
adolescence before you put them in habit
really yeah I learned that with CBD
plants the very hard way and every time
something happen I should call one of my
friends a buddy looks what I'm going
through please you know and I want to
think I just wanna see this now and if
it's okay if I shot them out always
offer chronic gene my friend Clancy has
been one of the most stand-up guys that
I know I see comic free CBD seeds in my
bookbag from him right now that I'm just
remembering so I will gladly donate free
CBD seeds to anyone that wants them
right now I hope people in this room
heard though no legit yeah I'll gladly
say it again but yeah
he's been a wonderful wonderful friend
and Josh from the plateau labs good dude
see ya every breeder every person that
I've talked about what I'm trying to do
is see me has been completely open
source with me and helpful and any
little thing that I it's literally
fast-tracked me so much that it's a
blessing you know it's I am completely
grateful for the knowledge that's been
dropped on me because it took me from
trying to provide for my patients and
struggling to knowing things that I just
would have never grasped before you know
like I said it's I'm truly grateful for
it but yeah I started as an extractor it
just took one of my friends getting
screwed over basically for me to say you
know what dude I'll grow for you yeah
there you go yeah
became very public about it and when I
first started growing my problem was
people hoard these or they were hoarding
these strange right
so it was like well let's share them
let's you know let's pull cut and you
know give them out and I you can only
help as many people as you can get this
cut out to you which is something I'll
touch into later but my main source was
you know okay well let's make this
happen so my time in Cali people were on
this crazy cookies craze I was going
from noir cow to SoCal and brilliant
Southern California no hits at all no
progress whatsoever in Northern
California so I fell in love with a
wonderful plant called sour tsunami and
I met an amazing group of breeders in
the Emerald triangle that changed my
life
some they were already caregivers for
some of the children in the state going
through cancer these men showed me what
real compassion was at the very starting
point when I was in this industry and
blessed me with some genetics and
knowledge and play me in the right
directions of things for what I wanted
to do a shout out a crew name or
something Ringo you know you know
the spirit lives on yeah man there's a
there's a lot of them you know they know
if they hear this they know they are
their kind hearted people who don't do
this for the name they just used for the
sake of continuing to push cannabis
forward you know for Jacob but they've
got my respect absolutely all right so
these people in NorCal you find this
crew in NorCal and you fall in love with
them you find Sauer tsunami yep you
start growing nowan yeah started asking
questions started doing runs with the
plan specifically then people started
talking about this plant this you know
because at the time even California
there was such a hype about Colorado and
Charlotte's Web and what it really was
and all these guys in California had no
clue so when you had these strains
popping up like sour tsunami and they're
like oh well it's just like sour tsunami
no and then you had Harlequin popping up
in the harbor side down by Oakland and
that was one of the stronger three two
one two two ones they're like no it's
nothing like Charlotte's Web and then
this ac/dc plant started to come around
you know and people just started
comparing them because no one knew as
all these new strains are coming out and
from Colorado is that a Colorado strain
the ac/dc you know okay alright just
really it started in Spain from what I
believe from where I understand it
started in Spain and somehow made its
way to California and then from that's
just from what I understand from what
I've been told you know as far as our
Colorado CBD strains you know R 4 R 5
the Wu 5 or as well known before Stu you
know the work that natural mystic
caregivers down here and absolutely
wonderful natural mystic for their one
of the only shops that really focuses
heavily on CBD absolutely this three or
four different kinds of top-shelf flower
that are CBD dominant it's actually one
of my favorite places in the springs to
go to for see buddy fire because you
know I support any place that will put
good CVD products on the chef and I know
the growers there I know Joey pretty
well yeah
hope you listenin bro well else was I
gonna ask you got so many questions you
were talking about labs that getting
your stuff tested you have a lab that
you prefer well there was a friend of
ours that has an independent lab and he
really does help a lot of people with
low-cost testing and does his part to
help you know Colorado law has made a
little hard for caregivers patients
parents to have their right you know
meds tested because obviously most labs
are forced to deal with people that have
MIPS licenses whatever the case is so
there are those few independent people
who have taken upon themselves with
their own dollar to provide a place
where patients can have their meds
tested and there's actually a place like
that down here in the springs I don't
have all the information so I don't want
to shout no worries yeah that's all
right yeah Nate knows who he is and he's
definitely killing it down here so once
I get more information I'll gladly pass
along your way and we can share it you
know sounds great yeah we'll get it out
- yeah he's the one who did the testing
for the cannabis cup entry that Caleb
and I did he's done some other testing
for the oil that I've done before and
and the numbers of those comes spot-on
to the point where if I go somewhere
else and I feel like my numbers aren't
right I go to Nate because my numbers
record sweet you know that's I can count
on that
alright so the Cannabis Cup is coming up
its January you guys were recording a
2016 and it sounds so weird to say that
you do anything for the Cup this year so
there are some few plans for the cup I'm
keeping myself open right now the way
that they split up so cow for the two
weekends is a little confusing so
honestly that is why we kind of backed
out of doing anything so quickly but I
had some things going obviously you know
with whatever happens in Denver we'll
have a showing out and there is
something in California that just
calling my attention that you know a few
people reach out you never know you what
collabs you might see shout out to queen
bee extracts by the way oh is the CBD
winner for chalice I believe okay and
one and she's she's doing great things
out there in California to support the
chalice festival you guys dougies the
sponsor the podcast
so I'm like definitely looking forward
to seeing what will come to fruition
between now and first yeah yeah five
days this year it's gonna be Saturday
Sunday Monday Tuesday I mean there's one
more day see the Friday before or the
Wednesday at the end there because for
Denver because 4/20 is on yeah yeah
something like that see there Tuesday or
Wednesday so they're just stretching it
out well I'm incredibly excited for
whatever they want to do for Colorado
it'll be great so you know that the meed
has their feelings about how cannabis
events should be and what they are
Colorado they have a huge opposition to
a lot of the way that these events are
run what's your two cents if I can ask
personally on how that goes here for
people like us you know that obviously
have companies and promote within as
well as the people who enjoy these
events wait does what it does for me as
I work for a meed regulated dispensary
so I can't take my seed company and set
up a booth because I'm affiliated with
that dispensary so closely that I'll be
find my dispensary will be find if I'm
there selling products or giving
products out yeah yeah which I
understand that oh my god
when you get your meed badge that's part
of what you sign but I feel that
dispensaries this is Colorado we're
allowed to smoke everyone there's 21 and
over it's in an enclosed area we should
be able to the dispensary should be able
to go and set up a booth and show our
wares just like any other industry we
have beer festivals where I'm not gonna
name any beer brands but whatever brand
AB&amp;C bring their beer truck they set a
beer they serve it to people all day
they shut down whole blocks you know
yeah whole blocks of downtown Denver
we're doing this at a private event area
at the I forget the name of the place
the Ducks X no it's not denver mart yes
there were renting a place where they've
been doing it in the city blocks I think
that the dispensary should be able to
come set up a booth and bring smoke and
smoke you and I out and everybody out
they should say this is our flagship
strain this is what we grow come check
us out I think it should be fully
allowed yeah absolutely yeah it's kind
of crap it's not
great I'm glad to get your two cents on
that yes you know being an independent
caregiver on the other side of it I
don't necessarily have to answer to them
but at some point you know we cross
paths and things are mentioned so it's
interesting for people that are running
within that model in Colorado and how
that affects us for trying to actively
promote at events like this you know
without being threatened with fines or
whatever the case may be you know fines
in your business clothes absolutely big
enough fine green and healthy is a small
small business just a few of us and a
large enough fund would end us that
would be the end so we have to be pretty
careful on that I'll be down there open
we're officially open oh yeah this will
come out we're open today but this will
come out like two weeks so we'll be
full-on
check them out yeah he will he'll be
back to give you guys a review on what
he thinks of the perfect check out the
shop there's more rigs there and some
stuff you'd want to see awesome I took
some notes but I think I've gone through
them man I love how cool Colorado
Springs is we don't have one of these in
Pueblo so this is kind of children yeah
there may be one but it's real low-key
and I haven't gone there yet I think
it's open yet so as soon as it opens
I'll go check it out
this is chill I like it everyone's just
hanging out have a good conversation
taking dabs it's cloudy as [ __ ] in here
just let us come hang out do a podcast
maybe I can get Camille's attention to
come say hi hear me it's cool I'm not
gonna bugger she's being social she's a
great poster I love it
everyone here is super gracious yeah
I'll be here a lot more often alright
bro we've been going for like 40 minutes
you got anything else that you want to
throw out to the world about CBD while
you're on the microphone you will be
back on the show you know I I started
this company because obviously something
happened to me you know somebody that I
couldn't help my goal is to help as many
people as I can because if you know that
feeling of
not being able to help someone but then
or put in a position where you can why
not right you know and so every day I
encourage people to learn something new
about cannabis and I encourage people to
take up a cause that's close to them it
doesn't matter what it is no matter what
it is for me it's epilepsy awareness and
I will talk about it and so my face
turns blue and you know more about
epilepsy than you did and before we
started talking I learned a lot today
I'm really glad so that being said like
that's just my main focus with
everything that I do Jeff thank you so
much for having me oh thanks for coming
man and you know that anything in the
IRA genetics lineup is always I don't do
a lot of CBD that's just not my thing
there like there are a lot of people out
there doing it but if you do need my
help you let me know thank you so much
back at you man it sounds like a great
way to wrap up the show right one more
big shop to be canna Canyon shout out to
everybody here shot us all the people to
my left it listen to this ridiculous
podcast thank you guys I'm gonna wrap it
up I will be back to close the show bro
thanks again for coming we're gonna take
some dabs now you guys I'm gonna hit
stop recording here we go all right that
was episode number 114 I want to thank
you guys for listening
I want to fake kabuki Jay Fox once again
for coming down and doing a podcast with
me I also need to send a huge thank you
to everybody at the canna Canyon for the
hospitality thanks for letting me doing
a show there make sure you guys check
out the candy candy and I pull it up the
itis right now it is at 1507 West
Colorado Avenue in Colorado Springs
check them out if you're 21 and over and
you have an ID with you you do not need
to be a medical patient drop in say hi
let them know that Rasta Jeff from the
girl from your heart podcast sent you
also make sure you support our sponsor
hit man glass make sure you check out
www.mcamillionaire.com fortunate youth
the song is for a friend of mine I'm
gonna give you a huge shout out to my
ninja spins and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
Oh
you