[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 116 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff want to thank you guys for
joining me
like always hope you got a fat blunt
hope you got a DAB hope you got the
vaporizer going hope you got something
going into your head right now putting
some THC and or some CBD into your body
hope you're getting blaze this [ __ ]
everybody at this table is red I've got
a good smile on their face I've got a
nice group of people over here today
sitting to my left is my new friend
Danny I want to welcome you to the show
how you doing buddy talk to me the
microphone for me please I'm gonna have
to remind everyone to talk into a
microphone everyone's already it has
been a long day you go to Boulder last
night or today nice nice oh you new to
Colorado yeah good luck Thanks right on
sitting to his left did you notice I had
to [ __ ] see which direction that was
oh my god this is gonna be a fun show to
his left is a repeat offender a return
guest our good friend Joe buzzy welcome
back brother how you doing yo what's
happening thanks for coming man yeah no
problem Joe showed up and rolled a
couple of joints lift them up tasty
stuff what are we smoking in that joint
right there uh this one right here is a
mystery cush plant it is some unknown
bagsied that was grown and has smells
lemony cushy good to me let's smoke that
shoot whenever you're ready
thanks for coming again bro no problem
awesome sitting to his left sorted to my
left issue a little bit still as my new
friend
yeah diagonal left Ceaser
right awesome and talking the microphone
a little bit more fun oh yeah there you
go right there
reporter style it was gonna wreck you
you're not a heavy dabber no well thanks
for from New York also yeah New York um
it's great for the listeners they don't
they get tired of here in this Colorado
plain voice they'll enjoy something new
so you stand are you just coming to
visit no I'm just coming to visit I mean
nice better people more relaxed vibe
here than on the coast I'm sure holy
[ __ ] gets exhausting how much does we'd
cost in Manhattan hit or miss alright
yeah that's what bet so it's gotta suck
about you're gonna spin that 50 and see
they're gonna be oh yeah it's gonna be
oh man delivery service where you are
[Laughter]
thanks for coming on the show I
appreciate it sitting to his right which
is directly in front of me
I remember I have two names in my head I
want to clay I want to say Audrey am I
correct Lindsey yes [ __ ] yeah I doubted
myself Lindsey thanks for coming yes you
live here now right yeah I do actually I
just moved out here with Chris when we
came across how many days ago we've been
here since like December 28th okay yeah
we were all over the place in Colorado
just kind of seeing everything and then
we kind of like settled in Pueblo for a
little bit nice yeah you guys actually
landed in our friend sloppy's old house
right yeah they're sharing a microphone
you guys sitting to her that's your left
but my right kind of is our friend Chris
who is actually also known as
buh-buh-bah yes hello
how you doing that's me yeah I do
blaster Co if people don't know that bar
Chris yeah I do the email tables and
stuff stuff like that Gmail tables
shelves cases Pelican cases cases yeah I
have some weird other stuff too I have
like a little halo helmet set it's
coming out pretty soon - I have a couple
little ideas that are in the works he's
gonna make me a small email for
travelling purposes so that if I were to
be in somebody's vehicle maybe there
could be actually just talking about
that I actually have a car version that
I'm trying to do for camping for when
you're parked and you want to take a DAB
in the car to any of the professional
people in this room right right so
thanks for coming man grab a mic if
you're gonna shout that's cool I'll just
keep reminding you guys these guys are
new to podcast we didn't have enough
mics for everybody so they're sharing
mics we're doing a kind of radio station
style or whatever like a board show
style I think Mike slap the guy next to
steel is Mike we took plenty of dabs
before we got started so I want to give
you a big shout out dude
Chris boba blaster Co sent me the
coolest dab table of several months ago
I've been dabbing on it on a daily basis
I take I'm gonna say ten dabs off that
table hey assembly it looks like it got
work I'm happy it has been huge it's
been put to use I'm happy to see that
all my periscope friends have seen
anybody that's watching my youtube
videos have seen it I it is still going
man you sent that thing to me months ago
it was warm when you sent Diggs and then
in the periscope video I'm wearing
shorts to me and that thing is still
rockin if you say three months ago four
months ago at ten dabs a day whatever
kind of math that is that's a lot of
depth everyone looked at Joe that's
really funny did you compute yes that is
accurate
see a lot of debt so when it stood the
test of time the table has stood up I
appreciate the work I'm gonna give you a
huge shout out as it burnisher dot Big
Cartel calm yes yes go there check that
[ __ ] out tell him that you heard about
it on the Irie or the girl free heart
podcast and he will do something special
for you he'll make sure you definitely
in DME if you want custom orders and
stuff too if you got ideas or thoughts
or stuff you might want to build
definitely DM me on instagram @ bobo
plastic oh yeah or definitely send me a
message at the burnisher i asked you out
I asked you what you could make into an
email for me and your answer was it's
more about what I can't make into a nail
for you so if you've got the funds and
you think you want to turned into an
email he can probably do it if you're
patient yes that's what I wanted was a
Nintendo an old Nintendo but then I saw
it done so I didn't want it anymore
sorry that's it that's the thing that's
what's hard about this everybody's doing
in that it's it's an easy thing if you
really know oh if you know you're if
you're an average Latricia n-- and you
can kind of understand some electrician
you could probably make it and there's a
billion d duis every di my god I'll
cover for you it's my fault
I give him dad you guys I get so much
shut up Tudor pecs and the lemon GS holy
crap since we're doing shoutouts I do
one shout out to our good friends at
Hitman glass big shout out to our
friends at Hitman glass when I'm
shopping for glass I want to buy
something made in America by an American
right now I'm taking dad's out of the
hit man short stack these guys were
laughing at me because there's like a
glam and a half of reclaims
like what you gonna do one level of that
stack is this level is where all the wax
glass shoutout to the chalice festival
you guys I'm trying to participate in
the chalice festival I want to be there
this summer so shout out to hitman Doug
you make sure you follow my friend
dougie it's at Hitman glass dougie on
Instagram also make sure you check out
www.paigeedraw.com I don't buy glass
made by a little kid with no shoes and
no protective eyewear no glasses little
Dew didn't get a lunch break got a
[ __ ] whip up against his ass all day
I'm just kidding that's true though it's
possibly chokes wait for me thank you
that's [ __ ] beautiful
we talked about this on another episode
but there's a whole new group of friends
here that are actually more involved in
the cannabis industry have you guys seen
the mothership rig that's sold for one
hundred and one thousand dollars rages
beautiful beautiful piece okay
outrageous like crazy number like so
what first off I'm a huge sagen fanboy
so sad awesome amazing but that's just
outlandish okay so say you won the
Powerball was right one the Powerball
would you throw it on one hundred and
one thousand dollars on a glass breaks
down second would live in my face man
blow everything so if you want a hundred
if you want that billion dollars you
just tie slice up and he'd be in the
basement because
oh there's pie and stumbling around
stumble in debate let's go there is oh
man just being the high kid now most of
our listeners are right there with you
if you're not take a dad right now so
that what joe says makes sense
let's hear a joke
so was that mothership event in like for
charity of any kind was it all because
it was all like silent auction style I
think I think the charity was Scott
Debbie's [ __ ] pockets that's what I
think that charity was for hi yeah I did
not know under I don't know that there
was a charity involved only way I could
somehow justify spending a hundred
thousand dollars on a glass piece is if
you could somehow write it off and if it
was involved with a charity that might
be the way that they finagle it that
would be also no unfortunately I think
it was at um it was at one of the trade
shows that happened on the west coast he
was either Vegas or the west coast and
mothership had a huge booth there and
instead of this is what I think what I
was told by somebody instead of selling
mothership rigs they've learned that
they can make a lot more money by
creating demand at these events because
people are hyped so that's how they got
a hundred and one instead of a hundred
is because two people were fighting and
one dude set 101 along guy said 100 and
101 got it so I'm pretty sure that's
just he go to the events and I've done
it myself I've bought overpriced [ __ ]
rigs and events cuz it's in front of me
and it's hyped and it sounds like a good
deal and instead of it being 1200 it's
only 9:50 today so I feel like I got a
sweet-ass deal and you buy it then you
get home you're like oh [ __ ] I just
bought this rig done something like that
before but that's how you treat the
height the stood next to me holds up his
new room
this show is sponsored by hitman glass
we're talking about mothership right now
but dude this rig is nice this rig comes
from illusions class it's the ill glass
flux capacitor it is the right size it's
got a quartz banger on it I like the
mouthpiece on it and it's sturdy enough
for the email so nice purchase dude they
got him on the [ __ ] hype they marked
it up double what it should be you would
have price that's a good rig I like it I
like I'll fix the glasses if you can
tell it's not made by some Chinese kid
with no protective eyewear ill glass so
we can all agree that that rig was a
little bit overpriced right over here is
any rig over like say realistically
twenty five hundred dollars overpriced
like a hundred percent understand that
you're paying for the craftsmanship and
the dedication that the person has put
into learning and perfecting an art form
and his guess what you really the time
if I were he like but I'm just trying to
think of a realistic number that isn't
affected by market value would value the
markets pudding it kind of depends on
I'm sure everybody in this room makes a
different paycheck and it kind of
depends on oh yeah oh that's too much
for a rig and different people will be
like yeah I pay that for a rig and it
just kind of depends on where you are
and there have been times in my life
where I'd have been like a hundred bucks
for a glass pipe [ __ ] you but now there
I'm like sitting there hitting this hit
man short stack that we all know is not
a hundred bucks
so just times have change and people
change so it's all it's all what is it
subjective like what's over profit yeah
spin it over a thousand or two thousand
bucks for a piece of glass you could
drop and break and this rig over here
this one is closer to the four or five
and it hits like a boss and it's a hash
pipe still no matter how much you pay
for how pretty it is it's a hash pipe
like the only way I could feel like I
would justify a reasonable amount of
money is if you're buying it for a
sculpture like aspect of it we just went
to the banjo joke it's like more of an
art piece sculptured everything like
even that is anywhere near
right right but there are so many things
I could buy a car with I can buy four
cars the 500 really nice car buy a house
buy a college education you could
realistically own a skyscraper in
Detroit with that much you could own
[ __ ] Detroit you could buy a few
blocks probably all right me too
me as well I'm just saying why are Riggs
$25,000 yeah does there are a few
there's one there's like maybe an SD
Rhino Reigate pay good money for and
probably a couple of Coyle pieces that I
paid good money for but then you guys
ever have that feeling like I'm gonna go
buy something you get to the store and
grab it you carry it up to the cash
register and the lady tells you how much
it is it's something inside she's like
much money out of my pocket give it to
you like I was cool with it till like
this moment for 2,500 bucks and the day
before I drove the Denver to go get it I
woke up and I was like take all these
hundred dollar bills and give them to
somebody's right now like it was a cool
idea
needless to say I came to my senses and
did not purchase a twenty five hundred
dollar mothership at there's just
something that I can't do that it feels
weird that's a lot of money this is
gonna be the most expensive rig on the
table for a long time and this was
actually sent to me by our friends a hit
man glass so this this will remain the
priciest rate on the table for quite a
while I'm I don't want anybody to think
that I'm hating on these dudes who are
making Bank selling their glass that's
it's great that these guys can support
their families and their kids are going
to college now because the student made
art and it's sold for a lot of money
when you approach it from okay see I was
never I was not approaching my argument
from the art standpoint I was
approaching it from the abyss is a
matter how pretty it is so I talked
about it on another episode but let's uh
let's look at a picture of it since
we're we're all gonna other people that
listen to that episode might be
listening to this one and didn't hear
that episode so let's go to Instagram
right quick and I want to pull up a
picture and share it with everybody so
we can all see it together crap I search
for a lot of stuff here we're just gonna
go hashtag mothership and it'll come up
trust me so do you can we agree
Wow I don't see it yet can we all agree
that it looks like something that maybe
Tim Burton would have made or maybe if
Wes Claypool had become a glassblower
maybe Les Claypool would have made this
thing there's a picture of it here but
it's not the picture I'm looking for
yeah sure not the Primus all day there
they played yesterday in California and
I heard the show was amazing so let's
look at this piece right here it is God
on the top the mouthpiece is supposed to
be a moon then it has got I think that
color is called Stardust but it's got
other stuff in it with this like
metallic iridescent glittery [ __ ] that
just drives my eyes crazy I can't even
focus on it properly then it is it's a
Faberge egg underneath that but it's
made with such dark glass you can't see
through it to see the proper shape of
the egg and it looks like a hand grenade
to me you guys agree with that it's too
[ __ ] much it's kind of gaudy
is it's like reflected stained-glass on
a lake that's rippling yeah it's nice
but I mean it's so ugly at the same time
mothership is known 101 yeah it's an
extra one this to pay taxes on it
mothership is known for really like
smooth sleek glass no extra [ __ ] on it
and really nice function yeah clear
function like a clear color maybe like a
the piss yellow lemon drop or the pink
or blue the azure blue is really nice
and this thing is just gaudy and
overdone in my opinion this little moon
down here they sent that to the moon to
space in a weather balloon yeah he did a
whole set of attendees yeah yeah so it's
got these moons around it it's got a
bunch of moons attached to it and that's
supposed to be the actual phases of the
Moon if you'd spin it around it goes
through the moon phases it looks like
they made a cheap bong and glued a bunch
of [ __ ] moons onto it just custom IRA
genetics mothership not coming in the
mail they could send me one of the race
car series any day of the week that blue
race car is dope the finish that green
race cars I got cash in my pocket
somebody bought the red one up right
alone of course it's beautiful yeah it's
so gorgeous but that race car series I
will take it anything that's not a for
mothership I'm happy the what I want to
say is the reason that cosmic peace gets
away with it is because it is a collab
because it's not a straight-up
mothership peace it's a mothership base
and then an artist went to town on with
the [ __ ] to town on it team so that's
why it is what it is and Francona never
gets smoked out of know they were
dabbing out of it bro like there are
pictures on Instagram of these dudes
dabbing out of it how often you really
gonna use that yeah without much money I
don't have to use them
my hand would be on it while you got out
of it my head would be on it while you
dab at it I'd be like no I got it
yeah all right so uh you guys check out
this rig if you go to mothership glass
on Instagram you'll see what we're
talking about
it is redonkulous um also here's
something I've been seeing on social
media sites have you guys seen the super
clear hash that somebody made super
clear it is clear as glass in which in
which state are you talking about
not-not-not United States like which
which phase is the hash in so they're
holding it in their hand with a rubber
glove and behind them is an across
international vac oven and they just
hold it in front of the camera took the
picture and there was no caption and the
picture went up and stayed up for like
three or four days and people went nuts
over this hash because it was as clear
as this rig it was super clear you guys
didn't see it no well I'm just gonna
ruin all your guys's fun it was ice
course it was just straight-up a piece
of ice but since they wore a rubber
glove and took a picture of it in front
of of a coven and didn't post anything
everybody's mind is wet look at that
clear hash and everybody just jerked off
and had a [ __ ] orgasm to it yeah so
many of my friends I'm a lot of people's
cannabis expert you know what I mean on
their weed guy people were sending me
the picture all day like is this real
what is this is this real and finally a
message like where can you find this how
much a gram like what is that exactly
it looks like ice to me and they're like
it's ice okay nice good there's no
comment or anything they just posted the
picture and they just let everybody
assume and everybody's minds went right
- oh my God look at this hash because
they saw rubber gloves in a back of it
and that's what you know if you see
lotion and a Kleenex in your buddy's
bedroom you think he's drinking off its
if you got [ __ ] back up and in rubber
gloves you're making hash it's kind of
just how it goes
the girl in the room almost spit her
water on me because now
the only female in the room almost lost
her [ __ ] that was good all right so we
talked about that on the show yesterday
but you guys are more in the loop a
little bit the guys are here yesterday
our local dude the owner is hip into the
scene no offensive guys listen you know
I'm saying so you guys just moved here
you guys got a brand new house you guys
were spoiled because you moved into
sloppy's house yeah that may have
already been equipped for growing if you
had chosen to grow in there
yeah a lot of people that are gonna move
here aren't going to have that advantage
so there's a few minutes left in the
show that we could keep going for a few
minutes let's talk about things that if
people were going to move to a house in
Colorado and you plan to grow what are
some things you should look at when
you're looking for a house before you
move in like have this in mind before I
move here look at this when you're
looking at houses if you plan to grow
there like the first thing just to get
it rolling like make sure you've got
enough electricity coming into the house
the power is really limited if you get
an older house you may have like a 50 or
an 80 amp maximum in your house my house
we could pull 200 amps here so we I'm
letting a nice big fancy residential
area but some homes you can't pull
enough power to run more than two or
three or three or four lights so
definitely check out the electricity if
you're gonna have an electrician come uh
here's a good segue into the next thing
check out the landlord that's something
to really think about you just rolled
your eyes you had a [ __ ] experienced
[ __ ] landlord is that your front
door and you've got to grow in the
basement he wants to come in and do
something and there's no keeping him out
make sure you got a good landlord
fortunately my landlord lives in
Michigan so they have been here eight
years they drive by when they came to
visit their family and they like the
front yard looks great thank you and
that was pretty much what I got from so
find a landlord if you can find one of
those rental agencies that they rent you
the house and they forget about you as
long as you send that check every month
if you can find a place like that those
are rare in Colorado because there's
because they are aware of what people
are renting houses to do very true you
really want to find like a local
landlord
if you are planning to grow it's very
easy to grow legally here there's no
reason to grow illegally when it's so
easy to have all your paperwork in order
and then and oh I forgot where I was
going with that all right Wow yeah yeah
there's uh other things for your grow
room too like what are you doing for
your ventilation yes is your landlord
cool with you modifying the house oh
yeah you might have to cut some ducting
holes yeah you environment is key think
about how many rooms does a house have
yeah are you gonna have enough room to
adequately grow don't have crazy
expectations not your two closets and a
bedroom and a flower flower clones and
moms this other room so like Joe said
have a good roommate or have a good
landlord don't get any [ __ ] roommates
you're doing weed that'll pay the other
pills don't get any roommates don't do
that that'll screw everything up angry
roommates are one of the no offense my
angry girlfriends and angry roommates
are one of the leading causes of garden
failure angry partners don't have
another partner do it yourself get your
own house set that [ __ ] up
another thing make sure there is access
to water you need to get plenty of water
to your garden
you're gonna need I say probably about
five gallons of water per light every
three days that's every thousand watt
light you'll need about five gallons of
water every three days that's in my
experience if it's too hot you're gonna
have to get more water find a place that
you can control the temperature a lot of
basements get really really cold and
dank in the winter you're gonna think
this is gonna be awesome but that
coldness will give you powdery mildew
that drastic change from hot to cold is
a huge huge cause of powdery mildew the
plants don't know what to do with that
they'll freak out you'll get mauled
you'll [ __ ] up the whole crop also a lot
of the basements around here the
basements are just dirty you would not
want to grow in and
basement around here until you kind of
frame it out or build something in there
so look and see how dirty how dusty how
funky the place is check your pipes make
sure you're not gonna have any busting
pipes in the basement I know I keep
saying basements but basements are the
best place for aggro in my opinion the
temperature is easier to maintain nobody
goes down there it's a little more easy
to keep private so make sure it's not
real dirty make sure you got somewhere
for the water to go make sure maybe you
got a floor drain or a way to get rid of
the water maybe if you get our old
bathroom shower and old a shower down to
the basement or an old toilet down there
make sure you just have somewhere to
dispose of water because there will be
water make sure your neighbors aren't
right on top of you my neighbors are a
few feet away if they were any closer I
would be uncomfortable having any
blowers coming out of any windows it
wouldn't do it so make sure your
neighbors are cool make sure you don't
live next any cops or just bust it out
right in front of the cops ass and he'll
never [ __ ] notice cuz it'll be like
why would that [ __ ] grow there they
just carry and grow it here's another
tip when you move in
don't go carrying in your grow lights
and your hydro setup all at one time
kind of wait for the if you can drive
yeah yeah if you can drive the car into
the garage and unload there do that
don't show up with seven sign this as we
grow you need electricity you need water
you need somebody get rid of the water
you need cleanliness you need some way
to feel secure don't buy a house it's
got old ass doors old ass doorknobs pay
attention to your neighborhood it's
easier to get away with to grow in the
hood but it's also easier to get your
girl [ __ ] stolen in the hood so
there's a kind of a boundary you have to
work with there you guys are right on
that cusp yeah in your new house it's
kind of its hood enough but it's a
little hood
well our neighbor seemed pretty cool I
haven't had any issues they are our
happy little slop was there before so
that's slop regulated slop came in and
laid down the long shot at the sloppy
for not taking any [ __ ] yeah I love the
kid slop I owe you a hug bro sloppy uh
yeah can't be beef I'm a vegetarian
brother zombie I love you I'll come give
you a hug
I'll [ __ ] and put on my shoes and
drive over there after this even though
I should not because it's late I'm not
complaining but haven't had a day off in
over 32 days so sorry 6 when I get that
day off I'm gonna come give you a hug
and a kiss on the cheek I play with that
big ol [ __ ] what's name sloppy's afro
listeners called action we would like
you to name my friend Poppy's afro hit
me up on the girl free heart podcast
Twitter page @ g f YH podcast in-game
sloppy's afro sloppy's afro you wanna
the flux capacitor rig prevail
just for you
so if you've made it listening this far
I [ __ ] love you guys thanks for
listening to our podcast a lot of fun um
somebody told me it would be really
funny if I say hey Siri Google golden go
on my podcast because a lot of people
have an app on their phone called Siri
and if you say hey Siri it activates it
makes it start working so now people's
phones are randomly googling golden good
if that worked
haha and I'm sorry somebody told me to
try that let me know if that worked if I
[ __ ] up your phone that's really funny
to me so guys I'm gonna put together an
episode all about getting your badge I'm
pretty sure we did a short episode about
that but two maybe three people have
asked me to do an episode all about
getting your badge also shout-out to the
mama that worked on my dreadlocks for me
she is one of the people that said I
should do an episode about getting her
bad a badge she's a manager at a shop
and a lot of people come in without
badges and ask her how to do it so she
had a podcast to refer them to and help
her out so I'm gonna make that episode
thanks for working on my dreads
I'll get that episode for you the dreads
look sweet that feels so good I
appreciate it so we should shout out
everybody's Twitter pages or Instagram
or some way to find all these weird
[ __ ] that you guys were just
listening to bunch of good people so
we'll start over here you said you had
an Instagram it's creative kre ativ okay
that is creative Joe buzzy do you have
any way that you'd like people to follow
you or do you just want to remain
anonymous over here well yeah I'm good
it's not difficult if you really tried
you've got anything you want to share
with this Caeser Instagram Twitter
Facebook I mean I
me filling my Jeep and Chavo 45:18 tha
vo nice little check that out you might
find the girl of your dreams right now
just creepin on your Instagram so you're
looking for a girl that likes Italian
food got big boobs ready to go on the
sunset right in the Jeep smoke some I'm
not gonna edit that out am I gonna take
that out no I'm [ __ ] not because I
think the man is right thank you for
coming thanks for taking time out how
about you young lady yes I am the
traveling stoner on Instagram and all
other social medias are you traveling
yes yes I just wanna make sure you're
not [ __ ] around so you're the one
that I'm talking to a lot of the time
was gonna come out once I said it okay
so now I can finally tell you that it
was the reason I even got a periscope
was because my favorite thing is when he
would jump into your periscopes the way
you say Bobo blaster go used to make me
giggle so very scopes I could hear you
say the traveling stoner I wish you
would have been there the first time I
giggled so
she's like wait for it wait for it
[Music]
making people giggle on periscope you
guys follow me on periscope it's fun I
don't do as many videos as I used to
because sloppy bro busy dude come on we
still got a bromance
you're still my Tuesday [ __ ] soft check
out the traveling stoner make sure you
check out the traveling stoner follower
I'm sure she posed some good pictures I
might look one day okay now my friend
over here mr. bubble blaster Co yes
you've got a lot of stuff to plug you
got the burnisher stuff how can people
find burn ature yeah the easiest way to
find branches branches Big Cartel calm
or you can hit me up on Instagram at
bubble blaster Co Co o blaster Co I
fully endorse his product you guys it
takes a lot to get me to endorse your
product the only brands I really
represent right now are highly educated
titanium oil slick hitman glass Terp X
of course team green and healthy and
then boba blaster Co the furniture
because that [ __ ] works I put it to the
test
yeah I'm happy cuz I was hoping that
house I was expecting you to come back
with like alright give me like a 6 a 5
ml cigar like I go back to the drawing
table fix all the little tweaks and send
your nieuwenburg I test this one that
the green button gets warm yes like my
only complaint that's the only mean it
doesn't my only issue I've already fixed
it that's why I said that's why I can't
wait to to refurbish that one before you
go add two more at the other end
yes I'm just kidding I appreciate the
table though you guys check out the
tables when you buy your table if
there's a comment section on Big Cartel
I do not know what the shopping cart
looks like if there's a comment section
make sure you type in there I heard
about this through Ross - Jeff Ross -
Jeff told me something girl from the
heart podcast let him know so that we
can high-five each other and he knows
where the sales are coming from where
the business has happened and it's
always nice for us to know that stuff we
appreciate that kind of thing so um does
anybody have any sort of important
message you'd like to relay to the world
before I start closing up the show here
all right he's got nothing my message
for the day is don't be a dick that's
good enough right
don't be a dick be nice give each other
a hug it's a new year forgive somebody
give them a new start all right we're
gonna wrap up thank all you guys for
coming that's [ __ ] awesome these guys
will all be back even the folks from New
York this guy's gonna move here this
guy's gonna come visit again we're gonna
go all right wrapping up the show to
thank everybody for listening I'll be
back in a few days with another episode
make sure you check out our sponsor hit
man glass hit man glass calm followed
dougie I also support the chalice
festival in California you guys don't
forget the show is available on iTunes
stitcher and almost every episode is
available on I read genetics Colorado
com there's a glitch in the server the
first 20-something episodes are gone
I'll get them back for you I apologize
every episode is on iTunes if you need a
link to an episode that's not there hit
me up I'll get it for you
don't forget about the donation paid
donation button at the top to the
podcast page go to I read genetics
Colorado com click on the podcast tab on
the top right there's a donation button
it looks like a little PayPal logo it's
oddly misshapen I'm not good at building
websites if you throw some money in
there maybe I'll hire a web designer to
fix that [ __ ] thing honestly what
that goes to that goes to all the
Bluehost fees to keep the website alive
to keep this podcast coming to you so if
you'd like to make a contribution I
would definitely appreciate it this show
will always be free it comes from my
heart I love you guys I love growing
cannabis I want you to grow better
cannabis the show will always be free
but if you want to contribute I will
give you a huge shout out on the show if
you have a topic you'd like to discuss
and you throw something in there your
topic comes up first
that's just how [ __ ] works right if you
throw a 50 in the DJ's tip jar and you
write a song on there he will play
whatever song you wrote on there next I
work the very same way all right you
guys I think that's all I've got for
y'all to give you a huge shout out to my
ninja Spence and until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me
and it's a protege a chronic so where
you say
who knows
I just Laura the trade wind blows Jenny
love to
and I suppose
[Music]
when we see Tommy see Yahweh rustically
straight for me progress me I say a
everyone who they wanna feel I see pain
they don't know country don't sigh drop
off at e3 Lucy say poverty no reason is
what the reason
I just go ago
pretending love
Oh
[Music]
I don't know
got the sunshine rivers and true
when we real pizza but Tony roof earth
just a theme kept up by 20 to life
inside dream if you've got a key to
toggle tell the regime that guess that
way we do now information you think on
your own for else you're a slave to the
things that you know what do you know if
you learn everyday so be careful a team
play your side
I just go ahead the savings
my friends and
[Music]
we heart these are the important sea
lion I gather if we cannot show Nova
ballensat we had or do we propose and
China
ALPA every one I wanna money's just
someone it shall be a coronation
I just gotta
[Music]
that's a boy
that's sunshiny but
[Music]
we just know
Oh