[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 117 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran tavern if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jack I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to say a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic weeds crew hope you guys are
having a great morning great afternoon
great night time great evening whatever
time it is wherever you are hope you got
a fat joint rolled up maybe you're
taking a DAB with me I think you got a
big ol fat blunt with a half a gram of
wax down the middle of it maybe you got
your girlfriend's hair straight around
you're making some rosin and dabbing
that tonight whatever you're doing okay
getting lit up with me you guys I'm
sitting you're hitting the hit man short
stack big shout out to my friends at hit
man glass you know me when I buy a new
rig I like to buy a rig made in America
by Americans the dab as hard as we do
that's why I buy hit man glass hit man
glass made in Southern California make
sure you guys support hit man glass calm
also make sure you follow my friend
dougie on instagram at hit man glass
dougie at hit man glass dougie on
instagram follow him let him know you're
listening to the girl from your heart
podcast and that you heard about hit man
through the show I would appreciate that
so with dougie you guys I'm also dabbing
on the email I got the email with the
drop down on the hit man rig I've got a
replacement coil so I need to give a big
shout out to my buddy Jason big shot
it's a bawd extractions and Gaea edibles
my friends came through and paid me a
visit they laced me up properly I
appreciate you guys thanks for the help
life is Turbie I think that's all the
shoutouts I got for you today you guys
on this episode this is the episode
where I have the lovely Miss Charlo
Greene we'll drop that in here just a
little bit I went to the Denver patient
support group in Denver at a place
called Castleman's
and I was granted a 10-minute interview
with the lovely Charlo Greene so I'll
play that here in just a few minutes
before I get to that I want to read a
news article you turn on the music this
article actually comes from the extract
sun-times dot-com I found this on the
Internet of course lately there have
been some revelations made in the
cannabis industry if you've got a
commercial grow or a private grow you
may want to hear this if you're using a
product called Guardian you need to get
that stuff out of your garden out of
your place just get rid of it it is not
something you want to be spraying so
let's get right into the article here
I'm looking for an author here it says
written by Emily gray Brocius alright so
this article was posted on January 21st
and it goes like this
a popular pesticide approved last week
by Oregon health officials for use on
cannabis plants has now been removed
from the list of acceptable marijuana
pesticides due to detection of a
controversial chemical ingredient as
reported by The Oregonian and guys this
is an article from Oregon but soon you
will see how this applies to you a
marijuana testing lab in Eugene found
traces of the chemical abom ekdam and
supposedly organically grown cannabis
and discovered growers had been using a
pesticide called Guardian might spray
Guardian might spray includes natural
ingredients such as lemon oil and
cinnamon among its active ingredients
and is marketed as an all-natural
product abom Ekman was not listed as an
active ingredient on the product label
the pesticide has become widely popular
because it's more effective than any
harsh chemicals Neal Bernstein owner of
roots garden supply told the orgo nyan
of course it's more effective they're
lying in their shin they didn't tell you
about I'll continue to read Oregon's
Department of Agriculture has
temporarily removed the product from its
list of approved cannabis pesticides
until further investigation can be
conducted Abba magnin is commonly used
in fruit and vegetable production but
those produce items are not marketed or
sold as organic
according to Green Rush daily detection
of this chemical an allegedly organic
marijuana is problematic because people
often pay a higher premium for
organically grown cannabis especially
medical marijuana patients so this
company was putting out a pesticide and
they were having great success with it
it was taking down all of the problem
but they were not listing the album
Ekman on the label which is not an
organic compound or chemical and it was
clearly in the product so there may be
if this was if this was a rule in
Colorado if this product was banned in
Colorado and this was applied to a crop
in Colorado and a lab found this that
crop would be recalled and none of the
products made with the trim or the buds
of that crop would be allowed to be sold
in a dispensary the product would all
have to be destroyed people would lose a
lot of money I hope the people for
Guardian are held accountable when that
time comes it's a gray area because
cannabis is federally illegal I don't
know if we can sue for that but if crops
have to be thrown away because Guardian
was applied and there was a an
ingredient not listed on the label I
hope the folks from Guardian can be held
accountable for that um I have posted to
Facebook that I'm trying to get in touch
with the people from Guardian their
website is gone the distributors and
vendors that I was aware of for Guardian
have disappeared I cannot find them if
you work for Guardian or you were a part
of Guardian might spray and you'd like
to talk to me on behalf of Guardian on
the show and tell us what's up why that
[ __ ] wasn't listed on there or if you
have something to say I will give you
time on the podcast all you have to do
is contact me it's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com it's very easy grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
it's an open invitation to come be on
the show let us know what's going on
with this you don't even have to come to
me I can come to you I've got portable
podcasting equipment we can do it over
Skype we can do it over FaceTime we can
do it through a simple phone call
however you guys would like to be on the
show this is an open invitation I would
like to know why that was not listed on
the label of your product I'm sure you
knew it was in there because you had to
pay for it to put it in the product all
right and if anybody else has guardian
in their garden or in your garden pantry
area properly dispose of that I honestly
do not know the proper procedure for
disposing of a bottle of pesticides but
please do some research and get rid of
that stuff if you've already applied
guardian to your personal crop you
should be okay it's not organic anymore
you can't say it was organic it's not
going to kill you and if you've got a
commercial crop and you've applied
Guardian in Colorado I hope you pass all
of the testing when it comes up
you guys if you're thinking about making
a product for the cannabis community
think long-term these guys weren't
around very long if they would have made
a product that worked and put some
thought into it and put some heart into
it they'd still be part of the community
we'd still be giving them our money
instead they tried to pull some [ __ ] on
us and now they have to hide that are
shunned from the cannabis community no
one's ever gonna trust these people
again whoever they are if you know who
they are
you're never gonna buy a product from
them again if you're a sales rep from
that company people are gonna have a
hard time trusting you the legal
cannabis industry is just getting
started
and if you're as part of this evolution
of the cannabis industry before it goes
nationwide you'd have the opportunity to
be in a huge business but instead these
guys pretty much just got blackballed so
don't be these guys grow from your heart
be a good person alright guys I'm going
to time warp us back a few days and we
are going to go to Denver Colorado to
Castleman's where we had the Denver
patient support group with our lovely
speaker miss Charlo Greene this was a
very great interview this was the first
interview I've ever had where the person
I was interviewing had an assistant who
was keeping time she told me you have 10
minutes when the interview started she
put her hands up it showed me ten
minutes when nine minutes happened she
showed me nine when five minutes came
around she showed me the five when three
minutes came up I got the three about
one minute kind of gave me the look so I
know it's time to wrap up the interview
miss Charlotte was on a tight schedule
so I do appreciate her for taking a
10-minute chunk out of her night to do
an interview with me so you guys here we
go let's spin back in time we're going
to Castleman's in Denver and ladies and
gentlemen to Ross to Jeff and Charlo
Greene
[Music]
all right welcome back podcast listeners
I'm here at the Denver cannabis patient
support group at Castleman's in Denver
and I am joined on mic by the lovely
Charlo Greene thank you for joining me
thank you for having me Jeff this is a
great event that a lot of people here
already it's kind of early and we still
already getting people right we're
filling up I think this shows just how
excited people are for this opportunity
to share their own experiences and learn
I mean now that you guys have passed
that barrier that most of the rest of us
are fighting for we're all watching to
see what you do and the fact that so
many people are taking initiative to
educate themselves it's encouraging
education that's the key here tonight as
Nicky I see a lot of vendors here
everybody has their educational info
it's not like they're here doing a swap
meet trying to sell I love the vibe that
people have brought it's more of an
educational and not give me your money
which is what we've needed in this
industry exactly it's a service that's
what it is it's not a trade show it's
not a fair so I appreciate it thank you
for doing that for us
it seems like every time we have an
event like this they're just trying to
pull money out of our pockets we
forgotten medical marijuana we've done
all recreational exactly about the
patients so thank you I'm a patient
myself so on behalf of all of the
Colorado patients thanks for coming well
I am thrilled to be co-hosting with dr.
Michelle Ross who also sits on the board
of Advisors for m.d. herb which is a
medical marijuana resource make sure you
guys google that right now do they have
a website yeah MD AB dot org there you
go guys check that out support that it's
a good cause so um you're kind of
well-known for your [ __ ] I quit
statement on the news yes
a lot of my listeners might not be
familiar with who you are can you give
us maybe a brief history lesson up to
today and then we'll talk about the
event sure I was working as a news
anchor in Anchorage Alaska I became the
cannabis reporter and I learned about
the true Hannah harms surrounding
cannabis prohibition I was able to meet
the patients that were being affected by
our broken medical marijuana system and
I knew that I was probably the only
person with the knowledge and resources
and access in order to do something in
order to help so many people that needed
it so I created the Alaska cannabis
while still working as a reporter and
decided I would build the club up and
step away from my career as a journalist
and I decided to do so in a public
manner so I had one of the club's
youngest patients his name Solomon and
he was battling testicular cancer
he decided he'll he agreed to not
disclose the fact that me his
interviewer was also the weed Li he was
doing the story about and so that
pre-taped segment aired I let the
teleprompter run with something
completely different from what I planned
on saying and I just spoke from my heart
and I told everyone that I owned the
Alaska cannabis Club and that I'd be
quitting my job to fight for freedom and
fairness and as for this job well [ __ ]
it I quit and so that led to more than a
hundred million views countless
headlines we rallied freedom fighters
across the state of Alaska across the
world really but in Alaska we got as
many people registered to vote in that
short span of time that we had left and
then from there was all about education
education education so we criss crossed
the massive state of Alaska just sharing
our own experiences sharing where we
came from and addressing real concerns
that our neighbors had and that led to
the legalization of marijuana in Alaska
on November 4th of 2014 well thank you
for uh putting your future and your
career on the line
if that didn't work the way it was
supposed to you could have really put
yourself in a hole it was gonna work
that's an amazing step to make an
amazing commitment to make thank you I
it was the right thing to do I became a
journalist because I wanted to make a
difference and this was an opportunity
to make a real difference there's no
difference to be made in journalism
because the network's kind of limit you
don't they control the truth with me
awesome so that brings us to today here
at the cannabis patients what is it the
cannabis patient support group we kind
of talked about it a little bit ago can
you give us a bunch of details about
this and who's here and what we're gonna
do today and what we're gonna hear right
well right now cannabis patients from
all walks of life all different ailments
are coming together and sharing their
own experiences this is again
gathering that's the first of its kind
where it isn't just Crohn's patients or
patients suffering HIV or dealing with
cancer everyone is coming together so
that we can share the knowledge and and
we know that we're all growing and
learning and that no one is the end-all
expert in this it's important that we
all just continue sharing what we're
learning so we get to where we have
those direct answers and it is and
everyone's still feeling their way
through their treatment you know it is
still a little foggy out there the
doctors can guide you very well you've
got blood tenders at dispensaries that
are basically in charge of your medicine
or caregivers exactly and when we're
talking about medicine and how this
would be handled by someone that's gone
to school for years and years and can
tell you exactly down to a science how
it's going to be affecting you that's
what we're working toward as as an
industry as a medical marijuana
community and so this is one of those
steps in that direction I really look
forward to the talks I'm gonna stick
around I'm gonna record some of it
Richard give me permission do some
recording so I'm gonna before you guys
absolutely some of that into the show
I've I may do some editing you don't
know it'll have definitely in Richard
Haines is organizing it he's the founder
of md herb dr. Michelle Ross is
co-hosting the event along with me and
we have several patients coming up to
share their stories including Richard
Haines
Bobby West Ashlee Webber and a few more
that will really touch hearts and open
minds great I hope to get some of that
onto the show everything comes out well
so I follow you on every social media
outlet that there is you're quite
popular on the social media a little
while back the Alaskan cannabis club was
raided it was very few minutes after
that you went to Facebook and posted a
video
you seemed calmer in that video than you
do right now police were here again I
mean it just is what it is if that's
what's happening now then people need to
know it if we voted to stop something
from happening and police and the
authorities are circumventing the will
of the voters then everyone needs to
know what's happening now so that people
can show up and they did show up because
of that how many times has that Club
been rated
we've been raided twice much comfortable
with the routine now you know it's not
comfortable I mean it's a horrible
experience no one should have a gun
shoved in their face because of cannabis
cannabis I agree that's absurd we're not
hurting anybody exactly and the fact
that they felt the need to send more
than a dozen armed officers and SWAT
gear into my home to put guns in all of
our faces it's it's sad you look like a
pretty badass criminal I know right so
threatening one of the violent offenders
well I was impressed with how calmly you
went on Facebook just minutes after and
you're like we just got raided I was
definitely impressed so that has to be a
little bit of reporter experience but
I'm sure that's just your character so
that was awesome thank you well thank
you that was amazing so I've done a lot
of interview questions I kind of wanted
to have a little bit of fun how do you
prefer to consume cannabis well it
depends on what I'm going for
okay I'm going for a calming effect that
I like a CBD spray okay when I want to
just relax and chill then of course I
well yeah I just like to smoke for the
most part okay Beauty grabs I I do dab
okay I haven't seen that yet so I'll
have to take a DAB with you eventually
some flowers yeah it's blunts that are
preferable I know I shouldn't say that I
know but I know I'm going to and I do
what's your favorite strain do you have
a favorite strain Jack Herer all right
yeah that was quick you had no
hesitation feel like the sativa had buzz
sort of thing I do absolutely and
everything that it stands for every time
that I light up I'm reminded of that yes
we should all be support exactly keep on
fighting there we go every day keep
fighting never give up so are you gonna
be here for the 4/20 events in Denver
during the cannabis cup I was here last
year
that was my first u.s. camp that was my
first can of his Cup period in that way
so many people around you for me to get
to you to say hi going on yeah yeah that
was it was quite an experience and I
would love to do it all again okay
you're there we're gonna smoke again
this interview let's plan on it I
appreciate it you know I was gonna make
sure that I let you get all of your
plugs in and advertizing tell everybody
how we can find you on social media and
your website okay well you can of course
find me at Charlo Greene com that'll
contain all the links to my social media
Facebook Instagram we're constantly
working on producing fresh new content
so you'll see video from tonight on
Charlie Green Comm in just a few days
and you can get used to that constant
content I'm always on the road so we're
taking cameras along and giving you guys
the opportunity to take in all the
information that I am blessed to to be
receiving so Charlo Green Comm is one
outlet and also my main project right
now is go green dot org that's green
with an e at the end of it it's all
about cultivating diversity unity and
opportunity in cannabis so what we're
doing is having these sorts of events
looking for leaders in diverse
communities that want to stand up and
champion the movement for the people
that that they share their own homes
with being their community and so Go
Green org check it out you guys make
sure you support it make sure you follow
around all the social media outlets her
are you her assistant is that your
official title okay well you are today
is giving me the it's time to wrap this
up so I'm gonna let you go thank you
very much for joining me I look forward
to seeing your presentation you guys
I'll be right back to wrap up the show
well I feel like that went pretty well
that was my ten minute interview with
Charlo Greene I hope you guys enjoyed
that as much as I did I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to charlo
thanks for the interview and also thank
you for treating me like a VIP for the
entire evening and also big thanks to
Richard from herb MD he gave me
permission to record the entire event
you guys I recorded the whole thing
unfortunately the sound quality was not
super good it was not their fault it was
my fault I just used my zoom h6 a little
XY mic I didn't pick it up real well
there was a lot of room noise there's a
lot of conversation in the back of the
room so I'm not gonna torture you guys
by making you listen to that I do
recommend that you go to a Denver
patient support group if you ever get
the opportunity if there is a medical
marijuana on a support group in your
area I highly recommend that you go to
that go mingle with the patients go hear
the testimony of these people whose
lives are being dramatically improved by
using medical cannabis several patients
took the stage to speak and one patient
that really stood out in my mind was a
young man who said that he had the
opportunity to move to Colorado and use
medical cannabis to feel better and he
feels much better now he's able to run
he's able to play he's able to jump he's
able to be a normal kid with energy but
the only downfall is it now he doesn't
care to do that because all of his
friends are in his home state where they
do not allow medical cannabis so you can
go to these meetings you can hear this
testimony if you don't believe in the
power of medical cannabis go to one of
these meetings hear one of these
children talk here's some of these
adults talk some of these people develop
these conditions at adulthood some of
these people weren't car accidents and
developed conditions then some of these
people were born with conditions if you
go and listen to what these people say
you will be a believer of medical
cannabis most of the people listening to
this show already support cannabis
anyway preaching to the choir it feels
like right anyway I want to thank
everybody for listening to the show I'll
be back in another 7 days with another
episode you guys do not forget to check
out our sponsor hit man glass visit hit
man glass dot-com you guys know that the
show is over please go to iTunes go to
the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast find the review
section give me a 5 star rating after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode make
sure you guys follow us on all the
social media we're on twitter at g f YH
podcast or on facebook it's girl from
your heart podcast
and if you want to follow me on
instagram and see what we're doing in
green and healthy wellness you can
follow the IRA underscore genetics
account I posted a whole bunch of great
cannabis photography opposed to pics of
the grow my personal grow I post pics
with the green and healthy wellness Gro
post a whole bunch of great cannabis
stuff so check that out and speaking of
green and healthy wellness you guys by
the time this episode comes out we will
be harvesting the first crop of products
that I grew at Green &amp; Healthy Wellness
they will be drying and curing and they
should be available very soon if not by
the time this episode drops so stop in
green and healthy wellness for 30 west
Colorado in Colorado Springs it's a
medical only shop so you have to have
your medical marijuana card but drop in
come say hi damsel could be working
Haley could be working buzzy could be
working ami could be working if it's
Friday you have a chance for a free
doughnut and a free back rub you cannot
beat that uh well that was a hell of a
free shout out for green and healthy
wellness make sure you go by there and
let them know that you heard about this
ad on the girl from your heart podcast
it was an accidental free ad I support
that place with all my heart if you've
got something to say and you don't do
all the social media stuff you can
simply email me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you guys don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and I read genetics
Colorado comm we added a donation button
to the podcast page on the website if
you feel like the show is worth a few
bucks
you can't go to my website I read
genetics Colorado com click on the
growth from your heart a podcast tab at
the top right there's a donation button
it looks like a little PayPal logo click
on there that goes directly to my PayPal
account you guys I will never charge you
for this podcast the show will always be
free but if you feel like making a
contribution I would certainly
appreciate it and I would give you a
shout out on the show it looks like we
did a short episode this time but I
thank you for listening big shout out to
my ninja spins until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
on the track spittin the truth