[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 118 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Davor if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew
hope you guys are having a great week I
hope you've got a pen and some paper
handy because this episode is loaded
with information you guys this time we
at our friend Shawn also known as King
Cola drop by and we're going to talk
about integrated pest management and
we're also going to talk about organic
hemp farming this is a great episode in
my opinion so grab a pen and paper and
get ready for some information but
before I get that far this podcast is
brought to you by my good friends at
Hitman glass hit-man glass when I'm
shopping for a new rig I like to buy
something made in America by an American
I like to buy a dab rig made by somebody
who dabs as hard as I do that's why I
support hitman glass you guys hitman
glass they're made in Southern
California you can check out hitman
glass comp for more information make
sure you follow my friend hit man glass
Dougie on instagram if you're gonna be
in California this summer I hugely
recommend that you check out the chalice
festival the chalice festival hash Music
&amp; Art there's not another festival like
it it'll be an amazing time hopefully I
will see you there alright guys let's
get right down to business i'ma let the
music play for a couple of seconds and
I'm gonna use the time machine to get us
back a couple of days ago and when we
land there Shawn will be sitting at the
table with me so hang on here it goes
alright ladies and gentlemen welcome
back across the table from me is my good
buddy Shawn also known as King Kola how
you doing tonight bro good man thanks
for having me oh man thanks for coming
your eyes are as red as mine feel bro I
am and it's been a while I appreciate
you having me thanks for coming you
brought some delicious skunk that tastes
amazing yeah thanks for the dabber I
don't know what that was but it was
ridiculous well now I get to brag that
was g-funk
turned into live resin by our friends at
tur pecs I actually grew those flowers
at Green &amp; Healthy Wellness
that was my first harvest at the at the
Grove so thanks for the huge compliment
you didn't even know what that was and
you said it was awesome congratulations
man thanks a lot man so we brought Shawn
on the show to talk about some
integrated pest management but before we
get there men tell the people what you
have been up to it's been a long time
since you've been on the show build some
credibility and let all these folks know
what you're up to
so I think the last time I was here I
was working on a Three Rivers organics
projects nice organic grow out here in
Pueblo finished it out turned it over to
some great guys so there
from what I understand they're pumping
out some great product right now so
congrats to them I moved on was doing
some just some consultation in the
industry of different grow gigs writing
some stuff out helping some extraction
companies and now I'm actually involved
in a hemp project so we're a nutritional
hemp company were pulled our permits
through the CDA we're all legal
everything that we grow is under 0.3%
THC so you can smoke my whole farm and
not get high we're really excited about
this project
what is the CBD level of that 15 percent
but what we're averaging is no value so
we're specializing in our extraction of
that through critical co2 very good is
that do you need to be a medical patient
to receive that since its no THC you
don't have to be you can be any age from
any state anywhere in the world just
come here to Colorado and get it from me
that's amazing
yeah yeah any amount he invited you come
get it you guys it'll be available
fairly soon so you said the word
nutritional hip is that something you a
phrase you coined I mean and you could
say that technically we pulled in an
industrial hemp license and industrial
hemp traditionally thought is gonna be
fuel fiber you know seed crop okay
in puebla there's actually a ban on male
plants meaning you would kind of discuss
this earlier and we don't grow male
plants we don't do traditionally on a in
a hip operation they drop a pound and a
half a seed per acre there'd be a 50/50
male to female ratio that rely on the
male plant pollen to drop the THC levels
in the female to give them that point
zero three whereas we have been
selectively breeding these high CBD low
THC ratio strains just like people have
been breeding high THC low CBD strains
so it's a really similar approach to
growing is traditional MMJ style but
with its industrial technically it's
industrial hemp
because we don't do the male plants and
we're going further more of the
medicinal nutritional factors of it
that's why we try to coin the steering
nutritional him because it's not FDA
approved I do not say there are any
medical purposes right okay let's wait a
plane safe appreciate that all right
do you want to shout out the name of
your farm yeah ass and saw CBD there we
go yeah I can't say that enough sand
sauce TV everybody go and check us out
on Instagram Facebook you go to my
Instagram King Cola you can find links
through various pictures but we've been
busting out there we've got about twenty
acres that will be farming this season
we've got a 3,000 square foot greenhouse
11 mm square foot hoop houses and a
10,000 square foot forever flowering
under construction we're really planning
on producing the highest quality organic
CBD that's ever been produced it sounds
like you're on the right path for that
and thanks man
so you said that you've got to have all
females and no males with the number of
plants that you're working with I know
the traditional way is to just flour
them out you cut a clone and flour them
you were working with a very large
number of plants you told me the number
I don't know if I have liberty to say
those numbers uh you know we can sue you
just the guys can do the math at home if
they really want to twenty acres on six
foot centers so you do the math on that
but it's a lot of [ __ ] plan that is a
whole shift on a plant there's more
plants than I ever imagined being
responsible for almost poop myself a
little yeah every time I think about it
you know I feel that way but every day
it seems like more of a reality you know
we started out with nothing this was an
empty field four months ago and now
we've got this infrastructure we do and
I still have a while and a large crew
you know longer we've got a great team
out there I couldn't stress it enough
Pablo Justin Eric Chris Kelly
Tony everybody out there's just it's not
just me kicking ass I mean these guys
all heard that yeah I'm gonna it's their
job we'll make them listen Matt so what
I was getting to is how do you know that
all of those planets how do you verify
that all of those plants are females out
there
we everything's from clone okay so
everything yeah is from clone it's gonna
we you know just like you would endure
Lisa we start off see batch call out the
males you actually had to grow yet the
flower some of me yeah you know flower
him out cold the males test out the
females we knew with this what we were
working with what to look for so it
wasn't as difficult as one would think
because this is already something that
was in existence Suzie Q which maybe
some people are familiar with so it
wasn't too hard for us to work it out we
started out with a good mitt a quite a
few females and then slowly built our
way up and then now we've got a whole
army of other plants just clone and
clone and clone and that's the name of
the game and got a 10,000 square foot
propagation building a greenhouse going
up and it will be used for half of it
for mothers half of it for clones so you
said the strain was called Susie Q yeah
Susie okay so you guys that are kind of
just learning just like you'd buy some
pot called sour diesel or OG Kush the
hemp has the varietals the same way
right now
Centennial seeds there shoutout to sin I
don't know if you're familiar very
thoroughly
I wouldn't met with the guy at the owner
of the companies I think his name's been
bit yeah he's great guy shout out to Ben
and he's got a lot of wisdom yes he said
we're growing his auto and box out there
we've got Auto to it clean and healthy
we've got up in the future yeah we've
got out of 11 great yes maybe ours is
auto 11 I just read it as it probably is
its Roman numeral two okay maybe is no
room in number two and I mean it is 11
so who knows we'll have to ask them one
day we just call it Auto but yeah so
there's fee nose in there that you run
every which way so we still we're
running in Mass the I won't really
release what we're running in particular
but those are the strains were running
we're running and mass what we know for
certain is our point for 15 percent CBD
under point three it's actually testing
at 0.25% tea
see right now the other stranger pretty
experimental we still have a while I'll
get a good flower I'll get a good
harvest off and then we'll maybe
propagate a couple of thousand and put a
pound in the field but uh yeah so
everything since we can't grow for a
male or we can't have male plants
everything has to be taken from a tested
female okay is there a lab test for that
that you can use actually we
there are lab tests so we've been
working with we used to work with labs
here in the state
all of a sudden Emmy do you wanted to be
a holes and come out and say that
licensed or meed certified testing
facilities are no longer to test him are
allowed to test him if they have an
excuse for that I believe it's because
they're the tracking system is
implemented through with the hemp so the
CDA supposed to start implementing the
RT are the radiofrequency tags so RTI F
I can't remember
RFID there you go those every day yeah
so they're supposed to start issuing
some of those for us after harvest to
get us into these testing facilities so
back in the day last summer
basically they is at the end of this
harvest season is when they kind of
implemented that law yeah I think it was
November they quit and we couldn't test
it anymore so we haven't really been
able to test since then so we built our
own facility so right now we're building
our own testing facility on the farm
there won't be any need to go any
outside sources
you guys are problem solvers aren't you
you know it's just
yeah cut out the middleman necessity is
the mother of invention I think they
said well you know the way it works is
our reg our governing body a regulatory
agency is the Department of Agriculture
so we work with the Colorado Department
of Agriculture issued us our permit
we're very open with them everything we
do they you know we file harvest reports
planning reports it's kind of the way
the compliance works but they test
frequently they but you know it's
sporadic testing they don't announce
when they come and it's usually around
harvest a random drug test exactly and
the problem is is if they were to come
out and test my field and you know as
well as I do it the cannabinoid count
can fluctuate or change due to anything
you get a pest infestation or you get
prolonged periods of UV light or you get
a drought period you whatever happens
but you can have
exterior factors that can you know
change the cannabinoid council lutely
so if this if I have the CDA come in and
we're at four percent five point four
point five I have to destroy my crop Wow
four point five is your limit on time
point three percent point three is my
limit so anything over point three is uh
has to be destroyed on the property man
that's terrible I'd hate to have to see
that yeah so that's the you know we'll
build our own fasting facility it you
know it's worth it that way we can test
these things periodically and make sure
we we have that consistent product same
thing with we'll be doing an extraction
now that we can do our own in-house lab
testing our own in-house homogenized
testing so as we release in large batch
products you know everything's gonna be
the same quality everything is gonna be
the same grade you know that's something
that I really I'm so fortunate to be a
part of this organization because they
believe the same way I do that we will
not skin or skip things like that when
it becomes too health and it comes to
the purity of the products we don't [ __ ]
around should see the look on his face
dude seriously these series they do not
[ __ ] around dude big thank so much
respect for that we've needed people to
come to this industry like that
when a lot of the new rules came into
play a lot of money came into play the
guys with a lot of heart like you and I
kind of got pushed away by the guys with
a lot of money and a lot of backing so
it's good to see some heart coming back
into this industry thank you it's good
likewise man it's good to see you where
you're at - thank you very much respect
so uh is there a market for a feminized
hemp seed yes but the question is is how
do you feminized your seed and miss
colloidal silver registered to see
like stare back ask this fast yeah no
but no the markets getting there you
know that's something that we're looking
we're very interested and everybody's
interesting creating your own seed stock
right
what farm isn't interested in creating
their own see suck especially something
in the CBD industry is where the MMJ
industry was ten years ago
this is theirs mean like six other
companies out there it's there's not a
lot of us and if you think that six
companies a lot you've obviously never
driven through Denver in seeing the
dispensaries South Broadway in two
blocks all right so uh man that's a lot
of information in the first twelve
minutes of a show so I truly appreciate
all that that does that give him
credibility you guys can I start asking
questions about stuff that we need
advice on now do you believe him I hope
so dude every time I see you you have
gone 12 steps ahead of yourself and I
love it
congratulations keep going man that's
freaking awesome so what we brought you
here for is to actually talk about
integrated pest management so Wow you're
just running a huge outdoor you were
telling me what you were doing earlier
do you want to tell me about you can
start with the posting of the Instagram
picture and just be real with you guys
cuz people run into problems and I ran
into some problems so we'll just kind of
go over what happened to me what I used
is treatment and then what we do now is
weekly preventative measures and yeah
what kind of start there so yeah keep in
mind you guys this is in a greenhouse
and outdoor setting and then once you
get to do with this I will ask questions
about indoor stuff okay so well yeah
this is you can run this this is
everything that we're talking about can
be ran in an indoor environment also so
we were you know running in our
greenhouses transplanting plants we
actually just moved from an indoor
environment we were growing in a small
warehouse and then moved everything into
her greenhouse and if anybody out there
is familiar with greenhouse growing it's
not easy
it's not it's not an indoor environment
this isn't something that you can just
fire up put plants into unfortunately
investors don't see it that way business
owners don't see it that way they want
plants in there so we introduce plants
as fast as possible the environment
isn't where it needs to be the you
there's just a lot of stresses that are
going on at the time and that kind of
goes to the first step in integrative
pest management this is a real dumb
statement but healthy plants are less
likely to get sick yeah and what you're
saying that I really mean that if your
environments in good condition and your
water is in good condition and your
light is good condition and it's like a
report card if you're hitting aids and
all of these things if one fails you're
still gonna have a doubt so you need we
rely on this system to catch us so if
you're half-ass in everything you're
gonna run into problems yes so we
stepped into this greenhouse not fully
ready we have asked some things and we
ran into some problems and it's life I
mean I'm not I'm human so we run into
problems so we were we ran in there
running into some environmental issues
we were getting them straightened out
and the plants weren't as healthy as
they should have been soil was on point
and you know feeding schedule everything
was right where it should be but things
were lagging you know plant growth was
slow and we were having some issues
couldn't really figure out what they
were
we were actually posted some I'll let
you guys be the judge go my Instagram
picture and see if you're smart as these
people are and I see if you can't find
the picture that tipped them off to
where I was actually contacted by a
dragonfly earth medicine shout out to
Josh Kelly and sky you guys are my
saviors we're gonna get them on the show
even if it's through sky person yeah
they're yet you have to they're just
pioneers at what they do really hope
they're really helped the you know
influence the way that I'm setting my
farm up for sure you know okay but so
they actually contacted me
we had some you know leaf curling the
way that they were curling kind of some
of the discoloration problems that we
were having and through a few other you
know things they actually saw the
pictures and said hey man you have broad
mites and I said oh no but before I
could cry they had taken care of it and
sent me over some predatorial mites and
along with that they actually sent me a
little IPM program so immediately you
know we were gonna implement these mites
so but before I implemented these mites
this is what we actually did I heat
treated the greenhouse I don't know if
you've ever heard this you can do this
in your grow room if you have spider
mites also your plants can handle it
don't be scared
ours did and I had to have a lot more
money invested in mine than you do your
grow room so yeah but a heat treatment
so we actually you can run your grow
room at about a hundred and twenty
degrees for about 45 minutes holy [ __ ]
your plants will survive the spider
mites won't any bugs won't your gonna
nuke alive any beneficials or anything
in there but you're gonna sterilize your
room to a greater extent I mean it's not
gonna be perfect and then went coming by
you know so run it for 45 minutes coming
back off of that for the next 15 minutes
no direct sunlight to hit the leaf no
water so you want to slowly you know
cool your room back down give it about
15 minutes before you start introducing
light you there's actually a lot of
research on that so if you're interested
if this is something that you're
interested on you can just go on google
google green house heat treatment and
then kind of go their steps okay but uh
so that was first step hit him with the
heat burn those [ __ ] alright so
we hit him with the heat treatment and
then after that dragon fire earth
medicine had sent me some beneficial
insects so we had predatorial mites
they actually sent me two different
packs we got a I believe it's a ski and
three packs I'm probably pronouncing it
all wrong but so two different types
both of them can protect against the
broad might okay one of them the sworsky
I believe it's called protects against
the russet the spotted the brown suit
that one ass or skis all spider mite and
it's the broad thrip x is for thrips and
white fly and then also these predatory
mites also fight some broad mites and
they feed off each other cuz they're
carnivorous okay so we introduced some
takes about three weeks for them to
inoculate the plant and before I started
like you guys run out and you you want
to start trying this this doesn't work
in a synthetic system it right only
works in an organic system you cannot
use since you can't you certainly can't
use any systemics so you know don't go
and spray things that kill mites and put
beneficial mites on your plants because
that's counterproductive second thing
don't use synthetic nutrients because
the thing is is when you use synthetic
nutrients you're bypassing natural
processes you're feeding your plant
through an IV there's no need for
microbiology there's no need for
protozoa and nematodes and anthropods
because you're just feeding it straight
to the root zone so when you bypass
these natural processes what's happening
is you're not allowing the plant to
build its natural immune response so if
you can keep it organic and you can keep
this biological system just in check
throughout the whole cycle then when
your plan gets infected your ally the
plant itself can react to it your plant
is can finde off spider mites you know
the if your plant couldn't then there
would be way more spider mites than
there would be marijuana plants but your
plant can naturally fight off spider
mites the problem is is the
a synthetic growing environment
especially indoors you play has no
resistance if I has it's a puss grew up
in a plastic bubble yeah so you know and
that's kind of the same thing is that
you your plane isn't going to build any
resistant if you're feeding a space food
the whole time you know it needs the it
needs to digest it it needs to chew it
it needs to you know work that whole
process out itself otherwise it's just
going to become weak and decrepid and
have no defense because at that point
what is your plant doing it's quick
vegetative turnovers fast veg times and
high yields that's all you care about
and that's all you're focused on so
you're focused on increasing leaf
surface area an increasing bud area
you're not worried about increasing root
zone you're not include about increasing
you know the the bricks County you're
playing well you're focusing on the
wrong things and there's a lot more to
it than that so when you miss these
things you plant you know can't defend
itself so just wanted I've forgot to
mention that is this is for organic
systems only and if you're not running
an organic system you're gonna have to
spray unless you keep it completely
clean you're gonna have to keep a very
clean environment but in an outdoor
system something like we're running in a
greenhouse and an outdoor hybrid
environment where you pull in fresh air
not through a HEPA filter you know we we
have shutter fans we got we've got
outside exactly it was seven degrees
this morning man but the plants are a
lot tougher than we give them credit for
even though you know honestly even
indoors plants are a lot tougher than we
give them credit for then we've grown
from millions of years by themselves we
should give them a little bit more
respect they can they've been fighting
for themselves for a long time and I
think that a lot of the problems that
modern growers run into or because of
the modern methods that they use so it's
the center at my opinion this is you
know just me speaking it but it's the
synthetic systems and the synthetic
environment too when I say synthetic
environment
I'm not meaning grow lights I mean in
synthetic pesticides and yeah but uh we
you know with these synthetic systems
that's what's creating this influx these
super Hardy spider mites these crazy
resistant powdery mildew strains is
because you're creating a feeding your
Colorado is a whole is creating a
feeding ground for pest and disease you
know every single dispensary is spraying
the same thing you know they're spraying
neem oil or you know the it's a very
short list for a whole lot of plants
right and they're not using these
biological controls so if you don't want
to run into problems kick it you know
start using organic methods ASAP
and then you know you can these
beneficial insects they're not something
that are hard to get you can go to your
local hydro store go to top-notch calm
go to Cooper try to contact dragonfly
maybe bug them enough they'll get them
for you but uh you can get these mites
um you don't have to spray you know we
in you know for example we put these
beneficial mites out we top dress with
neem and karanji
we table dress with diatomaceous earth
I fold your spray with natural mystic
which is a dragonfly or it's nice
product so it's just like nettle thistle
horsetail lavender petula all sorts of
[ __ ] it almost take a bite out of eight
smells wonderful and yeah I'd love to
spray the greenhouse with it but you
know we spray natural mystic so natural
mystic barley and earthworm cast or like
a barley malted tea near CTC sprouted
team [ __ ] but yes so barley natural
mystic earthworm castings that was a
preventative that we were foliar
spraying with natural mystic earthworm
castings and bacillus third iNSYS that's
great for the fungus gnats
exactly
wife doesn't that's what that yeah so
you know a lot of these things are just
this the same thing over and over again
right just different forms different
ages actually so right now on a weekly
basis we give them a weekly app of
natural mystic Rocky Mount worm castings
and then see crop yeah so yeah so yeah
trace so trace minerals natural mystic
worm castings weekly basis you'll be
right that on top of just maintaining a
healthy plant I mean you know like I was
saying the key is to just maintain the
biological immune response through the
entire growth cycle so no synthetic
nutrients no pesticides period no
bypassing natural processes
don't put your plant in a bubble I got
that in exclamation points on both sides
so nobody would know you're reading
anything and I just say it's very
important in there not let's see what
else we got so we got Ben if we went
over the beneficials so Lister Genesis
you know I mean the big thing with
integrative pest management is
maintaining a natural system is going to
be looking scouting you know stay
observant you need to mean you know the
time when you notice a bug problem it's
too late right you know stay on top of
these things look out for yellowing
leaves here there's a reason sticky
traps are yellow
bugs are attracted to dying leaders so
keep all the other leaves out of your
grow room if you are a no-till gardener
and you are somebody who top feeds with
your leaves know what you're doing top
dress with make sure your top dressing
with neem and car wash you make sure
that you do have beneficial nematodes in
there maybe you do treat with bacillus
thuringiensis every now and then because
otherwise you're gonna run into fungus
gnats so you just need to be a little
bit more educated that's how I got my
fungus gnats trying to go no-till yeah
and I did it before too and I mean you
know that's it it is what it is but you
know you learn these things it's a
process
and your plan will work itself out
you know it'll you lil end up with
different sprig tails and different soil
mites and shredders and anthropods and
it'll balance itself out yeah it's just
nature does its thing they're not
welcome you know your plants are healthy
you treat them you know you keep doing
what you're doing you hit them with your
bacillus thuringiensis hit him with some
diatomaceous when your so my guy is at
work I can't [ __ ] get this through
their heads man the diatomaceous doesn't
work when it's wet love-god abrasive
rough yes yes yeah and that also goes
for right after you water I said when
the soil still wet
don't put diatomaceous on it having a
hard time getting these guys to put
diatomaceous out correctly and that goes
back to just education is key know how
to put your pests you know earned I say
pesticide about how to put your products
out correctly you know like I said the
cd8 came by our farm last week but
nothing on our farm is considered a
pesticide or really even a fertilizer
you know our diatomaceous earth is
bought as an anti-caking agent for
animal feed we use food grade aloe and
cocoa our neem and caranas bought from
you know Nate natural select source a
Rocky Mount worm company so in its other
three great yeah so you know Jay only
uses food grade material for his worms
so I'm only getting food grade material
for the plants that's awesome it's good
to know the patients are being taken
care of man awesome yeah yeah so a lot
of what you covered you said organic
only and then you said if you're doing
synthetic nutrients you're gonna have to
spray so now here's what we're gonna
have to talk about that one the dreaded
I'm gonna have to spray let's say walk
in and I see freaking spider mites in my
grow room I've got a light infest day
infestation I've never sprayed anything
before what is something we can spray
that's not gonna do too much damage
biologically to my planet and also to me
when I smoke it and also not make my
concentrate States
like [ __ ] you see you your first go-to
would obviously be the nîmes okay I know
then the first thing that you want to do
is throw down a nicety of some neem
karanji earthworm castings just right
drench into the root zone the roots okay
yeah or you know if you don't want to
make it too you can top dress that's how
we ran it at our farm okay just wheeze
and I say neem and karanji it's because
garage is cheaper than me so you can cut
it 50/50 and save a good bit of money
there you go so yeah we cut yeah I cut
those in neem oil wouldn't spray it
after veg obviously essential oils
you're gonna pay a whole bunch of money
but S&amp;S does kind of work okay um
rosemary oil yeah they'll kill spider
mite eggs on contact and it'll irritate
the spider mites push them back a good
bit and inhibit their growth so
essential oils things like S&amp;S 70 I'm
not like a huge fan of like ladybug
killer red Rosenthal's to your tolerance
I haven't seen great too good results
but as soon as I have it's extremely
pricey you can make it yourself it's
rose 90 you know it's like nine percent
rosemary or two percent rosemary oil or
something like that so you could make it
if you feel like being a little
experimental I have cooked some plants
before with essential oils oh yes so
they're extremely volatile I got to be
really careful outside of that I would
go to biologicals you know would be my
next step so that's when I would step
into the predatorial mites ladybugs
ladybugs don't eat spider mites lady
bugs eat larger insects like aphids
things like that it's actually ladybug
larva they'd eat the spider mites so you
need to bring them in and then give them
enough time to you know lower the lights
light some candles play some music and
then have them make babies all over your
garden need a little lake bug or J there
you go dude just would stockin in your
garden and their ladybugs limit any to
their larva will emerge little alligator
larvae and then those elite soft-bodied
ends
you know
smaller soft-bodied insects mites things
like that okay so you can you know start
implementing that system defoliating
taken off the infected areas people
overlook that so much I can't tell you
how many times I've gone to an infected
garden and seen stippled plants and
these things look just Fox and you know
my first question why are these leaves
still on here see you know the spider
mites are still on your plants man yeah
so remove that vegetation unless it's
absolutely needed you know and I'm
learning a lot from plants running on a
larger scale like I am plants can take a
lot and if you need to thin your plan
out to two tops from a [ __ ] 12 top
five-gallon it's gonna survive yeah and
if if all you're trying to say and
that's maybe something that you need to
assess too so and you fight you walk
into your garden and you find the spider
my problem which you know may be the
first thing that you really need to do
is think about what is this plants
intention is it getting ready to be
flowered can I just kill it could you is
it too much right now for you know if
perfect world I would tell you to throw
the plan away yeah you know yeah and
maybe you can't maybe you're too far in
you've already got too much invested
growing cycle that's what I'd say you
know neem oils and then the essential
oils and the predatory you know the
predatorial 's and things like that by
the time you notice it's usually too
late unless you can you know veg for
another four weeks cut her back take
clones off of that and inoculate the
clones and usually what what I try to do
if I find something to out of control if
I I do consulting as well and if I go to
someone's grow and I can see that their
mother plant or their vegetable and has
gotten too far I just say take Collins
bro we can kill you no bugs on clones
and get rid of those big-ass plants less
vegetation like you were saying around
to keep all those bugs around so cuz
some clones clean the room start fresh
that may be your only option sometimes
yeah and
you know and a lot of people don't they
don't understand start fresh means get
off your ass scrub your wrists rub
change your filters you got pain to film
go and buy some new rolls you you're not
you don't just pull your plants out
these the spider mites got in there two
ways they got in there because you
didn't change your clothes and you
walked into an effective garden and
brought them in or somebody you know
brought them in or the second option is
they brought themselves in and I you
know have an agricultural background
I've worked in a cucumber a of grown
cucumbers tomatoes and Falcon up and
north of herb Western or Eastern
Colorado all [ __ ] up but no so like
when we would do I was in charge of IPM
there and we would do scouting programs
so every morning you would walk out with
your magnifying glass and your clipboard
with your map of the greenhouse and
would have your rows marked out and you
would be surprised to see that you know
we would find stippling and we would
mark him on the map as we found
stippling in these rows once we would go
through all these rows you could follow
this map back to a cracked seal in the
greenhouse Wow
to where there was a broken because it
was a glass greenhouse - a broken pane
where weeds had grown through same thing
in your grow room you notice that the
spider mites in the back corner of your
room maybe it's not sealed you know you
might have a draft back there maybe
that's where your window is and you put
a piece of plywood over it with hand
film because you thought that was gonna
be enough to cover it you didn't whether
seal it but that is that's how spider
mites get into your gray room they it's
evolutionary thing to want to survive
and in Colorado when it's four degrees
outside and you have a ninety you know a
75 degree grow room that's where I'm
going
oh yeah like going on buck your plants
an outtake in vacation time in there bro
yeah go get warm go slow
I've been doing during this winter
hiding in a grow room so you nailed
something you nailed two things off the
list I had written down there's your
environment will contribute to your bugs
heavily and also you bring those bugs in
so I get to cross off two things on the
list without even asking that's amazing
you guys if you're going from grow to
grow you're bringing something back with
you every time you come and go and if
you if you really want to you can buy a
lab coat and that's something that I
recommend to all of my growers every
consultation every we do it at my you
know will do it at my work when we're
not growing in a when we get back into a
more of an indoor environment but yeah
get a lab coat they don't cost anything
you can order them I get one for your
home grow and put it on every time you
go on your grow room hang up on the
outside right by the door exactly right
next to your clipboard yep don't take it
anywhere you know buy yourself a grow
room Tam and then you don't wear that
box might carry something there that
might get caught in a fan everything if
I don't keep them off I have a hat
specifically for the grow and it's you
could probably collect a quarter gram of
hash off of that thing but that's the
key though is just that contamination
it's as simple as not wearing the hoodie
that you were hiking in Indian you know
you laugh but to a lot of people it's
Eid they don't think about that stuff
absolutely a lot of the guys hid my work
probably go home to their gardens
right after my work do I worry about
them bringing things back now really
because you know they're an indoor grow
bringing it to an outside environment
now am i you know they should be really
[ __ ] worried about bringing something
home because if a spider mite comes into
my garden it's not gonna like it very
much it's gonna jump onto your shirt try
to come home with you and see what you
got but that's you know everybody's
garden so the next time you go to your
friend's house and his garden looks a
lot better than yours yet change before
and after oh yeah yeah do him a favor -
don't don't be a dick and go
your friends grow after walking in the
woods yeah don't tell me don't come to
my grow and be like all your plants are
great I'm fighting spider mites don't
come over if you got spider mites stay
away from my garden exactly yeah don't
bring your powdery mildew to my grow
yeah and that's you know and that's
another thing too is the the powdery
mildews you know now that you said that
it's traded you know so frequently back
and forth and within the community and
that's another one that when you know
when when I say kill and start over
I mean scorched earth IV burn it down to
the ground and build her back up yep you
have to sometimes and you know and
honestly when you your grow room should
bill be built with that capability and
if it's not rebuild your grow room with
either walls that you could clean with
bleach or peroxide or whatever cleaning
agent or maybe it's paying to film but
build it to where you can replace it
been a frequent basis you know you spray
foam insulation don't you shitty you
know stuff wall insulation exactly don't
you know and if you can't afford you
know these nicer options paint a film's
not expensive if you build the room
right you know it's really expensive if
you don't know what you're doing and
you're running it 15 times around it but
yeah you know build your rooms correctly
make sure they're sealed yeah pay
attention to what you're doing yeah
that's that's one of the main keys to
growing is a good room and it you only
get that one shot to build it correct
before you put your plants in there so
do it right I'm like Sean said try to
replace that room if you if you're using
pan to film that's not gonna last
forever you guys take it down every like
six months like every couple of harvests
pull that [ __ ] down clean behind it get
the shot back out clean out all the
corners behind there where all that dust
built up no I don't know how many like
especially home grows I've been to I
don't know why people like to build
floors
there's no weirdest thing to me but I
don't know how many grow rooms I've been
in where people have floors built up
just a couple inches or you know they'll
have pain to film rolled out on top of
concrete for extra reflective
this is just creating more space for
bugs pests mildew and problems like that
so less is more in a grow room if you
can hold temp and you you know don't
need to cover your floor if you have
your growing in your garage utilize that
concrete floor man you know it's nice
it's clean it can be cleaned easily yeah
you know drop you some two by fours and
call it to the floor go get some great
stuff foam insulate it no bugs are gonna
crawl through that but just little steps
through like that's what's gonna prevent
you know for you from having a massive
infestation like that what you said once
you see it it's probably too late that's
that's something that people are
probably not aware of especially if
you're in flower
if you're in flower you just got to
start pulling off leaves and write it
through yes and I can't tell you how
many times I've had to do it you know I
mean you know it's in spider mites can
be dealt with they can be gotta get you
can get rid of them it's not the end of
the world and you don't have to kill
your plants you know but like you said
if you if you're getting ready to go
into flower and you see stippling don't
flower don't be that guy you know
because when you find yourself with that
decision of an old man am I gonna have
to spray in week four with neem oil
you're gonna have to spray a week for an
emo because you put yourself in that
position because by week six you're just
gonna have crispy ass leaves and
nobody's and you know and you know it
but what was worse is or even if you
were a week into flower would been worse
reverting back to veg or you know
holding on to this spider mite
infestation and having to ride it
through and potentially losing
everything you know it's another month
to power bills versus losing your entire
harvest so you know you gotta weigh your
options on that goes back to really
think about your situation what are
these planes for true that yeah you
grown your own personal medicine or you
got a crop out there that you're trying
to make some Bank on you're trying to
buy that new car yeah is it a
dispensaries and not your plants is
somebody else's money in you that's a
that's a stress that people don't
realize exist out there is you know we
me and you both we grow personally and
stuff but we manage other people's
gardens I mean they're our gardens but
it's other people's money ultimately
absolutely somebody else's you know so
what do you do in that situation you
know how do you as a grower come to the
decision of to Kola plant you know like
wait yeah I mean that's the stuff that's
the daily decisions that we have to make
and if we can do it you can do it at
your home oh yeah you know I mean but
that's what you really people have to
start thinking about things a lot
differently I meet a lot of people and
it's I got spider mites what can I spray
I got powdery mildew what can I spray
it's not what can you spray it's what
should I have sprayed you know if you
should be spraying ahead of time stay on
top of these for your compost tea
folders you do compost tea foliar sprays
on a regular basis along with beneficial
insects mites nematodes you know top
dress with diatomaceous earth neem and
karanji I don't see you having a pest
problem you know and then for in my
greenhouse you know like I was saying we
thought that we had a broad mite
infestation actually turned out that it
was a another problem was a water issue
because our well had collapsed we had
brought water from another well at a
different location um and did the very
foolish thing of not fully checking the
water's chemistry before we ran it
through an RO ended up putting high
levels of salt in the plants but I'm a
firm believer that it was the soil the
environment and the overall health it
was that natural immune response that
pushed me out of it you know if if I was
in cocoa growing with mills and I put
that much salt on my plants it would've
been over the instantly it'd have been
like a pepper sprayed I've been
screaming yeah but we rode it out and
you can go to my Instagram you know or
go to San saw CBD Instagram and look at
this greenhouse filled with beautiful
greenery
I mean it was 3,000 square foot of just
canopy wash canopy I was checking out
your security cameras earlier that [ __ ]
looks good bro thank you man yeah nice
and organized super clean that's another
thing you guys you don't need [ __ ] in
your grow room that doesn't need to be
in your grow room
don't keep your your broom in your
dustpan get those out of there your
gloves take those out of there your hat
take that out none of that extra crap
needs to be in the grow room maybe the
only accessory I see that you can use in
there is a little iPod dock so you can
jam some music yeah anything else get
her speaking of which Dewalt makes an
amazing grow room radio it is a yeah you
go to Lowe's and they're like 90 bucks
but they're Bluetooth and waterproof and
kik proof there you go I can't tighten
my [ __ ] across the room all the time man
yeah they the little the little
Bluetooth speaker at the Grove
definitely gets infused it falls off the
table I get [ __ ] spilled on it don't
want that [ __ ] man all right there we go
you guys big shout out to Lowe's and
Dewalt iPod dock it's the little things
in life you know make yourself
comfortable in your very room your
plants are only gonna be as happy as you
are that's the truth if your misery you
know if you go into your grow room and
you're looking at it is work and you're
and you think of it is I gotta get in
here I gotta check these plants and I
gotta hurry up in water so I can get out
of here and I can go and do this stop
and quit growing yes because that's the
wrong approach yeah and that's when
you're gonna run into these you're gonna
miss the stippling you know cuz you're
not gonna have stippling if you're
staying on top of it you're checking
your environment on a regular basis and
you know that there's no air leaks or
you know ventilation issues and if
you're staying on top of your
maintenance and you're pullin your
yellow leaves and you're cleaning up the
inside of the plant so they've got the
you know airflow and you don't have to
worry about the mildew I met with the
guy today was telling me that one of
their greenhouses like that powdery
mildew it is February 3rd in Colorado it
was 4 degrees with like 0% humidity
and these [ __ ] got powdery
mildew why because they were growing
with synthetics they didn't clean their
plants bright it was operator error
yeah you know it's not plant error you
know these and that's something that
don't blame yourself and don't blame
other people because that's really not
the way to view a pest problem
you should always view it as what can
you do to improve it if your buddy gives
you spider mites don't punch him in the
face because he's dealing with the
problems too but now you know if
honestly though if you get spider mites
from your buddy
then you're kind of a dumbass for
bringing a plane without checking it for
spider mites and that goes back to you
just being educated enough to identify
what stippling is to know what spider my
eggs look like to know how to use a
magnifying glass you know there's so
much information like what me and you
were learning we had to buy books man I
remember going to Barnes &amp; Nobles like
trying to buy Vito books about growing
weed it was a difficult experience to
ask for him did he have them out it was
so weird and nowadays I can go to 50
different web cycle everything yeah I
mean it's ruined you can listen to a
podcast yeah driving down the street and
absorb massive weight that's the thing
is just I don't understand me running
into these problems with all of this
information available absolutely the
resources are out there dragonfly earth
medicine Rocky Mountain earthworm
company those guys come through for me
time and time again Jase castings not
justice castings but aloe cocoa secret
oh gee by Oh our earth cult this
everything that we can source through
him
neem karanji kelp he's always hooking it
up dragonfly the same way and then you
know the same thing follow us on our
farm saying saw CBD me at King Cola
I'm not afraid to tell you I got spider
mites you know I'll post that if I get
powdery mildew you know we were dealing
with algae blooms on our root riot we
had algae growing on root riot blocks
that's because the temperature
fluctuation our air temp was staying
warm enough but the cube temp was
dropping okay I can you they don't make
thermometers to check cube temp but you
know so we were basically keeping the
cubes too cold we had our so when we
claimed we'll do like a allo cocoa I'm
sorry allo protec and full power and
then we'll usually fall your spray with
like a seed crop or a compost tea but
basically we had some nutrient content
and the plants wouldn't take it because
roots never develop because it was too
cold the plants didn't die but you know
there was nutrient content excess
sunlight algae bloom you know but yeah
you just got to live in you learn man
look you had a little pond happening
exactly yeah
but you can fish in there see yeah we
now we're running easy cloners I'd love
an easy cloner shut us through the easy
planners it's it's wonderful yeah but
indoors in micro room it's you know
anywhere that else that we've run it we
do the same cloning method over and over
again hitting you know ninety percent
you know clone rates bring him into this
greenhouse
I have plant I have clones that aren't
dead aren't rooted still green and lush
they were taken almost a month to go Wow
and the reason I haven't thrown them is
because I'm really anxious to see what
happens they're gonna live or die dude
I've got plans
I've got plants like that I've taken
clones off of from like clones I took
with you know I took that clone right
yeah but so yeah roll with the punches
you know information is key preventive
is key or preventive is key and
information is a big part of that
preventive is know what you're doing and
don't don't go and conceited and cocky
like you know what you're doing but
really do your research yeah
spend some time you know looking at what
spider mites looks like if you hear that
your friend has a spider mites go and
for the love of God find an old t-shirt
or something but volunteer to go over to
his house with the microscope look and
see what the spider mite damage looks
like because you're not gonna know
unless you look and but that's what I
think is so important is the education
you know what you're looking for
yeah yeah so if you can become familiar
with stippling you can become familiar
with fungus mat or your new difference
between a fungus gnat a flying rude
aphid if you become familiar with the
thrip or all three or Wi-Fi you know
people these small-time guys aren't
familiar with it you know we me and you
run into it because we're growing
hundreds and thousands of these plants
but when you're in your home grow and
you run into these prized is you're not
perfect it happens but you stop you know
evaluate the you know situation and
don't panic exactly educate yourself you
know don't run down to that gross store
and buy a chemical and spray your plant
if you've never used a synthetic you
know nutrient if you haven't you mean
even if you had so if as long as you
haven't sprayed there systemics is
really the big thing um if you're in veg
and you hit it with some advanced newts
or something like that um stop go and
hit it with the compost tea top dress
with some earthworm castings try to make
start that biological system implement
some beneficials start foal you're
spraying and then just ride it out like
nature intended and they won't want to
hang out don't get exactly the plate of
the bugs a leaf no yeah so I don't think
I would be as experienced of a gardener
and in the position I am in if I did not
[ __ ] up a whole bunch that's how I
learned the most I think that's how
humans learned the most is by making
huge mistakes the more mistakes we make
the more we're able to learn so accept
your mistakes guys when you see some
bugs in there it's not your fault you
did
do that you didn't cause that learn from
it that's what we're trying to say here
learn from it
admit it you're gonna have to miss got
something yeah sure with your friends
you guys might all learn something you
might be able to come on a podcast and
talk about it one day all right bro
we've been going for almost an hour here
but thank you for coming you got
anything else you want to say while I
got you here no I just really yeah check
out saying saw CBD san Sol CBD comm
check that CBD instagram at king cole on
instagram you can find me you find those
linked but yeah check us out support
what we're doing we're really trying to
lead by example here in Colorado with
the Seoul CBD movement you're definitely
making me feel like I'm not working hard
enough I'd maybe come back and we can
just talk about this whole CBD gig and
they express a little bit more on what
we got going on out there I'd love to
hear more about that I'm sure the
listeners would love it we had our
friend Fox on who's a CBD guy he had a
lot of listens cool man well I really
appreciate you having me again oh thanks
for coming and taking some time and dude
thanks for smoking that skunk joint with
me I'm a little slow I appreciate that
no problem man alright we're gonna wrap
this part up you guys I'll be back in
just a minute to put a tail on the show
thanks for listening yeah I hope you
guys learned as much from that episode
as I did
I want to thank Sean for joining me make
sure you follow sean on instagram it's
at king underscore cola underscore king
with the k' colo with the c make sure
you follow him give him some support I'm
sure you learned something else from it
Mickey foe I'm on Instagram you guys
want to send a huge shout out to the
sponsors make sure you check out hit man
glass at hit man glass comm I'm sitting
here dabbing some turf XG funk OG fresh
nectar out of my hip man short stack
there's nothing like it you guys I want
to give a huge shout out to hitman
highly-educated titanium oil slick and
emo tech and a huge shout out tutor pecs
I think that's all for the podcast this
week I would appreciate it if you go to
the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast find the review
section give me a 5 star rating and type
in a little comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on an episode that is coming up
very soon very likely the next episode
if you've got something to say I would
love to hear it you can find me on
social media on Facebook it's at girl
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
at G fyh podcast or you can email me
it's simply grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you guys don't forget that
the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and most of
the episodes are archived on I read
genetics Colorado comm I think it goes
to about 27 or something like that for
some reason part of the episodes got
dropped I will fix that also there used
to be a donation button on the podcast
page they took that down you guys
unfortunately PayPal did not approve of
my podcast being related to cannabis
they did not want to let me take
donations for that they have suspended
my PayPal account my account is frozen I
can't access my funds I cannot take in
any more funds I will contact them and I
will see if I can fix that somebody said
they tried to donate to the show that is
why you cannot donate I am NOT the
webmaster my friend Tony is the
webmaster he was also a college student
he's been a little tied up when he gets
a minute he will fix that for me unless
I can convince PayPal to let me accept
some donations all right you guys I want
to thank you guys for listening make
sure you check back with me in a few
days have got another episode coming up
make sure you follow me on Instagram
I've got a new Instagram pages Irie
underscore genetics I would love it if
you'd follow me there I'm gonna give a
huge shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you