welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 120 grow from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
right a pure new grower appear
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if your
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots ban Colette amuse
their music on my show big shout out to
Kat
to the entire mystic roots crew
you guys this episode was fun to record
add a few people over we had our buddy
buzzy over we had Mike over and our good
homie sloppy was back how we did an
episode about how to interact with law
enforcement in case you're pulled over
or in case you bump into the cops out of
public or a case of cops come to your
front door there may be some useful
advice in this one for you before we get
to the podcast and you did give a huge
shout out to my friends at hitman glass
tonight I'm sitting here hitting the
Hitman eseries sidecar smoking Sumter
pecks our Death Star
I've got some live resin big shot it's
my friends a hit man when I buy a rig I
like to buy a rig made in America by an
American that's why shop with hit man
glass took mine at
www.www.pinesicearena.com to SoCal
festival do not miss it all right guys
that's all I've got for shoutouts and
advertising so I'm gonna let the music
played we're going to get into the
episode about how to interact with law
enforcement thanks for listening so what
I think we have learned today is that we
need to sign like a an emergency contact
form for people when they come over and
take that I try to [ __ ] people up over
here apparently ladies and gentleman
welcome back to the show sitting to my
left is our good friend buzzy how you
doing today my friend hey y'all as well
right on thank you for joining me no
problem awesome over here kind of in
front of me a little bit off to an angle
is our good buddy white Mike welcome
back to the show bro
thanks man good beer thanks for coming
over here even more in front of me is
our buddy sloppy how you doing bro yo yo
doing well right on man thanks for
coming I don't get to see you often
enough for sure that's why I shot over
here like that sloppy was on time if not
early I was [ __ ] impressed good work
bro thanks for coming for sure
awesome uh we've got a topic that we're
gonna talk about tonight I'm gonna tell
a little quick story yesterday I was at
work and one of my trimmers I will not
say his name just cuz I got respect for
him one of my trimmers called me and
he's like hey bro can you do me a favor
he's like anything for you bro and he
said can you
pick me up at the fire station and I was
like well what's going on and he said I
got pulled over and they gave me a DUI
for cannabis so they gave him they
pulled him over they had probable cause
to pull him over when they pulled it
walked up to the car the car wreaked of
cannabis because he's a trimmer I'm sure
I rock you patient hazard yeah yeah yeah
and so the cop was like holy [ __ ] you
smell like cannabis and my buddy was
like well I'm a trimmer and he's like
alright well get out of the car I want
to give you a sobriety test and my buddy
failed the test okay they then put him
in the cop car took him to the fire
station and drew blood at that point
they called me I my buddy called me and
said that I could come pick him up a
couple minutes later my phone rang it
was my buddy saying hey this state
trooper just said that if you look smell
or act high at all he's going to arrest
you so be cool if you were coming or
I'll call somebody else and I was cool I
hadn't smoked yeah it was really it was
like 2:00 in the afternoon and I don't
even think I smoked before I went to
work that day because I go to [ __ ]
early to smoke sometimes right so in
smoke though they ask crispy the only
reason my eyes would be crispy is cuz
they'd been up for too long working you
know in the [ __ ] grow room so I Drive
over there and I called my buddy I'm
like can you come out and he goes hold
on the cops gonna come talk to you I was
like [ __ ] he's gonna come talk to me I
got my couple of friends in the car from
work I just brought everybody with me
cuz I didn't want to leave him there
without the boss so I put him in the car
like a field trip for the boys didn't
took them to the fire station and we I
get out of the cars like you guys stay
here
somebody record this so a couple of the
people recorded the interaction on their
cell phone just in case [ __ ] went sloppy
nothing went wrong it was all good so I
I walk up to the cop and he's like so
your buddy
was pulled over for DUI he's too
intoxicated to drive I've got the
opportunity to either take him to jail
and keep him or I can release him to a
responsible adult who will declare
responsibility for him for the next
eight hours so uh I know the guy he's a
good dude and he's gonna come work but I
need to [ __ ] come work with me he was
on his way to work when he got pulled
over so I was like yeah man I'll sign
the paper so the cops like I need your
ID and you
my ID and watch me write down my
information as I was doing it and ran my
license and [ __ ] because you're not
wanted and I go oh thanks I've never
felt more unwanted because I was sober
and it was kind of the cop I want to
give him a shout-out I don't remember
his name he was really [ __ ] cool for
being a state trooper that had to get my
friend a DUI he gave us information on
how to avoid getting ourselves in
trouble he said stuff like don't smell
like cannabis so strongly don't smell
like cannabis have expired plates and do
these sir he said there are 15 he didn't
tell us what they are he said there are
15 things that they look for as main
keys and my buddy hit nine of them so he
definitely got arrested but they let him
go to me the cop was really cool but
I've been talking about doing this
episode about what to do if you're
involved with law enforcement I feel
like my buddy handled himself well he
told them he worked in the energy had to
over you wouldn't gotten that call
exactly yeah and that's that it was very
different calls yeah yeah yeah if you
come out of the college what's up why
are you arresting me you're not gonna
get yeah you're gonna go to jail they
didn't even tow his car they pulled it
off to the side oh yeah yeah they asked
us a lot of questions and I'd quit when
I was picking him up be the cop asked
basic questions and then he got friendly
with us and started asking questions
about the industry and work and at one
point I just shut up I was like oh I
don't want to answer any more questions
he tricked me he's my friend now and I'm
telling him [ __ ] to pull myself out of
that one but it brings us to this
episode it's a really good way to segue
into this don't drive high because
they're out looking for people in
Colorado right now it's the start this
officer told us it's the start of their
searching for DUI season all the
troopers have recently taken a drug
expert class a lot of the state troopers
are now cannabis what is tox cannabis
intoxication or impairment experts or
whatever so where they could tell how
high you are and this cop said things
that made me think he was serious he
knew stuff about my buddy being
intoxicated that I know about cannabis
like he knew that level he said your
buddy doesn't look high or act high but
when I interviewed him I can tell there
are things inside of him
that are going on that indicate that
he's high well that's kind of [ __ ]
like I was impressed by the way that he
put it by are a Jedi Master like right
port medical training like whatever I
don't know
but ah so let's talk about some things
that we could do to maybe help ourselves
out and not get in as much trouble and
maybe prevent ourselves maybe hopefully
walk away without any [ __ ] handcuffs
or maybe instead of getting all the way
taken to the jail keep yourself in a
situation where they call Rasta Jeff and
he gets to come pick you up and sign for
you so let's talk about like if you get
pulled over ah you've told me a your
method our friend buzzy over here he's
told me his method of how to handle
himself when he gets pulled over so I'm
gonna go around the table and I'll start
I would all start with buzzy cuz used to
the left you're driving down the street
you're on the interstate you're driving
maybe you got a little weed in the car
but it's hidden you know it's cool or
it's in Colorado so Colorado so but not
all of our listeners are in Colorado so
a lot of these people are gonna be like
however many per sale where you are is
really gonna depend on what you should
do before you get the car
also if you are driving with weed
regardless of where you are should
pretty much put it in the trunk
always and we're know it in no way
endorsing breaking the law just we're
gonna teach you how to be a little
smarter about getting Colorado where
it's all right yeah okay then we'll
stick with Colorado let me find you
ashtray brother just do it right here
onto this table right here do that then
look imma Davor make my blunt blunt
divert I don't think you I appreciate
you brother all right all right let's
see order in the court I'm tapping the
gavel so you get pulled over you got my
buddy buzz you over here you getting
pulled over you got those red and blues
behind you they're flickering bling
bling bling and you're getting pulled
over for your blinkers be being in a car
and driving and just being a person
windows are tinted they don't know what
color you are in there they have no idea
what you're doing I don't know just
pulled over you don't even know yet so
you're pulled over walks up to the
window shines is like right [ __ ]
goddamn face and usually he'll say
something like yeah I would have the
window rolled down before he gets there
okay your hands should be on the
steering wheel all right both hands on
the steering wheel yeah you want to be
able to the cops should be able to see
both your hands this is to my method is
avoid anything possible be extremely
what the cop wants to happen him the
most desirable situation possibly
submissive to him all trying to avoid
paying money to the state for getting
shot as my goal so far yeah so you just
keep your hands on the wheel
he's like bleh license registration say
it's in my glove box can I reach into it
he says sure you go into it you get your
stuff out give it to him then I don't
know different things can happen from
there okay so he grabs your license like
how you doing you're like um pretty good
sir how about yourself probably is what
you're polite dude there's me like
license registration proof of insurance
he's gonna walk back to the car
hopefully he's gonna come back and he's
gonna say my friend buzzy you were going
a little too fast
I quit driving like an [ __ ] in these
parts I'm just gonna give you a warning
hopefully it goes well so the key to it
I think we're all gonna have the same
story be polite to the cop don't try to
be know your rights but don't try to
invoke them immediately when the cop
comes up give him what he wants and
totally start telling you start [ __ ]
with you like the important thing to
keep in mind here is that they have all
the power and can execute you I mean not
to [ __ ] blown it at all 999 times out
of a hundred or probably even more than
that you're gonna get annoyed ticketed
and sent on your way but you that one
time out of however many they're gonna
freak out shoot you in the face or get
pissed and drag you to jail for it in
some towns the cops are just straight
robbed you know take your [ __ ] don't
lean be there
take your [ __ ] lie on the side of the
road like
I want to continue open mind like
exercise your rights but do if you
follow the little script they're
expecting nine times out of ten you're
on your way in ten minutes all right
yeah yeah ten 15 minutes long it takes
him to rush it all right we're in the
same pullover you've gotten pulled over
you've gone through all the [ __ ] our
buddy buzzy over here is handled but now
when the cop comes back with your
license registration proof of insurance
he goes hey Mike uh kind of smells like
you got weed in there I would like to
search your vehicle now what's the
proper response at this point I don't
sloppy
law enforcement unless it's in a video
game so just I do not consent to any
searches there's just you keep repeating
that when they ask you to search your
stuff all right they need major probable
cause and they'll make [ __ ] up like
you've got Altoids that's probable cause
excuse that to come under breath new
that that's not probable cause what
about like myself I work in a giant Gro
I was trimming plants there were six
feet tall today I had to chop I had to
lean in between two plants and chop
plants down and carry six foot tall
plants so my shirt I probably reek I've
got trim on me right now if I was coming
from work and they said you smell like
marijuana it's I work in the legal
marijuana industry that's just a side
effect of my job it's probably the
probable cause to search my vehicle
though not be I'm sorry to jump in I
would say be strong on distinguishing
the different smells between smoke
marijuana and fresh marijuana this
doesn't this does this smell that you're
smelling is work-related this is not
smoke marijuana is the smell of a plant
right at this point you're like they're
arguing about smells because you're not
slurring your speech because your eyes
aren't red because they didn't catch you
weaving so I don't do that [ __ ] is
probably one of the things we should put
on the list to avoid getting your ass in
truth you're sober right now you can
argue it this is a smell that I picked
up at work working wall sober I'm on my
way home sober like that's what you're
smelling if you insist on searching the
car like unless they're finding roaches
in the ashtray or add a brick in the
cupholder
and put your [ __ ] away you guys yep
you're headed on the road yeah have it
out of reach
you're Stephanie you know if you've got
a locked container that would be ideal
that's what they'd prefer to keep in the
trunk I think we were talking about that
earlier right it works just like booze
if you've got a 12-pack in the backseat
of the trunk you're fine if that 12-pack
is open and the 12th one is in your cup
holder you ain't fine no more sloppy
little blunt he never passed it to
anybody what's going on with you bro
I've hit it four times sir I figured
there's only two of us smoking in your
house
thanks for coming man I respect the
block no there's like what happened to
some of my friends just not wanting to
smoke and I just see her face Hills all
day they made me this stoned
alright so sloppy yes I want to hear
about it I'm a cop
I got the red and blue lights behind you
you're in the car I'm just cruising
ain't nothing wrong that you know of
yeah you pull over I come up behind you
how do you handle yourself what are you
gonna do okay
so two different answers when I was
younger
cuz I have two totally different
perspectives on this that's why I got
you here from being an adolescent to
being in a you know what I'm saying like
from going from you I told ya when I was
just saying I'm just a respect for the
blunt and my homey yeah I could die
happy right now
no I have goals no okay so when I was
younger
I was one of those oh [ __ ] the police
man they can't do [ __ ] to me too
and I would you know approach to the
situation they pulled me over and I'd be
like why'd you pull me over this is then
I'd be really confrontational towards it
and then I'd go to jail and that's what
would happen because I was being
confrontational in a scenario or II
didn't need to nowadays you comply you
[ __ ] comply to everything there are
asking you within reason like oh why and
why are you speeding this keep like what
buzz he said keep your hands where they
can see them my goal is to make the
police officer feel comfortable like as
soon as I walk up to the window that
should be your best friend like all
those teeth are mighty white today sir
you're looking real sharp tonight close
like I yeah it's nice and sunny out
right like don't don't say the phrase
mighty white so without without putting
myself out there too much I was driving
not high at the moment going 15 over and
I had weed on me this is back in North
Carolina or whatever and I got pulled
over and I had Colorado plates because I
had a rental car I'm going I'm going 15
over and I just I was like [ __ ] you know
what I'm saying like dude get out of the
car with his cowboy hat like he had a
cowboy hat and his badge was on the Hat
yes yeah so so so what happened was I
drove back to North Carolina I brought a
little bit of personal because I didn't
want to deal with no like [ __ ]
ratchet [ __ ] to get weed back there [ __ ]
that I got we now I actually got pulled
over in Kansas worst place to get pulled
over ever so he got out with the badge
on his hat and I was like oh he's gonna
shoot me and my dogs I had two little
puppies but so I'm nervous I'm like [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] Colorado plates and I remember
right until he was in my peripherals
I was nervous like scared and as soon as
he was that I sung to him he was I could
have sung him a hole disc I was so nice
to him
and he asked me why I was speeding I was
like officer I've been driving for like
eight hours I saw that there's a rest
area up there I was honestly just trying
to make it there so I can go to sleep
runs my stuff now I don't know how the
police things work but I'm pretty sure
that when they run my name in any state
they can see my
criminal background I'm pretty sure it
goes from state to state so he saw
somehow perfect but the bigger stuff yes
yeah I'm sure he saw I had a record and
he treated me totally respectfully he
looked me he said I pulled you over to Z
were speeding and I wanted to really
come talk to you because your Colorado
plates I wanted to see if you have
anything to hide from me but obviously
you don't have a good day and then he
left me didn't even give me the speeding
ticket and it's all because I was I made
him feel comfortable and I was polite
cuz fifteen over they could take your
license on the spot if they really want
to be a dick and we were in Kansas and I
had two pit bulls in the car and after
he left I threw up because I was like oh
my god Duke yeah I really thought I was
going back to jail and I was like I hate
life they're gonna take my dogs but I
could have handled it like when I was
younger and been an [ __ ] and got my
dog shot and got [ __ ] tasered she
killed myself for throwing back in jail
but I was polite that's what I hate I
hate seeing all these videos where
they're like oh that's that's police
abuse that's police abuse but the dude
isn't doing what the police is asking
him like lay down on the ground lay the
[ __ ] down like what why do you want to
get DDT doc I just don't see the point
like they're pointing like I saw a video
that's all video the police had a gun
pointed at a guy he had a knife and he
lunged at him and they shot him and
people are like I'm necessary force
you're a [ __ ] hypocrite because if
you have a legal gun on you and I come
and try to stab you right now you're
gonna shoot me you [ __ ] so don't
[ __ ] don't vitae it on the police and
and and when I say [ __ ] I don't mean
gay people's it'll be all upside up it's
an old-school version yeah yeah for sure
don't be a little [ __ ] [ __ ] about it
don't be a little [ __ ] like because if
I try to stab you say one more time
we're gonna do something
but not I hate that because people are
so hypocritical because if they put
themselves in the same position they
would act totally different than what
they're speaking and I hate that because
if you try to stab me I'm shooting you
if I have a legal right yeah like stand
in front of that guy with a knife and I
give you half a second decide he will
shoot him or not you're shooting them
every time the judges be like why didn't
you shoot him 17 times there was only 16
bullets I was like Big Lebowski
reference for all the people that didn't
get it the real trick here though is to
just be calm and go through the script
that they're expecting and that's really
easy to do yeah if you're not doing
something you're not supposed to be
doing like but a lot of people are doing
something we shouldn't be doing well no
like I remember how he used to be in
Colorado I used to have to drive go pick
up weed and drive at home all the time
and that was the time that I was most at
risk is when I just went and picked up a
new quarter and had to drive at home and
I made it real easy on myself I threw it
in a backpack when I bought it I threw
that backpack in the trunk when I got to
the car if I got pulled over on the way
home it wasn't for speeding cuz I did my
damnedest not to break a single traffic
law with weed in the car crews could but
I got pulled over plenty of times with
weed in the car and when they walk up to
your car and go good evening officer and
it doesn't stink like weed in the car
you're fine they go oh I pulled you over
for this let me run your [ __ ] oh here's
your ticket have a good night
you show up the court you pay that [ __ ]
it's done click try 205 on i-25 rasta
Jeff right yeah cruise control I also
think looking looking them in the eyes
is key yeah because you're hiding
something you're like aftershave yeah be
respectful like like if you can be calm
and confident they don't wonder why
you're nervous and try to figure out why
you're you're freaking out and want to
dig through your car the hardest part
for me is when they make you sign the
ticket like normally I sign my suit my
name like you'll get a little motion but
then you get all nervous and your [ __ ]
looks like [ __ ] polygraph or some
[ __ ] like I'm ok thanks officer right
it's all good - you look like you've got
a major neurological disorder always
sloppy so like if that happens I
yes I don't know what I'm gonna decide
my real name end up going to jail and
they're gonna owe our buddies headphones
here taking a poo on us
are they back now in business yeah it's
it's this connection here you're gonna
slide and sloppy one time and they're
gonna make that your real name you're
gonna have to sign everything as sloppy
it's my alias under the NC inmate
whatever it's just sloppy I
unfortunately unfortunately I got
arrested once and my hat said sloppy on
it and so they take it down cuz your
gang name now he brought it to me like I
can only assume that you're sloppy huh
[ __ ] I also had it tattooed on my arm
for a while you had it on your arm for a
while it's covered up now that makes
more sense
yeah yeah yeah how did this dude have a
tattoo fight well I have covered all of
my gang affiliation tattoos nice work
trying to be a good person now bruh I'm
trying not to be a target one of the old
heads one day looked to me said all that
is is a bull's-eye for everybody that
doesn't like you and the police and I
said oh my god like that is genius
he's like what you walk down the shirt
you're just telling everybody like you
don't need to do that oh yeah yeah all
right all right so now let's move on we
all we all know how to what to do if you
get pulled over now pull the [ __ ] over
as quickly as you can safely pull the
[ __ ] over keep your hands where they can
see him let the cop come up he's gonna
be like I watch it yeah don't don't
flirt with a female cop know that pisses
her off so bad don't do it don't holler
miss Carter Koppel come up be like hey
what's up and be like yes sir no sir but
that interaction goes smoothly when they
ask for your stuff tell them you're
gonna reach for it I'm gonna reach for
into the glove box
ask them to reach for it asking can I
reach my glove box and grab my license
registration proof of insurance I'm
gonna reach in my pocket get my wallet
out now please
all right don't shoot me sir then hand
him your stuff I recommend everybody
records interactions with the police's
as soon as you're pulled over turn your
camera phone on places somewhere or like
you know what I'm saying like just
stream it yeah for sure because then
like yo I mean why not at least is there
you a I don't want everyone seeing me
cry on periscope
if you can record it it's an extra layer
of protection for everybody it if you're
lucky you live in a place where the cops
have cameras stuck to their chests that
they can't turn off but you're not lucky
and then when you drive away don't get
all nervous and do something stupid
right try not too hard I've done it
before there's something else I was
thinking about earlier today that I had
to realize as an adult is a not every
officer is a [ __ ] scumbag you know
I'm saying by saying that every officer
is just trying to make your day worse is
basically being racist it's like the
same as labeling a racist doing so yeah
like I it's just Java store some [ __ ]
yeah yeah every fast-food person's gonna
be an [ __ ] and every cops trying to
[ __ ] you over because I've seen cool
cops I've interacted with wait cops who
are literally just trying to do their
jobs yeah cops ative giving me so when I
was younger like 24 25 ish my girlfriend
at the time worked managed a bar and we
would go smoke in the Halle
there was an alleyway that went one way
he could turn left or right to come into
the parking lot of the bar if you go to
the other way you'll go through another
area this cop would roll through and he
knew we were out there just puffing all
the time in that alley cuz you just walk
right out of the side door of the bar
and go sit on this little area between
cars and smoke when he would come
through it flashes brights
so we know put our [ __ ] away and be
prepared to he wouldn't have to [ __ ]
with us you know he would just rather
not see us smoking or maybe he's got
somebody else in the car but not all
cops are [ __ ] that guy was trying to
help us out like not have to do
paperwork yeah with us just cuz we want
to smoke some weed oh sorry oh no I've
just had dozens of interactions with
couple doing I was a teenager used to
get pulled over like twice a week I had
a car that had really loud subwoofers in
the area I grew up in that made me the
biggest star on the planet
yeah for sure I've seen that but if you
follow the script nine times out of ten
you drew out of there in 15 minutes tops
we never see we rarely see any good [ __ ]
about the cops on the news on the
internet on
anywhere like that because you rarely
hear anything about the good [ __ ] when
people do good [ __ ] like oh yeah that
cop helped that old lady up it's this
[ __ ] job you only see cop kick to get
that space that's actually one
psychology class I learned about this
that's actually life period if you
notice like people talking about stuff a
lot or even the news it's never good
stuff because uh none even though it's
unknown you don't realize that good
stuff is happening all the time so that
bad stuff is a blip on the radar and
that's what you remember in reference to
because it's usually things are
copacetic
so when something bad happens it really
sticks out and that's what people want
to hear they don't want to hear like a
hundred kids were saved today they want
to hear you know puppies getting kicked
off of a cliff people are [ __ ] up man
like they see bad stuff and it it gives
them peace getting [ __ ] vine of six
seconds of just somebody planting
puppies just replays over my [ __ ]
head I personally feel like people want
to see bad things so they have a reason
to fuel unnecessary fire to complain
about why they're not doing well or to
use it to to why things are so [ __ ] up
this and that like yeah especially like
oh man here in America like we are so
privileged as Americans I hate this
whole anti-american thing that's
happening like people standing off
flights if I see you standing on the
flag I'm running you over at my Prius I
don't give a [ __ ] like that's so that's
so ignorant you want to know why this yo
this is why this is why because no one
is fleeing from America you are not
putting your family on a door and
pushing it into the ocean to get
somewhere else like America is fine
there's no there's no death rage
happening when it's nighttime we're in
here making a podcast we're not having
one of us make sure that death troopers
aren't coming to killing everybody in
our [ __ ] village like you know what
I'm saying I hate people that are like
Oh America is horrible no you're able to
be the person that you want to be
because you're in America because being
yourself in other countries can get you
[ __ ] murdered like as shitty is that
sense jarl weed this is probably but you
think that's about a half ounce
yeah half ounce a weed right here in
most countries would probably
get your head cut off bro you over but
several in a few for sure yeah yeah a
lot of countries this would be the tail
time in most yeah we we are so like free
to do even like there aren't a lot of
problems you can't downplay the no no
there are you sure absolutely 75
different kinds of food we could drive
our own vehicles we can we're okay we
all I bet everybody in this room has
varying religious beliefs and we I'm not
gonna ask good all's that do but we
could all express them by having I've
got a tattoo here I've got dreadlocks oh
you've got your symbols there I think I
have a good idea what you follow and I'm
sure you two kind of linked up in the
same similar sort of way from
conversations we've had but in other
countries one of us would be beheaded
for what we all be fighting to the death
right very very least like spend all day
pretending like that wasn't you yeah
yeah I couldn't have these dreadlocks in
a lot of places you know I do a lot of
States not Colorado you get pulled over
like I asked you this profile at one
point I literally asked you like how the
[ __ ] do you not get pulled over all the
time and it's because you don't stand
out in Colorado anymore yes a lot of the
listeners don't realize they I've been
told so many times that my voice doesn't
match my appearance when people
especially when I made the story green
and healthy wellness all going I buy a
lot of product there and I also deliver
products sometimes I buy a lot of
product there and when I do something to
people they're shopping and they're like
I recognize that voice and they turn
around they look at me and they're not
sure if that dreadlock guy is the guy
from the podcast it's really funny so
the listeners that have never that
aren't privy I guess I'm six five and
I've got dreadlocks seriously to pass my
ass like mid thigh region almost to my
knees one of the really longer ones goes
almost to my kneecaps by now so yet I
feel pressure from the police sometimes
the cop yesterday asked me he said how
long did it take you to get those
dreadlocks that long
like 11 years and he goes Wow commitment
buddy was cool I was at the courthouse
getting fingerprinted for when I worked
at a dispensary everybody had to go get
fingerprinted and had to go take a day
off because it took him all [ __ ] day
to fingerprint me but uh cop in there
walked by and he goes great dreadlocks
bro and I was like that was a cop like
cop complimented my dress now yeah and
he meant it he wasn't even being
sarcastic he was like had a smile on his
face and [ __ ] so not all cops are [ __ ]
some cops are cool but yeah and I'm a
frickin so sometimes they do feel some
pressure I think the police I think all
that America stuff time is it good with
the police like cuz that's just a big
thing going on now I I could really just
go on about go on man well social media
warriors and stuff people who are like
just bitching about the world but not I
think that what we were just talking
about earlier like all like how X public
executions and all that stuff like I
think that for one hour out of the
waiting about that yeah we were talking
about other countries being [ __ ] yes
yeah like really I think that no I
followed it was just we're all hi Steve
I've uh I think that uh everybody should
be made to watch one hour of what's
really going on in other countries like
a week one hour a week of like show me
like what's up in Mexico show me what's
up in Egypt like show you was really
[ __ ] up because that would be a great
it's all about the source where are you
gonna get that material the [ __ ]
Internet has all of it it has people
being publicly executed by the good also
does it have the good as well as the bad
well yeah no no what I'm saying is every
was just referencing to the fact that
people [ __ ] about America oh yeah yeah
okay it's we are really okay here like I
got I just went to Cali Cali was awesome
first time ever in Cali amazing
shout-out to Cali
I think someone like Cali but I I got
into a debate with my friend there
because she's like an active feminist
and stuff which I support that's awesome
but she said they're like women
have a lot of rights here and they're
really restrained so on and so forth
which in some ways I do see like
statistically they get paid less and
stuff I understand but as far as
freedoms of the world women are really
free in America and and and I hate to
say it but like in other countries women
are still getting stoned to death for
talking to males in public and we got
women running for president so like yes
things are different but like we are we
are Farley advanced in a lot of ways I
don't know if that sounds like weird to
say but like how can people find you on
Twitter
angry to eat me if you want to I want to
hear everything make sure all of the
tweets about the the anti feminism
statements are headed towards sloppy
well I didn't say anything about anti I
said I'm totally for it there were some
microaggressions I feel like it was just
a statement you almost swallowed your
whole plot when I said the word
microaggression that [ __ ] was funny like
I also think that I think it's [ __ ] up
that it's [ __ ] up to be proud of your
heritage nowadays like like no but nope
nobody really doesn't nobody's like i'm
italian and then another like nobody's
with their roots everybody wants to be
guilty of cultural appropriation right
right is it well it's a step away from
being racist it's almost it's a foot
into the racist category which it isn't
but then again racism is isn't it just
having pride in one's race isn't bigotry
the real problem like or something like
that like cuz like it's okay I feel like
it's it's a thing like it shouldn't be a
thin line like everybody should be proud
of who they are like if you're German be
proud you're German if you're a black be
proud you're black if you're if you're
Asian you know what I'm saying like but
it's when you add hate to it like oh I
don't like these other people because
they're before sure oblem yeah but I
think that it's misinterpreted a lot
like if people just see what they want
to see like straight up you could take
any story and make it good or bad and by
changing some like minor details
altering [ __ ] I've seen them do it to
people
read the same book and get totally
different stories where two people can
watch the same car accident and tell two
totally different stories perspective is
the damn thing yeah and watch the same
fight I have two totally different
stories both people one might beat the
[ __ ] out of Jeff and you'll be like Jeff
beat the [ __ ] out of Mike he was
stopping them I can the whole time I've
heard stuff like that like bad your
school [ __ ] like both people were like
one man you know just like everybody is
is Hulk your Superman here all right
guys we got way off course here but I
tried to squeeze it in America yeah they
do hashtag I like it when you ramble so
I talked about what to do if you get
pulled over by the police guys behave
yourselves don't reach too quickly we
all saw the video the guy that reached
into his car to get his ID
it got blasted by the police cheese
don't reach so quickly just chill out
ask chill out chill out chartering
trying to get a good recording whoever
said that as a genius
sly high five since you got your hand up
five you there you go high five want to
record it alright so how about we're
sitting here Mike I'm gonna no I'm gonna
ask you I want let's go Mike first this
is your house
let's say I just gave you the house
we're sitting here doorbell rings and
not even doorbell it's this one it's
[ __ ] this sound the cop we all
everybody's heart sinks when you hear
that [ __ ] the police what are you gonna
do how do you handle that um
take a quick look around the room and
make sure there's nothing laying there
that I wouldn't want laying out that's
just to have it from back when we was
illegal here right that's a good tip for
anybody that's not HollyRod oh I should
have not so hard on the [ __ ] table
ridiculous
it's I don't know how cops knock like
that repeatedly like that way they're
annoyed when I open the door right so
open the door good you know good evening
officer what can I do for you
and then see what they've got to say at
that point like nine times out of ten if
they were there and you were in real
trouble they wouldn't knocked like your
door exploded a flashbang gone off you'd
have an m16 planted your head if they're
knocking they just want to ask questions
and so you just if you're not interested
say you're not interested come back with
a warrant in play we in the conversation
and step back inside if they're like
asking about something that happened up
the street or whatever you want to talk
to him step out on the porch and pull
the door shut behind you sit there and
have the conversation should you almost
lock yourself out unnecessary all right
they can't open the door and go in for
any reason not legally they're at a
warrant like without probable cause that
like there's a crime being committed
insider that somebody's in distress so
what if the cop says well Mike I'd like
to take a look inside as why because we
believe you did it did what the thing
that we're here to accuse you of I know
come back I'd like to look inside Mike
I'd like to go inside shut the door and
continue my evening officer if you don't
have a warrant please come back if you
don't have anything to hide Mike there
shouldn't be a problem with us coming in
and taking a look don't you think I got
stuff to do have a nice night before all
right Mike thanks for thanks for playing
along do you [ __ ] win would you like
a dad like it's a lot because you won D
played that perfect all the right
answers over there
it's you've got a lot of rights in
knowing how to exercise them is key grab
a pen or type flex your rights calm I
think it is yes or just Google flex your
rights it's a series of videos put on by
a defense attorney out of Baltimore
who's really fun to watch on video and
it's really nice to know exactly what to
do and you run into law enforcement
Google flex your rights your rights
likes your right
oh we should have gone there before we
did this we should have read that right
it's it's awesome I meant to review it
before I came over but I got a kid now
and I just try not to the microphone yes
I read something the other day that says
that undercover vehicles cannot operate
normal traffic stops in Colorado do you
know if that's true or not
I saw a Chevy Tahoe ish looking vehicle
I don't want to be certain on the Tahoe
it looks like a Tahoe pull somebody over
on i-25 the other day while I was in
Denver yeah yeah I have I have somebody
works at the Honda dealership that said
that he got pulled over by undercover
and they said you don't have insurance
and he said you're not supposed to be
pulling people over in this vehicle and
they let him go but I you know I know I
don't never believe 100% what people say
so I was trying and he was a car dealer
no he just he's a mechanic okay it's
gonna say if he's a car dealer he
already loses a little bit of credit not
even though do you want me to turn your
mic up over there Mike baby loans Mike
don't smoke cigarettes you guys are
you'll end up sounding like yeah that's
exactly what that is
intervention one day we're gonna tell
them we're having a podcast and this is
gonna be an intervention sloppy sloppy
all right here we go we're at your house
up it's the cops you open the door no no
first thing I do
first thing I do because I'm a pet owner
I'm putting my dog somewhere where they
can't act aggressive towards the police
because [ __ ] that like honestly like not
trying to sound like crazy or nothing
but if they shoot my dogs in front of me
I'm catching some charges because I'm
swinging no regrets
dogs look [ __ ] scary as [ __ ] and
they're so lovable but there are 90
pounds of pit bulls so I understand like
sometimes I forget that they're like
that because people like oh my god I'm
like get in their face but yeah I know
I'm putting my dogs up and then I I'm
going to answer the door as
soon as I see that it's the authorities
I am stepping out and closing the door
like I when you said that that's exactly
I I don't want them looking in my house
I don't want them to have reason like
it's on the table at the door yeah that
well one of them talks to the other one
searches as much of your house as you
can please do be lurking around oh
there's a grinder on the table or so I
don't want none of that [ __ ] get out
shut the door why are you here
always be polite I I contact I guess
yeah hands out of your pockets yeah for
sure that's an Essex boy you don't have
your hands
all rights up here's the ultimate
question well mr. sloppy
I'd like to come inside and take a look
why I just thought I'd want to make sure
you didn't do it I really don't know
what you're talking about
you did the crime that we're here to
invent if they don't have a warrant
don't don't let them do anything don't
let them [ __ ] in your house yeah and
and honestly from from past experience
even if they have a warrant they're
gonna do whatever the [ __ ] they want cuz
the one time I was arrested was this
exact scenario I will not exact I
stepped out of the house I went to the
gas station to get a Dutch I was with my
friend Julian I think I've told her shut
up - Julia yeah yeah shout-out to
kilojoules and see he makes beats oh God
oh but no I think I've told this story
on the cast before we we pulled up to
the gas station it's like half a mile
from the house and mad cops swarmed the
car and get out and they're like full
tactical gear and stuff and they're
yelling at Julian and I whoa mistaken
identity I literally thought that and
then they looked at me and said my
government name and they had the warrant
they showed me the warrant I read it I
was in handcuffs I looked through it I
lived in a third storey apartment one
way in one way out told them the door
was unlocked said my girlfriend's in
there with my dog go ahead just go in
like you already have all the paperwork
at school they went up there and still
busted out every window flashbang my
girlfriend
knock the door in and and I told them
where everything was and they cut my
cushions open broke my fridge
they found half a gram of marijuana a
bong and an unregistered firearm
I wasn't 21 yet I was three months away
and that was it and I told them the door
was unlocked to go inside and they still
blew that [ __ ] up like yeah so if they
have the morning [ __ ] you if they don't
have the warrant get the [ __ ] out of my
face like leave me alone if they've got
the warrant they're pretty much doing
what they want to do they didn't knock
anyway they booted in that [ __ ] door
what it was was they planned on doing
that to me anyway and then I went to the
store and he was like oh you took all
the fun out of it [ __ ] their toys
alright so we all know what to do now if
the cops come to the door step outside
talk to them be kind keep your hands
where they can see them if if a cop asks
for your ID you do not have to present
ID but it helps with the interaction if
you want to keep on that like polite
like I don't want to go to jail side
compliance just give me a [ __ ] ID if
you're not hiding anything you can you
can flex your rights and be like I don't
have to give you my ID but just kind of
being a dick
there are a lot of YouTube videos where
you can really learn your rights and
some people really enjoy pulling the am
i detained am I free to go
that's a good rapid-fire that's where
I'm headed with this there are YouTube
channels that are solely dedicated to
people harassing police officers with
assault rifles just to get a rise out of
the police like sir what are you doing I
can be here because of HB 41 be my
nunchucks and samurai sword and what ass
naked are fairly legal right there well
no depending on where you live in the
u.s. like along our southern states
anything bordering Mexico they've got
random highway checkpoints where they
look for immigration documents and all
kinds of [ __ ] and a lot of that's
unconstitutional it really pisses people
off and so people who know exactly how
to flex their rights in a very specific
way
addressed giving the living [ __ ] beaten
out of them and thrown in jail and go
flex the rights it [ __ ] massive
checkpoints and stuff and it's nuts but
exactly how to do that makes getting
pulled over really easy to handle like
you stay calm keep your hands in plain
sight yeah asking what is your info out
of the globe what if you're walking down
the street what if you're just down on
[ __ ] 4th Street walking from one
store to the other that's kind of
[ __ ] dark out the cop walks up Tina's
like hey you come here I want to talk to
you a cop just walks out of nowhere or
he comes from somewhere specific he
there's a manhole ran he slid over on
the cop elevated slowly out of it turtle
you don't know where he came from you're
in conversation you and I were talking
we're blind
cop pops up bumps into us excuse me boys
I'd like to talk to you how can I help
you officer hey what's up sir what's
going on I'd like to see your ID you
reach in your pocket hand me your ID
yeah sure sure I'm just standing there
and it's not harassing I was just about
to say that that's where I'm headed next
looks like you guys we saw you guys
smoking some weed back there when you're
walking I saw you and you can reek like
weed okay I like the way you're going
with this probably right now right now
I'm gonna mace you tase you and hit you
with something and then put you in the
car cuz my perfume that was the one
that's what I always smell and I like
point to the cigarettes in my pocket be
like no sir Marlboro and they go the
question would change all right so when
does the Y want to I want to search
pockets Mike I think you're the guy
smoking weed you don't consent to any
search I feel like I need to search you
Mike
I don't consent to any searches sir by
being detained I don't have any grounds
to detain you so can I run your name
first yeah I'd like to run your name and
then I'll let you go you can go because
you're an [ __ ] and you know you're
right just stay really calm and like if
you're screaming it might be the answers
gonna be yes get on the ground but if
you just calmly I'm I'm sorry sir I have
somewhere to be am I being detained
I'm not being detained sir I'd like to
go am I free to go
Thank You officer have a good night you
know good luck investigating whatever is
what me look all right so a couple of
weeks ago weekends ago two or three
weekends ago by the time this podcast
comes out it would be three weekends
there was an event called the frost ball
the frost Bowl was a local cannabis
competition where people grew cannabis
and entered their cannabis and people
were judging it and there was a party
where people were consuming cannabis and
the police came and they raided that
[ __ ] oh they they didn't rate it
the word they use was rated but they
came and shut it down but there were
like 35 cops it's surrounded the place
and I'll stormed in all at once and shut
the place down ah let's say word an
event should well I have to change my
event now so I was gonna say the
cannabis cup but as of the past couple
of days it does not look like the Denver
cannabis cup is gonna happen yes a new
venue yeah and I it sounds like a lot of
places are not going to be able to give
that permit than they were in Pogo state
fairs already at the State Fairgrounds
in Pueblo Colorado I could [ __ ] take
an uber over there to cost me six bucks
an uber over there dab the [ __ ] out I'm
walking around I've got I don't know
four grams of shatter in my pocket seven
grams good flour okay let's be real I've
got an ounce a good flour and I got like
10 grams of shattered possession I'm
legal to carry that as an adult in
Colorado
cop walks up to me and wants to give me
[ __ ] how do I handle myself with this
cop in public
and an event had a cannabis event where
I'm gonna be [ __ ] with sorry I said
straight in public but it's at an event
where we're all consuming he's like come
here I want to talk to you know inside
the event die I'd immediately like stop
moving my feet and make sure my hands
were implants I'd just be like what
could do for you officer I'd offer to
smoke with him yeah I just kind of
resist their questions just the am I
being detained am I free to go circle in
an event like that especially like I'm
not there to get messed with I'm not
doing anything I haven't hurt anyone I'm
not carrying a weapon I didn't steal
anything
like I'm just not in the mood to be
harassed that's how I play it not in the
mood to be harassed yep all right do you
say that to the cop occasionally
occasionally it hasn't really come up
that I've had to run it like that since
I was a teenager like the good evening
officer how are you what can I do for
you like it doesn't matter if it's oh I
was speeding or oh we got a noise
complaint or oh it smells like weed out
front like if you started off that way
nine times out of ten just being played
going like no I don't consent to any
searches now I've got stuff to do later
like stuff you guys know what can I do
to howl like sorry guys have a good
night usually that gets you through it
in five or seven minutes
worst case scenario they go get out of
the car they search your car they find
the weed they write your check for the
way to go home all right that sounds
reasonable sloppy standing up taking a
DAB nice no I like it so you don't bump
the rig on the mics you don't dab the
microphone like you did last time you
were here like even if you're about to
get in a bunch of trouble playing it
cool with the original interaction with
the officer assume asurs you don't get
really injured during that and don't get
injured something I didn't mention
earlier that I should have totally
mentioned the cop that pulled my friend
over and gave him a DUI asked him how
long it had been since he smoked last my
friend tried to play mr. honesty and
told him a little too early I think I
think that played a part of the the
arrest say yesterday like if that cops
like how long ago you're you're driving
to get pulled over cops like well when
the last time you smoked cannabis
yesterday yeah yeah not today before I
went to bed I only smoked cannabis to go
to any of those questions so when the
cop goes how long has it been since
you've consumed marijuana you can say I
don't I'm not legally obligated answer
that question plead fit like if you're
thriving you're required to hand over
like license registration proof of
insurance but you're not legally
required to self-incriminate you're not
legally required to answer any other
questions dry snitching give them the
minimum amount of the information that
you need to give them you know let it go
on which you're you're legally obligated
to comply you can get arrested for just
resisting like if the cop walks up and
you run away like the köppen even say
anything you just walk onto your block
or whatever it immediately turned and
ran and he chose to chase you and arrest
you you can get arrested for just
resisting arrest got arrested for that
all charges got dropped it immediately
but under correlation of mine got
arrested just for that he they were
climbing through the window of a party
while he was in high school and he put
his arms out just to the sides and went
get out of my house piggy and he got
tackled and handcuffed and he thought it
was hilarious but he knew he he'd
survive it because after he was tackled
and handcuffed like he could do and say
what he wanted he was gonna get bailed
out in less than 24 hours anyway like
yeah I I was young on probation walking
with another friend that was on
probation and we had heard that if
you're on probation you're not supposed
to be with other people on probation so
these cops came up on us and I darted
and then I had a little dope sack on me
but I threw it and then I got arrested
and as soon as I like I went to jail got
bailed out and then as soon as I went to
court he was like where are the other
charges and I was like what do you mean
he was like well what else did you get
charged for him I said oh I just ran
because I thought I wasn't supposed to
be hanging out with this person
automatically dropped let it go bad I'm
not right here nice umm so I mean that's
a that's a easy so yeah if you could
just come you know even if you're about
to get in trouble it's so much easier to
do with a core
without the why did you run away like
why did you live on a car chase yeah
like why did you injure detective
so-and-so with your door don't do that
type of it just don't do that you just
play it cool and you're locked in his
head like I don't want to be played just
let it go into the mic night now it was
directed toward you though I don't think
you thank you thank you that dr. pepper
stain shadows to the dr. pepper those 23
Terps
right oh my god religious date sometimes
I pour others rinsed in their 20th pow
Oh interesting thing about the police
all right so if you're getting pulled
over by an unmarked vehicle would you
pull over or would you call it in
ah I'm a I'm a dude
ah I can handle myself I feel like for
the most part I got pretty good
judgement of what a cop looks like and
when huh but if I I'm not trying to be
sexist here if I were a small woman who
wasn't is [ __ ] wasn't six five and
two hundred pounds you know there are
some girls and I'm not even trained you
could pick some girls up and just
[ __ ] carry him off yeah if I was that
size of a girl I would if you just call
9-1-1 and be like hey is this cop it's
pulling me over for real they'll tell
you they just hit your your hazard
lights slow way down get over all the
way to the right and then just do like
four miles an hour call 9-1-1 and I am I
really being pulled over like I'm a tiny
woman or I'm in a sketchy part of town
or da da da da it doesn't look like a
cop car except for the flashing lights
in the windshield 911 oh if you're being
pulled over for sure yeah yeah and if
it's not they'll send people to pull
over whoever's trying is doing then just
sit there with your windows up and wait
yeah they can get that was an issue like
it still is from time to time like every
now and then you'll see in the police
blotter was someone was arrested for
yeah yeah like a year ago that I was
here so but they pulled over a cop oh
wow immediately he was like you ain't a
cop and like got out with his gun and
was like somebody going to jail
North Carolina somebody who's
impersonating an officer and uh and
robbing people like bless you Joe that's
another thing would you do you think
that you have to roll your window down
all the way or can you just do it than
this necessary amount to talk and
exchange like is that being a douche are
you pushing the limit by not giving them
the full endo light what are you trying
to prove
yeah I just roll it down to talk to him
just yeah I mean yeah cuz if somebody's
gonna salt you they're doing it through
stopping no like sir how can I lick your
ballsack today right like it that's why
you play it cool from the get-go so that
the cop doesn't decide to play it the
hardest way possible is they could just
decide to arrest you and come through
that window no problem like yeah just
roll that [ __ ] down that's why you put
the weed in the backseat or in the trunk
throw it in an extra bag or a backpack
so that your car doesn't stink when
you're on the road don't have a roach
burning in the ashtray when you get
pulled over yeah don't don't yeah I
don't smoke and driver shout-out to
ozium I man I have to get on that don't
smoke and drive [ __ ] for sure you got to
be careful with that road duis are no
fun if you do get [ __ ] and pulled over
if you get [ __ ] get yourself a good
lawyer and get a lawyer yes you can't
afford a lawyer get the free public
defender one or go to a law school in
your area nine times out of ten they've
got a third-year law student who would
[ __ ] love to defend the living Shetty
for free don't don't believe what all
your pothead friends are gonna tell you
and [ __ ] like did they'll hype you up
they'll get you scared they'll make you
feel relaxed but they they're just there
they are not a lawyer they're not a
judge they don't know the law they don't
know what's gonna happen use a little
lawyer
yeah it take their advice don't take
your crazy uncle Larry's advice just go
around there tell them that you were
this just carry a fake ID you get
arrested a simpie
know that for you I'll do bad sloppy
don't do that [ __ ] [ __ ] alright so we've
been going for a long time you guys yeah
thanks for listening if you've made it
an hour with us that's that's really a
journey - time flies when there's a
bunch of people - yes it sure does so
does anybody have would you like to
shout out any social media or anything
anything that you want to say since you
got a microphone in your face since the
people is listening I'll start going
we'll just go to the left here you got
anything you'd like to say over there my
friend not really hanging out just
hanging out kind of quiet this episode
but it's all good Mike had a lot to say
it's cool I wasn't trying I'm just
hanging thanks for being here brother
yep all right way Mike just be safe
people don't get don't get [ __ ] by
being nervous how do our friends follow
you on social media you can find me at
at Nemo punk 15 on twitter or pablo for
sensible cannabis laws on facebook pablo
for sensible cannabis laws on facebook
make sure you support that click it give
it a like follow it check out what mike
posts share it observe it it's good [ __ ]
dude people should start paying
attention to politics do get registered
to vote this next year is gonna be
interesting in most states
I wonder if Randy ever listens to the
podcast talk now poor Randy and his
little square dome know he doesn't read
anything that he suspects might not be
pre-approved educating somebody somebody
shared this podcast with Randy let him
learn the truth alright sloppy we're
gonna move over to you Mike thanks for
coming again bro and then you gotta take
time away from your youngster to come
hang out with us high-five your boy for
me
will do nice sloppy sloppy Oh how can
all the people listening how can they
find you on social media Instagram
Twitter Facebook however you want to do
em sloppy nine one nine on everything
except for tumblr I think it's sloppy
brains yeah sloppy brains I didn't make
that but somebody made it for me oh and
then ya dead god nine one nine as well
as our
music so you trying to check that out I
think I follow that didn't know that was
you yep that's me oh boy nice alright
stay out the left lane people oh dude
are you [ __ ] serious did you just say
that I turn it over to the table I Drive
50 miles to and from work every day it's
50 miles each way 100 miles on the road
there's one exit where I go it probably
takes me 10 minutes just to get on the
damn on-ramp because the construction in
Colorado Springs right now ah if you're
in the left lane
you should be passing somebody if I am
behind you in the left lane and you
think I'm riding your ass I am NOT an
[ __ ] see the left lane is for passing
yeah that lane over there to the right
is for the slower moving traffic there
are big signs on the interstate it's a
slower traffic keep right that means
[ __ ] you yeah yeah if I'm right if
I'm riding your ass in the left lane all
it means is you're conceited [ __ ] that's
right don't flick your cigarette at me
don't give me the finger put on your
damn blinker in Dover and let it pass
you and then - I don't even care if
you're going ten miles over and I'm
trying to go 20 honestly not to sound
like like a like [ __ ] it but the left
lane is the go as fast as you please and
risk getting a ticket link just right oh
yeah yeah and then get back in the right
lane as soon as you pass somebody get in
the right lane keep doing it people be
like oh you're weaving a lot I'm like no
I'm driving correctly you [ __ ] idiot
like yes get out the left leg get out
the left lane every five miles this says
keep writing less passing truth all
right and don't be that that's social
justice warrior that tries to slow me
down he's going too fast I'm gonna play
it's not your road no [ __ ] if I want to
get a ticket I'll take it
I throw water bottles this is how the
brats to do things now that you've grown
up right right right you don't do that
anymore right soppy what I do that -
come on
I'm playing I did but yeah not for real
yeah yo driving is driving is not a game
you're playing with people's lives and
sometimes when people do stupid [ __ ] on
the road yeah and and I Drive a Prius
nobody wants to get beat up by the guy
that was driving the Prius cuz then you
got to go home and lie you have to be
like it was six guys in a Jeep and it
knows one dude with a [ __ ] Bob Ross
afro hopping out here and whoopin your
ass out the Priya and then get back in
there to Bob Ross and Prius isn't
driving away in all years Adele it's
hard to be tough you pull up in your car
goes no you don't know that's where
you're wrong you don't hear the phrase I
have literally had people in the car and
then drove off and they're like you
started [ __ ] alright so we've got a long
time if you guys been listening for this
long I love all of you
we're gonna wrap up this part of the
show we're gonna take some dabs and I
will be back to put a tail on this
episode all right guys I want to send
another huge thank you to our guests big
shout out to buzzy big shot to Mike and
a huge shot at the sloppy for joining us
only give you another thank you for
listening with this long episode I'll be
back in seven days with another episode
I will have Rob from sour seeds here
we're going to talk about selecting a
male plant for breeding it should be a
great educational episode I need to give
another shout-out to our sponsor big
shot to hit man glass make sure you
check them out www dot man glass dot-com
if you would like to sponsor the show or
if you have a product you would like me
to review send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you please follow me
on Twitter it's at g f YH podcast you
can find us on Facebook
it's just grow from your heart and you
can also follow me on Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics guys thank
you again for listening I'm out for this
week I want to give a huge shout out to
my ninja Spence and until next time take
a fat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you