[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 121 of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated adder if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I'm gonna send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show big shout to
cat to the entire mystic roots crew I
also want to give a huge shout out to my
friends at hit man glass hit man glass
when I buy a new rig I like to buy
something made in America by an American
and that's why I support hit man glass
if you're lookin for a new piece I
recommend you check out
www.montgomeryvillenissan.com
[Music]
and when we come back our good buddy Rob
and I will be sitting at the table stay
tuned
[Music]
alright ladies and gentlemen welcome
back I am back with our good friend Rob
from sour seeds how you doing and I bro
how you doing man thank for having me oh
dude thanks for coming taking this time
out of your day always I've been talking
we're both busy cats dude you got a lot
of things on your hand I'm impressed too
much you looking forward to the cannabis
cup absolutely so this will be the first
time we've spoke about this on the
podcast the cannabis cup that was
planned for Denver over the 4/20 weekend
Denver said no they did not issue the
permits that were needed high times
response was to move the cannabis cup to
Pueblo Colorado yeah that's where we are
that is our location that is my town
that's where this podcast is recorded so
the pod cat no matter where the podcast
lands in Pueblo it will be 20 minutes
from my house at maximum that's I'm
pretty stoked on that we're gonna have a
whole bunch of cool people around here
we're gonna have a whole bunch of cool
[ __ ] to do I'm hoping to get a whole
bunch of cool people on the podcast
since it's nearby they can either come
here and record in the kitchen slash
studio podcast setup or I've got a
portable unit we'll take hopefully we
get a whole bunch of cool folks don't be
afraid to come you guys a lot of people
seem to be talking [ __ ] on Facebook
about Pueblo Colorado all the people
that are talking [ __ ] have never been
here well that's it and I'm from Florida
and I love it here so that tells you
something right there yeah it's I landed
here because of research there you go
that that's even worse I landed here
because the research the one I got here
I visited Denver I didn't visit the
Springs I've been in I went it's south
wallenberg but I've been all over for
being here a short amount of time in
three years and uh I really love public
Colorado it's a nice humble town you get
to know the people here they'll take
care of you yeah yeah I been first too
expensive Springs is a kind of a
military vibe I think it's a high crime
- okay yeah I've been I'd work in
Springs now and I see a lot of wonky
[ __ ] on my breaks honestly I see some
strange I just watch the crazy local
news man and it's always going down in
Springs yeah yeah well there are a
couple of parts of Pueblo that I would
not go to but for most for the most part
this place is not that bad you guys so
come hang out at the Cannabis Cup have a
good time
sour seeds should have a booth out there
you know I'll be running around I don't
have a booth I will not do a booth this
year I'll have an IRA genetics t-shirt
on I'll be running around having a good
time that's a long ways away but we're
stoked about it the Cannabis Cup is
coming to Pueblo Colorado I don't be
afraid come see us absolutely it's gonna
be a lot of fun guys all right guys so
we're gonna do a little show about
breeding cannabis we want to do a show
about selecting a male plant
sorry we're both coughing over here I'm
taking some dads Rob smoking a joint
what's train are you smoking on bro
probably submit Tutankhamun the King Tut
it tastes good smells it smells kind of
a it's good at unique smell very unique
smell I don't even know how to describe
that uh it almost reminded me of a
specific terpenoid I can't remember
which one we decided it smelled like
anymore blend a little little Lin Ahlul
thank you for the heads up there I can
never remember the name of Lin Elul it's
always the one that I forget there herb
smells like it's got a lot of Lin Ahlul
in it anyway we're choking over here cuz
we're getting high I'm smoking some
perfects our death star wax shadow to
the Terp ex crew all right we're gonna
do a podcast about selecting a male
plant for breeding if you're if you're
trying to breed some seeds there are a
few things to look for in a male plant
so let's say you buy yourself a 10 pack
I would do it to 10 packs if you're
trying to do a female hunt to find a
male but not everybody's got the room
try to do at least two 10 packs there's
power in numbers when you're hunting the
more plants the better I agree 20 to 50
is a good number right you can usually
find super plants in 20 to 50 just
astounding keepers they stand out yeah
and if you can't do that many at a time
just do them in phases do 10 find a
keeper out of that 10 do 10 more find
the best out of those 2 or that yeah out
of those 10 and then you got to to stack
up against each other keep doing it
until your room is full and it's not
eliminating [ __ ] that's right I even
sometimes I do it from seeds right out
of the gate you can kind of tell you
know you have those seeds that just look
like they're gonna have a hard time
they're gonna struggle and you can tell
whenever they open the shell they have
the little tiny leaves or sometimes are
mutated or doesn't look as strong or
vibrant as the others I just go ahead
and chuck them as a breeder as somebody
who is I've read a lot of plants and if
you were looking for a male plant you're
going to have to learn to get rid of
some plants and not be too attached to
your babies be ruthless yes be ruthless
these are not humans these are little
baby plants and you were
creating the future of cannabis if you
do not pull those ugly little [ __ ]
you are going to ruin and [ __ ] up and
you're gonna [ __ ] the progression of
cannabis that's exactly the genetics
down yes you are and we don't want to do
that we're breeding to improve the
genetics so if you have a plant you
start a bunch of seeds you got a couple
that are kind of wonky looking you got
one with the [ __ ] up leave don't be
afraid to get rid of it right as they
grow keep a good eye on them so before
we get to that part let's talk about
what the male plant is going to bring to
our breeding project when we hit a male
plant with pollen - a female plant that
accepts pollen that has pistols it's
going to create seeds that are going to
have traits of both plants what is the
male mostly going to bring to the table
here I feel like it's going to bring a
lot of the pest resistance and a lot of
the vigour and a lot of the shape that's
it that's a literally a lot of what it
is the hybrid vigor and in and without
that male side of the family you really
can't catch that true hard vigor like
that um I always tell people all the
time you know you can't create you know
Halle Berry's by eliminating half
gameful I like the way you put that
people catch on there alright so yeah we
need the male to bring back good
structure and the resistance I think a
lot of the flavor comes from Mama it
comes from the girl so when you're
looking for structure and shape a lot of
it is gonna come from the boy so now we
could talk a little bit about what to
look for in a male plant I keep saying
the structure I like a male plant if
you're breeding a sativa you're gonna
want one that gets a little bit taller
the meals are always gonna when you're
when you're in veg the males are always
gonna start taking off a little taller
their goal is to get above the females
so that when they pollinate their pollen
falls down on to the girl so that's a
good hint when they're growing in veg
look for that one that's taken off that
might be a boy for you absolutely
so you're looking for if you've got a
sativa you want the one that keeps not
too tall and doesn't take off too much
because you don't want to make your
progeny skyrocket immediately but you
want to find the one that's the right
shape of you almost want to find what
you want your girls to look like you
want the boy to look the shape to be
what you want your females to look like
what I think I'm trying to say so fine
look for that you want tight clothes
note spacing you don't want a whole
bunch of gaps between your branches I
don't like it when a plant spits out
really long branches like Tahoe say the
oh geez that was about to come right out
of my mouth the og family the whole
family over there on that side even
grape stomp Orochi and some of the other
ones that are hybrids most of them take
off because the boys like you're saying
the structure it comes from the male is
a perfect example Joseph the Joseph male
that gage uses everything they crossed
that great male by the way but it comes
out tall a lot of the times you get
mostly dominant phenotypes of stretchy
plants because the stretchy stretchy
with little popcorn balls coming off
everywhere it's a dominant og male and
that's that's what's going on there it's
that structures taken over the dominance
from that male plant in this do G
dominance and that og is always the
cushions have always had had that
dominance and it really there's an
Afghan Heritage's it's just a traceback
it's recessive Afghan genes that are
really strong and they're always gonna
come forward and breed true unless you
find a dominant gene from a different
side of the family that breeds just as
hard like something from blue dream for
example a good example of a good
breeding parent or white widow used to
be a really good breeding parent spread
the white widow with two other strains
and it does very well that's exactly and
that's what you're doing at that time
you take another s'ti of genotypes from
different parts of the world Brazil
South America things like that and then
diversifying them against things like og
cush is which are originally derivative
afghan places like that then mostly
purged into california east coast places
with coastlines and then out out a lot
of the stuff that started off in the
dutch genetics has those real thin
leaves because it was all bred for
indoor cultivations a lot of brazilian
institute genetics and in nepal and
things like that and Nepalese genetics
Moroccan genetics you see a lot of Spain
a lot of Spanish genetics that's where
you see an influx of that in Netherlands
so I wanna give a shot at the gauge
between genetics since we were talking
about the grape stopper OG there those
guys finally took home a cannabis cup
for the grape stopper good work guys
nothing but love and respect for egauge
congrats m4k mk4 and key play the whole
true they kind of help me get a little
start in the cannabis industry so much
much love much respect
for that so yeah look for something that
doesn't get too tall too crazy if you're
looking for an indica if you're trying
to breed an indica male find the
shortest stoutest [ __ ] dias one you can
find probably with those big fattest
leaves you can find the what there's
dinner-plate leaves if you can camp out
under those leaves if you can almost
make a hammock under those leaves that'd
be a sweet male to breed with if you're
looking for a nice indica plant so you
want something with nice nice tight
closed node spacing so if you can find a
male plant you got a flower about you
guys so you got to fetch them out start
looking for note their structure in veg
watch what they do you don't have to get
them too tall take a clone off of them
label the clone that matches the so
clone a to plant a clone be to plant be
flower your plants out see what they do
if you've got females and you're looking
for males you can just go ahead and toss
the females or you can finish them out
and have some buds
I will take my male plants and flower
them all the way out to see what they do
all the way to like seven eight maybe
nine weeks into flower I want to see if
they're gonna produce trichomes I want
to see if they're gonna produce a whole
bunch of pollen I want to see if they're
just some plants will only produce a
little bit of pollen as a breeder you
can see which pollen will be so there's
kind of grainy pollen I don't feel like
that pollens worth a [ __ ] it's the pre
pollen it's the pollen before your
plants actually start busting out that
real grainy dusty [ __ ] I don't think
that is good you want to let that if
you're gonna collect pollen let that
fall let that get away and then collect
that like it's about 14 days into the
pollen e pollination that's about 10 to
14 days into when they bust open that's
one of the really good pollen starts
coming out it's a little softer little
smoother to the touch
plants fully mature and in the flower at
that point yeah hormones are going and
over dirt he's doing it yeah so if
you're playing is producing trichomes
and a whole bunch of resin and has the
perfect structure you want to breed with
that I like to rub the stem and smell
the stem of my plants when my favorite
thing ah if it smells like puke it's a
good thing all those plant when you for
some reason to win it's got a hint of
bar trash can and vomit but that's a
good male to believe with it to me
that's it a lot of that when you smell
that stem and if he if the male you can
go across the board and say you have a
bunch
in a row from your phyno hunt that
you're doing put them all next to each
other sit down smell each one of them
side-by-side make sure you're cleaning
your hands each time fear really good
profile what each one's doing usually
the one that stinks the worst is the
best one you use yeah typically and then
you judge
narrow it down by smell and then narrow
down by structure sight use all your
senses don't don't eliminate anything
you know feel free to take a leaf and
snap one off and taste the stem a little
bit if it's sour and tart tea and stuff
a lot of the times and you're using
hardly no nutrients at all it's a good
thing it's telling you I got a lot of
terpenes I got a lot to add to the table
and they're definitely the bail is
definitely going to contribute to the
flavor I think the mama definitely over
overwhelms the flavor category but the
male is going to contribute to the
amount of flavor you don't just use any
old male you want to use the best one
you can at any and all costs you know so
if you know that that's just one of
those things that we look for I think
yeah see so if you best a ten pack of
seeds you probably find you know maybe
five males hopefully you know five
females five males you're gonna toss two
of those right away one of them's gonna
be funky one of them's gonna be a runt
so those go away now you got three I
think that I never use no I know I
personally know that I never used that
first plant to show me male flowers I
don't like to take that first one he's
too dominant I feel like he's going to
do too much to my breeding he's gonna
all the plants are gonna look like that
one if I've got three of them I kinda
would lean toward the third one to
flower if I've got five if I had five
males that worked well probably that
third or fourth one would be the one
that I would use I wouldn't go right for
that first one that busted out it's too
obvious me I always choose it honestly I
when I'm doing my breeding I always
choose it on it like like based on what
the mothers doing what I'm trying to do
if I'm trying to say like if I'm out
crossing like a blue dream or a sativa
or something close to it has a longer
flowering time and I want to come in
with an indica and actually shorten its
flowering time than then that's when I
would choose a male that it's bust out
first because I want to take that flower
and Tommy cut it really cut it down with
that dominant male yeah that's perfect
thing good but but if you say you have a
little indica dominant but you want to
make it a true hybrid and you want to
make it go a little bit long
in the garden say more if it's a 7/8
week and you want it to go more like 8 9
maybe 10 ish or something like that then
that's you know another reason you'd go
with a longer flowering male same same
same instance vice versa and don't be
afraid to have plants that flower for a
long time you guys I know 9 10 and 11
week sounds like scary flowering times
but I've flowered plants for 14 and 15
weeks and what happens is amazing once
they get that right that's far in the
Sour Diesel is a good example of that
going that long 1011 weeks on it but
it's well worth it in the end I mean
you're getting a connoisseur product
that you can't get anywhere else and the
test results will show you the rest for
and the harvest weights come through it
makes it well worth it
but I had an African landrace that
didn't have a name and it grew colás I
cut it down at week 14 and the coals
were bigger than my legs I think I think
it's the biggest complication with all
growers uh young to old is patience yeah
I think it's the hardest thing we all
have to overcome just in life that's it
in general that's it all right I got to
take a drink I'm about to choke and then
we're gonna keep this moving all right
I'll let it that part out I was gonna
beat Boxster oh man you should have out
have been friends I might not even edit
it now since you're beatbox and I might
just leave that part right there all
right what else you want to add to that
bro you got anything you want to add to
just talking about selecting a male that
we pretty much covered I mean use all
your senses you know and breathe for a
purpose that that's is the biggest thing
breed for purpose I cannot stress
nothing for purpose all because if it's
good and you want to bang it together
with something else that just looks good
just don't do it just because to do it
or don't do it because you got a cool
name lined up do it be do it for purpose
do it for purpose we see too much of
that in the industry every day that you
get you know create the strain come up
with the name lastly yes and if you do
make something and it sucks okay so
let's say you make a stream you take
whatever you've got this mail and then
you've got this prized female you throw
pollen all over it you let it go so once
you pollinate
it's gonna take you you know sit about
six more weeks until the seeds are ready
maybe six or eight more weeks before we
can chop that plant down I let the
plants dry until they're crispy at that
point I just chop them down let them get
super crispy and then I just rub them
and the seeds fall out then I go
all the seeds then I blast the material
into oil honestly but so then you got to
grow those seeds yourself I would
recommend you grow a hundred of them
just at least germinate a hundred of
them right away and see what they do
before you give any of them away to
anybody germinate a hundred of them veg
out at least fifty and flower at least
25 of them dry um Kyurem smoke em see
what they do if it sucks flush the seeds
down the toilet get rid of them feed
them to your birds it's human we all we
all make mistakes and you can only
control what you're doing so much it's
not its nature I would say nature you
can only control so much of what you're
doing the rest is left in her hands yeah
and sometimes things just don't want to
breed together I made a stream that
totally sucked it produced giant colas
that tasted amazing but it would not get
you high at all you could smoke the
entire crop and dues no high at all my
main thing was a breeding we had one
recently that came out was a Dante's
Inferno he was a big hit for a lot of
people because a lot of people through
our connoisseurs smokers out there
they're like like growing things like
Grinspoon and other other strains out
there that are just absolutely 100%
top-grade connoisseur weed they yield
like crap you know Girl Scout cookies I
mean it's not a known for is yield it's
known for its power and flavor
it hasn't every sweet funk taste well
that's it and you're not growing that as
a cash crop you know you know a lot of
the times you're growing that for
personal and if you do you are growing
it for cash crop you have a lot home in
a lot of lights what were we even
talking about to get a snails but anyway
I did have what something I wanted to
add to the RAL terpenes breeding for
Terps um want one of our perfect ones
it's coming up now it's gonna be one of
our big frontrunner is the s-1 version
of our blueberry fuel um this cut that
has amazing terpenes it's off the it's
just off hey it's hard to explain it's
really really hard to explain its it's
got a little bit everything in it and
the reason that is is because when
you're choosing males and females and
you're doing that breeding work you know
actually look at the terpene profile if
you don't know and you can get it tested
spend the 40 50 75 bucks whatever it
takes get it tested
paperwork to back your stuff up if
you're in a legal state you should be
able to test and the more widely it's
becoming nowadays you have literally
half the country now we're 50/50 and
it's taken over and you should be able
to get it tested by someone somehow
somewhere forums you know use your
connections to reach out and then get it
done you know
it makes a big difference I mean you can
find out like a terpene profile and then
try to match it up with something that
absolutely would complement those
terpenes but doesn't have them like our
very fuel you have blue dream which is a
good clone only a good breeding parent
breeds true it breeds solid it doesn't
isn't it's known the breach table I've
read a couple good strains with it you
know you can pop one hundred two hundred
seeds and you might get one or two harm
ease out of it just because it breeds
that stable and and it usually takes the
dominance of things but when you breed
it would was something like Oh Gees and
diesels and things like that you had a
whole different terpene profile that
really complements the blueberry muffin
II Hughes and the blend and the
creaminess of the Blue Dream it just
stands out and everybody creates a whole
nother animal and then you don't even
most people when you smoke it with them
first tell them what it is lastly they
did never even what a guest it came from
blue dream that's the thing they look at
it never would have thought and taste it
never would have thought and it just
peels them back it's got you know
diesels it's got oh gee tones it's got
blueberry tones it's got creamy tones in
it and just that's all I could say I
think I've smoked some of that with you
before I think you brought that last
time and it was definitely a tasty
strain if that was what you brought for
me to smoke so I've noticed everything I
breathed to the Blue Dream I've never
used it as a mail obviously because it's
a clone only and it's a girl but
everything I've read to it it has made
huge colas everything you put to it
that's it that's a - that's why I love
work that's why we did the og cross on
it typically was dudx to gain a little
bit extra you wanna yeah because oh jeez
our lanky and stuff I was trying to put
more i bred grateful dog to the Blue
Dream and I call it the Blue Heeler and
my point was to put more vigor to the
Grateful dog just make it a little bit
bigger a little chunkier but I'm not a
fan of the flavor of Blue Dream that
it's a girl it's a girl wheat it's a
stripper weed it is it's real it's kind
of like a bland blueberry it's real
muffiny and real creamy it's like it
tastes like Jiffy muffins
okay like in the oven when you get the
jib alright put the blueberry man and it
kind of has that aroma blueberry muffin
e blueberry air freshener
instead of candies there like that
blueberry marker yeah oh man I miss that
smell the markers in class you just gave
me a weird flashback but yeah yeah and
I'm not a fan of that so I put that to
the Grateful dog
and it made it more pungent and more
more piney and then it brought out a
bottom layer of fruit i bred it to the
king Kim Cross the grape stopper OG and
we call it the wall it's the blue
stopper but uh that one made it much
stinkier and that the kink in grapes na
/ OG made little tiny popcorns and now
it makes Spears since we put it to the
blue dress yeah tell people all the time
you know I've know you've had it I know
it's been around for a long time held 15
years now but don't count it out as a
breeding mother with hybrids you know
don't see blue dream on the label and
automatically turn it away because
you're probably passing up a really
really good cross I know a lot of people
that do not like blue dream at all
shadows are those guys they know who
they are not gonna see your names on the
show hold up boys I don't know a lot of
the nightmare lines people fell in love
with and things like that the reason why
they called it nightmare where do you
think nightmare dream I mean put two and
two together people didn't even know no
yeah mini Tom like no there's no blue
dream in there alright so something
important I should mention this is uh
this is kind of a breeding by eye
technique here you could make Eliel
charts you could take a whole bunch of
notes you should take a whole bunch a
whole bunch of notes either way but this
is kind of just a breeding breeding with
love grow from your heart sort of do it
by your eye old school sort of thing
we're breeding with a lot of experience
here so I think if you find a good male
you're gonna want to do a Fino hunt of
at least twenty seeds you're gonna want
to find one with a good structure you
want it to look you want it to have this
shape that you want the babies to have
find one that makes a resin if you can
find one that makes a whole bunch of
pollen if it doesn't make enough pollen
you're not gonna make enough seeds
find one with real close node spacing
find one that smells real good
try not to select the very first one
that goes into flower and shows you that
it's a boy definitely do not use any
male plants that show any sign of her
effort ISM male plants can hermaphrodite
also you'll see pollen sacks you'll see
little mail sacks popping out and then
right out of the sides you'll see female
pistols come out yeah it's not those
aren't nut hairs
that's a hermaphrodite plant you got to
cut [ __ ] Bruce Jenner down and get
rid of it yeah I just said that I am
afraid you're out of there we ain't
trying to have no none of that [ __ ] in
the grow room you got to get rid of it
that will create lots of problems in the
future you do not want to breed
hermaphrodite into your plants that's
right that is not a good that's the
exact opposite of what we're aiming for
so um yeah and then pay attention that
pollen you guys and when the pollen does
start spitting you don't want that first
grainy sandy pollen you want that the
pollen will when you catch some of it
and put it in your hand and rub it in
the palm of your hand it'll feel smooth
and silky it'll feel real nice and then
when you leave the grow room even have
to hose yourself down get a mister like
a sprayer and spray it like a pump
sprayer like you'd almost used to pump
pesticides get one of those and just
spray yourself down and wash your hands
because time or work truly great as
chlorine and safe for everything plants
animals beef there you go that'll
deactivate any palm that you've got on
you and then if you are going from that
pollen room and do a room that has
female plants you can always hose them
down as you walk in just hit them with
the sprayer and they won't receive
pollen for a little while just trying to
prevent that pollen from getting onto
your females if you don't want to breed
because if you have a male plant in the
house or in the room or in the facility
with your females it's going to try to
get pollen everywhere one thing I've
noticed where you could tell me if
you've recognized this I've got separate
breeding rooms I've got an upstairs in
the downstairs area and an area over
here an area over here that I've got a
male in one area and females in a
totally different area I've noticed when
I've got girls and a flowering male in
the same house the girls get a little
stickier and they flower a little more
quickly do you think those girls know
there's a male around somewhere good
question that is a good question it goes
into some of my forté lighting and it
actually yeah they do
they know because of infrared lighting
okay plants use infrared lighting to see
around them that's why you have natural
spacing in the woods
that is why trees naturally spaced
themselves out naturally weed out
smaller ones below them and around them
and you typically go into the woods and
new pine tree forts and things like that
and they have an equal spacing between
yeah they do
that is why ok infrared lighting my
horny horny girl plants no there's no
blowing as load they know she's I don't
want somebody I think there's pheromones
I believe as well okay I would believe
that because well they can take in co2
and they can they breathe out carbon
dioxide you know there's always a
constant intake between oxygen and
carbon dioxide battling back and forth
back and forth right and in a lot of
their annual plants so they built over
thousands and millions of years beyond
Earth they have built defense mechanisms
to try to breed that is their purpose
that's why they're hermaphrodite
honestly Fenny buddy remembers the first
Jurassic Park allegation say nature will
always find a way and then y'all said
you have eggs that is why because nature
will always find a way and you're
talking about something that is on a
total different level than what you
think it's mind-boggling to think how
you know an evolution sense how far
ahead some plants are then then what we
are you know we tend to think we are the
kings of the world you know weird sin of
the universe every day its weak but
really if you look at an ant if he was
our size you could lift your house right
yeah they can lift like five hundred
times under natural weight and it's
riding a smile at you with one oral in
your house because that's really what it
is you know it's really more about
perception than anything you just [ __ ]
with all the listeners heads mothers
visualizing ant lifting up my house and
running away with it while we're
recording in reality when you put it
that way I mean is how you perceive
things it's just pretty much pretty wild
man yeah the whole plants mission is to
survive alright
so man you got anything else so you want
to add to this podcast it sounds like
we've covered selecting a male I hope
that made a lot of sense to you I mean I
just want everybody show up and show
Denver that we can do this better than
they can I really do I think I think the
people of Pablo are gonna show them that
we've held the put we've we've held the
state fair here for how long and
somebody we know actually made a good
point on social media that uh it's 11
days long 25,000 people a day yeah if
anybody can do a Polk County
right we can host that many folks we got
enough hotels eating places that's it
you guys I actually plan to put together
a podcast I posted it up to social media
asking my local friends for a little bit
of help I'm gonna put a podcast together
and be a little bit of a tour guide for
you I'm gonna find places for you to
stay places for you to eat things for
you to do gives you a little bit of
information about our town so that when
you come here you're prepared and then
we can all have a good time and take a
bunch of dabs and be friends and you'll
have a good time with us it's gonna be
such a blast I'm proud of landed in this
spot a lot of people talk a lot of trash
but look what's about to happen here the
biggest cannabis event on the planet is
going to be here in our backyard
I know it's gonna be a blast cos I have
fun everywhere I go gonna be yeah it's
gonna be there and I'm gonna be there
and Jessi and Spencer it's gonna be what
else do we need bro you're gonna have a
good ass time Spencer competing this
year I can't speak for Spencer okay
shout out garden weed man boy what's up
buddy I hope you're listening to this
shut up to Maddie the whole garden of
Weeden crew and Spence and the doggies
foot ups a rock boy what's up Nana I
hope everybody's doing well over there
we just gave Chad outs two dogs on the
podcast that's pretty red all right make
sure you guys follow my buddy sour seeds
on social media how can people find you
bro
find us on Twitter you can find us on
Instagram or Facebook we have our own
website wwm I'll hide NGO which we'll be
changing over to us our seed company
calm lowland calm we're gonna go eat
commerce you can get our happens and get
custom links right tor right towards
right to our sites that sell our seeds
bro thanks for the hat pins you brought
me a nice little selection a hat pins I
really like the the dab scraper that's
pretty nice I appreciate that I'm the
heart man I enjoy doing it it just keeps
everything fresh man are your products
available on the dank team.com at this
time not yet not yet well we got to get
you in touch with our buddies over there
yeah Yankee needs to talk to you but
make sure you guys check out the dank
team comm let them know that we sent you
there's a little bit of ira genetic
stuff available go check that out
there's some black cherry chem available
up there just damn good by the way
well thank you thank you he grew some
over a green and healthy wellness it'll
be on the shelves by the time this
podcast comes out very likely be gone
made some of the best concentrates I've
had in Colorado dude honestly I mean I'd
say top five that updated thank you just
the flavors off you can taste the cherry
taste the Kim I really liked it that
black cherry comes through my two
favorites beating in a tooth - favorite
that's why [ __ ] happens see that's how
breathing happens you see - strength and
a breather that's bread as many times as
we have you can see what its gonna do
you're like oh if I put that to that
it's like becoming a chef it's like chef
almost a lot of it yeah it's an art it's
an art there's some artistry involved in
it and we're not don't don't ever let us
think that we're taking that away it's
not just pure science there's art to all
of it extractions growing breeding
especially absolutely it takes it takes
a good eye and a little bit hard you
gonna listen to the plants you got to
lay down next to them and listen to them
you gotta feel the vibe from the plants
help you out Oh bro thank you for coming
out thank you for asking rolling joints
and smoking down yeah hit that sucker
again you look to me like you want to
hit this yeah I do I'm gonna hit a joint
guys you guys fill your head with
thoughts while I fill my head with smoke
there you go people think I don't smoke
a lot of flour but I've been smoking a
lot of flour lately yeah yeah it was me
I'm guilty of that that's how it is
we're not the once you get to to that
level you just hold on to a joint for a
few minutes and smoke it these are mine
I'll smoke it for a few oh yeah well
congrats on not smoking cigarettes or 21
years clean sober do it guys
right now almost two months almost two
months we mentioned that you had a
problem one night on the show and we
didn't talk too much about it I just
said that you're planning on coming but
you had a little issue yes yeah I'll be
honest from smoking cigarettes he smoked
too much he collapse along what happened
damn son well I'm wait glad you're
repaired and back in it I'm getting
there run some laps
I could good good good
all right well thanks for spending some
time with me you guys we're gonna wrap
up this part of the show we're gonna
take a bunch of dabs I'm gonna get a
fresh drink and then I will be back to
wrap up this show
all right you guys that was a lesson and
how to select male plants for breeding I
hope you learned something I want to
send another huge thank you shout out to
Rob thanks again for joining me big
shout out to everybody and thus our
seeds crew I'll be back in a week with
another episode I'm putting together an
episode on how to get your Emmy D badge
so that you can work here in the
Colorado marijuana industry legally I'm
also putting together a tour guide
episode the cannabis cup is coming to my
hometown of Pueblo Colorado so I'm going
to make an episode about places for you
to stay places for you to eat places for
you to avoid and maybe some fun things
to do before during and after the
cannabis cup while you're here so look
forward to those episodes I hope you
check those out don't forget to check
out our sponsor hit man glass visit hit
man glass comm also follow Duggan
Instagram it's at hit man glass Dougie
on Instagram if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I'll get you all of the information that
you do need you guys know that the show
is over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the Grove from
your heart a podcast find the review
section I would appreciate it if you
give me a five star rating
be honest click what you think after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comment on a future episode I would
love it if you would follow me on social
media you can find me on Twitter it's at
G fyh podcast on Facebook it's just grow
from your heart podcast and if you want
to follow me on instagram it's i reaiiy
rie underscore genetics I read genetics
on Instagram I would appreciate it if
you give me a follow check that out
click like all that good stuff you guys
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher and I read genetics
Colorado dot-com make sure you check out
all the old episodes if you're a new
listen or go back and learn a whole
bunch of great stuff if there's a grill
essen that you would like me to cover
something you have questions about
simply email me grow for me at heart at
hotmail.com I will work it into a future
episode you guys that's all I've got for
you this week I want to give a huge
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
Oh
[Applause]
[Music]