welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 122 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friend is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff phone to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shots
of cat cute in the entire misty breeze
crew you guys sitting across the table
from me is our good buddy white Mike
thank you for joining us bro what's up
everybody happy to be here well thanks
for coming man thanks for taking some
time away from the rig away from the job
and especially away from the new baby
thanks for coming and hanging out happy
to man better heard the kid ate potatoes
today you did first potatoes shout out
to the baby and the potatoes mashed
potatoes big shout out to the wife for
taking some time and letting you come
hang out a little bit I don't see your
name on the on the show here but thanks
to Mike's wife Lily I might complain let
me borrow a little while it's really
cool I appreciate it all right we'll go
talking about babies and we'll get on
with the podcast you guys thanks for
jumping in thanks for joining the
podcast ah let's see where we want to
start I want to give a big shout out to
my friend John Anthony Moses I know
you're hanging out listening to the
podcast thanks for listening but I
appreciate it all so let's get into the
big topic that's been going on here in
Pueblo Colorado the cannabis cup was
supposed to be in Denver on 4/20
supposed to supposed to but
unfortunately the city of Denver
declined all the permits I'm not sure
exactly
Denver officials declined all the
permits they were County I believe well
either way they said nope not gonna do
it nope they had some issues namely
out-of-state dispensaries handing out
samples and what was supposed to be
14,000
actually being 35,000 people a day
alright well anyway they said no I would
follow this one close High Times came
down to Pueblo Colorado where Mike and I
reside yes
they claimed we they were going to do
the festival on the 18th 19th 20th 21st
within that range those original goal
they put up flyers they put out some
announcements on their website they put
out some stuff on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook and then suddenly they
retracted all their statements and said
oh [ __ ] the next weekend so the permits
have been entered they've been submitted
they're being reviewed so far the city
of Pueblo has not said if they are going
to allow or decline the cannabis cup to
happen in Pueblo Colorado this episode
will come out in two or three days and
I'm pretty sure the decision will not be
made at that time so right now there is
no definite location for the High Times
Cannabis Cup in Colorado and it if it
does happen it will be moved to the
weekend of the 22nd and the 23rd if it
does happen in Pueblo Colorado at all
yeah I read something today claiming
that this move was it was sort of an
option B if Adams County didn't go
through and they've been looking for
bigger locations than the Denver Mart
and the location down here in public
claims to be able to handle the 25 or 30
thousand people a day no problem so I'm
not too familiar with the location I
thought Denver Mart was great but of
course when I heard that it was going to
be in Pueblo I was excited that's so
awesome that shaves a lot a huge chunk
of money out of going to the cup first I
really just want to go to the cup yeah
you got to go up you gotta get a hotel
room you don't want to be driving back
home to Pueblo after the cup
and it's a multiple day event I have to
go to every day just because that's how
I write if you're trying to go to all
three days or have to do it all three
days you got to be up there for you know
paying top dollar for hotel rooms right
now and Denver sucks
and every all of the shitty hotels go
expensive if you think you're gonna pay
70 or 80 for a hotel those 70 and 80
dollar hotels are now 130 on cannabis
cup weekend yep Denver knows that 420 is
a big weekend in Denver and they cash
the [ __ ] unfortunately a bunch of people
have already booked plane tickets they
have booked the rooms
yeah the big complaint about the Cup in
Denver was always that the planning was
sort of like a d-minus like the roof
didn't fall in like nobody got squashed
but other than that it was kind of a
[ __ ] well when they changed their
mind that they weren't going to do it in
Denver and they decided to move it to
Pueblo a lot of people were like yeah
[ __ ] Pueblo fumbles got an interesting
reputation out there yeah we sure do we
sure do but then when they push the date
to a completely different weekend I'm
sure that a large portion of the people
that we're going to attend just decided
[ __ ] it they weren't even gonna try if
the cup goes off in Pueblo because it's
not at all a sure thing at this point
folks it's the decision comes down to
the County Planning Department and then
if they decide yes it can be appealed by
any number of people and our local
sheriff has told the press that if it's
approved he's going to appeal um because
he doesn't he doesn't have any idea how
he's gonna handle 35,000 cannabis cup
attendees not because of the number of
attendees but because they're attending
the cannabis cup something about the
event makes it special how we're going
to be we're going to be too high to
drive what I saw in a statement they're
really scared of DAV's
yeah to the average to normal person
who's never seen cannabis and sees me
pull out a torch and heat up a nail and
do this crack like looking drug I can
understand the fear but he's a police
officer he's a sheriff he needs to
figure out what's going on with the
medical marijuana community and be in
touch with us and come join us instead
of be afraid of us and try to persecute
us and prosecute us right spend ten
minutes talking to any member of the
community and Lula seems to be scary
truth I may look intimidating I may say
a lot of big crazy weird words but when
it comes down to it I'm a peaceful
chilled out dude and I'd love to sit
down and have a conversation with
anybody who needs to be educated
properly about cannabis that's what the
show is all about cannabis edumacation
that's what today is
there was there was a lot of hilarity I
think in this story if you look at some
of the reasons stated and quoted that
the permits wound up in Denver were
denied the two big reasons that are
cited over and over and over again in
the press are a a woman jumped out of
her car
like somewhere in or around the cannabis
cup or she had just attended her was on
her way it doesn't really specify but
like clearly marijuana use doesn't cause
jumping out of cars now I've smoked
people if you know me like Colorado sold
almost a billion dollars will be last
year if it caused jumping out of cars we
would know how many people have I would
have a good band saying I smoke more
cannabis than ninety percent of the
people on the plane right like that's
not an effect we wouldn't see four years
down the road I made you jump out of
cars I would have done backflips out of
buses by now
right and there were thirty five
thousand people a day at the cup and one
woman jumped out of a car like that
exactly like event-related they forgot
to mention in the article that she took
a DAB and then she went and did a whole
bunch of Molly and then she drank
whiskey and then a chick jumping out of
a car one of the time and she was stoned
sober and finally boyfriend so like
there's a lot friend nope I was not I
was friends with the boyfriend and they
should have de long story I'm not [ __ ]
tonin now let's not go there but yeah
like that wasn't drug or alcohol-related
that was I can't be in this car another
minute [ __ ] craziness longer so you
do come to Colorado and you come to
pleasure if we do have the cannabis cup
here please behave yourself represent
yourself as a positive cannabis user and
a responsible cannabis user be careful
they're going to be looking for people
driving too high let's talk about this a
little bit I don't know the exact rule
here but they treat cannabis like
alcohol if you're going to be leaving
the cannabis cup have your cannabis in a
sealed container if you can put it in
the trunk of your car put your rig your
dabber your carb cap your torch and
especially your product any product
you've got that smokeable edible
drinkable if it's cannabis infused
related if you can rub it on your balls
put it in the trunk of the car if you
don't have a trunk if you've got an SUV
put it in the backpack zip the backpack
up put it way in the back of the vehicle
have it out of reach of the driver don't
get yourself a DUI or an illegal
possession of cannabis ticket because
that is still a possible thing here in
Colorado it
um this cannabis cup if it goes off in
Pueblo is gonna be under a lot of
scrutiny and honestly pueblos could use
the cup down here and I'd really like to
see the event do well if it gets
approved at all I would love to see it
one of the big complaints in Adams
County was out-of-state dispensaries
coming here and selling weed and dabs at
their booths some of them were doing
donation legal mumbo jumbo other people
were straight doing sales Attili um at
least according to recent reports and
yeah that's a big no-no here which is
why none of our local dispensaries were
even handing out product at the cup I
get that the cup is supposed to be the
community gathering and celebrating and
having a huge smoke out but how you hand
out samples or what people bring to
smoke like there's a lot of rules around
that you need to know the law and please
try to comply with it like as much as
practice' Bellaire phille please please
don't [ __ ] it up for us we've worked
really hard here to do this we've got a
good thing going come have a good time
I'm not trying to be a dick about it
come when you're at the event take dabs
share your dad's with your friends give
me a fat dad take a fat dab with me
high-five me let's take some selfies
let's get on Instagram together let's
snapchat it the [ __ ] up but be careful
when you're driving away from there keep
your cannabis safe keep your eyes not
red be able to walk the line be able to
pass the tests remember we did the
episode a little while back about
interacting with law enforcement be
prepared for that [ __ ] if you're a
nervous person don't be extra high and
nervous when you're leaving the cut for
an extra hour you know understand if you
take a couple dad's hang out for an hour
when I went back and listened to that
episode the one thing I realized I meant
to emphasize and didn't was the easiest
way to not get in trouble with law
enforcement and to be calm and cool
during those interactions is to not be
breaking the law you know that's
something my buddy Lewis shoutout Magoo
he goes you know what you forgot to
[ __ ] mention was don't have [ __ ]
expired plates don't have your tags
expired don't have a broken headlight
don't write a can taillight don't be an
[ __ ] to have a cracked windshield
he said break one rule at a time his
advice not to Magoo fur I grew up in a
lawyer samuil if you haven't figured out
that figured that out yet by now I don't
know if you've been listening but that's
an old lawyer joke is like if you've got
to break the law break1 lot
and it's [ __ ] true like if you've got
weed in the car and you ain't allowed to
have weed make sure that that's the only
rule you're breaking if you're speeding
you're asking to get caught if you're
you've got a [ __ ] up car you're asking
to get car Ruth in a lot of states if
you look like Jeff you're asking hey hey
and what bite what some listeners don't
know some of the listeners this gets to
me occasionally some listeners don't
know this when people meet me or they
hear my voice somewhere they turn around
and like is that you cuz I go to the
grouse tour sometimes and people like
dude that's [ __ ] you uh you guys I am
six foot five and I've got dreadlocks
almost to my knees I am not even joking
my dreadlocks go
damn near to my knees now I can close
him in the car door I used to roll him
up in the car window but now they're so
long that that [ __ ] isn't even thought
about yeah they're long tell testify for
me Mike he's [ __ ] ridiculous
with a gentle weave they could be like a
legit hammock or blanket this one here
is bigger around than my torch
I've watched steals things from other
people's hands without oh my dreads will
clean off a table do they work like a
bullwhip from time to time you get two
layers if I need space at a concert I
just shake the dreadlocks around a
little bit and then no one wants my
dreadlocks in their face and or their
beer so they just back the [ __ ] up
dancing room in Colorado it's not that
unusual to see some dreadlocks it's
really unusual to see locs this long
alright but yeah in other states you're
a walking advertisement for a dude
that's high yeah oh you should see me
try to go through the the TSA going
through the airport right they inspect
my dreadlocks they [ __ ] want to
squeeze them and see what's in there
honey yeah so uh you guys if you're
coming to the cannabis cup be careful
walk out at the cup have a good time I
will be there look for me I'm gonna do a
shameless shout out here since the
cannabis cup in Denver will not be on
the week of on the day of 4/20
everyone's looking for something to do
on 4/20 in Denver I want to give a huge
shout out to an event called the secret
sash the secret Center will be happening
at the Gatsby Gardens in Denver Colorado
on 4/20 and I do invite you to join us
for more information you're gonna have
to follow the secret Seche colorado on
instagram search them out we will get a
website going there's more happening or
homie Adam ill will be coming out to
deejay or not to deejay to host the show
I apologize I'm not sure if I can
announce who the deejay will be I'm
excited
know who the DJ is I think I think we've
got him lined up but I don't want to say
the name of the DJ on the show here and
get everybody pumped up cuz it's a good
DJ you guys will recognize his name when
I say it if you're a fan of the podcast
you might know who I'm talking about and
it is not nicotine so I'm just gonna
cross that one off a lot of people might
think I make a tea coming to DJ an event
but we do not so big shut it for the
Grammy gets me big shout out to the
secret sesh we want to get the secret
stash packed up we want you there come
check it out all right so we do have a
topic for this episode it's not just
gonna be - hi guys taking dabs and
rambling we got the topic our friend
she calls herself that one mountain girl
sent me a message on Instagram and she
said hey you guys should do a message
about how to get your badge in Colorado
so big shot it said that one mountain
girl for listening to the podcast also
big shout-out for following me on IG
meant today and today it happened to a
lot of people but I noticed several
Instagram accounts got wiped the [ __ ]
out the green and healthy wellness
Instagram account for the shop buh-bye
the Terp X account for their hash
buh-bye I'm afraid to open mine right
now and look if it's even there because
I mean that's my crew you know what I
mean I grow the herb for green and
healthy and then it's blasted by Terp X
and we're all all tagged in the same
posts so I feel like my times coming on
Instagram you guys if it disappears I'll
just create our Rasta Jeff Instagram it
won't even be I read genetics any more
than be Rasta Jeff this time it'll be
the second incident that a second I read
genetics Instagram get blasted down so
I'll just make a Rasta Jeff if it
disappears all that you know grammars
good on yeah yeah yeah I love Instagram
it's fun I like to post pictures of
what's going on and interact with my
friends my family out there so big shout
outs to that one mountain girl also also
shout-out to my friend Jessica she kind
of encouraged me to write this episode
she is a manager at a very prominent
dispensary in the Colorado Springs area
big shout out to her and her staff and
her dispensary I'm gonna say the name of
the dispensary I'm sorry I just got a
mini shout out you got a shout out jest
big love big hugs but jess was like you
should do an episode beautiful we had a
friend doing this going through the same
thing and I was I thought about we
should do a show for that right yeah
well Jessica deals with people at the
dispensary every day and one person is
how do ya and Mike works at dispensary
too and Mike and just both have one
person a day say how do I get
so now all they have to do is refer that
person to this episode welcome new
listener if you learned about the
podcast by somebody saying hey listen to
that you'll learn how to get your badge
welcome thanks for joining us I'm Rasta
Jeff cross the tables my buddy white
Mike what up we're gonna teach you how
to get your badge I took a bunch of
notes um so I'm gonna open the notes I'm
gonna find him here we go
since how to get your badge in Colorado
and this is how to get a Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division badge so
that you're able to work in a legal
recreational and/or medical marijuana
facility this could be a dispensary
where you're either rolling joints all
day where you're a budtender if you're
going to be there's a million different
types of jobs sensories but be prepared
to start at the bottom of the ladder
kind of regardless yeah yeah look at my
sarcoma two million bucks but anything
you're gonna do in there you need a
badge from the owner to the budtender to
the joint roller just to the dude who
paints the walls yeah to the lawyer yep
a badge
the guys that come in and build the
place have to get either real badges or
visitor badges so all the people that
work for the dispensary the grows the
processing facilities where extracts are
made the facilities where edibles and
drinkables are made the places where
topicals are made even the testing
facilities where the cannabis is tested
for cannabinoids they all are required
to have a Colorado marijuana enforcement
agent badge which requires a thorough
FBI background check fingerprints and an
intensive intensive application process
if you don't meet the requirements
you're not gonna get a badge we'll get
to that we'll get to that so let's talk
about the steps on how to get this badge
because if you want to work in a
dispensary this is the first thing that
you need to do and this is really really
important if you're thinking about
moving here to work in legal weed know
this before you move yes there's one
step in here that you'll need to know
and we'll get to it I'm excited to get
to it's one I did a lot of a lot of
research that's one of my favorite parts
to get to because there's a buttload of
people who moved here that didn't know
how to do none of this and don't meet
the requirements and so they're [ __ ]
yeah or they're stuck trying to get a
job doing whatever it is it was they
were doing that they hated so much they
moved across the country to learn work
in legal weed or they're trying to set
up a black market grow to survive
right and they're struggling alright so
the first thing you got to do if you
want to get a badge here in the state of
Colorado you've got to find the
application online and they will put the
application in the shownotes I'll put a
link to the application let me read you
the website address if you've got a pin
in paper or if you want to type this
into your web browser quickly it is
Colorado dot gov slash Pacific the word
Pacific yes Colorado gov slash Pacific
slash enforcement slash medical -
marijuana - occupational - licensing so
it's Colorado gov slash Pacific slash
enforcement slash medical - marijuana -
occupational licensing yeah yeah well
hopefully somebody type that into their
web browser
hopefully somebody got that wrote it
down I'll put it in the show notes but
that's where you need to go to get the
application that's where you start it's
not super hard to find if you just
google it by name right there are a lot
of things to filter through though it's
confusing and what you're looking for
yeah it does take a minute of reading
and kind of clicking around to find the
actual application that you need cuz
they've got like four of them posts
right and you're looking for either a
key badge or a support badge and we'll
talk about that in just a couple of
seconds I think I made a note to talk
about that so find the application read
and review the application you'll get to
a part that says this marijuana
occupational employee application form
is an official document if you provide
false information on your marijuana
license application and/or do not
disclose all information the application
asks your license is subject to denial
or revocation and you may be subject to
criminal prosecution the marijuana
Enforcement Division will conduct a
complete background investigation and
we'll check all sources of information
you are advised that it is better to
disclose all information than face
denial revocation or criminal
prosecution so guys that are not
bullshitting when they say that I know a
guy named Tim who has been waiting
months and months for his badge because
they are doing a thorough investigation
they found some stuff on his record they
are contacting the state where that
happened there talking to the actual
judge that resided over my friends case
to find out if he can get his badge or
not and it's been a long time he writes
them letters all the time and they reply
with we're still investigating so we'll
get back to you
so they're not bullshitting they were
gonna go through this
they're not kidding disclose your [ __ ]
so it says if you need clarification of
any of the following questions please
contact any marijuana Enforcement
Division office so it means if it's not
clear to you call them because they're
happy to tell you exactly what's up and
when we get into the requirements in a
minute like we'll get more specific but
like really just tell the truth
there's no fudging this yep no the
requirements if you don't meet them
straight up don't try cuz you ain't
gonna get passed and if you do it's a
special crime this is the age of the
Internet if you did some [ __ ] like just
write it down they really don't care as
long as it violates the couple of
requirements and they play those
straight up and down for the most part I
might hurt one person who didn't get
their badge and they tried to make it
sound like a big conspiracy that was
like nah dude it was that felony three
years ago oh yeah well trivia the
disqualifying conditions it says these
questions go like this have you ever
discharged a sentence for a conviction
of a felony pursuant to any state or
federal law regarding the possession
distribution manufacturing cultivation
or use of a controlled substance
including probation or parole within the
last ten years even if the conviction
occurred more than ten years ago
so that means have you been in jail for
any felon it is that what that means
discharge the sentence that's no drug
felonies in ten years is what that
questions asking about like you have to
have completed the jail sentence and any
probation or parole at least ten years
before you apply for your MIT badge so
ten years ago you guys if you have it's
a drug felony ten years drosphila
let's be specific it says drug felony
yes oh yeah you had to have drugs
involved in your felony and it has to be
more than ten years ago if that happened
if it was nine years and 365 days
because it's [ __ ] leap year then
you're still not able to qualify you
gotta wait another day and then apply
yeah so condition number two have you
served a sentence including probation
parole within the last five years upon
conviction for any felony even if the
conviction occurred more than five years
ago so once again if you're on probation
or parole five years ago or within the
last five years you are not allowed to
work in the industry so no drug felonies
and ten no felony
period in five or probation or parole
yep in the probation of parole for many
of those felonies has to be got done at
least that many years ago and then this
one is neat are you a licensed physician
making patient recommendations yep if
you're a doctor in the industry you
can't be affiliated with a dispensary
you're involved with that part of it so
you don't need a badge that makes good
sense I understand like that that rule
kind of makes sense and I really get
where they're going with the felony rule
they're really trying to play it so that
the state can say with all reassurance
that people who were dealing drugs in
the past aren't owning dispensaries and
an easy way to do that is to make sure
that anyone convicted to selling drugs
doesn't get to be a dispensary owner for
at least the first decade and yeah that
kind of sucks for people who got busted
back in the day and they're not trying
to be totally straight-up legal but
that's how Colorado wants to play in
this position part they just don't want
you to be a doctor hanging out is
they've quash that elongation yeah yeah
all right number four says have you had
your authority to act as primary
caregiver revoked by the state health
agency so if you're you were somebody's
primary caregiver as not under the
Medical Marijuana type of caregiver but
as their caregiver for somebody who is
elderly or disabled if that's been
revoked you are not allowed to work in
the cannabis industry the next question
is are you under 21 years of age you
have to be 21 years old when you apply
it gotta be 21 that's not too hard to
figure out 21 the next question says are
are not question but let me take a sip
here hold on talk Mike I don't know what
the next question is but I can guess
student loans and child support not yet
no those are further down the list sorry
for the teaser no that will come up in a
little bit though that's not on this
list thanks for the time to take a drink
excuse me are you the spouse or child
living in the household of any person
employed by the Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division so if you're
working for both sides yeah yeah your
mom you can't be a regulator and a
profiteer your mom works at the MEP you
can't have a badge sorry
yep tell mom that she's got like this on
you or something that's to switch sides
on the right to join the force there's
special rules to prevent that from
happening for a chunky years when you
join the meed now because a bunch of
people we're going to work for the meed
going through training doing a bunch of
em ID inspections for like three or four
months and then getting a job at a
dispensary for like ten times the pay to
be a compliance officer because they
could put on their resume a mediator oh
wow that's it was happening so much the
meed had to pass special like
non-compete clause rules that they have
to sign contracts when they put their
job at the APD now that's pretty good I
like it and then the next one on the
last one
are you a Sheriff Deputy Sheriff police
officer or prosecuting officer or any
officer or employee of the marijuana
state licensing authority or a local
licensing authority if then the next the
next little cups don't get no badges the
next little note here says stop if you
answered yes to any of you of the above
questions by Colorado law you cannot
obtain or hold a Colorado marijuana
occupational employee license those are
just straight up you can't get a license
period don't try we'll find it with the
FBI background check yep so if you heard
if you qualify under any of that [ __ ]
that we just read you cannot work in
Colorado in the legal marijuana industry
you're gonna have to go to California or
Washington or Oregon or maybe Michigan
or who else is legal now Mike where can
people go um other legal states Alaska
Washington Oregon DC sort of go if there
was Charlotte Alaska there's 23 medical
marijuana States get online look at the
laws in each one see which ones you can
still work or or or or what you should
really do where ever change the laws
better make it legalize cannabis where
you are if you can't work in the legal
industry that doesn't mean you can't
lobby on its behalf that's the truth
shout out to Daryl if you listen to the
podcast I'm just going to throw that out
there uh yeah you can you can do what
you can do for your area maybe you can't
be a grower maybe you can't be a manager
you can't be an owner but you can always
be a lobbyist you can be an
the best you can do your part in some
way shape or form that is for sure
so after it asks you all these questions
and when you check no to them or yes to
them it makes you sign and it says I
have thoroughly read and understand the
questions above and understand that I
cannot hold a Colorado marijuana license
if at any time in the future I can ever
answer yes let answer if at any time in
the future I can ever answer yes to any
other questions above that's weirdly
worded it's weird but it's it's crazy
legal talk for if the answer to this
change is like if you committed a felony
nine years ago in two years past
oh god that felony conviction and all
your [ __ ] with it was over ten years ago
like you're good to go now alright you
can reapply or apply period so then
there is also an arrest disclosure forum
form if he says if since turning age
eighteen have you ever been arrested
served criminal summons charged with or
convicted of any crime regarding the
possession distribution or use of a
controlled substance
you must disclose this information to
the marijuana Enforcement Division make
sure you get them all on there too cuz
oops I forgot that one looks really
[ __ ] bad they give you plenty of
space to list
yep holy crap check any of the following
or professional licenses you have held
so it asks which licenses you've had it
asks if you've had a liquor license or a
lawyer license or a racing license a
lottery license so it's gonna ask you a
lot of crazy questions fill all of this
out truthfully okay so read the
disqualifying conditions if you qualify
then print out the application don't
[ __ ] print it it's like ten pages of
paper let's see there's several pages
here yeah read through it page the
qualifications the ones we read you
verbatim are the the automatic
disqualification ones if you start
checking yes to some of the ones we're
talking about now that doesn't
automatically mean a no it means you got
some explaining to do those those okay
yeah the first ones were knows yeah the
first ones are automatic knows if it's a
felony in ten years or a felony in five
years a drug-related felony in ten if
you're a cop or I don't remember what
the last one was copper doctor those all
disqualify you those all dqu
automatically but the only two of those
that apply to most of the people listen
to the show
sooo alright alright she don't think any
cops listen to the show well maybe I
really hope there are law enforcement
officers listening to the show and
because the more I think about it
there's probably a couple you know I
remember listeners there was an event
that we did for the show we did a live
show somewhere the place doesn't exist
anymore but we did a live show somewhere
and we invited people to come and I made
flyers for the show
right and I put out flyers for the
podcast to come listen to wall people it
was a smoking place I remember because I
used to sit in a room with a number of
members of law enforcement every Monday
night okay and so like when this
happened that I was keenly aware of how
many officers were in that room every
Monday night I put out flyers to listen
to the podcast at a smoking event and
somehow law enforcement found the Flyers
and thought that they were like some
sort of tickets to get free weed at the
event or something and so in the next
episode I gave a shout out to the cops
open that they were listening because
they had the Flyers and it said how to
listen I had a little QR code if you
scanned it would take you to iTunes and
you could hear this show so if you're in
law enforcement I appreciate you for
listening I hope you're learning the
truth about cannabis it's not evil it's
not terrible it doesn't ruin anybody
we're not that scary we do understand
that there are laws that you have to
enforce but we wish that you would do
what you can to change the laws because
I'm sure you see that it's not a problem
where you are officer much respect for a
thanks for doing what you do
alright so print the application that's
the next step here we're gonna keep this
show on track Mike's got a DD today
print the application complete the
application that shouldn't be too hard
so at that point obtain any court papers
that you need any arrest disclosure
forms anything like that if you've got
tax paper forms that you need if you
have child support paper forms that you
need print all that find those papers um
then you need to make an appointment the
Denver office in Longmont accepts
walk-ins in Grand Junction you need to
make an appointment in Springs you need
to make an appointment the phone number
is on the website I guess I could have
had that for you I do not I apologize I
failed you there you're gonna have to do
a little bit of this on your own so call
and make an appointment it's way easier
to call and make an appointment in
steering's than it is to sit there and
wait for like three hours in Denver if
that's what I did in a kind of sucked
you waited all day in Denver
yep I made my appointment for Colorado
Springs I showed up about 15 minutes
early because I thought it would take
much longer to get
it's hard to judge i-25 it could take
you now it weren't how would I have to
get from here there so I got there about
15 minutes early and the lady was like
hey the guy that was scheduled before
you didn't show up Oh
Kerry you ready [ __ ] yeah I'm ready and
it took her I don't know maybe an hour
to do the entire process she filled her
printed me interviewed me that's why
you're waiting all day in Denver is
because that's how long it takes right
and there's a lot of other people just
showed up every day and just relax in
their fingerprinting you it's easy and
you know what if you've got warrants or
something if you're wanted in the state
of Colorado and you're in the a media
office getting your [ __ ] done they run
your ID and if you're wanted they come
in [ __ ] arrest you yeah we really
can't emphasize like read the questions
and the theatres yes to the first four
or you've got like active warrants out
now don't apply don't apply cuz I'm not
even kidding they will come arrest if
you're getting fingerprinted and they
run your [ __ ] you're wanted by the FBI
there's a sign on the door that says
unmarked or plainclothes security
officer on premises at all times he will
come and arrest you again I spent
three-and-a-half hours trying to find
the dude and I think I found both of
them like they're not playing around
read the questions answer them honestly
for the the secondary questions like
child support and student loans if
you've got any of those you know any of
those questions apply to you you're
gonna need to contact that institution
like I had to cut contact everybody I've
got student loans with and get a paper
that says my student loans are in good
standing which means if you've been duck
in that [ __ ] for a decade you need to
stand up take the punch mmm set up a
payment plan start making payments you
only need to make one payment same thing
with child support right if your child
support is [ __ ] up I was cool cuz
mine's legit but if your child support
is [ __ ] up they will make you get a
paper from your caseworker that says
that you're paying and that you're doing
what you can if you had felonies 17
years ago or over the deadline and
you're good to go
you need paperwork from the court that
adjudicated your felony in the originals
of jurisdictional you gotta [ __ ]
contact the court to try and sends to
you and get the paperwork from them that
says you completed successfully and on
what date you completed for every [ __ ]
felony and it can be a real pain you've
got I mean I've talked to people and
Denver while I was waiting that had to
go to like seven different courthouses
to pick up stuff the big out between 20
or like 18 and 20 and then they've been
perfect for a decade but they had still
had to spend four days driving between
courthouses getting paperwork so that
they could then apply to work in the
legal marijuana industry like have you
[ __ ] together and some for some of you
that's gonna be a lot of paperwork
gathering if you don't have it together
the lady at the meed office or the man
the person that helped me was a lady so
I always think it's a lady but the
person that helps you with Amy the
office they will give you a list of
everything that you need after you fail
the first time yeah that's the first
step of the process when you get there
and it's your turn as they go through
your [ __ ] piece by piece and make sure
you have everything and when I got done
it was very clearly like you have
everything it's your first try Wow high
five that's kind of yeah you know I was
well prepared I knew plenty of people
that have yeah I was the same way yes so
we neither of us had an issue but we've
all talked to countless people that have
no idea what this process looks like
they even moved to Colorado moved across
the country unprepared and so knowing
this and doing it right is sort of
essential folks if you've got forty four
felonies you're probably not gonna exact
thinking about him this hold everybody
forty four shout out but nobody's ever
known why we call them forty four and
that's the only hint we're gonna give
you so um we're gonna keep moving when
you show up okay the next step is show
up and complete the damn interview ah
it's an interview it doesn't matter
which is where I'm hard comb your hair
if you do that if you got dreadlocks
flying them down they're gonna make you
take off they're gonna make you take
take take your hat off and then you're
gonna wear the picture they take around
your neck for the next two years bro I'm
six five and that picture place they
have like a little like a swatch on the
floor of our on the wall of material
where you're supposed to stand in front
of that shit's like five ten like where
those people are so I guess the squats
I'm trying to smile as I'm but not real
far yeah it was pretty funny all right
so when you show up for the place when
you show up for the interview
bring the completed application have
that [ __ ] filled out before you get
there bring your ID bring your court
papers and disclosure forms if you've
got any of those to bring with you bring
proof of residency if you don't have if
you're new to call
on your ID if you do have an
out-of-state ID that's what the [ __ ] I'm
trying to say if your idea is from
out-of-state bring proof of residency
that you do live in the state of
Colorado bring the phone bill bring up
[ __ ] cable bill bring the white bill
bring whatever you got this this goes
back to column and they'll tell you
exactly what you need and this is the
time to bring up my ID says I'm from
Texas or Tennessee or wherever the [ __ ]
like bring it out and they'll tell you
exactly what you need supporting
paperwork wise if you've got felonies
they'll tell you what to what to ask the
courts for same thing with your child
support stuff they told me exactly it's
all on the application when you look at
it so and that's happy to answer these
questions super important they do not
take cash bring a money order or bring a
check if you're going to get your key
badge and this is where we'll talk about
this part if you're going to get your
key badge it's gonna cost you $300 if
you want your support badge it is a
hundred and fifty dollars my colectomy
is that wrong dude cuz I just know what
surprises were right but I think Denver
takes cash I'm like 85% just somebody
else that was helping me with this
episode should my change will not accept
cash and the website says bring check or
money order so I'm pretty sure they quit
accepting cash just that what surprised
me the I knew that only one office did
and I could have sworn it was Denver but
I might have taken the check I worked at
a place that had a lot of cash flow like
we had a lot of cash in the end of the
register at the end of they I've worked
at several places and just imagine how
many applications they handle add $150
the badge minimum times 16,000 employees
huh imagine / 365 days people you can do
the battery guys you just don't want
that much money in a box and then the
office anywhere like over a [ __ ]
couple of days that boxes full of cash
so I understand they probably they just
be prepared you guys take a check or
take a money order
just stop it somewhere that sells a
money order freaking Walmart sucks they
have money orders I think most Walgreens
will sell you a money order several
7-eleven 7-eleven money order go to the
meed place now let's talk about the
difference between a key badge and a
support badge there always has to be a
support badge on premises nobody can be
in micro without a support battery there
has to be a red badge which is the owner
badge if to own the place to get that
one
or a key badge if you don't have a key
badge if there's not a key badge on
premises nobody else can be in there
none of the support badges can be in the
room so I find it advantageous to go
ahead and get that key badge because
then you're kind of more qualified to do
more [ __ ] you've already got more
ability to take on more responsibility I
made sure to get the key yeah and did it
help you do you feel like getting your
key badge helped you advance in your
position at the spot I think those rules
are more heavily enforced on the medical
side okay or maybe I'm just no I've got
to be the odd the only support badge
several nights a week at work why do I
or my only key badge that might be why I
got promoted yes it just makes you more
promotable so a support badge you can be
like a budtender you can be a trimmer
you can be a joint roller you can in the
gardens you can support badges the
starter badge like if you've only got
150 to spend on a badge and you know
you're gonna be a trimmer for the first
year like tinder or a budtender you can
go ahead and get the support like we're
not saying don't but the key badge
definitely gives you more opportunities
in the industry and if you're one of
those people that's moving to Colorado
with the degree in biochemistry like you
might want to go ahead and get the
support badge or the key badge I'm sorry
I think you mixing those two I was
trying to figure you confused me so I'm
sorry
yes the cube edge is the more important
one I was looking for the distinguishing
it says something about on the
application if you're going to have keys
and be in charge of employees and have
access to limited access areas you
should go ahead and get a key badge
so I recommend of course get the key
badge if you don't have the money for it
get yourself a support badge if you're
an ambitious ambitious person and you
feel like you want to move up if you're
gonna manage that [ __ ] get the key go
ahead and get a key badge if you want to
work with the grow team if you're real
enthusiastic and you can show that you
can do it get yourself a key badge we'd
love to see you move up in the industry
super quickly I knew I wasn't gonna be
on the bottom rung for long so I fully
got that one on purpose like I know a
lot of the people that did that too and
I know a couple of people who got the
support and have been kind of passed
over several times because they can't
meet some of those requirements that you
have to have the key for gotta have a
key badge on premises at all times if I
got to be pretty much in the same room
with the support badges they don't even
leave them in another room so all right
so if you want to be like the
cultivation manager get a keypad you
feeling to be a trim team leader you get
a key badge maybe even if you want to be
lead budtender you might need a key
badge because you'll be carrying product
back to the storage room which requires
a key badge to get into or at least it
should so get your badge it's gonna cost
money
decide which badge you want the next
step here you guys once you've got your
badge wait for it take a picture
[ __ ] smile for your picture look good
in the picture bro that's the next step
yep you don't want to look like a
dumbass and then hang that picture any
night for the next two years
wear that bright green Colorado medical
marijuana Enforcement Division lanyard
cheesy ass picture on it it's so funny
walking into place originally like
original green one bro yeah oh gee buddy
emoji alright so once you've got that
that picture with your cheesy ass grin
on it you got a badge the next step is
to get a job if once you get the badge
now you can apply in the industry yeah
yeah so think about what you're good at
are you good at bud tending are you good
at trimming honestly we keep saying bud
tuning and trimming those are the ways
into this industry if you want to be a
master grower most places have a master
grower you're gonna have to start
trimming you're gonna have to show them
that you know about plants one day the
master grower is gonna go [ __ ] I need
help transplanting plants and you're
gonna go I'm good at that he's gonna go
we'll come show me what you got and if
you can follow directions and do it the
way that he wants it done and also
contribute skill knowledge and care to
the job you may end up being assistant
grower one day I mean let you come help
me pull leaves in the garden one day
you'll work your way up and one day when
I'm not not me I don't want to say by
Malinda master grower or whatever's
facility you work at one day when he's
sick or whatever he's got the shits and
can't come in maybe you get to water the
plants or whatever and you get to learn
how to become a man you're gonna work
your way up one way or another Jeff and
I were both bud tenders like that's
where you start a lot of people start
off as trimmers that's where you start
like you can be almost anything in the
marijuana industry like we literally
need every profession I have played
budtender
manager hire and fire er I did the hire
up firing I grew the weed
I'm still doing the growing I do the I
do some transportation do a bunch of do
all of that yeah I used to help with
design a different point it's designed a
couple of facilities rooms yeah so there
what it starts off at the bar and like
people the I talk to people every day
that aren't prepared for that idea
they're like well I've been in marketing
for like 10 years and it's like cool are
you ready to trim some weed you learn
everything in this room and what their
different applications are for different
patients and and sell it accurately and
inform well-informed like can you pull
that off because if you can't do that or
be cool with trim to show a little weed
like you're gonna have a really hard
time looking for a dispensary that's
actively looking for a marketing dude
who's never worked in legal weed before
and doesn't necessarily know the
community the culture of the product the
clients like there's a lot you need to
know and you learn that when you start
as a blood gender a tremor it's a whole
and a kit it's a whole world to be
involved in a buddy of mine started as a
trimmer in like six weeks later he was
running a trim crew for like seven
different dispensaries and they just
cycled between them as they harvested
shout-out to Linus yep shoutout - like
he had a he struggled for a while find a
dispensary that would even take him on
as a trimmer and when he finally found
one he made sure to put it in his all
and now he's running a big ass crew and
a big crew I see what he's got on
Facebook and he's killing it his crews
they're killing it right now they've
done a good job I'm the same way you're
the same way like we moved up quick be
motivated if I come here and work so
rapidly we're growing so rapidly and
there are so many people coming from
around the world to be in this industry
that there are 50 people trying to take
your job in this industry every [ __ ]
day green and healthy wellness is a
small shop with a small know a small
location we aren't very well known yet
we're kind of new we don't have a large
following I think that's what I'm trying
to say with a whole bunch of words we
don't have a huge following but we get
probably five to ten applications every
single day of people that want to be
growers trimmers get bud tenders
whatever they can do they like I will
clean the toilet
as long as you give me a job in there
yeah I see some crazy I see a lot of
people coming in that are doing it right
that are ready to work that know the
industry and know how to sell their
place in it and a lot of it comes down
to like knowing how to pitch your
previous work experience because I sold
weed for my living room for the last ten
years
looks like yeah it does you did an
episode before that covered like some of
the red resumes you gotten to grow and
how ridiculous some of them could get
put together real resume like if you
don't know what that is google it yeah
be prepared because there's a lot of
people gunning for the jobs that are
available even with this how fast we're
expanding so if you want to stand out at
all you got to do all right
no let's talk about some of the problems
that come with getting a job working in
the cannabis industry the number one
most obvious problem to me is banking
yep that's an issue when you worked at a
dispensary or as a grower and I can't
speak for every shop or every grow and
this is something that I probably
shouldn't say too much about but this is
the damn truth when payday comes you get
an envelope stuffed with cash everything
is done in cash it sucks
yeah you get a pay stub and taxes are
taken out and that you get a solution
jobs is the same but instead of a check
at the bottom or better yet a voided
check that tells you about the direct
deposit you just got you get a check
stub folded up with a bunch of 20s in
the middle a bunch of [ __ ] yeah you got
to carry all these damn twenties in your
backpack or somehow to the car and then
home but it's not just payroll it's
everything like state taxes federal
taxes electric bills rent it's it's yeah
so when you get home you got to figure
out a way to convert all that cash into
some way to pay your rent so that is the
obvious problem luckily employees can
usually get back accounts it's smaller
banks no problem it's the businesses
that really can't get accounts but
you've still got a transfer cash to bank
right right you gotta hand that cash
came from a dispensary sometimes it
stinks like we
your account to get closed we have a
mutual friend whose account was just
closed because their cash deposits
smelled way too much like cannabis
shout-out to that person yeah also one
of the problems we've talked about this
a little bit on the podcast another
problem that can happen if you work in
the cannabis industry is you're gonna
get pulled over you're gonna smell like
a pound of [ __ ] weed and the cops are
gonna harass you if you've got a badge a
lot of times they expect you to be a
model citizen because you've got the
badge and you know the rules
it we're gonna be a little more careful
we're back to putting your best foot
forward like don't stink like weed with
your badge and also how because they're
good they're gonna as soon as they see
that [ __ ] or even the green lanyard
that goes with it they're automatically
gonna be thinking is this person high
right now behind the wheel do I have a
DUI arrest so don't be that person true
also renting is hard yeah getting a
house is hard when your place of
employment is green and health and
wellness there's a stigma involved that
a lot of people don't realize I've got a
friend leaving the industry right now
and they were talking to me just this
afternoon that they're applying for jobs
that aren't in the cannabis industry and
he's real hesitant because he hasn't
faced the company the drug tests in a
decade
he's a budtender and a cannabis consumer
and passionate about cannabis really
enjoys that aspect of his life and at
minimum he's gonna have to give it up
until he can pee clean and he wasn't
except necessarily expecting to leave
the industry this abruptly so he's not
prepared for that and so it best his ass
is gonna be out of work for a while
while he looks for either jobs that
don't test or whatnot but he's extra
hesitant because as soon as they're like
well what did you just get stopped doing
and he's like well I'd work in the
marijuana industry for three years and
now I'm trying to get a job at a bank or
you know wherever the hell outs
Wow yeah yeah they're gonna they're
gonna be judgmental for sure right so
like even if they don't typically drug
test or there's a lot of companies I
worked for a bunch of them back in the
day they just threatened did
test and that the only drug test they do
is whether or not you show up to get
your cup they can't actually afford to
pay like the 75 bucks or whatever to
test yeah yeah even those companies are
more apt to test somebody who's coming
out of the legal weed industry it's just
got that same edge to it so getting
banking renting cars who's gonna get
renting a car is kind of a [ __ ] I was
turned down I just bought a new car you
guys whoo shout out to my new car but I
also shout out to mario Archuleta for
the sweet hookup in the new car a winter
karna some regard now nice but uh I was
declined I've been getting stacks of
envelopes in the mail from credit
companies that declined my credit and
when you look at why it says
insufficient employment and I make a
[ __ ] ton of money not to brag about my
money but I make plenty of [ __ ] money
for the car that I bought and they just
didn't like it that I worked at her
dispensary they would call me while I
was waiting in the Ford dealership to
buy my car they would call and they'd be
like hey we've just got one question
about your employment what is this gah w
you work at I just write down GH have
you turned to avoid questions since for
green and healthy wellness like oh are
you a weed grower we can we sorry we can
we can't give you credit today and they
just hang up it's not all companies but
it's several yeah um
shout outs of the companies that don't
apply to this but like there's a
statement that you're gonna take on and
you kinda have to be ready to bear that
cross it's not just out in the world
like plenty you got family that's like
Oh [ __ ] cousin Ricky working at the
weed store and we should mention all the
drug testing talk the dispensary bong
drug test you noop don't worry but don't
show up high either don't be an [ __ ]
if there's too many [ __ ] rules to
come toast if we can't tell you're high
it's ok if we can tell you're high
you're in trouble don't be that high
[ __ ] obvious problems with working in
the industry are banking credit getting
a car getting a loan that kind of [ __ ]
is hard shout-out to my friend Jessica I
asked her for guidance on this because
she is a manager in a dispensary she
said the first thing she spouted off
with the passion
[ __ ] sexism in the cannabis industry
this is she called it a boys club and
said that this is ran by guys and she's
a woman and it's hard to be taken
[ __ ] seriously by all the men in this
industry so ladies uh when you come to
Colorado your chances of getting a job
are nearly tripled of what a guy with
the same qualifications are going to
have the chances of that same dude are
gonna have of getting employment I know
that sounds rude to say they don't care
what you look like if you're a trimmer
for the most part but if you're a
budtender automatically hot females go
to the top of the stack and that's kind
of true in any industry but it's really
true it's super true in the cannabis
industry unfortunately so you're gonna
get hired first at the same time
everybody's gonna look at your titties
all [ __ ] day long in the cannabis
industry that we are used to growing
weed in our basement we're used to being
a bunch of bros it's kind of a boys club
we should know this by now but the grow
environment the weed business
environment sometimes people forget and
it gets a little bit sexist a little bit
so you have the rules the necess tree
like we're under so many weed specific
rules that in a lot of ways the ball
gets dropped with some of the others so
slap us remind us be like boys or women
in the room behavior [ __ ] themselves and
a guy like myself will check myself
after one or two of those I don't say
some [ __ ] when damsels around shut up
damsel I've learned to respect the
ladies a little bit better because I've
been reminded so shout out to the ladies
that have taught us that there is some
sexism in the cannabis industry be
prepared for that a little bit another
huge problem you cannot consume on site
if you want to consume cannabis while
you're working at a medical marijuana or
a recreational marijuana grow facility
processing facility anything like that
you cannot do it anywhere near the
building you got a note go somewhere
else I don't care where you go to the
cameras cannot see you people that are
leaving the dispensary should go far
away consume your medicine somewhere far
away
safely that goes for customers to like
you're shopping in the league we de
distrito try to [ __ ] roll join the
parking lot yeah yeah well okay yeah
don't do that get out of there also
something that I would mention is a pain
in the ass and the
this industry and you may think I'm
crazy some people can make glam but
there is so much tedious regulation and
so much pressure they were way overboard
with the regulation and like just I
watch people every day grind up scraps
of marijuana like stems like [ __ ] that
you wouldn't even consider feeling bad
about if you threw away like it's just
trash
they have to grind it with coffee and
shredded paper to make it
indistinguishable and unusable yes like
it when that you translate that to a
major grow the amount of like just how
you throw out the trash becomes a
majorly complicated process so what do I
run the the big row we are harvesting 85
lights worth of plants when a trashes on
you right so what we do I will start a
trash can where the trimmers are and
I'll put I'll harvest the plant and I
will put that pot of dirt in the bottom
of the can now there's like a little bit
of dirt in the bottom and then as we
trim the leaves and a little bit of
sticks will go in and then I'll go
harvest another plant or maybe we've got
old pots stacked up and I'll pour some
and it goes dirt leaves dirt leaves and
then like I'll sweep up the floor and
[ __ ] and pick up sweepings in there but
you got to mix up that weed the weed
shouldn't be recognizable right and then
it has to go into a locked trashcan
which is also behind a gate and we still
have had our [ __ ] trash broken into
torn out of the dumpster they tear the
bags open and they destroy all that and
I got to go [ __ ] sweep it up and put
the trash back in the goddamn trash can
in the morning when I get there so there
are a lot of regulations the regulations
are ridiculous I have to everything's
got to be weighed a million times
everything and there are checks on
things also so it's a little bit
stressful on all the regulation all the
pressure is crazy things have to happen
at a certain time things have to be done
quickly you can't wait for some [ __ ] in
a big grow and you're on camera from
9000 different angles so don't ever
think you're gonna get away with
anything
the be it on camera on every square
inch-- takes some adjustment like I
watch it all day at work people forget
there are camera or I pointed out to
customers like we're on
like we can see in here everything stop
it here everything like you try to get
us in trouble like why stop [ __ ]
asking how to take we just Texas like we
can't answer you right yes stop asking
how many pieces edibles which you should
eat it's [ __ ] one and wait two hours
[ __ ] I told you twice they get
stressful and also the rules always
[ __ ] change I get emails once a week
with new rules rules there's a special
company that makes law books and they're
on their like 3rd marijuana book now Wow
like you have to buy the original book
and then the 2 addendum books so that's
uh that's most of what I've got that's
stressful but one thing that might can
testify to because he's a budtender
mostly now the consumer is so educated
that they expect a bud and and fo
educated they think they know what the
[ __ ] they're talking about that they
expected but I hear the phrase set of a
lot and I hear good to go even more oh
wow it's a good and a bad thing I'm
blessed to be in the the medical side of
things now I get a lot of that too but
honestly I see kind of a terse a more
touristy side of it and honestly they
just haven't had the the culture in the
community out loud and proud like we
have here in Colorado like down in Texas
in an Arkansas for is long but like you
can really tell who who's been in the
community actively and who hasn't who's
been like a marijuana consumer in the
total shadows like most of their friends
don't know they definitely wouldn't talk
about it in public or on the news around
the radio so they've never heard anyone
say sativa before or indica it's just
never happened they've only ever read it
and just thinking about that kind of
boggles my mind a little bit so I try to
pity him a little bit but a [ __ ] when
I hear for like the 14th time on a
Saturday it makes me want a [ __ ] [ __ ]
punch somebody but I saw the same thing
in the wine world like so it exists
other places people think they know a
lot and they act snotty it's funny I
love the dispensary where the budtender
knows [ __ ] everything it makes you
feel stupid and doesn't realize that I'm
a breeder right like I love it when
they're wrong I was in a shop the other
day in Denver and I heard wrong from a
there was a strain labeled wrong and I
listened to the budtender go on for like
four minutes about how it was an indica
when it's a really popular sativa and
I'm just sitting there shaking my head
as the customer gobbles it up and I'm
like dude look at the buds like I can
tell that's a [ __ ] sativa the buds are
growing dammit stupid professional weed
smokers alright Mike thanks for coming
to the show bro happy - yeah you guys
that's all we've got for how to get your
badge here at the state of cards how to
get your badge and some of the things
that come along with that particular key
the awesomeness yeah shout out once
again to that one mountain girl and also
a huge shout out to Jessica both were
huge contributors to the show also shout
out to the CD the Colorado Department of
Public Health and Environment website
for all the information they gave me I
want to give a huge shout out to
everybody who wished me a happy birthday
if it was on Facebook if it was on
Instagram if it was on Twitter if it was
here face to face if it was that through
text message however it was thanks had a
great birthday the whole week has been
amazing we're still raging it has been
several days since my birthday it's
actually the fourth now and my birthday
was on the first and I finally eaten all
of the food and snacks that I was given
however have not consumed all of the
Chipotle gift cards that I was given so
yeah somebody gave me a Chipotle gift
card so I got that on deck maybe that'll
be my my after work treat tomorrow so I
just want to check the phone to see if
Chipotle was still possible everybody
that hooked me up for my birthday if you
fed me if he took me out if he dad me
out if you gave me some solvent let's
hash that I pressed into one giant
[ __ ] dead big shout-out if he dad me
out with fear X big shout out also big
shout out to my friends at the can of
Canyon I dropped into the can of Canyon
yesterday and hung out everybody in
there dad me out everybody in there was
happy to see me big shout out to the can
of Canyon if you're ever in Colorado
Springs and you need a place to stop and
kill a few minutes you want to smoke
down I always recommend the can of
Canyon it's on Colorado Boulevard it's
on Colorado it's not hard to find if you
google the can of Canyon in Colorado
Springs you will get there tell Camille
that rasta Jeff sent you
that you listen to the girl from the
heart podcast she will treat you like
royalty that's what I think I've got for
you this week you guys I do have more
episodes planned I'm gonna do an episode
with a bunch of lovely ladies and we'll
talk about women in cannabis um what
else do we have anyway it'll be in the
future anyway we don't have to talk too
much about what's coming up my little
notebook is over there I'm not gonna
reach for it Mike Oh No thank you for
hanging out dude you had to leave the
little guy at home I hope I'll you
didn't miss him too much while you're
here I'll let you get back to him real
soon yeah it's about that time but it's
good to be here man I heard an episode a
little while back someone mentioned
missing me on the shows yes dude I'm
trying to be here man it's life got
crazy but this is still important to me
and I want to be here as often as I can
but that's not as often as I would like
right now so I apologize for my absence
and I hope you like me on the show
lately that was her buddy Mike Oh was
his name yep he sent a couple of emails
which I like I like repeated updates
yeah well he was a little pissed off
that you hadn't been here for a little
while he was kind of upset with the
shelf life exploded and this show had to
take a back burner for a while for for a
minute there it was it was a big part of
my extracurricular activities and I just
sorted that time got filled big time
yeah man
I don't believe me at all that kid is
the most important thing in your world
as it should be no but yeah the show's
still a priority so uh we're recording
real late at night like we said Chipotle
be [ __ ] close so yeah we're
scratching it out but I wanted to be
part of the show getting badges like
I've seen so many people [ __ ] because
they didn't know this information before
they made a big little bleep and I want
to really wanted to be a part of this
show so yeah sorry for the ramblings
hope you got the information you need
because knowing is half the battle
no mic come in I will be back in seven
days with another episode I'm not sure
what I'm gonna put out for you in seven
days I've got a lot of stuff written
down it'll be great I promise you that
make sure you tune in make sure you
check out the show on iTunes stitcher or
I read genetics Colorado dot-com we do
not have any sponsors on this episode if
you want to sponsor the podcast or if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I want to give
a big shout out to a product called
sphere X I was able to dab this new roll
called sphere
tonight at the Cannon Canyon I only took
one dab of it so far
it's got my [ __ ] attention so check
that product out if you're in Colorado
if you've got something you want me to
review send me an email girl from your
heart a hotmail.com I'd love to review
your product you want to be a sponsor
we'd love to give you a shout out on the
show the show is aimed at a cannabis
community so if you've got a cannabis
product this would be the perfect Avenue
to show off your wares you guys want to
thank everybody for listening
big thanks to everybody out there in the
cannabis community who's doing their
thing who's making this should happen
you guys want to give a big shout out to
my ninja Spence and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
gun dancing girls come together like
they die man
[Music]