[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back cannabis community this
time for episode number 123 of the glow
from Earhart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're a new grower the pure
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated Gabbar if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who
is just curious about the current state
of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host my friends
call me Ross - Jeff I want to thank you
once again for joining me as always I
need to send a huge thank you shout out
to my friends in the mystic roots band
colliding to use their music on my show
big shout out to cat food and the entire
mystic roots crew I want to dedicate
this episode to my friend Zach we lost
his act to cystic fibrosis this month so
[ __ ] you cystic fibrosis and Zach I miss
you hon I love you brother
this tab is for you I'm gonna take a
little dab because zach had cystic
fibrosis and it messed with his lungs
really badly if he took too big of a dad
he would sound just like the bong so
we're gonna take a little dab farm we're
gonna breathe in some love we're gonna
blow up some [ __ ] this dab is free
brothers AG everybody dab with me
[Music]
alright that was a big night stab Zack
I'm gonna miss you brother it's not
gonna be the same yeah much love much
respect shout-out to Tim also if you're
listening Tim I hope we get together
sometime soon and celebrate Zack all
right so ladies and gentlemen I wanna
thank you for joining me this episode
will come mostly from the canna Canyon
the candy Canyon is my favorite cannabis
social lounge in Colorado Springs where
we are allowed to congregate and
socialize and smoke recreational
cannabis like a responsible adult should
be allowed to so before I get to that I
want to talk about something I've been
seeing on Facebook the cannabis cup for
Colorado has been canceled for the year
2016 there will be no cannabis cup over
the 4/20 weekend high times intended to
have the event in Denver Colorado Adams
County I believe it was rejected all of
the permits and would not let high times
have their event high times had to
scramble to find a new location for the
cannabis cup they opted to try pueblos
they put in applications for permits
they decided through that process that
there would not be enough time to
advertise and organize a cannabis cup
should the event be approved so what
I've seen a lot on Facebook is people
bitching out high times and people
bitching out the city of Pueblo and
people bitching out the city of Denver
for a cannabis cup not happening hey
guys this was a huge event there's a lot
of risk involved
we can't blame any city for an event not
happening maybe Denver they did kick
high times out they did not approve the
permit so maybe we can be mad at them
but it is not high times his fault nor
is it Pablo's fault that this event did
not happen in the backup plan of Pueblo
ah high times submitted the permits and
high times also pulled the permits they
decided are the applications for permits
they decided to stop the process so
there wasn't enough time to get an event
together even if Puebla did approve it
so high times just decided to pull the
plug we can't blame it on anybody let's
quit pointing fingers let's all be
friends again
let's get back together let's dab like
we used to let's be a community that's
what I have to say about that we will
talk a little bit about this in the
episode when my friends join me
since there is no cannabis cup you guys
let me invite you to the secret sesh the
secret sessions hosted by Gatsby Gardens
we will have a ton of great sponsors our
friend Adam hill is coming from
California to host the event I will be
there the Grammy gets me will be there
our friend dude its damsel will be there
there will be a lot of people there
dabbing bending having a grande 420 time
I hope you can join us follow secret
sash Colorado on Instagram for more
information as soon as I have more info
I will get it to you you guys I talked
about doing an episode about what you
could do if you came to Pueblo for the
cannabis cup obviously there's no point
in doing that because you're not going
to come here because there's not a
cannabis cup so I apologize for teasing
you about that if there's something
you'd like to know about the city of
Pueblo Colorado send me an email grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I will
answer the email and we'll talk about
Pueblo a lot of people are talking about
moving here there's some things that you
should know and things you probably
didn't think of we'll talk about those
all right you guys I think it is time
for us to time warp we're gonna travel
back in time to just a couple of days
ago when I met with my friend Camille
with Steven Daffy know who else was
there a kabuki Jay Fox and my new friend
Matt we all gathered at the Cannon
Canyon on 1507 Colorado Boulevard I
think Boulevard 15:07 Colorado in
Colorado Springs it's a great place so
we're gonna Time Warp I'm gonna put on
some music and we are going to journey
back in time and when we get back we
will be at
[Music]
all right podcast world we are here at
the canna Canyon in Colorado Springs
Camille will you remind me the address
please because I'm high as [ __ ] one five
zero seven West Colorado Avenue thank
you so much coo so come down to one five
zero seven West Colorado Avenue check
out the can of Canyon it's a great place
the couches are comfy the tables are
covered in rigs and they've got an email
come hit it so guys welcome to the show
sitting to my little further to my left
is our good friend Camille thank you for
joining me you're welcome thanks for
having me thanks for coming up such a
great smile I'm happy to be here it's a
good day you look great today sitting to
my immediate left over here is our good
friend Steven Duffy no you are the
president and founder of the veteran
farmers Alliance is that correct that's
correct
thanks for doing that thanks for being
on the show thanks glad to be here
thanks for coming over here to my kind
of far to the right is our buddy kabuki
Jay Fox how you doing bro I'm awesome
man thanks for having me back we're
awesome as [ __ ] thanks for joining me I
appreciate a stag run CBD all day
hashtag terms for tots sitting to my
right is kind of a new friend remind me
your name my friend Matthew Kail Matthew
Kail yes I'm with an outfit here
veterans for natural rights I'm one of
the individuals that helps out with the
event the other night at the dab lounge
and thank you for doing that yeah thanks
for doing that we're gonna talk a lot
about that before we get to that so
thanks for joining me everybody before
we get to the end I let me put a
disclaimer out there Camille is working
at the can of Canyon she is the host and
are you the owner here is that correct
I am co-owner owner so she may have to
stand up and take off and go for a run
any given moment here so excuse her if
that happens we'll try to get some of
her stuff covered in the beginning of
the show here so one thing I want to
talk about everybody the cannabis cup
for Colorado
yeah we were all stoked about that I'm
sure everybody here had an idea of
something they wanted to do for 4/20 and
for the cannabis cup absolutely fairly
excited I think that this is going to be
kind of the turn of 4/20 being about
private events I'm kind of excited about
that I know the secret sesh we're
planning on doing something as well I
can't talk too much about what we're
planning on doing but I'm excited I
think this is kind of a new wave of
different 4/20 I think it's gonna be
cool I like the way that you put that
because that kind of works me into part
of what I wanted to talk about the
importance of consumption clubs since
they're not going to let us have large
events like that we need to have places
like the canna Canyon to consume our
cannabis for people to come and
socialize like we're all we're doing is
hanging out in consuming cannabis and
being friends here absolutely
we definitely need something like this
so before I get to that let's talk about
the veteran farmers Alliance event that
happened a couple of days ago I want to
give you a huge shout out Stephen that
was a huge event how many people do you
think Shelly was I'd see we think Matt
probably over 200 we were at the lounge
in Colorado Springs is another social
smoke lounge
shout out to the dad lounge and thank
you Dan for letting us so Steven hosts
an event there called the veteran farm
official title the veteran farmers
Alliance get together have a good time
all right can you tell us a little bit
about the veteran farmers Alliance
absolutely basically the veteran farmers
Alliance brings the community together
brings veterans together with civilians
brings breeders together growers
together nutrient manufacturers and
glass blowers
it just takes everybody and brings them
all in one place and allows these guys
to have free genetics free information
education all that and they're able to
get it in one centralized location to
where they can have good medicine and
get the best medicine that's out there
it's not this watered-down crap no these
are fresh genetics good genetics and
these guys care so we had 300 people
came through this event inside of the
dive lounge we had breeders set up with
their booths they had seeds available we
had nutrient companies we had glass
companies and all of these companies
threw down stacks of merchandise for the
veterans absolutely well the total the
total value was just a little over
$12,000 $12,000 with the products given
to veterans to help them grow better
cannabis to fight their PTSD their pain
their absolutely usually respectable and
also thanks these guys to the right they
all showed up and last night there was a
city council meeting everybody's facial
expressions I'll just change everyone's
body language just deflate it a little
at this city council meeting a lot of
things went down I live in another city
I was trying to keep up what I
understand is they have put a moratorium
on more social clubs like this and in
eight years all clubs like this force to
close yes yes so the moratorium was
actually set in place back in September
six months a moratorium set so we're we
are reappropriation
what they decided was they wanted to ban
them originally supposed to be for five
years but they extended it to eight
years kind of a blow but at the same
time this is what the voters wanted
we're very passionate about that that's
what we believe in and that's what we're
gonna fight for so this isn't the end
this is just the beginning okay yes the
way that it's written does that mean
that in eight years you have to close
yes in eight years by March 2024 we will
have to close our doors is there a
second vote coming right so there's
another vote on March 22nd the second
round of votes but you know a lot can
happen in eight years
marijuana can become federally legal you
know the opposite direction as well so
it gives us a little bit of time to get
a ballot referendum to allow these kind
of clubs and it gives us a little bit of
time to force legislation on the issue
because Jonathan singer himself and also
the representative KITT Roop from
Colorado Springs himself he's backing a
bill to legalize these types of clubs
statewide so these are already we
already know that there is a lot of
support here in Colorado Springs other
otherwise get root wouldn't be on board
absolutely so I think another thing that
really spoke volumes about that as well
was the amount of people that showed up
for that initial meeting on like
February 22nd 24 yeah I mean a
standing-room-only and I think I think
there was only like two people out of
like a 120 plus that we're against these
Cubs and the majority of those people
there were very much so for them about
them and so that was very frustrating
but the community has spoken so I saw
the meet I watched part of the meeting
on the internet the other day and the
place was packed once again
we got to see our friend from the lazy
lion that guy's named Andrew I'm glad he
chose he's a veteran also so shout out
to the veterans cool that he came and
supported the vast majority of people
there were veterans how about the two
City Council members was it okay so I
was and I asked a city council members I
said how many of your veterans show me
no not one of them raised their hands
they wouldn't acknowledge that they were
veterans that's disrespectful
absolutely disrespect and they are
veterans to their service I'm sure that
when they go other places they get a
veteran's discount of course yeah well
they wait raise their hand then but you
know they didn't raise their hand so I
asked I turned around and said how many
veterans are behind me and like three
quarters of the room marijuana patients
you know they these guys don't
understand this is a cry for help and
all those guys that raised their hands
all those guys and girls will have to
say that they raised their hands and
it's like they didn't care they don't
care it was an emotional cry for help
too there were people breaking down on
the stand talking about the importance
of these clubs and the importance of
these gathering places because they
can't go anywhere else they have lease
agreements that prevent them from
smoking in their own homes
these are people who serve their country
and they're not allowed to take part in
the freedoms that they're guaranteed by
the Constitution of the state they live
in
it's a travesty we could almost just in
the show right there that was that's
yeah that's exactly what's going on
about the importance of these clubs you
got something to say go for it yeah
you're just gonna say and not to mention
shout-out to the dad launched for
providing an awesome space for those
veterans to have the veterans farmers
Alliance event I mean if it wasn't for
these social clubs that community
wouldn't be able to be brought together
as easily so
I gave veterans dabs for their first
time I met four sets of parents that had
special needs children that were curious
about cannabis and curious about CBD and
it's funny that places like this bring
all sorts of patients throughout the
spectrum together in some way or another
and we help each other even if it's just
lending an ear and understanding or
being available and being you know
introduced to someone and networking
with someone that can help us these
clubs are absolutely essential to anyone
who really is seeking a healthy social
outlet in our community to not only
discuss cannabis but why it works for
them and you know I really can't see
anything healthier you know it saddens
me to see it go the way that it has and
you know I'm happy to help fight it in
any way possible because it's it's
[ __ ] it just makes me sad and
honestly working here also I mean we see
all types of members as well and one
thing that really kind of stands out to
me is the amount of questions that
people have that they're scared to ask
yeah whether it's about CBD or THC or
the benefits edibles or proper dosing
information that they might not get in
dispensary started cuts you off oh no no
that was just adding on that point like
that we were having a conversation as
friends at the front counter just a few
minutes ago to smoking dabs talking
about growing and the folks behind us
we're learning everything we were saying
yeah we're absorbing that as one of that
one of those people in that group was
learning from us on accident oh
definitely education and support they
get just from showing up here is crucial
yeah we can go to a bar and drink
alcohol until we die you can physically
drink enough alcohol at the bar there's
one bottle if you drink that whole
bottle of whatever you choose it will
kill you
you can come here and no one's going to
let you smoke enough cannabis to hurt
yourself and I don't think you can smoke
enough cannabis to hurt yourself now I
will say you could probably get higher
do some dumb [ __ ] I can argue that but
yeah I mean no one's gonna let anybody
that's that high leave here we all have
each other's backs we look out for each
other
I've never seen anybody getting in our
this is and that's what's different
about bars I think that's one of the
points that I brought up in the the
testimony the other day was you know we
may have had what 300 combat veterans
packed into a club we could not have
done that in an establishment serving
alcohol and I was a peaceful night it
would not have happened yeah it was
packed I have I have a pass with alcohol
and we don't get along very well so if
it weren't at a place that served
alcohol there's way less likely of a
chance that I would have gone yeah and a
lot of these guys it's the same way you
know these these veterans especially you
know they they've self medicated with
alcohol before in their lives they've
self medicated with pills all these
things are harmful to them they hurt
them they hurt them they're for their
families they hurt their their friends
bodies but but this it doesn't it brings
them back inside society it brings back
into this community that we can sit
there and help each other and take care
of one another like we should we got to
become friends and hang out guys real
good with words there I think the first
time I met everybody in this group the
first time Oh kabuki I met you at a
cannabis cup you gave me some of that
delicious banana yeah but these awesome
Steve and I met here at the can of
Canyon and I've met you at the event
last weekend yes yeah without the social
clubs I wouldn't be making all these
friends that I've got absolutely neither
this little educational support group
that we've got this is what smokes like
it might event there was guys that
haven't come out of isolation over a
year they came out the Medicaid and they
were stacked deep you know 50 almost 55
people at times
in that little Club and that little
nobody freaked out everybody was under
good medication the pts guy PTSD you
guys you could see they were ready to
leave you know some of them stayed the
entire night though
yes great it stayed the entire night
that I know for a fact have severe
problems with crowds they were there the
entire night and they they they were
dedicated to it they they loved the fact
that we were having that event that so
many other people around them had their
back they were giving out free food all
night which I thought was super awesome
my ass all day all night you know it's
this guy's we took care of it was a free
meatball sub or free huh yeah and it was
a free drink you know I could have gone
for the drink I survived my vegan home
it was a great event
there were POWs there there were every
type of military there and then there
were dab kids there yeah there were
normal civilians there that you couldn't
tell what walk of life they can't have
what's funny is we we opened up the dab
bar from five to six I think we kept it
open till about 6:15 like we always you
know we asked first for the death have
you ever dad before do you take big dabs
little dabs you know we were trying to
be polite and make sure these guys
weren't overmedicating I was sending
them over there all day am i bad right
and these guys nobody made it through
you over two rounds I saw a couple of
guys choke pretty good oh yeah watch
them well they're like oh yeah we take
big dogs in like are you sure yeah Ryan
from uh the seed company remind me his
seed company to Ryan for pollination he
was giving out huge dabs he brought me
out a couple times that was this we take
a second and list off the sponsors and
the people that threw down stuff they
deserve an eye shadow absolutely if I
can go down list we got we got
nectar for the gods awesome
pollination yeah nectar for the gods
they don't need it like 55 cases and 25
lakhs in sweets
it was crazy thank you sir
full-size pool table like it was it was
awesome to see here we had them we have
Charlemagne extracts they donated the
galaxy email pollination also donated
the mothership
we had smokin iguana they donated that
that flow rig I think was really nice
the recycler absolutely let's see here
we had Rocky Mountain seed bank
we had TGA genetics we had the positive
distal positive creations thank you
boneyard yeah boneyard seeds Callie
Lucy seeds Jim Blues Brothers genetics
yes covert genetics genetics yep they
were man they donated a ton of packs to
let's see there was concentrated
genetics they donated he donated a whole
bunch of really interesting crosses the
cookies-and-cream
a lot of really neat stuff fox genetics
through the strong alliance their spouse
or and they they made those key pops by
hand they have the best cake balls i
still have a dozen in my room on my
table like that one because I saw the
way everybody was acting over them shout
out to Tammy Dominguez yeah we also had
neat Tuesday from cb1 analytics he came
out he was collecting stuff to get
tested who threw down the white somebody
threw down a growth yeah thank you that
was awesome you know let's give that guy
a shot
his name-o sure no no he won the
mothership and it was really cool
because he came out of nowhere and
seemed kind of shy no offense who's sort
of a goofy dude he also won a six-pack
yeah yeah that dude killed it yeah yes
he bumped into Steven and made friends
yeah - bounded right away and made
buddies of anyone it was really great to
see that dry sift the screens yeah I got
I got a squeeze myself yeah it was great
who was the guy next to your booth that
was DS T okay yeah I think it was pretty
much done by the time you got there man
I was bugging him all day for CBDT that
was a huge event that's a lot of
sponsors you got more let's see here I
feel like we had 16 20 uh officials they
donated four hundred and fifty hash caps
yeah they probably like an ounce to have
two ounces worth the cannabis
um grew all the weed you were donating
to people so that was now you put me on
the spot I got to Michael Lee louder for
ya he give away the Kim dog and the
gorilla glue for Stefan's in it he gave
me like an ounce and a half of Harlequin
and then me an ounce of my New York City
Diesel I won away some sherbert gave
away some grateful dog we rolled up
probably half an ounce and joints gave
those out and that was just a mix
between all my strains that you know I
usually carry around with me and I got
there and you walked up and didn't have
time to talk like a man good to see you
want a joint I was busy man I mean there
were so many people I wanted to talk to
that yeah I wanna show that day but I
could see it in your eye that you were
pretty much done by the time the event
was over oh yeah I was I was I mean that
was crazy that was the first event I've
ever done
I mean it went down pretty smooth I had
I did have a veteran that was upset the
way it was going down and I had him come
back and I talked to him and you know he
brought up a good point on some things
and so I hooked him up with the case
nutrients and was it like five or seven
packs of genetics soil and couple joints
[Music]
and that's the thing man like my my
organization I don't charge any
membership fees to these veterans it's
free they've already paid enough these
guys shouldn't have to pay a penny out
of their pocket so if somebody's a
veteran in the Colorado Springs area a
cannabis user and need some help how can
they get in touch with you they can get
in touch with me at the veteran farmers
Alliance at gmail.com you hear that you
guys get in touch Steven will help you
out we'll help you out
the veteran farmers Alliance will take
good care of you we'll invite you to our
next event you can hang out the next
event I set our like I'm you know and
you know here's another thing the
veteran farmers Alliance doesn't stop
there you know it takes organizations
that are out there and brings them all
together in one place so veterans have
an access to you know to care they they
can reach out to each organization that
has these specialties and use that you
know whatever pertains to them whatever
matches up with that organization in
them they use that and then once they're
done then come see the other
organization or they can use all of it
now they have this central network hub
of actual you know they can go to
outreach functions they can go to
different events they can go hiking they
go fishing and that's that's bringing
these organizations this is you know
this alternate therapy you know it's
just another way of helping these guys
heal and being able to offer them that
that's like nobody's ever been able to
do that everybody wants to make things a
competition yeah we're trying to save
lives we just need to all come together
and stop the BS yes and just say hey
we're gonna take care of these guys you
know what I can't take care of them but
you can you take them when you're done
with them I'll take care of you when I'm
done with them you go to that next
organization it's no competition we're
here to save lives let's drop this
piddly bullsh
and let's start doing what we need to do
veterans unite pretty much there you go
and the community that's the most
important point exactly
people need to see that the community
and veterans can come together and they
can integrate together and they can
socialize and there's no drama you know
you can't do that in a bar somebody says
the wrong thing you know somebody's joy
that oh man you got your someone's gonna
get something the face yeah you know and
but you go to a cannabis club and people
are able to sit back relax get some
education you know throw some knowledge
to these guys and and and maybe show
these guys what's really up with with
cannabis I mean some people go in there
they're scared they don't know what's
going on right you know I think a lot of
the clubs in town offer free entry for
veterans I know that we do the lazy lion
does the dab lounge so if there's
veterans that are out there that are
maybe um intimidated or nervous we're
very accepting very welcoming to
definitely veterans we definitely
appreciate all of your service this is
another thing you mentioned PTSD in the
in you know veterans are the public face
of it right now but they are we know
that we are really a tiny portion of the
people in society that actually have
PTSD the vast majority are actually
women and we may be fighting a fight for
our rights right now with PTSD but we
know that we're still fighting for the
people who are way too hurt too scared
too
angry too ashamed too afraid locked up
in their home somewhere we're fighting
for them too in order for their rights
to be recognized as well as ours
absolutely if you guys are intimidated
to come to a social smoke lounge the can
of Canyon has classy leather couches IR
comfortable the walls are closed oft
stylish hardwood floors we did we did
yeah houki and I'm a great key and
Steven met here this is what it's all
about yeah community building community
here and the place is classy you guys
it's clean it's super clean handicap
accessible restroom it's a great place
so don't be afraid come check it out
it's not it's not like a bar it's
well-lit the music's not too loud we can
Con conversate we can have conversation
Camille says it's real it's real let's
go within conversation here yeah let's
get it together we're dictionary don't
be shy come hang out I don't feel like
if you're new at smoking if you if
you're not a dad kid if you're not into
the whole scene we'll help you out I'll
give you your first a bow make you choke
I'll help you out
teach you how to use the rig oh you know
absolutely why'd you get you yeah we get
their bottles of water on the shelf over
here you'll be well taken care of don't
be afraid and other than that there's no
legal place for people to congregate and
consume so if you want to have somewhere
in smoke other than hanging out in the
car behind some building or something or
be public which we're technically
legally not allowed to do and you know
to be respectful of others you know I
don't feel the need for others to smell
my medicine and that's just me being
considerate but I also as a patient and
there's someone who's over the age of 21
recreationally don't have a lot of safe
places to go you know and not everyone
works in the industry or has made their
lifestyle around everything that we do
so in those moments were a patient or a
normal record herb occasional
recreational user might want a safe
place to enjoy cannabis what are we
gonna do if these places aren't around
the fact is is that if they pass laws
banning these types of establishments
they're gonna push people out into their
public spaces and who wants to smell
weed wherever they go yeah nobody wants
to smell weed wherever they go well
everyone has to go
people breathe exactly there's a large
majority people out there who probably
are gonna want to smell weed in the
public parks why do you give people bars
so they won't sit on a public park bench
somewhere such a great point I'm a
cannabis consumer I'm a breeder I'm all
about the cannabis life but I do have a
daughter that I don't hide her from
cannabis I don't hide cannabis from her
she knows what cannabis is she has not
attracted to the smell of it at all but
I don't think that anybody should have
to be at the park with their child and
explain what those guys over there doing
my daughter about that anybody's sure I
should decide when that conversation
yeah absolutely yeah keep that in mind
you guys know code a bit at the park
yeah those guys I completely agree I
have a daughter
very much feel the same way you know
right you know it's funny I was in City
Council me and I looked up I was like
how many liquor stores are there in
Colorado Springs hmm 104 we said how
many bars are there in our space 188 Wow
but 15 cannabis clubs Oh everybody loses
their [ __ ] it's kind of like when they
did the whole caregiver act it's not
even 1% of the people that grow in
Colorado are caregivers did they sneak
something in at that City Councilor
residential plan countess 12 plants
twelves yeah so a huge problem with that
in the fact that the I have a large
concentration of pediatric patients here
that they're not even epilepsy for the
most part their cancer patients they
Supply on it they rely on a heavy supply
of Dino THC heavy material and 12 plants
sometimes doesn't even cut 60 days of
medicine for them depending on what
they're working with you know most of
these guys are you know they're not
commercial growers they're not you know
they're modestly growing organically and
getting you know decent yields but
these parents can do a lot better with
some you know with more decent numbers
but restricting it to 12 I feel is just
it's gonna cause caregivers a lot more
headaches it's gonna cause parents who
are trying to grow themselves because
they can't go to dispensaries to get
what they need because they might not
have it or whatever the case is I just
feel that it's unfair and very unjust
yeah just about to say it seems like
time and time again it kind of feels
like we're not getting what we voted for
yeah absolutely yeah it's I feeling the
medical market away and forcing
everybody to go shop at the dispensary
they want the caregivers and they want
all of the tax money they do they was a
defense ruse they're actively pushing
for that and there are senators who are
trying to take away home grow as we
speak this this year actually I saw some
language off of I'm gonna go ahead and
call her out senator Conte her desk that
wanted to limit all caregivers and
patients in the state to six plants
maximum and this would not only affect
individuals but it would affect
structures so that an apartment complex
complex would have a maximum of six
plants and that'll come in the same
apartment building exactly a felony
that's so I you know thankfully we
managed to get that language removed
from that bill but there are a lot of
issues like this that are coming up that
are coming from from the industry
they're they're being actively lobbied
for by recreational and and some medical
facilities to ones that are joint
medical record to eliminate medical
rights and push everybody into the
recreational market and a lot of those
dispensary owners have issues with clubs
like this because they think that it's
going to ruin their business as it yen
no not that we've noticed it's still
growing
yeah our shop is still open this place
is still open and every one of the
business owners that I know they are all
happy for wanting regulation they're all
for licensing none of these people that
I know that run these clubs have an
alter motive to take money from any
establishment but to provide a service
for people that is genuinely needed and
that's my honest two cents I don't work
for any of these clubs I you know visit
them from time to time and that's just
honestly how I feel here every time I'm
here I don't mention I'm coming and
you're here hey man what can I say I did
and I forgot [ __ ] I'm sorry
take a dad it'll come back to you yeah
there's a black cherry Kim live resin on
the table which by the way it tastes
fantastic thank you thank you it's tasty
I bred it we grew it over at the green
and healthy garden and then our friends
at turf X blasted that so shout out to
the whole crew there yeah energy you've
got a lot to say about the 12 plant
don't you I'm very upset over this I I'm
basically allergic to every single
prescription pill out there the one I'm
not allergic to a lot a lot of listeners
might not be familiar okay so on April
11th of 2008 I was doing route clearance
as a combat engineer in Sadr City and I
was scientific with Sadr City it's in
Iraq okay
right right yes sorry it's not Colorado
we were ambushed and v IE d that went
off blue a 13 inch hole into my vehicle
and blue a 5 inch hole into my back
causing my my hip to be shattered my
pelvis to be broken and my spine to be
shifted forward causing me to have so a
little bit of spinal injury head over
200 pieces of shrapnel in me and took
about three and a half months for the
wound closed up very lucky to be alive
absolutely thank you I'm very happy
Thanks and for the listeners it looks
like if you took a normal dudes back and
it excuse me no you're good you can I
I'm a big dude I could put my fist in
the hole that's exactly how I described
to fill the hole with putty would take
your fist
my wife she jokes she's like I need to
slap a little bond alright alright but
you know the whole 12 plant count thing
like I mean I consume so much I ingest a
smoke I dab I use topicals
you know for them to cut me down to 12
when I have a 65 plant count is asinine
it's it's just with they're not doctors
there's no way for them to judge who
needs what I mean the standard whatever
they're not medical doctors I spent
three hours with my medical doctor going
over my plant program failure rates
pesticide rates clone failure race you
know successful harvest you know like
fan failures light failures and you know
you go over that and then we're like
okay we have finished product this is
what's usable this was is usable and
then for City Council to have no
training in the medical field to to not
even understand what a plant count means
to somebody to not even understand what
you know what level of a grower they're
you know is is just
forgiveable it's just an insult and I'm
not gonna buy the wall because I paid
for that extended plant count I have
proven every right why I need that plant
count and they are not gonna take that
what it should stand up in court
oh absolutely you know I think it has
before you're gonna file a lawsuit
against the city phone rings yes sir
will your lawyer come to court with you
good because I have over 6,000 pages of
medical documents that can prove to them
that in every single manner they are
wrong you've got better SOPs than some
dispensaries I've gone to taking and
your planning is better than some major
grows in this state I just appreciate me
and I just I take this seriously this is
my medicine this is what keeps me alive
can people follow you on Instagram you
wanna give up absolutely yes my my
Instagram name is Triceratops he's got
some great pictures of grateful dog he
does is on Instagram he's got a hell of
a great grow absolutely one of my
favorite strains thank you well thank
you very much yeah I would not have met
these guys if it weren't for a club so
I'm very grateful there's nothing crazy
going on nobody's slamming in the walls
nobody's arguing or fighting there's no
drop I've got a question for Camille but
she just took a big old dad so I'm gonna
give her half a say you ready all right
all right
have you ever had anybody act up or try
to fight in their fight yeah no so the
craziest thing that happened was um we
like to keep a certain atmosphere for
members it's very important to us so
occasionally we'll have a member come in
who is intoxicated and in that moment
you know we try and scooch amount as
fast as possible but occasionally they
will get into the main lounge just by
people exiting so there's been one
instance where we had to escort someone
off the the premises but it was fairly
easy they went they went kind of
willingly so that helped and and they
were drunk too so
no we just had to deal with a couple
drunk people that completely proved my
point
social lounge or the drunk people that
showed up
I can't really appreciate you is more
than once we've had members kind of
bring something that someone has left up
to the counter kabuki is notorious yes
my wallet on the counter here earlier
and it was promptly returned to me it
was yeah you called members members this
is a place where people look out for
each other the City Council meeting they
said it wasn't safe that these are safe
[Music]
city council comes and what's really
frustrating is all of it Matt was
talking is it okay if I call you Matt I
do perfect okay
Matt was talking about KITT repay and
can't repay is how you said pronounce it
like yeah met his name although sorry
thank you it's a weird name it is weird
name so they've been working on this
this license for the clubs and um there
there came out and said nothing's made
in a vacuum and that's very true and
what's frustrating is it feels like city
council does not have that mentality at
all they can't seem to grasp or
understand a few different sides whether
it be veterans people who consume on a
recreational level or even just business
owners they just don't seem to want to
listen to what we have to say
but ya can't repay an Jonathan singer
are doing some really awesome
progressive stuff with the licensing and
trying to make these clubs here to stay
which I can appreciate but Colorado
Springs a whole nother story right yeah
we have the same issues in Pueblo it
feels like our city council hears us and
we're like we want social clubs and they
turn around they talk to each other and
they they go guess what happens do they
just like yeah have these conversations
right in front of you and it's insane
aren't they there to represent us aren't
we supposed to be telling them what they
want they provide it and then 200 people
show up and they say we want this and
two people say no and the whole City
Council can say oh yeah no I did that
you were saying it's it's just act
yeah it's incredibly upsetting to me so
sorry if I'm for a lack of words at the
moment but yeah that is infuriating to
see that and I mean it's like four
people come up wait is bad and they're
spitting out facts that you could go on
the internet and it's like yeah that's
been there reading [ __ ] off a piece of
paper not looking anyone in the eye then
walking out of the room right George
it's in its stack because they had the
people that were four against all go up
first it's not like you know normal
sessions everybody's allowed to voice
their opinion whether for or against
Cooley at the same time that way you can
hear both sides know it's they said
their thing and they got to leave
because they're like yeah we're not
gonna make these old people stay and
that's who it was the people that are
complaining we're over 60 and you know
what that's not cool man you made a very
very firmness propaganda exactly and a
lot of people that were making these
complaints or more about the opposition
of what happened after we voted in him
in 64 then about the club's themselves
and I feel like that distinction was
completely lost in translation if yeah
most of them like they would say things
like my I live next door to an apartment
complex and the people there they smoke
they smoked marijuana x' and they they
they grow the marilyn
and they vent it right out into the open
and it had nothing to do with the actual
consumption clubs whatsoever they were
complaining about the the ancillary
effects of amendment 64 they're just
stuck in the mud and if they have a
problem with it then they should take it
up with the voters who actually voted
amendment 64 into our state constitution
Constitution right now people call it
marijuana's CBD I don't like it when
people PluralEyes waters drivers anymore
so these clubs are important you guys we
need to do everything we can to
absolutely hustle to what can we do for
the next eight years is there anything
we can do to sway them on that one or is
that a permanent thing here in Springs
okay
so right now what I can say is that
there are petitions at a lot of the
clubs here in town to kind of what's the
word recall yeah
the ban so you can get out there you can
put your name on the list
no let your city know that this is not
something you're down for and that's
what we can do initially there's an
online petition as well Stephen says
Steve and Camille are politely sharing a
mic so sometimes Stephen gets cut off
here I was looking for the petition he's
searching in his phone and since I'm not
a Colorado Springs resume am I able to
sign that petition yes all right so I
will sign that for you guys thank you
map webelo residents oh yeah I guess
that's awesome well looky you're gonna
be a blow guy
sorry should have said that on the show
no you're good I don't give a [ __ ] come
find me in Pablo the podcast more
frequently yeah and so my friend who
just totally off topic but he just got
300 acres in Pueblo and totally
dedicated to his CBD craft so I'm gonna
be doing a little bit of consulting out
there with him as well so be some fun
stuff if you guys need help I know the
guy for you he's been on the podcast
several times sweet [ __ ] yeah awesome
sweet alright okay so we got this
website looks like the website is geo
petition GE oh oh go petition I'm sorry
go petition g-o-p e TI tion calm and
then just search stop social club ban
and it'll come up as well jump on your
computer go spend that time signing a
petition you have to do is open the show
notes and click it if he's got a phone
tap on the on my face if you're looking
at my face on your face or on your
itunes tap on my face it'll spin around
and show you showed us there's a link in
there click on that link it'll take you
to this petition you do it second spin
your face website it'll be in the show
notes also go to the website go to the
girl from your heart podcasts tab click
on the newest episode will be right
there in the show notes there will be
able to sweep your lazy you won't have
to type anything in will hook you up
want everybody in Colorado to sign it if
you're a computer nerd figure out some
way to set up your computer and proxy in
yes and change your IP address every
time and just do it billion times
absolutely I didn't say that on the air
hire some kid in Malaysia to do it on
Fiverr yeah that's fine I'm not gonna
argue with you
also in canvas to me after that whole
city council people are talking about
running for office now oh yeah yeah
someone needs to kabuki yeah okay the
problem with that is
a lot maybe in Pueblo but here's the
thing what's happening in the Springs
right now yes we obviously need a voice
we need a voice on that council but I
think it also starts with maybe removing
if these people who are supposed to
represent us won't listen then maybe
they shouldn't be representing us and
that's what it comes down to their job
so maybe getting that rotten apple out
of the bunch and trying to progressively
put someone who will voice all of our
concerns and I mean yeah we do need to
find someone and I wish I had the time
but I know there are much more people
out there much more qualified to do
something like that
and I would willingly back them a
hundred percent foxtrax run see with
ijen eggs and just me as a person as an
advocate and I know Thursday's yeah sure
why not someone's gotta someone's got to
teach them but that's the thing there
needs to be education these guys have no
education they're basing all of their
decisions on their emotions and you know
the 50 year old arguments the most
outdated medical information exactly and
and what's happening is when you have
maybe seven people come up and say no
and you have over 200 people willing to
testify that they want something you
should be supporting the people that
look that want it I mean that's what the
people want or it's not it's fair it's
just it's it's insane to me that you can
not even just hear or try to shelve it
to make two hundred people I mean was it
less than twelve people that came up
against it I mean it sees eleven okay
yeah so less than a dozen people - like
200 people in a room motion batteries so
that was about 30 minutes yeah testimony
five hours all right yeah Wow five hours
of testimony and even after all that you
know you disrespect other veterans you
don't even acknowledge that you're a
veteran and then you sit there and you
have these smart ass looks like wasn't
one of them nodding off yeah yeah yeah
and someone did because that would have
made me fear so to throw a shoe at that
dude
that's it's ridiculous guys crying yeah
your job is to stay awake this is your
job do you mean yeah and they're all
over 6000 most of them are only 65 you
know what's past if you're over 50s time
to leave office isn't there the right to
redo the entire meeting since somebody
fell asleep there was a member not
present 488 they didn't even represent
deaf people there no have a person that
is sign language who's good with the
legal [ __ ] in Springs help us out here
maybe that meeting can be totally redone
since a city council member took a nap
during the meeting maybe we need a redo
on that whole thing thank you since
there wasn't something there for deaf
people so that they could hear and
participate as well maybe we need a redo
maybe we need to try that one over
absolutely to see how this second vote
will go on what's the ones the date
right okay can the public come to that
one again yeah they're not gonna
actually allow public comment protests
actually is that our best bet right now
is to call like a massive amount of
people and show people how unhappy we
are but I still don't think that that
would actually sway their vote but it
would at least show them what they're
doing is wrong and we're starting to
assemble yeah exactly that we are active
and that we can we can actually change
the face politics in Colorado Springs we
can get them on out of office isn't it
I'm sorry go ahead
I've just seen it done in Denver you
know I've I've hiked up to the Capitol
plenty times to stop this [ __ ] for lack
of better words they've so many bills
that they've tried to pass with children
not being able to medicate on school
grounds them trying to CPS trying to say
that any parent with the red card was
you know basically you know in drink
engaging their child you know if they
had yeah just a whole bunch of [ __ ] that
we've had to go through so I feel like
in the springs first of all educating
people about what's going on just like
we did in Denver
and bring making people aware of
everything and then like I like Matt
said getting people together to actively
show that we can be the face of change
we do need that down here these clubs
are essential limiting that plant count
is absolute [ __ ] I've been getting
phone calls non-stop from these parents
that are freaking out about that and
patients that are freaking out because
they're actively growing anywhere from
you know whatever you know 24 to 36 or
sixty plants you know whatever the case
is pending on their needs without a
problem without there ever being
overages or stacks and sometimes they
still come showed up for their medicine
when it comes time to be processed even
with that many plants depending on what
they grow and how they grow so I just
think it's insane for an Olympic city to
talk about limiting what patients can
and cannot grow and how they can it just
upsets me so much that that also wasn't
talked about enough that wasn't you know
DEA the focus on the clubs is equally
important but I feel like they're
sliding one in with the other and that's
horseshit and that needs to be addressed
more and I feel like within the group of
everyone that's for the clubs and and I
don't think you know people are aware
about these plan counts if I if we bring
both these groups of people together
that have this the same invested
interest I think we'd have a greater
showing and that's just you know my
personal opinions so I'm more than happy
to reach out to the people that I know
that are really coming at me and are
distraught about them you know cutting
down the residential plant count and
obviously you know we know all the
veterans and all our friends and all our
colleagues that are in this business and
are for these clubs they're doing
amazing things in the community let's
get together this is the only way we're
gonna make a change is to put any little
thing aside and come together so we can
actually show them the real numbers and
the real faces of people that they're
affecting do you think we'd be so bold
to show them give them maybe a preview
of what's gonna happen if they ban these
clubs on the 22nd I say we get a
thousand people out there by City
Council and just smoke it up let's show
them what happened yeah massive civil
disobedience
it works yes I mean that might be what
it takes to show them I mean we won our
clubs we don't want to do this but maybe
this is an example we need where does
that lead us and how okay so and that
was something I don't know if it was you
or somebody else brought a point of
about Manitou and then being in the same
El Paso County and then allowing
recreational cannabis do they have clubs
in Manitou or now okay so I just don't
understand how you're going to allow
these different assets you know these
even with medical big Medical
dispensaries we have attend down here in
the springs we have a ton of places or
medical and recreational patients can go
and take me taken care of and then where
they go okay that's just the truth of it
that's that option why are you setting
up your pro the police chief I mean just
to not to jump on my note but he came in
the room and basically said this is this
is not enforceable so and that being
said that's coming from the words of the
police chief of our city basically
telling us that there's really no way
for them to be able to enforce this
didn't he say he put in 900 hours to
bring a single kid to college and
whatever it was and our tax money like
I'm just saying like stupid thousand
hours divided by 40 our other cops
probably yeah we're work week how many
cops was that for how much Thole yeah
yeah for one club citizens of Colorado
Springs you paid for that
yeah no charges brought nine thousand
hours at a cops wage so that's what you
guys paid for them to come and hang out
at one of these clubs with us try to
mingle yeah and they still don't
understand it probably came here and got
stoned how God had a great ass time
models oh yeah watch cartoons and eat
pizza but yeah so that's also it creates
a little confusion because you have the
council saying one thing police chief is
telling you another citizen saying a
completely different thing yeah no one's
being heard
you have a couple yeah and if the police
isn't gonna enforce it and the citizens
obviously want it it's only a matter of
time putting that wall breaks and we
just keep pushing forward yep there you
go well I have a question for Camille if
now that they've done this they're
giving you eight years to recoup your
funds and there's no regulation doesn't
that reopen the black market can it I
wasn't gonna go there encourages the
Craigslist seller it encourages um deals
going on behind in parks behind schools
and parking lots that's what that
encourages now we have tourists
like I said jumping on Craigslist
looking for 420 weed marijuana these are
things that were brought up at the
meeting for the licensing with Carrie
pay and Jonathan singer so they're just
not thinking it through like at all huh
it's all about the outside image even
though you can see through it it's all
about what it brings to other cities or
other businesses that may want to come
to this city it's a very military town
there's a lot of military influence here
and an Church influence and true yeah
both yeah I mean are weird kind of a
area they want to keep that image they
don't want to look like Pueblo or Denver
they want to have that clean military
churchy feel yeah unfortunately the data
goes the other way after they legalized
marijuana soldiers piss and hot actually
went down so they went in the opposite
direction now that it's legal it's no
fun yeah they'll do their yeah and
that's how most veterans that I know
even felt being out of state out of
medical states is you know in do their
time or you know they serve their tour
whatever the case those and come back
and medicate and be done with the whole
thing girl on their beard and be happy
you know
when you come to Colorado yeah you know
why [ __ ] up while you're working you
know those if your employee says you
can't and obviously that's the rule of
the game if that's how you're getting
your money you know if that's what's
paying for your school why jeopardize it
out trip I know more people think about
it that way than the other but at the
same time that's also asking someone not
to medicate and that's a very hard
choice that people have to make to make
all those decisions so you know it's a
double-edged sword on that you know but
to that thought of this place being a
church heavy military town
I know more housewives and girls I know
that consume cannabis you know that's
such a closeted thing in this community
it's really funny weeds the did the
biggest growing demographic of weed
smokers is about 55 nice elderly people
are flocking to Colorado in order to
retire because they want to smoke weed
that's great to become members you are
definitely older just kind of want the
experience ask questions like well what
does a gram look like what is a DAB what
what are people saying this thing called
salvia sativa what does that mean
educating these people what they really
just want to experience it for the first
time like that's awesome
it's great to have people like you here
to invite those people into the
community and welcome and show them how
it's done
yeah with those people are profoundly
grateful that these places exist
you know they mean and it showed that
the other night I mean a lot of them
broke down into tears otherwise you got
people that just bought their first
medicine or their first cannabis their
first AB they're in their car so first
marijuana
have you guys seen that there's a
documentary or the dudes light in the
bottom of the pipe you don't know what
you're doing you're brand new I get the
glass hot and somebody here will
definitely show you how between going
into a dispensary and talking to some
chick that has big tits and there's no
education on what strain does what or
this or that she's just there oh yeah
that falls up to management you know and
they're right into that regard
I will say I love the Springs that there
are a lot of places here that have good
educated but tenders now you go into a
club like this it's different yeah and
there's also another issue I mean if you
get you get a 21 year old kid you know
would you rather him go to a bar where a
bartender can sit there and monitor him
and then cut him off when he's had
enough or would you rather him go to a
liquor store and go home with a bottle
of vodka and get himself stupid drunk
and ended up destroying something or
getting behind the wheel and destroying
somebody yeah I'd rather him be at a
cannabis club not drinking if he were my
son sitting on the couch collection
conversation listening to laid-back
music and I see people do that these
clubs members might not offer whatever
the case is none of these club owners
wake them up early to leave or you know
it's not about a turnkey spot thing and
they rest there comfortably till they're
comfortable enough to wake up and you
know they make sure they're okay they're
hydrated every club I've been to has
literally had that mentality and I point
that out to people because people don't
know and they assume that it runs like
something that's not I like to take huge
dabs and to sometimes when I take a
giant dab here before I can blow it all
the way out somebody's got a bottle of
water in my face like you're gonna need
this bro you never have to cough more
than once or twice before someone's got
water for you and they're free think so
yeah if you're thirsty you need a couch
and it
it's a great sport here for you the
mixture of people is always great here -
oh yeah definitely
I got dreadlocks down to my butt and I'm
sitting next to a veteran so it's
awesome like I love it definitely
- dreads some veterans a guy from Miami
yep our new friend over here this is
honestly I've done several podcasts away
from my home studio this is my favorite
that I've done on another friend this is
awesome thank you guys to the listeners
when it comes time bill let's be
proactive it's time if you're in
Colorado and you do not have rules on
social clubs it's time for you or your
nerdy friend that's involved in the
politics you know who he is he's in
every group is that one guy Mike that's
you in Pueblo bro get you guys together
and start making rules for social smoke
clubs in your city before they get bad
be proactive put that out there I don't
know exactly the steps on how to do that
but one of your friends does knows how
to create an initiative knows how to get
a petition started they know how to get
it going it that's probably you and your
group right Matt exactly veterans for
natural rights basically exist push
policy we defend all kinds of natural
individual rights such as the right to
medicate yourself the way you please
also veterans rights any other
individual right that has to do with
freedom and liberty but right to safe
access medicine safe access of medicine
is is the primary one that we lobby on
here in Colorado because it is such a
big issue here this is a new industry
it's forming and it's the Wild West you
know there's there's no real regulation
it's being crafted right now we're
setting policy and everyone's eyes are
on us we are the revolution yes to be a
part of it thanks for standing up for it
with us well it's I'm proud to do so
thank you thank you so now also if you
are in a state that has not gone legal
with cannabis yet start if you're
writing the rules to create medical
and/or recreational cannabis in your
state be sure to include these social
clubs
make sure they can be open make sure
that they exist make sure they're
regulated in a fair way make it I
recommend that you make it tour these
places have a grow tour these social
clubs have a grow attached to them that
can provide the product to this place
would be ideal in my opinion or at least
a private road right that has like an
overabundance and they want to offload
their their extra they should be able to
do that I mean we should be able to
stimulate and stabilize the economy in
every shape in way and manner I mean it
only makes sense to do that and by
blocking that we're just blocking you
know really good medicine that otherwise
could be shared all over the city
how many potholes did you guys hit on
the way over here oh [ __ ] yeah right
swerve every six months in Colorado
Springs because of the potholes if we
could kind of do proper things with the
tax money yeah enter a proper tax
revenue places like this we could fix
some of the damn pothole pothole could
be filled with Bob yep fill those
potholes with pot money let's do it what
it's for I want to give a shout out to
Rhode Island I was told there in Rhode
Island the dispensaries are going to
open without grows attached and the
grows will be done by guys like you and
I that know how to grow and we can take
it to the dispensaries and legally sell
it to them you do three three sheets
paper you get a test and then you can go
that every last grower the top-notch
growers in Colorado they they're not a
dispensaries no they're independent guys
guys who are running their own grows and
they're growing the best medicine in the
entire state in the entire country in
the entire world
all the best growers I know are
independent growers or breeders or have
not working with
yeah and it's very rare I may be you I
guess like I'm Jeff you're the first I'm
trying I run a small grow I've got a
very small grow that I breed a lot in
mostly I'm trying to bring that quality
to this large facility I'm running the
green and healthy wellness grow now 85
flowering lights I see why the quality
falls off a little bit it's a lot of
stuff to manage it's a new environment
you can't just throw up a 14,000 BTU air
conditioner a couple of blowers a fan
going yeah yeah I put in tons of air
conditioning you have to have ducting
for days there are miles of PVC tubing
in that grow I use one room uses a
thousand gallons of water a day if I mix
one of those tanks off of it imagine the
amounts of nutrients I'm mixing there's
one thousand seven hundred and fifty
milliliters of one nutrient that goes in
there and I'm using five or six
different things if I mess one of those
up imagine the catastrophe trying to
bring that level of quality to that
playing field it's a true challenge not
a lot of people don't take any of those
things into account you brought that up
I see why the small boutique grows are
preferred and beneficial it's hard to
get this stuff going on in a big
facility like that yeah okay TIFF there
I promise for sure most of it solo right
I can take probably 78 percent credit
for it in the first run at the new grow
the ladies helped a lot shot it to
damsel and Haley they did give me a lot
of help John hunt is in there as often
as he can and then I have a crew of a
few dudes that come occasionally and do
if I need things that I just can't
handle by myself they do D leafing so I
could take like 75 80 percent credit for
it yeah and hunt runs a lot of the
bedroom for me nice that's nice you have
an owner that's involved yeah they're
involved in helping me out but I touch
every single plant every single of
course every single day I'm the first
one in last one out awesome yeah that's
great man open and close the gate every
day I love what you do they round keep
supporting thank you you get to dab be a
black cherry Kim live resident
did I'm probably gonna probably gonna
take another one we're gonna wrap up
this podcast this is one of my favorite
podcasts I've ever done so I want to
thank everybody for joining me thank you
thank you Jeff I hope to get everybody
back Fox you and I I want to do a show
here we're gonna get a lot of questions
we just need to get with Camille and
you're co-owner and set it damn we'll
try to get what's the maximum capacity
here 40 names we're gonna turn in 49
people in this [ __ ] try we'll invite
people on Facebook and we'll do
Instagram invites and well Tom I think
we could do that oh yeah we'll sit here
in these couches and we'll talk about
cbdu for a little bit and then we'll let
anybody in the audience it has a
question grab a microphone and ask
questions and you and I can answer grow
questions Yamini questions live on the
show
that'd be fun it'll be great we'd
appreciate the space of course any time
a bunch of stuff to give away that day
alright thanks again everybody for
coming Camille thanks for letting us do
this of course thanks for having me this
may be fun I hope to do it again I can't
wait I'm gonna get you on another show
with Maddy yeah shout out to both of
them they're both awesome ladies in the
cannabis industry big shout out to
Jessica
yes and that are educated on what
they're doing
very yeah I just out there shaking it
that's a girl to me - I love you all
Brittany Wagner I think he's talking to
you
maybe all right we're gonna wrap up this
podcast does anybody got any final words
well you got a microphone in your hand
if people are listening thank you Jeff
for having us again that was super
awesome yeah can't wait for the next one
awesome
we're gonna wrap it up like that I'll be
back to finish up the show you guys
hashtag run CBD oh yeah I want to thank
you guys for listening to that long
episode I also want to thank my new
friend Matt Oh to faint kabuki Jay Fox
and run CBB I want to thank Stephen
Duffy no and the veteran farmers
Alliance I also want to send a huge
thank you to Camille into the canna
Canyon for letting me do my podcast in
the club make sure you guys check out
the can of Canyon if you're over 21 stop
in take some dabs with us I would love
to meet you there if you have any
questions or if you'd like to hear
something on the podcast send me an
email let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear what you've
got to say if you've got a product you'd
like me to review if you'd like to
sponsor the show send me an email again
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I'd love it if you find me on some
social media follow me on Twitter it's
at gfy each podcast find me on Facebook
it's simply grow from your heart podcast
I would love to interact with you I
would also love to know what you think
of the podcast go to iTunes go to iTunes
store search for the girl from your
heart podcast find the review section
give me a 5 star rating and type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I will read your comment
on a future episode I would love to hear
from you guys that's all I've got for
you this week once again I want to
dedicate this episode to my good friend
Zack Zack I won't miss you forever
[ __ ] cystic fibrosis I'm out for this
week I'll be back in 7 days with another
episode shot it's my ninja Spence and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]