[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 124 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated Abbot
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross
the Jeff want to thank you guys again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank-you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to cat coop and the entire mystic
roots crew Dan thank you for joining me
you guys sitting at the table this week
I got our good buddy white Mike is back
thanks for joining me dude and also in
front of me felt lovely the traveling
stoner also known as what is Lindsay
thank you for joining me thank you for
having me you guys we were joking we
were coughing we've had a bunch of dabs
or hit me serious sidecar rig with a
bunch of turf X trying to kill it or a
black cherry Kim hash my throat's gonna
sound like [ __ ] for a couple of minutes
here right with me it's gonna be alright
because this is gonna be a very fun
episode in my opinion our friend Lindsay
are the travelling stoner she's been on
the show a couple of times here a couple
of rowdy episodes with a bunch of boys
she sent me a text message with a whole
bunch of questions about politics and
the upcoming elections and things and I
thought the best thing we could do is
get white Mike over here white Mike is
kind of my political expert me if I have
a politics question Mike is the guy that
I call everybody needs one of us yeah
yeah I made a new a new politics friend
also in Springs I meant the guy that
does your job in spring so shout out to
Matt it was good meeting you the other
day at the canna Canyon thanks for being
on the podcast a nice job Matt I enjoy
be on the show dude if you two got in
the room together the cannabis
opposition would be in some deep [ __ ]
I'm dying to get to the candy canyon
after that episode yeah shut us to the
county canyon you guys if you haven't
been there go check it out it's at 1507
Colorado Boulevard in Colorado
make sure you tell the lovely Camille
that Rasta Jeff sent you to the candy
Canyon I love the canna Canyon it's my
literal favorite place to go in Colorado
Springs my my grow is my home away from
home
but then when I have to go away from one
of those two I go to the candy cane yin
and Terp out when you do it right it's
easy to support right and they do it
right at the candy candy Canyon the
place is classy as [ __ ] so uh we're
talking about this email that the
traveling stoners sent we got Mike here
I thought that it would be fun if I kind
of handed the should be the host will it
be the co-host today the unofficial
co-host will pass you over that you want
me to move - how do you I was into a
little lower we'll play this perfect
some microphones on the show guys okay
there you go
welcome to the the backstage view their
show comes with a few technical
difficulties yeah my headphones aren't
working earlier there's the I'm gonna
wiggle this and see if it cuts in is it
coming as it coming no you're screwed so
there's a piece that I bought a guitar
Center it's the live wire advantage ha0
for four channel stereo headphone amp
[ __ ] that thing don't buy one of those
if you've got one get a replace cuz it's
gonna crap out on you and cause you
problems it almost blew Mike's head up
the other couple of minutes yeah my ears
are still ringing a little bit from that
volumes like those I apologize it was
you as the gear buddy as long as you
know that on purpose
I need your ears for this [ __ ] don't buy
the piece he said yes nobody sucks I
give it a thumbs down five rotten leaves
alright so we're gonna get to some of
these questions that Lindsay that typed
very professionally and sent to me in a
very nice PDF this is marvelous so
they've been scratched down in a
notebook for two weeks so I'm glad they
look marvelous you got a nice little go
ahead and this is my friend Lindsey also
known as the traveling stoner make sure
you follow her on Instagram she does a
periscope she's a great chick you'd like
to watch her I'm sure she's fun she's
got tattoos and takes that dad's got
some dreadlocks shout-out to Chris for
putting in the dreadlocks Mike looks a
little offended bit no I'm just
wondering if we can be on the team this
early yeah okay the only reason you're
raised cuz see I wouldn't know I've had
long hair before but I never went red
since she's had to deal with some social
stigma already she's been harassed by
some oh yeah it's not when they went in
I only asked as I watched what happened
when dude got the dreadlocks warm for
like two festivals and then cut them out
I watched the community revolt around
them throwback to cut I don't know where
that came from that happened years ago
with college but yeah I would just seem
like a good question to hit you with
Mike's comfortable on the show now yes
he was comfortable on the mic he's like
I'll say anything right like I'm yeah
there's something about this table I'm
possibly something about Debs it's both
it's both yes yeah I've already gotten
some serious negativity about them some
serious hate so I'm already gonna call
myself team dreadlock do it it's
official yep all right so I'm gonna kind
of hand you the hosting situation here
let you uh ask Mike some questions
I will definitely interject and drive
the show but I'm gonna sit back and take
some dad's of some triangle killer from
Terp ex well you guys chat so listeners
let her know how she does send her some
tweets and send her something on
Instagram or on snapchat and make sure
you follow her on periscope and let her
know what you thought of her performance
here on the podcast all right it's all
yours young lady have fun cool
so this idea for this podcast actually
came from a trip coming over to Colorado
while I was moving here in December I
spent most of the trip listening to the
girl from your heart podcast and I thank
you and tell us where you came from
Florida so you know from Florida
Colorado and listen to the podcast yeah
we actually went up to North Carolina
first and then came over too so like we
had an extra long trip because it was
Christmas so we see my family in North
Carolina and then came over so like I
mean it was a nice break for a couple
days but yeah we definitely got a lot of
podcast listening in that's a lot of
podcast show a lot of stats moving for
me yeah I think that's my Scooby likes
you so much he's like I've heard this
guy's voice already like but yeah so uh
Chris and I weren't in Bobo blaster Co
and I were discussing about it the whole
time that you guys really needed to do a
show about the upcoming election and
that pro-marijuana people need to know
which candidate to vote for and which
one will actually help marijuana laws
get put in place instead of helping us
there you know making us take steps
backwards so yeah so a lot of my
questions here are about the upcoming
election so I guess my question to you
Mike is um what states look like they'll
be legalizing marijuana in the upcoming
election okay it's a little too early to
tell what the votes gonna look like come
November but we already know that a
number of states are gonna be voting on
legalization or we've got a good list of
states where there are major groups that
look like they've got a shot at getting
it on the ballot and in November or were
states where there's a legislative
effort to get it on the ballot in
November in those states or Arizona
California Florida Maine Massachusetts
Michigan Missouri Nevada Rhode Island
and Vermont may all be voting on
recreational marijuana this November
okay um States voting on just medical
Mississippi Missouri Nebraska North
Carolina in Ohio and that's a shitload
of states voting this November other
states could make the list there's still
plenty of time in most states for either
ballot initiative or for people to lobby
their legislators enough to get the vote
on the ballot in November this year wow
that is a lot of states actually I
wasn't expecting you to say that many
right that's why I had to make notes for
the first time I got mailed this list of
questions Jeff was talking about a
minute ago that nerdy part of my brain
got really excited and I was like this
is the show I've been wanting to do it
somebody did the landside wrecking the
other two paid a front and a back side
because I've got notes on each state's
effort to I just don't know how in depth
you want to go with this answer I mean
you can really give it to me that's fine
because I mean you know the Articles
that I want to write I wanted to do one
on each state so if you want to go
through the like just a brief thing on
each state that's totally cool with you
know I tried to avoid the subject but
you just said something that I've got to
address I'm gonna bust you out here she
said write articles let our listeners
know where those articles are going to
appear and who you represent yeah so
shout out to miss Mary Jane Coe because
I am the new intern blog writer for them
and I have been helping them get their
blog up and running and in production
I've been writing the articles and stuff
for them so shout out to miss Mary Jane
Coe and Madison and danam you know so
that that's where the articles will be
eventually and you're an intern yes you
don't get paid absolutely supporting the
community for free absolutely yes we all
got to do our part you guys yeah alright
I'll step back ice we were at which
states are voting on legalization and I
was just about to run through a brief
little know on each or at least the
little note that I made looking these up
this afternoon this list came out in
December or January and already it's
only March but there's already been time
for another state to make this list and
I think possibly for one to drop off of
it
but back when this was this official
list that I kind of stashed was
published Arizona
folks there's a group collecting
signatures they need 150,000 signatures
by July 7th to make the 2016 vote in
November um the initiative includes home
gross so from what I could gather
they're gonna have a Colorado style
system that includes home grow not all
the states that are looking to vote on
legalization have home grow each state
has its own initiative it's an issue its
initiative comes with its own rules
we just Ohio vote on legalization and
vote against it mainly because of those
special rules they would have had
legalization they could have been
shopping in weed stores but chose not to
because of who was gonna profit the most
from the production end of that industry
um so if it's written specifically for a
bunch of people in your state to make
money it's probably not gonna pass um
California could go either way
California never shied away from
shooting itself in the foot here they
led the way with medical in 96 and that
existing industry has often worked
against legalization efforts there's a
huge black market in California that
also works against the legalization
efforts and then there's all the anti
pop people in some of the major anti
marijuana groups in the country or based
in California and all of that doesn't
bode well for either of the initiatives
in California that are being circulated
for signatures right now I think the
Shawn Parker backed initiative is
already for sure on the ballot and I
know that there's at least one other one
looking to be on the ballot competing
with it in Florida two different groups
are collecting signatures right now one
for medical marijuana one for full
legalization both initiatives look
really popular um get out and find
signatures people find a place to sign
and make sure you vote in November here
yeah we came really close last year like
stupidly close and you know it's funny
like I have friends in Florida who would
just complain about the fact that it
didn't get legalized and I'd be like oh
well
like who did you vote for in the black I
didn't like what right what you're
you're upset right like you actually got
to get out on Election Day it's really
not that hard not at all if you think
your vote doesn't matter the only way
your vote doesn't matter is if you don't
vote absolutely your yeah just [ __ ]
voting so that's Florida Maine Maine you
guys might be voting on legalization the
article I found on Maine didn't list
whether it was legislative or a ballot
initiative it kind of made it sound like
it was already on the ballot in 2016 but
if you live in Maine you need to google
it Massachusetts legislative efforts are
underway for decriminalization that
would include legal possession so it
would be legal to possess a certain
amount of marijuana but it's just
decriminalization which means it's still
sold from a black-market no no taxes no
regulations no lab testing none of that
and there's a group in Massachusetts
looking to put full legalization on the
ballot and they're collecting signatures
in Michigan there's a group collecting
signatures for full legalization
including a 12 plant home grill which
will be double here in Colorado Michigan
folks I definitely look get out and find
a place to sign that petition Missouri
one groups collecting signatures for a
legalization effort they look pretty
good
but it's going to take people turning
out to vote for it in Nevada
legalization will be on the ballot those
folks in Missouri started sorry to jump
in there I know those folks in Missouri
shout-out to Daryl and his wife Trish
those are the folks running the movement
out there they went with them a couple
weeks ago
nice Rhode Island in Vermont
both have legislative efforts for
legalization underway and then I didn't
collect any detailed notes on the
medical efforts I'm surprised to see
Mississippi on there and Ohio still
reeling from that major loss last
November
it doesn't surprise me that they're
working on medical instead of another
Foley legalization effort yeah that's
those are the ones that are for sure
already have major legalization groups
or legislative efforts to legalize
marijuana if you heard your state on the
list you either need to get out and sign
that petition or hop on Google real
quick look up who your elected
representative is for your area for your
state legislature you need to give that
person to call or email them if you're
shy at all or email them it's super
super simple write them a little letter
and email dear mr. so-and-so I'm one of
your voters
I'd like you to vote YES on legalizing
marijuana that's all you have to say if
you want to get in and start making the
arguments for them and helping them with
that part of it too you can in your
email you don't have to be windy
hi mr. so-and-so please vote YES on this
thank you that's all you need to write
the more people they hear that from the
more likely they are to vote for you to
vote for what you're asking them to vote
for so take the time and do it if you're
a state where it's got you need the
signatures gathered to get it on the
ballot if the state requires a hundred
thousand signatures collect three
hundred thousand when you sign the
petition make sure that the petition
signer knows that [ __ ] I see efforts
fail to make the ballot every year
because they needed a hundred thousand
they turn it in fifty one hundred and
fifty thousand and then the state D
certifies 80 thousand and they're short
that's happening in Maine right now and
I think in Ohio as well so when you're
gathering signatures from marijuana you
need you need to gather triple the
signatures like it's incredibly
difficult to get this stuff on the
ballot for about an initiative but it's
doable if you do it right that's how
Colorado did it that's how a number of
the other legal and medical states have
done it
awesome that's really cool um so in this
upcoming election which candidates um
does it look like we'll have the most
positive influence on the cannabis
industry if they're elected into office
by far Bernie
by miles um a distant second would be
Hillary who will probably continue the
nonsense we're dealing with now from
Obama most of the Republican candidates
are either indifferent most are all of
the candidates at this point that it
outright said that they would use their
position as president to come in and
shut down what we're doing in Colorado
and Washington in Oregon I mean now
Alaska they're off they've dropped out
of the race so that's done we've gotten
past that point in this election that's
a really good thing to know that at this
point like none of the candidates that
are on there will try to shut it down
yeah well none of them have pledged to
so far okay given the nature of politics
that in especially this [ __ ] year
it's that saying that it hasn't happened
yet is a really safe bet god only knows
where the elections gonna go this year
if you thought politics were boring
you're not watching the right news shows
I don't I can't say that I can't how
loud say that I endorse any specific
candidate by there but if you were going
to vote only based on cannabis you got a
vote on Bern one yeah that's definitely
who you'd go for you're gonna vote just
on cannabis laws that dude needs to go
to Grateful Dead shows that dude
protested something if if all those
images I've seen they're totally true
they've checked by major new media
outlets but here's the thing if you want
to vote for Bernie in November you need
to vote for Bernie now odds are your
state already had its primary caucus if
it hasn't yet your ass needs to get in
front of computer right now in Google
what you have to do to participate in
your caucus the odds are you're already
locked out because you didn't do this a
month ago but that's not true in like
half of the upcoming states or more so
if you want a chance to vote for Bernie
in November you need to get out and vote
for him now it just it has to happen for
him to get the Democratic nomination
it's gonna be a lot of work and a lot of
people turn it out who don't usually
turn out and that's your fan base that's
my fan base if you guys want to vote for
Bernie in November it's you got to get
out now all right
and some states have primary votes where
you just go vote like you do in November
um
each states different that's part of the
what you're googling to see how to
participate in it it's not hard it's not
difficult it won't be that big pain in
the ass and it'll have major
repercussions in November so get out and
do it
you can't [ __ ] if you don't vote no you
can't all right so we were talking about
the candidates that are most Pro
cannabis and we can all agree that it's
mr. Bernie Sanders so if Bernie gets
elected into office what does that mean
for legal we'd like across the nation
ah well his campaign pledge so far only
goes so far as to say he won't I
interrupt the experiments going on in
legal States he's very set against the
war on drugs I think he's talked about D
criminal or legalizing it federally on
the record this campaign it's as a
president he's got a couple of different
options he could take the president
could sign an executive order which
would legalize it federally sort of
executive orders aren't federal law
necessarily like there's a lot of
contentious politics involved with
executive orders but the executive order
isn't a change in federal law that would
still mean marijuana is illegal
federally it's just the President signed
an order saying who don't care what we
really need to happen is in act of
Congress and where the who's president
matters there is because they get to a
bully pulpit is what they call it where
the president gets to say hey guys in
Congress it would be a really good idea
if you work on this and they do it all
the time with all kinds of different
[ __ ] and there's no reason they can't do
it with all right you guys we're gonna
figure out how to legalize marijuana
this year do this this and this get on
it
and like he doesn't get to tell them
like what to do like a your boss does it
work but it's similar with Obama they
just kind of look at him and nod their
heads and then half of the people
elected to represent us have chose to do
nothing for the last nine years and it's
been a [ __ ] problem but I getting
Bernie into the presidency and paying
attention to Senate races this year
major shifts in politics could happen
over half of our elected representatives
in Washington DC right now are up for
election if we fire that many of them
and replace them with quality quality
candidates that are even mildly Pro
cannabis 2016 could be a monumental year
for legal marijuana the podcast just
accidentally full-on endorsed Bernie
Sanders so if you're a pro marijuana
person that's the logical rational
choice yeah definitely so there's a lot
there's our yeah there are a lot of
arguments to be made after that but
right that's what you're looking at a
hundred percent is cannabis then you
that's where your money and vote would
go I'm very much not a one-issue voter
but marijuana legalization is very near
and dear to my heart
and I can see voting in an election like
this based purely on that my life is
ninety eight point seven percent funded
by the legalization of cannabis right
that's only like twenty five percent
true for me but like yeah that's zero
percent true for me but I did still like
a big aspect for why I'm voting to be
honest right it's I've studied this for
so long in just having it prohibit probe
prohibited just that concept in our law
has ruined so many things it's infected
every part of American life from
politics to medicine to how we interact
with each other our neighbors the police
how they how the police interact with us
it's it's just poisoned everything it's
touched and it's touched everything and
it has to stop and it stops this
election year
when people under 30 turn out and vote
which will hopefully happen a lot more
this year than it has in the past
election we've seen so many people
turning out for caucuses and voting Pro
Bernie in a lot of places
yeah we've been setting records for
caucus attendances attend caucus
attendance yeah
so it's there gonna be a lot of new
voters out there this year there are
there are more than usual energized but
we've seen this before if you're a
political junkie they refer to it as
getting Dukakis it's a guy who could
have been president and everybody
thought he was gonna be in all the
college kids were gonna vote for him and
then he lost in a [ __ ] landslide to a
nightmare of a Republican and it happens
Bernie's really really popular and he
could he could lose in a landslide to
the Republican nominee whoever that ends
up being godly don't let it be Trump and
he could lose to Hillary in the primary
and we could be voting Hillary versus
somebody and then what that means for
legalization is very different Trump
just is [ __ ] crazy dude I was gonna I
was I did we're [ __ ] living a Mad Max
movie inside for you I've already and I
know everyone says this but like I've
already let it be very well known that I
will probably leave the United States I
have family in England I you've got a
lifeboat you gotta get out yeah I might
I might actually jump ship I mean I've
always wanted to go backpacking and like
do the Europe thing anyways so like
thanks for helping me make that decision
right yeah yeah I don't know what I'm
gonna do if that dude gets elected you
please yeah dude I'm gonna ride the boat
till it crumbles my life will change
that is an absolute thing yeah
absolutely
so I guess my next question actually
goes to both of you then so
realistically um is legalizing marijuana
across the nation something we want to
see um I know for myself I can say yes
but I know that my reasons and I guess I
would rather hear both of yours don't go
far do you want me to take it first
I I'm happy to take it go for it yes
it's a great thing for legalization the
people who are doing it right are gonna
be able to do it right across the
country and the the people that want to
come in and take over or come in and
corporatize can't compete like I don't
know any beer drinkers who'd be pumped
if another's Coors Light came on the
market I know a lot of beer drinkers who
are pumped regularly about some small
craft brewery coming on market people
who build up quality and turnout quality
or what we need this industry federal
legalization opens up dude the lab
testing problem goes away overnight
right we can use the same labs to test
the cantaloupe design problem the
pesticide goes over it goes out
overnight immediately the pesticide
manufacturers are able to run the
studies needed to put cannabis on the
label all the ones that already know
they can because it's on the label for
tobacco will have those studies done in
hours all of the seizure studies would
be able to be done for the Uppsala
medical research and adults that have
epilepsy Hashem trips for Tots like I
get that Marv Rose gonna come in and
plant five or five hundred acres worth
of shitty weed and roll it up and throw
it on the shelf at six and a half
percent pre-rolled joints in a [ __ ]
little pack and it's gonna be cute and
it's gonna eat a part of the market for
people who don't know any better but I
don't care so do you think if it was too
much benefits if it's completely
federally legal and there are places and
I'm gonna compare it to the beer model
like you did there's a cannabis
manufacturer that's the same size as
bush or Coors making producing mass
produce cannabis they're free cannabis
and then there's still niche Gardens
like green and healthy wellness and a
few others there are a few other shops
that I totally would shop and buy their
product right do you think that those
shops are still going to survive with
that large market like the Coors type of
stores that are coming out for sure okay
there'll be there'll be a section of
them they get bought up because women
Wynnum are lower occurs or [ __ ] those
companies but you go to I mean yeah when
they step in they don't create from the
ground up they look at you they
see what you're doing they hit you in
the face with a check bigger than you've
ever imagined and you walk away they
replicate your business model as a
franchise and then there's gonna be the
people who do this because they love it
they're gonna not sell out they're gonna
slowly expand there's a million people
who wish they could just hop on line and
order your seeds that can't because it's
not legal federally it's a federal
offense to mail those to people they
can't buy them like all that goes away
overnight people could just hop online
buy your seeds and enjoy life a lot of
percent legally without having to worry
about [ __ ] and the benefit for the
industry sky-high right now there was
just a report that the legal industries
worth four point four billion dollars
this year it's gonna grow to forty
billion dollars by 2020 if states
continue to legalize like they have the
last estimate I read on the black market
was Americans are spending sixty billion
on marijuana right now you figure a
third or more that's the black market
markup I mean the industry's worth forty
four forty five billion dollars
nationwide if you're able to export to
England every now and again or whatever
else is other countries start to
legalize in the demand for American
quality cannabis spreads around the
globe that growth is exponential the
idea that you're gonna get squeezed out
if you're good at what you're doing and
you're a competent business owner it's
just not there like you ever do a mic
drop I just like that's like the end of
the podcast right
that's why I want to choke the [ __ ]
stoners against legalization like I see
people every day online that are
actively lobbying against whatever
legalization efforts going on in their
area because it legalizes marijuana
somewhere in between alcohol and tobacco
not like tomatoes so like you can only
produce so much of it there are rules on
if you produce it in your home who you
can sell it to or give it away to or not
be allowed to sell it to that's
something I was gonna definitely
action is you got to be careful when
you're gonna make the it when it goes
federally illegal we have to be careful
about what we get like what we ask for
because there needs to be certain rules
about growing if we're all limited to
six plants that's gonna [ __ ] some things
up we need usable numbers more viable
plant numbers we need just a little
better rule so when it comes time we
gotta be careful that we get the right
stuff that we want
it's so weird in Colorado right now
especially when we're extrapolating the
federal legalization because right now
those rules really help keep the idiots
from [ __ ] this up for all of us
already we've got major problems mostly
PR problems like nobody's been hurt but
massive outdoor grows we're okay so few
people have been heard that was fair
head shake but massive outdoor grows
that piss off the neighbors that lead to
articles in the press about what
bastards we are and how the system's
being manipulated all of that leads to
major blowback that has political
ramifications including our area
possibly voting to ban the legal
marijuana industry this November that's
a real [ __ ] possibility mainly because
there's been a lot of blowback lately
about huge outdoor grows people with a
20 and 30 plant count doing 20 or 30 VW
bus size plants and a [ __ ] suburban
backyard like a douche bag yeah that's
not allow um nope and it pisses all the
neighbors off and it looks terrible in
the press and it's gonna lead to sick
kids losing out on their medicine
because caregivers are gonna get quashed
here in about five years
they're already pushing the caregiver
model out of the Colorado business plan
it's already going away yep and so it's
really time like if you care about
marijuana legalization or you want to be
part of this industry to really start
paying attention and getting involved
because right now everything is
happening it's actually becoming legal
everywhere very slowly but it's
happening like it's we're moving forward
every two years and if people turn out
and vote in the numbers that they can
Facebook post Bernie wins in a landslide
and huge numbers of congressmen get
replaced and we actually make major
problem
Ehsan marijuana law for the first time
federally in 80 years we can be a part
of that revolution all you got to do is
get out there and vote we already told
you who to vote for accidentally really
didn't intend to endorse a specific
candidate I'm gonna show but if you're
your only vote topic is marijuana you
really gotta vote for Bernie yeah well
so then I guess that uh that kind of
leads right there into my next question
what serious changes will occur if
Bernie a pro marijuana candidate is
elected into office like federally and
state wise obviously it'll change the
drug classification of it
which will mean that we'll be able to be
studied and all that the change at the
federal level is just so huge we will be
able to put our money in a bank yep yeah
we've spent 80 years thinking up ways to
make it harder to grow weed and every
single one of those rules is still in
place for the legal industry and
changing the federal law lets us change
all of those the banking the lab testing
the packaging requirements the state
line rules I I get five calls a week at
the shop about people wondering where
the Buy Now button is on our website
[Music]
like I I get it like you buy everything
online now like you're probably not
gonna be buying weed online now any time
soon but um it should be there like
everything else and it can be if it's
federally legal but just changing who
the president is it's sort of like the
first step and that's not how we get
this battle won necessarily that's
that's the next best step the real
change happens like regardless of who
gets elected the next election I'm
calling your state legislators calling
your state senators just google it
figure out who they are it's their job
to listen to [ __ ] when people call
and when you didn't Gamera it stuff
that's their job is for people that live
from whatever area the country they're
from call and talk to them and it's
their job to listen and then it's their
job to go pass laws based on how many
people call them that week and said vote
Yes or vote no so literally
this stuff matters there are a number of
areas cities towns counties that are
voting on marijuana legalization far
ahead of their states I just saw New
Orleans to criminalize that [ __ ]
Louisiana's never gonna but New Orleans
just passed a law
maybe not full decriminalization but
they just did some sentencing reform
guidelines I've been posting a story all
week of about a dude who got 13 years
for two joints in New Orleans
that's ridiculous yep it's part of
there's three strikes in your [ __ ] law
there's enough hash on this table to
lock up everyone in New Orleans yep
Miami Florida decriminalized it last
year didn't hurt this year earlier they
should think so yeah yeah I think
anything cities towns and counties
everywhere are and they're doing it
because the local officials in those
areas got swamped with pro marijuana
supporters calling hey I'm a voter in
your district I'm Pro marijuana let's
legalize it in the city enough people
call enough people got active and that's
what everybody listening to the show
needs to do if you live in another
country unless it's like North Korea
odds are you've got a system of
representative government of some sort
you can do a lot of this too because I
know we've got a listeners in Australia
if you're listening from North Korea
please send me a tweet seriously I'd
love to know if you're listening in
Korea my podcast on Twitter I want to
know and also huge shout out to our
supporter in Australia I'm sure we've
got several but we've got one guy out
there that is a huge supporter what's up
my Rasta friend thanks for listening to
the show but yeah get involved get
active because there's a lot you can do
even on a local level if you live in a
state that's never gonna legalize it you
might live in a city that will Austin
so in your opinion out of the states
that have legalized marijuana already
which state is doing it right in the way
of laws like who has a good set of laws
put in place to make a cannabis industry
actually grow and not have issues none
of them are perfect yet but I tend to it
might be biased but I took a quick
glance at the rules again today and I
vote Colorado by a mile
Washington's drastically over taxing
marijuana and has caused all sorts of
price issues and issues industry-wide
between the city the state the county
the in the federal sales tax is that the
legal marijuana industry pays having a
statewide tax rate of thirty thirty five
percent is enough to keep the shop from
being able to profit at all and that's
terrible for the industry hips in on the
black market yep if the shops can't
profit they can't pay their people what
they're worth they can't provide
insurance they can't reinvest in their
business and there's no reason to get
involved in it just stay in the black
market the black market will be fine
just like it was last year it always
exists it's never going to look I mean
Oregon's got its own issues
your whole new set issues as yesterday
but Colorado is far from perfect to
weird social clubs are a very gray area
in our law some areas allow them no area
has shops up and running where they're
allowed Colorado Springs just voted to
ban all the shops but gave them eight
years to shut down which is a leave them
alone for eight years so yeah they're
too dangerous to allow to continue to
exist so they have to shut them down but
they gave them eight years actually they
actually said that they're going to vote
again within that eight years oh they're
probably gonna vote at least eight times
yes hopefully we can turn it around
there so when you guys are writing the
rules in your state or city or a county
or whatever it may be on your island in
your bubble when you're making the rules
for your cannabis laws be sure to
include some sort of way to consume
that cannabis legally and safely with
your friends there are places to go to
drink alcohol we can all go together I
can name 12 places within five minutes
of here that we can all go get drunk
until we [ __ ] die yep but there's
nowhere that we get other than right
here at this table we can all congregate
and safely consume cannabis without any
problems we take it as kind of a given
but there's a huge contingent of people
out there that want no rules and they
think that's possible and it's not it's
marijuana might be the most safe
intoxicant known to mankind it might be
the most beneficial plant known to
mankind none of that means you're gonna
legalize it to be produced in the home
at any amount with no regulation or no
rules as to how or where it can be grown
like you'll never be able to grow it
like tomatoes at best you'll be able to
produce it like homebrew alcohol works
um and we need some of those rules
honestly with the abuses we see just in
the legal states that are going now like
there are idiots everywhere like and we
kinda have to set up the rules for the
slowest link you know what I mean like
other was the guy growing 8-foot tall
trees in his backyard here in our
neighborhood yeah and some kids tried to
steal his trees and he shot them like
thank God it was a [ __ ] pellet gun
yeah but there's been others their home
invasion robberies because they've got a
ridiculous grow going and yeah it's
legal here dude congrats bro but it's
not legal estate over it's in fact worth
eight thousand a pound and you've got
four hundred thousand dollars worth of
marijuana in your suburban backyard in
the ghetto like that's your life like
twelve times over bro what were you
thinking um like not only did you put
yourself at risk everybody else in your
house at risk your neighbors at risk but
you shot the whole movement in the foot
at the same time and I honestly don't
want my [ __ ] kid climbing over your
fence it's doing your wheelies well like
maybe you should [ __ ] hassle bums I
like I had to do with boost and I was
getting gas today and a dude who looked
well liked good decent shoes and looked
clean he's like bro you got a extra
couple
Bulls [ __ ] [ __ ] asleep
I don't even know what to think dude i
stupid ask right it's a spare change not
do you have 47 dollars a couple of extra
balls like maybe like if I had a row
Chotu hooked you up a couple extra Bowl
I don't know maybe if I hadn't no guy
might have thrown it his way yeah but a
nug is a bull right I mean like I guess
I thought about offering him I was like
you should just get in the car and take
the biggest [ __ ] dab you've ever had
there's what I thought about doing to
the kid but it was got more questions
for white Mike there's a couple more
questions on the list yeah I got the
list also yeah okay so what other states
um accept other states medical cards
okay the only state that does they call
that reciprocity the only state that I
know that does that is Nevada okay and
they accept all other states are just
selected as far as I'm aware Nevada is
medical marijuana dispensaries except
medical marijuana cards from all other
states which is great for the medical
marijuana industry in Nevada because
last I checked they had like 20 10 or
14,000 patients that just changed a lot
of cool things because one of our very
good friends is getting married there on
the 23rd of July and I've been invited
to their wedding nice and so that means
that I can travel and I can stop at a
dispensary and I can pick up some
products yep I haven't wanted to go to
Vegas since I was like 24 and I suddenly
it's back on the list of to do's shout
out to Harney and reveille congrats on
the wedding you guys so that might have
to happen soon it's a it's you
definitely do it a couple of times
before you die I just told everybody
that I'll be in Vegas on July 23rd I
haven't wanted to go to Vegas we're
drinking and legal weed or legal access
to my medical marijuana should be more
specific do you think do you think beach
will improve your gambling Oh bye miles
yeah that's yo yeah I'm not a drinkers
that's what I was gonna say about
smoking club's thing like that's a huge
thing for me because I don't drink I
haven't drank and maybe two or three
years now like I don't really do
anything else so smoking is really
important to me and like being able to
have somewhere to go and to do that is
like really important so knowing that I
can go to other states and like consume
cannabis about having any issues or
anything is like a really I think it was
Matt that said on a past episode that
they made bars so that you don't have
people drinking on the streets all day
they need to make cannabis social clubs
so that we're not out in our car trying
to dab at the [ __ ] Safeway parking lot
right and then we get a DUI right yep
yeah yeah you know there's or some
stupid [ __ ] right
like legalization doesn't exist in a
vacuum like it has to be practicing just
like everything else and there are a lot
of people who live in places where they
can't smoke there are a lot of people
who live in situations where they can't
smoke I'm about to be in one and it gets
cold [ __ ] and collar out of there the
winter and so you've you know you need
places to go where you can legally
consume you don't want to be standing
out in an alley if you don't have to be
and there's no reason to have that be
the legal consumption method
I [ __ ] hate tourists or Talent or is
that just go to the back of the hotel
parking lot like we should have a better
answer than that right ah smoke out your
car yeah I love the points that got made
on that show that last show of candy
Canyon about like we've got kids now
like I don't necessarily want to explain
that like I want to do that on my own
time I don't want to have to explain
that [ __ ] in the park or [ __ ]
anywhere else like yes signs are one
thing like what are those guys doing
over there like that looks fun should we
go do that dad like I want to skip those
questions for as long as possible and if
there are consumption clubs that
conversationally comes up like that if
I'm at a consumption Club yeah right and
it's [ __ ] on me because I've got my
twelve year old the consumption club
like I'm the douchebag in that situation
of the guys smoking weed you guys they
will not let you have your 12 year old
the bar just I'm gonna lay that out it's
really got to be hard to telling people
that about the whole
tell because you're putting them at risk
too because if a cop were to catch them
smoking out in the open they get you
know they still get a fine or whatever
it is here income we had a friend who
got caught smoking in a parking lot he
didn't have anywhere to be for a little
while he parked underneath the stoplight
or the just the lightness or a
streetlight there and was chilling out
loaded himself up a bowl and took a
couple of puffs off the bowl as he was
blowing out of hit cop walked up to his
window and knocked on his window he had
no choice but to roll down the window
and let the smoke billow onto the cops
face and he just roll all he did was
write um any illegal possession of
cannabis ticket and he kind of chewed
him out he's like you can't [ __ ]
smoke here and my buddy's like I was
just waiting I didn't have anywhere to
be and he's like I don't care you can't
[ __ ] smoke here yeah like that was
our buddy's fault 44s fall shout out to
forty-four afraid but if there had been
a place for him to go where he could
safely consume cannabis 44 and two if
there have been a place for him to like
safely consume cannabis you know that
wouldn't have happened that whole
situation wouldn't happen for people
that would have happened but for our
friend 44 and two that still would have
happened that way there should be more
hotels that cater to the level of
tourists coming through Colorado and
they just that part of the industry
hasn't caught up yet
I mean come consumption Club saw a
couple hundred different questions about
how legal marijuana works there was a
dispensary in Manitou Springs since the
dispensary I work for is not a
recreational store it's a medical only I
can tell you about Emerald fields in
Manitou Springs if you're gonna be in
the Manitou Springs Colorado Springs
area and you're looking for recreational
cannabis I would send you to Emerald
fields I like the vibe and the
experience of the place it was unlike
any other recreational dispensary I have
ever been to the place was really
[ __ ] cool had a neat vibe to it it's
a little overpriced because it's
recreational cannabis and I'm used to
plant paying member pricing over at
Green and healthy but the place was
cooler [ __ ] check it out right down the
street there is a 420 friendly hotel in
Manitou they advertise that they are 420
friendly so they're not gonna kick you
out I don't know if you can smoke in the
rooms or if they've got like a
designated 4/20 area but it advertises
420 friendly on the side
it's basically if you're coming to
Colorado and you plan to consume
cannabis the the best thing you can do
is call around to several different
hotels and just as straight-up asking
what their marijuana policy is don't use
euphemisms don't let there be any
confusion they've gotten this phone call
eight times today the person on the
other end should just give you a rote
response if anybody from Emerald fields
or that hotel heard any of that you can
kindly send an email with a check in it
[Music]
but yeah just callin ask what's your
marijuana policy they'll tell you that
they'll kick you out for consuming on
property at a story they'll tell you
that they don't know why you can consume
inside what they have a smoking pad
there is one below or one hotel on the
south side of pueblos that is cannabis
friendly but I cannot recall which hotel
house right now the one I used to send
people to I sent a guy to the other
night and I got a call back maybe 45
minutes after I had this conversation
and he was like no they said they're not
anymore and he yelled at me and I had to
leave I felt really bad yep sorry dude
but yeah it there's just some Colorado's
got the best set of laws so far in my
opinion but we've still got some serious
serious holes in our law right now that
need to be fixed there are a couple of
classier hotels in Denver I don't know
if I even want to say the names of the
places wouldn't but I if you we go for
the cannabis cup and when we go for the
cup we get expensive hotels yeah when we
go to Denver we would go get [ __ ]
high-end hotels yeah we be kind of
[ __ ] about it eat lunch on the
balcony and trip spoil yourself a little
yeah and so uh if you told the people at
the desk like so what's the the smoking
fee like it's $500 here we're gonna be
here for three days there's eight of us
thrown out like 40 bucks each or fifty
bucks each or was I don't I can't do
math that's quickly while I'm talking
about it but if we divide the wheel
divided the smoking for you like can you
just bill us for that not [ __ ] with us
and like okay and they just let us pay
the $500 smoking what they were gonna
charge us advance like we're going to
smoke this [ __ ] out like okay they just
let us do that there are there are other
hotels that won't let you smoke them out
but
some of or all of their rooms have
balconies and some of them are more or
less lenient with just go out on the
balcony and puff yeah
others have straight-up told people just
go to the back of our parking lot and
every time I Drive by one of them I see
like three people standing in this
parking lot just in the back corner so
Warwick has killer balconies there's
actually a little smoking Club in Denver
called
I bake or I baked yes I bake yes have
you guys ever been there okay so I
visited Colorado twice before I moved
out here and both times that I visited I
tried to go there and like they don't
open until noon or something like that
so my overly excited woke up too early
you know so I was not prepared for
something to not be open till noon and I
was not ready to wait to smoke a blunt
so I said but anyways yes I have never
actually been there but apparently that
is a really chill like no entry fee
no nothing place so if you're ever in
Denver and you want to check that place
out that uh that's a cannabis smoking
Club I bake you can hit my PayPal
there's a bunch of speakeasy style
cannabis clubs around Denver and other
cities in Colorado there just if they
were legal it'd be simple you know I
shot out the can of Canyon all the time
I really had fun at the dab lounge a
couple of weekends ago with Steve de
Fino doing the veteran farmers Alliance
and then I went to this speakeasy
that's the 4/20 speakeasy it's next door
to the lazy lion it's a completely
different vibe than both places it's got
a big stage and there is a band plan and
there are pool tables there are a lot of
options I really enjoyed all three of
those clubs on a different level I just
prefer the candy cane Ian because it's
got this
hardwood floors leather couches this is
classy as [ __ ] it's funny I always
explain the smoking clubs in Colorado
Springs if you're trying to go with
people who you're trying to I wouldn't
even say distract but there's a lot of
TVs and a lot of things to do at the
lion so you don't necessarily have to
interact with people
um the dad lounge is the same way right
and but canna Canyon is where you go
with your like true friends to like sit
down and talk and actually have like a
real conversation because there really
isn't any TVs there's some music and
stuff so you really go there for the
atmosphere and the Cannabis everything
music has kept it a real quiet level and
yeah the hostess is usually Camille and
she's amazing
bring your bottles of water if you yeah
right and like that's what I want what I
hope to see like all over Colorado
slowly start to spring up is places
where people can go with their friends
socialize a little bit consume some
cannabis safely out of public view like
away from people who aren't interested
in it I mean it's just that simple it's
some place to wait for the [ __ ] cab
of the uber you know where people can
safely consume cannabis and hang out
with a whole bunch of their friends and
meet Adam ill this table the secret
session Denver Colorado on authority
posted by Gatsby Gardens I was supposed
to shut that out at the start of the
show you'll be there I'll be there I
like working Mike will be working sorry
someone's got to do it bro yeah shot
it's a Grammy Gatsby thanks for all the
love bro I appreciate it
we actually just confirmed our DJ I've
been talking about the DJ that we might
get we just confirmed it so I have to
get permission from the people that are
hosting the event before I can announce
the DJ and confirm we've got it we've
got a good DJ I asked one of my favorite
rappers to come rap and crickets
I really think right at one hour I'm in
that fine spot between two Deb did not
either too high for this [ __ ] or not
high enough for this [ __ ] so honestly
the last three questions are what we had
talked about that they're all shows in
themselves so I don't mean we can do a
round two of this what I think we should
do is let the listeners listen to this
one and if you guys have any questions
or things that you'd like to follow up
on in this you can send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
or you can hit me on twitter it's at g f
YH podcast or
you can go to Facebook and find the girl
from your heart podcast Facebook page
send me a message on there I check all
of them semi-regularly so I'll find the
message I will guarantee check it and
find it eventually and we will do a
follow-up episode with part of the
questions that are on the bottom of the
page that you guys say can be an entire
episode on their own maybe we can make
one episode out of all three of those
plus listener comments it sounds good
guys both back for round two I in two or
three weeks or so something like that
absolutely alright so maybe like episode
127 to 130 the [ __ ] goes on in my world
this bits podcast you guys I had a whole
nother show planned and this podcast
happened today so this was I love the
way my life goes and the way that this
worked out really really well I think
yeah yeah hey Mike how can people follow
you on social media you can find me two
places at Nemo punk 15 on Twitter or I
run night pueblos for sensible cannabis
laws Facebook page hit me up on there if
you're looking for basically any
cannabis legalization news a lot of its
local but I do nationwide and now
worldwide when it's good news you can
tell he knows a lot of buzzwords and
knows his [ __ ] when it comes to cannabis
legislation nationwide
he really this is on the state and the
local but he knows his [ __ ] all
statewide I'm kind of like a heroin
junkie in that fashion like when I wake
up in the morning one of the first
things I do is hop online and check a
couple of different really good news
sources for what's going on in in
marijuana today and I have to like it's
a [ __ ] compulsion after all these
years when I don't get to do it in the
morning all day at work I get to read
the [ __ ] paper it's digital now so
I'm not just getting the Denver Post I
read like 17 or 18 different newspapers
if you want to classify the amount of
news as a paper a day just following
this stuff is a compulsion now so yeah I
do all the good stuff I share to that
Facebook page or some of the stuff gets
up on Twitter make sure you follow that
Facebook page guys and also check them
out on Twitter if you follow Mike on
Twitter from this podcast
Tagg Mike tagged the podcast and tell
him I heard about you through the G fyh
podcast and let him know cuz he likes to
know where his listeners and followers
are coming right
most of my followers follow me because I
regularly smack anti-marijuana people on
Twitter and that gets you a bunch of
really weird follows and then every day
every now and again at 2:00 in the
morning I'll get a bunch of random
follows when I haven't been on Twitter
at 6 days and I have to think it's a
podcast thing where I never [ __ ] know
so answer that question for me please
hey an emo Punk
what's the number 15 yeah at Nemo Punk
15 an emo Punk 15 we found you on that
and then @g fyh podcast following from
the pot if you don't want to do it in a
tweet you can do it a message yeah
whatever you plug I know alright dude
thanks for coming
happy to members to the wife and kid
babies yeah all right miss traveling
stoner yes how can people follow you on
the social media so Instagram and
periscope are the same it's the
travelling stoner my twitter is
traveling stoner and then my snapchat is
traveling stoner without the G so
someone went and snatched up all of the
traveling stoner on a certain amount of
social media sites that I didn't yeah so
anyways so yes so it's all over the
place but those are them and blog intern
for Miss Mary Jane Coe my girl a shot
yeah it's it's Miss Mary Jane code word
press.com so be sure to check it out it
has a lot of information about what they
do as a company and it has some
information - about cannabis if you
check it out you guys also big shout out
- we're gonna give a shout out to your
your find her other half the other ganja
girl yes oh we should explain so she
posted a picture to Instagram last week
oh I saw that on Instagram hilarious her
above elastic or on a hike and they post
a picture and she tags it ganja girls
really popular hash tagging so I mean
he's the sexiest ganja girl evolved but
he's got a beard like and a mustache yes
he is appealing so one of my girlfriends
called it out and she was like oh my god
what cute ganja girls and
immediately rode like oh my god I'm so
sorry like I sometimes I get really high
I think I'm funny on the internet I'm
really sorry what's up you're my
favorite girl you could easily be a 420
nurse absolutely I've only seen one
photo and I took that photo and I just
threw the [ __ ] godness now you're
imagining those little green crosses bro
also shout-out to sloppy for the the
man-sized ad that he tried to take with
me yesterday also we're gonna do the
shoutouts here but big big huge
shout-out and a fat hug to my friend
Manny alright so uh we kind of
interrupted you on your social media
stuff that's good that Miss Mary Jane Co
yeah that's pretty much it for right now
all right well thank you for coming
absolutely thank you for having me I
really appreciate you taking some time
away from the house and coming and
hanging out so funny the dog yes that's
a cool little dog here to bring it next
time she can like bark in the dog
waddles around the house he's like got a
funny shape to him his legs are too
short he's a great little dog she's
pulling up pictures for Mike he's a cool
little dog oh thank you guys both for
coming I want to thank everybody for
listening to the show you guys you know
I will be back in another week with
another episode our friend kabuki Jay
Fox was messaging me he was gonna try to
get over here for the podcast but he had
a lot going on we took forever kabuki
we'll be in Pueblo much more frequently
he just got involved in a project here
in Pueblo so we're gonna have run CBD
here in the room way pumped about the
kitchen slash studio slash dining room
we'll get kabuki over here we'll take
some CBD dabs and talk about Terps for
tots and stuff like that the best bucket
hashtag I just I spotted it out one day
at the the event and for the veteran
farmers Alliance all right guys the
podcast is officially over I would like
it if you go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart podcast find the review section
give me a five star rate if I'm star
rating just do it please what happens
when you do that that moves us up in the
rankings
god I stuttered when I said rankings
that was weird why is that such a hard
work I
moves us up in the rankings more people
will see us the more people that see the
podcast means more people will listen
which means more people will be growing
much better quality cannabis it'll make
better cannabis available for the world
we will over grow the government one
click at a time I think I just made up a
new slogan on accident but you guys
seriously give me a five star rating
type in a little comment let me know
what you think of the show I will read
your review on a future podcast if you
don't want to do a review you can send
me an email girl from your heart at
hotmail.com
I've talked about the Twitter feed it's
at G fyh podcast and of course the
Facebook don't forget you guys the show
is available on iTunes stitcher and most
of the episodes are archived on I read
genetics Colorado calm when some of
those key episodes go away I will put
them back up into the feed iTunes only
holds about 100 episodes the website may
only hold 100 episodes of what I'm
learning so I will go back and win it
when it takes down the important [ __ ]
I'll put it back up anyway um yeah they
took down the PayPal button what's up
with that we don't have a PayPal account
anymore that's [ __ ] anyway you guys
I want to thank you guys for listening
followed the new I read genetics
Instagram account it's Irene underscore
genetics that's all I've got free this
week and until next time take a phat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you