[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 126 of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right if you're a new
grower if you're professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated Abbot
if you're a cannabis activists even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me also I want to thank my buddy
white Mike for joining me again how you
doing today brother doing good man how
are you I am doing good now that we got
this recording equipment figured out
yeah we spent some time working on the
sounds for some reason 126 episodes into
the show I opened up the recording
software in hit go and the recording
equipment was just given me the middle
finger it was like no not today took a
couple of dry runs to get her going he's
out and right I got her fired up it's
working good I think I've done more
damage to my head working on this
podcast that I did it like all of the
concerts I saw in my early 20s working
well I just said it's working good
what's working our English skills today
class yeah well I apologize for the
other headphone malfunctions there now
we're good I don't know what was going
on with this equipment today it was
super loud and it was super quiet and it
was extra loud and you guys don't care
you guys just want a quality show so
let's get into that part um we're gonna
read some news articles we may actually
play a news article but first let's talk
about another email that I did not
include in the last episode I think it
might have been a Facebook message is
why I missed it shout-out to her friend
Rasta Seb
Rasta said has had a little bit of bad
luck but things will turn around for
your brother I feel bad for what
happened to you but Rasta said sent me a
question asking what is reclaim and we
can't laugh at the guy we got it we got
to remember not everybody is smoking 4 &amp;
5 grams of hash on their day off not
everybody lives across to a completely
good question no giggles at all most
people well yeah a lot of people in
Colorado be like let's reclaim reclaim
is this bro so
for all you folks out there who are not
able to consume a whole bunch of Earl
spoil hash breath I talk to people all
day who I like I don't even bother to
get to reclaim with them because like I
already gave them with thesaurus worth
the [ __ ] the look on Mike's face was
priceless here okay so let me tell you
what reclaim is when we use a dab rig we
put a nail attached to the rig somehow
it either sits on the outside of a mail
joint or it sits on the inside of the
mail joint and then you put a dome on it
either way you heat up that nail and
then you put some hash onto there and
you inhale and as you inhale some of
that hash oil will collect onto your rig
just like the resin collects on your
pipe they doing good so far Mike yeah
okay
just as we vaporize the hash before it
all gets to us some of it on vaporizes
and reconstitutes itself and to reclaim
yeah and then a lot of times that'll
fill up in if you're smoking BHO I
highly recommend you using a rig we call
the rig a pipe it's a bong you guys it's
a small bong I like a little small
bubbler especial little hash bong we
call it we call it a rig but I like
something small I'd highly recommend you
smoke with something with water in it
you want that bubble actually down the
hash is really hot just cool it a little
bit before it gets to your lungs and
throw it'll really help you out so a lot
of times a water will collect a lot of
reclaim in there so there's a lot of
claim in the water there's a lot of
claim on the entryway to the pipe a lot
of times I'll use what's called a drop
down grabbing my drop down right now to
get it nice visual the drop down goes on
to the rig where the nail would normally
go and it's an extension of glass it'll
actually go a little lower to get the
nail out of your face a little bit and
get it further away from your head and
then the nail goes on there and then a
lot of the oil the reclaim oil will
collect right into here and there's some
here that we can talk about there's I
don't know that's probably a measurement
of one DRAM 1/2 DRAM I think is what
that it would be probably if you poured
it out it would be half a gram one of
those little tiny vials yeah they'd be
half of one of those is what I think so
I've got a half of a half a dram of
reclaimed that I could remove from here
and do something with so that's what
reclaim is it's that's basically
reconstituted hash oil that stuck to my
piece what can you do with it was one of
his follow-up questions I've seen people
just stick the dabber inside of
this mucky part and pull it out and read
a bit some people will do that our
friend forty-four he would do that
that's not against his standards
lots of people go for dabbing and uh I
know a lot of people who take great care
to clean it out and then try to like dry
it out drying it out is the part that I
would make really well leave it on on
some parchment paper or on an oil slick
pad make sure you let it dry really well
before you try to dab it again I talked
to one dude who's cleaning his rig with
Everclear so that he could throw that
into a glass dish when he was done
agitating getting his rig all clean and
then slowly evaporate that back down and
death like reclaimed powder I think our
friend Gary was uh teaching me about
that a while back so shout-out Gary I'm
not sure if you still listen to the show
but he was talking about doing something
very similar our friend Fox with CBD CBD
extract on CB B I think what he would
say would be to make edibles at it
that's of another use that no number of
people do it's already been D car is it
decarboxylase or decarboxylated eyes
eyes okay look like you just picked one
I was gonna say you just pick I said
them both in my head and I was like now
the first one it sounds like it's bendy
carved because it's been heated to a
temperature above a certain Beyond for
it's been heat I don't even know how hot
the surface of this nail is it is really
hot and it's reconstituted so it's been
activated essentially so many eat it
it's already broken down so that your
body doesn't have to break it down as
much to make the psychoactive components
bioavailable well that was deep on
accident but okay so that's what reclaim
is I may be an [ __ ] because what I do
with it is I fill my rig with rubbing
alcohol and I shake it up real good and
I pour that [ __ ] down the drain and
ironically for some reason my garbage
disposal doesn't work that's too high
I'm a vegetarian I don't eat anything
that would really clog that thing up I
don't put anything down there I just
need some like 90% sure I need to pour a
bottle I sew down my resin I got a whole
bunch of reclaim in there I nine times
out of 10 I do the same thing if I've
got a big fat glob of reclaim sitting
somewhere that's easy to get to I'll use
my torch to
extract it real quick just kind of heat
it up just a little quit it turn it into
basically liquid yeah and then pour it
and do a silicone container and I use it
for seasoning my nail that's a great use
for it honestly it's the only reason I
keep it around and so I only do it what
I've got like a really fat glob sitting
there cuz what I've got now I could
seize about 100 nails with so we're
gonna get another question what the hell
does he mean season your nail when you
get a new titanium nail just like any
skillet that you would want to cook on
any pan that you're gonna cook on you're
gonna want to put some oil or fatty
substance on it to grease it up before
you cook on it so that you don't taste
that that iron that cast-iron you wanna
just cast iron on whatever you're
cooking if it's you're making some
asparagus in there if you're making pork
chops you don't taste [ __ ] cast-iron
and you don't want to just taste raw
titanium so when I get a new nail I'll
heat it up just to about dab temperature
and I'll let it cool so that the nail so
that the oil will puddle on there and
kind of soak into the pores of the nail
so you want to kind of season your nail
before you start dabbing with the brand
new titanium meal and you can do with
quartz also once you get a quartz nail
perfectly seasoned it's so smooth and
tastes really really nice I finally got
to hit a really nice quartz banger
recently and it tasted really good
shout out to boba blaster Co and the
traveling stoner sloppy 9:9 and whoever
else buzzy probably was in the house got
it through the whole crew they got to
take some dabs I know where you were bro
let me give a shout out to Lindsey yes I
did I gave a shout out to Lindsey on the
last episode you did a great job on the
show and Mikey were awesome also we're
gonna get Mike and Lindsey back on
another episode
hey listen or sent a Facebook message
you know I wasn't even prepared for this
let me grab my phone and we'll read a
Facebook message right quick yeah that
was a fun show to record I got some good
feedback on it from some people this
Facebook message stemmed from that
episode I'm pulling it up on my phone
right now this is impromptu it was not
wait till you guys are both here but uh
it seems like fair time to mention this
here we go this comment she said oh and
she has replied to my reply she said I
listened to this podcast and was sad to
hear that the libertarian candidates
were ignored or were entirely ignored
Gary Johnson is way better than Sanders
on cannabis Johnson besides owning an
x-ray
even admits to using cannabis so when
Hilary Burt's burnt beats Bernie which
she will and that she leaves us a link
to follow so that we can read about a
libertarian future no I'm very familiar
with Gary Johnson I'm a big fan I'm just
a realist
Gary's awesome but Gary don't have a
shot she said thanks I'm actually
rooting for Bernie for the DEM
nomination but my heart is with Gary
Johnson and she said it's not totally
impossible for Gary Johnson so I don't
know enough about that to have an
opinion it sounds like Mike does what I
do have an opinion on is that Elizabeth
I appreciate your interaction with the
podcast on Facebook keep it up if you
ever have any more questions or anything
you'd like to say feel free to throw it
up there on the Facebook I like it thank
you
the the Libertarian candidate is
typically far better on marijuana policy
than the Democrat or the Republican
candidates but they don't have a shot
right now like we just don't have that
third-party infrastructure in the United
States sorry I liked it I didn't do it
Mike knows a lot of political [ __ ]
you're a buzz around champion bro I
listened to the episode because of
course I clean them up a little bit
before I put them out if anybody pauses
for too long or so [ __ ] they want taken
out I'll cut it out for him listening
back to that episode you were buzzword
King it's like ding ding ding you're
just getting my mind every time nice
that's awesome so um we talked about
reclaim shout out to Rasta Seb uh he
said I owe you one bro you helped me out
one time by contributing to the podcast
it looks like you may be in a time of
need if there's anything that Mike and I
can do for you Mike I just volunteered
your ability if we can do anything for
your bro let me know I owe you one
I don't know what we could do but if
something comes up that you think of
send me an email send me a Facebook
message we'll get it on um our next
article our next topic is going to be a
positive thing I'm gonna go to the
internet for this one we're actually
going to play a quick video clip from
Channel 13 News here in Pueblo Colorado
and Colorado Springs that says I should
give credit to Katie Spencer who is a
multimedia journalist the cannabis clubs
in Colorado Springs United and did
something
three uh they were giving away free
joints to people who volunteered was
this all of those this some of them just
a small group there was a group of them
I know okay so there was more than one
yeah oh she sure is more than one the
article should tell us but I saw our
friends from one shop posting about it
and I saw the guy on this news articles
from another shop so I don't know how
many of the places participated but I'll
play the news article for you but what
they did was they were giving away a
free joint if you participated in their
litter cleanup program if you went and
picked up one bag of trash and brought
it back to the organizer of this event
he would give you a free joint and
there's an image of him standing here
unfortunately he's standing in the park
with a bowl of doob tubes full of joints
he's got the joints aren't exposed
they're in little containers right like
if I would have organized this event it
would be an organized slightly different
but I love it for what it is and what it
did for the community it's a very good
item it's not a hundred percent like put
your best foot forward necessarily as
far as optics go but I love it do joints
for picking up trash all the way clean
everything up oh and if you could smoke
the joint while you pick up trash was
that make it a lot better sure you can't
do that that's the whole thing was
handed about cuz I'm sure plenty of
people did that like it was just bring
me a bag of trash get a joint I'm sure
there were plenty of people who brought
him several bags of trash I don't know
how many people wouldn't cleaned out
their car but I'd like to see see more
the industry doing stuff like that like
the consumption clubs can really push
the boundaries with like giving away
product and stuff like that like the the
shops can't even give away product
legally they have to charge at least a
penny right the only way a dispensary
would be able to do that would to be if
they checked your ID before they let you
sign up for the program and then they
would have to give you a coupon it may
give you a joint for a penny because
they can't give you anything for free
right and so that then you'd have to go
back to that shop and get the joint for
a penny with your coupon but then didn't
you just technically you were employed
by that dispensary if that happens
you're like kinda not really because
they're just handing out it's you who
they hand coupons to this doesn't know I
don't know if you claim that's
employment but like
I'm sure that I stink would get raised
if a dispensary actually did that oh
yeah too many times to jump through for
the dispensary nobody would take tax
money on it right all sorts of things
well the shop would have to pay the
taxes on that as though it's sold at
normal price I bet it would be the bike
that the shop would have to take but
like there's a shop down here that's
adopted to strip a highway and I Drive
that strip a highway every day and it's
always [ __ ] filthy and I shake my
head every time I Drive and see that
sign so they need to get out there and
clean it up they're part of the highway
their little redheaded stepchild part of
Highway part of the highways all dirty
you know get out there and fulfill your
obligation and shout out to the shot at
the consumption clubs that did this
event I wish more the industry was
thinking of stuff like this now but
clean up or better they're little part
of the community all right I'm gonna
play the video um I gotta get the
volumes correct I apologize if things go
wonky here I don't know how loud this is
gonna be because it is coming from the
news 13 website we'll deal with it here
we go
cannabis club offering free marijuana
today to those who helped pick up trash
dozens of volunteers showed up to help
the pothole cannabis club clean up
vermejo Park into other areas and krd uh
news channel 13's katie Spencer tagged
along it's new at five o'clock
the goal of Sunday's get together making
Colorado Springs more beautiful one
trash bag at a time we're gonna go out
here on the west side and clean up down
here off the Cimarron and the park off
of 26 the effort started here at vermejo
Park where volunteers were picking up
trash for a unique reward as you bring
bags of trash back to me
I'm gonna give you a joint per bag you
bring back for those clean it wasn't
just about the free weed I hike every
single day and I see trash on every
single trail and it saddens me it was a
personal connection to their home so it
feels good to actually don't pick the
trash up you know I don't mind it
because I use I use the trail cleaning
up the park as well as the reputation of
the marijuana industry to show that we
are a positive impact you know there's
nothing wrong with every month and move
to other parts of the city
yep so every month that'd be cool to see
people picking up trash for pot yep yeah
so that shows you guys we're not just a
bunch of lazy stoners we do contribute
to the community we want it to be
cleaner we're at the park chillin out
enjoying our buzz we want it to be clean
we don't want to look around and see
trash everywhere right so because this
weird myth out there that because we're
associated with marijuana like we want
everything to be bad and destroyed and
stoned or I don't know that we're like
bad people and it's just nonsense like
we're people just like everybody else is
just we like cannabis - one thing I've
noticed being around pot heads a lot for
the past 20 years is a lot of them have
OCD
especially and I may sound sexist but
this is just what I've observed a lot of
women get got to clean some [ __ ] OCD
they get stoned and they're like all
those dishes are dirty [ __ ] all that and
they just go clean the dishes and it's
not it's just goes in their mind they
like those dishes can't be dirty it's
driving me crazy so they do the damn
dishes and pot heads get the same OCD
like there's trash everywhere I gotta
pick it up make my environment look good
it's just miserable I was a Boy Scout
back
the day like it was important that the
people around me that like when we went
camping not only did we do zero-impact
camping so I Leave No Trace camping but
like we actively pay attention and grab
other trash while we're out there like
we always had one pocket full of other
people's [ __ ] like on the way back
to camp at night just so that next time
we were up there it was a little better
than it was this time and like I do it
at my house too like when it's been
crazy windy down here so every night
when I get home I spent like two minutes
picking up other people's trash out of
my friend yeah we should put up a net we
need a trash would be really helpful I
want to give a shout out to four pieces
make sure you follow at four pieces on
Instagram I'm not sure their website and
stuff but if you check them out on
Instagram four pieces is a organization
that encouraged you to pick up four
pieces of trash per day doesn't matter
where you find them well it kind of does
you don't to go take them out of the
dumpster or some [ __ ] but I mean do your
part pick up four pieces of trash per
day take a picture of it post up on four
pieces encourage other people to pick up
four pieces of trash so good I'm
continuously blown away by should I see
out in the public
like what's the Starbucks cup doing in
my parking lot like it wasn't there 20
minutes ago I go on hikes and I find the
weirdest [ __ ] on hikes and I'll be far
from like the car or whatever where I
can't wherever there is I'm far from it
I'm like how did people bring a [ __ ]
pie and some Forks out here like what
were these people doing and why couldn't
they just take their pie container back
right pie container and a bunch of
plastic forks and I found a stop sign
out in the middle of nowhere one time
just clean your [ __ ] up people are weird
all right we are way off on a tangent
here but no the news article picking up
trash for joints it's a great idea I
just yeah take it all the way through
please yeah let's not give out the
joints in the park next time that looked
a little weird on the news there right
that's the one thing that everybody sort
of has against the consumption clubs is
that some of them have found a way to do
some sort of distribution and we're
giving joints away in the park for
bringing us bags of trash like that's an
awesome program dude getting people to
clean up trash I don't care how you do
it I'm gonna jump in and interrupt you
and do my part for the consumption clubs
I'm going to avoid the word distribution
sorry we would much rather hear the word
reimbursement well I'm just educating
you and our listeners so that when you
if you guys come to a consumption Club
don't say purchase don't say buy say may
i reimburse you for some of that fine
quality product they're like
reimbursement is the key word in these
places and this is why it's important
how you [ __ ] vote I'm sick of word
games you just call them all [ __ ]
yeah we're just talking about how some
head shops in Colorado we're still
playing the water pipe game because they
have to and it's just nonsense it's
because enough of our generation isn't
voting regular yeah the water pipe game
I want to define the water pipe game
because some people might not only come
into my marijuana store I'm happy to
show you the bongs on my shelf and tell
you how much my bongs cost but if the
head shop up the road shows you the
exact same thing they're not allowed to
call it a bong because if it's a bong it
might be used for marijuana and if it's
used for marijuana it's not really legal
legal to sell it's still against federal
law because you called it a bong yeah
it's 2016 we should be able to say can I
check out that bomb it really you should
be saying I'm in that rig right I'm sick
of the word games it's legal in Colorado
now and there are still places where you
have to say water pipe and I'm a huge
advocate for consumption clubs and
learning another word game makes that
harder well that segues into my next
news article because you said
consumption clubs in you're a big fan
but um this article says this is from
the indie the Colorado Springs
independent it was by NAT Stein the
article headline says City Council bans
cannabis clubs knowing full-well
lawsuit is coming and this is was
shocking news because just a few days
ago we were told they had eight years to
get their [ __ ] together to recoup their
investments it was a really weird
decision they're too dangerous to be
open but they have eight years to recoup
their expenses like well which is it so
the article goes a little bit like this
nice trying to hide that I
that real well do cancer [ __ ] fierce
[ __ ] and cheers [ __ ] did I drink
this whole aah it's like 1:00 in the
morning I'm just glad to be getting the
show disordered at all ginger raid
kombucha and I don't know there my time
I don't know I feel strange from it
every time you drink I see random things
floating in the bottom of it that's
kombucha you know I think I have a nice
little kombucha buzz going on to tell
you the truth anyway this article goes
like this America a marathon session at
City Hall on Tuesday featured City
Council dissenters of all stripes those
who push back on councilor Andy Pecos
proposed resolution opposing refugee
settlement those who delivered a
petition demanding repeal of the
recently enacted pedestrian access Act
those who bombed that promotes land swap
deal with the Broadmoor and finally
those pleading once again for Council to
keep the cannabis clubs on shuddered
none of that resolved except for the
club issue but not in a way most had
urged the clubs which were membership
based social clubs that allow for adult
marijuana use have caused consternation
for city officials for several years now
they first started springing up after
voter approved amendment 64 in 2013 2014
excuse me studio a 64 one a zoning
violation appeal in which the city
granted the downtown club a similar use
determination in essence saying that
cannabis clubs are like social clubs so
are areas zoned as such and then in
parentheses it says permitted in
multi-family residential commercial and
industrial zone districts more clubs
opened up all over town even after the
six-month moratorium on new marijuana
business licensing began in September
the city couldn't stop issuing a license
that did not exist then earlier this
month the Planning Commission
recommended banning the club's outright
counselor Don Knight took the ordens to
Council proposing the group prohibit the
opening of any new clubs mandate
licensure for all clubs that operated
prior to the moratorium subject to all
sorts of new rules and forced those
clubs to close doors after eight years
this is the ordinance Council gave a
final reading on Tuesday councilor Bill
Murray move the move to the table the
ordinance for six months so council
could work with the industry to develop
more moderate regulations
the end council voted six to three in
favor of adopting Knights original
proposal counselors Jill Gabler and
Helen Collins joined Murray in voting no
we talked about limited government all
the time but limited government is not
about number of employees it's about
limited laws Murray said returning
democracy into a morality play Gabler
said she was skeptical of the pup of the
public process behind the measure or
lack thereof Collins on her part said
she didn't think a band would be
constitutional Knight and counselor
Keith King both argued that council had
already exercised its right under
amendment 64 to opt out of the retail
side of marijuana night cited articles
from The Gazette and Fox News as proof
those articles highlight the club's
practice of offering marijuana to
patrons who didn't bring their own
sometimes in exchange for a donation or
reimbursement assisting other adult and
the use of marijuana is permissible
under act 64 is what this article says
this article is written in two different
colors so I apologize for my stutter it
makes my eyes jump around when it's in
two colors like that don't do that if
you type some [ __ ] that's great coders
and goers took their opportunity during
basic public comment to try and correct
some misconceptions amber Reis ik owner
of studio a 64 insisted that cannabis
clubs are benign relative to bars that
serve alcohol she says I get off at 1
a.m. in the morning and every time I
Drive downtown I see people outside the
bar stumbling around causing problems
getting into fights we are peaceful
peaceful people she said all we want is
a place to be accepted as human beings
smoking weed is how we choose to relax
and it isn't hurting one it's our right
presents mercier I hope I said that
right patron and cousin of a local club
owner took a different tack even if you
hate pot that's fine she said but we all
love money right think about what you'd
gain from these clubs and that's such a
good point I mean that's kind of a
tasteless way to say it but I mean it's
the truth think about all the money that
you're gonna miss out on if they closed
all of these clubs yep
- shutting down a bunch of businesses I
mean you lose you lose a lot more than
the sales tax payroll tax property tax
business tax and then all of the money
that those employees go spend back in
your community I mean I know this is
silly like there are places in the world
that already have these clubs owned and
regulated little counties happens to be
one of them
there's just Colorado Springs isn't one
so they're pretending like it's
impossible and because they're refusing
to throw rules down and just like
alright follow these apply here and be
done with it they're gonna be doing this
nonsense for the next half decade they
need to figure out that loophole of how
people can reimburse the club for the
product that they use there right that
is the only that seems to be the lure
that like the club has to have a way to
survive and right now a lot of the rules
that are in place are like they can't do
anything other than sell prepackaged
drinks and snacks like you can't even do
like cold sandwiches let alone like
decent food it's just nuts
um no way to reimburse for the product
like well at that point right how do you
exist as an entity yeah I mean how far
out in the middle of nowhere do they
want to push it like eventually it's
just gonna be like it like cousin Earl's
farm and then that's pointless we just
need we like having a place in the
congregating area dude with losers in a
big house and a barn in the middle of it
slap up an ad on the Internet to be
honest I've been in those situations
I've been out in the middle of nowhere
smoking because we had to hide I've been
to gatherings in every environment you
can imagine you know what I mean from
some random dudes house to some hippies
house to some gangsters house to I've
been in every environment smoking and
those social clubs are the ideal safest
environment nothing's gonna go wrong I'm
not on somebody's turf I'm in a club
it's come on hang up you paid the entry
fee you showed us your ID you're part of
our club we don't have anything against
you nobody here is in a different club
they'd come hang out let's smoke there
was a video that I saw years and years
ago where they're interviewing a coffee
shop owner in Amsterdam and that's what
the consumption clubs and Amsterdam are
called and he says he's been open for
like 15 years and he goes there's never
been a fight in here it was the bar
across the street the police are there
every night every night and I mean it's
just a different it's a
prynt type of intoxicant it doesn't come
with that aggressive tinge
I see anti-pot people linking like
anytime there's a violent incident in
marijuana gets mentioned like they post
it up though it was directly caused by
and it's like well then you wouldn't had
to go to Texas to find this story like
your town sold 17 million dollars were
the weed last year like if it was being
caused you could link that article from
pueblo but problems with the clubs are
just they annoy people that really
really hate marijuana and that's the
biggest problem caused by allowing
consumption clubs is that you annoy the
squeaky wheel I'll give it a few years
they're old there's never been a problem
it won't be here forever there's never
been any trouble there alright I'm gonna
continue with this article joking that
being from Denver shouldn't be held
against him activist attorney Rob Corey
reminded council that amendment 64 which
he had a hand in drafting protects the
activities in question and Colorado
adults have the right to associate with
each other consume marijuana cultivate
it distribute it and help others with
all of those things he said that's the
supreme law of the land the voters have
spoken and just like the other
constitutional rights which council
members swore to uphold the rights
afforded by a madman 20 and amendment 64
are non-negotiable Corey said that may
be difficult for you but that is the
reality jill Gaber asked Corey how other
municipalities in the state are dealing
with cannabis clubs not a single one has
banned them because they can't he
answered plus a city devoid of videos
for social consumption creates other
problems he explained marijuana will be
smoked by adults and groups no matter
what you do you can't prevent me from
inviting 50 of my closest friends over
to smoke pot together so where are they
going to go coming soon to a
neighborhood near you yep right yeah if
they ban the clubs we'll just open the
front door bro just come on everybody in
everywhere and come just take some
damage in my house we're gonna start dad
with some really interesting people we
go that route well that's part of the
beauty of the club I love that because I
mean I would go to the club once or
twice a week I would make an effort to
show up once a week or so honestly it
got to about once every two weeks during
trim time because we're just busy but
once or twice a week I'll pop in there
and try to spend an hour there and say
hi to people and I would always meet new
people and
sometimes I meet people that I wish
would walk away but most of the day I
would meet people I'd be like damn I'm
glad I'm friends with that guy yep
that's I like most of the people I've
met in the community and I wish I could
spend more time with consumption clubs
and I haven't felt that way about a bar
and forever but the gray area they
existed just annoys the [ __ ] out of me
at this point in time like absolutely
it's it's just ridiculous at this point
and that the more people don't see this
ridiculous is starting to really annoy
me yeah why can we yeah
I've said this so many times why can we
have so many bars but we can't have
somewhere to smoke cannabis it seems
unfair and they voted to regulate retort
that I always get for that is well you
can enjoy a one alcoholic beverage
without getting any sort of intoxication
but every time you consume cannabis its
to get high and it's like well sort of
but you can also consume a small amount
of cannabis and get no high I do it all
the time I do it
consuming large amounts of cannabis
products when I'm consuming a straight
CBD stuff my first couple of dabs
right that's just but like that's
metaphorical consumers like you and me
like one or two high THC dabs there's
still no intoxication that's just all
sort of pain kill it's different for
everybody and just to make that argument
as though most people don't go to the
bar for more than one drink or to feel
some sort of ease relief of stress or
blow off some steam or get a nice buzz
like I've been aware of the phrase
three-martini lunch since I was like 5
um it it's just a nonsense argument but
I hear it day after day from elected
officials people in suits people whose
opinions being printed in the newspaper
and it's just nonsense and it's unfair
how come you guys have somewhere to hang
out and congregate and drink one drink
and I don't have somewhere to hang out
and congregate and take one dab right
it's the same damn thing all right I'm
gonna continue because there's one more
paragraph it says at the end of his
testimony Corey made a show of
delivering the icy attorney a draft
lawsuit he intends to file as soon as
the mayor signs the club
ordinance on behalf of nine clubs and 14
individuals who own or operate those
clubs the complaint asks for the
ordinance to be struck down for
violating plaintiffs rights of
association freedom of speech and due
process under the US Constitution as
well as their right to life liberty and
the pursuit of happiness
religious freedom and right to medical
and personal use of marijuana under
Colorado Constitution councilor dine
took exception to the claim that counsel
has no right to ban cannabis clubs we
will talk about that in court
Cory said yeah so what this happened
they had four days to draft the new
rules and have the city attorney sign
them is what I was told and that should
have happened I think the day for that
signing would be today and as soon as
that was signed is this tourist of the
velum as soon as the paper was signed is
when the law suit went into so it's the
27th is when the paper will be signed
and that's when the lawsuit will kick in
is what I think I was told it'll be
interesting to watch this will play out
it sure will I do I don't want these
clubs to get closed I want to be able to
go hang out like we have rules for them
down here it's just none of them are
open because essentially the rules mean
it's gonna be a huge upfront investment
and the rules also mean they've got to
make that investment back with a quarter
profit apiece on like prepackaged bags
of chips and bottled water it's insane
yeah and those buildings are expensive
yeah that part of most parts of Colorado
Springs right now are really expensive
all right so I've got one more news
article I want to talk about oh I want
to mention something everybody was
reading a CBD article from Facebook
everybody was sharing it the article was
a hoax you guys it got all of us riled
up I was looking at it a little further
and that actual article was a hoax
99% of it's a hoax it's based on a truth
though like the FDA did set out warning
letters to different CBD companies but
it was my understanding that a lot of
them were the ones you and me were
warning people about a couple of months
back right the the Chinese nonsense
companies that are like two drops of
this superior cancer it's pure CBD and
then they test it and it's
your codfish oil or some [ __ ] right well
I read an article on Facebook that was
saying that the FDA sent out a letter
saw that that all risa are all CBD
products were banned because it was now
FDA regulated right that was not true
that was a hoax so if you guys saw that
don't panic that [ __ ] was [ __ ] it
may come down the pipeline in the future
but as of this time that was a hoax I
was clickbait people were trying to get
you to click and I bought the bait when
I read it I was like this isn't written
well it doesn't look right I need to do
some research it wasn't true so in a few
episodes ago continuingly we've been
talking about a raid that happened in
Santa Ana California when some police
officers raided a dispensary that was
open and full of customers right if you
don't know the which raid were talking
about hit pause real quick in Google
Santa Ana police dispensary raid yes and
I should bring the video right up
so these cops were caught on camera
destroying this dispensary they ate what
I thought was edibles on camera but this
article covers a little bit it tries to
back him up a little bit on that I can't
say that they were eating edibles I
wasn't there
this article kind of defends them the
headline says Santa Ana cops a notorious
pot eating video charged with petty
theft and vandalism the article is by
Nick Shu so I'm gonna say it if the
headline calls at the PI video we can go
ahead and yeah it looked like they were
eating edibles in the video I would
still say those were edibles the most
articles OC Weekly it goes like this the
Orange County District Attorney's Office
has filed charges against three of the
police officers seen and into in a
notorious video eating pot laced candy
bars during a May 26th 2015 raid in ne
Santa Ana medical marijuana dispensary
called sky high holistic damn that
sentence was hard for me I apologize the
video first posted by OC weekly last
June clearly showed officers passing
around candy bars joking about feeling
light-headed and tossing darts after
finishing their Scooby Snack the
shocking footage of the sky-high cops
went viral leading to nationwide and
international news reports yet in its
official announcement of the misdemeanor
charges filed today the OC DA claims
there is no evidence that any of the
Santa Ana Police Department officers
shown in the video consumed marijuana
products during the raid instead they're
being prosecuted for causing
tensional damage to legally disabled
video cameras and eating detour sample
protein bars and mr. thin stir cookies
that were not marijuana laced products
on sale at the dispensary but were
simply snacks available to staff I hate
the word laced I hate the word lace too
but you know basically the good news is
charges were filed the bad news is
because the video footage is so grainy
they're claiming or the cops are
claiming that what they were consuming
were non infused products that the store
had on hand for staff and one of their
charges if I remember correctly is
stealing those food items then yeah
we'll get that's an article so we'll get
to that yeah but you do eat just
listeners think about this what's the
last time you shared a candy bar with a
co-worker like pass that [ __ ] around
Michael how many times have you been at
a place yeah okay I'm because you think
about that the officer's name in the OSI
da announcement has facing petty theft
charges for eating the supposedly non
pot laced candy bars okay I want to stop
don't say it laced if you put it in
there on purpose and it's being sold as
waste is hiding it like a laces when you
put some when you take a joint you put
some special sprinkles in there and you
don't tell somebody and they smoke it
like yeah I'm [ __ ] up Neil yeah it was
laced ah-ha that's laced infused is what
we're doing here we are purposely
writing this thing only happens in crazy
people's minds like it's mostly a myth
well it's definitely not what
dispensaries do to do to get their
customers stoned right
lacing doesn't happen in a dispensary so
non pot infused candy bars the let's see
the officer's name in the OCD
announcement is facing petty theft
charges for eating the supposedly non
pot infused candy bars our Brandon
Matthew do we want to read all their
names I don't want to glorify them by
reading their names
another officer also faces an additional
account of vandalism for damaging the
disabled video cameras and allegedly
smashing their lenses into the corner of
a display case and cash register okay as
an extra dick let's go he gets an extra
charge the three defendants are accused
of consuming the food items and sharing
the protein bars with other SAPD
personnel
the press release states before leaving
the premises at the conclusion of the
search warrant to officers I can't even
say one of their names are accused of
taking extra cookies with them the DA's
office says it concluded a thorough
investigation of the incident including
the careful review of more than 16 hours
of unedited video surveillance footage
with cooperation of the SAPD while other
SAPD personnel like the bald cop seen in
the video saying he felt lightheaded
after eating one of them ate some
protein bars there is unseen sorry I'm
stuttering on this one there is
insufficient evidence that they knew the
food items belonged to the dispensary
and not their fellow officers the
release states there was also no
evidence that any SAPD personnel
consumed any edible marijuana items
available at the dispensary a minute
they expect us to believe this [ __ ] well
the article even says right no evidence
whatsoever other than the fact that the
cops were at a pot shop eating candy
bars enacting hi one is that one is then
left with the obvious conclusion that
these poor officers are so underpaid
that they have no choice but to munch
down on pilfered protein bars while on
duty that makes so much more sense right
like they broke in they smashed
everything and they they were like Oh
Chaz brought cookies like to their
military-style raid like you've seen the
video they jump out of their SWAT car
and their SWAT gear and they [ __ ]
bang open and unlock [ __ ] door by
kicking it the wrong way a bunch
screaming yell at everybody and they're
like what the dude in the back had
cookies how are you like how little
attention do they think we're paying
they sit there in the video and talk
about how they're all woozy from eating
the protein bars they stole like what do
you see the video and then you look at
these charges and it's like okay the
rest of that was just legal calm and
procedure like how is that comment well
it also says if convicted on all counts
the trio of uninformed snack fiends
faces between six months and one year in
jail plus fines so if they do get if
they do go to court they do get a jury
the jury is gonna watch this video and
convict them if they get real people on
the jury if they don't [ __ ]
to fix that real nice yeah I kind of
want to see what happens to these guys
if they go to jail
nothing good cops don't do well in jail
I haven't been there I don't know but I
could I've seen plenty of movies to know
that cops are not gonna do well in jail
the behavior is so egregious that we've
seen it for so long in this community
there's a raid for a dispensary or
whatnot and they come back the day after
the raid with video cameras and
everything's broken like everything
everything the walls the lights the
lightbulbs the doorknobs everything's
destroyed the carpets ripped up
electrical wiring is destroyed and it's
like well this you were serving a search
warrant it's just a display of
aggression you just came in destroyed
everything ambass you didn't even arrest
anybody no charges were filed you just
came and took everything destroyed
everything he didn't that isn't worth
taking and laughed like that's not why
law enforcement that's piracy that's
terrorism it's insane and
most of the public school with it
because they're doing it to the stoners
the stoners that worked hard to open a
business and try to help in a tribute
thank God it hasn't been a lot of this
these raids in Colorado but I see them
regularly in other states where a
business has invested years millions of
dollars to get up running start getting
successful and then the cops come in
destroy everything take everything worth
money and bounce in a year later no
one's been charged with anything and the
store is back up and running again yeah
I mean from my perspective that's why
they don't want us to use banks cuz
there's more paperwork to seize a bank
account than to just snatch the saves I
hadn't thought about it that way that
sucks
yeah yeah that sounds accurate there's
more cash in there they just gonna get
it and buy themselves more armored
vehicles and Humvees right these are
necessary pens the podcast these
defendants away by yourself I agree with
you I might support your statements my
friend is why I bring you on the show
like that's that's why I don't mind
waiting for hours in line to vote it's
because I started paying attention and
the more
attention the more caught my attention
and the more I saw the more pissed I got
all right start reading the news in your
area folks Mike you should just do Mike
drops you just think that Mike right out
of the sand a short drop on occasion
we've had enough gear problem so that we
break him like all right so speaking of
gear problems let me see how long we've
been going I'm guessing about 33 minutes
I haven't looked we are at 44 minutes
shot it's my friend 44 44 and to anybody
I don't know if you listen to the
podcast lately but you've earned the new
name of 44 and to number one was that
ticket and number two was your recent
adventure so 44 and 2 is your new name
tough guy um yeah that's all the podcast
we got for you today Mike thanks for
coming and hanging out sorry I had to
make the late night for you after two
I'm in late nights to get these shows
and there's the name of the game right
now yes it is you got the kid I got the
job you got the job
hope you guys enjoy it cause uh we work
pretty hard to bring a good one to you
yes we do we do that's the truth
I was gonna try to come up some smartass
to say but I don't have [ __ ] for you oh
right too many dabs to be a smartass at
this point in time I want to thank
everybody for listening to the podcast I
don't have a lot to say here at the end
of the show I don't have any sponsors
make sure you check out the secret sesh
yep that's it big shot it's my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I knew