[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 128 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right if you're a news
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
jabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you on -
thank you guys for joining me as always
I want to send a huge thank you shout
out to my friends in the mystic roots
band for letting me use their music on
my show
big shout out to Kat ku and the entire
mystic group screwed
[Applause]
off into the mic nothing happened there
I never do you did that freehand
I always figured that was pre-recorded
and plugged in oh no I do that in every
episode
sometimes I coffin the middle of it this
time I had something in the moustache
that was gonna make me sneeze but I got
through it are you guys that voice
joining me you might recognize that deep
sexy soulful voice over there that very
white guy over there that's a good
friend Jesse thanks for joining us bro
oh yeah for sure oh man any any time you
want to be here this is a great episode
to have you I just realized that it
these episodes are kind of recorded we
do two a week sometimes we'll do three a
week and then I won't do one for a
couple weeks and then we'll put one out
they come out once a week but right
about now is two years of recording this
podcast it's our two-year anniversary so
thanks for joining me on the 2 year ish
episode versus one person chance I was
sitting here quite a bit
I bet the folks that have been listening
consecutively consistently I bet they've
learned a [ __ ] ton of outdoor stuff from
yeah I hope so
and they're gonna learn a lot more today
and the folks that have never met you
are going to learn a lot about outdoor
growing or miss our episode is all about
outdoor growing this time you guys
thanks for joining us I hope you guys
are dabbed out cuz we're dabbed out
we're smoking some turf backs I want I
need to give a huge shout out to our
friends at elevate glass in Colorado
Springs I don't have their address
written down they do it's 517 South
Tejon and Colorado Springs make sure you
check out elevate glass that's all the
commercials for this one so Jess you
haven't been here a while bro have you
been good very busy good well that's
good for you I got some licensing
happening got some big things going on
good job man we've got our MIP and our
in [ __ ] cam member the initially so
many initials yes industry we've got our
holes your face a little used so grow
with no store attached and a hash
producing license so nice BHO hash or
like water hash co2 co2 very cool I
don't own the company that's not the
choice I would have made but by its
product they're not cutting any corners
with it I could tell you that much you
tried any of the distillate that's made
from co2 no I mean I love that I've
heard about it and I did not know that
was made from co2 or this here this is
sphere X I'm about to drop it
I've got two containers stacked up cuz
it's hard to get that bottom
out so I just turned this way to put it
on there and it trigger there it did it
for me in July that's some spear X it's
made from co2 oil and then they turn it
these they use a fractal distillation
process as far as I understand I don't
know exactly what that is but I know
that the basics and they pull out the
goodies and that's what it looks like
we'll take a dab of it here we can't do
it right now it's just too much of a
pain in the ass you'll do it after the
show I'll leave it here so we see it
yeah that's made from co2 oil so I got
uh some serious Terp so it's got some
serious Terps on it I'm gonna crack this
one open sooo good so now you're
reaching for the clear I like the clear
look honestly I like this sphere X
better okay yeah that's clear from
California it's the super Lemon Haze
this is sphere x OG Kush and I liked the
Terps on this one I prefer the sphere X
alright sorry my friends in the clear
those are my homies they listen to the
show I'm honest about the things I smoke
and review oh it's almost overwhelming
right yeah it's literally Wow it's it's
almost Tudor P well yeah yeah I can see
that little dabs of that when I put I'll
take a big dab of something else and dip
it into that a little bit so that it's
not so overwhelming yeah this one out
the sphere X I could dab a gram of it by
itself and knock off my throat it
doesn't burn that's super smooth yeah so
shout out to the guys at sphere X you
just got some free advertising from this
hey that happens when you make a good
product it does when you make a good
product Rasta Jeff will give you a shout
out um so yeah let's talk about outdoor
growing man everything's going good for
you you got the new the business run in
yeah some outdoor weed hopefully people
have access to some clones or some seeds
cuz now it's time to get those going
yeah especially seeds yeah yeah you
might be a little behind if you're grown
from seed you might be by now yes so
well I guess the first question when
should we put our plants outdoors in
Colorado second week of May is that kind
of that's like the earliest I'd do it
all right
I've put them out you know first to June
and they still yielded just as good as
the ones that went out the second week
in May alright I get a little extra
attention to catch him up yeah so okay
so yeah you got about a two week window
that's prime to put him out
yeah he's out by the the first weekend
of June though if you haven't done it by
then carry him out
scuse me a burp and carry him out that
weekend get them started get them
outdoors do you know offhand when we're
gonna start the flowering season
typically kind of varies from strangest
drained but typically it's around the
end of July beginning got obvious all
right that's here at Colorado
I believe that does change a little
regionally right that's gonna be a
little bit different the dates when you
put stuff outside the time frames are
gonna be a little bit different varying
from coast to coast California you can
put them out today there's probably be
okay I have friends on Instagram that
they're already out today they've been
out for weeks honestly yeah they're in
Oregon in Northern California there's
oiled out there though bastards we can't
do it like that it's cool we do crush it
though yeah we figure out how to fix
that all right so get them out there the
first week of June at the latest get
them out there get them ready hopefully
you've got some clones you got some
seeds they're going you've had them
sexed already you know if they're boys
or girls yeah get some plants healthy
don't get him too big because they're
gonna grow really quickly outdoors last
year a lot of people weren't prepared
for the size of plants that they were
growing and that [ __ ] got way too big
the camouflage got away from them their
fences way too crazy that's a good thing
but it's also a bad yeah so be prepared
for that your plants are gonna get
really large outdoors make sure they're
not root bound either that's really
important when you take them outside
yeah when you put them in the ground
I've just I've noticed through my years
of experience rootbound plants sometimes
they go into shock going outside
sometimes they go into shock in a way
that they want to start flowering right
away yeah okay and that's no good yeah
so make sure they're not root bound and
that's you know if you have if the
weather is holding or like you have a
greenhouse or some you can put out
earlier than the second week of May but
also right now we're around 12 hours of
light here in the first week of April so
if you put plants outside there is a
chance that can go into bloom and you
don't want that to happen doesn't gonna
revenge aren't they yeah yeah we're
gonna have they're gonna flower that
they're gonna go back and then I'm gonna
reflow or the party is gonna be all fun
plants yeah bad structure and limbs
break off and it's just no good
all right so though kind of be don't let
them get root bound and that leads me
into my next question perfectly I was
gonna ask you if we should plant into
the dirt outside or if we should take
them outside in pots my I mean my
preferred method being kind of a crunchy
hippie I like to plant straight in the
ground it's it's less work I feel like
and the plants just are healthier but
you know doing it in containers who've
is very very possible to last year I did
plants in 150 gallon smart pots for the
first time and I was really stoked with
those how they were your stocks gigantic
size your arms the the first and second
round of plants that got put in there
got stolen by some [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] Pheebs and I haven't talked much
about it but I had a horrible summer I
never mentioned it on the show but we
talked about some people getting ripped
off you were one of those [ __ ] whoever
took Jesse's plants so they didn't get
as big as name is you know if the first
ones I put out there would have got left
there the stalks probably would have
been as big around as a 2-liter bottle
um they ended up about as big around as
one of these uh six to twenty ounce of
water bottles okay Wow and that was with
about four and a half weeks of edge they
were gonna be beast yeah the the first
ones that got taken they were mice
trained government mule and as you want
to tell us about government mule I'll
give you an opportunity to do that sure
it's uh it's made by shimira I think
mara chimera
is a company that's not really in
existence anymore he's still around
though yeah yeah he just doesn't make
seeds anymore but it's a deep chunk Tom
Hill's deep chunk crossed with g13 okay
it's uh you were growing this [ __ ] out
of that yeah the pheno I have is like
pure indica it's real short and stocky
in this plant that was in the hundred
fifty gallon smart pot last year within
maybe six weeks to being outside or no
make it that long probably about four
weeks with being outside it was
seriously eight foot tall six foot
around six foot you know it was just
beast and that's not a strain that
really beasts like that so if it was
making it happy oh yeah all right so
that's that leads me perfectly you keep
helping me out your segue into my next
questions on accident here if we're
gonna put our plants into the ground do
we just want to throw them into the dirt
that's in the backyard or do we want to
dig a hole and put some good dirt in
there some good soil that we buy from
the store or do we just wanna use the
backyard soil I mean if if that's all
you have you can use it okay I wouldn't
know
right especially here in southern
Colorado the native soil it's pretty
hard it's pretty dusty and kind of clay
like yeah yeah it's been killed off
pretty good especially like in
residential areas and stuff yeah it
doesn't hold water well when it's dusty
like that the nutrients that are in it
thick because of shale based soil
there's a [ __ ] ton of nutrients in it
but it's not accept accessible to the
plant because of the structure of the
soil so you're growing you basically end
up growing in a pretty super salty
environment yeah yeah literally
so at the very minimum to have you know
pretty good results I'd recommend but
cutting your native soil with like one
part coco koi or one part peat moss and
then one part native soil and then one
part worm castings or compost okay and
by default that that soil recipe pretty
much works everywhere and you'll end up
with some really great soil so you know
that'd be your base so then you can
still add extra amendments to that also
if you if you wish you can afford it and
if you want to yeah but okay
that's like farmer recipe that's produce
gets girl on that recipe like in the
raised permaculture beds okay that's
that's it so all right so can we throw
that same recipe into those hundred and
fifty gallon smart pots that's it that's
actually exactly what I did I added a
little more aeration to it and maybe
went a little bit heavy
the peat moss okay yeah that's exactly
what I did so yeah and it worked out
great and stocks the size of football of
two litre gallons that's huge bro that
is huge
good job I wish I had pictures to show
me me too
all right so I'm gonna throw out a
little bit of a soil mix that I wrote
down I would buy if I were gonna use
hundred and fifty gallon smart pots
outside that's got to be a huge pot how
is that about six feet around yeah yeah
three feet tall it's like a kid pool
it's about that tall yeah okay 24 28
inches ish yes yes yeah so yeah that's
that's a [ __ ] kid pool yeah people
wrestle in there so I would put I would
buy some bag - soilless mix I'm not too
picky about that whatever the store has
I like the roots organic I like to pur
it's pretty much all the same [ __ ] it's
a little bit different it's all the same
you run a hydro store you know there's
all the same different [ __ ] routes has
more aeration in it like your Fox farm
products so I always feel like they need
a little pearlite or something at it
right and they need to be sifted because
their sticks and [ __ ] and Fox farms all
the time the hell are they doing so I'd
go some bagged soil it doesn't matter
what you use I would definitely put worm
castings in there I like the coco coir
like Jesse said I think it gives the
plants a little bit uh it's adds
moisture to the plants life their
vascular systems a little more healthy
they just seem more hydrated with the
coco in there I think they get more
flavor cocoa most definitely it it well
it holds water differently than peat
moss does well you're like doubling down
right there and you can use a little
more nutrient you need a little more
nutrient that's always I like to put
perlite in there yeah just to keep it
airy and fluffy and then it helps you
not over water especially in outdoor
situations you might get a rainy ass
night that provides a save your life for
sure the peat moss like your ATAR the
peat like you're saying and then for
pest prevention I we learned this from
our good friend Sean shoutout to keen
Cola if you're listening I like to mix
in the Quran Jamil and neem cakes if
we're going outdoors just to keep those
bugs away yeah that's that's part of my
personal I mean yeah you came real close
to my personal recipe would you put some
oyster shell in there yes very easy all
right
I'm learning outdoor from you guys I
don't do it myself but that's why I
bring you guys here's a trick on the
oyster shell add go to hydro store guy
given away okay go to the feed store
and get oyster shell for chickens it's
been collected off the beach it's not
ground-up its whole oyster shell breaks
down it takes it more time to break down
so put that in as a bit of a
time-release and then get the powdered
powderized oyster shell from your local
hydro store and you got two different TT
races available times yeah that's
awesome good tips you get all the way
through the season I like that you're a
hydro store guy that doesn't just make a
shop at the hydro store your own feed
store stuff yeah I have to pay for the
[ __ ] too man I mean right one thing I
want to mention you can use bottled
nutrients in your outdoor grow if you're
just gonna throw the plants into some
soil containers or dig a hole in your
backyard you can go to the store you can
buy some botanic air you can buy some
nectar of the Gods you can buy whatever
brand they've got there a and B their
bloom feed solution other bloom boosters
you can mix that up if you're throwing
it into some outdoor soil you can
actually mix it up kind of heavy you can
feed it pretty damn strong with that
stuff outdoors you can do that if you're
not able to maybe somebody's not
able-bodied we're pretty healthy dudes
we can do things maybe somebody doesn't
have the physical capabilities they
could throw a few pots in the backyard
and mix up some nutrients and have
somebody help them do that way instead
of having to mix up a big batch of dirt
and plant these you can do that you guys
for sure we would just as a ganja farmer
myself an indoor ganja farmer and Jesse
and outdoor farm boy I think we'd rather
lead people into this way of mixing up
some soil outdoors and letting nature
kind of do its thing it takes a lot of
the guesswork out of it this will prove
this will promote pest prevention and a
healthy environment oh yeah using those
bottled nutrients isn't gonna contribute
to plant health it's only gonna
contribute to big buds yeah and the soil
recipe so we're talking about here they
they actually help with the healing of
the earth they contribute back to that
they make the soil better so when you
leave there that that piece of ground is
better than it was before and that's one
you know you I suppose you can do that
with bottle nutrients to just watch out
for salt build ups and stuff like that
so right that's not as friendly and if
you do grow outside do it on your land
don't do it in some
at National Forest don't be an idiot
like that and clean your [ __ ] up like
take your bottles inside don't make
don't ya like Jesse said make it cleaner
than when you found it pick up some
trash shout out for pieces I think I've
told the story on some of the older
episodes or the earlier ones but a few
years ago there was a gigantic cartel
bust here in the mountains real near
here and I have family land that
neighbors the land where they got busted
on so we hiked in you know after the
cops and you know just to check it out
look around and the amount of trash up
there was just appalling terrible that I
grew up on that mountain and you know
it's kind of it almost brings a tear to
your eye to see that see that up there
and is it accessible to folks like us no
no you'd be trespassing
excuse me from coffin what if we were to
clean it that's not really trust back I
don't think anyone I don't think Bob
would say anything so that is I was
gonna say what was that four years ago
that happened we're still hauling trash
out of there and that's we make it it is
a pretty good hike from the road or from
where my cabin is but we make a few
trips up there year and Houston trash
out cones that's uh yeah it's ridiculous
how much was up there so it's just all
so it's ridiculous how much the cops and
the DA left up there cuz you could tell
the trash from the cartel growers and
you can tell the trash from the cops and
they just left [ __ ] up there the Dunkin
Donuts was from the cops and the beans
and rice was from the cartel yep right
free you told me in my one of my
friend's dad's was a police officer I
don't know how much I'm supposed to talk
about that he's not a cop anymore so
they can't probably do [ __ ] but he was
retiring at the time and they called him
and had him go stand there and watch
like once they raided everybody ran but
they needed the teams to get up there
like the DEA and [ __ ] wanted to go and
investigate so he stood there and
watched just made sure that nobody went
in that area but he said that he walked
around and they had little camps set up
like stoves with beans and rice and all
the all
food was from Mexico it was all Mexican
packaging and straight up making Mexican
dinner up there every night even the
miracle can grow containers that I have
cleaned up off their they have Mexican
riding on them there's no English on
them whatsoever
you're like segwaying into the things I
have in my mind for the show on accident
which is [ __ ] awesome would you add
anything to this soil mix before we move
on would you do you use azomite azomite
yeah yes down for next year's lessons I
like doing minerals so I do basalt
this is real similar to the Clackamas
coupe recipe from the forums build a
soil but this is old-school but I
haven't heard that name in a long time
really
basalt gypsum these are all things you
can find at your local garden stores
especially like gypsum dolomite lime
those are all pretty easy to find then I
used azomite those four combinations of
minerals you got pretty much every
single trace mineral in the world
covered right there that's gonna make
your plants
chirpy it's gonna make it healthy I'm
gonna smell real well and then oyster
show a shrimp mill fish mill some
something like that some kind of I like
aqua products I stay away from bone meal
blood meal like slaughterhouse product I
would use kelp meal if they were up to
me so I'm gonna write down kelp meal for
my style just make sure whatever I used
to yeah tons of coke mill alfalfa meal
I'll get four nema nitrogen yeah and
alfalfa breaks down really quick so that
can give you some of that real early
season you know boost to get them
exploded to you know pop bottle sized
stops for weeks your plants are gonna
take up 90% of their nitrogen during the
vegetative phase of their lives yep
yeah yeah actually you don't want to
over spike that that's why alfalfa Mills
good because it breaks down so quick you
in the middle of flowering towards the
end of flowering you don't want them to
find a source of nitrogen that can have
some [ __ ] up yeah I'll make them taste
funky and it'll slow down the flowering
phase rest of the buds out a little yeah
they'll start to finger yeah get that
little fingers foxtails alright so you
said a minute ago you cleaned up a bunch
of [ __ ] miracle-gro containers from
the cartel grow site you guys if you
want to Google the cartel gross
I'm sure you could find it it was a
cartel girl found in the Santa Isabel
National Forest area off highway 165 I
was about probably four or five years
ago I was well well covered by the news
around here so they threw out a bunch of
miracle-gro containers which tells me
that they probably weren't growing super
quality product no no let's talk for a
minute about why we should never use
Miracle Grow or any Scots type of
product first of all Miracle Grow is
made by Scott which is owned by Monsanto
which is trying to force the entire
world to be force-fed seeds that are
made by them which are all GMO produced
to be able to be sprayed by their
products that are made by them they're
ruining a whole bunch of things and not
healthy I'm just [ __ ] talk about a
circle right now but they're killing the
bees they're they're real it's all about
money for science is shown there pretty
much single-handedly responsible for the
bee die off right now so we do not want
to support anything with Monsanto in the
first place is why we don't want to use
any type of Miracle Grow or Scott's
products yeah if you're gonna buy stuff
like that go to go to a hydroponics
store go to your local grocer or get a
decent grow soil don't go get like a
turf builder at Home Depot or a lot of
people hate on the Fox Farm brand I
think that's actually available at some
of the larger hardware stores like ace
mayhaps Fox Farm Fox farm isn't amazing
but it's definitely not bad yeah it's if
you're gonna buy something at Ace or
Home Depot or Lowe's get Fox Farm don't
get the Scotts brand stuff yeah Pro mix
is available in most places the pro mix
is a good product yeah sunshine for pro
mix yeah oh the sunshine different
companies okay but it's the pretty much
exact same just different proprietary
blends of micro mixes good [ __ ] you
could hide that in bulk oh yeah they
sell that in so if you're doing some
outdoor Pro mix oh yeah go get that
that's not bad at all these amendments
give me [ __ ] golden out there but
let's talk about why not to use it first
of all the obvious reasons the there
Monsanto products but they're way over
loaded with the wrong NPK ratios
ton of nitrogen tons of nitrogen way too
much and that soil is loaded with these
little they used to be green when I was
a kid these little green speckles yeah
and those are time-release nitrogen and
basically there are little time-released
vitamins for the plan yep
so what sucks about that is you don't
have very good control of what you're
feeding your planet however often you
water those are gonna dissolve and your
plants gonna get that nutrient you don't
want nutrients going to your plant every
single time you water you're gonna start
getting salt buildup you're gonna start
getting crinkled leaves you're gonna see
burnt tipsy buds aren't gonna taste
funny so don't use that type of stuff
don't use any of that miracle girl
feeding go to a real gorilla store I
recommend botanic hair nectar of the
Gods I've seen great results from nectar
of the Gods relation it's my buddy Steve
Daffy no I don't know if you listen to
the podcast bro but you grow with nectar
of the Gods and the stuff you grow
tastes really good so I nectar the Gods
is good botanic air is good I'm used
advanced nutrients and I had okay
results but I was more happy with
botanic air by a long shot I did not
like psycho at all the psycho brand I do
not approve I did not like it there are
a lot of brands available to store
what's super hot right now I haven't
been paying too much attention to the
new stuff nectar we push some nectars
coming up it takes a while to get people
switched over to a line you know from my
perspective for a retail setting oh yeah
but botanic air and general hydroponics
are she's definitely reliable general
hydroponics general organics and then
Mills and Mills pays the bills I've some
good [ __ ] with Mills I learned some last
week some things about Mills that even
this organic growers gonna give him a
shot some endure suspense was killing it
with the Mills he was crushing it so
shot it dispense with the Mills was
doing a good job we get bio business
always vibe is especially for like
outdoor canna is a great line if you
want to spend some money yeah yeah there
the other Dutch and they're well
well-made jungle juice is there sorry
I guess the labels I just oh yeah it's
so long do the same thing I really
recommend if you can use bottled
nutrients I like to add humble honey
it's a good product yeah it's definitely
yeah it's got good stuff there so go to
the Hydra store get yourself bottled
nutrients if you if you confuse don't
buy that stuff at the hardware store
don't buy try not to buy your soil and
stuff at the hardware store their gross
stores somewhere if you live somewhere
honestly if you live somewhere where
that shit's inaccessible maybe you're
better off not growing there you if
you're gonna do it but we can't condone
it and we can't encourage it so you're
only listening to this for entertainment
purposes where you yeah it's illegal but
also it's not immoral so and you're
probably a grown-ass adults oh yeah yeah
oh hi you better be a grown-ass adults
totry gotta be it's an 18 and over show
so hopefully you're an adult alright
we've got kind of rant either
um so also last year in our area we live
in Pueblo Colorado this is kind of it's
not the valley but we are kind of in a
valley were surrounded by mountains on
every side burnable we're in a bowl
that's a great way to put a river flow
[ __ ] the other day we were in the Dust
Bowl brother there's so much wind and
dirty just blowin I thought my car was
getting sandblasted yeah I was miserable
and it was cold too
it was weird super sunshiny yeah
horrible so we're in this weird bowl and
we get really strange weather changes
and drastic weather changes it'll be
today I used my heater and my air
conditioner both in my car yeah me too
yeah right now it's a seven forty nine
in the evening and I've got the front
door open and two windows open I thought
I just heard the front doors so yeah
it's the weather it changes a lot here
my point is this caused a lot of folks
to get powdery mildew last year a lot of
folks that grew outdoors their plants
were riddled with powdery mildew so what
I'm getting at is you've been growing
outdoors for a lot of years now your
dad's been growing outdoors for a
hundred years
shout-out to the old man what's up
brother good day good to hear from you
hope you're doing well how do you guys
go about preventing and taking care of
powdery mildew outdoors you know
prevention
planning the areas you know we have
plenty of circulation around our plants
we don't cram them together we cleaned
we hollow them out in the Middle's we
clean shape the lake soap all that you
know only goes so far though you know
there's a few products a zmax I mean I
can't really recommend spraying anything
out of bud but if you have to you have
to basil max green cleaner just good old
h2o or h hydrogen peroxide h2o2 3630
percent hydrogen peroxide diluted at
about 20 to 30 miles per gallon will
help keep it away but it will not stop
it more organically T's would help like
you could even brew it to you with like
me I think Shawn would tell you to
Berlin I smell opposed to note some
karanji and there to see your I think
you're gonna want to fungus dominate to
battle p.m. yeah that will disrupt the
pH on the surface of the leaves yeah and
then like there's some some plant teas
you can make I've been experimenting
with Shama mill which is it's a natural
herb you find it in a lot of like tea
blends for like drinking like hot tea
it's considered a weed in most of the
world
it grows naturally here in Colorado so
I'll be able to a while crafted in the
fall I've just been buying it from the
health food store right now but it's a
natural antal antifungal and
antimicrobial yeah anti fungal bacterial
okay so I believe it makes it t that has
a higher pH was another thing I heard
but with those you know two properties
it battles p.m. pretty good it looks
like so and then also a added benefit of
it is its high and P and K so that's
just another you're going to help
increase trichomes yeah that's
I'm actually right now my current run I
gave half my yeti og plants a teammate
of this um I'm week five right now I
think I gave half of them a tea made of
that and then I gave up the other half
for that feeding they just got water so
I'm kind of kicking back seeing let's
have a wait and see what does what
that's always a good thing to do how do
you feel about is it oh so 28 yeah seems
like I'm really great yeah yeah I get
the numbers mixed up there's so many
others potassium silicon I think yes yes
a lot of growers are really respect or
preaching it I haven't used it
personally yet so but it's a different
kind of silica so and if you mix it in
with almost any of your store-bought
foliar feeds it really increases the
effectiveness of both products I see
that sometimes we I have used it in
conjunction with my integrated pest
management system and my plants will
love it it kind of helps the whatever
you're putting on the plants it helps it
stick a little better I think too it
works like a snicker spreader a little
treat okay it's got the the consistency
of dish soap almost when you open up the
bottle we stick my finger and [ __ ] I
know I'm not supposed you but I want to
know I smell it almost taste it yeah
soul synthetics make some products that
I would drink if you served me a cup of
like if I went to the monta factor and
they handed me that no that's [ __ ]
what is this it's sole synthetic
nitrogen blend light let's get it on bro
what is a nectar for the god smells kind
of good too yeah it's very similar to
soul synthetics okay it was soul
synthetics and another brand that I got
some samples of but there's a bunch of
molasses in one of them and it just
smells so yummy I didn't drink this
humic acid and molasses together yummy
flavor speaking of that full power you
actually can drink and it's actually
good for you that's funny
yeah it's a it's a humic and fulvic they
have to label it as humic acid but it's
actually fulvic acid
that has something to do with labeling
laws but yeah this there's no warning on
it there's no real MSDS for it
so this effort Jeremy from build a soil
talk about drinking it too that's what
kind of got me to research I was like
this guy's nuts nuts but he's got a lot
of great ideas yeah yeah I mean I'm
pretty you know he seems like a guy
concerned about what's going into his
body so most of the Dragonfly earth
medicine products are guaranteed it's
mostly just alfalfa and what such good
stuff if you need brutes use that lush
roots just yeah take your little baby
clones where the roots are showing and
just roll the clones in that lush roots
and then put them in the soil and
they'll just they'll be rootbound nice
day fat flowers is a good one too okay
I've run too big of a crop for the price
of yeah most definitely
that's a for a boutique grower for sure
that's three less or something insect
frass is amazing but we could never use
it at either one of our works because
it's different it's the price it would
take to make you know 300 gallons once a
week of the [ __ ] is ridiculous this I
can't want to give a shout out to a
product but I'm not sure yeah let's go
for it a big-time exterminator it seems
to be working
that's all I have to say about that
big-time exterminators right this comes
in a black bottle with a skull on it
this is big-time exterminator on it it's
pretty red it's mostly organic and it's
approved by the meed rules which is very
important very important and I feel like
I've been adapting I run a personal home
drove a caregiver grow for my patients
which is all legal and legit and I can
do whatever I want there's no nobody
looks at it but I adapted the same Emmy
Dhiru 'ls to my personal grow like if
they don't allow it there then I got to
throw it away also there's no need for
me to and it keeps me learning here also
yeah and there it keeps me prepared for
both places
my wife Bernadette my life my life she's
been studying that list very good and
getting to know pesticides I'm actually
really proud of her
shout out to burn she has had growers
from some of our clients calling her
and asking her about stuff and what they
can use in what they can't use cuz she
knows more about it than the head grower
for these gigantic grows so the email
out lists to everybody at metric oh yeah
I get a list of all the new pesticide
yeah yeah she's actually she tried
calling the Med to talk to him about it
one day and a certain lady with her name
starts with an M called her back and was
not cool at all but then we called the
department agriculture and she ended up
spending about an hour on the phone with
a lady those guys are super cool the
Department of Ag is really go I hope
they're the people that actually
regulate us one day
that's one of my hopes and dreams Gary
had some great points on the show that
we recorded last night that hasn't been
released yet everybody that listens to
the show has heard it by now but and
you'll hear it but there are some great
things that kind of go along with that
statement it'll be entertaining
so powdery mildew how are we getting rid
of that remind me again uh we're mixing
up some spray yeah Shama mill chamomile
tea
all over the plants yeah it'll disrupt
the pH okay I want to make sure that we
covered that one I bet adding some
silica to that tea to help raise the pH
even more maybe probably be real good
time exterminator with some Costa 28 in
there yeah be really really effective on
p.m. is what I would assume I'm sure a
big time exterminator we have it at the
store but I've never used oh really oh
yeah cool I didn't know that's cool we
have another one their products to the
enzyme big-time enzyme big-time roots
big-time inoculate yeah that's what they
got there you should see the story they
just had a good shout out those are good
products I like the big time there's one
with coconut oil and some other things
in it I really approve of that one nice
alright so if you guys do
here's another side note if you do have
buds that have powdery mildew on them I
know it sounds like the easy way out
do not blast them and turn them into BHO
please no please don't do that don't
press them and turn them into rosin we
don't want to taste your burnt popcorn
and powdery mildew you I haven't seen
any powdery mildew frozen yet I made a
joke the other day I said well since
everybody learned how to make BHO nobody
gets powdery mildew
any more truth you never see it nobody's
like I lost a whole crop to PM her yeah
we got PM's like no we have a whole
bunch of shatter that's what you see now
and I know a few people they think it's
safe yeah I could okay
here's I'm not a scientist I'm not a
chemistry student I'm not this is I'm
not qualified to give this speech but
this is what I understand about the idea
of blasting powdery mildew covered buds
ah some folks say that the PM will not
get through the screen good enough if it
doesn't maybe it won't maybe it'll stay
in the tube maybe it's right there
pressed up against the screen just like
your coffee and it's not getting through
and all the coffee is coming through but
what is coming through maybe not the
spores and not the mildew but there are
mycotoxins inside of those spores that
have been extracted just like your
cannabinoids and your terpenes they've
been washed off so you're getting the
mycotoxins which are going to affect you
in the long run if you if you inhale the
spores
you'll get that sooner you'll get an
infection in your lungs who get an
irritation the mycotoxins are gonna take
a little while to and infect your body
and it's gonna be different gonna have
fungus inside your body you know
mycotoxins running around inside your
lungs now they're gonna get in your
bloodstream I'm not a doctor I don't
know enough about that but I do know
that it's not a good idea because you're
just washing the mycotoxins off the
mildew into your hash and then people
are gonna make edibles out of that hash
some times and they're gonna consume eat
that [ __ ] and they're gonna smoke it
this is supposed to be something that
improves the quality of people's lives
not makes us sick er not [ __ ] us up so
please do not blast your powdery mildew
buds the only thing that I recommend
I've never done this
shout out to Shawn and Jordan that's all
there I don't know what else to call
them Shawn and Jordan some friends of
mine they say that you can take the 30%
hydrogen peroxide and put it in
distilled water and you can mix that up
and they say you can dunk your p.m.
covered buds or hoo p.m. dosed buds in
that and then hang them up and they will
dry and that will cure your powdery
mildew problem yeah I've heard that if
anybody has done that email me it's girl
from your heart at hotmail.com I'd love
to hear what your experience about with
that on that
object I've heard that you can wash your
butts in the exact same way like your
outdoor boats to wash the dirts and
stuff off of them yeah doing that exact
same thing but without the hydrogen
peroxide okay water he's done that let
Jeff know about that too yeah cuz I'd
like to hear
I had a friend named Donovan who was
known as DJ tanki Online back in the day
he I don't know if I supposed to say his
real name in his online that doesn't
exist anymore so we're cool he used to
say that he would rinse his buds off
just like a week before harvest he'd
just go in there and rinse him off with
the spray bottle and hose him down just
to get all the dust off of him huh which
is a good idea because in my opinion all
that dust that you kick up during the
grouse season all that it's been windy
as [ __ ] out oh yeah people got plants
out if it's this windy in the middle of
the flowering season people are gonna
have buds that are just covered in dirt
on one side yeah that's going into your
hash yeah you're just gonna blast that
right into the pot of gold right there
dirt extract it's gonna taste like earth
yeah maybe the buds is a good idea in
this region I'm gonna try it this summer
it sounds lazy but in my personal grow
room I quit sweeping around week six the
buds are getting sticky everything's
real sticky and I don't want to stir up
any dust or dirt off of the floor into
those buds so I will let it get kind of
funky from about week I mean there's not
a lot of [ __ ] on the floor I'm not even
eating snacks or anything but their
leaves and you spill soil when you kick
pots occasionally and [ __ ] happens but I
won't sweep sometimes from like week six
or seven until after harvest or at the
end of harvest
I'll cut off all the leaves pre harvest
and then sweep up and yeah pretty much
cut down the plants pre-harvest cut down
the plants and then sweep up and clean
up yeah I start fresh spray the whole
room with hydrogen peroxide water and
[ __ ] clean it up vomit yeah bomb it
clean it up redo the flooring fix all
the ducting that should be a whole
episode what to do between Bros we could
probably talk for six weeks about that
oh yeah untouched subject a lot so yeah
so we've been known for about 40 minutes
dude I think we gave the folks a decent
start all we did was tell them how to
mix up some soil so dig some big holes
and put all that stuff inside of it and
then put your little baby plants in
there I'm about May 15th to June
fifth ish yeah and then keep an eye on
them keep them watered decently just
real quick do your soil at least two
weeks before cover the top of the hole
with plastic that helps accelerate the
composting process of the of the Rodman
mints being broken down and being plant
available earthworms are great yeah
throw some worms and that if you can't
mulching is awesome Oh your hole size do
you know it kind of depends on you know
the size of your plant then and how big
it can get but a at least 3x3 hole and
you only need to go with cannabis you
only need to go down about 18 inches
there's no need to try to fill a [ __ ]
six-foot hole full of highly enriched
soil
I think it's expensive quickly yeah it's
just a lot of work and it gets really
expensive yeah go get you some bales of
pro mix yeah dude thanks for coming to
being on the podcast for sure for sure
tell everybody how they can follow you
on social media yeah can I can I shout
out mine
yeah dude chatter - sure you can follow
me on instagram jesse gross you can hit
me up on facebook if you know how to do
that and you can also check out my
podcast that i would have never started
without being on jeff show so well thank
you about a lot of and he's already
taught me a lot and everything but uh
it's the colorado podcast that see olor
ad ope podcast right now we're just on
soundcloud and then we're also on
facebook as the same thing and our
emails colorado dope 4/20 podcast at
gmail.com what'd you guys talk about on
the Colorado podcast cannabis lifestyle
one of the other hosts is 44 so nice a
special little flavor a shout-out to 44
and then our other 44 and too now
I tried calling him 45 you didn't think
that was too funny we still love you bro
you're still on the team Dori and then
my good lifelong friend despicable to
Eric dank Derrick whatever you want to
call them dirty Derrick he is pretty
involved that fish yeah fish yeah fish
in a long time fish number two Kyle we
all of us would have known him a long
time knows cousin two hands we all met
the cousin first so this fish number ha
yeah it's back up fish yep
but he's real active and the local
hip-hop and music scene so he adds that
to it and we are quite a bit more
unorthodox than Jeff's very professional
show so we cuss and talk about a few
gross things and chips we've done the
show oh yeah yeah 44 has been on this
show yeah true true I remember a moose
knuckle
[Music]
shoutout to Clint I hope you listen to
the podcast bro if you do message me and
let me know we got to get together if
you left something here last time you're
here it wasn't this virginity oh I think
we're gonna wrap up the show on that
note dude thanks for coming taking an
hour out of your day we're gonna take
some bad before you leave smoke some of
this fear X oh yeah if anybody out there
is interested in sponsoring the podcast
or if you'd like pronto or if you've got
a product you'd like us to review I
don't have any paperwork to read off of
them going no script lately you guys
it's so much fun free bowling yeah yeah
for free you doin that to a product you
like me to review I will not talk about
free balling in the advertisement of
your product or as a review your product
but if you've got a product you'd like
me to review or if you'd like to
advertise on the show send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to work something out with
you I think that's all I've got follow
me on all the social media on Twitter
it's at g f YH podcast on Facebook it's
the girl from your heart podcast on
Instagram it's i reaiiy rie underscore
genetics
I read genetics follow me check me out
post a lot of great cannabis pics I'm on
snapchat tiny genetics I love the way
you take pictures I'm on all the Krait
thank you bro I appreciate that you've
been at it for a while so that means a
lot no I like your style I'm on a lot of
the social media I should not be hard to
find so search me
look for me interact with me I really
enjoy a listener interaction it's a lot
of fun that's all I've got for you big
shout out to my ninja Spence and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you