[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 129 of the
girl from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Ross - Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I want to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band for
letting me use their music of my podcast
big shout out to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew
this episode's gonna be coming out on
April 18th I hope everybody is in the
middle of a happy amazing celebration
for the 4/20 weekend with 4/20 being on
a Wednesday I'm sure a lot of people
started celebrating Friday evening
Friday at 4:20 when they got off work so
if you're having a great 4/20 weekend
wherever you are whatever you're doing I
hope you got a fat blunt roll - hope
you're taking a fat dab hope you've
eaten some edibles I think you're taking
a fat bong rip however you like to
consume your cannabis I hope you were
doing it it's kind of weird without the
cannabis cup here in Denver this year
everybody spread out I don't know where
the party is I don't know where
everybody's going to be but I know where
I am going to be that's right I will be
at the secret stash if you want to learn
more about the secret stash hosted by my
friend Adam Hill I also heard a rumor DJ
jokey would be DJing the event make sure
you check out secret stash Colorado on
Instagram I cannot do anything to get
you tickets I was lucky enough to get
myself one ticket because of course I am
family I've got one for myself that's
all I've got I apologize I cannot help
you get in I can't do anything for you
figure out how to find their Instagram
and then there are instructions on their
Instagram on how to try to get yourself
into the event by the time this airs it
may be full so good luck I hope to see
it there I want to talk about something
that I saw on the Cannabis just recently
this is a little bit related to the
cannabis cup not being here in Denver
that looks like a lot of people kind of
back down on coming to Colorado without
the giant cannabis cup but I'm gonna
read an article from the cannabis and
the headline goes like this Cypress
Hills cannabis cup concert just moved to
a much smaller venue the sub-headline
says I think that's called the byline
that says fewer people will be getting
insane in the brain for 4/20 this week
then this article is by Ricardo Baca of
course from the cannabis stand it says
and the hits to the cannabis cup in
Colorado keep coming first the US
cannabis cup got booted from its Denver
adjacent home and its plan to stage a
cup in southern Colorado fell apart then
High Times magazines largest event moved
from Colorado for a greener more lenient
home in Southern California and now the
cup Sloan Colorado event high time
sponsored concert with Cypress Hill
George Clinton and others with a
cannabis cup award show tagged on is
moving to a much smaller venue less than
a week before Showtime
and even with mother excuse me let me
try that sense again and even with the
move to the smaller venue tickets are
still available instead of playing the
6500 capacity first Bank Center in
Broomfield the Cypress Hill concert and
High Times award show is moving to the
1700 capacity Ogden Theatre in Denver
according to promoter AEG Live all
tickets for the first Bank Center are
good for the Ogden and a limited number
of tickets remain and are on sale now
according to a media release the tickets
are $65 the bills other acts are George
Clinton and Parliament Funkadelic Action
Bronson and chronics you guys you've
heard chronics on this podcast I might
write it down to end of the show with
chronics I'm gonna put a little note on
myself there we go
I'll probably in the podcast with
chronics it's when my favorite rate
reggae artists chronics with two x's at
the end make sure you check that out
great artists I wasn't gonna go to this
show you guys because it was at the
First Bank Center it's kind of a big
event it's kind of a big venue unless
you're up in the front and those big
venues it's just a party and you only
really get to see the concert the
artists I want to see is the least known
artist on the bill so he's going to play
first he'll probably get like 30 minutes
to play but in a small venue like that
it might be worth it for me to go when
you're 65 and you got dreadlocks down to
your ass and a reggae band starts
playing and you know all the words and
you walk from the front people move the
[ __ ] out of your way so I just go right
up front and check out chronics and then
I'd be gone by the time I might check
out Action Bronson and
parliament-funkadelic that'd be fun but
yeah I'd stick around and see the rest
of it if I paid 65 for a ticket but I
just want to go see chronic see guys
it'd be a great time in that little tiny
club I'm gonna continue with this
article here it says so why didn't the
event sell surely the lack of accompany
cannabis cup Expo didn't help ticket
sales and with Snoop Dogg playing
fillers Green Wiz Khalifa and Lil Wayne
playing the 4/20 rally and Method Man
and Redman playing red rocks all in the
same week competition is no doubt fierce
is this venue downsizing indicative of
the 4/20 to come it's too early to say
but Colorado will surely see fewer
cannabis tourists this 4/20 because of
the cups move West that is absolutely
true a lot of my friends that normally
would come out to Colorado for the 4/20
weekend from California from Oregon from
Washington from
again from all over the damn place from
North Carolina they're not coming out
because there's no cannabis cup this
year there are a lot of vendors that I'd
like to hang out with that probably I
will not see this year because we
usually bump into each other either at
the cannabis cup or age so unless
they're at age in the winter or the fall
time I will not see them shout out to
the oil slick crew handmade crew the hit
man glass crew tasks and highly educated
everybody that shows up at all the
events there's one group in my head that
I'm thinking of that I cannot think of
Johnny being the no GU crew how did I
forget about those guys see all those
guys I'm gonna miss seeing them at the
Cup this year Johnny B I hear you'll be
on the road with the goo mobile I hope
to see you HAP can't
Jools all kinds of folks that I'm not
gonna get to see because there's no
cannabis cup it kind of sucks uh I feel
like I'm just ranting and screaming
about not getting a cannabis cup I feel
like a little [ __ ] suddenly I'll quit
whining about that on this concert you
guys it sounds like a lot of fun they've
moved it to this small venue but they
did put out a press release and it says
you cannot medicate in this facility so
there will be no ganja smoking that's
what they say they always say that kind
of [ __ ] at these events but this video
is tiny and they can see you from all
angles so I don't know what they're
gonna do if one person starts puffing
and then two people start and then the
whole place is smoking they can't kick
everybody out but at the same time you
never know what they're gonna try to do
they're gonna say no smoking they'll
probably just let you do in there anyway
oh sorry I'm burping the wall I'm
recording a podcast shout out to Dr
Pepper 23 flavors love it gotta happen
all right you guys that was my my news
article I'm not gonna read any more news
in this episode I'll go ahead and close
that web browser and we will go ahead
and focus on some emails I did an
episode about listener emails and that
spawned more emails somebody sent me a
message about a probiotic I mentioned
that I like to consume probiotics I like
kombucha and fermented products I think
they're good for digestion I have some
stomach problems which is part of why I
have a medical marijuana recommendation
it'll talk a lot about that I don't
think anybody really wants to hear about
my medical conditions but my stomach is
messed up it's wrecked I like to take
probiotics it makes me feel like my food
digests better it makes me feel like my
body's better I think your gut health
has a lot to do with your mental health
and your physical health so it all
starts in the gut so probiotics and good
food one of our listeners sent me an
email asking about ace
Pacific probiotic and to tell you the
truth I lost the message I cannot find
where that message came in I can't find
it on the Facebook pages the Instagram I
can't find it in any of my emails
um you asked if I had heard about a
product or if I am familiar with the
product honestly I've never heard of
that product I intended to save the
message you sent and go and research
that product and tell you what I thought
about it but honestly I don't know what
happened to the damn message so if you
sent me that message let's do this
easier send me it again on an email I
grow from your heart at hotmail.com that
way I'll find it
and I will read your email again and I
will research that product and I do
apologize for losing the damn email
I drove me crazy I spent about two hours
just searching for that email seriously
not all at one time
but I've put about two hours into
looking for that thing probably and I
can't find the message so I apologize
send it again I will answer um all right
our next email comes from I'm opening
the message right now this message came
from a friend of ours I'm not sure if he
wants me to say his name so I'm not
gonna but it says um I'm a new listener
to the show and I gotta say I'm a huge
fan I'm very thankful for the wealth of
information you provided all the
knowledgeable guests you bring on I am
listening from another state at the
moment but have plans on moving to
Colorado soon to get involved in the
industry any way I can I listen to the
episode about the meed badges and I just
had a few more questions if you have
your med badge does that mean you can go
into a medical dispensary as a customer
to buy products as well or is that a
different car I hope that makes sense
but think again thanks again for
everything and I look forward to meeting
you one day I look forward to meeting
you too I hope you get to take some phat
dad's hopefully smoke some flowers
together I would like to see what kind
of flowers you are getting in your
location and I'll show you what kind of
flowers we've got here and we can smoke
down together you're a new listener I
encourage you to go back and listen to a
few of the older episodes if you're a
new listener listened to I think it's 50
55 and there's an episode about
scheduling your grow scheduling a
perpetual grow there's an episodes about
building your garden I strongly
recommend listening to some of those
more educational in-depth informative
episodes um what else did you say here
you're very thankful well you're very
welcome
definitely very welcome your main
question is
the meed badge doesn't work like a
colorado red card or a medical marijuana
recommendation the red cards are now
purple which is a drastic change anyway
no the main answer is no the Colorado
meed badge does not work the same as
your Colorado medical marijuana
recommendation you cannot shop in a
medical marijuana facility just because
your badge it does not work like that
your badge we'll get you some discounts
and other dispensaries if you shop at a
dispensary it also gets you into some of
the smoke lounges for free I know that
if I wear my badge to the can of canyon
Camile does not charge me to get in
Camille has never charged me no one's
ever charged me to get into the cannon
Canyon because I do advertising and I
show love to the community but if you
have an M II D badge they will not
charge you to get into the cannon Canyon
is what most people would pay $5 at the
door so there are some perks of having
the badge just some industry perks some
friendly things that come but it does
not work as a medical marijuana
recommendation to get a medical
marijuana recommendation to get into a
medical marijuana facility you do need
to see a doctor there's no doctor
involved in the meed
paperwork and questionnaire so I hope
that answers your question
one thing I will mention if you do have
a Colorado medical marijuana card you
can use that card in Las Vegas in the
state of Nevada Nevada has medical
marijuana and they do a reciprocal
program where other states cards work
there so if you're a tourist and you are
in Las Vegas or if you're in the state
of Nevada before you go to the bunny
ranch you can stop and grab yourself
some ganja so big up to Nevada for being
a reciprocating state on the medical
marijuana recommendation cards that is
super cool so I hope that answered your
question I appreciate the email please
send me more questions I do appreciate
the listener interaction all right I got
another email this is a Facebook message
from a friend of ours and he asked me
basically what stops people or is it
possible for somebody to buy a package
of seeds and grow some plants out of it
and then call those plants something
else and then enter cannabis cups or
other competitions with something that
they claim is something babe red but is
actually something that they have
purchased from a seed bank or they got a
clone from somebody and the answer to
that is nothing is stopping that other
than
our community and people's morals but
honestly if I sold you seeds of any
strain that I bred you could take them
home you could grow them you could find
the keeper you could wait three or four
months until everybody forgot that you
had that and you could say hey look what
I created you could name it your
whatever I've got Arrowhead water
bottles in front of me so I'm gonna see
you could say you bread your arrow head
and you can call it this Arrowhead you
could enter it into cannabis cups and
you're gonna fool a lot of people but
you won't fool the people that are
really into the industry that know what
strain is what strain there are guys
when we go to cannabis cups you can
smoke a flower somebody'll pass you a
joint and a lot of these guys will say
oh is that Aaron's og cush that he grew
over there at the clinic and people know
what these flowers taste like look like
smell like we're catching on all the
stuff that stands out there are very few
things that stand out enough to be Cup
winners and so when we smoke these
things we notice them we remember the
flavor remember the high then when we
smoke it again it's familiar so if you
try to pass it off as something else
somebody in the circle is gonna notice
but honestly 90% of the people in the
world would be fooled they will believe
you but the only thing stopping you from
doing it is having some morals and not
being a cannabis dick I don't remember
the year exactly but I do remember that
several years back there was a person
who bought a bunch of cannabis I don't
remember where he purchased the cannabis
I think he bought it from a coffee shop
in Amsterdam or from a grower in
Amsterdam in Holland and he entered it
into the cannabis cup in Amsterdam the
original cannabis cup and he walked
around and persuaded people at the cup
to vote for him as the best they kind of
bought votes from people it wasn't a
legitimately one cannabis cup but these
guys want a cup they kind of stole a cup
from DNA genetics by buying another
professional growers flowers and putting
their name on it and marketing it is
their name to create their new seed
company to make hype on their seed
company but a lot of the people most of
the folks in Amsterdam knew what it was
the people that were voting for them
were mostly tourists and people that
were not really familiar with the weed
game so all the people that all the
local Amsterdam had smoked it and they
were like hey this is whatever's haze
they knew whose haze it was they knew
exactly but these guys called it kooky
could
mouki and they [ __ ] won a cannabis
cup by stealing a stream renaming it and
entering it into the cup and then
persuading other people to vote for it
by kind of buying votes by giving them
weed by talking to them by kissing their
asses there's actually kind of a
documentary on it
if you want to google it and look for it
a lot ago find the name for you all
right you guys I did a little bit of
research all I can find is some stuff on
IC mag make sure you check out IC mag
comm join the forum it says in 2007
Hager produced a reality TV show based
around the high times offices titled
high times office the show's twelfth
episode culminated in the 20th cannabis
cup where big apple seeds from Brooklyn
New York want a blind taste test against
DNA seeds that was judged by Robert
Connell Clark it was later revealed in
high times that Doc and Dom the owners
of big apple seeds were actors and their
entry
ouki kabuki was actually Neville's Hays
purchased in Amsterdam from a pot broker
with a good nose for good weed
so that was posted up on icy mag from a
poster calls himself Saluki he looks
like he's well known on this place here
so I shout out just read part of your
post you don't even know who I am I
don't know who you are but you just got
a shout out so that is the legend of who
q kabuki and how that went there are a
lot of rumors on how that went down
that's just what I found on this one
form kind of brings back a lot of
memories so the original question was
can somebody steal a strain and rename
it yes they absolutely can in this
example these people didn't even grow it
they bought it and then entered it into
the cannabis cup and it was Neville's
haze which is always gonna win that's
one of the best strains on the planet
when grown properly you guys I have to
take a quick drink I'm gonna press pause
I'll be right back with alright I am
back before we get too far I want to
give a huge shout out to our friends at
nugs in Denver Nuggets dispensary make
sure you check them out at 38 99 Quinton
Street in Denver Colorado they're open
Monday through Sunday 10 a.m. to 7 p.m.
they are currently only a medical
cannabis facility in the future they
will have a recreational side of the
building so we will be able to serve I
read genetics products to the entire
recreational market that is coming soon
stay tuned for that so big shout out to
our friends at nugs in Denver make sure
you follow their Instagram it is nugs
dot 303 shout out to the
me Gatsby alright let's get on with the
show I've got another email from a
listener this one is a question about
seed pack labeling and flowering times
and when you're looking at seed packs
online you look at a package and it will
say flowering time usually 56 to 63 days
is what most packages will say some will
say 60 to 70 days hopefully they're
writing the truth on there but usually
it's 8 to 9 weeks and they'll indicate
that by the number of days now what that
number is is the flowering time unless
you've got Auto flowering plants if
you've got Auto flower plants this does
not apply but if you've got regular
photo period plants this is what that
number means when a breeder labels his
package of seeds and it says that this
plant takes whatever 8 to 9 weeks or 56
to 63 days to finish that is the
flowering time that's how long that
plant is going to take to reach full
maturity from the time you initiate the
flowering period and that is when the
vary from the very first day you turn
the that timer to 1212 when the lights
go from 12 hours on to 12 hours off that
is now day one of that phase that nine
week period that's written on the
package has nothing to do with your veg
cycle you can veg those plants you can
sprout them as seedlings you can get
them like 2 inches tall and then you can
flower them if you want to so that could
be 20 days or you can sprout them you
can veg them for 12 weeks and take a
million clones and then flower I don't
know what you're gonna do with the
plants the breeder doesn't know either
you're the only one that knows what
you're gonna do with that so the veg
time is as long as you want it to be
okay the flowering time is what is
indicated on the package and it begins
the day you turn those lights to 1212 so
if that breeder Pak says that their
plants are going to take 56 to 63 days I
usually recommend going the full 63 days
unless it's completely obvious that that
plant is going to be done earlier
because of course some phenotypes are
going to finish sooner some are gonna
finish a little bit later I like to push
them I like to see what they're going to
do sometimes a plant won't start putting
on its bulk until the last couple of
weeks you might be cutting yourself out
of some weight you might be cutting
yourself out of potency sometimes those
plants will just throw on a whole nother
layer a trichome
right at the end you never know what you
might be missing if you cut down too
early so if the package says that it
could go nine weeks let it go nine full
weeks on the first run and then
hopefully you've got clones so now you
get to pick your favorite phenotype out
of that seed pack you get to run it
again and then you get to dial in
exactly how many days to flower that
plant for sometimes your first run with
the plant is just an experiment you got
to see what its gonna do so that's my
take on that the time indicator on the
pack is how long the plant will flower
so keep that in mind when you're
purchasing your seeds if you're looking
for a reputable seed vendor in the
United States I would recommend the dank
team calm the DEA NKT 'i am calm the
dank team calm let them know Rasta Jeff
sent you they have got things from
Gabe's green genetics sour seeds mile
hike an adventure they got a lot of
great stuff on there they may even have
some I read genetics I'm not sure what's
available you'll have to go and take a
look for yourself so let's move on to
another question this question actually
came from a friend of mine shoutout to
Lowe's I hope you're listening to this
there is a cultivar there's a clone
there's a varietal there is a stream
there's a plant that goes around our
region that is a Sour Diesel clone and
when it has grown properly you cannot
keep it in a baggie and a jar you can't
put it in a baggie inside of a jar you
can't hide this weed from anybody if you
put it in a baggie in a jar and in your
car you can smell this Sour Diesel
outside of the car this [ __ ] is potent
this is some super loud weed this [ __ ]
is crazy but when I give it to a lot of
my friends they cannot grow it I myself
cannot grow this string worth a [ __ ] I
know three or four people that grow this
strain [ __ ] amazingly it comes out
beautifully the calyx is swell up it's
covered and resin it gets that gassy
fuel funk smell to it so me being the
inquisitive guy that I am ah I know if
you guys had grow it so I asked them I
was like hey how do you grow that Sour
Diesel and all three of the people that
grow it successfully have told me that
it grows in some type of a hydroponic
system
so what that leads me to think these
guys myself included that are trying to
grow this cultivar this clone is
varietal this plant this strain in a
soil or soilless mix we're not gonna
have much success because this plant was
probably phenol hunted from a pack of
seeds by somebody that grows in hydro
this plant was selected for a hydroponic
system I don't think anybody growing it
and I this could be wrong but I don't
think most of the people growing in in
soil are ever going to bring out that
flavor and aroma that my friends in the
hydroponic system are getting because I
feel like some plants like hydro and
some plants like soil and this is a
perfect example of phenotypical
expression the grower that found this
plant probably grows hydro so he thought
look at this amazing plant that I've got
and then he gave it to all of us soil
growers and we're just frustrated
we're so angry so that is my opinion I
think that some strains and I keep
saying all these different words and
they're known as different things in
different circles people will call them
varietals and you'll hear a cultivar
also I'll say strains or clones some
strains or clones or plants are just not
simply going to work in a day and I'm
sure that if you took one of my soil
plants and you tried to grow that in a
hydroponic system you may not have as
stellar results as you would have in
soil it's just some plants are going to
like something so that's my opinion
that's what I think is going on with
that plant so shout out to Lowe's for
asking me that I kind of told him the
same thing and he scratched his head and
looked at me like I was a genius I
thought I would share that with you guys
all right I feel like that's enough
emails for this episode I've got a
couple more emails that I will read on a
future episode I feel like if I get into
one of them today
it will be way too long of a show oh
wait there is one email I can definitely
reply to right now somebody sent me an
email asking about cannabis and sex they
said can you talk about cannabis and sex
here is my take on cannabis and sex
do that [ __ ] alright somebody else also
sent me an email about cannabis and
pregnancy they wanted to know about the
pros and cons and the advantages and
disadvantages of cannabis use during
pregnancy honestly I am NOT well
educated in that subject so I'm going to
do some research and I will try to get
you an episode that features a little
bit about cannabis and pregnancy I'll
get that out to you in the future try to
do it soon because it sounds like
somebody might be pregnant right now
congratulations I hope that goes well I
hope mama is happy hope the baby's
healthy and I hope daddy is doing well
alright that pretty much wraps up this
episode you guys if you see me at the
secret session please introduce yourself
shake my hand say hello give me a fat
dab I'd love to meet you tell me what
you think of the podcast I may have a
microphone and a recording device with
me so we may be able to do some
recording if you're interested I would
love to meet you I hope everybody has a
great 4/20 I hope you've had a great
4/20 weekend so far nothing show's over
you guys I would appreciate it if you go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the girl from your heart podcast
find the review section and give us a
five star rating after that type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the podcast and I will read your
comment on a future episode I will do
that for you if you're interested in
sponsoring the show or if you've got a
product you'd like us to review send me
an email to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I will get you all of the
information that you do need I'd
appreciate it if you follow me on all
the social media that would be cool we
are on Facebook it's grow from your
heart podcast we are on Twitter it's at
G f YH podcast and of course I am on
Instagram I use the name of my seed
company it is Irie underscore genetics I
RIE
underscore genetics make sure you check
that out that would be really sweet you
guys don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and it's
also available on my website I read
genetics Colorado dot-com I think that's
all I've got for you this week so big
shout out to my ninja Spence and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
Oh
so easy
[Music]
so just coming from near and far to
execute
[Music]