[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 132 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right a pure zoo
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
Abbot
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank-you shoutouts my friends in
the mystic root band to let him use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat to the entire mystic
Greeks crew
against mystic roots is on tour this
spring they're touring around with catch
a fire they're doing five or six shows
in Colorado I will be at the Colorado
Springs show at the black shoot for sure
there's a good chance I'll be at some of
the Denver shows I cannot commit to any
of that right now but I will definitely
be at the show at the black sheet look
forward to seeing you there look forward
to seeing the mystic roots band there
everybody stay positive get down a great
week
I am I having a wonderful week it was
hot as [ __ ] here today in Colorado today
is the hottest day of the year that
we've had so far hit 80 degrees in
Colorado Springs I was over 80 degrees
today in Pueblo Colorado I was the first
day I got sweaty it was the first day I
actually got a little bit hot in the
large grow and I thought holy [ __ ] it's
warm in here so we're off to a good
start it's time to start making those
summer adjustments in your grow rooms
start thinking about air conditioning
and stuff like that you guys maybe we
need to do an episode on doing the
season switch all right let's do Welles
do some important announcements you guys
the secret sessions coming back to
Denver on May 19th the secret session
brought to you by Gatsby Gardens if you
want more information on the secret
session Denver Colorado on May 19th all
you have to do is follow at secret Seche
Colorado on Instagram that's right
secrets SEO on the Instagram you guys I
cannot get you tickets I cannot get you
passes I can't get you on the list I
cannot do anything to help you out I am
simply blessed to be at the event myself
I can't help you out so all the people
that ask me for help all the people that
sent me text messages I apologize I'm
telling you right now I can't do [ __ ] to
get you into that event so dude you
gotta do get on the list make your
reservation to pay your dues I'll see
you there i'll take some fat dabs with
you shoutout to the grandma gas me for
throwing this event also huge shout out
to adam ill for coming from california
to host this event for us much love much
respect to Adam hill without a DeMille
this podcast may not have happened you
guys animal kind of inspired me to do a
show he quit doing a podcast I felt an
absence there were a couple other
podcasts it inspired the animal had a
huge park so big big respect much love
to Adam ill all right you guys I'm gonna
turn down this music here and we're
gonna talk a little bit about let's see
I've been growing in Cocoa lately I've
made the switch I'd land a few pots at
the big grow with nothing but cocoa in
there and I am really liking it you guys
it seems like I'm watering a little bit
more frequently but one thing I've
noticed is that I cannot over water the
plants that are in the cocoa I've been
doing a couple of experiments I've got
one pot
set aside from all the other pots and
when I water I give this one pot double
or triple what every other plant gets
and it does not ever show signs of
stress from being over watered so that's
something I like there are some times
when I know I'm not gonna get back to
the grow first thing in the morning so I
will just heavily heavily water those
plants and I felt like when I was
running soil sometimes I would flood
those plants so much that I could see
them getting droopy and being angry from
being over watered that never happens
with the cocoa so I'm able to flood
these plants and they don't get pissed
off from being over watered but it does
feel like my regular watering schedule I
need to hit them a little bit more
frequently I've had to increase the
amount of water that I give them because
they are drying out a little bit more
quickly one thing I've noticed with
cocoa one thing I should mention with
cocoa there are no nutrients in cocoa if
you're just using straight cocoa there's
nothing there to keep your plant going
so you're going to need to feed it
nutrients almost every watering I've
been giving it lots of nutrients and I
do about so I water the plants twice a
day I'll do nutrients nutrients that's
two waters in one day nutrients
nutrients the next I'll go nutrients
nutrients and then I'll go nutrients and
then the watering before I leave on the
third day I usually just hit almost
clean water so they're getting a lot of
nutrients they don't look I don't see
any deficiencies I don't see any over
nutrients they don't look mad from being
over watered I'm really liking the cocoa
you guys one thing I should mention
don't let your cocoa dry out once you
see the top layer of cocoa drying out
that's when you're in danger of your
plants getting a little bit too dry it
happens very quickly on cocoa the time
frame when you walk in to a soil grow
and you see your plants drooping they're
kind of starting to get pissed off if
they're drooping in cocoa they're
[ __ ] angry that's one thing I've
noticed I've been doing some experiments
and I'm learning so that you guys don't
have to kill plants to learn I've got
more access I've got more space so we're
learning with cocoa I really do like it
this kind of segues into something else
I want to talk about over watering I see
a lot of people and a lot of grows over
watering their plants and they are
wondering why the growth of their plant
is stunted there is something that
happens when the soil starts to dry out
a little bit or when you're medium
starts to dry out a bit the moisture to
oxygen ratio in there really makes your
roots want to grow it really makes your
roots want to eat so they start
searching for nutrients they start
growing a little bit this
really makes your plants get active I
have noticed that when I used to run
clones in root cubes or rock wool I
would notice that my clones would
actually root the best when I would
forget about them and the cloners and
The Rock will cube would dry up a little
bit I really think that that dryness is
what the plants are looking for a little
bit more than the wetness you don't want
to be soggy all the time so it's kind of
a good idea to give your plants a short
dry out period you don't want them
getting wilty and crispy but keep an eye
on your plant water your plants
thoroughly and then keep an eye on them
and watch you'll see right when they
start to droop a little bit that's when
you need to give them water so start
learning right before that happens and
then start feeding them right before
that right before they start to droop
that's when you should be given a water
every time so that you allow that dry
out phase something that happens in that
dry out phase that we've talked about on
this podcast several episodes back as
the moisture level in your root zone
changes as the water level in your soil
ball in your coco area as that moisture
level changes so will the pH so if
you're feeding your plants a nutrient
solution that's real high-end pH you
pour it in there only certain nutrients
are going to be available at that pH
level but as the moisture level and
temperature change inside of that soil
ball inside that rhizosphere
inside your pot in your container there
the pH will change and different
nutrients will become bioavailable to
your plants so there are several
advantages to letting your plants dry
out just a little bit I don't want you
to let them get crispy but it is good
for your plants to dry out just a little
bit you'll see much more production this
is why I like to put my mother plants in
root pots or air pots or earth pots any
type of fabric pot that they can breathe
a whole bunch or they make those plastic
pots that have a bunch of holes in them
that have like the dimpled shapes on
them I really like that
because I feel like your roots get a lot
of oxygen and then if you're using that
in Cocoa your roots are going to be
surrounded by oxygen and they're going
to grow rapidly and your plants will
love it so that is my take on cocoa and
kind of a segue into letting your plants
dry out a little bit I love cocoa you
got to use more nutrients you definitely
need more Cal and more mag with cocoa
more Cal mag heavily with cocoa and then
if you're using soil
or cocoa or a soilless makes it a good
idea to kind of let your plants dry up
just a little bit alright that was a
quick talk quick ramble about how I feel
about cocoa and what I've learned about
letting the plants dry a little bit so
um let's move into the next part I want
to talk about collecting pollen you guys
yesterday I spent a couple of hours
working with a male plant if you've been
following my social media you know that
I've gotten a rise mail from a rise f1
seed he's a male plant that looks like a
true stud he plans I plan on using him
as my breeding stud I took him to about
eight weeks of flour and a flowering
room to see what he would do and
yesterday I cut him down but before I
did I collected the pollen now here is
how I collected the palme there are
several methods to doing this I actually
used a couple of different techniques to
see what I liked better just cuz I
wanted to talk about it on the show the
way I started you guys I was holding a
mason jar and I was just going to the
bottom buds and I grabbed a drumstick
because I'm the drummer I grabbed the
drumstick and I was just tapping the
male buds over the jar and pollen was
falling into the jar and I liked it it
was working but I felt that a bunch of
the pollen was missing the jars I was
tapping the bud pollen was falling down
the side of the jar pollen was falling
on my hand the site of the bud that
didn't have a jar near it there was just
pollen falling onto the floor there was
plenty of pollen collected but I felt
like I was wasting a lot so I had this
jar and I'm just tapping buds and I'm
tapping the buds the pollen into the jar
I got a lot the next method that I tried
was I cut the buds off of the plant and
I just laid the male flowers the buds
with the male flowers onto a glass tray
and then I was just tapping them with my
finger and what I was noticing was a
bunch more pollen was falling off and
landing directly onto the tray and I
wasn't losing as much the only problem
there was I was gathering a whole bunch
of male flowers so what I had to do was
sift out the male flowers from the
pollen because you don't want to leave
those male flowers in there if you store
it with those male flowers in there
there is a chance that those male
flowers have moisture in them and they
will mildew up inside of your jar and
moisture is one of your biggest enemies
to pollen we're gonna talk about that
here in just a minute so what I found to
be the most successful was taking them
the chopping of the tops I just chopped
the top right off the male plant and I
set it on a glass tray and just tapped
it
and I just tapped it for a couple good
minutes I was tapping it kind of hard
and then I could just see the pollen
falling out of the buds and then I
turned it over and did it again then I
picked it up and kind of tapped it with
my finger to knock off any pollen that
stuck and then I just threw that big old
pollen what I do just pull and remove
the bud just threw that part right into
the trash so I felt it sending it on the
Tran tapping it was my best method for
collecting pollen however I did get all
those male plants so I just used felt
kind of sketchy but I just used an old
ID on a plate and just separated the
male flowers from the pollen I kind of
felt like a cross between when you used
to pick seeds out of schwag weed and
also when you used to use a credit card
to do bad drugs it's kind of what it
felt like so I was a weird feeling but
it was definitely I worked it worked
very well so I've got a mason jar with a
nice like two-inch layer of a rise
pollen in the bottom of it and I do plan
on making some crosses with the Rise and
I also plan on making and a rise f2 in
the future here so look out for some
seeds coming up for my region etics in
the very near future I'll need some
testers I need you guys to run those for
me and tell me what they do and I'm
gonna get a bunch of messages from
people who want to be testers that's
cool I could deal with that I'm very
selective on testers you guys so when it
comes time to test seeds you need to
have an impressive resume if you want to
be a tester for me because I need to
know what's truly going on with these
plants I need reliable testers when the
time comes I will talk about that on the
show it's not time for testers yet
alright another method that I was using
to try to collect the pollen that I
didn't find to be very successful was I
was cutting the branch off that had the
male flowers on it and just cutting it
into six or eight inch sections and
holding actually kind of dipping that
into a mason jar and then tapping it at
the base of the stalk and it was working
but I was not able to knock off enough
pollen to make it worth my time and I
was also knocking off a bunch of male
flowers into the mason jar which meant
that I had to pour that back out onto
the plate anyway to sift it so it wasn't
really I didn't find it to be effective
so I think the best method was to put if
you've got a giant mirror or if you're a
drummer and you've got an old kick drum
head just drop an ugh the male plant
right down onto the giant mirror and
just tap on it and all the pollen will
fall off and then you use a credit card
or an old ID just to scrape it up it's
easy to collect pollen so once you've
got your pollen you're going to need to
store your pollen I recommend putting it
in a mason jar and then I like to put
that mason jar in a brown paper bag to
keep it dark and then I put all of that
inside of the refrigerator carefully
label your jars of pollen II guys that's
really important my jar says a rise f-1
pollen collected five five sixteen
that's easy enough I know that that's a
Rhys pollen and I know when it was
collected I've never really tried to
store pollen for too long I always use
it kind of soon I could imagine it would
last a few months maybe but I'm honestly
not sure if it's properly stored six
months maybe a year I don't want to lie
to you if you've got information on how
long if you've had pollen stored for a
long time and you used it and it worked
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I want to hear your pollen
methods on how long and how you apply
pollen I wonder how long you keep it
before you apply it and now what the
oldest viable pollen you ever had was
that's what I want to know all right so
you've collected a bunch of pollen
you've got it in a mason jar it's well
labeled it's been stored in the fridge
for a little bit here's something I must
have mentioned do not get your pollen
wet in any way shape or form Moisture is
pollens worst enemy a lot of people ask
me they're like
bro you breed and you grow seedless
flowers in the same facility
aren't you scared having that male
flower around or that male plant around
that's just spitting pollen aren't you
worried about seating up all of your
females um sometimes [ __ ] happens yes
sometimes I have grown crops it were
meant to be seedless and I've
accidentally discovered a whole bunch of
seeds in there and it was because I had
a male plant in the same area and it
just got cross pollinated
but the secret is water deactivates
pollen II guys so I've got two separate
areas one's got a male plant one's got
female plants the female plants are in
flower and completely able to accept
pollen they're still in there of ulation
phase they can accept pollen they can
make seeds they could become seated they
can they're gonna grow long enough to
make viable seed the way that I prevent
them from being seeded when I mess with
my male plant so yesterday I was playing
with a male plant about 30 feet away
from those female plants what I did was
I took a like my backpack sprayer that I
would apply pesticides or follow your
feet in there I just mixed up some water
in there just straight clean water i pH
hit at 6.5 and I sprayed that all over
my female plants and then I went I
played with my male plant in a separate
area I collected all the pollen from him
then I cleaned up I threw away all the
trash I threw away the pot I threw away
not the pot like the the container I
threw away the container I threw all the
dirt I cleaned up I swept up that room I
cleaned up the room where the mail was
then I took the clothes that I was
wearing and I walked straight to a
washing machine I took the clothes off
and threw them into a washing machine
then I walked myself directly to a
shower and I hosed myself down including
you guys I am 6 foot 5 and I have got
dreadlocks almost to my knees my
dreadlocks are mid thigh region and I
had to run to a shower and just rinse my
whole self down so I did go wash the
dreads had to go wash the beard just
wouldn't scrub myself I feel that the
water I applied to those female plants
made them unable it was a little bit of
birth control it made them unable to
collect pollen the pollen was not
allowed to land on the pistil and move
into the ovule because the water was in
the way I also feel that any water or
any pollen that was on myself and my
clothes was destroyed as soon as it hit
the water I carried those clothes up to
the washing machine I threw him in the
washing machine turn on the water
even the Hat that I was
whirring got thrown into that washing
machine so all the clothes got washed
the Hat got washed then the dreadlocks
got washed i got washed and then before
i went back into the grow room with the
females i went and grabbed my sprayer
again and i sprayed it in front of me as
i walked into that room so there was
water landing on those plants before i
got into there is kind of what i was
aiming for
i'm pretty sure that these plants will
not be seated the female plants that i
was messing with and yesterday after i
played with my male plant i went took
pictures of the girls i am 99% sure that
I did not see them it's all about water
you guys I have seen people set up a
screen like a screen door so you open up
your grow room door then there's a
screen door and they've got water
running down that screen door there's a
little mr. spring water right at the top
and it collects on the screen and runs
down that is their pollen catch they
also sell a UV light that will kill
pollen that goes in your ducting so if
pollen comes in it goes through this UV
light that goes through your ducting and
then it is just killed right there it's
neutralized so pollen isn't as scary as
a lot of people like to think water will
destroy pollen if you were afraid of
pollinating your plants just apply a
little bit of water and you should be
safe alright if you guys are playing
with pollen and female plants and male
plants in a in a small area in a house
and a home grow the first couple of
times expect to get some seeds it takes
one little tiny speck of pollen to make
a seed and pollen is so tiny you can't
get it all off of you unless you kind of
have some experience you know what
you're doing so don't be surprised if
you pollinate your crop on accident you
guys have been going for 17 minutes now
and you can hear the dryness in my
throat so I'm gonna take a quick drink
and a couple of dabs and I will be right
back alright I am back I'm well hydrated
and well medicated I need to give a huge
shout out to my friends at tur pecs
big shout it to the holter pecks crew
right now I am dabbing some cactus
cookies cream shatter made by the
friends at tur pecs and this stuff
tastes delicious great work you guys
also props to the grower whoever grew
this it was not me I'm not bragging
whoever did the growing here they did a
really nice job so great work great
concentrates you can always pick up your
terp x shatter your terp X live res in
your terp x waxes your terp x butters
you can get your terp x products at
green and healthy wellness at 4:30 west
Colorado and Colorado Springs make sure
you check that out
is a medical only facility so you do
need your medical marijuana
recommendation to shop there all right
many of you may know that I am a
consultant I do consulting I help people
build grow rooms I help them get their
grow rooms going if you have a problem
in your grow you can contact me pay me a
small fee I will come to your garden and
check out your grow and tell you what's
going on and tell you what's wrong and
help you correct and improve your grow
so recently I was called to a place
where this guy had powdery mildew and he
could not figure out what was causing
the powdery mildew the problem was that
he was not getting rid of his old stale
air I talk about this a lot you need to
remove the stagnant air from your grow
room you need to get rid of that extra
humidity you need to get rid of that old
moisture you need to get it out of the
room and get some fresh air in there
this guy is failing to do that in his
area and he is getting powdery mildew
we've tried a few things to get rid of
the powdery mildew we've applied a
couple of products that seem to be
working but unfortunately he had to
harvest a little bit early because the
PM was over taking a couple of plants so
let me tell you a little bit about what
we tried to get rid of this powdery
mildew awhile back when I first
discovered the powdery mildew in this
guy's garden I started applying a
product called stylet oil it's JMS style
and oil it seemed to be working very
well it was knocking the PM off of the
leaves we couldn't see any on there it
wouldn't come back for quite some time
but we had to keep spraying at about
once a week to keep the PM away and I
really didn't want to spray this stuff
on heavy chunky buds cuz I could tell it
was leaving a little bit of an oil on
the plants which was actually the main
ingredient that was stopping the PM I
just didn't want to put this oil all
over his buds so I didn't like spraying
it I researched another product and I
was recommended big-time exterminator
big-time exterminator is 90 or is mostly
citric acid or citric oil I don't
remember which one it is I think a
citric acid and it works very well and
keeping insects away it makes the plants
look really good and it also took the
powdery mildew off of the plants
unfortunately this product only worked
to keep the powdery mildew at bay for
about three to five days at a time
before we would start seeing little
speckles pop up it was getting closer to
harvest and I wanted to try something a
little bit more extreme we were ready to
go extreme we did not want to use Eagle
20 I am trying to only use products that
are allowed by the meed in my
will grow and in my caregiver grows and
in my consultant grows just because it's
easier to have one playing field so we
will not use Eagle 20 in this garden
what I did use was I got 30% hydrogen
peroxide and I filled up a four gallon
pump sprayer and I put twenty
milliliters per gallon of 30 percent
hydrogen peroxide in this water and I
adjusted the pH and I soaked all of the
plants with this hydrogen peroxide
solution and it took off most of the
powdery mildew and it did not come back
unfortunately there was one plant in the
back corner where the powdery mildew had
kind of taken over and I didn't see it
was so bad back there I didn't spray
enough it did not take off the powdery
mildew on one plant so my friend
harvested most of his plants didn't show
signs of powdery mildew this one plant
that did have powdery mildew I found a
solution online my friend Jorge
Cervantes taught us about this
I took a five-gallon bucket and I put 50
milliliters of the 30 percent hydrogen
peroxide in the bucket you guys whenever
you're mad let me let me back up a
little bit whenever you were messing
with this hydrogen peroxide be sure to
wear rubber gloves you need some latex
gloves you don't want to get this stuff
on your fingers it'll burn your fingers
depending on what kind of skin you've
got it could mess up your fingers I'm a
white guy I dribbled some on my fingers
it made my fingers look bleached white I
imagine if you don't have working hands
if you've got some softer more gentle
hands it probably could burn your skin
pretty well so make sure you wear gloves
when you're using the hydrogen peroxide
so mixer 50 mils of hydrogen peroxide
into five a five gallon bucket of water
and you guys this may sound crazy but I
chopped the buds off of this plant and I
was dunking them directly into the water
and swishing them around for about five
to seven seconds just swishing it under
the water with the peroxide in there let
me back up I would cut off most of the
leaf you guys most of the larger leaf
I'd give it a little pre trim and then I
would dunk the bud in to the hydrogen
peroxide and then I was hanging it on a
line with a flat fan an oscillating fan
blowing near it constantly to dry these
buds out as quickly not dry them but to
get them water out of them as quickly as
possible
I left the fan on there for two to three
hours and then toward the end of the day
I just turned the fan to where it wasn't
blowing directly on them and I gave all
the buds a squeeze
I cannot tell the difference between the
buds that I dunked in their solution and
the buds
that were not dumped the best part is
the buds I dunked shows zero signs of
powdery mildew I don't know if this is
something you want to try at home this
is not something I would do in my garden
but I saw it work you guys and when I
smoke this product it's not ready to
smoke yet it'll be ready in a couple
days I am 90% sure that I'm not going to
notice any of the peroxide solution in
these flowers so may sound completely
crazy but if you've got a plant that's
got to be harvested and it's got a
little bit of powdery mildew on it the
best solution is to get a five-gallon
bucket some water and a little bit of
hydrogen peroxide and go ahead and dunk
those buds in there believe I'm in there
for five or six seconds pull them out
hang them up put a fan on them and try
to start getting them dry safely and
then from once they get dried out from
that water you just put in there you're
just drying them just like normally you
would dry and cure them just like any
other flowers that you've cut down so I
hope that helps save your crop the most
important part you guys if you're
getting powdery mildew you need to
correct the issue in your grow room
something is causing that powdery mildew
to happen you are not getting enough
airflow in there I highly recommend
heavily defoliation your plants take off
all the extra leaf that will prevent
p.m. there will be less surface area for
the PM to build up on if you've got two
leaves that are on top of each other one
leaf lays on top of another and you get
that little water layer underneath there
that will eventually turn into powdery
mildew your plants are sweating on top
of each other and that sweaty space is
the perfect environment to create some
p.m. also another thing that we are
experimenting with I need to get with my
friend that's got this product but he
recently bought the clean light with the
clean line is it is a UV light that is
designed for the strawberry industry and
the pumpkin industry because
strawberries and pumpkins apparently get
powdery mildew very heavily so they take
this light and they hold it three to
four inches above the plants and they
just move this ultraviolet light around
and this light supposedly kills powdery
mildew my friend just got it he's only
used it a few times they say it takes
about a week of constant use of
consistent use to get rid of the PM but
I will check with him in a few days and
we will see if this has cured his
powdery mildew problem hey guys since
I'm talking about p.m. I have a theory
I feel like CBD rich plants seem to be
more susceptible to powdery mildew
I think there's something in the THC
that gives it resistance to p.m. and I
do plan on talking to Fox a little bit
more about this so the next time I have
Fox on that will definitely be one of my
topics so Fox we got to get you on the
show soon bro also the guys from the
Colorado podcast this is the second time
I told you we got to get you on the show
we got to get Jesse and his crew back in
here to do another outdoor grow less and
for everybody they're asking for you see
you guys got to come back soon all right
I want to thank everybody for listening
if you guys are interested in sponsoring
the podcast or if you've got a product
you'd like me to review send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I will get you all the information that
you do need I would appreciate it if you
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store find
the review section
give me a rating a star rating that you
feel I deserve I'm not gonna ask for a
five star rating I'm not gonna ask for a
1 star rating click on the amount of
stars that you feel I deserve type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the podcast and I will read your
comments on a future episode I would
love it if you'd join us on all the
social media I'm on Facebook it's the
girl from Earhart podcast we are on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast on
Instagram it's at Irie underscore
genetics I RIE underscore genetics I'll
check that out I post a bunch of great
cannabis photography you can see what's
going on in my life also you can follow
me on snapchat I post a lot of pictures
from the big grow I post a lot of
pictures from my life to snapchat follow
me on there my username is I read
genetics on snapchat check it out
there's a lot of stuff going on there
that you may be interested in all right
I would appreciate if you guys follow me
on all the social media I enjoy the
interaction with everybody I think
that's all I've got free this week you
guys shut suspense he just picked up his
whole life and moved out to Washington
I'm proud of you I hope everything goes
your way out there brother
also shout-out to Maddie and also
shout-out to Ciroc and nany I'm gonna
miss all you guys
much love to the whole family so shout
out my ninja Spence and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for
[Music]
Valley
to myself
[Music]
everything
you