[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 133 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversations new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big shouts - cat - and the entire mystic
roots crew you guys don't forget to
catch the mystic Ruthven on tour this
spring they're coming to Colorado you
know I'll be there well that means it
was loud holy [ __ ] that's what it sounds
like ooh be in my head I apologize if
it's echoing in your head
ladies and gentlemen welcome to the
podcast I'm dab the [ __ ] out I'm hitting
my new rig from elevate glass shot it's
my friends at elevate I've got a dope
new recycler got a dope new banger got a
dope new dabber shout at all my friends
over there make sure you support elevate
glass in Colorado Springs sitting across
from me you guys is the lovely the
traveling stoner my friend miss Lindsay
how you doing today honey pretty good
sorry I introduced you right as you're
about to take a drink but it was just
alright sitting to my left here is our
good friend white Mike how you doing
buddy doing oh man what's up dude I'm
hanging out taking some dad's doing a
podcast loving life right Bryce just
delicious ash trying to get that echo
out of this show I think I just fixed
that echo sorry about that go there guys
I realized it was happening I just could
not figure out what was coming from
becos been solved alright ah let's see
what do we talk about first oh I'm proud
to announce that this podcast is now
available on Tok radio.com I think the
show is airs on Wednesdays at 1:00 p.m.
Oh Tok radio.com make sure you check
that out big shout out to Jay citizen
jaya Tok radio
I should verify the time that arason
mostly sure that's Wednesdays at 1:00
p.m. you know you never know how it goes
I'll verify that by the end of the show
and you guys are talking I will check in
that I got from Jay and we will make
sure that I'm sung-hee the right time we
took a bunch of dabs did we shout out to
elevate I'm pretty sure we did that all
right also uh what a secret sash yes
secret stash was it a secret if we talk
about it here I guess we just can't talk
about the location right that's a secret
but a secret sesh we would like you to
join us Lindsay will be there I will be
there Mike you're gonna come to the
secret stash bro it's entirely possible
Mike white Mike might make an appearance
he doesn't make it to a lot of cannabis
events because he's busy at City Council
fighting for the rights of cannabis just
home with the kid yes I know a lot of
podcast listeners deals this one for a
second how's the kid bro good good I
just had another checkup today and all
good all right there you go Sorry Sorry
listen there's two seconds about the kid
for the kid how's the wife guys may 19th
we hope you will be there make sure you
check it out
secret stash underscore Co on Instagram
all of the information on how to get
tickets how to get VIP tickets regular
tickets that's all there come party with
us come take dad's with those come glob
out some of the best shatter some of the
best live resin some of the best wax
some of the best THC distillate not some
of the best people just kidding I did
meet one day one dude there that I wish
I would have never met I don't want to
go to a lot of them but this one's high
on my list
nice yeah the last one was really sweet
I got to hang out with you all night
actually Jeff so that was it worked out
yeah you can you can retell the story
that you told Mike about the dam I took
oh okay so we shout out to um Mary's
motivation on Instagram Brent I got to
meet him at a secret session he had some
of this THC disel it
um Jeff is a walk and always take such
big dabs and he took a nice chunk glob
of this THC discipline and you just
watched his whole face change and that
was it he was like super stoned
I mean don't get me wrong Jeff was still
dabbing Jeff was still like you know
smoking it was assessed he's not gonna
look like a wimp but I mean like he you
could just see it all over his face that
that dab changed his level for the whole
night and like that was it I kind of
remember that I remember being like hey
give me a fatty gloppy because I love
some distillate you can pull the fattest
so we should kind of try to describe
what distillate is so they take co2 hat
they and a hash maker will take co2 hash
hash that's made with co2 oftentimes
it's kind of black and goopy sometimes
it comes out kind of gold but then they
do what I think is fractal distillation
is what I think it's called and it it
could be done with steam it could be
done I'm not sure how a lot of companies
do it all the companies have their own
proprietary method but they pretty much
distill this product and they give you
pure THC with terpenes put back in or
some of the companies actually put in
terpenes that are purchased from other
products they're derive from other
products but what this guy had was just
pure cannabis with cannabis terpenes in
it
cannabis terpenoids and so it's all pure
it's just super pure its THC and turps
and you can take the biggest freaking
dabs and you don't choke yeah my lungs
feel like they got a little little smoke
in them I was like oh yeah my lungs got
some smoke and I blew it out and there
was a cloud yeah I'm not gonna cough but
I could definitely feel yeah you can
feel the face go a little bounce from
white to red to white to red
that's the usual yeah that raw THC
distillate was just out of this world
actually he gifted Chris and I that and
the added terpenes one and Chris can't
remember which Terp Ian was added to it
and it was a good week that was it was a
really good week
morning bathroom special Mike brought
over some strawberry banana dabs we're
gonna have to dab that in a minute that
sounds super interesting
some live resin I picked up the other
yeah nice is that from the the place of
employment yeah I picked that up at work
it's a botanical product though nice
shout out to botanic oh yeah they make
some tasty stuff I like to do tur packs
packaging that's pretty rad yeah love
their new packaging secret stash may
19th I don't know if we finished that
part up but I take dad's secret stash I
hope you come take dabs with us all
right so we're gonna talk about a couple
of things here Mike and I and Lindsay
Mike and I have lived here for a
long-ass time we've seen this cannabis
industry change we thought all the the
raids and all the cannabis [ __ ] has gone
away --lens he's been here for a while
she hasn't seen any cannabis trouble the
time that she's been here no and then in
the past how many weeks Mike is seven
seven weeks
how many raids eighteen now eighteen
raids in seven weeks in well they're all
they're not like stores or licensed
facilities or anything they're private
groves that are way over their legal
plant count way over that legal plant
count I saw him pulling a whole bunch of
plants out of one guy's garage on the
news though the number 18 only have like
50 plants but a couple of them before
that were in the the several hundred or
like 1200 1500 there I read somewhere
that a lot of these girls are connected
there was another set of raids up in
spring thirteen doesn't count that we're
all connected in like El Paso in Denver
County the our laws didn't change the
black market anywhere else and so
there's still a bunch of black market
growers that are sitting around all
winter going where's the place where I
think I can hide and no one will notice
me growing marijuana and apparently like
if you're sitting in Florida all we're
thinking that the answer is Colorado
because there's a shitload of people
from Florida getting busted growing a
shitload of plants here yeah most of the
raids happen to people yeah they happen
to be
yeah so where are you from over there
miss Lindsay missed the traveling stoner
I was born in Jersey so I guess I'll
claim that today like I never tell
people I'm from Jersey I've made a
couple of friends that are recent
arrivals and Colorado like over the last
year to have four so from Florida and
I've told all of them like you know if
you're growing wheat make sure your
plant count is spot the [ __ ] on because
it's only a matter of time before our
sheriff knocks on your door and is like
I hear you're from Florida well there's
a couple of things that work here like
all the busts are in the same area and
if you ask me because all the the press
stories all say the same thing a citizen
complaint was called in the sheriff's
went out to check confirmed the
suspicion that there was marijuana being
grown there checked the plant counts
found a shitload of plants and no
paperwork and arrested the recent
arrival from Florida like there's like
18 grows and like 15 of a match that
exact layout and so I think it's the
anti-pop people that have that that are
working on that ballot initiative most
of them live out Pablo West I think
you're just driving around looking at
new house or looking at houses for vents
and the stink of weed and they're just
calling on everything they find they're
not reporting on all the grows that are
perfectly legal where they knock on the
door and the dude's like I totally grow
marijuana here it's on 2% legal I have
blank number of plants and X number of
paperwork sheets here's everything to
confirm what I'm legally allowed to have
come take a look here's what's I've got
you can confirm it's all correct - have
a nice day
yeah he's trying to leave having a small
grow isn't a big deal right now no
having a little grow isn't an issue at
all they're not messing with the
businesses they're not because that
happens in a lot of states it's just the
home grows that are way out of
compliance with that law do you think
they're using electricity bills defined
just like yep I was gonna say they're
looking at that then they have a lot of
angles but at the end of the day when it
comes down to is that if you come out
here please do it legally get the name
work do I have listened to so many
podcasts of you to sit here and say do
it the right way stop you know stop
China you're making our community look
bad you're making us look like we are
trying to break the laws and trying to
get away with this none of us in the
community are trying to I have not
started growing yet since I have come
out here because my paperwork is not in
order yet I'd love to be growing I'd
love to have a whole you know two rooms
going but it's not gonna happen right
like I need to get my paperwork in line
first and I can grow six legally as a
Colorado resident I can't be a hypocrite
I know there was a time where I was
moving and shaking and doing [ __ ] that
should not be spoken of on a podcast but
we've told some hypothetical stories of
my past so if you're if you are hustling
on the black market doing your thing
we're not a hater we're not managed to
do your thing do what you got to do but
eventually there's gonna come a time
when you gotta start to think about
shifting to the legal market there's a
difference between making money to
survive and being greedy and having
these huge grows that these people are
getting busted for and that's the issue
it's it's these huge commercial grows in
houses for no reason like you're all
gonna go and sell that in another so you
know like I mean if you really think
about it it's just so stupid like this
is why they were in the national parks
ten years ago and they hide anywhere
they think they can hide it's and
they're trying to hide in Colorado they
just they don't realize how well
publicized the rules are have been here
because they're not publicized anywhere
else like New Mexico Florida Kansas none
of these places care about what the
zoning rules are for the shops or what
the home grill rules are in each city
and county so none of that [ __ ] makes
the paper just as weeds legal and
they're allowed to grow their own how
strange and so they think oh I can move
to Colorado I can go to the gross store
I can throw down the 18 grand or
whatever I've managed to save up on grow
equipment rent a house pull a crop or to
drive it all back to Florida and bam
I've got four on our grand and they just
don't see how insane that plan is like
the gross stores gonna sell you all that
[ __ ] no problem
the when you plug it all in you're gonna
have to have the power company come out
by the time the power company's done
upgrading you all your neighbors want to
know what the [ __ ] you're doing as soon
as it smells like weed which is gonna be
about what eight weeks later um one of
them's gonna call the sheriff and go
would you knock on this bucks door yeah
he had some guy building some [ __ ] their
new electricity watch them carrying a
bunch of [ __ ] now it reeks I'm pretty
sure he's got an illegal operation yeah
and this is all assuming you don't have
a landlord that's gonna be checking on
everything and all of that jazz as well
do a couple of these guys were like just
showed up right at a house went to
bought some ply board it's sort of ply
boarding over exterior windows like one
dude had a pit bull chained to a window
well like these idiots in the most
extreme sense because I mean if you
think about it you could move here grow
even your six plant just being here as
an adult limit and if you were dumb
enough to take the risk to move that
back to Florida just that small or
harvest you could still make a fair
living like it wouldn't be extravagant
you wouldn't be rolling back and forth
in a brand-new Escalade but I mean you
could make enough to pay your rent and
pay your bills but they're trying to do
hundreds of plants because they're
stupid and greedy and they think no
one's gonna notice here and it's that's
just so insane like it's a neighborhood
even if you do get it harvested and
dried and cured you're gonna get pulled
the [ __ ] over as soon as you cross it
again a couple of them got busted
halfway to where they were headed
because they just turn signal violation
hundreds of pounds of weed in the car
smells like hundreds of pounds of weed
in the car
y'all know how bad your quarter-ounce
stinks on the way home from picking it
up like magnify that by a hundred pounds
yeah because you guys aren't being smart
and vacuum-sealing it and like doing it
the right way you're just putting it in
trash bags and throwing it in the back
and praying to God you'll make it their
bags is the gangster way to carry double
bag that [ __ ] only be five
my little friend that's not real tall he
used to give me the trash bag the clear
trash bags full yeah back in the day
that hypothetically happened from you
know that allegedly it's just insane the
days of coming up and grown big
ridiculous amounts of cannabis in
Colorado maybe come into it and here
it's still possible if you're gung ho
you got to be smart about it but be
careful you guys if you're gonna come
here from another state and think you're
gonna set up shop read the rules get get
really familiar with the rules be
careful the two parts of this that
pissed me off the most is like a now we
got to pay to send these folks to jail
and be there [ __ ] up our reputation
and they're giving a whole bunch of fire
to the anti-pop people and they didn't
need to fire they they've lost two years
in a row every time they smoke up they
got told [ __ ] off and they're really
really angry they don't need fuel for
that fire yeah 18 busts in seven weeks
like Jules
in every single one of them is out in
public 'le um I mean you've lived here
for how long public hasn't report [ __ ]
um and all of a sudden we've got 18
successful patro tips in seven weeks
like there's some weird [ __ ] going on
right now and people didn't see coming
so if you're growing up webelo be
careful that's that's Colorado ID right
now like gearing up for the election we
got a new president coming in everywhere
away everywhere if you're growing
everywhere you're on get your [ __ ]
cleaned up now is a good time to think
about it if you if you're a medical
marijuana grower if you've got a plant
count count your [ __ ] plants go
consider like go get one under your
plant count so that if some [ __ ] goes
wrong and you break off a branch and it
looks like an extra plan on accident go
check your gram wait get to your perfect
gram weight and then roll up a fat joint
and smoking so you're a fat joint
underneath your gram limit I just go get
your [ __ ] in order my clique to me like
that's that's no that's really good I
had that thought the other day I was
I've got a nice hash pile going right
now and I was like hmm like I can't even
take this like when I move technically
I'll have to break the law
moving this from house one to house too
because I'm not supposed to have that
much [ __ ] out in the world I'm how over
my grand
it wait how much weight you've got it
can we talk about tricks ninja plant
count in your medical marijuana card can
we talk about no no but just
theoretically just for the legal rules
because at the same time I was thinking
about needing to go get my card again
like a lot of this applies to us too
like we're not special right we've got
deadlines to reapply and dates the
following card caps to adhere to yeah we
do yes I gotta go I get to go I get to
go to I get my doctor my MMJ doctor a
shout out uh I need to go no he did he
would do [ __ ] line is long enough it's
true that is true yeah sorry guys Mike
just made a really good idea Oh takes
like four weeks to get into the [ __ ]
dude dibs
I've gotta go may 19th to go renew my
sheets pay don't you give me his number
one or two people but don't show I just
was just trying to prove a point it's
okay no but all Bruce needs some
business shyness is the same one up here
though there yeah you catch him on his
Springs day yeah he's in Springs like
four days a week he's in Pueblo one day
a week so shout out to my MMJ doctor he
knows he knows my conditions he knows me
well when I walk in he just starts right
now
good to see ya what's this like the
tenth time and I'm like you ten years in
a row buddy good to see you I've been a
medical marijuana patient for probably
close to ten years I'd say Mike's
thinking back Mike's got a better I have
a seven or eight for sure alright did
you guys go get him together for the
first time around similar time it was
the same same year within two years he
had one before me yeah I was running a
shop and that's right he came in as a
patient with one with another patient
and we got along those days it was
insane but that place was fun alright
we're reminiscing on chatterbox you know
it's good people like hearing insight to
our lives
they really do because like guys like
Seb shout out to Rasta Seb oh they don't
get to sit around and be on a podcast
and take dad's and live
life that we get to live they got dodge
ostriches what does that [ __ ] thing
he said almost run over it was it an emu
whatever that thing was said what was
that thing tell me bro posted a video he
was driving in Australia and a giant
long-legged bird it looked like an
ostrich a mere it may be me it could
have been what I thought I guessed but
it could have been an emu Randy for
network of the video camera while you're
driving broke giant running birds wheezy
it's 2016 everyone's got a dashcam of
some sort going on everywhere escape and
snapchatting something don't judge the
dude he lives in Australia I'm just I'm
just messing with so actually somebody
actually said well you're in Australia
everything is trying to kill you [ __ ]
attention Russia where everyone has a
camera on the mounted on their dashboard
16 yeah it could be for different
reasons like there it's because the
other thing someone sits out mugs use
really I use a cane something Wow hi how
about you guys I want to give you a big
shout out to my friends over to elevate
glass and the lovely ladies and the one
gentleman that run the place over at
elevate glass and also my good friends
at hemp higher elevation masterpiece
productions make sure you guys check out
the showroom it's a elevate glass it's
5:17 South Tejon in Colorado Springs
Colorado make sure you tell them Russ to
Jeff sent you please do that I've got a
brand new recycler rig here with the
brand new banger on it and I filled it
just to the perfect level and you can
you can really pull so hard you don't
get water in your face and you get a big
fat go I'd be bad and I think it's nice
it does it does it does all right so uh
Mike you were talking about some
political stuff is why we've got you
here oh it's just the one thing I wanted
to throw in right now is uh a lot of
people are focused on the November
election as they should be yay for
paying attention good for you but
podcast the other night where he was
like really mean to the listeners and
you're like to hear
but there's primary elections too in
everybody's area in these matter and no
one ever turns out for these um the
example down here is this November we
might be voting to ban the recreational
marijuana industry however before we
even get to that vote possibly happening
there will be election election primary
election that are that sorry about that
space the word a primary election down
here will reelect people like city
councilman and County Commissioners in
the local judge and maybe there'll be a
couple of small local issues they get
handled like city or county why what are
you going to run for ah nothing in this
round but if two people down here
happened to get elected instead of the
two people that currently have this job
getting reelected retail marijuana could
go away anyway because the number of Pro
and anti marijuana votes would swing
that far with just two people getting
swapped out so there's a lot going on
politically in everyone's area that they
need to be paying attention to right now
and right now is the time to go find out
if you're registered to vote
go find out how that works in your area
in Colorado it's awesome they just mail
it to your house you don't have to do
anything but check the mail when it
shows up you fill it out you take it to
a drop-off point you get the sticker
that says I voted and you get to be
awesome for like the whole next year
it's really that simple in other places
it's a little harder you got to go stand
in line but do it like figure out how to
do it now is the time to figure out how
to do it I know it's not till November I
know that's a long time away I know a
lot of you were like I just planted my
outdoor fuck-off like after harvest
right now like the elections not so
November why pay attention I'm not
saying I'm not telling them to [ __ ] off
I'm saying that I'm thinking there's no
they don't want to pay attention to
politics yet because that's just months
and months away like but now's the time
to get registered now is the time to
start paying attention to what's going
on in your area and start
to making sure you've done what you need
to do to actually vote I'm sick of the
marijuana community just being a
non-existent entity politically like we
outnumber Christians think about the
number of Christians that annoy you
constantly because they're doing [ __ ]
politically think about how powerful
that particular group of people is in
the United States we outnumber NRA
members by five times and that's just
the DA's estimate for how many people
smoke pot in the u.s. there are more pot
smokers than gun toters yep Wow don't
matter at all politically why because we
don't show up I got no hatred for
anybody with a gun if I said that
condescendingly anybody carries a
firearm when you think about how much
influence the NRA wields and then you
look up the actual number of NRA members
and their actual operating budget it's
terrifying how a group that small can be
that influential if we were just to get
a little bit organized or at least just
all show up on Election Day we could
have a serious Authority coast-to-coast
but we don't and we definitely those of
us that do show up don't show up unified
even a little bit and I'm yeah I'm
pushing your listeners get out get out
we need so we all we all will take a
party bus anywhere if you put a dab rig
on a bus oh yeah and a bhag on a bus
right put some Rasta man with dreadlocks
and some reggae music
Rasta man driving at reggae music
playing real light and you paint a red
gold and green people get on there and
smoke some [ __ ] hash and smoke some
joints and have a good ass social time
Boop let's let's get one of those and
pick up stoners and driving them to
polling places to get them to vote it's
not an unheard of idea I'm hoping a
couple of the industry players do
something similar yes somebody somebody
that doesn't work a lot and have a
podcast and drive too much already help
me out with this put together like some
buses did you like a show this is real
like Denver that would totally fly I
think something like blow that might not
get away with driving them smoking them
out while you drive them requires a lot
of extra insurance and a much much
larger vehicle but every election
there's groups that grab vans and go
bust seniors and other people that love
to vote and have trouble sometimes
getting to the polling station I'm
taking the seniors often vote though
whatever way they want them to vote like
they'll go round up those people on
signal
free joint if you if you vote I think
but just giving them a ride that's
helping someone perform their civic duty
I'd love to see someone getting legal
trouble for that that would be an
awesome court case yeah get involved
start googling after the show you could
do it right now where you listen if
you're at work you could in your cubicle
the bosses have behind you just [ __ ]
guns ready you just wanted to know what
Election Day was so you could think
about requesting it off because civic
pride is important to you or if you're
at work just go to the bathroom act like
you're taking a dump come back out until
all of your friends about it that's a
good one Instagram
do you know how big that that place is
like not even a viable way to hide like
viable not liable drop a pin in there
and they'd hear that
let's go weird again I think something
that Mike said on the last podcast
though that's really important to say
again though is that a lot of people
this year up for re-election and if we
get the right people in the right seats
we could be looking at this moving a lot
faster than we really thought it was
going to we're already at the breaking
point we're at 24 or 25 including
one for medical it looks like it's gonna
be 25 here in a minute
that count Pennsylvania since
Pennsylvania sleepless that's horrible
okay so 24 plus DC so we're still
looking at 25 we're at the halfway mark
we're you know and it's funny because my
dad said something really interesting to
me the other day that at this point in
gay marriage it had already steamrolled
and it went across all 50 so maybe we
just have to hold on for a little bit
longer showed up in big groups and voted
yes yes yes you're blushing before you
can push more who cares
keep blush and they can't see our friend
yep I know I I just want to motivate you
yeah Mike doesn't mean to be no Mike
does mean to be motivating inspiring he
wants you to go out and vote ah there is
a chance that we could lose recreational
cannabis in Pueblo Colorado yep that's
tremendous
politics and public opinion work on a
pendulum if you look at your history we
swing from liberal to conservative
socially and so social issues like this
can swing back quickly in the early 70s
we had a president that was thinking
about legalizing marijuana nationally we
had a number of states that have passed
medical marijuana laws does anybody
remember these when we were children
no because the [ __ ] eighties happened
and public opinion swung back the other
way hard we decided to do a war on drugs
instead of legalization and we all know
how that played out and had a couple of
candidates stayed in the election or
done better running up to this point we
could still have candidates that were
promising to send the military to stop
Colorado's weed stores
like that's a reality in 2016 that we
have a major popular well-funded
candidate for the highest office in the
land who's talking about sending the
army to shut down the weed stores in
Colorado you guys working the retail
what are you gonna do one day when a
tank rolls up into the [ __ ] parking
lot Springs so like I don't know if I I
guess if it goes away for good yeah
they're there first in the spring people
are already in the spring when the tank
shows up I'm gonna stop worrying about
the consumption on site rule take it
down real quick and bounce with my new
ring as much hash as I can carry s
speaking a new rig yeah I think I would
just have to look over and be like my
bad hun inserts
exactly like set up a station real quick
and be like so who wants a job I'm gonna
go outside and yell at the tank I don't
think they think that I don't think
they'd be surprised those like who wants
to help me carry all the stuff that we
can carry out this window that's on the
other side of the building from the tank
[Music]
is it started it started around it
started when we start dabbing at 11:42
record is bound dad it's been a long day
yeah big big big huge respect to
everybody that I had fun with stay you
know who I always shout out to ah
[ __ ] cooper-breaux coops ah you're
doing the 22 push-ups every day when you
start it off really like a wiggle worm
by like day three bro you're doing
push-ups oh man I'm proud of you
I think it's inspiring that you actually
posted the videos from the beginning
when you knew you weren't killing it
because I'm sure by day 22 you're gonna
look like a [ __ ] Marine dude so shout
out that is awesome much respect
a lot of people wouldn't even have the
heart or the balls to try it let alone
post the videos that you post oh so
that's [ __ ] cool
Lindsay's over here putting her hand up
I haven't done it I'll do it I I don't
even know if I could throw down 22 to
tell you the truth I'll try it I can't
22 girl ones I got you when trying to
girl ones that's why I told you that
story right that hunt had posted and he
had called out all of the nugs family
and I'd liked it by accident before I
like read through the whole comment and
I was like now I'm like obligated but
like I don't know how to do push-ups
that's what I was gonna give a shout-out
to it was our boy hunt do you like
something without reading the whole post
and now you have to like learn a new
physical activity I couldn't like on my
kids I feel like that was rude too so I
mean not like he would have noticed
right but I like I don't know I just was
like I'm just gonna leave this here like
pretty good yeah big shout out to hunt
what we're talking about is the 22
push-ups for veterans because every so
frequently I don't remember the stats I
don't have the posted for every day
every day thank you Mike every day 22
veterans commit suicide so some of my
friends are posting to Facebook videos
of themselves doing 22 push-ups every
day for 22 days straight to raise
awareness for veterans to show support
for veterans to help out to encourage
people to reach out to veterans so a big
shout-out to John hunt I'm not just from
doing this push-up challenge but because
he's a bad [ __ ] every single day
in every single way that dude's an
inspiration he inspired koop to do
push-ups he inspired me to do some
push-ups he's gonna inspire Linds he's
doing before too long
he pushes everybody to the next level in
all aspects that's an inside joke
aspects if you hang out one time you'll
see why I use the word aspects but a
shout out to hunt your bad [ __ ]
so uh yeah some people that deserved a
shout out everybody just nods oh yeah
they can't hear I always and if I'm
gonna talk about veterans
I didn't plan this wasn't part of the
show I was gonna give a shout out to
coupon hunt Steve Daffy no my friend you
deserve a huge shout out for what you do
at the veteran farmers Alliance if you
guys are a veteran or have a friend or
relative that's a veteran make sure you
get them in touch with the veteran
farmers Alliance I had a listener that
sent me a message saying they wanted to
get in touch with Steve and I gave Steve
your contact infos easier for me to do
it that way it's Steve said he's
attempted to contact you so I hope that
is
on through so yeah that was random that
was a sidebar but shout out to all the
people raising awareness for the
veterans no that's awesome yeah we need
to be doing a lot more than anything to
raise awareness I'm for yes for anything
that's worth raising awareness for
absolutely yeah all right we go for a
little while
anybody got any final words to say well
you've got a microphone in for you and a
whole bunch of people are gonna hear
your opinions and thoughts I laid down
pretty much what I had to go out get
your shirt registered to vote vote when
the time comes because if we don't we're
gonna lose [ __ ] we'd do it seriously
we don't want to start taking steps back
now and that's what could easily happen
in the next couple election cycles my
count can really walk this backwards how
can people find you on tweeter you can
find me at at Nemo punk 15 on Twitter or
at pool for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook there you go make sure you
support Mike's Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws Facebook page Mike knows a
lot about cannabis he knows a lot about
local cannabis laws and rules thanks
dude thank you honey
we just mental fist bump awesome
beautiful how can people find you on the
Twitter oh man
I'm actually trying to use Twitter more
so please actually tweet at me I'm the
travel stoner just the travel stoners
yeah someone took the traveling stoner
damn I know but you guys can find me on
Instagram too as the traveling stoner
yeah check her out and instead can we
tell them about your snapchat yeah sure
it's traveling stoner without the G are
you the one responsible for the snapchat
for a green and healthy wellness and the
massroots
and the massroots so give those pages a
shoutout for us it'll be get more
follows um its G a HW seven one nine on
both massroots and snapchat so feel free
to follow the store and all of the crazy
sales and things we have going on yeah
and make sure you support those she is
the the beautiful budtender at green and
healthy wellness since a couple of the
lovely young ladies have had to move on
to better adventures better ventures the
[ __ ] is the word there gingers sure
whatever they've moved on and so now
Lindsay is picking up the slack
thank you mm-hmm
should we even talk about the flowers
that were on the Shelf that were grown
by me that are probably sold out by the
time this episode brought drops yeah
they will definitely be gone but
there'll be more of those strains on the
shelves later there's there we are going
to keep good stuff coming on the shelves
I've gotten it under control now it's
gonna be awesome
good we've got a lot of good things
coming I think everything is going great
shot at the Tirpitz for the new
packaging now it's dope Giada editor
packs in general just yeah I'm a huge
fan - hey Jordan when are we gonna put
the band back together yeah also a fan
of the music boys well done so should we
get them back on the show again
yes a million times yes all right
Euterpe boys I don't think they'll
listen to the show Jordan Dan Shane we
got to get you on the show
all right so we can go for a long time I
feel like I've got a TD so the listeners
probably have got a TB by now I want to
thank my friends for joining me it's
[ __ ] Thursday
well now it's Friday morning Thursday
night recording a podcast takin dabs so
uh once again I do have to give huge
love to my friends at elevate glass for
this new recycler ring that they gave me
I shout out to all the lovely ladies and
the one gentleman down there and also
shout out to the adorable little dogs
the one dog ate a packet of taco bell
hot sauce and it smelled like an atomic
bomb went off in that store for a couple
of seconds but it was really funny
because the dog is so cute that it was
worth it
the look on your face I know cuz I know
what dogs you're talking about cuz I've
been in there before so like I I can
only imagine they're so cute though I
think you dropped a bomb so shout out to
all my my lovely friends over at elevate
glass they treat me like royalty there
if you need glass and you're in the
Colorado Springs area go check them out
it's a dope-ass place tell them I sent
you please do it make sure you let them
know that Russ - Jeff sent you mention
that [ __ ] alright we're gonna get out of
here um yeah all right all you guys got
to do now is go to iTunes
search for the review section search for
the girl from the heart podcast give me
a rating I'm not gonna tell you to give
me five stars you do what you think I
deserve I think asking for five stars
might have been in it like a cheap thing
to do that's not you may not think I
deserve five good give me what you
really feel that I deserve that sounds
fair type
let me know what you think about the
podcast and I will read your comments on
a future episode if you guys want to be
a sponsor on the podcast like her good
friends at elevate and you want some
information all you need to do is send
me an email to go from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all of the
information that you need make sure you
support Tok radio.com make sure you
check out elevate and make sure you
check out the secret session also follow
my friends on the Instagram and the
tweeter and the snapchat and the
Facebook and all of the social media
that you can handle lindsay has got an
evil look on her face as you just took a
snapchat all right
we're gonna take some more dabs you guys
and until next time take a bad dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
your blessings cone them one by one and
give all the time some procedure for all
the tears don't count your blessings on
them to buy to others as you love them
to one to you I call my blessing because
we judge up by my side there is no
stressing know if but maybe there is no
guessing we reap what we sow when we
keep on progressing
no God when you think you got it but
somebody got it haha feeling sad and oh
well somebody feeling sad out to give
unto your sister and your brother la me
give thanks for this Universal
University may give tons for my own
strength and sanity million tons for my
friends also my family I know may chime
in with the MIP fraternity
[Music]
bless I'm putting in the past all of my
stress I'm not hurting that's for
certain cuz I'm working with the best
God put me to a test and said he'd lend
a hand and told me he would move me to
an independent man now I'm looking at me
and I'm a little mo better my mom a
loose in the dream I just won't let up
I wanna spread a message of positivity
and an opportunity it's what you're
giving me so warm I spread my love from
Mussina to the babies respect from my
brethren and smiles [ __ ] the ladies you
can look but you can't touch cuz I might
looking clean in the Rockaways jeans and
now white shirt
and yes I might flirt but that's my damn
bar for men need lovely ladies and I
think I love I got a lot to give that
somewhere got to live and like the homie
positive collaboration with my brother
from the UK mystic roots fan Chico
California hey the only thing that's the
same
I'm understandably busy I'm coming up in
the game and got my family with me I
feel blessed
we answer this what this without me no
feet jump weight-loss get up mismatch
man up and take I'm economy [ __ ] my
luck Anna lightning cup on the week I
drop some come down and get talked to
the earth is like a melting pot gravity
criminal creepy like wrapping a bubble
into news will race out to play football
you need about to play kick it to the
Nina back think it attended a summer
listen it'll come at the restaurant I
think another lucky enough to make it if
a baby for motherf---ing out so the area
negative make any make any make sugar in
a cup a cup bliss
[Music]