yo it up boys and girls it's Rasta Jeff
and it's time for episode 134 of the
girl from your heart podcast yeah
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for up so number 134 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new growers if
you're professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends at the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my podcast big shout outs of
cat food in the entire mystic roots crew
you guys missed the Kreutz is on a
little mini tour this spring so make
sure you check them out if you can
they're coming to Colorado consider
doing five or six shows they will
definitely be at the Aggie theater and
they will be at the black sheep in
Colorado I'll be at the black sheep show
I hope to see you there
once again much love to my friends in
the mystic root fan and the entire stay
positive production company much loves
much respect also while we're at it this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends at elevate glass that's right
elevate glass in Colorado Springs make
sure you check out elevate glass if I
have 70 South Tejon if you're looking
for an affordable rig if you need a new
nail if you need a carb cap if you need
a case for your new rig if you just want
to go hang out and be social and see
what's going on make sure you check out
elevate glass its 512 South Tejon and
beautiful downtown Colorado Springs
Colorado also you guys make sure you
check out toke radio.com the podcast is
available on talk radio calm Wednesdays
at 1 p.m. big shout out to my buddy
citizen J thanks for supporting the
podcast make sure you guys check that
out I think that's all the official
business I got one more thing I do have
to remind you guys of I've got an update
is what this is on episode number 126
we're talking about the organization
that was passing out joints to people
who collected trash in the park and we
made a comment about how it was not cool
that they were giving out joints in the
park I've been corrected you guys big
shout out to Lindsey and Chris for
correcting me they were listening to the
podcast and they were
Hey Dude they did not give the joints
out in the park what happened so we did
an article where people collect the
trash in the park and they clean up the
park and after they picked up the trash
they got a free joint it was under my
assumption they got the joint at the
park because of the news kind of made it
look that way I was told that they got a
coupon and they had to take the coupon
to the smoke Club and the smoke Club
then gave them a joint when they
presented proper ID and that coupon so a
correction had to be made they did not
give the joints out at the park they did
it correctly so shout out and also shout
out to my friends for correcting me I do
appreciate that
alright I hope everybody had a great
week because I am recording on a
Saturday usually I record on a Thursday
but this week was chaotic this week on
Thursday I had a medical marijuana
doctor at 9:30 in the morning in
Colorado Springs then I worked all day
and then I went to the secret stash the
secret session was amazing oh I almost
forgot part of my day I got up I drove
to Colorado Springs and then I got stuck
in a [ __ ] elevator yes I've never
been stuck in an elevator before but
Thursday morning it happened I was stuck
in an elevator with two strangers I
wasn't in there for very long it was a
little bit freaky but I didn't panic or
anything says like whatever I'm just in
an elevator people know I'm here
someone's gonna get me out it wasn't
that big of a deal one of the people in
the elevator was a couple and the older
dude was getting a little bit pissed off
if he was stuck in an elevator there's
no reason for him to be mad but I think
just the simple idea that he was stuck
pissed him off um I was going to the
medical marijuana doctor I walked in
there's no stairs at this building
oddly uh there's an elevator got in the
elevator more people walked in I held
the door for them I hit floor three it
started to go it went and then it
stopped and I looked at the dude and I
was like I don't know that I want to be
in here he said I think we're stuck in
here and I said if it stops and then it
stopped I was like well [ __ ] and so I
first my first instinct was trying to
pull the door open just to see where we
are you know how far up did we go how
far down did we go nor the [ __ ] we went
ah tried to pull the door open
it was stuck it was good and stuck so
nothing was gonna happen there's a
little uh an alarm button on the
elevator I hit that then there's a
button that says call for help I hit
that a couple seconds later a young lady
answered she's like hello and I was like
that I just called the front desk or
what the [ __ ] just happened I was like
hey I'm stuck in the elevator and she
asked if I was at the address where I
was and I confirmed that she said okay
hang tight we'll send someone to get you
out
I was like well that's like and I just
basic you know what I mean like ask if
we're okay or some [ __ ] geez so we sat
in the elevator for a few minutes and
then another person I kept hitting the
little alarm button they would just go
jingle jingle jingle so that somebody
would know I was in there and then
another person came and they're like hey
are you stuck and I was Ike yes we're
stuck and she just started pushing
buttons and when she pushed up I don't
know which button cuz I wasn't there
when she pushed the button I could feel
the elevator shift a little bit and I
said hey keep doing that and then I saw
through the crack in the door I could
see that we were only six or eight
inches up off the ground we'd only moved
1/2 a foot so I was like keep doing that
cuz we're going down every time she did
it and then I saw I saw the little
threshold piece like where the elevator
would fit into the floor and as I hold
on hold on I wanna see something quit
pushing it I didn't want her to squish
my fingers and I stuck my fingers in
there and I totally just pulled the door
open so I was able to slide the door
open once she got it a little bit lower
we were a little bit late for our
medical marijuana doctor appointment but
uh what can he do I called them and I
said hey I'm stuck in the elevator so
please don't screw up my appointment and
they took me they got me in there big
shout-out to my medical marijuana doctor
I can't say it I don't think I should
say his name on the air because he's
crowded already but yeah if you know my
medical marijuana doctor you give him a
high-five that was quick it was a quick
easy appointment I got everything
handled the way that I needed to I got
out of the elevator went to the doctor
saw the doctor went and took care of the
gardens all day big shout out to Jon
Randall's jr. big shout at the zac also
he was shot at the hunt everybody kicked
ass in the garden vini guys I got to
wrap it up oh I went to the dispensary I
bought a bunch of a Terp Akshat or big
shot at the Tirpitz the new packaging is
dope and that lemon G I might have grown
that that lemon G live resin that stuff
was fire you guys so it was so tasty so
then I went got some hash and then I
headed up to Denver where I went to the
secret sesh and I met up with our buddy
John hunt and you guys I want to give a
shout-out to everybody but I got to dab
with if the secret sesh I dabbed with so
many people that I'm not even gonna say
one name cuz I will forget somebody so
if you were at secret session we took a
dab much love I was at the secret stash
I was dabbing and Hannah mill said I'm
higher than everybody here and I was
kind of pretty sure that I was higher
than him so I was like no you're not and
he saw me he goes Ross and Jeff I see
you shaking her head come here bro and
he called me up to the stage I went to
the stage he his buddy Tim gave me and
it was at least a gram I think I took a
gram and a half dab on the stage at the
secret session forever
and did not choke and then we brought up
a couple of people on the stage and dab
them out that was a pretty good time but
honestly I was lit up because I would
give people like a two gram dab and
whatever they couldn't take I would
finish it for him and oftentimes it was
most of a gram you trying to dab
somebody a two gram dab and they start
choking and they look at you like I'm
done so I would just grab and finish it
so it's pretty late we took a little
break and went sat in the greenroom and
I ate a bunch of Cheetos uh drinks with
Dr Pepper I usually don't need a bunch
of crap but I needed some crap in my
body so I had a bunch of junk and drop
my [ __ ] back together while I was
sitting in the greenroom chilling out
our good friend Lindsay the travelling
stoner showed up and she had her
beautiful friend Molly with her shoutout
to Lindsey and Molly they encouraged me
to have another bag of chips and get my
[ __ ] together and then get back to the
party so Lindsey and our new friend
Molly and I went cruised around the
secret sesh and shout out to our friend
at T and T extractions that dude gave me
a doughnut that got me rekt shout-out to
whoever made the strawberry lemonade or
the pink lemonade cupcakes with the
chocolate or the peppermint bark on top
of them sorry I'm my brain still maybe
fuzzy from the secret session I think
there were 250 or 300 milligrams each
and I ate two of those I had some fruit
there was pineapple and strawberries and
some other random fruit that was chopped
up that had medicated chocolate ganache
that was hot on top of it that's enough
it was so tasty so the secret session I
got stupidly if you walked up and tried
to talk to me and I was kind of
non-responsive I do apologize I had
eaten about 850 to a thousand milligrams
of edibles and I had smoked about four
or five grams of hash so I was in no
condition to be conversational I
apologize but shout out to everyone at
the secret session I had a good ass time
huge shout out to our friends at TNT
extractions and Shuman bars human
edibles those dudes gave me a 1000
milligram edible and I ate that 1000
milligram edible yesterday on my way to
work and by the time I got to work it
felt like somebody had replaced my blood
with sand my body was so dry and heavy
that I just wanted to curl up in a
corner and take a nap I have not been
that ridiculously high in a long time a
thousand milligrams is no joke you guys
I do not recommend it I don't know that
I want to do it again I feel like I
wasted probably a day and a half because
the entire day I was useless and then
half of today it took me half of today
to get my [ __ ] together so a thousand
milligrams will [ __ ] you up if that's
what you're looking for but oh my god I
don't recommend it it was an adventure
it was it was like a shamanic journey
but I had to go and live my day doing it
I had to go to work and I had to
function so that's kind of hard don't do
that unless you can lay around and just
be lazy
so shout it to those folks shout it to
the secret says you guys if you can make
it to the next secret session you need
to be there big shout it to add a mill
and all those kids I'm not gonna try to
list names because I will forget mad
people but we're gonna move forward and
you guys I want to get into some iTunes
comments we haven't read the iTunes
comments in a long time I think there
are one or two more that we haven't read
so I'm pulling up iTunes right now I'm
getting to the comments section I would
like it if you guys would go to iTunes
find the go to iTunes Store search for
the girl from Earhart podcast find the
review section type in a little comment
give me the amount of stars that you
feel I deserve and let me know what you
think about the show because I really do
appreciate reading the comments all
right I am here where I need to be I
found the new comments our new comment
comes from our friend tarantula hawk
he gave us 5 stars he left this comment
may 18th 2016 the comic goes like this
to date this is hands-down the best
informational cannabis grow podcast
rasta Jeff doesn't overload you with
endless advertising informative free and
entertaining much love to Jeff and the
crew give your mom a hug for me if you
liked it review it and donate a few
bucks straight-up it's that good that is
a hell of a good comment thank you I
appreciate that that's something I
noticed when I used to listen to another
cannabis podcast people would ask aggro
question and instead of giving solid Gro
advice the host of that show would sell
you a product and it wouldn't solve your
problem it would temporarily solve your
problem it would mask your problem is
what it would do and then you'd have to
keep buying that product what I like to
do is if you have a problem in your grow
if you say hey I have spider mites I
like to help you figure out how you're
getting spider mites teach you how to
correct that so that you don't ever get
mites again instead of having to buy
some product that is sponsoring me over
and over again I don't think that's cool
so I do appreciate that you notice that
free and entertaining and informative
that's those are the things I aim to be
so perfect awesome thank you
much love to me and the crew I will
share the love with the crew hopefully
they're all listening right now so you
guys this dude tarantula hawk gave us
mad love
and then give your mom a hug for me I
will do that and then review it yes you
guys review the podcast go to iTunes and
leave a review just like this guy says
and then also donate a few bucks
unfortunately PayPal did not like me
having a cannabis related podcast linked
to their PayPal service so PayPal has
shut me down I do not have a way to
receive donations but if you'd like to
make a contribution to the show send me
an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com we will figure out how to
receive your contribution
all right so big shout out to tarantula
hawk you give us a five star rating and
wrote a super super sweet comment I
appreciate that
our next comment comes from 100% Clint
and I don't know if that's Clint that's
been on the show or if that's just a
listener but they gave us a five star
review and they left a comment on May
20th of 2016 and it simply says give
your mom a hug for me
so next time I see my mom I / her - hugs
and I want you guys to do the same next
time you see your mom just give her a
hug for me
tell her Rasta Jeff says hello she knows
who I am trust me alright guys that was
the iTunes comments I want to thank
everybody that sent a comment I
encourage you to go to iTunes like I
said and post a little comment post a
review I would truly appreciate it if
you've got something you'd like to say
and you don't want to do it on the
iTunes comments you can always send me
an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com and of course I am on all of
the social media I'm on facebook I'm on
Instagram I'm on Twitter I'm on snapchat
find me support all of those I would
appreciate that and speaking of social
media a couple of days ago I saw a post
from my friend Nicole West big shout out
to Nicole Nicole is um she's
well-established in the cannabis
industry let's just say that she posted
something to Facebook that I thought I
would share with you guys it says dear
people applying for jobs in the cannabis
industry just a few tips and I can
support everything she says here tip
number one please do not make the first
sentence of your intro email B I can
pass a drug test that should be
self-explanatory you guys number two if
you failed at attaching the correct
document or attaching the document
correctly the first three times I don't
think the fourth time is going to get
you your job guys when you're going to
attach when you send in your resume to
work at a dispensary you need to include
a copy of your badge and probably a copy
of your ID and there will probably be
more documents attached that [ __ ] don't
forget that's hat your resume don't
forget send it right the fur
also you guys I heard a friend talking
about this a friend of mine got an email
that was addressed to the wrong person
my friend's name is Lee the email said
hey Bryan this indicates to me and Lee
that this email was a mass email sent to
multiple people and all the person was
doing was going and changing the name is
who the letter was addressed to you guys
make sure you change that [ __ ] if you're
sending an application or a resume
don't say dear live well when you're
trying to work for the clinic make sure
you get that [ __ ] correct so number
three do not ask me to how to get a
badge in your intro email that's the
truth if you're applying for a job do
not ask the person giving you the job
how to get your badge that's on you
I've done a whole episode on how to get
your badge go back and listen to that
that'll truly help you out number four
please do not spend the entire interview
talking about how shitty the last
dispenser you worked for treated
everyone don't do that you guys have you
worked for another dispensary or trying
to work for ours we don't want to hear
about the problems at the old place that
means that you're dramatic that means
that you're gonna bring some [ __ ] to
our place that we simply do not need so
keep your drama at home especially
during an interview number five no basic
weights and measurements if you're
coming to work at a dispensary know what
1/8 weighs know what 1/4 weighs know
what a half ounce weighs know what an
ounce weighs know this [ __ ] know it well
start understanding weights you need to
be quick you should be able to eyeball
an eighth you should be able to throw an
eighth on the scale just by grabbing it
and tossing it on there get good at that
[ __ ] hey guys
3.5 grams is an eighth there are
twenty-eight point three five grams and
bounce that point three five does matter
most people skip the twenty-eight point
three five twenty eight point three five
is a true ounce you guys so do your math
from there alright then number six
regardless of the job you're applying
for always dress professional at
interviews even if you're coming in to
be a trimmer even if you're coming in
just be an entry level person at a
dispensary look good you need to look
presentable you will be around products
that people are going to buy and consume
people don't want scuzzy people hovering
over their cake or their baked goods
you don't want scuzzy people hovering
over the medicine that you're going to
smoke especially in a medical dispensary
we need clean people we need a clean
environment so guys those were a few
tips that my friend Nicole posted to
face
I thought it would be really helpful to
share this it's kind of a smartass stab
at the people trying to get a job but
it's so real that it was worth sharing
so she meant to post something smartass
I took it seriously because some people
need some help with this I thought it
would be helpful so big shout out to
Nichole West you guys my throat is
getting dry as [ __ ] so this is the point
in the show where I'm gonna press pause
take a couple of dabs and take a drink
and I will be right back yeah I'm back
and I dab the [ __ ] out you guys I need
to give you a huge shout out to my
friends at elevate glass at 517 South
Tejon in beautiful downtown Colorado
Springs Colorado make sure you check out
elevate glass if you need a new rig if
you need a new nail if you need some
smoking accessories I highly recommend
elevate glass go check them out also one
more important thing I need to mention
you guys I've said this before I need to
remind you again politely kindly I'm not
mad at you but I cannot ship anybody any
seeds at this time I do not send seeds
if you're looking for seeds I can
recommend that you search the internet
for the dank team.com
the DEA NK team dank team.com check them
out they may be able to help you out but
I certainly cannot get you any seeds
alright guys that's enough business
let's get to an email that I received
this one came from our friend Sam shout
out to Rasta Seb down there in Australia
thank you for listening to the show
thank you for supporting the show thank
you for your being the coolest Facebook
troll ever thanks for hanging out it
feels like we're Bros it feels like
we've sat around and smoked together
I've never met the dude in person but he
is family now so big shot at the Seb
cool ass dude make sure you follow Rasta
Seb on Facebook let him know that you
found out about him to the girl from
your heart podcast
he's a cool ass dude it makes him really
funny memes ah sometimes I act like I
don't see them because I don't even know
what the [ __ ] to say so he sent me a
long Facebook message with several
questions I'm gonna go through a couple
of them here the first one he says how
can a humble simple ganja farmer folk
avoid buying an RO and get rid of clora
mines is asking how he can get rid of
the chlorine and whatever else the water
company is putting in your water without
buying a reverse osmosis machine because
those are quite expensive and sometimes
people can't afford that sometimes you
don't have word of anywhere to put it
so how can a simple ganja farmer get rid
of the chlorine and the stuff that the
city is putting in our municipal water
quite simply you can put it in a giant
jug and set it in the Sun and the Sun
will help evaporate off any of those
contaminants also I recommend pudding if
you need to do it indoors if you have to
do it indoors most of us have to put the
water put the tap water in a reservoir
whatever size you're using and put a lot
of air stones in there put air stones in
there and make it bubble real heavily
because then you'll move all that water
around in surface area excuse me for
clearing my throat over and over again
but surface area is what you're trying
to create so you want to bring some of
that water from the bottom up to the top
and help move some of that chlorine
that's trapped in there up to the top
and then it can evaporate so the easiest
way is just to put your water in a big
container and put air stones in it and
bubble the [ __ ] out of it get your night
self a nice air and air bubble or what
do they call an air pump I just get
yourself a nice powerful one they make
one that's got like 8 air things coming
off of it
put all 8 of them in like a 30 gallon
trash can and fill that sucker with
water and just pump the [ __ ] out of the
air into there and that'll get rid of
the chlorine of the core amide or
whatever you're worried about in there
we'll get rid of most of it and then of
course before you give that to your
plants make sure you adjust the pH check
the pH of that adjust it before you feed
it to your plants depending on the
plants age their pH they will want
different stuff so that's how you get
rid of that stuff and it's free and it
doesn't take much but time and a little
bit of energy you may have to go buy
yourself an air pump the second question
said asked is thoughts on Michael Raisa
and trichoderma bacteria beneficials do
you use and how much so he wants to know
which of these beneficials i use and how
much there are several brands out there
they're mostly the same you guys I like
there are several brands that I like I
really like great white shark sometimes
I like oh jee bio war I like a lot of
different things the chunkier white ones
seem to work the best for me umm how
much a whole bunch when I put my when my
seedlings come or when my clones come
out of the cloner they're going into a
cup of soil or a small pot of soil I
like to sprinkle a little bit of the
great white shark around the base area
where the roots are gonna hit and then
put or also I can't forget this one
dragonfly earth medicine they make a
lush roots is also a great product for
this dust the roots in there or put a
little right where the roots are gonna
go and then bury the plant into that and
then when I let the roots grow in that
cup or a small container for a long
until it's almost too much and then I
transplant it into the next container
and as I do I'll cope right where I'm
gonna put the plant
I'll coat that area with just a sprinkle
of whatever powdered root inoculants
sort of thing that I'm gonna use if it's
great white shark if it's OG bio war
whichever brand you're using you can use
ogt there are a whole bunch of different
products they're mostly the same I
really like the great white shark it's
affordable its cost effective OG bio war
is affordable its cost effective it's
worth its weight in gold in my opinion
so those would be the two I'd recommend
the great white shark or the og bio war
and you can't use too much use it when
you go from the cloner into the cup and
then when you go from the cup into the
pot and then if you go into another pot
do it again every time right where
you're putting those roots the fresh
roots just put some of that into the
dirt right where those roots are gonna
touch and then I like to fill a
container with clean water and then I
just mix the powdered solution into the
water with my nutrients and feed it to
the plants just like a water feed just
like I feed all my other nutrients and I
feel that that helps soak it in there
real good so now I've got something that
was in there with the roots when I put
it in there in the dirt it's already
touching it the roots are eating it and
then I feed some in kind of like a tea
so that it can get more I really like to
give it that sort of stuff give it all
and give it excuse me once again give it
give it these things all through the veg
phase like maybe once every other week
through the veg phase and then do it the
first three weeks and flour would not be
a bad idea at all because you want to
build those roots and keep those roots
moving so I hope that answered your
question dude which uh which beneficials
do I recommend so the next question you
said my thoughts on LED lights the
benefits you're thinking better tricone
production maybe if used in conjunction
with HBS not to mention energy savings
ten to one for similar lumens output
I've seen a lot of great [ __ ] come from
LED lights I don't have any experience
with them honestly they're expensive and
I'm afraid to invest in a white that's
not going to make my plants perform the
way that they need um in the right
situation if you're in a small area and
you can't run a big light do it if what
you're able to do is run an LED run an
LED my friend Amanda has an LED and I've
seen pictures of her cannabis plants and
they
good uh I can't argue with the led my
friend Nancy Budd well I don't know if
she listens to this podcast but shout
out to Nancy she grows with the lush led
and her plants look [ __ ] stellar her
plants look really really good she does
a great job I've seen a lot of great
stuff from LEDs I just don't have any
experience you are totally accurate with
the cost-effectiveness of LEDs they
really do keep electricity costs down
the lights themselves don't pull as much
power which means they don't make as
much heat which means you don't need as
much air-conditioning so it's really
beneficial it is a good thing if you get
the right LEDs I'm sure that there are
some cheap china-made ones out there
that you wouldn't want to purchase I'm
sure there are some great american-made
LEDs that would work very well so just
do your research if you're gonna buy an
LED I guess that's the best I could say
on there tricone production yeah it's
gonna help you out with tricone
production because you're getting more
types of light it's gonna make the
plants grow a little bit differently
also it's gonna change then gosh I'm
sorry you guys I'm just choking up over
here it's gonna change the nutritive
cycle of that plant a little bit it's
gonna speed it up a little bit I feel
like cuz it's getting more different
light so you're gonna probably need to
feed a little bit differently there will
be adjustments to be made if you shift
shift from an HP S to an LED or if you
add an LED to your HP s room you're
gonna see different [ __ ] happening that
you're gonna have to adjust to
I saw sub cool hanging a lush LED in his
HBS room and the plant underneath it
hated it but that's just because it
wasn't sub cools Gro style so you're
gonna have to adjust some [ __ ] I hope
that answered your question about LEDs
in my opinion so the next one is why I
want to ask why more commercial grows
don't get solar to offset massive power
costs honestly at the amount of
electricity we're using I don't know
that solar would even be a viable source
I honestly don't know enough about solar
that's something I would have to
research but honestly I we pull we've
got a t5 1000 watt lights in one room
and 25 1000 watt lights in another room
the electricity bill is high dude and
we've also got
[ __ ] tons tons and tons of
airconditioning on top of that building
that just keep us cool all day it was
really warm today well not really warm
it was fairly warm to the outside it's
gonna get way hotter but it was fairly
warm and the building was nice and cool
was probably 74 degrees in the whole
building and we've got a nice office
space we've got a trim area so there's a
[ __ ] ton of lights I don't think that
motorcycle was so loud I hope you guys
heard that cuz it kind of scared the
[ __ ] at me I don't think that we could
get enough electricity through solar to
run all of the stuff that we have of
course I am NOT an electrical engineer
or anywhere educated in any means of
solar power but that's my opinion that's
what I would assume that's what I would
guess dude so then he asked me question
number five said said how do you keep so
cool under pressure when the cop pulled
you over and then he also said being
responsible for so much medicine and
patients as it does it keep you awake at
night worrying about timers and stuff
any tips on how to relax and not freak
out like I tend to well [ __ ] bro I I
didn't worry about timers and stuff
until you just pointed it out now I'm
having a damn panic attack and I want to
check the cameras on my phone and see if
everything if the Gros is cool and I'm
just kidding I'm just totally joking
with you um how do I keep my cool under
pressure like when that cop pulled me
over well I'm a grown-ass adult and that
cops just a grown-ass man with the job
to do and I didn't have anything to hide
and I guess being a white dude with a
nice car probably helped me out so I
didn't feel like it was worried about
too much and because I mean we know I'm
not even kidding if I was a different
race it could have been a totally
different outcome I'm not accusing this
cop of anything but we know how things
go so being a spoiled white dude helps
me out for sure in that case keeping my
cool with the cops and I'm just well
educated and I speak well and I'm very
sociable so I don't worry about cops
they're just people with a job to do and
if you're not doing anything stupid and
hiding anything most of the time you
should be cool I feel like and so I just
I hoped for that I guess that's how I
stayed cool the cops
honestly I'm not intimidated by people
people are people if the person next to
me is Rasta Seb if the person next to me
is white Mike if the person sitting next
to me is Lindsay or if the person
sitting next to me is the President or
if the person sitting next to me is
whoever I am feel the same there people
we're all humans we all fart we all poop
we all have to go pee we all need to eat
food to live life we all have feelings
we're all those people so I don't people
might make me nervous they were all just
people like rock stars are just people
that play guitars real well I don't get
nervous around people so that's how I
keep cool in that situation the part
about being responsible for so much
medicine and patience and does it keep
me awake at night no because I wouldn't
be in the position if the people that
put me that let me have this position
didn't have full trust of me and I would
not I wouldn't even do it if I didn't
have faith in myself that I could do
this I would say straight up like hey
this is not my thing I can't handle this
and also I've got good backup it is my I
do run that grill by myself for the most
part but if I need help I can call hunt
hunt will come help I can call Zach Zach
will come help I have a tremor that's
their trimmin eight days a week now so I
can have him help me if there is trouble
in the grow that I need help with so
yeah I am responsible for it but it
doesn't keep me awake at night
I've got it figured out I know the
building really well I know every timer
in the building I know what time
everything clicks on what time
everything clicks off I know what the
temperature is in each room right now so
I don't worry too much about that and
then you said does it keep you awake at
night worrying about timers and stuff so
one time dude uh it was late it was
midnight and I was laying down to go to
sleep and I thought I should check the
cameras at the Gros just to see what's
going on and it's an hour away from my
house in good weather so I look at the
camera and I can see that this one pump
is broken I can see it on the camera
that a tank that should have been fed to
these plants was totally full and the
pump had not pumped in several hours
probably six good hours and if these
plants didn't get a drink of water
within the next three or four hours it
probably were gonna die and it was
midnight and I was getting ready to go
to bed and I saw this and so I did the
only thing I could do I put on my shoes
and I got in my car and I drove the hour
there and I fixed the pump honestly it
took me maybe five minutes to fix that
pump ah then I got back in the car and
my car broken down it wouldn't start add
up I had to get my car [ __ ] towed
home that night that was really funny
cuz
five in the morning by the time I got
home but uh I have cameras I can check
and see if anything goes really wrong
and at this point I've been there long
enough to where I know like I said
earlier I know every timer in that
building I know every breaker in the
breaker box I know where I know every if
I'm if a leaf moves in that room I know
which plant it was on that's how well I
know that grow so it doesn't stress me
out too much it doesn't keep me up at
night
ah man if you smoke as much hash as I
did and smoked as many edibles as I did
you'd have no problem sleeping at night
but I just have faith in myself honestly
I've been doing this for a long time I'm
a confident dude I take a lot of notes
honestly I write notes on everything
I've got billions a little post-it notes
all over the grow that helps me out that
honestly helps me keep my cool because
they're just all the [ __ ] that I need to
do is right there and once I figure
finish a couple of tasks I cross them
off the list and throw the post-it note
away if you give me something that I
need to remember I just write it down
and I just keep post-it notes that
really helps me that's something that
really helps me keep my [ __ ] together
his notes and then I talk notes into my
phone also I felt Siri hey Siri make a
note of this and cereal remind me later
so that helps me out any tips on not on
how to relax and not freak out like you
tend to just chill out bro you got it
what are you so [ __ ] worried about
chill out you're cool all of you July
you got it whatever you're doing be
confident you're doing it you got this
and you're probably gonna [ __ ] up but
that's life and when you do fix it
you'll be okay like seriously I run a
big ass growing I was talking to a guy
we're opening a new facility and I was
talking to a guy and he's like so what's
the first thing you do when you get here
I said honestly the first thing you do
every morning when you walk into a big
facility is find the surprise because
I'm gonna see twice a week I walk into
the grow and there's a surprise ah the
other day a breaker had flipped and a
cloner filled with clones that I really
wanted to have of the breaker flipped in
that cloner
all those clones died because the
breaker went out and today the building
next door to mine all of their power
went out because of a breaker I had
nothing to do with me but I mean there's
always weird [ __ ] like that going on in
a commercial grow there's always gonna
be surprises so no matter how hard he do
it you're gonna get some kind of
surprise and it's how you deal with that
so just
be ready to deal with some [ __ ] don't
freak out and have faith in yourself
just know that you can do it you got
this far and you're gonna [ __ ] up like
don't worry you're gonna [ __ ] up no
matter how old you are no matter how
much you've done it you're gonna make
some mistakes
no one's gonna laugh at you maybe we are
but laugh at yourself too and if you
overflow reservoir get the squeegee and
push that water down to the drain and
then mop up the floor and then next time
don't overflow that reservoir if you
kill a plant remember what you did don't
kill a plant again I don't know that's
how I see it's only don't freak out
about stuff I've been at this a long
time and I've dealt with a lot of
mistakes and a lot of problems and I
know that I'm prepared to deal with
almost anything you can throw at me in a
grow room and if I haven't dealt with it
yet I'm ready to learn so that's how I
don't freak out but I just stay
confident and know that I got this [ __ ]
that's life just how it goes
plants are gonna die reservoirs are
gonna overflow things are gonna happen
lights are gonna fall I've seen why it's
just completely fall I've seen tables
fall over random [ __ ] happens I'm just
confident that I can deal with it when
it does
part of that is cuz I have I got a
little bit a little bit of faith in me
and some other things so it makes me
confident all right so I'll give you
huge shout out to my buddy Ross the Seb
said thank you for five would you send
me five good questions there were more
questions in that message but I've been
going for 33 minutes now and I feel like
most people only stick around for 36
minutes is what the statistics show when
I look at my uh my stats for my podcast
looks like you guys like a 36 minute
episode so we're getting close to that
which means I should start wrapping this
[ __ ] up so thanks everybody who listened
for this far I do have more emails with
more questions I am getting to those if
you sent me a message if you sent me an
email I will answer your questions you
guys I get emails and messages on a lot
of different platforms so it's hard to
find all of them it would be really cool
of you if you can send your questions
and comments to me through the email
let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I will check that and then
all the podcast stuff will be right
there I could just look at it and be
like oh look there's bills email and
then I could just read it it'll be so
much easier it's cool if you want to
send them on Facebook and all that but
sometimes I lose them and I forget where
they are and I gotta go searching so I
try to take screenshots honestly when I
have your email and I want to use it
screenshot it
a picture of it but anyway uh send me
questions via email that would be really
rad grow from your heart at hotmail.com
once again shout out to our friends at
elevate glass 517 south Tejon I may have
said the wrong address in a previous
episode elevate I'm sorry
smoke a lot of dad didn't gave me a cool
rig I want to give a huge shout-out to
my friend Chris also known as boba
blaster Co he needs a hug so I'm gonna
send it to him big virtual hug to your
brother can't wait so you get back from
your little trip hope things are well
for you also earlier I was talking about
the secrets a shout out to Lindsey for
hanging out with me shout out to Molly
for hanging out with me and keeping me
alive because I may have taken a nap in
that damn chair if you ladies did not
rescue me all right you guys this is the
end of the podcast I want to thank
everybody for listening it'd be really
cool if you went to iTunes and do what
those other folks did at the beginning
of the show good iTunes
find the iTunes Store go to the review
section yeah that's what you do uh type
in to find the girl from the heart
podcast find the review section in a
little comment let me know what you
think about the podcast type in some
stars just click on some stars I would
say give me five but that's kind of
beggin if you think I only deserve three
throw me three stars that's fair I want
to know what you think tell the truth so
go there
leave a comment throw me some stars
that'd be cool but would be even cooler
is if you told like three or five of
your friends about the podcast you're
like dude you should hear this guy's
podcast it's called girl from your heart
you can listen to it on stitcher you can
listen to it on iTunes or you can even
hear it on Tok radio talk radio calm on
Wednesdays at 1:00 p.m. or you can even
go to his website it's I read genetics
Colorado calm and go to the podcast tab
and you can listen to all the episodes
there so tell your friends about that
[ __ ] right and if you tell like three to
five people maybe one or two of them
will start listening you know that's
just how [ __ ] isn't that everyone's
gonna listen that's cool I get it but
tell a lot of people and then a couple
few people listen and then more people
are gonna learn how to grow better
cannabis and then more people are gonna
learn about freeing the cannabis plant
or people are gonna learn about the
healing properties of cannabis and then
eventually you know it's gonna happen
we're going to legalize cannabis
nationwide if you'd like to be a sponsor
of the podcast or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review all
you've got to do is send me an email
again it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to get you all
of the information that you need you
guys that's all I've got for this week
I'll be back in seven days with another
podcast shout out to my
next time Jenny from the block
[Music]
it's on my plate so I know you wanna
make I wanna put your hands
[Music]
get your rubies get your checklist
kitchen you know pardon this partner
with each other trade thing you don't
need a bank account
[Music]
you