let's be in conference what it what
exactly is a lesbian conference that's
where that's where lesbians get together
and they compress about stuff
don't you know what goes on with I
remember my first dad bro
that you say tell you what
he's just picked it up for me I'm
telling you dude like it's the redneck
it rubs off it does
come again do what now huh who said how
hos PAP
would you say
[Music]
[Laughter]
the dark comes out bunch of [ __ ]
grown silent when I did this
that would be so much fun
it's clear and it's it's it sounds legit
you know like a real question my
coworker has a nine-year-old nephew and
that kid wants to do voiceovers as he's
playing video games twitch style but he
doesn't know how to do it he wants to
record a video of the screen right while
he's playing with his voice over it to
play any of those games you got to have
a decent graphics card running hooter
hun not not well if he's know if he's
doing it through console you can get a
capture a
capture card I think is what it is just
basically this thing okay that plugs in
between your TV and your deal and it
records it in
what's the [ __ ] company that's enough
for me bro that's
okay I know gato is the name brand
I'm not sure that's my cat el Pussycat
Oh
[Music]
roasted
it needs a good trim
[Music]
dude he's tore the [ __ ] altered all
the carpet up underneath doors and [ __ ]
so yeah separation anxiety yeah
definitely I mean he went from the car
his whole life to like not having anyone
who gives a [ __ ] about him so
used to regulate my feces whoa the
phrase regulate my feces is awkward yeah
that's what it's about very good job on
that one Oh written on the dad
good job on the dad good job on the
depth yeah double on the dabs yeah I
mean I don't have like six tabs there
seven tabs since I've been here and I'm
not asleep yet or drooling from my nose
you know
good yeah all right yeah I think we've
done more dabs right now since we do on
our show no no today was pretty damn
heavy it started
at that point yeah yeah both you [ __ ]
but home took a nap I definitely take
some dads before I
eat yeah I came here like a long hour
drive to work every day and I definitely
like to be well medicated when I wake up
so I would I'm gonna start the day off
couple of I turn on the email I walked
to the pisser and turn on the email it's
like this is the pathway all right it's
on the way to the men's room
start this you just want to be like this
we'll check it out guys we're hanging
out at the table we're doing on what I
like to call a SWAT cast with two two
cool-ass Colorado podcast it's cheesy as
[ __ ] right we're gonna do a swap cast
sittin at the table I'm Rasta Jeff from
the girl from the heart podcast if
you're listening on the Colorado podcast
feed what's up guys my name's Rasta Jeff
thanks for jumping in if you're
listening on my feet joining me at my
table is our buddy Jesse hey go [ __ ]
your mother
[Music]
across the line okay hard at it right
there
[Music]
[Laughter]
kind of testing the waters but that's
goals there's no reason to edit
over here next to filthy Jessi with a
filthy [ __ ] forest so what do you go
what are you dirty d [ __ ]
despicable dare despicable Derek alright
welcome to my table and thanks for
letting me be on your guys's show yeah I
appreciate it thank you for letting us
be a part of your show this is fun I
like doing the swap ething and then
sitting over here my brother number 44
is that what we call you this before I
call you 44 and - yeah you're really the
originality of that I mean 44 yes I
didn't like it at first don't get me
wrong but it kind of grows on you and
it's one quite a few hatpin so I I can't
really [ __ ] shut up to a sour seed
company from throwing down absolutely
that's my boy right there now he comes
in the shop and we've talked I didn't
know he was like a literature originally
from Florida yeah we literally live
15minutes
the same
stuff like
I'm telling you
today that we're gonna have to we're
gonna someone's gonna ask for me and
Jesse we mix you know somehow dropping
hot fire you know dropping hot fire
doubtful he's got a mullet and he just
said dropping hop I mean
sir I can't make up my [ __ ] mind
leave me alone
it's more walks
[Music]
it's deep if you can rock it and don't
give a [ __ ] it works I'm telling you
more power to you absolutely are very
very punk rock
either Kentucky or punk rock
hey I got it when I was in the lovely
facilities here in the county I got the
name mole top so you know there was
actually somebody in there with a
beautiful a beautiful like flowing
Tennessee waterfall like the best one
I've ever seen and literally dude
everybody kept asking him where are you
from Kentucky like and he's like no I'm
from here and he's just like he was a
normal dude but he had the best mullet
ever to the doodle Halen mullet and in
in county lockup Tennessee waterfall
[Music]
I'm gonna take a DAB somebody else talk
yeah okay so yeah what do you been up to
like besides besides taking down
44 yeah no problem so how's your week
been Jesse
I was kind of lost in the moment you
know yeah yeah yeah so let me ask you
how's it how does it feel to be here at
the table like recording we've talked
about like it feels awesome
this is a show in this table's turned a
handful of people green oh you want to
admit that you were part of that
multiple part of
that RSO that is the highest I've ever
been I'm not sure which RSO iced hash
with ice the ISO is oh sorry
I was pho
man we took solving this hash and then
we pressed it and used a rosin press to
press out some solvent list some fresh
frozen solvent yeah nice and then I
rolled it out again i heated up a car of
cap and rolled it out
there's no operating moving vehicles at
that point bro like I literally pulled
over and slept in a parking lot I may
have been homeless at the time but I was
going somewhere else he knows he'll
meet Jesse at the time and I was like I
texted Jeff was like hey text Jesse I
can't he got some possession ticket no
no that was that was why I came over
here I think was to tell him show me the
position I was headed to be homeless
somewhere else
[Laughter]
[Music]
this is everybody's like why Pablo and
say why not why not you know like just
go from Walmart Walmart if there's two
of them so you know I want to talk about
this for a second since a lot of people
that listen to my podcast expect some
sort of cannabis talk Adam got the only
person that I have ever seen it happened
to got a possession of cannabis ticket
I'm definitely the first person this you
need 12 right
[Music]
yeah I may have dropped that I may have
left and heard his word to my own in my
own voice and been like yeah
perfect elbow I know killer I discovered
that like two shows ago over there it
doesn't work isn't this right here it's
like yeah I'm completely away from the
table at any point there's a thousand
dollars in glass on the table right now
and I'm like no no no there's water
bottles more than that I'm good this was
a G yeah well I mean a that piece though
that piece though yeah yeah shut up to
the problem they made that lots of
people get tickets in national parks I
don't know about most home improvement
every time you go to the woods in
Florida do you damn sure walk out of
there with a canvas somebody walks out
somebody owned up to it and they're like
well I mean I'm gonna write everybody a
ticket which we all know that's a bunch
of [ __ ] you know I'm saying
somebody's gotta own up to it or you
just found some weed bro I don't know
what to tell you good smoking that you
know like know every time you go to the
National Forest in Florida you get a
cannabis ticket don't care yeah but it's
not it's not it's legal and you can
still get a ticket no if you're not what
if you're smoking in the wrong area if
you're smoking at a state park if you're
smoking at the skate park what about
what about Fe you're watching a movie
with your cat in your lap trying to stay
warm while it's snowing and you're in
your car though you're smoking a bowl
because you're watching a movie happens
to be the best move we pretty much have
the beginning of the year they ruined
Star Wars [ __ ] them I've [ __ ] the
police I don't care what you guys that's
the way I feel about it these are all
dear opinions yeah 444-4444 and Lord abs
Inc 44 and - no no
no bro tell us about what we're dabbing
a beautiful-looking chatter here we 44
2/4 44 quarter yeah yeah see 45 just
doesn't roll off the tongue 44 plus one
ankle monitor
I honestly I told him today that we're
doing two podcasts so it's kind of like
whenever I know I'm good for an hour - I
have the second show you've recorded
today absolutely nice so it's not why
you guys were like we've done this
already I didn't mean to not fill in
your audience
[Music]
when you can I know how it is trying to
record a podcast you put that torch
right up to the mic dunno
Thursday's are normal recording days
shout-out to roster set by the way I
wish it
[Music]
straight up that we were a little mean
to each other so we've been trying to be
positive
talk a lot of [ __ ] to each other on your
podcast I listened to the Colorado
podcast as each other I
[Music]
don't know down at the box
I
[Music]
guess that's just how our friendship
friendship you remember I mean you were
here around that's kind of when I give
you a shout-out on the show on time
little you to [ __ ] get to work
it's like hey Derek get to [ __ ] work
we might pick that scab that day though
I love Derek just simply for that reason
oh is that what is that I see what
happened I see it oh that's [ __ ]
funny
the courts you can burn it off there's
no there's a courts banner over there
there's another banger on the show
[Music]
just happened so dirty D took a dab set
the rig down and just rested it gently
up against Jesse's his tea bottle now
it's perfectly carved now he's got a car
like that last yeah yeah like a
widemouth can or something like a
shotgun Keystone
college man that Bob Ross that too right
there everybody's gonna there's gonna be
people turning in like this dude shotgun
a key stand before we're good
my listeners don't know what yes
[Music]
I
mean if they're old listeners they might
they might remember about yes I'm chaos
you know the girl from your heart meets
a trailer park
[Music]
[Laughter]
summarize that very nicely they're gonna
hit the Hitman Simpson collab I was
gonna ask what this was
yeah I don't know what color they are
what color that pool is not sure what
color it's pretty fresh it's like minty
green turquoise ish it's got a green
label tip green flag I thought that was
the same way you've always had I see now
it's
[Music]
the secret shout it to had a mil Wow
right wish I could have been there next
time bro next time put yourself on the
list sent an email peace process
yeah yeah I just honestly I don't think
any of us knew it was happening you're
like
[Music]
it's a secret yeah yeah well I mean you
know we're kind of the local Pablo guys
though you know like you're you're a
little bit more of the bigger mover and
shaker we're down here down by the river
just you know Adams just laughs just
bollocks I'm [ __ ] six five and have
dreadlocks to my ass and it was like oh
it's that guy yeah
yeah
I tell people I don't tell people how
wrong they are I tell them how old
they're
like a child bro right yeah they're
taller than some people I know it's
definitely a word yeah
remember when you were to guitar center
they were only like yeah now you're
exporting the band down all the nipple
lame fish I had to quit rocking the
bandana cuz it was making my dreads girl
funny like I still do it occasionally
but it was making my hair grow weird so
I know all about that I can grow funny
yeah do you know love Ryan see
with dreadlocks
years
[Music]
he had dreads way before me I worked
with him this summer he put him in nice
and we were working up in Salida put in
phone lines that [ __ ] like that and he
kept the entire summer like even when we
were off work and everything kept it
wrapped up in a bandanna and everything
nowadays he's got their fur getting
massive I bet yeah I probably
I think it's so heavy
is it thick like
[Music]
smoky you know smokey now I do
I have probably a new smoke he's like
Hispanic no no no no then it's a
different smokey but he is a younger
Hispanic guy with a bunch of tattoos oh
I
feel like having red likes is like
having a child but only attached to your
head cuz you like take care of him a
[ __ ] I was born like this a little bit
of maintenance to be done now that
they're this long I get him tuned up by
a friend of mine about once a month she
doesn't work up on the top there's not
much to be done past year there's
nothing to work on that's what I need
this I need that hook you know
[Music]
I just need someone to show [ __ ] love
to this you know this monstrosity I'm
just found a couple people it's just uh
then again it's like I want my hair so
you know I'll show them and they're like
can't you know I come over your house no
no no just google it the number I have
books here in town earlene in Colorado
you think there's a be like
right
I'm sure if you go to Facebook you could
find somebody like my friend doesn't
really do Street where to get them
chicken wings that time
red and that white dude was like the old
white ball dude was like oh yeah my
wife's dude it needs to sit and they're
telling me how I should fix this and fix
that and I'm like this old 65 year old
white dude just sitting here telling me
how to fix dreadlocks and I'm like sure
all right yeah I swear it was me and you
I was going up there to get wings or
something
I've only eight up there with the one
with you so you guys still addicted to
street tacos absolutely very much so
everybody did the mics yeah
what's your favorite place here in town
me yeah
street tacos
yeah if I'm gonna go get some vegan
tacos I think the place is called
coquettes and Colorado Springs shout-out
to the vegan tacos or the burrowing owl
if you want some good vegan food yeah
I've been with you trying to order food
it's
the Coquette served like tofu it was all
your normal taco fixings but then tofu
that had been season 2 done well
thinking mushrooms
that's what the [ __ ] mellow mushroom
they replace all meat with that place
so fire dude that was that was probably
the best pizza I mean every wasn't cheap
for my standards but
everybody at the table didn't go yeah
it's not a mile away from the sacred
session there's a little pizza joint
that I could remember the [ __ ] name
of it because it's pointless to just
talk about it not know the name but it's
basically the size of the pizza joint is
the size of this whole recording area
like this recording it and they were
playing like hardcore music I guess I
don't the dudes [ __ ] real distorted
but kind of slow the dude was mad and
screaming a lot
I've noticed this before hardcore music
and pizza places
relation yeah if I had to work near that
[ __ ] hot ass oven all
Henry Rollins in the background
[Music]
this little place is pretty pretty
badass dude pizza slices were 250 for a
slice of cheese pizza and then had a
topping and like certain toppings for
certain prices named your basic [ __ ] but
of this slice of pizza was like a third
of [ __ ] eighth of the pie you know
what I mean it was a big-ass [ __ ]
slice of pizza so for 250 our three
slices of pizza I couldn't even eat the
[ __ ] third one so
[Music]
yeah have you tried Black Jacks tomato
and green chili its are here in town no
but I have a good friend of works that
are so shot at my friend of black jack
pizza I got friends
people yeah well I also know the other
one of the other delivery drivers there
so we really talking about pedia yeah we
are
[Music]
they go well together that's all we're
saying I
totally paid for pizza
yeah I know I mean for how long you've
been ordering the one place you go to
all the time like I I'm sure there's
been a couple delivery drivers
throughout the time you're like it's a
place that I can call and tell them Who
I am can I get that pizza and like yeah
we owe you and they just show up with
pizzas I talked about
the one that way I don't know
[Music]
pizzas [ __ ] free and delicious comes
in it takes two fat dads and sets now
pizzas I had a couple of bucks as a kind
of kindness to same same deal yeah
text me later text me anytime bro yeah I
can do that I never ever ever since you
know the the hash has gotten a whole lot
better it definitely that helped the
game too you know he's like holy [ __ ]
bro I was like yeah it's it's it's good
usually on my podcast I can't take big
giant dabs because I get all dab down
and can't talk but there's [ __ ] four
people here so I'm gonna dab this go
ahead dab that I'm
gonna go ahead dab all of that I'll take
a taste of whatever that
tastes
like a half a gram and that's only 0.3
you just ruined everything I know I was
trying to get high over here
trying to do the play-by-play here
trying to comp on a podcast so I don't
think that's possible he's got a dad
that it's about the size of a dime like
a little Donald I'm like ohh fati a
shout out to roster said it looks like
Australia
is about to smoke you
need to come to the States my friend
we need to go to him
I have to be here
everything
yeah
well that might be worth the risk see
Mike towards a little bit Oh
the problem with not talking into the
mic directly he's getting good at
podcasting he's I think his first
podcast appearance was probably my show
yeah he he didn't speak much and when he
did he said um Ilana
sation with this I'll listen to your
guys's to the Colorado podcast and do a
show now
definitely appreciate it
start to get pretty proud of the show
I have to thank God I have to contain
myself on this show and not totally just
take control and be the leader
from the beginning I
[Music]
was just playing around I was gonna work
out and we're [ __ ] beautiful
yeah yeah and I'm sure your mother is a
wonderful lady
friend who claims that they're going to
beat me to the intro like I'm gonna
memorize the whole thing and do it I'll
let you do it really want to we'll see
click try it one time that was really
funny that was so many times Clint's
been back yeah
hey watchin you do the intro is pretty
impressive actually no no paper now and
all the sponsors [ __ ] just kill it I
know notes I do most of the pot most my
podcasts have been happening in two
takes I do about 15 to 20 minutes
take a drink dunno by myself it's hard
to talk you're only said one person I
think this will probably be in the 130s
the mid 131 34 is up this actually in
the recording this is labeled 135 I'm
not sure goes 135 or 136 I'm um 52 weeks
out of the year doing one a week that's
yeah that's impressive yeah you got a
facebook memory the other day it was uh
just recorded my first podcast or so
nice right yeah that'd be about two
years ago
this shows my shows a little over two
years yeah yeah nice all over I was in
the middle of April I think was two
years around cannabis cup time mhm or
not cannabis cup time right before it or
something yeah I think so because we you
hit
[Music]
episode 50 right around cannabis cup
time I believe because that would be
about a year Yeah right you know
sometimes that would do two episodes a
week
it's hard it's hard to have that much
content yeah
hey I got a podcast do you want to come
be on it and people were like a
[Music]
week when I brought fetus in it was just
like he was my roommate he was just kind
of hanging out
he sat down and just saying it ya got a
friend named fetus yeah
literally like signaled the airplane to
land on the deck and then said hold on
one minute you have a name friend name
fetus yeah he's a little young so you
know it's like a baby type deal you know
like he's he's 18 but he's like he's
like an adopted kid that is allowed to
hang you know that so he's like your
little
[Music]
every group needs a fetus yeah
Seamus the nickname comes from an
incident with some acid and maybe a
position yeah
house literally dabbed him out so much
that he's sitting in front of a grow
tent with it on like bride his [ __ ] with
his hands on his like his head burns
knees trying to go to sleep
he's [ __ ] 18 years old dude like he
just can't stay awake and he'll fall
asleep on the couch and just like curl
up and it's just like that's all the
older that kid is yeah he's 18 yeah yeah
yeah yeah
nobody cares from you're from Wisconsin
bro or whatever the [ __ ] Iowa and
definitely not Cali hey [ __ ] K bro I'm
not saying it to you
[Music]
there's definitely worse places I need
to show you guys the
Mexifornia
cartoon or Calot i don't know which one
that is whichever cartoon that I watch
Borderlands our border you won't see
that yeah I did it's still there's some
in there what happened there Susan I I
didn't want to choke on the podcast okay
just delete Jeff just stabbed us Joe you
man
[Music]
I like to take dad's alright practice
talk afterwards that's what
the table because we're all cigarette
smokers and we're like [ __ ] you
I don't I was at a company meeting
yesterday
yeah this is a peek into my life you
guys I was at a company meeting
yesterday at the the 4/20 dad lounge I
don't remember real name the 420 and
things the 420 dad lamppost video go to
golf courses are like to brunch yeah
yeah and the boss handed me a thing of
hash and I was like am I supposed to
take a glob out of it or just taste it
he's like cuz everybody needs to get
some
good everybody
[Music]
yeah
I'm sure we all seen then meme go around
here recently it's like yes I'm going to
smoke all your hash yeah absolutely
you're the person I thought of like yeah
oh I can take a big job I've literally
heard you ask hey man can I get a big
dab of that and they're like yeah yeah
sure and they're like piecing two pieces
together and there you're like no no no
can I like that
yeah just hit that was something on
whatever the biggest piece is can I have
that yeah because and I've seen you take
it and they're like they're sitting
there with a job and guy it's not bad
man tastes pretty good cool thanks bro
where's who's next
but yeah for sure we're at the if one of
the cannabis cups and I don't even
remember which one it was it was hard to
find a place to smoke if this these
older events their work tables and [ __ ]
like there are now and I finally found a
place and I'm chilling out and this
girl's like hey can I join you guys
until we let her [ __ ] hang out with
us of course and she threw down some
hash she was here to smoke this and so I
did it was a good sized chunk of hash I
thought she was kind of kind of
challenging
that was for everybody to smoke
yeah yeah censored look how grown up
he's getting
you know we haven't we haven't have
another pot yet just for that kind of
story
we sure do we can record that story
right after this someone may have had
something that goes up a person's nose
and they
[Music]
misunderstood it and thought it was
for everyone
[Music]
we've done it with LSD as well
for people
that's what you're supposed to portion
it out
remember April so don't just hand people
drugs
exactly portion it out or just keep it
for yourself and make it last a month
under to do with people incorrect sir
incorrect just saying yeah I've been D
tripping about myself before that's not
necessarily a bad thing
it's like three four o'clock in the
afternoon that's what I want to go you
know I'm saying like I definitely
especially here with that sunset dude
you can just rip it in your car all day
I live somewhere now okay
[Music]
yeah that was
he upgraded now he's got I got the
Impala
hey I get around
[Laughter]
[Music]
silence
track me I ain't going nowhere I just
happen to buy a car for cheap that's
from out of town that's all I mean if so
I'll jump it or throw it off a cliff I
don't give a [ __ ] like zero how about
that [ __ ] anklet way a lot
they changed it from one ankle to the
other today it's still there's still a
mark in the other side of my ankle like
where it's been here for a month yeah
when they first put it on it was so
tight that it literally like you could
see the little holes
[Music]
[ __ ] emails get me every time yeah it
does I keep my kind of hot yeah
you keep it a little hot the last one he
had the little pyramid [ __ ] that thing
really yeah I figured you'd try to fix
it since you have friends in places they
like dude that's an OG [ __ ] nail
though yeah all right whatever okay it's
bad filete
it blinks just doesn't heat
it's just you can just run the other one
on the floor just have it up your
blinkin people would never know it all
and everything fried out on it oh well
we can get LEDs super cheap quit
blinking like
yeah and then it started again though
one day it started and then it went out
it wasn't a very good unit oh well I
mean it was kind of first of its kind
yeah towards the beginning it was kind
of a gift I sell D nails all day so the
company that gifted it to me kind of
went weird on me so I'm just avoiding
all that conversation
[Music]
over the border like six months later I
get a bill from the Canadian government
or somebody and I'm like what the [ __ ]
is about now like you owe us taxes for
some four hundred dollar gift to you
yeah that's called spam bro
[Music]
just the taxes on the four hundred and I
tried to ignore it twice and then the
letters changed colors did you know
you're related to his importance too and
he's got two trucks just waiting for you
if you change colors
from white to yellow
there's like 16 bucks
[Music]
to Miami but I mean
Prince of Canada
[Laughter]
changes name for like two pesos
that's that's the day and age we live in
now to where like your spam folder is
not your friend
good thanks for that just leave me
hanging with that laughs that
I get so much spam on my email accounts
that like only my good [ __ ] shows or the
good [ __ ] shows up at the spam account
now spam text messages
and if you apply for jobs like do any
flake off third party sites like
Craigslist or [ __ ] like that it's all
sketch they'll call you back and want
you to like dial star six seven it's
like I'm not dialing [ __ ]
why would you apply for a job on a third
party website because Craigslist is a
normal place for normal poor people
Jesse and I mean I'm sorry
like applications I mean you can't find
jobs and cheap place drop their monster
calm
understood oh my bad yeah
[Music]
let's keep it a little more positive
guys yeah
[Music]
hey go [ __ ] yourself
I'm sorry
[Laughter]
you had like 90 dabs broke up here and
there's like three left and we're all
staring in it like the last piece of
pizza some of my own [ __ ] you guys take
that when I got my own shatter here
there's
your fingers all over the Shannon
[Music]
dude I think was named
yes Jew guy from fun Joe Rogan like the
pardon on Joe Rogan from church I think
is Lisa I am yeah
what's that he doesn't really hide
the one of him tripping on acid was
last podcast dude I needed to watch that
thing cuz the one them taking LSD on
like the podcast and they're like this
podcast is brought to you by [ __ ]
naturebox yo Dee are you qualified to
use that [ __ ]
[Music]
like four times I
could've done that for you if you like I
would I would absolutely be capable all
right well then do your damn self then
yeah there's positivity for you Oh
put the microphone against his forehead
and yeah see this is the thing the video
just with trying to you know for these
special episodes oh yeah video this show
would be ridiculous it would be every
fun yeah I don't think it's fair that
some people would be able to see it I'm
absolutely abandon some people when we
start talking about video
no they don't have a really fast render
process for this body making the videos
- yeah for damn ever yeah vamp ever
Hellfire
so I had never started a collar at dope
show without if I did never been on your
show so thank you though sometimes
wanting to bring up tonight and some
series I'm serious no thank you from I
do have one little subject if that we
could do maybe then I'll blame part of
my show on like Tim Martin
cast not Tim Ryan actor just no no no
radio yeah Tim JDR way back in then I'm
poking again I'm wait I'm a little bit
of Danny Danko show kind of enjoy this
yeah and then Adam Dunn show of course
yeah but then I had him he'll for sure
[Music]
that might control
for sure I like the
survivalist show
non non cannabis
okay
what other podcasts do you listen to of
course everyone at the table is mr.
[ __ ] Joe Rogan right
Joey Coco Diaz more okay I didn't then
Joe Rogan just because Joe Rogan it
seems like he's three of my week and
brought out how the [ __ ] do you do that
like I Drive an hour to and fro yeah
we're gonna grow where I stick one ear
but in one ear and just go to [ __ ]
work have you ever heard of unpopular
opinion no but I should listen to it it
sounds like yeah check them out they're
funny weird I will I like them it's from
there from cracked.com I don't know if
you okay yeah yeah I like Doug Stanhope
spod cast ironically they just sit
around get drunk and take adderall and
talk [ __ ]
[Music]
it's pretty [ __ ] good it's the Doug
Stanhope shot-clock podcast the guy's
name that does that one because I'm too
high right listen to this I mean no I
mean when you forget listen
we all like stare to him like
now I can't remember the host like yeah
like wait did I miss some of this
now are we talking about this right now
later
[Music]
listen to the podcast called this bro
this
back to the travelin ship be careful we
might be sent back to stop Donald Trump
see ya oh yeah just rolled all that in
the whole podcast no this is a three in
a row he's brought up the thirteen
monkeys thing mister Timo he's saying
[Music]
the box is
out the movie
no
the box right is that what no that's
seven okay all right
the [ __ ] head in the box all right
whatever it's all right who gives a [ __ ]
about how many monkeys you got I don't
care how many boxes all right we'll just
watch the movie I'll watch it tonight
[Music]
I dropped butane
everybody [ __ ] relax
thousands of dollars in glass on this
table you
should
break your mutant mutant
just trying to do air horn I need no air
horn
in my pocket every time I come over here
like tappman like the little tiny huh
yeah do it get a sign see what happens
you keep making rules I keep breaking
them that's the way the system works
buddy I
[Laughter]
guess we're not getting invited back
love this
we're not taking you anywhere with us
this is why you can't take me anywhere
I'm example we're gonna walk out of here
both oh you're gonna like whip off the
belt
[ __ ] stupid dumb redneck go home and
think about what you did don't listen to
anything we'll save the beating for the
next episode high school we'll get it on
tape exactly yeah yeah yeah well let's
just in this one
[Music]
hey I'm just saying I bet I could take
one of your lists
hey
no no yeah we all know your past not
saying that Jeff wouldn't be just as
equal but you know at least he's skinny
you're [ __ ] yeah you could probably
just go like
yeah for sure no
I try not to piss you off at every point
in time because I've seen you bastard
who I call when I can't handle this [ __ ]
right
Jessie's pretty weak
thanks Dee positivity all the way yeah
well I've thrown him down a couple times
so I might be skinny
would you like to toaster yeah why don't
you tell your
own in the garage now
but I'm not stupid but I did
eat that Rasta
I mean it's like a brotherly type love
literally thinks he's [ __ ] coming
into the room and jumping onto the top
rope at any time like
all the time
that's my trim dude he trims [ __ ]
seven hours a day eight hours a day with
me seriously seven hours a day dreams
like I do probably the other hour of the
day I chop down trees and bring them out
to the room and weigh them and then
[ __ ] hand them to Randall's and then
by the end of the day I got a pile of
trim buds dude it's [ __ ] amazing I'm
shoutout to that kid I see those
episodes something like all just sitting
around kickin it singing like [ __ ]
and oh what the Turbie boys yeah boys
tribute boys do you do metric stuff yeah
I do metric all day long yeah what you
think you're their cute little message
oh yeah metric went down I was gonna
talk about that I normal on a normal
episode of my show but this is good
metric went down
for like [ __ ] six hours dude and you
couldn't do anything
thing you couldn't yeah you pretty much
could was it around on the retail end
because I think they use MMJ menu on the
retail end so they could do that the
retail worked fine but any of the grow
we had we were packaging a transfer and
a large transfer like we're in the
middle of a hefty harvest don't even
want to talk about how mature we were
packaging
it took me and another dude [ __ ] a
couple hours to put all these packages
together so we put all the packages
together there weighed their bags we got
the marker written on and when we go to
do it in the computer and metric says
sorry we're down
we're gonna do [ __ ] yeah I can't quote
it with this but a stupid little message
but it came back up the next day and
it's like we've had our yeah had our
buds have been working or we've been
working our buds off to get things back
smoking again or something like that and
they tried to be cute about it and they
apologized but they definitely tried to
be witty you guys get that wrote from a
dispensary up and in PETA or what
just sounds something cliche like they
would do
I'm not I'm not even drop any names
we wouldn't send him in there oh
I had a screen shot I just must find
whoa
that's pretty sure you got a screen shot
of that
I was tagging plants
[Music]
oh
my god
you're ridiculous yeah
fortunate
hold that torch closer to the microphone
you told Dee you know I you know what
I think we need to give Adam his own
show what are we gonna call it the [ __ ]
off
oh no we'll do it with Asterix it's fine
that would work trailer podcast yeah 44
minutes what did you call your hairstyle
Moloch's podcast yeah the wall locks 44
yeah what do you want dad rigged let's
be a highly-educated
titanium [ __ ] nail
will taste so good
it's a little dirty because I'd take lab
so it needs a little heat to it but once
you put some heat on it
[Music]
when I asked this question earlier I got
so much [ __ ] from everybody but you see
how these two [ __ ] just gave you
[ __ ] and I said nothing because I've
already been down that road and I was
that [ __ ] getting [ __ ] talked about
but it's cool it's fine you know I I'm
your friend don't feel jealous I'm not
it's just jealousy
right I got a couple for free but yeah
absolutely well I paid for a lot of them
I can just put it on my checks the Hat I
never even see the money so yeah there's
literally and you know I can't first
robot Fight Club you know
the nicest part of your apparel
absolutely and my shirt that I got for
free from from Jesse so I mean
that's easy cologne I [ __ ] rock the
easy cloth you're a [ __ ] table that
picture you showed me was the picture
monstrous those roots never eat em roast
Oh easy Colonna roots no
he's a clone of brutes I did them a
little bit of rapid starter a little bit
of be alright an easy cloner and an easy
corner but I put in this I put an air
pump in my easy clean
circulation
[Music]
the more air the better in your cloner
prolly
router in it yeah it's so smooth it's
like it's a dry hit but there's one
because there's hardly any water yeah
it's literally right above the second
per client we've dabbed so hard that the
water is kind of you can see the old
god damn it Derek oops I'm not the
owners
because my broken hand
[Music]
torch off your plastic yeah oh yeah you
that it's got a little lump a bottle on
there
there dripping on to here this is care
packs packaging okay your parchments
it's got a little dab left on it but
Colorado problems
whoa
I mean why not you know like
different if you're the smoke detector
that's just but it's not else it off
there's
like glowing and
yeah I guess you know the Tirpitz
containers would be plastic too so it's
just gonna be vapor on there so let's go
yeah yeah you're trying to drip it onto
a zig zag bro
there's some other shitty papers that
you're trying to pawn off I wasn't
trying to pawn off I gave a couple of my
friends samples of some papers there's
someone pawned off on me all right I was
just trying to be nice and even thought
about him because I have to at least say
I like the packaging am i right like the
picture on that well yeah but I mean
come on when do you get papers with with
it's like listening to Mandarin
how much [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] her
energy drink
[Music]
you know like just to hang out with
these two [ __ ] is one thing like
together but then like you're always so
busy now that you know I
mean I gotta figure out is different
pitches and tones
[Music]
you guys doing a rap song
you can absolutely I'll give you
everything you need and dared it came
like wow listen I'll give you exactly
what you need just let me know it's
scary I'll give you exactly what you
yeah all over the microphone don't give
a [ __ ] zero
somebody
jesse was saying something I was giving
somebody [ __ ] like oh you don't need to
say that on ba-ba-ba-ba-ba social media
and I was like I don't go [ __ ] my
nicknames 44 I give zero [ __ ] and he's
like oh you talk all this big [ __ ]
online and Jesse chimes in with no
that's really him
[Music]
that's really him he wouldn't give two
[ __ ] and he's not a troll
under the bridge not on the internet
yeah is it what was that sound for you
cuz that was that my ego to [ __ ] under
there there's a secret behind what you
said oh there's a secret is it a troll
secret because I mean if I if I had a
troll secret I would I would probably
come to you you've been have you been
known to took this quite a few people
huh no no no it has one of the best ones
ever I
can't no
shoot myself in the foot on that but
I'll tell you later I'm working on
another podcast and you alluded to the
name has it don't don't do to get my
friends I've already done cross over it
now I'm good but I'm just saying
it's good it's good good [ __ ] oh just
beef Jesse pulled the Mike out of the
bike stand
that's Jesse right there
[ __ ] that that's stupid that's
definitely how we do it I remember
seeing a Zac day the road should do that
you're not a trap artist either though
trappin I could introduce you to one of
those if you need
fresh hot beats
really I got these fresh hot beats yeah
yeah there's demon hot save a tree
killer trap artist I'm not sure why trap
artists and trees where does that man
just just kill artists
save a puppy killer trap artists Wow
tell us how you feel yeah yeah Jesse
doesn't like trap music no did your
headphones cut out cuz you
do a shout out to this piece of
equipment every occasion the live wire
solutions h AO for 4 channel stereo
headphone amplifier pop things [ __ ] you
it is cutting out sometimes but if you
like pull on the wire and I put my
that's the connection
here yeah it's one of the things that me
and Jesse literally sat down at the
table and we both kind of looked at it
and said uh you're still using that
piece of [ __ ]
because if I go to Guitar Center and
it's on this sucks they go oh we know
here's another one try this
the upgraded model is the same thing
just look like a fancy plastic housing
fixing solution we get bigger problems
yeah use a
like it's a four-way splitter but it's
all molded together no independent
channels yeah I like the independent
channels I like to crank my enough when
I do my show
yeah and I mean you got owns broadcast
to
hear that yeah that's a phone so I guess
someone's about to give text yeah we're
all digging I looked up across the room
and everyone got cracked screens now I
had to get my soul I did crack a screen
like a month ago and
that was like 100 dude really you got
that sticker on there man this phone
goes away that sticker so [ __ ] cool
you know you know you know what this
sticker does prevent people from
stealing my phone
[Music]
and I had to go to the Apple store and
they charged me 200 bucks to replace my
phone and they wanted a whole bunch more
money but I was like I just got the
phone the screen replaced so it can I
get some some love and they hooked me up
they charged me 200 bucks that sucked
yeah
yeah Apple dude - just [ __ ] close
today
oh yeah I try not to have my phone out
when I'm near reservoirs yes
yeah 300 gallon Reza's in a room lined
up and then I've got two 55-gallon trash
cans on wheels they're usually filled
with water then I've got another resin
another room I try not to have that
[ __ ] phone I got a mop bucket what
about you Dee because I know you gotta
work to worry about losing your phone in
or probably some some soup no I got a
Hot Wheels at work okay okay yeah I
didn't where we put the food in yeah I
got a mop bucket that's about my or the
toilet you ever deep-fry phone on
[Music]
cleaning that
no like
[Music]
we need a macbook 4d to do recording yep
another macbook for me because this
one's filled with photography and other
nonsense i need one to dedicate to the
show and one that i could Google with
[Music]
put me above my tax bracket I need one
of those new iPads that iPad pro thing
you would definitely get shoutouts all
the time from the garden would be
phenomenal
from the garden I wouldn't have to go
use the main really Wow you do metric
from an iPad cool
you just walk around and do you
just carry with you be so much easier
the MacBook or something in the [ __ ]
grow with you
yeah come on guys go ahead
they're gonna be starting him a
Kickstarter
that'll be cool trying to buy like an
$800 iPad
Kickstarter
sure I bet you could put a jar on the
table and be like you this way you could
watch me at work say we don't hang out
enough here you go
that was my phone there's thousands of
dollars I'm not going through this every
time I drop something I'm buying damn it
that's why it has a cracked screen yep
and that sticker
[ __ ] have they real parvis to do
hey I gave you first got here so what's
up its own so he's like oh yeah yeah now
so that's such a big conversation is
very big who's very make the blaze
there's not big for him because we had
this conversation I was like okay
the chapel oh hey stop
a
couple episodes back this is totally
like shut up
[Music]
two shows ago this is you look at me and
you go you've already said forty point
over my shoulder to shoulder core to
piss on the Mayans over here right
behind me right on Jeff right on the
back of his chair that'd be great
you said right behind you - [ __ ] ray
crevasse right oh my
[Music]
for quiet enough watch if we're quiet oh
yeah you think so I'll be
just right for it so we can hear okay
P louder
in the bowl
[Laughter]
[Music]
valiant effort that was
probably the weirdest thing I've ever
[Music]
thought he was like answering the phone
he's like hello
hello super for the people that are
listening on my feed where can the
people listen to your guys's show
we're on soundcloud at Colorado podcast
at the moment and then you can also find
them on our website you can find him
find him on our web site at Colorado com
jeez come on D
[Music]
time bro what the [ __ ] we're
trying it ain't workin our guys Rangers
they could find my shows available on
iTunes we're gonna get your show on
iTunes
stitcher I'm on iTunes I'm on stitcher
my shows available on my website I read
genetics Colorado calm and my shows
available every Wednesday at 1 o'clock
on talk radio
I'd go to talk radio calm you can listen
it's a live feed it's just always
streaming something's going on sometimes
J jumps in and does live stuff he'll
just play music based on his his vibe of
the day I know you're busy guy now but
is there are you still doing genetics
definitely why just I didn't know if you
wanted to
oh well I don't have anything available
at the time but I'm making a rise f2s
okay which I'll be on my testers bust
through a bunch of those and then I may
put some of those out to the public I
definitely like a rise a lot it's it's
dream we had a really good cut of it
yeah it was like our number three year
number five or something like I know I
rise number one
I think it was number one that we kept
around for a long time so some of the
early stuff you had got an amazing boy
of that that cross and then I've got
girls of that and then I'm gonna put it
like
several females in a room probably like
somewhere between 16 and 20 girls and
that arise male in a room two of the
arise the same male the two clones of it
the same room and grow about and [ __ ]
hit that pollen on all those plants and
make like between 15 and 20 new crosses
and test them all out works
now that I think about that arrays
number one that we had
it's that your male is the male
counterpart to that phenotype nice
just big tall amazing by that's crazy
projection
[Music]
the first time we ran that actually that
was two years ago we also had the black
cherry Kim last year when I've read
arise I really expected it to take
longer to finish flowering but I get
seven and a half to eight to nine week
phenotype that stuff it's like
yeah you would think
golden go on appearances I think a lot
of growers if they didn't know what it
was but think it was a longer flowering
strain than it really is that trait
actually comes from the Romulan in it
because from Canada those guys brother
[ __ ] to finish a little earlier they
found the earlier finishing sativas and
went for that aspect that's like we were
talking to Christian the other day on
one of the forums or one of the groups
if you guys want to learn something
please check out the girl from your our
podcast I mean we're Jesse's
knowledgeable and there is you know he's
got the years on this belt and I'm I'm
learning as we go but like Jeff you've
had you've definitely had the experience
for the endure for years and years and
years so I did a lot of practice lately
yeah don't you have to go from your art
podcast
honestly the two best growers in town
are sitting at the table right here
you're the indoor dude and you're the
outdoor dude I mean that's the way it's
been on your podcast and that's you know
like so if I was gonna ask the question
for somebody you're the person I would
call friend or and you're the person I
would call for outdoors so I yeah thank
you no no that's cool I'm happy to be a
part of all of it you know I don't think
a really
well I don't know too many outdoor
growers either so don't
the Sun will save your ass many attires
won't it Jeff
watch my plants live and die
the first year I was here I was granted
like scrambling to ask you questions and
like I was telling him to ask you
questions I'm shows like what do I do
about I know I'll just like dude that
was the worst thing I ever did I covered
it at dirt at like 11:00 in the
afternoon by - they were like literally
floppy plants and I was like
[Music]
color cover it in like fine particulates
and that he bought from a store and it
was I've seen people do that to
get rid of nasties yes I've tried it
before it's a pain and [ __ ] ass but
outdoors and a root pound container that
is so rude bandaged burying out every
day and they were in a five-gallon
bucket I mean no they were in earth pots
but they were actually drying out every
day every day
I wake up at 10 o'clock and be like holy
[ __ ] what's wrong did you hear that did
you hear that you guys I would wake up
at 10 o'clock
I've done by 10 o'clock in the morning
pipe shop
there's different spectrums he like he
just told me today he's like man you
really need to try for your badge love
to but I mean for
[Music]
10 years
I mean and none of my charges until way
way back when I was judicata as an adult
have anything to do with any kind of
like drugs so yes I mean violence yeah
some [ __ ] or just
dumb kid when I was 19 no [ __ ] you know
like give me a [ __ ] break [ __ ]
hurry I think your 19 year old self
still shines through
is actually
22 but
[Music]
my lesson on them 20 year old
[Laughter]
no I
had that conversation
really weird I think in my next episode
I'm gonna talk about how to take care of
fungus gnats and like soil-borne pests
and stuff like that what am I listen or
send an email so I'm glad that you said
fungus gnats don't use [ __ ] sand yeah
yeah just yeah it worked but it I think
it caused more per suffocates everything
and then yeah yeah this was on an
organic grow I like growing everything
I've been growing in Cocoa lately
that's there things mixed in to my cocoa
because that's what we we purchased it
we still have the [ __ ] and I mix it in
just because it works but eventually
we've mixed quite a bit of coke thanks
to Billy the long way oh yeah like where
we done the first run in cocoa and then
we're like yeah [ __ ] that
so yeah we've we've had cocoa to makes
Emily sure I'm doing a home in cocoa
right now
I like it well to purr okay
[Music]
we both came to the same conclusion -
yeah yeah head coach
Bill species
okay I'm just giving them to chase mills
and key bad
[Music]
okay so I'm just gonna do that as a like
a base test og biome or crushes oh yeah
I've been using since it was called caps
beneficials actually okay yeah when you
could order it from the dude on the
[ __ ]
he goes back yeah but it was on TV
farmer pages way back in the day bro
yeah remember when you had to do [ __ ] on
IRC hmm I don't remember IRC sadly I
remember IRC through Anarchy online but
that was my experience with IRC because
I mean I played in our downline for 12
years dude like that was those years of
my wife's life that I wasted
[Music]
because he goes to Benson and Benson so
bond point with that I'm like here hold
it get a picture with me and my wife
he's like yeah yeah I'm giving it to you
so then my plan is is
I'm gonna do another run after it with
the exact same thing but I'm gonna add
T's to it once a week okay and just see
final product yeah yeah we're doing a
side-by-side comparison with two
different nutrient brands right now
oh now you're [ __ ] out touch it now
I touch it again [ __ ] kill it again
wiggle it again is it working can you
hear me can you hear me now can you hear
me now
so we're running and we're gonna retire
one brand so I think I could talk about
it I don't know I'm not sure what I'm
allowed to talk about really because
some of its confidential but we're
testing I've talked about it on Facebook
we've got veg blue in one tank and we're
on week one like three or what's today
Thursday so we're four days in the
plants look [ __ ] happy it's like but
I mean we're in Cocoa so I'm sure I
would see something by now if they were
not happy and they get fed they're on a
cycle so they get fed multiple times a
day so they're getting plenty of
opportunity to show me if they're happy
or not yeah they look really really good
I've always been intrigued by the I mean
I'm an organic grower also because of
the simplicity right but so I've always
been intrigued by the simplicity of veg
boom it's all they send you like for
powders and one liquid didn't weigh them
out by the gram like there's so much per
gallon so many grams per gallon you just
weigh it out on a scale and I just pour
it in there and stir it real real well
and just let it go I just let the
reservoirs I put huge pumps in the rest
of it [ __ ] spin real well the water
cycling in the RO water
unfortunately it's hard to produce that
much RO water can i and I feel you a
little secret there let's hear it buddy
walmart has RO water for a dollar fifty
nine a gallon and if you go in there and
fill up water or like like gallon
bottles it's 89 cents water station
well I'm just saying like
you know I'm not trying to piss Walmart
but they have
well yeah I mean if you're doing it
yours alright you know I use a thousand
cups of water a second for the listeners
thousand gallons of water every other
day then we're in the same [ __ ]
budget plan with them have them just
backed the truck in and we use water bro
actually veg will actually sent us a mix
they sent us a two-part mix that I use
half one and half the other and it
balances the pH and adjust for my I've
tested them some water tests they sent
us a formula for design for our water
the tank was getting about halfway down
so I just do the hose in there and
filled it up with water and leather so
it totally six five yeah all the way to
the top and it's still at 6.50
[Music]
organics great but I mean yeah it took
time this is sustainable to
[Music]
our kind of style of growing - very
simple and simplistic and with this is
more the round a lot of the stuff grown
at green and healthy I used
six bottles total and the flowering
cycle like total like and that's a be
like a big flood system right that like
runs back and forth or
yes I mean I I don't
I know they're tiered right is what I'm
saying tables
flood flow tables at an angle with lots
of cocoa essentially with a sprinkler in
each pot this is what I saw I knew it
seemed like they were at an angle you
know a gigantic version of my little
greenhouse man
in 85 you guys when I go see that go
check out the CC 420 on YouTube of the
CCC 420 the CCC 420 I'm sorry yeah they
did a cool little video tour of our
thing and also check out my Instagram
[Music]
they're trying to get I've been trying
dude it's not that I mean I've been
following a lot of glass artists here
lately and I mean I'm in that what do
you want to follow you
over grow the go
grab follow this guy on Instagram you
guys over grow the Gov
jesse grows well but follow 44 and let
him know that you've learned from him
through the girl from her pot
come back from the days back before you
change the name and all that yeah
do that I got a little carried away with
the in stores like
a long time but it's always hair said it
twice yeah it's always there dude
Jesse what are you on Instagram
Jesse girls Jesse grows follow Jesse
grows despicable they're despicable
Derek and overground overthrow the
Governator you're here brother
appreciated you prefer the recycler over
the the inspector huh yeah
can I give a shout-out to my sponsor
rounding up the courts a banger from our
good friends at elevate glass in
Colorado Springs if you're in Colorado
Springs and you're looking if your web
load you're looking for glass if you're
in Denver you lookin for guys drive to
elevate beautiful ladies wonderful glass
great friends great prices it's 5:17
South Tejon in beautiful downtown
Colorado Springs Colorado don't park
right in front of the place where you
got to [ __ ] pay for parking turn left
or turn right and there's [ __ ] free
parking just right at the street you
don't have to pay for that [ __ ]
go get these dope ass rigs don't
Colorado like Leafs on them and it's
it's like Colorado their little logo is
pretty sweet check out my little dabber
they gave me here it's got a it's got a
little colorado flag in the teardrop
nice see I've been saying we need
Colorado stuff like so heavy so these
guys rep Colorado heavy they do
everything is now I've seen people after
we I believe they're in the can of pages
I would believe that yes
and we ele v8 so its elevate yep they
have another store called higher
elevation masterpiece productions if you
break your rig you can take the higher
elevation masterpiece productions and
they will repair the rig for you at a
very reasonable price that's also nice
check them out yeah awesome do they got
a website I don't know the web address I
know they're on Facebook I have found
them when I googled go to the elevate
Facebook
yeah I'm sure hey that Instagram posted
the other day looking out the window
my phone's broken for a day and a half
so I got away from me I realized how
much Instagram and Facebook I see
because there was like you see this you
see this and I'm like nope
extra two hours worth of work done that
day it was there was a like an older car
it only takes me three minutes to pee
sometimes when I have my iPhone it takes
me like seven or eight
that's a dangerous place to have your
iPhone out like that's is that what
happened
use it check messages so that nobody
could see me then you go back to work
right
yeah we hear we see what you're doing on
the water like you're washing your hands
you wash your hands
in hands leave hands for you clean hands
it's not to beat then the feet are
[ __ ] filthy bro like that's the
bottom see wash it before I go to bed
ain't climbing into my bed with walk
feet see don't wear anymore hey don't
like I like classy girls
no oven dude you clean your feet back
clean
do that
I'm gonna salt you dude I left my
sandals on you take your shoes off in
here
[Music]
come on how to touch them today they
don't smell they just look like crap it
looks literally like I've walked through
a cow field to get here bro I'm sorry
and he's like dude you're lucky they
don't stink I would have literally told
you to go home and wash that [ __ ] and
then come back and I'll be like dude I
live across town please please don't you
have a sink or something I can get you
know
[Music]
like with bowls by the [ __ ] door you
know yeah that whole deal you know you
got to watch someone see that makes you
feel humble it's all the life of real
life we choose yeah the life before we
had a pump you know those like the pump
that you would use yeah
I got one testicle stuck in it
now
blue every listeners head
[Music]
I got a compressor it stopped it but
holy
it's not Adam level that's for sure but
between GarageBand do your thing my
thing so you know that you know the
pumps you use for like a water wand you
just throw in a big container and you
just [ __ ] I use those that stirrer
pumps and a big 300 gallon tank I use
one of those I'm gonna put some hose on
it and then I run the hose to something
and clamp the host of something so it
stays in place I could hear it slipping
out like the hose was creeping while it
was pumping and I ran to it to grab it
and it came out
this hose shot water up my shorts up my
balls
like how did that even go there little
undercarriage rinses
hashtag Colorado problems went up my
shirt got stuck in my shirt for a brief
second I tried to grab it and couldn't
catch it it slipped out and went back up
and hit me in the
nutrient I got veg blew up my nose like
my nose and eyes all I could do was like
reach to find the plug to turn off that
[ __ ] hose it was fun so today I solved
it by [ __ ] I
[Music]
was I took a cinder block and I [ __ ]
zip tied the hose to a cinder block and
I was like I'm gonna do this [ __ ]
italian-style and [ __ ] water
[Laughter]
tie brick and drop in the bottom of it
about it problem solving
[Laughter]
[Music]
this crazy [ __ ] looking at me like I
just killed somebody I might have [ __ ]
don't cross the line you want to get in
the car
three should be enough yeah do you think
this would like say keep a hose down to
say if I didn't really needed to keep it
down like it was life imperative
you can't talk about cannabis so you
have to be real vague good old man and
Lowe's asked me what I was trying to do
and I said I needed some cinder blocks
to keep my hose underwater
[Laughter]
[Music]
all right all right all right all right
okay
[Music]
Podcast her bladder I'm sitting here
still drinking jogging bladder
to see Joe Rogan they wouldn't let us up
or order food or drinks we couldn't do
[ __ ]
recording the [ __ ] comedy special bro
yeah went by himself he got first-class
service
put in the front row he went with me
they were like yeah pretty girl but
[Music]
nope ain't happenin no no we we got put
like middle row like right underneath
the other like it was bright as the the
the audience stepped up like that that
step that I was directly under the
camera is how far back since the very
back camera was right above my head that
cameraman had to view over my head so
Joe Rogan was telling jokes to that
camera and it looked like he was talking
to me all night
and he did the vegan and the Grateful
Dead joke right at me
was
a good time I catch a lot of [ __ ] for
that but that was well worth getting in
trouble for that was one of those
moments that like he's gonna say [ __ ] it
and go do it yeah and it was worth it
like that was very memorable experience
here a grown-ass man he get in trouble
no all right here I go or you you're
still getting [ __ ] for that absolutely
[Music]
release
bro I think I think no I'm leaving that
alone too
[Music]
not sorry
very nice
so anyways for listeners
good [ __ ] redneck who was that it
did you send me to hillbillies and
drunks why don't I just decide to play
with that that's weird I see why
everybody plays with their water bottle
I usually don't do that
everybody else do it and you're like
well I want
our proof cap for my inclusion zone unit
down here like me and but this is Buck
Rogers uh look I tried to put it on my
other head go with your probation
officer's name I don't have a probation
officer I have a bail officer what's
your bail officer's name Mitchell shut
up Mitchell shout out Mitchell's let me
come record another podcast yeah go to
my spot did you tell mother [ __ ] live
he knows oh
you want how to present GPS on this you
know
this is I'd go in there looking exactly
like I looked like this can you work
where and I was like a pipe shop bro I
sell people bongs you know like Oh
strictly water pipes but anyway yeah no
no you know it's like dude
I was like you have any weed in the
cards like yes like so yeah
when they gave me my position of
cannabis they didn't take my cannabis
that was my first question in the court
was I excuse me officer on the day of
question did you collect any evidence
and he's here
no no your honor I did not and I was
like case closed in right
exactly what I did everybody laughed in
the courtroom and then they played the
video and it's like Your Honor I'm just
a grown man living in the car trying to
keep my [ __ ] warm
[Music]
[ __ ] the cops like just fighting it
dude you could see it on his face he's
not mad then but he was mad oh man no I
can't believe the [ __ ] cops showed up
dude musta made some kind of impression
I didn't have a lot to do yeah it was
like dude I'm the most compliant stoner
you're gonna mess with all night I was
like there's no excuse I'm sorry I know
I'm smoking in my car but I live here oh
I've been pajama pants my keys are back
there in my real pants like bro I got my
cat in my lap and I'm watching the Star
Wars movie
might have been part of the problem
that's probably why she showed up [ __ ]
sorry Oh check this out still
want to grab a seat yeah go sit in the
cruiser
hey I'm not gonna drop his name but he
was the most racist person when he got
back to his car and thought he was all
alone like that - that bad chest cameras
still rolling brother like I literally
had to tell Your Honor we can we can
skip the racism and get back to my case
forgot you yeah yeah dude it was brutal
you know is it racist against you no no
no I'm white
I would just say it's what you do to a
joint you know okay
officer cells
that's all fiction officer fix you know
officer pass
[Music]
opposed to use the r-word anymore oh why
not does that
correct
you're using it towards who's gonna go
yeah
do do does videos on YouTube that uses
that word
yeah I mean it's to who it is
probably if yeah I don't think you watch
you're probably thinking of like Walking
Dead stuff right no no he's got a really
big grow in Washington I
know exactly yeah hashtag YouTube gross
do your research it's all free
yeah I mean bro I my phone wasn't such a
piece of [ __ ] maybe once I get a better
phone I'd love to put your like your
podcast on an hour podcast on down at
the shop I've been playing hash Church
cuz it'll play on YouTube you guys have
a computer down there well we do but it
has no sound and it has no speakers and
you need a password to put the speakers
on it that's
thank you here's a password hmm I
get told that there is no password oh
you're not in the club then I'm not an
admin you're right I'm not you're great
so it's fine it's cool we can play it
over the loudspeakers through a phone
cuz we have that that bat we can plug
into the phone you know I'm saying and
it but my phone sucks [ __ ] sprint 3G
just sayin step it up to the game on
blast
you want to let him keep going
have smashed their phone
subscribed to my show because of this
episode
[Music]
so you guys still work with that [ __ ]
redness this is exactly what I expected
from
taking shits and random chaos
tries to keep it like informational you
know like he tries to bring the
information to the table but I mean me
and dick pretty much ruined that at any
point
[ __ ] you and he's like yeah and I'm like
yeah and he's like yeah I'm like yeah I
wrapped it yeah exactly so we've had you
know we've done stuff up with that you
know we've just set around a bull [ __ ]
with Bulls just been here and it's like
why are we recording this you didn't
like those memorable [ __ ] stories
you're going down tonight I would love
to just listen to those like I wish we
had a private loop you know or there was
some kind of private kind of podcast you
know things that you could you could do
where pay US $500 an episode and you get
the unfiltered I have a website totally
make that stuff had to its
podcast calm so
just plug it all over your show huh
[Music]
penetrated by airshows devil
my listeners have been assaulted by
reptiles
[Music]
send me some funky ass emails you guys
I'd love to hear your emails my show
either either show that you if you're
hearing me on my on my feed email me at
school comm know what you think if
you're listening to me on the Colorado
podcast do it again email me grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I want to do
it what you guys are thinking of this
[ __ ] chaotic random show here oh yeah
we want to know what you don't want to
know
yeah well there's definitely another
podcast here the works I just wish we
all had [ __ ] seven hours recorded
[Music]
for your podcast too as well I thought
it one the other day yeah
don't say it
steal it everybody in this group right
now is on that that I can own your
domain name
tell everybody that on the podcast Oh
Lyon Park domain names all day long
you know I bought my new I know you've
already been on that height for a few
years but Jesse just found that hype and
he's like do you know I could [ __ ] with
my friends pretty hardcore yeah go ahead
yep still open and I wouldn't really
call these people friends well
keep your friends close and
the other ones closer on Facebook
follow them on
patrol accounts and follow their
Instagram
put your phone down depends on how
committed you are you're way too
committed to the whole trolling yeah get
on snapchat if you can't like do with
your own real account it's not really
worth effort yep all right guys it's
been an hour and 40 minutes
no way it's gonna go in one episode
we're gonna have to cut it we can get it
on the website oh yeah we can do that
like a special episode just for on the
website or so if you want me to edit it
down to a solid no no I could put it up
on Soundcloud
one week I mean
let's not argue about this while we're
wait
this is the end of this part of the show
if you're listening on my feet I'm gonna
come back and talk in a minute so listen
to music on my feed and we'll probably
do the same thing yeah hard cut yeah
yeah I think
I apologize my listeners we're not
talking about this was a lot of [ __ ]
fun Adam you're not as crazy as you
think you're it's a lot of fun dude
you're quiet you should talk more and
dude it'll get a podcasting thank you hi
I apologize you're pretty
by now but thank you
I'm gonna hit stop on this for sure
speed things