[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 138 the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
it's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band to let me use their
music on my podcast big shout outs a cat
to an entire Vista crew its crew
last night the mystic roots man played
at the black sheep in Colorado Springs
and it was a great show and a great time
I danced my ass off I sang my ass off
the mystic lutes man came out they
played their first song and then they
dedicated their second song to I region
etics and myself and that song was past
the marijuana so big shout-out to my
friends in the mystic roots
thanks for putting on a great show
thanks for making me feel like a VIP I
had a great ass time also big shout out
to katchafire and also big thanks to
everyone at the black sheep for letting
us get down in there there may have been
some gun just smoking and nobody tried
to stop us so much love and respect to
the black sheep in Colorado Springs big
shout out to the band's big shout out to
catch a fire they came all the way from
New Zealand to play in the States that
band is pretty cool I had a good time
checking those guys out but it really
had a good time getting down to the
mystic roots I hope I saw you there I
hope we got a high-five together I hope
you got a DAB I hope I got to shake your
hand
I hope we saw each other and had a great
time big shout it to smiles in the crew
big shout out to Jessica all the whoops
that are hung out with had a great time
with you guys all right guys in this
podcast I have my friend Wil the
barefoot grower over and we also had Rob
from sour seeds over and we talked a
whole bunch about breeding my friend
Fred Garvin sent me an email and he
asked about harvesting his first seed
crop fred is halfway through his first
breeding project and he wanted a little
bit of guidance on how to properly take
down his seeded plants how to get the
seeds out of there how to store them and
how to care for them so we were gonna
give a long discussion on pulling the
seeds out of your seeded plants before
we get that far you guys I want to give
a huge shout out to my friends at
elevate glass in Colorado Springs if you
need a new rig if you need a new nail if
you need a new dabber if you're trying
to buy a brand new email you can check
out my friends at elevate glass they're
located at 517 South tae-ho's and
beautiful Colorado Springs Colorado make
sure you let them know Ross and Jeff
sent you and let them know that you're
listening to the girl from your heart a
podcast you would both appreciate it so
make sure you check out elevate glass
517 South Dakota and Colorado Springs
you guys I'm gonna let this music play
for a couple of seconds in when we get
back we will be joined by the barefoot
grower and Rob from sour seeds
all right podcast world we are back
joining me at the table is my good buddy
we'll also known as the Barefoot grower
welcome to the table bro here you still
blown glass just curious I saw you
changed from bare flip blower or glass
that's another podcast welcome to show
man thanks for joining us
I also across the table from me is my
good buddy Rob from sour seeds how you
doing today brother long good to be back
man we got Rob a little bit too high
he's got a funny look on his face but I
think he's gonna be alright in a minute
got that Bill Cosby green man so you
might be the Barefoot blower this is not
gonna turn into the Colorado podcast
we'll get this back on the rails very
quickly so thanks for coming to the
table guys both these guys we've been
talking about how busy we are we sat
here for an hour and talked about how we
don't have time for [ __ ] which is kind
of funny if you ask me so we're gonna
talk about our friend Fred Garvin sent
me an email and he is halfway through a
seed breeding project this is his first
run trying to make seeds he wants some
guidance on how to harvest the seeds
maybe when to pull the seeds and things
to look for so I thought she had my
buddy Rob breeds a lot of seeds I've
read a lot of seeds will get Rob over to
talk about it will was coming over to
hang out take some dabs he brought a
dope-ass mothership so I was like hang
out we'll put you on a podcast so we're
gonna talk a little bit about seed
breeding BRABUS got a bunch of notes I
was there anywhere you'd like to start
with bro cuz you were looking at that
thing pretty intently um I think we
should start from the beginning okay
like we'll write the moment exception
basically you know when when the seed
starts you know when to pollinate and
yeah okay I had a pollinate like the
timing wise in ACCA's versus the TVs
okay so hopefully you've got yourself a
solid male that we've talked about
before actually you came and talked
about that with me ah so hopefully we've
got a solid male you've got your females
chosen and now it is time to actually
breathe some plants so if you're gonna
pick some indica plants when should we
start to Paul
our indica plants I would say between
week three and four when your bud sets
really starting to form up for the first
time I would say when they get about you
know good nickel to quarter size okay
that way that way you got plenty of cuz
because what it's really gonna determine
down on this how many hairs you have
basically how many pistols you have yeah
and they're they're what carry the
pollen down
they actually make the progress happen
so when you see the pistols nice and
thick
it kind of looks like you got some
little spiders going on but when those
dandelions when the hairs and the
dandelions I know that's such such
obvious terms but when those pistols get
thick and ready that's when that plant
is ovulating and it wants to receive
that male pollen so thank you and your
indica plants you're absolutely right
about three weeks ish about day 21 to
about a twenty eight ish is usually when
I try to hit an indica dominant you can
get away with maybe sometime week four
if it's you know bred out with a sativa
or something like that has a slightly
longer found flowering time you know you
you just really have to use your best
judgment you know but typically week
three is about the money for it alright
in my opinion how about if we're working
with a more sativa dominant plant do you
want to go a little bit later you think
you do you really do want to get a
little bit later and the reason being
because if you do to it do do a
pollination too early you're not gonna
get the seed stock you want and then
they also might be sitting in the plant
for too long in the plant by to not be
right but the proceeds will be so the
seeds will overripe and just like any
fruit or anything else out there it
can't overripe and I've seen them pop
inside the bud before I've seen all
kinds of things actually seen a seed
germinate itself inside of a button so
that's [ __ ] amazing I know when you
guys say indigent Stevie Tom out the
female you're using or the cross that
you're trying to get the female that
we're starting with yeah the girl that's
going to receive the pollen yeah the
girl that's why wills here were
definitely referring to the female for
sure okay yes it's a deep abdominal
plants you usually do where we beat week
4 week five usually typically a week or
two later than you would an indica you
know you really have to judge the
flowering period if it's a nine ten
weeks the Teva you know you want you
want to leave them basically what you're
leaving looking for is about a four to
five we get of just the plants going
through growth normal regular solid
growth for about four to five weeks
that's gonna make that seed go
and start to finish and really finish
out nicely from from starts and a embryo
to seed to harvest all right so we've
got pollen when should we put should we
put our males and females into the
flowering room at the same time um I
think it really depends on your
situation the easiest way to do it if
somebody's worried about getting
cross-pollination with other females and
things like that is to bring the female
out of the room or use a smaller room
like us maybe like a small 2x2 or 3x3
grow tent I've seen people even go down
and use something as cheap as a very
large cardboard box like like something
for a refrigerator or like the largest
box you can get at you call okay put a
CFL in it for your males you know and
stuff like that and just let them go and
then throw the female and they're just
for the day or two it need to do its
thing and okay you know right pull it
back out and then it's the deed is done
let it sit spray it down with tap water
introduce it back into the flower room
so you don't cross pollinate okay the
way I do it since I am when I spoon I
pollinate I do the whole room I don't
even [ __ ] around I know that I'm gonna
cry entire room so I'll get that male
nice and beefy and when he's full of
pollen and hopefully I've got him time
depth where my girls are about three to
four weeks in I just take him in there
and put him in front of the fan and give
him a good shake smack the sticks a
little bit and that pollen goes
everywhere okay everywhere but that's
only if you're trying to do the whole
room right if you're trying to time it
and you don't know how long your male
plant is going to take to start busting
a nut that's when it's time to flower
him early and take pollen from him and
collect the pollen into a container and
then you can apply pollen to the
branches you want or you can walk in
there and hold that jar up pollen in
front of a fan and shake it you can kind
of salt and pepper sprinkle the plants
if you'd like there's several ways to
apply the pollen that's exactly how I do
it as a breeder I buy harvest pollen
first and then choose females secondly
okay so I always harvest Paul and I keep
good storage appalling good waste or
pollen is a good question
I get asked all the time how do you
store your pollen um I I just used a
very clean container I wiped out with
alcohol first let it dry really good and
then wipe it out with water to make sure
there's no alcohol left that's gonna
kill the pollen and I don't use tap
water I use an RO water or distilled
water that way there's no chlorine
present so it won't destroy the pollen
right let it dry real well
that's it let it dry really well you can
use a dried rice is a really good thing
to use I've seen growers use dried rice
but the main thing is when you go to
store pollen is to make sure there's no
green material left over or any kind of
bug material or leaked material present
in the pollen whenever you're going
through there after harvesting it cuz
there's gonna be little pieces here and
there and what that's gonna do is it's
gonna create a moisture spot inside of
that pollen and it's gonna start molding
and that's where you can cuz cuz water
breeds bacteria that's basically right
what's down to and the bacteria is gonna
take over and it's gonna render your
pollen useless I do a very similar
method I'll collect the pollen from the
male and then I will have a clone of
that male and I'll flour him right
alongside my ladies so that I'm sure
that right around the proper day I know
that each of my ladies will get dusted
with the proper amount of pollen I'm
double double teaming it a little bit
and I'm kind of a weirdo I might be a
cannabis hoarder because I always like
to keep a little bit of pollen like just
in case something goes wrong I've still
got some of that pollen that's that's
what I love to do keep it back you never
know when you're gonna come across
something to say you know that one male
would be really good with right maybe a
new cut that you just gotten tried for
the first time and you realize hey wait
a minute if I would have had that male
or if I had that pollen I could just
made a masterpiece yeah yes so I've got
that pollen I like you were saying keep
it in a clean jar or a container I keep
mine in to clean those little tiny mason
jars like a baby food sized mason jar
and then I keep that in a brown paper
bag so there's no light getting to it
and then I actually put that in my spare
refrigerator right next to my silver
thiosulfate solution
I think cold is more preservative than
Heat exactly I think things will
deteriorate and degrade and [ __ ] goes
wrong more quickly and heat in nature
slows everything down so that's you keep
your food and your meats and [ __ ] I
don't keep any meat but I mean if you do
you keep that [ __ ] in a fridge keep it
cool just keep your also keep some seeds
in a cooler and I haven't seen any
difference in the seeds that I have kept
not in a cooler and in a cooler my other
seeds go in a safe I've got a big gun
safe filled with seeds the seeds that
were in the cooler
I've germinated those with the same
exact success rate as non cooled seeds
absolutely
all right so we know when to pollinate
the plants we know it's gonna take about
five to six weeks for those plants once
the pollination happens you'll see the
pistils curl up right now they'll be
clear looking they're white they're kind
of like clear veiny white tips what's
that pollen hits they're gonna crinkle
up like claws like like arthritis
fingers they're gonna start turning
brown that's how you know the
pollination has happened now the pollen
is moving up the up the pistol and into
the ovule and you're now actually making
a seed let's talk a little bit about
what to feed plants that we're putting
seeds into I like to give them a lot of
carbs I like to give him a lot of carbs
and sugar lots of energy and a good
little bloom booster that's that's about
all I really do to him other than that I
do give him a little extra nitrogen or
flour than I normally would because the
plants gonna use a little bit of extra
everything just for Mom would create a
baby inside of her she's gonna try to
she's gonna it's got to so you got to
take that concept and relay that into
your plan you know you you're creating
thousands of seeds so those offspring
have and they need they need nutrients
they need food to be able to grow
healthy and strong just like a baby
would or anything else would so
completely use as much light as possible
when you're breeding light is absolutely
definitely helpful you'll multiply your
amounts of seeds if you step up step up
from a four hundred to a six hundred to
a thousand you'll see the amount of seed
introduced and the quality of the seeds
those little white seeds won't happen if
you use a thousand you only get those
with a four or six yeah I actually used
sixes I do a twelve twelve regimen when
I'm when I go into flower for a breeding
project yeah yeah yeah but I actually I
used six hundreds but uh even like you
were saying it will help butter faster
with a brighter light source right or
hotter light source and so typically
what I do like this time of year I take
them and put them outside for the last
week to ripen let the UV rays really
taken over and not only does it increase
the THC and bombard the plant at all at
one time it really it really looks good
on the charts after it's cut down oh I
bet something about making oil out of
plants that were seeded once those
plants so we'll talk about this in a
minute but once the plants are finished
you take the seeds out you've got a
bunch of material laughs right I like to
take that material to one of my good
friends like will that makes hash for me
and the concentrates that come out of
that you get such an amazing high the
it's all there's more of a you know I
don't get a psychedelic high but it is
more of a psychedelic feeling you get
more of a mind trip from it you get more
body high from it it does something to
the oil it certainly does alright so we
know what to feed the plants now we want
to give them lots of carbs a little more
nitrogen you see you're still gonna have
to flush just like you normally would
before he cut down the plants you guys
keep that in mind always
I wanted to interrupt with something
that I saw on Facebook
I won't call them out but hopefully they
listen to the podcast they posted to
Facebook I found this stud mail time to
put him outside for the season and see
what he can do so that I can collect
some pollen as essentially what he said
so many bells went off in my head I saw
the post everybody four four miles of
this dude that is growing outdoors is
going to have a hybrid of whatever this
dude put outside yeah the wind and
nature are going to do their things and
this guy's gonna pollinate the whole
[ __ ] neighborhood don't do that you
guys if you've got a male plant don't
put it outside so that you can pollinate
Rob's outdoor crops and you can [ __ ]
pollinate and everybody's outdoor crop
don't do that [ __ ] please be be a Fink
full thinker a thankful STONER I don't
even be a for thinking grower is what I
need you to be don't put that [ __ ] out
there that's rude please don't do that
silence they think they just want to
stand up and walk away would be
acceptable
alright so plants are gonna grow about
six weeks until the seeds are ready ish
ah what should we start looking for
during that time period to know if the
seeds are getting ready or if we're
gonna have to let them go a little bit
longer well usually what I'll do if
there's none sometimes the they'll split
and you'll actually start seeing the
seeds president actually split and he
likes to protrude from it sometimes you
know when the ripe and then you'll
actually see the visual see just see a
nice gray dark color you'll see nice
tiger stripes yeah white tiger stripes
is what you're looking for a lot
the time then you know you got a nice
ripe seed you basically want to look for
no green and no white that's that's
pretty much the two things you've really
got to look for there's no green and no
white you got Tiger stripes and you got
great nice gray seas or dark seeds and
typically you know you're ready a cheap
move that I do after about six weeks of
pollination five and a half six weeks of
pollination I wait and then right at the
base of the buds or the stalk in the bud
meat there's usually one little calyx
that swells up I'll just pinch that
[ __ ] all right roll it around in my
hand and it you'll know it's either a
seed or what would have been a seed had
you not destroyed it and you guys don't
worry about crushing one or two of those
because if you did this correctly you're
gonna have at least a hundred closer to
five hundred if you do it like Rob and I
do
I pulled five thousand seeds from a
plant easy I'm looking at pulling like
around at least two thousand or two from
one plant right now I run I was running
seven gallon pots and hitting them with
big males
yeah thousands of seeds can come from
one plant where the hell were we um how
long to let it go what to look for you
can pinch that one little but you guys
will see what I'm talking about if
you've got a seeded crop and a lot of
times you'll see these little calyxes on
the bottoms of buds and they'll make you
think you've got a seed I didn't want to
touch one um letting them go a little
bit too long with the ramifications of
letting your seeds go too terribly long
yeah letting plant just basically going
to the point where hey you're gonna lose
most your teats he's gonna convert over
to CBD and things like that and then
secondly the progeny in the bud that's
actually growing oh if you've ever had
those seeds uh had a batch of seeds from
somebody or a reader that you've gotten
in and they're just hard as a rock I
mean they got really great dart the real
dark nice but I mean they're just
incredibly hard as rock a lot of them
have to be scored germinate yeah that's
what that's from that's a lot of it
basically what it is it's because
because the seed is this embryo and it's
developing a show that's developing the
show and the shells gonna do nothing but
like a bone it's gonna get harder and
harder and harder the more you pump that
plant and especially it comes from not
ripening the plant correctly also not
flushing properly things like that
because you got so many nutrients
present it's still telling it to drive
drive drive drive so it's gonna create
that and develop that and that's also
when you risk seed splitting seed
splitting will happen because whenever
you pull them out
they're gonna be so over developed that
once they start to dry out they're gonna
start cracking and splitting because
it's gonna be like there's gonna be such
a large embryo inside of this shell
because it's welled up inside of there
it's growing you know so you're gonna
have a lot of problems can develop from
that that's a lot of the issues when
people have these little issues with
seeds when they get them in the mail and
things like that from different breeders
and they are cracked and stuff but they
haven't been the package is fine and
they come great but but you got a couple
crack seeds in there and they look great
and everything but you can tell just a
shell split right down the side you know
and you're like hey this is not gonna be
good because the embryo is now dry it
out did so that seats toast you know and
then you get some day you have to score
because they just will not germinate
unless you score them let's talk about
that for a little bit what's the best
way to do you guys you'll know if the
seeds are super hard really thick
shelled you'll be able to tell by
looking they'll be extra glossy they'll
be a little harder than normal if
they're your first pack of seeds you
don't have anything to compare it to so
you're just gonna have to learn but well
it's the best way to score them to
soften them up a little bit to grow if
you got a matchbook that's real good way
to do if you got a matchbook use inside
of a matchbook just just rub like that
or a really fine grit sandpaper you
don't want to use a coarse grade because
it's gonna tear it it's gonna tear into
it right hard so you want to use a
really fine grit sandpaper is one of the
easiest things really to use I like to
just soak those plants put a little bit
of a couple drops of hydros I'm and a
glass of water or a jar of water either
way at the show a little bit those
plants 24 hours and then put them in the
paper towels
usually works for me another one I use
dr. Willard's plant catalyst okay that's
a good [ __ ] never talked about that on
the podcast they gave me a free bottle
of it the guy gave me a case 30 to 60
mils in your reservoir he said and I go
well how do you know how big my
reservoir is because it doesn't matter
with this you put 30 30 to 60 mils in
here and it'll make your plants go
faster and it did I could see them
side-by-side with seeds we took
blueberry fuel we took about ten of them
germinated with regular tap water and
then just sayin we germinated that the
same group another 10 seeds dr. which
the tap water 24 hour difference I was
amazed every one of those seeds
germinating within 24 hours is like nice
crazy yeah and then the regular tap
water took about 36 to 48 so it was a
dramatic difference you can see it was
like overnight you know versus the next
day it was like it was pretty wild it's
like that's some good stuff so we
squeezed it religiously so shout out to
dr. Willard's plant catalyst
if you want to send us stuff get in
touch grow from your heart at
hotmail.com we'd love to help you out be
cool alright so if you leave them in
there too long you guys your seeds will
start splitting so pay attention also
check it out I want to mention this this
is something that comes to mind if your
plants start dropping seeds if you have
more than one female in the room and
seeds fall out of your plant you can't
just pick that seat up and assume that
it came from this girl that could have
came from any of the females in the room
and it could have rolled to that spot so
you can't label that one what you think
it fell from you can only label seeds
what you're [ __ ] sure it came from
right don't ever guess when labeling a
seed that is the future of the cannabis
genome and we don't want any confusion
it's your job as a person breeding to
take beautiful notes for the future
let's do that for example I just had a
crop and we popped the seed out of it
earlier that goes in the happy accident
bag yes happy accidents are a good thing
when you're in the seed business or the
breeding game please don't ever make it
a really really great idea where I'm
almost like 90% sure where it came from
but I still label this so and put happy
accident yep and then I'll pop that seed
and it'll get a whole new name and a
whole new you know thing if it stays
around it could be the next hottest
clone only if it could be because it's
gonna go in trash a lot of the super
popular [ __ ] was an accident just like
that well that's what I try to explain
people it's more about selection and not
number you can pop a big and seeds if
you're not good at selecting those
plants what does the vacancy it's worth
yeah oh man I found some beautiful
keepers that most people would have
missed tossed I can name 10 of the
world's most legendary strange right now
that all came from five seats chem dog
really blue number four yep
Girl Scout cookies Oh Gainesville green
okay nice I don't know enough about the
Florida weed
yeah lot a lot of the most pop we we had
white actually did a whole episode about
accidents and clone only accident East
Coast sour dee golden goes west coast
our d OG Kush Bubba cush
alright so it's your job as a breeder
you guys please be careful to carefully
mark everything make sure you label
everything don't make any mistakes for
the future because you're gonna be
growing these seeds and hopefully some
of your friends are gonna be growing I
mean you don't want to mislead people on
what is in
a lot of this stuff is going to be aimed
at medical patients and we want the
medical patients to know the genetics of
what they're getting it's really helpful
so if you find some seeds on the floor
you can use them you just can't you just
got to be careful and carefully think
about what they are don't try to say
it's this times this until you grow it
and if you're certain then you could be
cool with that all right so it's gonna
known just label it oh no no that's not
necessarily a bad thing I've seen some
of the biggest largest breeders in the
world
labelled their genetics unknown crossed
with this you name it yeah it's like
gages number one male Joseph Joseph that
Joseph male that they used for years and
years and years and years it was it's a
bag seed male from somewhere and nobody
knows what it was so they just named it
Joseph ochi yeah and then they labeled
it properly as so and then everybody
knows that or we wouldn't know that you
can actually buy gages unlabeled seeds
and they've got a name I don't remember
what they're called but it you can buy
them they're all the seeds that fell to
the side
they're called good ideas is what his
extra seats are called some good ideas
they're a good idea but I don't know
what it's gonna be yeah alright so let's
get back to our little breeding project
here for Fred we've got plants with
seeds in them they've been pollinated
they've gone five and a half six ish
weeks since the pollen has hit them the
pistols are curly and brown the
trichomes are starting to Amber up the
plants are getting mature let's start
flushing the plants and now let's talk
about pulling down the plants and
getting the seeds out of these sons of
[ __ ] right on I I harvest them just
like a harvest any other regular plant I
take it down take away any water leaf
anything basically do a light wet trim
and then I just hang them and let them
dry and after one I let them dry a
little bit longer than normal because
they are seeded plants they have a
denser texture to them and they're a lot
more dense than regular so you gotta
really let them dry out after they're
done you know you just kind of carefully
roll them in your hands as well as
ideally roll them in I just let the
seeds fall not from a high place six
inches are lower above your table is
right here when you buy like a package
of ball jars or Kerr jars little mason
jars it comes with that cardboard base
to keep them in place I love to use that
thing or go to the liquor store and get
something that
just put cases of beer in just a little
flat one it's about you know three or
four inches deep and the seeds won't
bounce off the cardboard sorry excuse me
for clearing the throat so many times we
took so many dabs today the seeds won't
bounce off the cardboard I used to try
to use a cookie sheet or a pyrex dish
but then you take these buds that are
filled with seeds and they're dry and
you crumble them up and if you do it
right you guys it's gonna it's gonna
sound like it's raining it's gonna go to
dink and the seeds are gonna come
raining out of these buds use cardboard
because they will not bounce as badly as
they will out of a cookie sheet or a
pyrex dish so I usually just like you
said let the buds dry then I roll them
up in my hands crumble them up a little
bit where a rubber glove because you're
gonna get sticky as [ __ ] or don't if
you're into that some people like to get
that resin all over their hands our
friend rusty shout out to rusty he likes
to pick seeds without gloves and be all
dark fingered that's me unless I'm
playing with Coco I'm wearing gloves I
like to play at the Coco barehanded that
Coco just cleans your hands if your
hands are filthy just go stick them in
the cocoa and mix them around your hands
will be shiny again it's rad alright so
now we've got a bunch of dried bud
material basically and a bunch of seeds
depending on the size of your garden
there's a whole bunch of different ways
to go and try to pull these seeds out of
your buds I should mention this while
we're here because we're all stone and
we might [ __ ] up keep your female plants
separate at this point like if you're
working with more than one varietal more
than one strain of females in this
breeding project keep the [ __ ]
separate because you don't want kidding
you don't want to get your seeds
confused do you want to have carefully
labeled seeds that's the whole part of
why your breeding is so that you can
know what's going on
so keep the girls separated if you find
seeds on the floor and the dry room once
again those are good ideas don't label
those unless you're certain of what they
are so now we've got all this material
if you've got a little crop if your
garden is kind of small you can simply
do the old-school method where you put
the little container at an angle and
slide the weed up to the top and the
seeds will roll to the bottom and the
dried weed materials stay at the top get
you a good trade good magazine whatever
floats your boat 45-degree angle yep get
back to rolling papers put on some music
and just go
put all those seeds in a jar and that's
that's lettuce you know it's the easiest
way to do it but if you're doing it on a
level it's where you've got a seed
company that's gonna get tedious really
quickly you and your friends can only
sit around for so long and you're gonna
have to give away so many packs of seeds
break in their back so they do sell a my
good friends at mile high seed company
shot at the mile high seed company they
showed me a device it's actually a bird
seed separator that thing is sweet you
before all your material yeah you put
your material into the top and it'll
hand crank on it and it just spits seeds
out one side and all the other material
falls right out of the bottom so you can
just put that over a bucket actually buy
a fully automatic one nowadays it
actually separates everything for you
and everything it likes to separate your
trim and everything from your seed so
you'll have it in one pile it has a nice
calm and there's and I have a clear
container below you can get them on eBay
just look up parrot seed cleaning
machine how much are they about they run
your price points gonna be about $159 -
Fred get bucks
Fred buy one it's worth it just the time
that you it's it's like trimming instant
trimming is fun the first seven times
but after once you trim ten times you
want to put the scissors in your hi
[Music]
parents and birds whenever you rear
Birds and in an aviary they waste about
75 to 80% of the food they they're
really picky ears so they kind of go
through the food and sit through what
they want at the time and throw the rest
on the ground so so basically you take
all your bird feed that you buy in the
store that's quite expensive for these
parrots and stuff like that and run it
through the machine and you get like
seventy seventy percent return back and
you just keep recycling so it's all gone
birds are dicks I apologize for that I'm
gonna blame that on this hit man or the
mother ship rig that we'll brought over
that was right Oh shout out to this
distillate ah I'm not sure if we could
talk about too much where this distil it
came from but I've got a friend out
there named frosty who I owe a huge
shout out to yeah you guys want to link
those two together you can but I don't
know if they're related all right we've
got a bunch of seeds we got a bunch of
material we
pulled we put our seeds into the little
bird feeder we put all our stuff into
the bird feeder we pulled the seeds in
the material out you can smoke that
material or you can make hash out of
that material or you can make edibles
out of that material there's so many
uses for that material you guys it is
still good quality product you can roll
joints out of it smoke it I like to give
it to my friend will and let him make
pho at of it for me it works really well
yeah the high from it like I said
earlier is amazing you can also make oil
out of it make edibles out of it you can
make butter out of it you can do
anything that you would do with any
other buds out of that material so seeds
there is controversy online do seeds
need to cure I believe they do if it
also all depends on that's not where I
feel the controversy comes from is from
people that its climate it's climatic
yeah it's it's where the controversy
comes from okay coming from coming from
the deep swamp in the floor to the
hundred percent humidity hundred six
degree days every single day of the week
is wet though there's like soup
you have to cure seats for like three or
four weeks to get them just said the air
is like soup I've been to some festivals
down south and it killed me I was at a
festival just walking and I was covered
in sweat and I thought I was okay but I
looked around my friends like you know
what [ __ ] I'm sitting down and I'm
like you okay and I was like I'm cool
but I'm too [ __ ] hot I'm going to sit
down right now exactly I just needed a
minute just to not be so damn hot for a
minute yeah that's it it's real muggy in
the inn that's a lot of the humidity and
things like that
the higher the humidity the longer
you'll have to cure your seeds when one
of the best tricks I've learned since I
moved over here to Colorado takes about
three or four days to cure yeah and I
back back a four bowl two-foot long
t5 fixture okay and I back it off about
two to three feet off a pan and I let
and all the UV rays and everything cured
the seeds in about three days and that's
where they jump right out and see okay
they want to fly right out and then
we've all of our testers came back 100%
germination very cool I mean hundreds
and hundreds of seeds nice I mean it was
just like that was a good thing and
there's also a few dry ice methods are
you looking for any testers
always always looking for good testers
is willing to put in the effort and
throw back the result that sits that's
what we're always looking for let's uh
when a lot of people hit me up to be a
tester I'm sure people hit you up let's
just give these guys an idea of who is a
qualified tester so that we don't have
to keep typing these emails that's right
well I'm looking for I'm looking for at
least minimum three to five years
experience I want you to pretty much
have already run through every book
there is on the planet that you can get
your hands on the resource material
that's out there because you're given
all this free resource material nowadays
especially with the internet and things
like that that there's no really excuse
for you not to educate yourself you have
it right in front of your face to
educate yourself that's that's the first
number one thing I can tell any growers
educate yourself and that's gonna make
you a better girl or everybody always I
have what can I do to make my plants
better what can I do to learn this to
educate yourself that's the best thing
you can do yeah
nobody's gonna do it for you this is the
real world it's just the way it is it
sucks but it'll make you better and you
know this is the way the none of us
learn the easy way you know no one held
our hand through it or anything like
that
Ruth is what you have to do it in and
then from there you know just did that
we're looking for we're looking for
people that are you know headstrong that
are internet slightly internet savvy you
know they can type of complete sentence
disqualified you know if you say BAE
you're disqualified yeah at least one or
two lights that you can fully dedicate
to the seeds that I'm going to send you
at least one light for the ten pack of
seeds that you're gonna get for free I
want one light of your space I want you
to be able to make a diary of what
you're how you're growing how many of
the seeds I sent you germinated how many
of them were females how many were
hermaphrodites how long did it take to
see sex how long did it take you to find
the hermaphrodite how many of those
plants were male and female out of those
females how many were keepers how many
would you run again would you run this
strain again do you have the ability to
get this plant tested for THC CBD THC
THC eight each
viii CBG do you have testing
capabilities
do you have these testing abilities how
was the flavor how was the high like was
it worth the [ __ ] at all how long did it
take the flower we want that kind of
notes and then we want you to get a
camera if it's your iPhone that's red if
you've got a better camera we want you
to get a good camera and I want pictures
at least once a week of each phenotype
carefully labeled with the week number
the strain name and the phenotype number
that you have selected for that well we
can't stand in the industry as the guy
that we give twenty seats to that pops
three seeds and it takes six months to
get report back on those three seeds
yeah I'm trying to cannot stand that
more than anything if you're that guy
you suck guy I've been that guy before
because our friend
I gave green genetics sent me about
7,000 packs I'm like I only have so much
which one I can only pull over so far
yeah gage really helped myself out in
the cannabis industry helping me get
where I am so shot at the gage screen so
let's tell them why it's so frustrating
when I send you testers it's because I'm
trying to release a new product line and
I want to get research done on that so
that I don't put out seeds that are [ __ ]
because I don't want to put them
available at the dank team.com and then
you spend money on them and then they
totally suck so I send out to my testing
team I send out quite a large batch of
test seeds I've sent out entire first
runs of test batches like this first
breeding project I kept like 250 of them
and then sent [ __ ] a thousand seeds
out to other people to run and then if
it's worth of [ __ ] I'll make more that's
right and I always find you the easiest
way to select the best phenotype out of
a thousand seeds is to have a bunch of
really good testers yeah and stay in
contact with amido and keep up with them
and have them keep up with you and then
that way whenever it comes down to it
you're like hey you know well here's
something that you don't have for doing
all that work you know and give them a
little trade off or something finding it
for ya you find keepers and things like
that you find test results that you
don't find other places that's how I
know personally like a lot of Rusty's
and candidatures cuts and things like
that were found that's how our blueberry
fuel was found at over 500 seeds and
three years later it was it came out of
Boston and ended up out of Boston that's
my boy William
yeah I've got a friend who's doing a
really good job with Capleton and I'm
waiting for a cut of that and then I've
got a friend who can't be mentioned
who's got a really good cut of the blue
heeler today which has some little bit
of blue dream in there hashtag the fix
is trying to fix the blue dream editor
pains to it there wasn't presently there
just it does really well with OG Terps
we found because it's already got some
Myra scene present and some other things
that you'd normally don't typically find
and sativas but you can't really taste
it in the blue dream so why not give it
that extra kick in a do things that
aren't normally they're different
structures and the shorter flower a
really nice structure to it that's what
you need that's what you need nowadays
it is a great parent that that's that's
really where it's where it lies that
anymore I don't think it has a place on
the top shelf market anymore and but
potage breeders I still think it's still
going to these days cuz it is so stable
yeah but I'll give it that you know that
sets word that's why it's close to me
just in my hour this is because it's
always been a great breeder you can hate
it with anything Rafa did Akane's and
it's gonna come out great I've done it
and had happy accidents and great ideas
don't encourage anybody to no no don't
do that on purpose definitely don't do
that on purpose I'm gonna back up and
something we didn't talk about if you're
making feminized seeds you need to get
that mail going way early ah three weeks
ahead of time if you're trying to get
your female plants ready to flower at
week three you want to get those males
if you want to start spraying them in
veg spray and veg for a week and then
flower them almost six weeks ahead of
those girl plants you want to get them a
nice fat head start reversing a plant
takes a lot of time it takes a lot of
energy you need to stifle the copper
movement in the plant by hitting it with
the silver thiosulfate the plant needs
to react needs to learn what to do with
that reaction it needs to change its
hormones to create create pollen then it
needs to develop the sacks to create
pollen then it will release pollen it's
gonna take a long time if you're making
your first
first meal you're gonna be like I did it
wrong you just got to spray it more and
more and more and more yet don't even
waste time with collodial silver make
your own silver thighs okay that was
really good
since all these new growers are coming
on the scene people are trying to create
their new strain to stuff the colloidal
silver hype is coming back stronger than
ever it was around about ten years ago
and now it's back like bell-bottoms man
it doesn't block the gene well enough
and for long enough and hard enough
strong enough to not create a higher
ratio hermaphrodite problems don't do it
use STS it's it's properly you haven't
in the long run it's cheaper it's
cheaper oh it's so much cheaper I have
to throw it away cuz I make too large of
a batch at one time that's a throw that
to get away and it's it's dirt cheap
once you buy your first batch I've got
some from two years ago you use I think
you buy a one ounce in a three ounce jar
and I think you use like three grams and
two grams
out of each star for your first mash
this big yeah exactly and you can store
that jar for it's like 4050 it's in the
fridge right next door to the to the
pollen that we store in there if you're
gonna make silver thiosulfate Spray one
way to keep it around longer when you
mix the two components into these
separate containers of water keep them
separate don't mix them and they'll
store longer right yeah and I also never
spray my STS under light right I always
take it out spray it in darkness till it
just dripping off I try to get the other
sides of the leaves to stalk the stops
are important yeah it's press box yeah
and then let it dry out really good
maybe even with a little fans I'd and
let it dry out real good make sure
everything's dry otherwise you will get
burn marks and then and if you put it
back in a room with some girls that
you're not trying to flip you'll have
some [ __ ] in there that's ER yeah
you'll make some some Caitlyn Jenner
Caitlyn Jenner oh there's a little bit
of rub here a little bit of rub there
the last TS here the last yes there it
happens yeah you learn from experience
you learn plants are gonna take a whole
bunch of spring summer knock that's it
and some are gonna burn from it and it's
okay if the leaves curl up and look
pissed off as long as you still have
enough of that plant to create pollen
you're gonna be alright
it's that male plant is gonna look like
[ __ ] after that silver thiosulfate spray
and as people really need
stand to about reversing plants you not
I've had somebody coming to my grow and
say oh you have a hermie plant was like
no it's a reverse plant look at me go
huh
and they just look at me you know with
the most baffled look on their face and
they don't understand what I'm talking
about average plant is totally different
than our magnetic plant
yeah we did this on purpose we did this
on purpose and we're blocking genes
we're actually blocking genes in the
genome whereas our Meredydd ik is like
that because of its genome so the silver
the silver hits the plant and it can't
move by itself so the thiosulfate
solution makes it mobile and absorbable
within the plant and that blocks the
copper production in the plant the
copper movement in the plant which
triggers an ethylene responses at ethyl
or ethylene [ __ ] either way come on help
me out it triggers a response of ethyl
or ethylene I'm gonna say ethyl because
ethylene sounds like more of a gap like
it was like I'm making methylamine you
thinking ethanol
okay well either way it it messes up it
triggers that hormone and that hormone
is what tells the plant that it wants to
change sexes and start producing pollens
then you make pollen that since this
plant has no male chromosomes it will
not donate any male chromosomes to the
breeding project it'll all be female
chromosomes so basically three take you
back to its mother's yeah that's it
that's the mother of the plant that's
it's pretty much what it is if you have
a 50/50 hybrid that's what you can
expect it to lean toward that mother's
side and then it's ideal
once you find beekeeper if and I didn't
realize not a lot of people were doing
this when I started breeding I was
reversing a female to a male and hitting
several females so I was making nine or
ten feminized crosses at one time and
then I realized later that that's not
industry-standard of how that's done
most of the time people will take a
clone only or their favorite plant and
reverse that and hit it with a bunch of
the hit bat pollen on the same bunch of
the same clones and just keep doing it
I've actually been reverse reversing
plants and true breeding with those
reversed plants and I didn't even
realize how far out of the norm I was
stepping most folks would find a keeper
and then keep reversing that one to keep
making more and more and more but I've
actually I reversed the plant pollinated
another plant of the the clone of the
same strain made seedlings of that took
seeds of that took that original plant I
reversed
the pollen on that one and after a few
finial generations of inbreeding I was
unable to reverse the plant with silver
thiosulfate I bred it so so strong that
it's so female it will not reverse on me
it was a grateful dog experiment and I
called it GD 77 is the one that will not
reverse yeah
1977 is my favorite is why it got Gd 77
random breeder [ __ ] right there yeah
right I have another rant I want to kind
of go on but I don't know my piss people
off it frustrates me when hash makers
put two different strains in a tube and
run it together and think that they can
now call it I'm like no that took you
seven minutes like it takes me [ __ ]
years to develop something that I get to
name you don't get to name it
you don't get to name something who
expressed because you could Doctor Who
and pineapple Express and a [ __ ]
container together I'm half serious I'm
half frustrated half don't care like I
think it's it's misleading to the
medical patients because it's hard for
them to know what strains yeah no I'm
like the but I know I know that this is
Doctor Who and probably pineapple
Express because I've been in this long
enough but it's called who express a lot
of if you're a medical patient and
you're not hip and paying attention on
Instagram you don't know what the [ __ ]
that is and maybe doctor who's your
favorite but maybe pineapple Express can
be panic attacks and maybe there is be
like ogee and the really 50/50 blend
there is right and I'm not trying to be
a hater on that I just think that that's
a little bit misleading I know we've
come to the point technology is just
cannabis industry where we're supposed
to be stepping it up here in Colorado
and everything else you know we're the
guys that are these guys sitting at this
table right now you know among other
growers here in Colorado are the ones
that are sitting the forefront for all
the other states because they're all
looking at this day going how do we do
this you know and they're falling in
line you know models that's it we're
taking the lead and then you know
started ever since I've been in Colorado
and proud to be a part of that you know
this particular company will only accept
one
thousand gram runs so I understand the
need to make [ __ ] because you're gonna
if you've got a pound of this and a
pound of this then you got a thousand
gram run but yeah a lot of trim exactly
and they make they make a great product
I'm not gonna say their name or anything
cuz I kind of just talk [ __ ] but they do
make a great product I just find it
frustrating and misleading almost to the
market it's no I mean you're not really
talking to you just giving them you know
that's effective criticism yeah it's all
that is I mean if they can't you know
label it and you should they should
label it is so you know I mean then that
makes them that much better exactly you
know that that's no disrespect to the
people that are forced to combine
batches because metric makes you just
wish it didn't have to be that way
because there's a bleeder I get to take
grateful dog and Girl Scout cookies and
put it together and call it doggy style
people do that to hash and I don't feel
like I don't know they just grab two
tubes and mix my trim together and now
they just made a new strain no I can't
use the name that they just took is now
everyone's yeah I like that
I like how you labeled that I wish I
could say their names out loud my kids
are still sitting at this table right
now all right so we've gotten to the
point where we're pulling seeds out of
the bud we're curing buds that's where
we are I try to keep tabs on where we
are I don't even have any notebook paper
and I can still do a podcast and kind of
proud of myself all right we got to cure
him you say that here in Colorado we've
got I only got a cure for like three or
four days I agree with that I didn't
realize that in the swamp in the South
that you had [ __ ] soup for air a lot
more secure time my theory was that the
seeds finish in the buds in nature the
seeds would finish in the buds the buds
would kind of dry up and die and they
would fall into the ground and they
would sit in the ground all winter and
that would be their natural cure time
which is part of why I keep my seeds and
a cooler because I think that nature
would keep them in the snow maybe
depending on where they are maybe cold
rain and then that's what's also going
to germinate them the rains are gonna
come and germinate them in this spring
and then they're gonna start popping up
so it's a I just
figured they would kind of be curing in
the plant in nature yeah they've
actually been they've been domesticated
to the point now where there's only like
there's only certain regions of the
world just comes like a handful of
places in the world that we Texaco just
completely naturally like actual weed
not him yeah actual cannabis that it
grows naturally you know you know West
Himalayan mountains places like that I'd
love to go up there where I've seen
Arjen and his crew go up in smoke some
of that house full of a lot of old like
Malawi in places like that there's just
full of old land race genetics that are
falling and dying and same crops coming
over and over and over again every year
in the same spot those are heirloom
genetics we're gonna keep talking about
seeds but I've got another random note
that I want to interrupt because I've
got some grown people here that are
great to have cannabis conversation with
have you guys seen our Ian from
greenhouse seeds are Ian and Franco and
Simon travel all around the world and
they go to these places where they're
growing landrace genetics and they check
it out and they ask the farmers for
seeds and the farmers happily will give
them a bag of seeds your seeds right
soon as they've seen quite a few of them
are Ian then in return hands them packs
of his coloured greenhouse seeds because
his seeds are rolled in coloured coding
because then he can tell what strain
they are without having them in
packaging yeah there was some candy
coating that has also worked as a
fertiliser it helps your plants in
Germany so he trades them these
oftentimes feminized seeds do you guys
feel that he is [ __ ] up the landrace
genetics in these places by adulterating
them with his seeds
I guess if they're planning I'm like
right out there with their land races
and their cross pollinating and I guess
he just keep dying and regrowing and uh
eventually I guess it's gonna be a
different yeah did those [ __ ] of the
heirloom line but at the same time I've
seen a lot of those heirloom genetics
and stuff like that and nothing really
brag home about they look like some
straight slag and they're finished
drying there's really nothing to him so
the Heinz Heinz fifty-fifty you know I
mean he's gonna bring a better yielding
strains to places like you know Africa
and places like that but it was in
Jamaica is where actually saw him do
this yeah but like you're saying
it does is it's a it's kind of at what
cost kind of thing right it's it's it's
like yeah you're gonna you're gonna give
them better genetics for their future
and you know and their kids and their
kids and their kids are gonna have
better yielding better plants and stuff
like that which is gonna give more
profits for them so they're gonna be
able to yield more food for their
families and things like that but at the
same time you know like you said you're
gonna come and you're gonna completely
disaster eyes those heirlooms which you
know there's thousands of generations
yeah people you know they've been doing
the same thing it's history but change
is inevitable all right I like it I'm
torn on the subject 50/50 at everything
because life is a carburetor it's gonna
have good and bad to it like will said
someone's gonna get in there at some
point is something at some point because
been somebody's Mexican weed from
Florida green seeds white widows so I
guess with green house seeds isn't so
bad all right so now the seeds are cured
we've got a big-ass bag or maybe a
smaller portion of dried and cured seeds
how do we store them um again you can
use dried rice but I like to do a steel
silicon packets out of electronics and
things and things I get in the mail so
you keep all those yeah the silicon
packs that you get like when you buy a
new computer or exactly you take those I
collect all those I'm here in Colorado
it's pretty dry so I just grab thumb and
freezers soon as freezer refrigerator as
soon as possible to keep moisture away
from them all right
that way they prolong the life I mean
kind of tell when they're good when
they're bad it's a nice and good and
clear color they're good if they turned
like a dark or an amber color or a dark
brown color they're no longer useful
they've actually pulled moisture and
bacteria and things out of the air which
gave them that color the oxidized yeah
yeah so all right so they're no longer
good that's one good way to find out
wouldn't you know crack it open take a
look
I always crack them up and put them all
in a big jar and actually give them in
my seed packages actually in our vials
we do a layer of beads do we do a late
and then we do a layer of cotton then
the seats and the Cotton's and the beads
that way it's like a thirty-year storage
file nice you know you can throw that in
your fridge
thirty years and pull it out pop those
seeds that's impressive
yeah it's simply I have to up my game
simple but effective because we got the
unit we got the mylar packaging which in
itself is a food saving package yeah and
then we had the vial inside and then we
use those beets a lot of the time
growers would get them if you don't get
them that's because we didn't have any
to get right at the moment but either
way you still get the cotton into the
vial and everything else like that but
typically we always put beads in there
with them and people have asked me
what's that for testers have asked me
what are these beads for you know the
seeds in there I've had one guy ask me
about the seeds in there you know it
also throws them off looking for things
like that that's helpful but yeah and
fruit frigerator store not freezer I
would say you don't want you don't want
to freeze it because once you get below
freezing point you're basically the
water inside of the embryo is trying to
expand right you'll have more cracks
that's basically you're basically
creating in large earthquake inside of
your embryo because it's trying to
expand and crack outwards and it has
nowhere else to go it's it's it's
isolated and that shows all the water in
there's gonna crack and expand that that
that embryo and destroy it so you really
want to say anything above freezing
temperature 32 degrees all right but now
here's my favorite part
once you've got a whole bunch of seeds
you've got your herbs separated do
something with that herb we're gonna
move on to talk about seeds my favorite
part grow a bunch of the things that's
right get as many as you can that's
right and figure out how much space
you've got and then grow plant more
seeds than that even if you're not a
large-scale breeder and you have 500
seats you know give them to your friends
do your own testing you know that's the
way to do it you know the guys like me
give me the guys like we'll take some
will grow we're not afraid you might
have some amazing [ __ ] that's right
we'll go 10 of them for you I got some
in from California called silver widow
and it's a super Silver Haze white widow
cross hole that's gonna take 12 days to
finish
some of the pictures look great and you
know there's some good phenotypes I know
that are there there there you have to
find them but oh yeah it's a search yeah
it's it's a search you know you just in
if there's nothing there then we throw
them in the trash can that's just how it
works afterwards we smoke it and blast
it whatever we do and you know it goes
go on to the next project you know you
got to have a passion for doing what you
do and that's a lot of it too that's
another thing we looking for testers
that's passion passion that's how many
young people dedicated to what they do
just because they do it anyway
and what percentage of your breeding
project gets totally scrapped so you
breed you may exceed you take a few of
those seeds you grow out so many of them
and then you go uh how many times have
you just completely flushed a bag of
seeds down the toilet because the
project wasn't worth a [ __ ] I'd say at
least thirty forty percent of the time
that's a good breeder right there I just
actually went through my box like two
weeks ago man this threw away like
handfuls and just tossing it as a
breeder it's important that you don't
get your ego stuck on a strain you might
really think that this cross you've got
and this mail you've got is gonna make
the next [ __ ] hype and if it doesn't
don't be afraid to throw it away go
ahead and toss it we don't want those
shitty seeds out on the market you can
breed again you can make something way
better and then you're not gonna be
known as that guy that made that
hermaphroditic weak [ __ ] you might be
that guy that made that next flame you
never know and we want to know we want
to know if you got problems with the
seeds we want to know if you'd do great
garden and you're automatically having
her a frenetic problems and things like
that well ya know these things you know
some breeders don't want to know what
some breeders are too big to give a [ __ ]
but you know we're not those guys you
know that's that's it I know that for a
fact that and we're always down to
answer questions and that's why we're
here right now yeah well thanks for
coming for a few man appreciated uh what
else do you think we should cover we got
all the way down to growing them give
them out to your friends start to finish
grow them that's that's the next step
take careful notes and finally keepers
give me your friends to grow you know ha
then make F twos
because f2 is where [ __ ] gets really fun
oh you know then you get a recessive
segregation transgressive segregation
yeah that's a transgressive segregation
that's where your offspring will show
better traits
then it's parents will outperform each
parent so yeah cool [ __ ] don't believe
and don't believe in too much hype that
you hear on things either try it for
yourself and make your own determination
true yeah don't be afraid to get in
there and close ahead I've had F six
lavenders from someone everyone on was
her me Wow so so you know you really
would you attribute that into the way
that he makes his pollen sometimes I he
does and then he also does a lot of rot
ization I know that for a fact
he's written articles on it I've read
from him that he's done a lot of rebel
ization which is basically taking a
plant past its harvest point to the
point where it's creating a female
banana then harvesting a female banana
which basically is hermaphroditic banana
yep and he also will light a fire and
almost put the plant on fire so it goes
into a panic mode and that panic mode
makes it do the same thing it makes it
spit out her flowers have her pollen and
also do a light stress yeah yeah
old-school funky ship it too so he's a
lot of grief no no yeah someone who
strange some of the greatest ones and
still this Taylor lavender I mentioned
that that's a legendary strain and when
you get good phenotypes at them they
taste amazing it's so Gouda man they did
some best concentrates that lavender is
on point you know but these old-school
strains that someone was one of the guys
if it wasn't for him that the New York
City diesel really wouldn't be as hot
today as it is I really liked his oh man
the g13 hazed there's a g13 haze that I
picked up a while back from soma that
was amazing I loved the flavor of that
stuff still Hidden Mist but when you
find the good keepers their keepers you
know what I'm saying their keepers but
you got a lot of run a lot of his gear
to find those keepers he reminds me like
DJ shorts the same way and that's
nothing against DJ butt and you know
quit breeding go eat specifically for
what he wants right give a [ __ ] about
the TV lover TV lover and that's what he
breeds and that's his thing you know but
he has to understand you know there's he
he does pay for a lot of his advertising
because great advertisement
his book is definitely good he's a great
breeder he's a great grower and things
like that just not my forte and
you know it's the same thing with him
you have to run a hundred seeds to get a
good phenotype you know we're size I can
generally say I know you gauge me can
adventure quite a few others in this
game I'll hi I've had 10 packs and found
three keepers out of heat rare dankness
those receivers you know I've gotten
some really wonky plants from arid
dankness I would say it would make it up
make up for all of the [ __ ] they've ever
sold me right like all right yeah
there's one right there
right yeah yeah that's how was with us
with rug burn we ran up to a bunch of
rug burn sheets and every one of them
was like we got an eighth to piece of
them like this is the lengthiest walk
he's looking it's no good we don't I
don't think gage gets enough credit in
the game like people more people need to
notice gage green genetics that that's a
definitely a high-end breeding company
that gets overlooked in my opinion I do
the great they're great I mean they've
got good material they're working with
that's a lot of it's just a material
they have is golden joseph OG is amazing
great stopper and so many other great
plants and the Joseph Ocean Beach cross
was one of the one of the highly
sought-after but they're very quick and
gone plants you know that was that was
come and gone so fast because it went
out basically as testers and never came
back I may still have a pack of testers
from that I've got honestly I have a
small manila envelope filled with gauge
green genetics tester bags because you
just used to send me so much maybe like
run what you can right yeah yeah we took
the dominant oceans out of that one out
of those and actually bred with them too
we got a new one coming out with that
pre 98 bubble OB Ripper yeah Joseph
Joseph is just too stringy and I hate
the way he does that so we're gonna hit
him with that proof hit that pre 90 I
called behind but my prized male is an
arise male which was started with a
Daybreaker male from gage yeah I'm not
afraid I'm not sad to admit I've done
dabs with no those are good kids they
are they are and you know you talked
about it and you go to them with a 10
pack and be like hey I got the
Holy Grail I do you mind if I breathe
they're gonna look at you and keep play
your mics gonna go for it'll help you
name it that's it you gotta have respect
for that yeah I kind of use anything
that I breed to the Daybreaker I try to
use I don't copy gage but I use their
scheme in the names like a rise and
Cascade those are all crosses they came
from a gage male so right yeah just try
to honor them in the cross yeah you got
to get a little bit props to dad where
it came from respect to back to the
elders Bay pine you know we put it in
there just a bait pile yeah California
pine trees you know and swear words from
so let's get a little homage back to
Kelly yeah gotta give love to everybody
that does it all right guys we've been
going for like an hour we need to start
wrapping up this part of the show will
you were a little bit quiet but we
talked a lot about seed breeding you
grew some Kalonji cush from my seeds and
that [ __ ] looked amazing I actually
still have a mother from a back cut and
I just actually about to take a bunch of
cuts this week yeah yeah we definitely
take one I think it's better than the
cut that I've got are you saying that a
while back yeah it's better than the
coat we've got the cut agree Rossi and
your cut looks like covered in covered
in trikes it awfully favors to grow too
it often gets confused for la playa Labs
is Durango oh gee it looks very similar
the smell on the Kalonji was uh it was
something I'd never I had never smelled
weed like that before everyone I showed
it to was like what the hell this is
crazy nice so definitely stoked on that
one good find
oh yeah you know oh yeah cool man where
can people find you on social media you
can find me on Instagram it's the the
barefoot grower
I think it's barefoot yeah the
underscore barefoot underscore grower
okay all right you got pictures of the
new grow it work up there yeah yeah
we're covert of sin sin cannabis company
can find them on Instagram too it's just
at ascend cannabis company ASCE nd oh
man that might be a new strain named us
and
bro's yours go for it no I was what made
me think about it was arise that's a
good name cuz I go in a can of sewer a
lot and they run your eyes in there I
didn't know that yeah actually really
cool
yeah canister runs your eyes really yeah
it's always on the show that's one of
the favorites of the bud tenders and oh
[ __ ]
to the canister I guess I'm gonna have
to stop in there and buy an a it's just
the see but you know the only reason why
I ever go into that place is because
they're like the only place in Pueblo
West it doesn't just rape you you know I
can go in and get hundred 25 ounces if
I'm out between harbors you know and
it's it's the weeds crap but say the
weeds good user machines oh man true
machines suck people employ humans
that's it come on support Rica me that's
what's rude
stop cutting it early quit doing machine
work that's a lot of what the problem is
once they do that they know they got a
fantastic-looking grow it's clean it's
nice you know looks good they over feed
a little bit you know when your plants
look like the tying the shoes it's time
to back off a little bit speaking a
trimming weed I owe a shout-out to my
buddy John Randall's jr. that new trims
for 40 hours a week with no complaints
puts his head down to [ __ ] cuts up
fine good job brother thank you I
appreciate having you on the team keep
it up do you think will did we cover all
of your social media yes the underscore
barefoot underscore grower make sure you
support my friend we'll check out some
pictures he's got some cool [ __ ] up
there yeah for sure man I appreciate
your big-ass grow it over there hey post
some cool [ __ ] on do you want these
people to follow you on snapchat also
easy on snapchat
yes snapchats picky you can find me as
the Barefoot grower on on snapchat or
Il's wheezy on snapchat they're both my
usernames cuz you got to you can see his
morning dabs it's always snapchat during
the day where I guys seem to post a lot
of what we got going on over there we do
a lot every day so if you're interested
in what goes on in a huge greenhouse on
the daily definitely hit me up it
entertains me so it will definitely
entertain the average grower check it
out Rob how can people find you on the
social media Twitter Facebook
Instagram that's pretty much where we're
at right now you guys this our seat code
all right it's our Seco all right let's
have a website yet we had one we'll took
it down for a little while I'm gonna
redo everything I'm just gonna redo
everything from scratch again and no
more for them we're just gonna go all
out the forum gets to be a pain in the
ass doesn't it it does it does and then
you have a lot of spam that's what I
have in the main thing is the money to
get a good host it doesn't have a lot of
spam and security and everything else it
cost you a fortune
Chinese and Russian hackers trying to
get exactly every single day say those
ray-bans that's right they join the
forum and then they just go and they
type in in the forum they figure out how
to put in script in their forum post
they can corrupt my website then they
start stealing [ __ ] out of my website
and then redirecting it yeah this
happened twice now but I'm gonna walk
down pretty well now I think I feel like
I just taunted people but we had a great
moderator but it was a lot on him too
you know it was like taking a path of
his day just just trying to give you I'm
the moderator I get the emails laughter
dear forum and I have to go delete
they're doing all that work on our forum
um but yeah we shut it down we're doing
a website now and we do have a website
for the hatpins
17 hatpins comm check those guys out he
just brought me two dope ass hat pins I
got the little was a zombie pin doll and
I got the noose our seed Colo go for my
hat that's gonna look fresh you know
where they're gonna go check us out we D
$12.99 free shipping we don't
discriminate all overhead comes the same
if you have more than three hat pins on
your hat purse and or backpack
you are a walk three pins we can all
agree on three pins right everybody
solid three is a limit alright more than
three pins in your look three three
three makes you will walk two pins
you're all right I have like 15 on my
backpack right but I make hat pins for
living excuse you you've got an excuse I
got the I read genetic spin on
everything so I got that one of my frame
as I just rocked the one on the hat
that's all I need we're good enough but
I am a look
all right we can go for a long time make
sure you follow my friends on all their
social media feeds make sure you support
7:10 hatpins yeah make sure you support
them support the legalization of
cannabis and make sure you follow me on
all the social media you guys on
Instagram it's IRA underscore genetics
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast and of
course there's Facebook the girl from
your heart podcast page support that
check it out because I'm gonna wrap up
this part with my friends bros thanks
for coming thank your abs I'm gonna hit
pause for a minute play some music and
I'll be right back to wrap up the show
[Music]
yeah I want to thank you guys again for
listening I also want to thank Rob and
wilt for joining me you guys make sure
you support our sponsors elevate glass
before we go I want to give a huge shout
out to my friends in the mystic roots
band it definitely made me feel like a
VIP I had a good ass time at the show
thanks for traveling thanks for coming
through also shout out to catch a fire
big shout out to the black sheep and the
huge shout-outs my friends Chris and
Lindsey because I think that's all I've
got for you it'd be really cool if you
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for the girl from your heart
podcast find the reviews section type in
a little comment let me know what you
think about the show give me a scar
rating and I will read your comment on a
future episode I definitely appreciate
all of the comments I would also
appreciate it if you guys follow me on
social media that's right check me out
on Instagram it's Irene underscore
genetics I am on Twitter it's at g f YH
podcast and we're also on facebook just
search for the grow from your heart
podcast you guys every episode is
available on iTunes stitcher and my
website I read genetics Colorado calm
you can also catch the show Wednesdays
at 1:00 p.m. on Tok radio.com big shout
out to my friends at Tok radio make sure
you support the other podcasts on the
network big shout out to Lucy in her
podcast Lucy in the sky I think that's
all I have got for you on this long
extended episode thanks again for
listening to a long episode
big shout out to Maddy and Spence and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]