[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 142 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're new grower if
you're a professional grower you're a
new smoker or dedicated battery if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff on to thank you once again for
joining me as always I need to give a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat cooing the entire
mystic roots crew I got through it
without coughing you guys oh I deserve
worse oh man I was trying to go fast
welcome to the show everybody this
episode is the 710 episode this is gonna
come out on Sunday 710 happy 710
everybody I hope you got the email
turned on up you got the dabber going I
got you have you got a corset banger
heated up hope you got that highly
educated titanium quartz combo going on
you got an elevator rig with a phat nail
on it hope you're smoking some super
good shatter hope you're a spoiled [ __ ]
like I am Oh hope you're over there
smoking some of those fresh OG Kush
chirps from our friends at Evo labs
ladies and gentlemen on the show with me
today celebrating seven ten is white
Mike how you doing bro doing good man
how are you did I am DTF oh I'm dad the
[ __ ] out we had a little pre up three
game over here as well you're not gonna
cough you gotta keep convincing yourself
I'm not gonna come everybody seven ten
oh you're taking dad's with us
tweet me tell me what you're dabbing at
G fyh podcast on Twitter I want to know
what you're taking dad's up right now we
want to know is it live resin is it
shatter is it poop soup is it tain
batter what do you got going on is it
some of those Evo labs fresh troops
let's talk about some of these fresh
herbs it's like you talking about it's
not a lot of people yeah not a lot of
people
what the hell I'm even talking about it
got fancier people and we have stepped
up our game here in Colorado our friends
at Evo labs so we they I said we like
I'm involved in this [ __ ] i smoke it's
my role in this part of consumer level
only I do a little product research for
these guys but uh so I'll be your space
monkey I don't care
we take they take some shatter they take
cash I think they're taking co2 oil I'm
90% sure that this is made with co2 oil
a co2 extraction and there's a lot of
people right now in the industry playing
with refining co2 oil in one way or
another and this seems to be my favorite
way this is a fractal distil this is the
first home run I've gotta play with all
of the clear the they're calling it
distillate all of the distillate is done
with a fractal distillation process and
they're separating basically everything
the cannabinoids and terpenoids and the
lipids are all pulled apart and this
container right here is a container of
nothing but the THC this is ninety
percent ninety point nine four percent
THC and 1.1 percent CBD this is rod
distill it from Evo Evo labs I'm gonna
open the jar here and try to contain
describe what's in this container the
best I can
it looks like really runny honey or ah
super clear olive oil maybe yeah but
it's got more of the consistency of like
honey or maybe a little bigger than any
olive oil I've ever seen but yeah the
color might be right though yeah yeah it
just looks like it's like honey almost
in there but this doesn't have much
flavor it's it is just raw
super stupid potent I put a little bit
of this on the dabber and this is where
it gets fun I take that little bit
that's on the dabber and I dunk that
into the ghost train haze raw turps this
is mostly terpenoids with a little bit
of cannabinoids like one or two percent
to mind if I call it the adult version
of fun dips this is definitely well
we've oh I'm a Deadhead and we've got
our own little version of fun dips but
this is the weed world of a fun dendrite
this is uh it's a beautiful thing this
is a so you take that beautiful ninety
percent THC distillate and then you dunk
it you dunk it and the glorious part is
in my other hand I've got some og cush
Terps so I can either dunk it in my og
cush Terps or I can dunk it over here my
ghost train haze Terps
or I could dunk it in one and then I
could dunk it in the other and we're
changing up the flavors it the og cush
Terps if you put it on this distillate
and dammit it tastes like you if apples
tasted like og cush and you bit into an
og cush apple it was just oh gee cush
all in my mouth and you could almost
chew the flavor that's how much oh gee
cush flavor these Terps put in your face
it's the flavor contents really really
nice this way and then the high from the
distillate combo'd with I really like
the high that I get from the ghost train
haze it's uh this is sativa dominant
strain so I talk about this every day
the the other stuff that's in it that's
the THC is definitely a big part of the
high but everything else that that's in
it really plays with that THC in some
fun ways
I almost never go for the most potent on
the shelf and if you think about the
rest of your life you typically don't do
that either you've got to get that other
component to it in this way you can get
both you can get insanely potent and
really really flavorful I've been kind
of being a snobby [ __ ] I take some of
this blue shirt 120 micron fresh frozen
solvent less hash and I roll out a
little patty and then i dunk some some
some durbin poison shatter onto it and
then I rubbed a little cactus cooler
live resin on top of that I'm gonna put
a little bit of the Terps on it and then
I put some of that ninety percent THC
distillate on top of there and I took a
big-ass dab of that I remember in high
school when he used to go park somewhere
and see how high you could get I don't
think we got that high when I when I
took that big-ass dab my arm hair was
wiggling around like it was a visibly
waving like doing something similar
which is much much cheaper product with
with just your typical wax or shatter
I'll take a piece of shatter and kind of
pancake it out real far throw a little
wax in the middle roll up a little
taquito and dab that but mine
much smaller and much less fancy than
the ones you've been throwing down I
like to go big or go home and I take
dad's home I'll go a little and go often
I go big and go often that's one of the
best parts about taking dabs is that you
can grab the dabber and Mike can take
his dosage Mike's a cigarette smoker so
when you get Mike worked up a little bit
you can hear him gurgle he doesn't even
need dabs to start making funky longer
noises sounds like the bong occasionally
so you give them I give Mike if you
handed me the dabs that I gave Mike I
would laugh at you I'd say can you maybe
triple quadruple that up bread andd Mike
takes just little pince adds dad's
probably the dad's you take Mike takes
that size of a dab and he will cough and
turn purple and get sweaty with the
email carp cap setup as smooth as it is
over here you knock off like a beast
it's not nearly as bad as hone because I
don't have that carve cap to cut the cap
adds quite a bit people get yourself a
carp cap this is a 710 episode let's
educate folks on the email right quick
the the electronic continuously heated
now is a beautiful beautiful thing it's
also a little dangerous depending on
where you dab I I had one in the car for
several days well the space I I dab
often is also shared by three large dogs
that are really furry and psychotic and
so like if I was gonna add an email to
that makes like something would get set
on fire that I care about yeah dog would
get burned the bald spot somewhere so
there's kind of a reason I don't have
one yet but it's it's on the short list
of things to treat myself to I had to
take mine out of the car I was getting a
careless I was getting too high in the
car which I was like I'm pretty pretty
medicated here I got to chill out on
this and then also I had to set the rig
in the cupholder and I forgot it was
there and I felt warmth a couple times I
don't know that I was gonna burn myself
but I was like ooh that is warm over
there and had to think about it again
I'm kind of close to that so I took the
email out of the car that doesn't happen
anymore be careful you guys I can't tell
you what to do but if there's somebody
in the backseat that needs to have their
medical cannabis available while you're
driving they can consume their medical
cannabis do your thing you're an adult
but so the email there's a box on my
table
it's uh six inches long four inches tall
it's smaller than the original Nintendo
but a little taller yeah okay yeah yeah
and it's got a display on it little LED
display with the number it's got a power
switch on it but one of the coolest
[ __ ] features it's got a USB port
Mike is trying his phone pretty much
every episode that I've been on in the
last six months my phone's been charging
on that USB slot there's a really
beautiful shout out to my friend Gideon
this you know was actually a gift from
giddy up at emo tech so big shout out
and shout out to Margolese for the
replacement coils I appreciate that bro
ah but so there's this box with an LED
screen on the front with numbers
displayed on it then coming out of that
box is another cord it's a silver cord
it's a silver braided cord and it goes
to where the deck so if you're using any
sort of nail setup instead of the little
nail that sits inside the rig and the
dome or a titanium domeless we've got a
much larger titanium domeless that has
this coil leading to it and then it's
tightly wrapped around the nail so that
it can evenly heat that surface yeah to
whatever temperature we feel like and
that's where I want to jump in and
everybody talks about what temperature
is your email sent to I do not believe
that that number right there where it
says 717 right it's not at all integer I
don't think that's a temperature I don't
think it correlates to the actual
temperature on my nail surface because I
think this box would cost much more
money for it to actually have a
thermostat inside it that's doing that
one of our friends that is a guy that
works on my website actually told me
that's actually a frequency always
understood it to be is just the random
frequency that it kicks out plus it
gives you something to work it's like
your speaker's 11 doesn't [ __ ] mean
anything perfect yeah something to you
is like the prime spot if I go right any
six it gets a little you don't want to
hear that Jerry starts son and a little
extra heroin if you learn about too loud
I've posted pictures before us getting
ready to record and stuff and somebody
always chimes in and there's like dude
your e knows like 300 degrees too hot
and it's like that's not a temperature
is always like the first three replies
I'm sure if you bought seven emo tech
units
I've seen this helpful that have the
temperature display and I like that yeah
the one task rock made the original and
we're gonna talk about task rock you
guys this is the [ __ ] 710 episode of
you best believe we're gonna talk about
a boy task rock the original email that
task rock of highly-educated the
innovator the originator that original
email did I think that temperature did
correlate to the one in the box although
I'm not certain but I'm pretty sure it
did shot it to Big D with the original
he's got the museum version he's got the
first email that task made it's on
Daniels shelf much loved and respected a
big deep miss you bro hope to see you
soon
it's get you on the podcast into the
good old days I really don't think that
that number correlates I think like Mike
that's definitely not a temperature when
you get in your car or whatever whether
you like it where you really like the
jam out when your favorite song comes on
what born to be wild comes on you want
to drive on the freeway way too fast
whatever like 2339 what it's just a
random just aesthetic so it had
something for you to think about medium
high right before it starts crackling I
like to think my dad's kind of hot I
like the email a little hotter than most
people when Spence would come over shut
up dispenser from the garden immediately
turn it down you just you wouldn't even
ask he'd be like yo nail two hot dog and
just read you didn't say dog he would
call me the n-word you're nailed to hi
n-word and reach over and just turn my
[ __ ] now like it was his and I wouldn't
argue cuz that Spencer and he made the
hash for about too bad so I'm just gonna
let him do his thing but he'd always
turned it the [ __ ] down he'd be like my
Safa gif it always says esophagus so he
turned that [ __ ] down
I take pretty low temp dad's at home
every now and then I understood it or
like I sneeze between heating the nail
with the torch and going to dab and then
find it's a little too cold my puddle I
like a big chunky dad so I feel like I
have to overheat overheating is just hot
enough to cook all that otherwise I'm
sucking like we used to go way close
like keep eating oh I saw the grateful
the remaining members of the Grateful
Dead
Phil Lesh doesn't to her anymore so they
call themselves dead and Coe I saw dead
and co-ed in Boulder
shadow it's my friend that took me to
that show but I saw both the dead in
Boulder and
again there were some kids taken dads in
the back of this SUV they had the
tailgate up and they had the daybreak
sitting up on a little thing so that all
they had to do was put it to their face
and the dude heats it with the torch and
I'm just walking toward this car walking
through rows walking through the parking
lot and I see him just and I was like
it's hot
you [ __ ] stop trying to turn that
nail in the [ __ ] water right now and
I didn't say anything that's none of my
business I was like oh he's gonna put
the dome on or whatever and let it cool
nah bro I did through the dome on and
[ __ ] put that dabber to that nail
while it was glowing bright orange and I
just cringed I was like oh my god like
it was not my place to say anything but
my heart just tingled I was like oh god
that for poor [ __ ] damn it not only are
you ruining yourself for no reason
you're also losing so much of the flavor
do the Terps man I'm burnin the Terps I
the downside is if you understood it you
end up just wasting your hash on the
nail if puddles instead of vaporizers in
our world
so that's let me let me talk about that
when I taught when I hid the email when
I'm taking a big fat AB a lot of times
you guys I come home from work and I
want a dad like a half gram maybe a
grandma hash in one [ __ ] dab I'm not
kidding
there are more people in this room
they'll wait raise their hands a [ __ ]
testify Rasta Jeff will pull a grandma
dad gram dad no problem we got hands up
testify it's a lot but I like to take a
big fat dab I will do that on the email
a lot of times I'm smoking these Terps
and the distillate I bust out this one
right here my elevate cycler with the
little banger on it yeah it's got a they
say it's quartz I bet you money that's
[ __ ] glass I got a little glass of
banger on there that's my flavor savor
that I think it tastes a little bit
better I think quartz versus ty I think
sometimes you gotta say that the quartz
tastes a little bit better in my opinion
I I have that on my short list of things
I want to treat myself with is a nice
quartz banger
I'd really do I'm due this one here this
is a highly-educated titanium base with
the quartz the dishes - I saw some of
that on Instagram and didn't let myself
look because I was doing car repairs
myself that likes to travel with a
little rig like that that's the way to
go because this banger the way that I
travel with it that
would get destroyed quickly well where
were my Deverick sits most of the time
that would be safe like I can't risk
that you know right now but I could risk
the bug if the puppy could take the
bucket but not the email well it's safer
it's the cord that's the problem on the
email like just in practice I know my my
household well enough to me to know that
that rig would get yanked off that cord
is dangerous at this table right that
cord is knocked over and broken this
exact rig once before just sitting there
had just wobbled and spun itself over
cuz the you guys the cord on this he
knows it's was coiled in a box for a
hundred years it looks like and shifting
[ __ ] China and vacuum-packed and so
it's gonna be coy lis shaped for the
rest of its life and sometimes you try
to straighten it out and it makes you
think it went straight but then it just
starts coil and slowly winding itself up
and tip your rig over so turn your email
off when you leave the house that's a
reminder to myself also you know have no
idea how many times I've come home and
been like oh never leave the house with
an active heat source running like that
basic human ah low tip is better when
I'm doing a small dab is what I wanted
to kind of take that email versus the
quartz the titanium versus course if I
do a nice thing about the quartz is you
can bring that temp down even further
just let it cool get it get it glowy
high and let it go do it yes don't be
that do be that guy shout out to Jason
margulies I got so many friends it'll
heat the nail until it's glowing orange
and bust on a [ __ ] timer and they
have timed exactly like from what it
glows right here bro you hit go and wait
this many seconds perfect [ __ ] die
bro yeah I'm always like no you waited
too long I should have gone seven
seconds sooner than that because it's
too cool for me I like a little warm but
if I'm trying to dad these Terps all
oftentimes go for the quartz and go low
temp low temp they we say you got to
taste it to waste it
hit it low temp carb cap it just get all
that flavor in there take a little tiny
dab and then grab a q-tip and heat the
nail just a little bit and clean it out
with the q-tip and now you got a fresh
banger again they call that the q-tip
tech I don't play that way I heat the
[ __ ] out of it until it's clean and then
I throw another dad in it that's that's
how I roll with the banger I'm not on
the q-tip tech in the low temp tech all
that I like take a phat dab and get it
on all right my buddy Adam mill would
say red means go he
and just throws a mad dab in there no I
can't
it's it's too much on my throat yeah low
tip is better for you low temp is better
I fine so guys when you're trying to set
the temperature to your email everyone's
like what temperature do I set it go
ahead Mike you got something to jump in
when I say that's the right setup is
really key to getting the most out of
your hash you you can take a really nice
low temp tab on an email and with the
carb cap you don't waste anything
there's even if you go really low it's
still gonna continuously heat that
surface and vaporize everything off
you've got a carb capped even if it
takes a second to get it done you're not
gonna lose anything you can actually
enjoy all of that and it just it's one
of those things where it takes the time
and investing in the right tools to
really get the best bang out of your
product and that's part of the reason I
end up so baked here is because I've
only got like half the pieces at home
and so when I low temp that I end up
losing a good bit off the top of my nail
and so small dabs anyway and you got to
clean it up I noticed it the first step
every time I come over here I coughed
way harder than I have in a week or two
and then I get a little bit higher that
I've been in a week for the size I think
is because I use a smaller rig than most
folks yeah my rigs a little bigger I
really like I prefer a smaller rig and I
prefer an email on a small rig right now
I'm hitting the Hitman sidecar the
e-series sidecar this whole way small to
the point and it heats to the point
where he's got to keep an eye on the
water level because it will cook itself
dry yeah yeah that that has happened
before my mad Rob is like [ __ ] four
inches tall I love these little rigs I
like this itself rod during a podcast
before the sloppy taking a dry dab this
elevate Klein it's taller but it still
got very very minimal amount of airspace
and that's it I don't want a lot of
space from the time that I put my dab on
the surface of this dad nail for it to
go down here down this tube into the
water and into my face I want as little
resistance as possible I just want to
get that dab
to my brain just give it to me and I
feel like all the percolators and all
the extra bubbles and [ __ ] that's just
stealing your dad's still in your Terps
stealing your flavor I don't want all
that extra bubble äj--
I want enough water just to cool it down
from hitting that nail and then let me
get it actually took dabs today through
this little rig without enough water in
it and I got ultra high that's stupid I
didn't have enough water in it was it
kind of it was kind of Bernie
it made my throat tingle a little bit
but holy [ __ ] I was red-eyed the first
time I used a really good portable hash
pen they never last for very long but
the first time I used one they gave you
like that first dozen hits well burn the
[ __ ] out of my circulation tastes like
hot plastic no it was a different
company still tasted like hot plastic
because the mouthpiece was plastic but
[ __ ] dude that burn lasted all week if
the throat burn for a week remember like
when you stay at a bong and fill it let
me get it full and you keep sucking and
that chamber would fill and you keep
sucking and all your friends like pull
it pull it and you look at him like nope
I'm gonna get highs bong it and then you
pull it and then all that smoke goes in
your head that's the point of a big pipe
or a big bong or a big rig build that
[ __ ] up and then kharbut and get
smoked if you notice add a brig there's
no carb you just want that [ __ ] smoke
I mean throw the card cap on to trap the
heat and in the nail and put a little
vacuum in there you got a little tiny
hole in the carb cap you get less air
flowing through that heat stays in there
every bit of air that comes through
moves that oil around on the top of the
nail then it goes into your brain and
then you get stupid high I don't feel
the need to suck like a liter of oxygen
through my bong before I start getting
my I'm not a fan of bad songs and I know
a lot of people that are I sell an
amazing nail that is it's a beautiful
six in one that's designed for rigs or
bongs it'll fit anything on the market
it's a copy of the highly educated
infinity nail I'm sure it is it's an
awful beautiful invention completely as
I'm talking about and every time I see
it and I've got extra money in my pocket
I'm like that's [ __ ] so much now but
then I remember that I don't like dab
bongs it's just way too much volume
and I you
see it on the inside of the glass you're
like that's hash that's supposed to be
my brain yeah it's not it's on the side
yeah and as much as you coffin choke
anyway you don't need to spend that
extra energy on your lungs pulling a
liter of air up through your it's funny
I love a bomb for flower that's my
primary smoking device clean my bong
yesterday loved it
picked up flower today and yesterday
because that's mainly what I've been
smoking at home but for a nice nap you
got to go with a smaller rig yeah I
prefer when you started talking about
flower maybe you want a segue into
something else that I wrote down I
prefer indica flowers if I was gonna go
shopping like right here on the table
I've got some blue shirt that I grew
with the green and healthy wellness
garden
I smell so yummy and then here in this
container I got some Jeff Shoji that I
grew these are both heavy indica
dominant strains mm-hmm this one just
has like the end gorgeous thank you this
so far is my proudest grow in this
garden but wait until you see the next
couple runs I'm already impressed but I
prefer these indica dominant flowers to
sit you down chill you out cushy piney
dank flavored flowers I'm gonna roll a
joint with that and I'm gonna smoke it
and it's just gonna taste earthy and
funky and coffee like but then when it
comes to my dad's if you notice all my
dab selection everything over here is
like candy flavors and should I like the
cactus cooler and over here this one
doesn't even have a label anymore
whatever that was we got some of the
blue sure but course the solvent list we
got super lemon haze over here this one
is cold treat cush cuz obviously like
those cush Terps
I've been going super heavy citrus
lately for a while the only exceptions
the durbin which is all pine I was
building up to the lemon G hahaha
there's nothing like lemon G Terps the
flavor of lemon G live resin in my face
like if I could all if I can only dabble
and I don't know the lemon do you would
be my one and only but if I had to pick
three strains that I had had to dab for
the rest of my life lemon G would be in
that mix I may have to replace it with
lemon Geoffrey though I'm not sure I'd
have to set him side-by-side dick tabs
think about that no I've been going
sweet for a while I'm usually good it's
been a few Lee for a while and I just
went all sweet the last six months you
like the fuel yep it's that heavy diesel
flavor I've loved since nearly 2000 dad
for me
is that in your dabs or your flowers
both okay
I'm you know me I love the Sour Diesel
yeah yeah Sour Diesel live residents so
tasty I've got a little home right now I
can treat myself with I don't enjoy Sour
Diesel concentrates at all remember what
time I ended up with some sour diesel
concentrates on accident I'm pretty sure
I ended up yeah yeah it was delicious
just don't care for that flavor also
good I saved I used it as treats for
like when I did [ __ ] around the house
that I didn't want to do it all I hate
to say then live residence some kanji or
some Jilly bean Deb's oh god I'm a
junkie bro I've got some strap and then
a live resident oh that's really good
strawberry strawberry banana tangi the
SBT brother everybody seems to be going
googoo over the strawberry banana tangi
stuff from Crockett shots at rocket for
makin killer killer seeds
it's funny how being a breeder and
somebody that works in a large scale
cultivation facility seeing the
difference in buds that are grown in
plants that are grown for flower
production and plants that are grown
specifically for oil production we've
got to cut that we gave it to somebody
in another state and they grew it and
once they grew it out and saw it they're
like [ __ ] this plant and they cut down
all of the remaining plants of it and
they sent the flowers to an extraction
lab and that extraction lab was like
what the [ __ ] did you send us
I'd like some cuts that we got from our
friends in Colorado that would be me and
they're like what the [ __ ] is this [ __ ]
and the extraction lab ran it and they
called the guy up like bro you gotta
come over here and the dude went over
there he took a DAB it's the best
[ __ ] hash I've ever smoked and like
this is the best hash anyone in this
[ __ ] building has ever smoked do you
have any more he cut down all of the
[ __ ] plants that he had luckily I
still have it so it's still around it's
still here but it's it's ugly
conversation today we live in the future
here forget it so often here therefore
the rest of the country and for for sure
the rest of the world when it comes to
legal cannabis products or cannabis
products period we have stuff that I
mean if you guys want legal yesterday
you wouldn't see for five years
right this legend takes that kind of
time this [ __ ] strain will not finish
for anything and it's ugly but it makes
the best oil bro so things are gonna
change you're gonna start seeing
different different types of plants
growing for different things we're
growing specific should if they grow
right now they will only be made into
oil
we've got transit I will never let
anybody see that flower because they're
ugly as [ __ ] but the oil that comes out
of it is tremendous we're good through a
while now the hash has been stalled out
it just wax and shatter and butter and
butters just basically wax you you kind
of stumbled over if I'm not mistaken and
maybe I'm wrong for butter lovers sorry
but that was it and then live resident
came along and people really started
thinking about where can we go max with
this yeah and I love that people started
playing with co2 oil because there's a
huge demand for that but then you're
left with this goo in a syringe that's
impossible right soon without the date
is there I used to hate co2 oil I was
like I hate that goopy [ __ ] but it
didn't taste right now cleaned it um and
it's now that they've cleaned it up the
taste is pretty good
yeah um and when it's further refined
like this or separated completely and
then you reconstitute it back on with
your desk like do-it-yourself style it's
a lot of fun it is a lot of fun mixing
cocktails for yourself I like I've been
just taking this shatter and dunking it
straight into the Terps all night um
it's a long expensive process you guys
don't even want to know um but the
equipment alone you could buy a house
just for the nice ones yeah yeah just
for the equipment but this isn't the
only variety I've seen there's a local
outfit that's been bringing samples by
and their first two samples were epic
fails like unmarketable unsellable not
unsmoked bull way better than [ __ ]
you're gonna get in Florida did the name
of the company have a family member in
the name of the company okay but um it
was just not at all good good
concentrate ready to go like nothing
about it was was solid
attempts three and four were were really
really nice final products that are
probably gonna be really popular nice
but I'm seeing a lot of that there's
products that we get people who ask him
by name and stuff and like I don't have
people asking for the Leafs by Snoop but
I do have people asking for new styles a
hash that come out every couple of weeks
nice yeah when we send material out to
Tirpitz does all these extractions for
us from the green excuse me tur packs
does all the extractions from the green
and healthy wellness garden and when we
send out material we send them a lot of
fresh frozen material we send them a lot
of dry material the fresh frozen we can
request it's obviously gonna be live
resin that's why it's fresh frozen you
didn't even dab in your coffin you just
thinkin hit me rent I was looking at the
hash refresh frozen material out we
chopped down a plant we cut it into
small buds we throw those buds into
freezer bags those freezer bags go
directly into the freezer they get
frozen immediately then we run to the
store and get bags of ice and put those
bags of ice into a giant cooler put that
frozen material into that cooler drive
that to a location where it is then
turned in to live resin at that point we
can have it turned into live SAP live
sugar we can almost get a live shatter
from some of the strains the Sour Diesel
won't live shatter yeah once you build a
relationship with the extraction company
you're working with we have two specific
extractors that we talk to a lot they
work with tur packs and we can tell them
what we want and they like that strains
not gonna do that or that strain is
gonna do that and so we know that we can
get triangle killer sugar and Rudeboy
SAP like on consistent levels the
Rudeboy Live resin sugar is one of my
favorite [ __ ] things to dab ever it
is so turbid ellic that the high is
right where I want it like some things
get you on the top of the head something
used in the back of the brain some II
feel on the shoulders this Rudeboy hits
me right in the eyes and in the forehead
and it makes me film it makes math
skills go away it just makes me Goofy's
like dude I like pot they just [ __ ] I
want cookies after I smoke that [ __ ]
yeah all right so it is the 7:10
you guys we've been talking about 7:10
for a whole long time we should talk
about the origin of 7:10 Mike you have
any idea where the number 17 what all
this culture part of this community is
you flip it up upside down and I suppose
that oil that is true that's because a
lot of the people that started this
movement were of the age where they had
beepers and that's about as far as I've
bothered to follow it all right so 710
is the new 420 my friend Adam mill
coined the phrase 710 is the new 420
back in the day it was all about 420
let's get together at 420 and smoke some
weed now at 7:10 let's get together 710
take some dabs if you turn 7/10 upside
down it does say oil ah to the best of
my knowledge task rock is the person
that created the phrase 710 I think task
rock and a couple other guys were either
in a chat or on a conference call and
they were talking about stuff we need
they were like we need something a
little more bougie than 420 let's
upgrade it let's do it with the hash
well this was hash kids were separating
from flower kids kind of yeah yeah say
that my kids I mean like full-grown
adults but you know what I mean right
The Hustler kids so that's that's where
7/10 came from 7-10 was coined as far as
I know to the best of my knowledge and
I've done a little bit of research but
task rock and a couple other cats were
the guys that coined the phrase 7/10 so
they created 710 shot at the task rock
cast Rock of course is he's a rapper TAS
Brock has a couple of albums out one of
my favorite songs is probably first
place I like do it again
of course boil that oil he also does
hits from the nail and tax blah hash
hash related music I love to listen to
some tasks and take some dads or get
dabbed out and drive around and listen
to some tasks away I did not like they
didn't say that hypothetically I would
like to get dabbed out and driver as a
passenger and listen to tasks
[ __ ] tasks Rock is also the founder
proprietor this the dude for a
highly-educated titanium that's task
rock a lot of the times if you go to a
cannabis cup event in California
Colorado
those are probably the ones he goes to
if you go to those Cannabis Cup events
and you go to the highly educated booth
to purchase some highly educated
products you were probably going to pay
your money to task rock directly he will
be the dude there that helps ya so task
is integral in the 7:10 community
integral in the 7:10 movement he's been
a big part of it since the beginning
he's a huge supporter shot at the task
has made up the number 7/10 not the
number but the phrase 7:10 and that mic
stands kind of it might need a little
bit I just might get droopy we had a
quick equipment they might be done you
might just have to hold it you might
need another we're in it just give it a
minute give it a Gatorade and I got your
buddy just give it a rest it'll be all
right just don't talk about it all right
oh boy task Rock 710 is a new 4:20 shot
at the animal without task rock I don't
know and Big D is the person that gave
me my very first dab so I want to give a
shout out to Big D at the time he was
with Broadway wellness he moved on to be
top shelf extracts Big D moved on to be
the founder and proprietor of the secret
cup not the secret session the secret
cup the one with the dragon in the logo
the first hash competition I think I
ever attended I ever heard about yeah
yeah so I think task
I think Big D I think Adam Hill the guys
from health stone glass and of course
I'm gonna give a little bit of credit to
hitman glass dougie because he does make
the rigs that a lot of us are purchasing
and smoking and hash through so a lot of
those guys are pioneers of the industry
old-school folks in Colorado ah and the
hash movement Spence did a lot I want to
give a huge shout out to Spence in the
garden weed and Cru kind bill that whole
crew they did a lot in the hash but
honestly we all owe a huge high-five -
Derrick Cummings [ __ ] Derrick that dude
did so much for hash I know that's why
it's an inside joke but hash tag [ __ ]
Derrick just kind of an inside joke with
all of his friends but Derrick did a lot
for learning about hash Derrick did a
lot of research and learned a whole lot
of [ __ ] and then of course there's Tony
V there's a whole bunch of guys doing
stuff for hash in Terps
but shad it's all the people that helped
get 7-10 popular originated that [ __ ]
task rock we're gonna play task rock get
the
shows the the original people Diesel's
many people involved in keeping it as
what it is today um it's been fun to
watch it grow it goes so rapidly but now
that it's legal that we can do whatever
we want with this the equipment the
products have just every couple months I
got to go buy all-new [ __ ] just to have
what I need to have what to be on top of
things it's like any other tech right
now every six months
it evolves two to three times faster and
more effective than it was before the
Terps will avail themselves every part
of the legal marijuana industry which is
fun to watch we got a huge variety
products about a year and a half ago
they're all getting really really really
good now um it's just so much fun to see
you guys gotta legalize it where you
live
remember when I was like the only one
that had little jars of Terps on the
table you probably for a while there's a
lot of people out there now they're
available at a lot of shops eating them
up eating them up it's I really it's a
whole new thing I really love it
a lot of people are probably like with
the [ __ ] Terps ah are the compounds
that mainly provide the flavor and aroma
to your cannabis and or cannabis
concentrates they are they're part of
the flavor the Paley it's and the esters
have a lot to do with the flavor the
flavonoids have a lot to do with the
flavor obviously but the terpenoids are
mainly what play the part of the flavor
that work on your tongue that's mostly
the part that you get they also
contribute to your high I think that the
OG Kush one makes me a little more
mellow it gives me a body thing it kind
of makes my body go won't won't won't
won't won't and the ghost train haze
makes my head go like I just dabbed a
[ __ ] bottle rocket well essentially
that's what separates indica from sativa
is what you've refined into that tiny
little jar it's everything around the
THC there's there's some other stuff
that goes into that but yeah it's it if
you had to describe somebody to somebody
you had to show them strongly this is
the difference between indica and sativa
that would definitely be a good way to
do it just take that the
to drive as a heavy sativa was a heavy
annika oh you're way too high watch try
this one just put him to bed with the OG
Kush know if their problem was I'm Way
too high I wouldn't give them another
dad no I'd give them a dab of silly CB
have ya some CBD
cherry flavor but alright all this talk
about dads has got me wanna dad so I've
got some of this mob boss shatter and
I've dumped it into some ghost train
haze Terps you can see the Terps on the
tip of the dab it just looks like a
little wet spot on there I'm gonna take
a dad hey Mike I tell all of our
listeners how they can find you on
social media and make sure you include
your Facebook group you can catch me at
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook or add name upon 15 on Twitter
and that dad was massive he's gonna turn
colors right now it's gonna be beautiful
you can turn colors without choking I
see now he's pasty white now he's going
to red it's a proper set purple here in
a couple seconds of feeling oh it tastes
amazing it's just like heaven I've
always described haze strains and the
ghost train haze is really it definitely
stands out for what I'm talking about
there's like a velvet thing that happens
on your tongue it just feels like like
you know when you smell while Acts or
lavender if there's that specific thing
there's I it almost has a similar
coating like that that happens but it's
more enjoyable to me because I [ __ ]
hate lilacs and lavender I don't like
the smell that [ __ ] makes my nose feel
like I got particles in my nose yes I
like lavender what I'm surprised with it
like if we check into a hotel off just
get up to the room and it's all over
drives me [ __ ] nuts yeah there's
probably worth [ __ ] in that hotel rooms
in that lab in there bro no I know but
it's still avender that I've like choked
on and can feel in my mouth for like the
next hour like it's it definitely has a
coating I I don't know maybe we're just
equally high alright
shout out to 7/10 shot at the task
there's something else I want to talk
about on this episode that is not really
dabbe related not really 710 related but
it needs to be mentioned amendment 139
current event pom pom pom
there was a group I don't know exactly
who put this petition out there was a
group that was petitioning to limit all
cannabis products to 16 percent THC
that's right the buds that we grow at
the agreement healthy wellness this
should test anywhere from 20 to 30
percent THC nothing is lower than 22 I
wouldn't guess the average THC content
in Colorado's 18 really who the [ __ ] is
growing that [ __ ] no there's actually a
pretty solid demand for stuff that's
between like 12 and 16 percent people
that retired after 35 hours doing [ __ ]
they were drug tested for they really
don't want our our moonshine potency
weed they freak out when they try to
roll join up and smoke it like they did
back and put that [ __ ] around but they
did they like the whole like pass it
back and forth with you there why for a
while I have a friend who rents yes so
they they like stuff that they can smoke
on a list have it burn and what he's
writing yeah so there is a call for that
but the average is is 18 and so the
estimates are that this should have shut
down 80 percent of the industry as we
know right now I wouldn't want it I
would move to a place where I could grow
high quality cannabis well know
immediately all conscience rates gone
most of the edibles gone most of the
strains we could've gone most of the
vapor cartridges gone like what's the
point of a vapor cart
that's 16 percent that would feel the
black-market
so well yep and that's the design is the
people that were behind it wanted it to
kill the industry they know that a
public vote to and amendment 64
statewide would die laughably and so
this was their more reasonable attempt
to give voters to go along with gutting
the industry so there were three parts
to this they were gonna add childproof
packaging which we already do they
wanted us to add a health warning that
said this root causes like a reparable
brain damage or some [ __ ] look that we
already do health warnings that are
reasonable
we're willing to add more reasonable
health warnings but we're not really
glad some random [ __ ] did you just
thought up and then it was gonna limit
potency to 16% the group behind this
claims they have 80% of the public
support on this but what public where
that they won't tell you but they're
pretty sure didn't didn't ask any dad
kids
I think it's 80% of the people at the
last anti-pot meeting yeah
but 80% of the people in Parker that's
just from shout out to my hometown they
they really really want hate marijuana
and they wanted to shut us down this way
they claim they have a huge amount of
support which is nonsense they they
withdrew their effort today they they
essentially said they'd give a stop
trying and the reason they stopped
trying is kind of funny they claimed
that the group of marijuana industry
supporters and businesses that form to
oppose this effort called up all of the
petitions signature-gathering companies
in Colorado that are good at what they
do and can actually get a statewide
ballot effort on the signatures
collected because it's like a hundred
thousand or 98 thousand signatures it's
a lot there are companies in Colorado
they can definitely get that done for
you apparently they all got a phone call
from the Marijuana people like we're
gonna hire you for this here's what you
gotta do nothing go ahead and Bill us
and just hung up the phone and they
raised enough money to apparently make
that offer to the two biggest companies
the three biggest companies in Colorado
and on the off chance the anti pop
people tried to hire all three they were
prepared to pay all three to do nothing
and so the anti pop people were like
wolf we have [ __ ] do this ourselves
let's go ahead and not do it nice which
makes me laugh especially when they're
like well we have at eighty percent
support of the public oh my god then
it's so easy you just they kind of
played old-school drug dealer tactics
though I like that you just pop it up on
Facebook and you say hey community that
support
this so much we need all of you to grab
a signature and take it to work the next
day and say hey sign this the 80% of put
it's just such nonsense
yeah they didn't have 80% you know and
then they claimed that the marijuana
industry raised tens and millions of
millions of dollars to do this and the
digits public all you have to do is know
where to Google and you can check how
much they raise it's like for sad part
is that if you hand in a petition to
most people and you're like hey would
you like to limit the THC in cannabis to
16% I don't even [ __ ] that mean sure no
they decide like stop bugging me it's
ringing that [ __ ] Bell if I sign this
yep yeah that's sucks that people are
just willing to sign [ __ ] too without
even knowing what they're talking about
well and by law you have to print the
actual language that you're asking
people to sign for across the top of the
sheet they sign it can't be a separate
page or nothing like it's there's a lot
of rules a lot of them we've we've
discussed this before on the show a lot
of people that Walmart are in their
pajamas well no even and you're when
you're out really collecting this stuff
and trying to get people to give a [ __ ]
no one reads it yeah they're just a
[ __ ] hurry they want to sign it get
you the hell out of there are you a
resident you live in the county eighteen
sign here son here yeah that's pretty
much what you get all right so that [ __ ]
got dropped it did not pass you guys
they because you know the group behind
it is has pledged to reform as a broader
coalition of people uniting to [ __ ] over
the marijuana industry
it just sounds like a whole bunch of
[ __ ] bunch of big words that there's
a lawyer type for them the funny part is
is a big part of their press release
today they're like well this former high
school principal who was who was behind
this said this and this this the local
parent who's behind the other person
behind this said this and I'm sitting
there reading a press release from a
major anti marijuana personality in
Oregon and the press release talks about
major funding from a national anti
marijuana group and then if you keep
reading the article it talks about the
actual people behind the initiative who
are
these local lovable characters like a
teacher and a parent
their major politicians from around the
country who make a living doing stuff
like this but they're able to portrayed
is like oh there's there's just these
little folks being picked on by big
industry marijuana that's like do you
threatened a billion-dollar industry and
they raised 300 grand to knock you out
of the fight like come on now so you
just gave me a perfect segue before we
start wrapping up the show give me an
update on what is going on with the
effort to eliminate and/or eradicate
recreational cannabis from Pueblo County
ok so locally our petition effort has
been significantly more successful than
the one statewide I there have all their
signatures turned in it looks like
they've got more than enough valid
signatures to make the ballot there's
two questions in front of the courts
right now the first question is how many
signatures they should have collected
they collected 5% of the voter
signatures from that last election down
here which was like 5,000 signatures
they collected 9,000 almost and so
they're covered there if it's 5% but
recently a bill was passed at the state
level requiring this specific question
if it's going to be put on a ballot
anywhere to have 15% of passed voter
signatures which would Jack that number
to around 14 or 15,000 which means they
don't have near enough signatures
gathered and they need to get back out
there and gather signatures that
decision should come any day now well
it's Friday when we're recording this
it'll be Sunday when it comes out so
it'll probably be within four or five
days of this coming out when we get that
decision hopefully maybe as many as 15
but if your roster said this will be
Monday because he's from the future mace
but hopefully within seven or ten days
we get we get that first decision about
how what what percentage of the vote
they should have gathered odds are
strong that the judge is gonna rule that
5% is fine
recently we had a local politician make
a primary ballot and the it ended up in
front of the same judge and the judge's
ruling was yes he failed to follow the
law here and here yes he broke that rule
there but elections are about choices
and why not give you guys him as one of
those choices and a lot of people were
like wait what really but kinda I guess
like the judge gets to make the rules
that's why they wear the outfit it's why
they have the job so let them make them
and that was the decision they made so
we're kind of expecting the same thing
here there's another court issue that
involves some serious campaign finance
stuff that could really keep them off
about Colorado and pretty much every
state in the Union has very serious laws
that govern their elections when you
would like to put something on an
official election ballot there are rules
you must follow the anti marijuana
people down here are terrible at
following rules
it's a very fun character trait for them
to have if you're me so as soon as they
said they were running a public ballot I
was hoping for well like with nothing
complicated there's a lot of important
in ins and outs and if you can't handle
a licensing hearing at the county level
running a countywide ballot issue is
probably gonna trip you up and it looks
like it has one of the things is you
can't raise money in a jar at a
fundraiser that's not a thing in
politics if this donations over $20 I
gotta get your name I got your serial
number and that's just how elections go
the money is tracked like that unless
you're super rich and by which case you
didn't but you can donate hundreds of
millions of dollars to a company to run
evil attack ads and [ __ ] and that's fine
but if you're a little guy trying to
give twenty four dollars you got to give
me your name it's your serial number you
can't just throw
on the piano and at the end of the night
have three hundred or a thousand bucks
in there and call it good enough so they
did that twice and then there's major
polling that they've bragged about and
most people don't understand what what
kind of money's involved when you're you
when you poll people in a county like
Pueblo we're not a big County there's
only a hundred fifty thousand people
down here a poll like that still costs
ten fifteen twenty twenty-five thousand
dollars the good ones cost twenty-five
thirty-five forty thousand dollars the
ones that'll really give you the
information you want are expensive they
did one of these they paid for one of
these we know all about it and for some
reason I'm lying about it that's gonna
play out really interestingly in court
do we have access to the truth on those
surveys we we don't know what the
results they got back but we know they
bragged about them enough to the local
hospitals for the local hospitals to put
literature together that involved heard
that referenced this the polling done we
know who did the poll we know who paid
for the poll we know who probably got
handed the check that paid for the poll
we know who probably cashed it it's
disturbing that they're lying about it
all I had to do is put it on the
campaign finance report and nobody gives
you [ __ ] but they didn't and then they
keep claiming to the press that they
didn't and eventually the judge is gonna
want to know why and that's an issue
that could keep him off the ballot -
same thing with the money in the jars
that's a big enough screw up to keep you
off the ballot um if you want to make
law you got to follow law it's really
that simple did they hire a lawyer they
did it's their main volunteer he's
donated like ten or twelve thousand
dollars worth of lawyer hours to their
effort it's like six hours I have no
idea what he charges but that's on that
campaign finance reports well okay I've
spent it a disturbing amount of time
going through those reports um it's fun
to work on campaigns I'm sure they look
on your face when you talk about it's
great it's it's fun it's I mean it's
very could very well could be the death
of webelo like yeah yeah really can't
handle the loss this would be to our
community we were on the edge for a
while parts of town are still very very
bad crime is a huge problem
infrastructure spending is a huge
problem if we lose 60% of our
construction industry 1300 marijuana
jobs all of the expansion that industry
is supposed to go through over the next
several years all of that real estate
floods back on the market like that's a
death blow all those people that moved
here because somebody like myself had a
job and was like I need a helper and I
got somebody that I know in another
state that I trust brought them out here
those people and myself would be [ __ ]
you'd be [ __ ] well there's a huge note
where people weren't five people that
moved here within the last year yeah how
many people are employed by the spot
like 3035 yeah that's one dispensary how
many of them are there in Pueblo West
hundred licenses it's 1,300 people it's
it literally if this vote passes
thirteen other people are out of work
it's a full 1% of our population down
here you add that immediately to the
unemployment rolls and then you compound
that with all of it's not like I got
fired for stealing its thirteen hundred
people got put out of a work as an
industry closed we no one gets to apply
for the job I just lost all of us are
now applying for whatever jobs we're
currently available when our industry
shut down what percentage of those
people go home and buy a bunch of
[ __ ] lights with their first
unemployment check and build a black
market grow and start flipping a black
market weed
well that's I mean I figure half of what
we do about twenty million in annual
sales down here I figure half of that
immediately goes back into the black
market and the other half goes either up
the highway to Colorado Springs or down
the how to turn at the tourist money
goes to Trinidad and manna to the
medical money goes to Colorado Springs
everybody who doesn't feel like that's
effort worth putting in for a bag of
weed just goes back to the black market
yeah just put some seeds in the dirt in
the basement some lights on that [ __ ]
we lose out on five million in tax
revenue
like that's paying for all kinds of cool
[ __ ] that wasn't getting paid for before
because we didn't have the money the
city's starting to look decent it's
clean it's getting cleaned up the
potholes are going away it's nothing
little by little she's getting more man
I noticed it the last street I Drive on
on my way to your place it's really just
got repaid yeah they just repaving the
whole street in Jackson's I've known
about Pueblo yep
that whole Boulevard it's been quite hot
for potholes if it's working it really
does work it's just little by little it
takes a minute people are like why has
why are our schools perfect we've had
legal weed for two years why aren't all
our streets perfect it's been two years
I just thanks a minute do you have any
info on the scholarship that was awarded
to the child she and the Prophet doubled
it boom um like if I was king of the
world the scholarship would be bigger
and spendable in more places but it's
still really awesome dude we're sending
25 kids to college that probably
wouldn't be able to go without that two
grand explain a little bit how that
happened to people that have hooked up
at all our county commissioners we
passed the voters passed the local
excise tax so all of the production when
you grow marijuana and then sell it to a
retail store it gets taxed at that point
and that money goes into kind of a slush
fund for dream projects we couldn't pay
for it before we paid when I grow the
flowers it green and healthy wellness I
have to they have to be packaged and
then transferred to the store yep that's
where the tax happens yep okay if it was
in Pueblo County that's where the tax
would happen okay Aram when Colorado
Springs passes an excise tax on medical
event it'll happen there okay but we
already did that down here for rec and
so that's gonna be this is the first
year that tax has been in effect so
money's just starting to trickle in but
we expect three and a half million
dollars from that excise tax this year
and that's the bulk of the marijuana
taxes that Pueblo County is gonna make
next year we get three point five from
the excise tax ish it's an estimate so
far we'll see what how it actually plans
out and then we're definitely gonna get
1.7 1.8 in licensing fees and sales
yeah if the industry exists if it will
know that's that's through the end of
this year so even if the election goes
against this in November we still get to
operate until next November all right it
was sort of your licenses can expire as
it comes comes up for expiration until
November 2017 so the shop that gets
their license in like November the 1st
of this year is in is in the best shape
to operate as long as possible
regardless of the election outcome
hopefully that made sense yeah yet it's
just a deathblow to us it's we're doing
so much with it's not a lot compared to
our whole county budget but the problem
with our County budget is that it passed
its breaking point a couple million
dollars ago and we just have to look at
middle school kids walking in the middle
of the street with the buses in the car
traffic can go sorry
no money for sidewalks or crossing
guards or crossing guard books yeah like
all kinds of stuff there's we took
asbestos out of a couple of schools and
I read that in the newspaper and I was
like asbestos in schools it's [ __ ]
2016 oh it's hurting my face ow
think about it no that was way down in
San Juan County because that's how we're
spending that the state also collects an
excise tax in the first 40 million from
that fund goes to school construction
through our state's best program and the
best program literally when you apply
for it you explain how your school
districts broke how they've never had
money since the 40s and how you badly
need to do stuff that should have been
done 30 years ago which you've never
found a way to pay for and so they're
doing stuff like I'm taking the lad out
of the pipes taking the asbestos out of
the gym putting pads in the playground
yeah like or building a playground
period paving the road to it all kinds
of crazy stuff that we really should
have done decades ago but just never had
the money and we were never gonna have
it
and the now we can fund it with weed
money because it's just enough more than
what we need to do everything else that
wasn't getting funded the Lupus
background of the scholarships so sorry
the scholarships they gave each kid that
wanted up to 400 kids a thousand bucks
400 kids got a thousand bucks well that
was the offer only 25 ended up applying
okay um part of the reason for that is
you have to be a Pueblo high school
graduate and we had way more than 25 of
those dicks and thinking that but you
had to go to college in Pueblo County so
yeah if I was king the world would be at
least anywhere in Colorado right cuz
Nebraska Oni my [ __ ] they just want to
keep the money in the cow dad they just
wanted to keep it in the county they
wanted to promote the local university
and there's a lot of cool things
happening down here at our local
university so when I keep it on a good
music program a good math program but I
don't know about the governor like the
program so much he he used state
marijuana taxes to double it to 2 grand
and I mean honestly that's books for a
whole year
that's meals for for most of a whole
year for happier well depends you well
know I was a college student so some of
these numbers aren't real unrealistic
that might just be a decade old sorry
but uh I mean $2,000 down here in Pueblo
that's fully the difference between I'm
able to go and I'm not able to go yeah
and honestly if $2,000 is gonna really
make or break that difference like
College in New York or wherever else I'd
be happy to send you with that 2 grand
probably wasn't a make or break anyway
right like it requires a lot more to
live out of state than it does in your
hometown yeah you'd still stay with the
fam oh for sure like that was a huge
amount of a huge huge amount yeah but
it's a fantastic program and the
anti-pop you are all over it they like
this is just propaganda it's like it's
real sure that more kids get to go to
college it's a propaganda when that kid
goes to college how was that propaganda
like some real [ __ ] one of the things
people won't refuse to accept is that
marijuana was always here in a way
that's so much larger than any
one really wants to admit I mean it's 60
billion coast-to-coast six zero billion
I mean that's a huge amount of money I
don't think anybody can fathom that much
cash it's I mean yeah in 20 our bills
it's a couple of high schools full
probably I don't know but it's an insane
amount of big pools just and off
hundreds it's all just under the surface
it's your neighbor's house it's the park
your kids play at it's the school your
kids go to it's even the [ __ ] prisons
like prohibition doesn't work at all
it's right under our noses it's always
has been it always will be
it's just mostly invisible the only
people who are able to be visible with
it are the people with nothing to lose
and no one's willing to admit that in
Colorado anymore everybody's like it's
new especially the anti-pop people and
all we did was shift where people buy it
and we're able to do so many cool things
with that money
yeah industry now we can make Terps cuz
now we got science to be afraid to go if
you get caught buying the equipment that
it takes to make these Terps at the
store they turn you in for making a
[ __ ] meth lab back in the day and I
can be like no we're with this
dispensary and we need all this
equipment to make hash and now you can
do that we can more effectively treat
patients everyone forgets about the
patients we're all about getting Turkish
penned the first 20 minutes with a new
big fat bag of weed looking for mole
looking for mildew looking for washers
spine rigs all kinds of nasty funks yeah
I've got toenails and Syd they're
breaking up bud and have a bug crawl out
of the noggin up your arm like it was me
that [ __ ] we used to put up with and the
fact that it's all gone now
like there did this the benefits stream
just it's endless it's so far past the
money but for a place like Pueblo the
money's vital does south of town even
smaller the sheriff was in the paper
like it wasn't sure what to think at
first now I love it look what it's done
to the downtown area yeah yeah they
built a Riverwalk down there because of
cannabis money yep there
Trinidad's not gonna die now you
it was we had steel here yep and steel
isn't as big as it used to be people
want to go lightweight now so it's
titanium and we don't have a titanium
mill we have a steel mill and so people
were leaving and people don't want to
work at a steel mill forever now it's
kind of the technology era people are
getting the [ __ ] out of here
Stan was going bad I've lived here for a
long time Mike and I have been here we
were here before all the cannabis [ __ ]
happened him and I have seen this town
it was kind of a little little cow town
when I moved here it was flourishing
like it's actually going somewhere now
I'm kind of proud we're finally crawling
out of the funk we were in for like 40
years
Wow the flood [ __ ] us up I mean
honestly it was when the steel mill
started to slow down a whole huge
generation of people didn't have an easy
way to feed their families down here it
wasn't easy to find work anymore um you
really had to work at it when I moved
here you had to know somebody that was
hiring yeah period that's how this town
is this is one of those towns where you
can fill out a thousand applications and
unless you know somebody here you're not
gonna get a job
most of the the job and housing listings
never make it online here it's you drive
up and down the streets you want to live
on and look for someone putting out a
for rent sign and walk up and talk to
that person before it's it's out there
too long it's the same thing with jobs
you heard a friend of yours got fired
wandering to wherever they used to work
and talk to the manager stat um cuz
otherwise there ain't no job for you in
the city and that's slowly changing now
we have hiring a terse staffing agencies
now that that help people get a foothold
in the marijuana industry we have an
industry down here that's gonna need a
hundred more trimmers next year shadow
to lioness did the real downside is that
we're not publicizing in all 50 states
what it takes to work in this industry
but people think that they can show up
late and take a [ __ ] be 20 minutes late
and hang out I talked to people every
day that are shocked to learn it's like
a real business yeah they think you
could just hang out smoke joints all day
and [ __ ] off and like they thought their
high school weed dealer had a store now
where he just kind of like hung out and
played xbox and this totally would lead
at his table
and then you gave him money and it was
weird and then they'd leave and they
walk in and they see what looks
basically like an apple store or a purse
or shoe store in the mall if you just
gave me a chance to tease something that
we're gonna talk about on a future
episode I want to wait until you and
Lyndsey are here we're gonna talk about
the weirdest [ __ ] that people have ever
done in a dispensary I was asked to do
that episode to you by someone at work
who listened to the dispensary etiquette
episode oh nice nice we're gonna talk
about that when lens is available
Lynne's just got back from a little
vacation and she took the night off she
invited but she needed a nappy poo
so she's cuddle up with scooby-doo the
dog what up Scoob
what's up scoob's good boy shelter that
air conditioner over there but uh we're
gonna get lens on and we're gonna talk
about some weird [ __ ] that's happened in
dispensaries I've got a pretty good
store to myself two dispensers are
awesome this it's a really magical place
where but Bananarama [ __ ] happens on the
regular still remember we had a store
way back in the wild [ __ ] West days
so the crazy we gotta save those stories
I'm so excited and a cheesy aspirin on
my face cuz we ran the place before you
like you could get a weave really my leg
hurts I need weed card and they'd say
how much money you got and he'd tell
them they'd write you that many plants
like here you go have a great [ __ ]
day they didn't even care back then like
weed card for sale well that was the in
the very first days like even the
doctors were at the the fringe of
society because the DEA was still
threatening that if a doctor wrote a
recommendation for marijuana in Colorado
that they could lose their DEA license
to write prescriptions for anything any
other drug and so the doctors that were
like the first five doctors in Colorado
to sign paperwork period were the kind
of doctors where like if you were there
because you fell on something and it
went through like your forearm or your
leg you start talking to him and after
15 or some minutes or so you'd be like
you know what
don't doc I'm just gonna the next doc up
the road sorry look I don't care that
I've been paid for something that's not
gonna kill me immediately yeah but that
changed six months later when they
stopped counting doctors
that weird ass dock that used to come to
ponytail yeah with the ponytail no that
was the husband a husband had a ponytail
in a cane the doctor was the woman who
wouldn't look you in the eye
oh no I'm talking about the crazy guy in
the crazy wife they used to come
together yeah okay is that okay yeah
well see I was working in a dispensary
the lady that owned that dispense were
used to bake edibles and she would show
up with trays of edibles and she'd be
like Mike and Jeff you have to drag some
of those days around this carrot cake
this [ __ ] banana bread there's the
nine products I make here's your nine
samples and then you restock the shelves
with the rest the five minutes later
should go which one did you eat it's
11:00 a.m. on us at work and she would
go which one are you gonna eat right now
in front of me yeah she didn't give a
[ __ ] she'd stare at you and then look at
the pile of options you had really
curious as to what you might fake
totally oblivious that you took this a
little more seriously than she did or
you're not interested in finding out how
strong she made him this week at 11:00
a.m. and 15 minutes after you ate the
first one she'd ask you what the next
one's gonna be yeah and there are some
days where I don't know how we made it
through clothes there were some times
when the numbers were a little bit off
there were some days I wasn't sure
people were keeping numbers yeah so I'm
pretty sure there were some eight gram
quarters going out the door sometimes
like there was a window that we had to
stay within between and we just kind of
kept it from going too far outside of
that little box shout out to Karen and
her homemade edibles Josh and I fell
down the stairs like laughing like
ladies
I remember that walk you have three
flights of stairs and ridiculous heat
because it got really hot in that
building and I'd get to the third floor
knowing that that was where I needed to
go and have no idea why was it and I get
halfway back downstairs before I
remembered whatever it was I went up for
that place was fun speaking of edibles
I'm pretty sure I mentioned eating a
1000 milligram Josh excuse me for that a
1000 bucks guys I don't recommend it
don't eat a thousand milligram animal
unless you want to be [ __ ] up for a
day and a half if you're not me probably
three days I think like a civilian if
you gave that to like right
well not the OD else that we know that
doesn't the hundred milligram edible if
people get novices gobble that sucker up
six eight hours is what people report
it's just you ate the hundred milligram
just talking about a 1000 yeah a
thousand miserable honest I haven't been
I've been gun-shy / I haven't eaten
inedible since then I've been a little
bit happens I did it to myself the other
day
it wasn't even with a really big dose I
just I popped a couple I thought I'd be
comfortable with it we got to the movie
theater I looked up and was just pluck
there were so many food choices and
before I could figure out what I wanted
I heard my wife giggling next to me like
she's not a smoker but she knows when I
look up and I'm just too big to pick
from the menu and I didn't mean to do it
it was an accident um so what happens to
the pros - but yeah thousand milligrams
those were off on my system it [ __ ] me
up my whole body felt weird for a day
and a half people assume that that's
like the comfortable intro to some
marijuana consumption and it's not like
smokings the the time-tested smoked some
flowers through a pipe so explorers
through a bong or a joint get used to
that
take a DAB one day they're like three
dads in one day and then start taking
big dabs and then dab every day and then
eat some edibles progressed slow because
the expensive bit did well yeah
Rick junkie I like a good rag I did as
long as you can do you can you can look
people in the eye and say I don't eject
what I'm addicted to I just buy glass
it's not the same different kind of
glass just rig after rig after rig it's
such a beautiful face my friends at
elevate glass 517 South stay home if you
need a break you need illegal eyes in
your air make your table look like -
glass rinks everywhere you just want you
want to hear this kind of [ __ ] slick all
over the place oil slick it's a shout
out hey it's table cover mics give a
shot it's time to wrap up the show yes
the TV is covered in oil about to give
away some again
we can't do that who wants this old shoe
that matches with what you just said
that I said some [ __ ] today ladies and
gentlemen thanks for listening to the
podcast Mike thanks for Mike's wife
thanks rillette might come and hang out
he did an hour and 15 minutes the phone
a couple of times you can reach over and
check it out and see who it is I'll turn
off your mic in a second by myself make
sure you guys check out Mike's Facebook
group make sure you follow Mike on to
winter I almost said tinder make sure
you follow tendo don't do it on tinder
you'll get in trouble
Mike's a married man the new baby is not
on tinder don't do that good luck on
tinder whatever you're doing out there
as make sure you go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search the girl from your
heart podcast buy in the review section
type in a little review let me know you
think about on the show what you think
about of the show sure do that let me
know what you think about of the show
[ __ ] I'm going with it let me know
what you think give me a little star
rating I will read your comment on a
future episode it's always fun to hear
what the people want to think I would
love it if you'd support me on social
media
Mike's laughs and I'm gonna turn him
down bro you get to be you get to be
over there we were spot-on and now
you're stumbling over like catchphrases
let's do the program [ __ ] so it's making
it hard if we get to sober it could be
it that could be and I took a fat nap go
to go follow me you guys go follow me on
all the social media go to tit why do I
want to say tinder follow me on tinder
[ __ ] it do that too
I'll go check me on Twitter it's a it's
a totally different app don't do that
I'm not on there you can't find me it's
at GFY age podcast on twitter with the
dev you that's way better check us out
on Facebook it's the girl from your art
podcast go to Instagram and check out
i reaiiy rie ireon Durst or genetics I
read genetics is my seed company that's
where I post all the pictures of my
cannabis photography the other day I
post a picture of a butterfly had just
to get a little bit of variety on my
page but I usually post a whole bunch of
good cannabis photography big bud shots
big room shots trichome shots I like to
post a great whole bunch of great [ __ ]
so check that out
I think that's all I've got for if you
want to sponsor the show if you've got a
product you'd like us to review you
could send us your product and we will
unbox it live on the show and Mike and I
will check it out we will talk about
what we think of it we will follow the
instructions if it needs to be charged
up fired up primed lubed but whatever
you need it done first before we can use
it we'll do that we'll follow the
instructions we use your product
properly and we'll review and thoroughly
on the show with all those words well
had to go with words needed to be
descriptive words and they're quickly
off the top of my head that's the truth
we'll play through to this got dirty
quickly you can email me it's girl from
your heart at hotmail.com I'd love to
hear from you love to check out your
products I think that's all I've got for
you this week
shout out to dead and until next time
[Music]
you