[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 143 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right here a new
grower for a professional grower through
a new smoker or a dedicated jammer if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta jeboa
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out my friends in the mystic roots
band to letting me use their music on my
podcast big shout out to Kat coop the
entire mystic roots crew I've ever
really had a great 710 hope everybody
enjoyed the sunday episode you guys on
this episode I am joined by Jesse grows
from the Colorado podcast that we talked
a whole bunch about outdoor growing we
talked of a whole bunch of random stuff
the episode was an hour and 20 minutes
long so I'm not gonna waste too much
time here at the start of the show I'm
gonna let the music play and in just a
second I'll be right back with Jesse
grows hang out with us
[Music]
wait say that again is that a real thing
gunpowder Terps gunpowder tur what does
that mean
government meal smells like fireworks I
was kind of confused by that statement I
was like gunpowder what's happening now
ladies and gentlemen welcome back to the
podcast I said I'd be right back with
our friend Jesse and guess what
there he is welcome to show brother
Thank You Man let's tell everybody about
your social media so that they can stalk
you all they're listening where can they
find you online Instagram Jessie gross
Jessie grows whatever Jessie grows on
Instagram so I post a couple pics a week
they're glorious cannabis photography I
think those are very similar things yeah
I'll give the website yeah we've got a I
do
Colorado podcast we are now on stitcher
we're also on soundcloud and we're also
on our own website at Colorado podcast
Arco make sure you guys support the
Colorado podcast and my friend Jesse is
pickable D and our boy 44 guy that's all
those guys it's its podcast do the it's
loosely cannabis-based we get around to
talking about weed every now and then
wacky wild adventures for the most part
yes yes it's a podcast so if your
podcast had a haircut it would certainly
have your mic may jump out of that
little clip if you have it like cool
welcome to the show thanks for joining
us make sure you guys support his
podcast you guys so uh Jesse is kind of
an outdoors role expert he's been on the
show several times if people listen he
knows a lot about outdoor growing I know
a lot about indoor growing so we had
some outdoor questions Jesse wants to
talk a little bit about the differences
in small like basement cultivation
compared to large commercial grow so
we'll get into that also but let's talk
about an email I got I got an email from
a listener I don't have the email on my
phone right now I just set the phone
aside today a shout out to the guy that
sent me an email he asked when he's
growing outdoors how big of a hole does
he want a big to put his plant uh I told
him through an email I told him to
listen to show and I'd have Jesse on for
more info but I told him basically make
the hole big as you can what else can
you tell us about that Jesse
I personally over the years I've noticed
a fence somewhat limited especially when
it's in the ground by the size of its
container
and even emailing the grounds each
container but your hole has a premix oil
in it the shoulders of the plants aren't
going to go too far past the edge of
that hole
I started off with two by two bowls and
worked up to three by three bowls and I
do 4x4 goes probably keep going some day
five by five when you're doing these
four by four old isn't a four by four
square right yes four feet wide four
feet long just how deep are you going 18
inches it used to go deeper I've learned
a little bit more about music since - a
cannabis am I right in thinking that
cannabis wants to reach outward instead
of downward for the most part okay
I mean it does like to go down
especially for going to get the
temperature oh yeah go go go go hard
extraordinary
[Music]
but for the most part clumps you know
we're gonna reach a lenders to the sides
and stick a note on that' free by screen
by 18 inch three foot by three foot
holes that's 18 inches deep
is $99 of dirt that is a lot of hand
dirt see how many cubic feet that is
well we'd have to do the math on the
size of the hole that you just said
right is one of those Fox farm bags is
1.75 cubic feet how many of those bags
you think you could take a cube okay
this is how gorillas think in math you
guys alright that's that's a lot of root
space yeah how big are these plants that
in your example how big are your plants
at the end of the season four or five
foot around I mean all the way around
you know not just through one spot yeah
so you can't hug your plants you can't
go around yeah oh hell no okay they do I
kind of limit my plants they can only
get about six foot tall
if that if I was able to let them get
bigger they'd probably end up eight nine
foot tall
okay so you limited my privacy yes
that's a [ __ ] yes you do such a great
outdoor grill any you as a [ __ ]
um I used to fight it real hard to keep
them down I have learned a new trick
just plant later plant later huh yeah is
that the new trick yeah super high-tech
yeah yeah you don't have to bend him as
much at the top as much just take them
out later she's lazy tech so uh when
what are we are we in the flowering
phase officially yet or do we still have
a few days to go I feel like we've still
got a week or so to go okay so in about
a week here in Colorado and we were
doing research before the show from
coast to coast there's only about a
half-hour in sunlight photoperiod in
natural photo period right now we're
talking about it jesse was doing the
research in in difference between what I
was finding it was like New York the Sun
was coming up at 5:30 9:00 in the
morning and in Los Angeles it was coming
up at like 608 or some [ __ ] so that's
odd
but yeah so but of photoperiod you know
it's it's gonna start really shrinking
from here on out and you know the first
you're gonna get your indica varieties
into flower and then you're more sativa
varieties will follow along behind yeah
your flow and blueberry those are really
gonna start taking off right flow so
yeah when in Colorado the gross blow
that [ __ ] is gonna go into flower real
hard here in about a week ten days
she'll be spitting out calyxes real soon
for you you'll love it you'll see
pistols in like 20 days I bet yeah all
right
plant later is such a ridiculous
solution for yeah yeah it's yeah all
right
that's been my my co lately it's just it
ki SS keep it so keep it simple stoner
yeah so the size of your plant sorry I
keep clearing the throat guys we're
taking some dad's let's talk about these
dabs for a brief second I was dunking my
dabber into ninety percent THC this is
91% THC it's distillate from our friends
at Evo lab and then I take the 90%
distillate that's on my dabber and i
dunk that into pure terpenoids of ghost
train haze also made by our friends at
Evo labs this is amazing you guys is one
of the best ties you can get the first
couple of times I smoked this I got
stupid high I was just goofy I tried to
go back to work and I pretty much just
ended up doing stuff on the computer for
the next hour cuz like yeah metric needs
to be updated somehow I gotta sit down
in a chair for a minute but I shot us to
the dabs that's what my throat's a
little bit clogged I do apologize for
being so congested today yeah those OD
Kosh tabs were heavenly yeah that's
delicious isn't it though I've got a
g-ghost train hey our ghost train Hayes
turps and OG Kush chirps and then a
couple nights ago I took some of this
120 micron blue sure fresh frozen psalm
Ellis hash and I rolled out a little
piece into a taco shell and I put some
what did I have it was a cactus cooler a
live resin on top of that I smeared that
on like taco sauce and then I took a
piece of Durbin hoisin Durbin poison
shatter and rolled it into a little
snake and put that in the middle like
some taco meat and then I put I dumped
the dabber into the ninety percent THC
distillate and had bad on the dabber and
then I picked up the taco with the
dabber and dunked of that into the ghost
train Hayes Terps
I was blast-off I was yeah my I put a
little th was making funny faces and
funny noises I was really high for a
little while my first turf dab buy arms
and legs went
very pleasantly numb late almost
immediately yeah there's something about
smoking just raw Terps yeah that's I
immediately I was like damn there's this
is medicine there for someone someone
here for me it's great recreation but
someone somewhere that's that's
something I I like to take just the
normal shatter I've got I've got this
Durbin poison mob-boss shatter and I
just take little chunks of that and dunk
that into the OG Kush babs and it makes
it taste so amazing right it's been a
while when this is gone I don't know if
I'm gonna be able to properly get high
anymore because I've been smoking this
distillate and these Terps so heavily
bit my tolerance game is up to itself
when I go smoke with other people
they're just like dude what the [ __ ] is
wrong with you and I'm like don't you
want more dabs and there in the corner
come on let's party um one more quick
question on that come on pink the Terps
I mean I think I already know the answer
to this but I'll just ask dude do the
Terps complete if you dip it in just
like a normal shatter do the Terps
complete something there or make it more
powerful in opinion it pushes it yeah it
pushes the high a little bit higher it
certainly pushes the high up
I think the my theory it's probably not
such a theory but the terpenoids
work along with the cannabinoids just
like the the entourage effect absolutely
absolutely
the terpenoids that we're using guys
that looks just like it looks like pee
it's just a little yeah drops a gold in
a vial it's got the consistency of like
a really high-grade
like a machine oil or something okay
yeah yeah it's gonna say really runny
olive oil a little little runny er than
olive oil maybe and you just dunk the
dab right into it is what i've been
doing i've been putting a dab on the
dabber and just dunk it and i did i
don't get too hard one time i just
dunked it in then gave it a little
swizzle and when it hit the veil I heard
that the Terps could like sizzled and I
had turf face like my mouth just tasted
like ghost train Hayes forever
it was almost unpleasant it was like I
Oh deed my face on turps but then I was
a Rockette hi
that's something else and it kind of you
can almost wash away the flavor with
with too like it's so overwhelming you
don't even get it you just burn yeah you
do maximum overload your mouth and it's
like I can't taste anything cuz you just
ruin my palate yeah it's like we need
something too spicy for the next hour
everything just tastes spicy
alright so to our friend that send us an
email about digging holes the bigger the
hole the bigger the plant jesse
recommends about a three by three four
by four about eighteen inches deep fill
it with the best soil that you can
afford put some amendments in there
um let's give them a list of five good
amendments to throw in there worm
castings oyster shell alfalfa choke mill
kelp meal neem seed mill neem seed meal
karanji seed meal that's six I'm gonna
throw in crab crab shower oyster or
shrimp shell No okay alright pretty much
sit there
there we go you guys I hope you wrote
that down if not hit that little
15-second back button twice and you did
it again write it down
put that stuff in that big hole with
your soil we put some perlite in there
yeah rifles rock yeah some sort of
drainage want to get some oxygen in
there but you don't want to take up too
much root space with a bunch of rock and
perlite so figure out your makes an
outdoor soil doesn't need to be as
area's indoor soil especially in the
ground so you can do yourself a great
disservice by putting too much perlite
in there it's just it's gonna increase
the frequency of half of the water okay
so let's see that's why you're the
outdoor pro and I'm the indoor all right
big shout out to my friend that sent me
the email keep the emails coming if you
have any more or follow-up questions let
me know we'll get up on the show for you
and mulch that soil up keep it mulched
they got makes a huge huge difference to
at the end of the season man it's
totally totally worth it we're gonna
talk about a bunch of stuff for outdoor
season I've got questions this year all
right so our friend Fred Fred Garvin hey
Freddy he keeps the messages coming I've
listens to the Colorado podcast that's
to both of our shows we're gonna have to
do more of the swap casts
yeah those are fun we'll duct tape Adam
next time shut it Adam what's up 45
movie bro I also love picking on you
look you're doing well so Fred sent us a
message while back he was making seeded
plants he had pollen he put pollen on
female plants those plants have now been
pollinated they're forming seeds he put
them outdoors
he had many questions about putting
putting them outdoors about acclimating
them to the outdoor area and how to get
this timer right once I message Jessi
about this Jessi had a great idea
Jessi said that once you once those
plants are pollinated if you go put them
outside and the light cycles a little
bit off they're not going to her because
they're already pollinated they've
pretty much passed there I guess if they
were humans now they would be in
menopause if they were females and now
they can't there pass to that cycle
their whole sexual reproductive thing is
done they've already decided they're
making seeds they they have a manifest
destiny to complete yes and if the girls
pregnant you can't already get her
pregnant you can't really like so that
that's those plants that we told Fred to
put outside should be 100% legit he also
mentioned in one of his emails that his
outdoor plants were in full flower so
yeah so shout out to Fred for sending me
messages dude I appreciate it I hope
you've got at least an eye region attic
sticker or something send me a message
grow from your heart at hotmail.com tell
me that it's you because I know that
that's not your real name bro come on I
know better than that
what's in the email we'll get you some
more stickers or something if you want
it we love all of your input to clear
that one out clear out that was
ridiculous I got a friend on Facebook
that uh heard her or his name I'm pretty
sure to her though is the last name the
first and last name is last names of
movie stars and I called her out on it
one time in a private message was like I
know your names fake how do you figure
that out and I was like well doves like
so and so so so it's
Oh nobody's who they say they are on
Facebook no but I use my real name I
like it like you got any think about
what you're posting you can't spend time
trolling people if you got your name and
face up there yeah
alright so Fred put his plants outdoor
outdoors they're not gonna hermaphrodite
on him I do not believe so he's gonna
have viable seeds if he waits long
enough yep yep I think he was he
actually pulled some of those seeds I
think I think he's got some of those a
lot of them were white but plenty of
them were viable and tiger stripes so
it's good work bro do you know what the
cross was I count I really don't
remember I don't remember honestly I
read so many emails and read so many
crosses that a lot of that share a lot
of the crosses in the green and healthy
wellness garden I can't remember what
they are off the top of my head I'm the
same way yeah I learned a few you know
what I mean as I go I'm like that one's
this one I remember that now and I just
absorbed those slowly alright so he's
got a splint outdoors they've got seeds
in him and since then his [ __ ] got
attacked by spider mites and he asked is
I don't have his email in front of me
but basically he said none of this plant
material is going to be consumed or
smoked by people since it's all just
seeded how nuclear can I go to spray the
[ __ ] out of it for these spider mites my
opinion would be as nuclear as he is
comfortable that's what I told him I
told him keep in mind his health while
he's applying pesticides and keep in
mind the health of the rest of his
garden cuz I know he's got other
cannabis plants out there and the
insects in that garden absolutely the
diversity of that area yeah be be aware
of that
bees oh don't kill the bees that's super
important if the bees zone away
everything goes away we don't have food
if we don't have bees I saw my dad's
neighbor spray and roundup in his yard
the other day how couldn't chase that
[ __ ] down I was like no I was like see
those three white boxes over there and
instantly he was like oh man I'm so
sorry
we got him set up with some Epsom salt
and vinegar there you go go organic yeah
yeah that'll get rid of almost any
insect its you don't want around yeah
several
spoons of Epsom salt per gallon can I
ask you about how to get rid of [ __ ]
grasshoppers right now in a ganja garden
outdoors yeah that is a very popular
question lately yeah they're super heavy
everywhere this here I my wife
Bernadette my life my life my beautiful
life she has a list of pesticides
I cannot require or recall any of them
and none of them knowing the way they
work and how grasshoppers work I felt
really weren't necessary I didn't I
didn't feel like he may kill one or two
grasshoppers with it or you may
discourage one or two but it's so my big
thing mow the weeds around your area
that's one of the biggest ones that take
away their food supply okay
molasses traps which is a mason jar that
is a quarter of the way filled with
water a quarter of the way filled with
molasses buried to the rim around the
plants I know it's kind of arcade you
know really simple here building the
moat but yeah that's they fall in it and
they can't get up all right that makes
total sense try to attract blue Jay's
and Robins to your girly Robins I don't
know how to attract Blue Jays I know
really like peanuts so hey there you go
what else he's gonna show up if we throw
out peanuts that gonna bring rabbits
yeah I suppose so possibly can see my
first idea I told my friend to put a
chicken in his yard to give her to his
grasshoppers yeah is that gonna bring me
more problems in the beginning stages
chickens love grasshoppers they also
have juvenile marijuana plants okay once
you've got a four or five foot tall bush
the chick is gonna use it a shade and it
really isn't gonna notice it too much it
might pick it the understory a little
bit okay I clean it up for it yeah it
might do some lollipop in hmmm badges
[Laughter]
undocking ganja farm I can do a pest
management and lollipop and plants for
us we're geniuses over here let's train
some chickens bro yeah yeah four [ __ ]
tree service sorry guys this got weird
blame it on the Terps hashtag blame it
on the Terps there we go there we go
it's new
yeah shout-out to the Terps at one other
comment on grasshoppers I'm hippie
dippie when it comes to growing outdoors
as soon as I hear about a grasshopper
problem I feel like something's out of
balance so instead of killing the
grasshopper you might want to look at
the bigger picture and it's always
seeing something's missing there since
you're doing something wrong so I'm
gonna say that's like 75% of the time
that is okay sure it really I feel like
this applies to smaller girls like those
guys out on Thailand Road where they've
got four acres planted in the ground I
mean that's a completely different
scenario they're gonna have those issues
regardless that is a lot of damn
cannabis yeah went out and drove and
looked at the today date it's [ __ ]
huge Salem Road I like near Beulah yeah
okay take a drive out there it's called
the Green Mile for a reason yes oh yeah
they're doing huge things everyone talks
[ __ ] about Pueblo Colorado but
everywhere around this is green houses
and outdoor grows and just acres and
acres of hemp and acres and acres of
cannabis it's just everywhere it's so
rad right now drive out there 50 we need
more more I don't know that there's a
technical term for these restaurants
fast casual I think more fast casual
restaurants because that's what the grow
industry and people like us that's what
we crave we don't want the Taco Bell the
dr. pepper I hate it yeah yeah kind of
stuff it's it's D I don't there's
nothing at Sonic for me
yeah honestly there's nothing there
McDonald's offers nothing for probably
don't eat it mini fast food places no I
sometimes Jimmy John's if that's even
though you know Qdoba and Chipotle
because he can get a veggie burrito
there that's
pretty much the options the beans at
both those places taste like hell see
even vegetarians of course vegetarians
know what's up with a good batch of
beans oh yeah I made a Facebook post the
other day about sorry that microphone
sounds a little bit funny but it's cool
about if you know the spell are good or
if you can tell good beans based on
smell alone my favorite earthy smell to
them and not too salty you all right but
we need more like a like a Panera and
yeah that'd be dope like I don't know
just more of that style we don't even
have a Qdoba here yep just something
like that little deli on which which
Tokyo Joe's we could go for that kind of
[ __ ] which is yeah all kinds of free
advertising for a bunch of shitty rush
out to tomato Joe's and Pueblo on I
think that's Main Street can I eat there
it sounds like a place I could eat they
do have a veggie I'm sure sandwich for
sure yeah it's just uh your mic is
totally getting away from you here we go
you just gonna rock star yeah is that
how you do it on the Colorado pond yeah
we don't have to dance okay
I apologize for the thing going limp on
you yeah they got a couple uh veggie
sandwiches just a little mom and pop all
in the wall
okay it's right by the library okay
those are the best all right let's put
this trainwreck back on I'm on some
rails here let's talk about cannabis
growing this is not the Colorado podcast
we did not bring 44 sandwiches Sam who
couldn't break 44 he's not allowed to go
anywhere yep this is the exclusion zone
when is that done who knows who knows
poor dude we missed you bro can't wait
ain't come on play again so Jessie
wanted to talk about something that I
find to be really important that people
don't realize people want to jump into
the cannabis industry people move from
all over the country to Colorado to
Washington to California to Oregon to
Michigan to all these places that where
cannabis growing is legal and they show
up here and they've either grown in
their basement in an illegal state for a
couple of years and had two or three
lights or they set up a small grow here
in their garage or their basement they
run four or six lights and then they
think I'm gonna open a big-ass grow and
they're either gonna do it legally or
illegally they're gonna get permits or
not or maybe they're just gonna do
in an illegal place they've been grown
in their basement for a while they're
out there in the sticks in Nebraska and
I [ __ ] we're gonna buy that old meat
plant we're gonna hang us up a hundred
bucks and maybe they do it you know what
I mean so the mistake that a lot of
these people [ __ ] up is they don't
realize it going from the basement to a
large grow facility it's not just taking
this much air conditioning and
multiplying at times however more many
lights you're gonna work it doesn't work
that way you run into a whole new [ __ ]
stew of problems when you start going to
big scale growing the humidity is
ridiculously hard to control in a large
room retardedly
yeah ridiculously you can you can say
that word oh yeah it bugs me a little
bit everyone's evolving yeah it's hard
as [ __ ] to remove a lot of humidity in a
very large room it's also hard to
regulate the temperature and the airflow
and the co2 so there's a lot of tricks
to it what's the biggest mistake you see
people make when they go from what a
dude goes and just builds his first big
when new people get their OPC license
and they can build a grow where do they
[ __ ] up
air conditioning always air-conditioner
humidity never even gets considered cuz
yeah they think this is the desert I
mean it is the desert but they think
it's not gonna be an issue because it's
so dry here right that's a bunch of BS
you're gonna go pumping water into those
plants every single day and they
transpire and there are a thousand watt
lights a bunch of them right above those
plants and the water wants to come out
and go up toward those lights and then
it hangs out up by the ceiling and then
it falls back down and then it hangs out
and it gets between two leaves and it
festers for a couple of days and then
you know what it does it turns into
[ __ ] powdery mildew yep so the spores
are there flower yep it's just waiting
for you to give it a prime tradition
yeah that whole grow room is the perfect
condition for bugs and [ __ ] fungus is
and problems so you've air conditioning
in the humidity are always definitely
the first thing that I think of yeah
it's a big-girl room is a it's a living
organism that is full of lots of other
smaller lady living organisms
it was me explaining it to a buddy this
way earlier today and it itself has
special care that needs done to it right
not just the plants inside of it it's
there's a lot to it
we've got 85 lights in the flower room
at green and healthy damn and we run if
D it's 50 tons we've got a 30 in the
middle and two tens on opposite sides 50
tons of air conditioning to cool that
you get three years see that's smart
three air conditioners right yeah one
goes down in kind if the 30 goes down he
gets warm I bet it does but luckily
we're running kavita's with the Gavita
master controller see gets above 86 in
here I want you to dim the lights until
it gets back yeah that Gavita master
controller is awesome nice we have to
run two of them because we have so many
lights yeah but I mean they're so easy
to program that it doesn't even matter
there are 50 lights each part that I
think they'd only do 40 they have to do
50 because we're running 85 lights yeah
so yeah the nanos do 199 each nice
that's but see what it sucks about that
is you still might have to buy multiple
units if they're in different rooms
break them into zones right right yeah
luckily our room is 185 light big giant
open room with like six rows right now
big shot it's my friends at veg bloom if
you are growing on a small scale a
medium scale or a large scale and you
want nutrients to push your garden and
you want to see what you can really do
[ __ ] veg bloom is something I would
recommend it's affordable it's easy to
use and so far I'm six seven weeks in
and this is the best girl I've done at
the green and healthy wellness garden
and there's a run right next to it
that was not veg bloom and I've already
I've already passed the size of those
buds they're being harvested at week
nine and these other buds or a week
seven and they're already bigger than
the week nine buds so I support
vegetable you're gonna do three like
this one that would be awesome yeah
the only place he could go from your
last performance right yeah last time we
crushed it we did pretty damn well
shut up to the boys at Green &amp; Healthy
Wellness and the whole turf jungle for
helping me I appreciate it
you can shout out to the new guy so not
enough air conditioning and then nobody
considers getting rid of the humidity no
there needs to be an exit for all of the
moisture that comes into the room you
might be filling the room with co2 cool
but where is all of that old stagnant
air going that's in there you need to
get rid of that [ __ ] you don't want to
be in there if you walk into the grow
room and it feels funky to you it feels
funky to the plants you should be able
to close your eyes and breathe and not
notice that you've walked into aggro
yeah it should just feel like normal
like this living room right here it's a
little funky but it was like 90
something degrees today man um things
I've noticed uh humid like we were
talking earlier foliar spraying you know
how even just watering brewing a damn
tea you know brewing 200 gallons of tea
can spike the humidity in oh yeah it's
200 gallons into you too close to the
whites and it just starts evaporating
you hooked up the tea's little bat all
that moisture in the room carries heat
heats up the room as well you go through
the hot and cold cycles naturally
through the day at the building getting
heated up and I mean most of these grows
are in fairly thin shield commercial
warehouses that aren't insulated as well
as it could be and you know so you get
the heating and cooling effect from you
know just the natural outside
temperature we had to build a concrete
wall on the outside we defer it as I
think the the construction term we had
the furrow wall out six inches with
concrete to kind of insulate ourselves a
little bit well I'm glad to hear that
you're not the only heard that I'm not
the only person that might have to do
this are the east wall of our facility
right about or no the west wall I got
the west wall of the facility the way it
all sits as the Sun starts going down it
just makes it yeah and the wall goes you
know from being in the 70s all the way
up into it's radiating heat
I can feel you can see those waves
coming off and you go outside yeah ours
was the exact opposite when the winter
came it got so cold on that wall that we
could see moisture on the inside okay
yeah yeah do that
then you'll get a PM issue because
you're introducing moisture right there
that temperature fluctuation near that
wall everything the hard way oh yeah no
I wouldn't have it any other you should
have seen the guys that did the concrete
over the front of the building there
were three dudes that didn't speak much
English and they showed up in a truck
with a truck a wheelbarrow a whole bunch
of cement and some janky scaffolding oh
yeah two dudes carry the scaffolding to
where they needed to be and they just
pointed and grunted a couple times right
here yeah they set up the first level
and then one dude climbed that and they
threw parts to him while he was standing
on the scaffolding and he stuck him in
place and then climbed up that and hung
and grabbed other [ __ ] and built like a
four-story by himself climbed up and
down and like a spider monkey scared the
[ __ ] out of me so they start the cement
from the top and let it run down kinda
and he's up on the top of the
scaffolding and heels oh no and the guy
on the bottoms mixing cement in a
wheelbarrow with those little trowel
things in his hand and he puts a pile on
the thing and he doesn't throw the tool
but he throws the concrete just Chuck's
it up into the air between the
scaffolding and the dude up top puts his
trial down doesn't even look like
Daniels left right and then heals dose
and the guy throws two of them up and he
puts both of his little tools down and
catches both of them and smears it on
the wall
and he's running left and right and
shilling uno dos as he gets to the
middle and the guy throws how many he
needs and he just [ __ ] smear there
and as it's coming down he goes to the
top and pushes it down and then jumps to
the next level and repeats and then they
got her all done and went back and
smooth it out it took these three dudes
seriously two hours to do the entire
front of this [ __ ] building amazing
yeah I would hire those guys for [ __ ]
anything that's our so [ __ ] you Trump
yeah
a hard-working [ __ ] I mean do
you know my background I worked in the
construction industry for
over a decade and there's a reason why
there's not that many white guys
employed in the construction industry
anymore yeah so yeah yeah take that
Trump yeah [ __ ] you Trump I have no
problem with hiring some illegals come
to you some construction work they do
this [ __ ] that white people think
they're too good to do that's the truth
[ __ ] yeah you couldn't pay me enough to
do some of the [ __ ] that some of those
guys would do just to make enough money
to send home to their family yeah and
that's why I have no problem with that
do you asphalt and black tar Roofing I
do draw the line there without a doubt
yeah I'm [ __ ] white is this paper you
don't want me on a roof no honestly any
kind of roofing I draw the line at to be
honest yes all right so you gotta get
air conditioning and humidity you got to
have an exit you got to have a vent
drying stale air out of the building and
getting it out of the ceiling
that's something super important when
you're going from a basement grow to a
larger commercial grow do you guys have
to run we should be but we're loud we're
allowed one more complaint before we get
in trouble I understand that economics
the fine is cheaper than the filters
that we need we we had to hear it well
oh that was they immediately that was
like one of their big concerns those
carbon filters and we've got six of
those big [ __ ] all over ours we've
even got the inline ones on our
air-cooled lights
we're disgustingly lucky because across
the street from us is homeward bound dog
crematorium nice and so every day around
noon you smell garlic bread and then you
realize animals across the street a dead
animal being cremated so I told the new
guy we got a new guy and I smelled it
the other day and I was like I can't
even let him do that I walked into the
other room where he was it go hey bro
you smell like garlic bread Neos yeah
who's cooking I go that's the dog
crematorium next door don't enjoy it too
much
that's Rover and he just looked at me
like that's fee said that's fluffy
there's roast in that [ __ ] dude
and it's funny cuz the first few days I
worked there I smelled something and
there were two girls that used to work
there that are no longer affiliated with
us but they used to work there they'd be
like everyday at like noon or two
o'clock I smelled garlic bread and they
were standing in the groom room just
sucking it in one day like where is it
it smells so good I realized what it was
a few days later I was like those girls
were loving man sorry this podcast just
got really more of it that's awkward
right the reason I brought it up is just
carbon filter systems in a home grow
versus a commercial grower drastically
different hugely different yeah yeah
that's why I said what we need is way
expensive like HEPA filter great [ __ ]
and uh UV lighting possibly we've got a
small UV light that I use on small
plantings I run it over I just walked
through the grow room and just hover
that light about four to six inches over
every little plant and it keeps them
nice and bug free cuz the bugs want
nothing to do with that and the PM uh
there is not any yeah yeah so that thing
is helpful I was using that on another
guy's garden they had bad PM and I think
it took eight days to just deteriorate
all the PM you know an old guy that has
[ __ ] filtration and refuses to blow
the air out of his house cuz he's afraid
he keeps getting PM so they keep
learning new tricks on how to get rid of
it for him yeah keeps us on our toes
alright so filtration is something they
choose super definitely need if that
stale funky air out you're gonna need UV
lighting you're gonna need a HIPAA
filtration your air conditioners have
exchanges and they're gonna pull the air
from the grow room and that's gonna blow
back into your grow but also a large
portion of that is going to escape into
the outside atmosphere so you're gonna
be stinking it up that way also see the
carbon scrubbers inside the grow it's
pretty [ __ ] hard to keep this it's so
hard and be they came to us and they're
like hey uh we can smell cannabis and
we're like yeah we would try to keep the
smell down how do you know it's us they
said well we've been to all the other
grows and you guys seem to know more
what you're doing the meed in the city
loves us there because we're
we don't hide from them there are some
dispensary owners that don't get along
with those people because they're shifty
dicks and they're they're just keeping
it real and we're yeah you know they're
keeping it real and we're trying to be
on the legit side yeah we're cool and
they come over when hey what's up I'm
actually I'm looking forward to your
first visit because the place I work at
now is completely different than some of
the other places overto it's nice when
you can look forward to meb visits John
I know they'll have some issues I'm sure
they will they're all they're always
going to that's their job but I'm not
scared of anything
you know that's anything that we have
messed up on it's either cuz we didn't
understand it properly or right invite
the Department of Agriculture in for a
walk through like invite them and then
if you invite them they won't give you
any violations for whatever they find
they'll tell you to correct it since you
invited them and they'll be like you've
got 90 days to get it corrected when we
come back that's when we'll actually be
able to put you on like a warning notice
yes of item they show up and they're
like oh good job thank you and then you
can be like I need help come show me
what - correct
that's kind of the way to do with our
Department of Ag and guy that's been
going around us [ __ ] cool I can't
think of his name right now oh I can
almost remember his name in my head he's
a cool little dude he's an older dude
he's kind of a short guy but he's cool
he's fun to hang out with he's very
informative very educational
I mean he'll talk to you like you're a
human he won't treat you like a stupid
grower like some of the industry people
do like electricians and HVAC guys Trent
is like we're [ __ ] [ __ ] HVAC guys
yeah I was dealing with one yesterday I
was about ready to strangle the guy I
just had to walk out of the office like
yeah you're [ __ ] idiot sorry yeah
sometimes sometimes some contractors are
a pain in the ass to deal with so that's
something to look forward to and you're
building your big grow find some
contractors that you can trust in Pueblo
good [ __ ] luck if you're in Pueblo
Colorado you'd be better off paying
crews from Denver to come down and build
your grow in my opinion Gagliano is that
what is that a good good a good builder
he's decent okay man he's very connected
in the city he knows he's on personing
basis with everyone
all right so check this out if you're
trying to get aggro built in Colorado in
the Pueblo
rado region find a guy who does
construction by the name of gaglianone
AG Liana's construction in pueblo
colorado when you contact them be like
hey I was listening to a podcast this
guy named Rasta Jeff told me about you
so anything that we do business with you
owe him 2 percent commission yeah just
make sure that he sends me 2 percent
super since not a lot to ask no no it's
not it's that's what I'm headed with
this if using coins on the floor you
wouldn't care if I picked up two pennies
no break a buck I get it that's that's
breaking that's breaking the big one but
if you got the soft the soft hundred
pennies and you take two of them find
yourself a good contractor is the point
of all this yes yeah cuz contractors can
[ __ ] up your whole day I worked in
another facility that the blueprint was
drawn by one guy the HVAC system was
designed by another in the electrical
which we're gonna talk about in a minute
was designed by another guy and they
were all it was like we took a Ferrari
engine maybe a porsche turbo kit and
then maybe like a Lamborghini body and
then the suspension system for a
Corvette and they're like you got all
these dope-ass parts make it go fast
Ricky Bobby we're like yeah but the air
conditioning doesn't work when you turn
on all the lights there's not enough
power to do good contractors good
engineers [ __ ] engineer that's very
key as an engineer that understands yeah
because you're not always going to find
a contractor that understands indoor
cultivation they don't actually made
ideas come rarely we'll find a
contractor that understands it but you
can find engineers that know what
they're doing and engineers are smart
people you can explain [ __ ] to him so
yeah that's that was real key in the
uncle bun company development we had a
really good engineer let's talk about
that in a minute also I'll let you give
them a nice plug I'm gonna write it down
so that I remember I was able to relay
concerns I had to to him and I'm like
you know we got to make sure this
doesn't happen like electricity I was
like we just have to have plenty
electricity plenty three-phase power all
day long yeah well not quite but we got
two meters so okay how many amps are you
allowed to pull
we're 400 on both that's on each box yes
so you get 800 total apps nowhere near
drawing water amperage you get to flip
the [ __ ] on switch we've got to the
inside ever done it yeah I feel
ridiculous when at content when the
contacts touch yeah all that power you
can do like if you if you're not strong
enough to push it all right through you
don't want to do it like because that's
about our that's a lot of feeling to
shorten something there yeah yeah and
some smaller folks might not be able to
push that this is not the Colorado they
don't get any love what are we talking
about all right so another thing we kind
of touched on this one get a [ __ ]
certified qualified reliable
professional electrician yes if your
contractors do [ __ ] up
you can fire them oh yeah don't just
hire this guy I gotta stick with the
Mille [ __ ] dough you're not dating
and I can call him on it and you can
make a comeback and fix it or take away
their junk and you're not gonna pay for
it there you go
let's take weather junkie baby every
contractor has got a pile of his [ __ ] in
your facility while he's working there
hold it hostage until you do that that's
kind of a [ __ ] up way to go about it
but if you just lock the doors any like
bro you done [ __ ] that my walls are
all crooked make my Wall Street then
I'll pay you you gotta do [ __ ] right the
flooring forums always been a [ __ ] and
every facility I've been to the flooring
has been an issue yeah it's just hard to
get floors right in this industry oh
I've got a brand name of specific paint
for you but I don't know it off the top
of my hand
alright you know it's been great I've
got one little flake out of 2,000 square
feet
oh [ __ ] yeah yeah I mean it said it said
almost three months of work on top of it
and I think you drop something heavy to
get that one chip yeah
yeah yeah I like tables put your plants
on tables guys raise them up off the
ground we can work on it so awesome I
love it we've got ours on the floor
right now and that's some cleaning
mopping up after 6 plants 12 plants is
one thing mopping up after a hundred and
seventy-six plants is a completely
different story I've got an assistant
grower now and every like few days he's
like what do you want me to do bro
really just clean up he's like seriously
like yeah just go [ __ ] every little
random thing that's fallen out of a
plant all the pearlite that's on a table
or any whatever if there's a pair of
scissors lying around go clean all that
[ __ ] measurers yeah yeah exactly start
from the top in the flower room go all
the way down if there's old trellis for
old pots in there from something that's
been harvested that's got to go sweep
every goddamn corner get out the shop
vac suck up underneath all the weird
random little nooks and crannies that we
got in there anything that's not gonna
be used doesn't need to be in the flower
room I don't think like scissors and
boxes of material that [ __ ] should go in
the storage room store that yeah or put
it right outside the flower is fortunate
enough to have a storage room yeah put
the broom and dustpan and trash can
outside the flower room yes put that
[ __ ] outside just don't have that in the
flowering room or the bedroom simple
little tasks that you don't even think
about doing in a small group can
literally take days in a big defoliating
oh my god shaving legs shaving legs and
defoliants taking I know you guys are
all netting but yeah I'm doing a big
Seeger on so that wasn't really a right
an option I just double and triple layer
trellising I get it crazy on it
I can't wait I've got a guy that a
former employee that would be fully at
the entire room for an entire shift and
he would do 10 5-gallon buckets full of
leaves and he would push him down like
you just chopped leaves all day and then
go back and scoop up the leaves out of
the trays into five-gallon buckets and
he'd probably fill 10 5 gallon buckets
he'd fill one of those big like 30
gallon trash cans halfway full it just
leaves just never
the first run of defoliating things you
don't have to do in the basement we have
to weigh all that and we have to track
it that's yeah document what all that
[ __ ] weighed yeah
manicured wait leave off so we've got a
you know you're supposed to like mix it
with soil or vinegar oil or something
like that before you can throw it away
okay yeah let's sound let's catch the
listeners up though and a commercial
grow when you if you have see maybe a
but isn't desirable or they're the
bottom part of the plan you throw that
[ __ ] away when that's in the trashcan
you have to cut it up into little tiny
pieces and then you have to mix it like
Jesse said with soil or a kitty litter
is what they recommend it for gravel or
vinegar or something else that you can
put in there cooking oil yeah anything
to make it unusable and unrecognizable
so you sound like you got a good idea
yeah we've got three worm firms there
you go [ __ ] yeah feed it to the worms
yeah and they're loving it too I'm sure
they love their canna meal and the best
we use a [ __ ] ton of worm castings too
so it helps cut down cost there there
you go pre cycling yeah that's a good
way to do it
yeah that's when we get our greenhouse
built we've got a whole wall in the
greenhouse it's gonna be a shelf system
full of bins and every worm [ __ ]
into it into a funnel yeah just a warm
[ __ ] funnel just tunnel it down Dan
that's pretty rad we've uh we grind it
up pretty small we chop it on I chopped
up with uh like the the shears just go
ham on it with the shears and then uh we
make lasagna basically we take the old
pot that the plants been harvested from
and shake that soil into the trashcan we
let them dry they've all sat around and
dried for couple days
don't pull that soil into the trash can
throw a bunch of the waste into there
dump a couple more pots more soil couple
more far more a waste yeah just keep it
like that so that's a way to get rid of
all of our old soil at the same time and
Canobie you have a use for it wasting
all that good dirt because I know it's
recyclable I totally know and we use so
much cocoa we buy 14 big bags of cocoa
at a time when we go because that's what
fits in hunts car
oh you're talking like the big tall bags
those bags are right there the big feet
those are bigger okay all right that's
what I use at the house now - is cocoa I
love great news and shout out to uh shot
it's a way to grow I hope nobody to
serve me burp into that microphone
excuse me a shot it's a good way to grow
I was buying cocoa grow the other day I
really like the botanic air cocoa grow I
don't prefer the aeration bag just get
the cocoa it's just fun you don't need
that aeration in there I don't like that
[ __ ] but way to grow is nice enough to
throw in a bunch of bags of Fox farms
ocean forest soil for free they turned
that [ __ ] to my car like you buy a lot
of [ __ ] here bro here you go these are
shot it's my friends away to grow they
know who they are I don't know if they
listen to the podcast if you do listen
to the podcast contact makes I'd love to
have you as a sponsor on the show yeah
the rust - Jeffrey count they know my
account name and they laugh every time
they hear it they laugh every time
because we've got the commercial account
it's funny it's really funny alright so
you need a good [ __ ] electrician you
need a way to get rid of humidity you
need a way to get rid of heat you need
plenty of air conditioning
you're gonna seal up all the cracks all
the nooks and crannies you gotta be able
to clean the [ __ ] out of this place it's
got to be a semi clean facility you
don't want some old car garage where the
floors all greasy no you need a floor
drain for drains are crucial absolutely
yeah and water you need access to water
a lot of warehouses out in blood low by
the airport they don't have water ran to
them because they didn't need water for
anything there's if you get one of those
warehouses out there
sorry just make sure that was on track
here yeah a few one of those warehouses
out there you you might not have water
you're gonna have to be getting trucks
of water you have to pay to get water
out there something people aren't aware
of if you get a large grow on private
land out say in Pueblo County somewhere
you have to get water rights cannot you
just because you have land doesn't mean
you're granted water rights even if
there's a well there you have to
purchase water - off
what you're taking out exactly yep if
there are enough grows around that area
that that jurisdiction deems the water
is compromised by you coming they can
decline your water wings you can't have
any water saluted yeah and this I mean
even to the point that they don't care
that you're going to town to buy it and
that you have a big truck it's sorry
yeah yeah you can't prove that I've got
a inside track with the Department of
Natural Resources now if anyone has any
questions or anything message our friend
Jesse writes fun all of the great people
that we meet these people would never
take you and I seriously Jesse's got a
semi ponytail a beard [ __ ] tattooed
up he's got is that a trout on your arm
yes he's got two eyebrows that's so rad
he's got a trout on his arm he's got a
Colorado flag he's got a chili that's
just one arm he's got a monarch
butterfly and a snowboard yeah man this
is one arm he's tatted up and I bet a
lot of the and I'm six five with
dreadlocks and red eyes okay good it's
pretty much a good to skin a crooked hat
yeah and I just wore Dickies every day
because I close and it's easier just to
use that are indestructible and these
contractors and business folks would
never have taken us seriously before the
scanners industry and I find it so funny
I've noticed when I go to restaurants in
Denver and I'm wearing like a just a dad
kid shirt basically my IRA shirt and my
hat crooked and a pen D and skate shoes
and my Dickies and I walk in red eyed
before restaurants would kind of be a
dick to me they've kind of like oh this
guy's here like he's [ __ ] up our vibe
but now there's always some young hip
waitress it's like what's up guys at
work in the weed industry you're gonna
tip the [ __ ] outta me you want some
great service honey their work rich yeah
completely
yep yep I don't want I don't want fancy
things on a nice uh some good hash and
live comfortably I'm gonna go to a lot
of good shows let me go see the dead
whenever they come around I'm gonna see
fish every time they're around she check
out the dead company I saw the dead and
Cohn it was [ __ ] rad this is most
recent one yeah just this recent one
when they're in the boulder at Folsom
Field
super awesome I got a yeah you have to
yeah come with me one time yeah yeah a
good time I used to I used to eat a
bunch of psychedelic drugs when I used
to go to those shows and I've quit doing
that I had a head injury anybody that
listens to the podcast for a long time I
heard about the head injury it's not
been a year and a half oh man I still
have effects from it like I hate to
admit it and talk about it but I still
have like TV I I've got post-concussion
syndrome and I've got a traumatic brain
injury still I I played high school
football very competitively I had major
concussions in high school and I know I
didn't let him heal up correctly right
and I wonder sometimes how that affects
me you ever you ever doing [ __ ] and you
go oh that's from that time I have those
moments I have those moments where I
wonder if yes you know I just blame it
on that anyway yep that's that's from
the time I left for no reason in my
jackets all right let's try to get back
on track I don't even over the foot we
were talk about concussions and building
grows large large facilities yeah have a
first-aid kit oh yeah talk about needing
water oh we have water tanks water
filtration your average on the shelf go
store water filter can't handle them and
honor them no you need a lot of water I
use a thousand gallons of water every 48
hours
grow and that's a hundred and five
lights total I'm doing a 155 to 165
right now okay actually we're still not
even at full capacity yeah yeah I'm in
full flower or 5 feet tall with big
[ __ ] donkey dick buds on them and
either way that's still a lot more than
your basement grew oh so much more yeah
if you're using I figure you use about
indoors you probably use five gallons of
water per light every 48 to 72 hours ish
yeah that's the way I used to so if you
guys are trying to figure out how much
water you should be using in your indoor
every 1,000 watt or 600 watt light six
hundred a thousand watt light you should
be running about five gallons every 24
to 48 hours if your temperatures and
your humidity and everything are dialed
in and your plants are at their optimum
growth your plants are growing a little
slow you're probably over watering them
yeah that's usually the first sign of
over watering some plants outdoors it's
gonna be average I'd say five gallons a
plant per plant per day per day is it
okay to just turn on the hose and just
let the hose just [ __ ] flood those
outdoor plants yes for the most part I
try to concentrate it more just around
the plant because I feel like it's
wasting you know okay yeah yeah okay
yeah no you could totally do like a
field flood irrigation actually know of
a also a place here in Pueblo County
that floods their field just like they
do with cantaloupe or watermelon or Wow
yeah yeah just flow the whole field out
like a soak and I let it dry and reflet
it they're just doing a flood and drain
outdoor basically that's yeah okay yeah
I think they do it like two or three
times I need to go explore and visit
more of these outdoor cannabis in here
because I want to see how you guys are
doing a lot of this [ __ ] I want to learn
from the tech don't want to see what I
can implement into my indoor tech I can
show you a couple cool ins yeah I'd love
to see a bunch of big stuff um the
something pretty I think is pretty cool
the overwhelming majority of these
places are know to raise bed
Oh neat yeah so no till you guys they
they make an amended soil with a lot of
special amendments and then very
specific amendments that I'm ignorant to
honestly I don't know what goes into
that a lot of life okay
live worms live worms okay so it's
living soil you guys yeah and the plants
are harvested and do you pull out the
big root ball or you just leave that in
there
the stim around it okay try it do you
actually want to leave as much of the
root ball in there as you can kind of
worms are gonna eat it right into
nutrients for the plant again wife so
I'm going in circles
you pull the plan out and you put a new
one in and you send her off again they
use a lot of cover crops stuff like that
oh okay so you're stacking stuff into
the pot and then the worms will eat all
of that mostly that stuff will decompose
and become plant yeah and then so you're
gonna start losing a little bit of depth
every time right that's the depth of the
soil is gonna move down you just refill
it with your fresh that's how you got no
toes you that's awesome go back in top
dress in all your recharged amendments
that's pretty awesome I never thought of
that of a crow it's uh
[Music]
it's extremely economical that's why
most of these places are running it hell
are such a large scale that it's just
the plants taste good cuz either being
an intro er who uses mainly bottled
nutrients for most of my growing to
flush my plants yeah are they always
those guys I don't need to flush cuz
I've been crushing the whole time since
they're not feeding a whole bunch of
bottled nutrients a bunch of she lated
salts they're plants aren't backed up
with stuff the plants are probably more
able to I don't you can't even remember
the word right now it's simile all of
the nutrients that are going through
they can use it a little bit better it
kind of something goes down they get rid
of it a little more okay i debuff a star
they get to pick and choose yeah it's an
enforcement yeah I was crazy the plants
actually finish themselves off they
start fading just like you they would if
they're flooded
I mean flushed they know my seasons done
yeah all right do you see a difference
in specific strains does strain a versus
strain B do they finish differently in
the no-till outdoor I haven't done
enough of it to say that yeah let's just
curious if that was nutrients running
out or if that was actually the plant
realizing hey done I'm flushing myself I
I know in my experience the way I grow
in the grounds kind of no-till pretty
much yeah I know Girl Scout cookies and
flow will finish themselves off what Pat
doubt they'll the forum cut Girl Scout
cookies flow will finish herself off you
guys
all right we've been going for about an
hour let's uh let's start wrapping it up
because I'm actually expecting dinner to
show up in the next one I just started
thinking about that about 15 minutes ago
I saw you messing with your phone is
like he's doing his dinner
15:30
I actually got a girl foliar spray some
plans what are you gonna spray essential
oils okay so pesticide pest management
and a great pest management with
essential oils we are to 13 days in the
flower just about the end of that just
bring it right now and the lights just
shut off so I'm gonna go hit him with it
a few more times and that great white
yeah you know you are the forehead
greenlighter do you have a room light no
I got the forehead one thing I don't
like the full room once okay inevitably
that light switch always gets left on
right yeah just run in that green light
for nothing all day it's looking where
I'm looking yeah it's actually focused
where I am instead of just then you
don't get shadows all right we've talked
a lot about building getting your large
commercial grow going you have any
things that you want to add before we
start wrapping this up so that I don't
cut off any of your useful data for our
listeners find a person that can be
vouched for by many people throughout
the community to work with your engineer
to help design your building and pay him
what he is worth like you know if it'll
be a guy like me or Jeff and even if
he's not gonna grow for you pay him what
it's worth and your end product will
drastically improve and work better by
doing that in my first week and green
and healthy wellness I made minor
improvements that improved the financial
it just made sense it fixed their books
a little bit just by [ __ ] doing a
couple of adjustments like making the
garden more or profitable just by
eliminating this and adding this it just
took me a week to me
a whole bunch of small improvements just
because the person who set it up and was
running it was not an experienced grower
was not I don't want to I don't want to
bash this person but they weren't a
forward thinker they were they didn't
they didn't look far enough into the
future they didn't have foresight to
realize that if I don't put glue here
that shit's gonna come apart eventually
got you like yeah yeah so I fixed a lot
of just small details they didn't have
any heaters in the O's winter when I
started there were no heaters and the
reservoirs they're feeding the plants 54
degree water and they couldn't get the
pH of the [ __ ] water to come up
they're just pouring in pH they couldn't
get it to go down it was porn in like a
half a gallon a pH down and like it
won't move and I was like oh my god I go
where does the water come from he goes
of the hose I was like oh so municipal
water it's coming from the [ __ ] line
it's underground and it's 30 degrees
outside so I stuck a thermometer in
there and that water was 54 degrees well
that's why the pH won't move and that's
why the plants have the cloth they all
had the [ __ ] downward claw but the
plants were purple like everything so I
put aquarium heaters in there so let's
go to the fish store get the biggest
aquarium heaters they have put two in
each one sent him at 74 degrees and let
him run to get the glass ones are
beautifully then I learned that they
sell big ourselves there for heating
animal like horses yeah its stock tank
heaters those would have been more
economical but I didn't think of that
because I'm not a farm boy I just never
thought of that for sure I ordered in a
couple at the store last winter nice
we've been selling the glass once I
found the stainless steel ones and they
sold up very quickly yeah that glass
ones gonna break in there on accidents
yeah 50 gallons of water
you know someday it will but yeah that's
a failsafe though so you're not gonna
get shot right yeah they're not in there
right now so yeah you guys a lot of the
[ __ ] you're gonna go spend money on it
the hydro store go check out the
aquarium store before you do that
because it's cheaper or even crazier to
be totally honest oh yeah you don't
always have to buy all your stuff big R
has a lot of very useful [ __ ] the normal
grossed or not the
hydroponic store but like the local
garden supply center has a lot of [ __ ]
Home Depot and Lowe's and Target have a
lot of good [ __ ] just do not buy
nutrients soil anything that is going to
be consumed by you or your plant don't
purchase that at Home Depot Lowe's our
target only accessories made out of
plastic or whatever that kind of [ __ ]
lighting that's for specific still at
this point Hobby Lobby sells Fiskars
scissors for $12.99 as opposed to Home
Depot and everywhere else is 1999 the
little titanium tip Fiskars trim
scissors I think I'm not sure okay
Oh a high grow yeah we'll go get him one
love you sorry forget that you guys
change your names um I can't I'm not as
involved with the store anymore as I was
so is that the wife now oh yeah it's
always been the wife Shannon to the wife
yeah that's her baby nice she does a
good job I understand Springs they
finally if I were there I'd shot there
but I'm right up the street from the
store in Springs that as if I needed 14
bags of soil I don't know that you have
it yeah no I understand that's something
we should mention commercial ordering
yeah good luck the first time you want
to figure out how much [ __ ] soil you
need to fill all those pots cuz it's
that's a math challenge you heard Jesse
and I see here how much soil we needed
you're gonna have to go back to the
store a couple times don't expect all
stores you're gonna be able to get
commercial quantities of things when you
need them you need to think ahead about
stuff yeah you might have to start
letting we let the store near us know
that this is these are products that we
use on the regular if you keep these
stock we'll buy them if we come here and
you don't have it we will drive directly
to another store and get it cuz we don't
[ __ ] yeah and so it took him a couple
of rhythms you know it took them a
couple hey you don't have it like it's
come in Wednesday the trucks come
Wednesday I don't care
and so we kind of a job we we compromise
with that we can't [ __ ] with the day the
trucks run like that's some [ __ ] we
can't ask for it I will get it on your
next order it doesn't fit like you know
like bring it on the previous order you
guys are ordering a truckload of [ __ ]
a truck of your stuff it's funny the UH
there's two main truckers that they
literally move I would say seventy sixty
to seventy percent of the gross horse or
gross applies to old and gross stores
all across Colorado it'll open down the
Front Range that's awesome Gary and
James because there's probably one
warehouse that gets [ __ ] everything
there's three main warehouses and it
just gets distributed from there out to
Pueblo Springs Denver a company named
Denver air is one of the only delivery
companies that will work from Denver
south on a daily route oh wow
they go - way to go they go to us they
go to grow generation they go to all of
them all of them yeah way to grows my
favorite if you're going big you're
going big stuff if you're in photo and
you want to buy stuff for your small
Grove definitely hit one love life if
you're big huge gigantic County
greenhouse grow we already deal with a
handful of half a dozen clients out
there we know that it takes to to
service big grows like so if you're in
Pueblo and you're out there in the
county I'll take care of you I'll get
you a commercial account going drop
shipping yeah I pull up to your farm
just drop off loads of soil for you like
Jesse said he said to hire somebody that
knows what the [ __ ] they're talking
about when it comes to working with your
engineer to build the grow something
super important that just sounds
egotistical coming from myself and Jesse
but also hire a master grower that is a
master grower yeah interview people look
at pictures of plants they've grown I
brought people to my home grow yeah to
show them that I can grow on a
commercial scale as I here is what I can
do if you put me in a big grow I can do
it and they trusted me and they gave me
the opportunity by seeing the
cleanliness and the organization of my
home grow yeah so if you can go look at
their grow before you hire a master
grower do it and if you're the business
guy and you think you're gonna grow it
yourself and be professional you're
gonna [ __ ] it up I've got faith in your
skills I've got faith in your mind but
cannabis is something that takes a lot
of practice to learn it's like playing
an instrument you might have natural
skill but you're not gonna be Bon Jovi
the first time you grow
you're gonna [ __ ] practice you're
gonna have to tour a few times you're
gonna have to do it gonna have to have
ten cycles under your belt before you
even think about going big full cycles
from this clone all the way to drying
and curing all the way to move in the
packs yeah there's a lot to figure out
my boss gets of my head owner he gets
down and dirty and liquor it's it's and
he's he has this like child like
excitement about it so [ __ ] awesome
I've never I well I know hunt he gets
down in the room - oh that's for me all
show huh comes in at 6:00 in the morning
on certain down tuesdays huh I'll be
there at 6:00 in the morning and I'll
come in a couple few hours later and
he'll have a hundred pots filled with
soil being like he get all those
transplants done today I got you a head
start
nice and I'm like hell yeah bro and he
sweeps he sweeps the entire facility if
I need him to takes up trash he's like
bro you're below your pay grade it
doesn't feel like I'm not too good to
clean the [ __ ] and take out trash
but you're right I should be hands-on
with a plan it feels good though to have
to work for people that realize you
don't want to do that stuff that you
would do it but you don't want to yeah
and it feels good to for them to you
know tell you don't have to worry about
that I enjoy that program a lot of the
time I get the giant facility all to
myself so I just put on headphones and
nice yeah it makes me feel like
sometimes I got to clean the [ __ ] I
got to sweep the floors I don't mind
doing it for sure yeah and if I go take
a [ __ ] I clean the [ __ ] when I'm done
streaks for the next guy that's like
rinsing your plate as soon as you're
done [ __ ] some Windex right there
how's that Mitch down and cleaned up for
people that don't know much about the
industry or don't live in Colorado is
not common at all to find owners that
are actually involved in the grill
that's I think being Jeff we're both
fortunate to work unfortunately it's
equally as common to find rich dudes
that own Porsche dealerships and want to
double their [ __ ] money by opening a
dispensary and being a [ __ ] to
everybody and don't know anything about
cannabis
[Music]
very similar stories yeah very similar
guys they just want to double up because
they have a little bit of money so and
that's where might talk about hire a
real master grower loops around a lot of
people want to hire their cousin because
they want to give their cousin a job or
their nephew or their [ __ ]
brother-in-law because he grew weed in
the 70s and he talks a good game this is
your investment it's gonna cost you a
million bucks to get your your grow and
your dispensary going it's six hundred
thousand for to get started and they
need like another four hundred for some
payroll and whatever pops up and you're
gonna need a lawyer and an accountant
it's a million bucks basically a million
dollars here just for a small small
facility our little facility man yes so
unless you trust your [ __ ] cousin a
million bucks worth your future is on
the line your business is on the line
your grows on the line some of us
growers are weird people we've been
taught to hide this for so many years
the guys that are good at it did it like
when we were hiding it and we were kind
of sketchy about it so sometimes some of
our background history on the
application is a little vague sometimes
we've got a big furry ass beard they're
gonna have squirrels iDEN sometimes you
got dreadlocks down to your ass they can
have the whole damn zoo hidin in it they
don't we don't like sharing secrets we
don't like to share too many secrets by
dispensary owners by street people by
friends by family things have gone wrong
so we're a little we're a little
protective of ourselves and our
knowledge it's one thing I had my pasta
ate the other day growers are some of
the only people in the industry that
don't actually need a job right they
could go make their own money doing
their I hate to say this but I actually
very much meet my job I need more money
being a black market grower I than I
ever have in the legal industry but I
don't have to look over my shoulder
anymore I don't have to when I hear
ruffling outside the front door too
early I don't think the door is about to
get kicked the [ __ ] because I spent
20 years of my life just wondering is
today the day they kick this [ __ ] in
you can get a loan for a car you can get
a loan for it's hard work but I've got a
can get done
brand new car in the driveway that I
couldn't have done when I was a street
hustler because
I've got paychecks and pay stubs and I
pay taxes and yeah I pay child support
because I've got a child that lives with
their mom and just because we don't live
in the same place I'm required to
[ __ ] pay child support
it's cool with me today just driving it
over there I have to go through a system
which documents it being paid they were
always on my ass about my income you're
paying child support but we want to know
where your money comes from I was like
why does it matter if the bill was paid
yeah I just kept telling him like my mom
pays it or my grandpa died he left me
money his [ __ ] tone that kind of [ __ ]
but now I'm like hey look I work at this
place and like okay thank you yeah so
having a job not looking over my
shoulder is well worth the difference
it's the stress reduction although
there's other stress that comes from it
right the different kind of stress just
but now I can be I I am more proud of my
grow now than I was when I was a black
market for sure like it was kind of cool
having that thing in the basement that
nobody knew about
and why would disappear for [ __ ] 12
hours at a time what have you been doing
it but trimming weed but I can't tell
you guys that hire yourself own master
grower we may look like weirdos we might
be tatted up get yourself somebody
that's on [ __ ] time somebody that
doesn't drink and do some drugs but I've
had some problems in the past with
employees that have recently hired that
one guy was I partied too hard the night
before and was too drunk to come to work
and then I had another guy that ate too
many mushrooms the night before and
tripped way too hard and had a headache
and couldn't come to work plants don't
care about the yeah [ __ ] you you got a
job to do I rely on you the plants rely
on you if you don't show up and water
those plants they're dead it's a
business yeah if if you don't show up on
time in a pump diet overnight because
pumps die you're fired
the whole gardens dead you're [ __ ]
fired there goes your million-dollar
investment so hire yourself a real
master grower somebody that knows what
they're doing not just your cousin we
might look like weirdos we might be
introverts but if we're on time we show
initiative we're dedicated you got to be
a soldier you got to be dedicated to the
grow you got to respect the plants you
got to be able to build a relationship
with the plants you need something you
can communicate with someone that can
multitask someone that can deal with a
contractor something it's not gonna be a
dick when the electrician shows up so
it's not gonna run out the back door and
mentions of
did you hand them all the compliance
binders with all your info you tell him
to have a good day and they get to sit
there and figure out what's wrong and
they can't come in and check until they
tell you they need to really yeah yeah
just hand them those compliance binders
and wait for them to find an issue okay
yeah I'm gonna go back to work and by
the way I'm not the owner so you can't
even tell me [ __ ] I'll call the owner
the owner don't man meds here I'm doing
my job just go back to work I feel like
we've gone a long way in this podcast
I'm sure that's good were an hour and 15
minutes in but there's a lot of good
information this Connor this podcast was
everything there was a news education
and conversation I'm not sure what the
news was Terps Terps yeah the trips are
awesome that's the news it's official
you guys Terps are awesome derp some
turps
Terps all day long shout out to the yet
the Terps sweet and all those kids I've
got one more thing written down on my
paper of notes that we need to talk
about it is the Uncle Bud company told
me all about the Uncle Bud company Uncle
Bud company is the company I'm employed
by is that a grow and a dispensary yes
we've got an MIP out of OPC oh that's a
my piece of license to make cash
available medically infused products yes
marijuana products yeah we we use a co2
extraction method so that's primarily we
make bait or when we started off it's
the company's still new we're evolving
we've started off with a co2 oil of
eight pin refills and cartridges we're
bringing out a line of edibles that
we're going through testing and approval
which is a bit of a process right now
but those will be on store shelves soon
and it will also be bringing you I don't
know how I can state that we're bringing
a fractional distillation to product
called clear look at all right market
and I will be bringing our version of
terpenes to the record this distillate
is the new stuff let me read the label
on the distillate that I've got this is
raw distillate this is total potential
cannabinoids 94.1% th cannabinoids
and then it's broken down CBD 1.1
percent THC 90.9 4 percent THC in this
distillate and it's just like that yeah
it's basically the same thing you're
just taking rotovap and everything and
pulling out the terpenoids pulling out
the cannabinoids and making them into
separate products there's uh yeah yeah
yeah we won't we won't cover all of the
install of something named after a farm
animal so you said the jet edibles being
tested that would be coming out in the
market are those only going to be
available to Uncle Bud Company or are
those going to be available at
recreational and/or medical shops
statewide we are wholesaler we don't
have a storefront so much easier that
way yes our co2 oil right now I know
here in pilot available at the spot it's
also available at the spot and Trinidad
your co2 oil that you guys made yes okay
cool um so it's a recreational product
yes yes
edible products were coming up with at
the moment we've got a barbecue sauce
it's going through the proving process
no [ __ ] and we lose ass you know a the
people that owe my company are from
George in Texas be highest [ __ ] yes
barbecue sauces good oh dude it's so
good it's it's really good how many how
many milligrams of THC per serving
um that's part of the thing we're
figuring out right now the bottle scope
it's gotta be limited at 100 a smaller
bottle okay
but it's brittle be like two servings so
50 milligrams two serving all right so
gonna make some red you could just
squirt the whole bottle across some ribs
and as the heat when you're cooking the
ribs gonna [ __ ] up my medicine that's
one of the things we've got to figure
out all right so yeah there's I had no
idea vegetarian you guys hypothetically
talking about BBQ ribs over here I had
no idea the proofing process the state
requires for a new new style and it's
rigorous
they were doing popcorn balls - oh I had
some popcorn balls that were coated and
clear Oh
that's part of the a lot of our demand
we've been getting for clay right now
it's coming from edibles manufacturers
nice is they don't want any smell or any
right it makes it so much easier and
it's more viscous it's easier to work
with it's not chunky like pho it's a
higher percentage so it's easier to work
with I shot it to my friends at TNT
extractions they gave me a 1000
milligram chokolate bar it was kind of
like biting into taste they told me if
there's a gram and a half of shatter
melted into that chocolate bar it tasted
like they just took a gram and a half of
shatter and to a chocolate bar and just
dropped the shatter directly into the
chocolate bar because when I bit into it
it was chocolate chocolate chocolate
hash my teeth you know when you take a
dad and your lips getting sticky my
teeth were like they're making this
noise when I pull them apart that sound
like when I pull them apart they would
do that I was like damn I'm Hoshi I got
so high vit I made a list of things to
do go into work I hate it and went to
[ __ ] work bad idea I made a list of
[ __ ] to do and I would read it on the
list water plants and I'd walk to the
water and turn on the hose and be like
what was I about to do any edible since
that day at the front door so let's wrap
up this podcast but I appreciate you for
coming to do in an hour and 20 minute
podcast ok that's awesome of you thanks
to burn for letting me borrow your
husband for an hour and a half and
taking some dads with me that's super
cool shout out to the Uncle Bud company
you guys I'm gonna wrap up this podcast
thing thank you for coming Jesse make
sure you check out Jesse grows on
Instagram yeah yeah thanks for having me
you had something one more thing to say
throw it out Colorado podcast calm thank
you check it out stitcher and SoundCloud
- we're gonna get you on iTunes yes you
know how to do that
I just haven't had the time to sit down
and know how to do it
nice if you need help I will get you on
there sweet bring get this podcast on
iTunes cuz iTunes is a place most people
listen stitcher is number 2 I
so you really see your uh your like
comments and [ __ ] will come in on at
least we're not just stuck on Soundcloud
now which is like probably number twelve
or fourteen and I can't listen I don't
even have SoundCloud on my phone so I'd
have to go through your Facebook post
and then use the link given it was just
a pain in there and then if I get a call
then I have to start the episode over
and that's I hate that yeah that's the
only thing I use SoundCloud for is just
to check our show so that's as soon as
we're on stage and you played with your
your your statistics yet your metrics on
stitcher no I haven't don't get to it
attached to it but it's fun to go look
and see what your ranking isn't [ __ ] I
love doing it
the first night I kind of looked at it
but it didn't have any info yeah word
okay thanks for coming yeah thanks for
having me big shout out to 44 and
despicable D yes sir we'll get you guys
on next time next time I'm gonna come be
on your show I don't think I've ever met
fetus but I hear a lot about the dude so
I'm gonna let Jesse go home we're gonna
take a couple dabs and I will be back to
put a bow on this [ __ ] nice see you
guys later alright podcaster oh I want
to thank you guys for listening to a
long episode I want to thank Jesse for
joining me I also want to thank Fred for
sending me a whole bunch of useful
emails if any of you have questions that
you'd like answered on the podcast send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I'd love to answer your
questions
on a future episode also I'd love to
read your reviews on iTunes on a future
episode go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store find the review section find the
girl from your heart podcast type in a
little review let me know you think of
the show and I will read your review on
a future episode
give me some stars let me know what you
think of the podcast I would love to
hear from you also I love all this
social media interaction find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast find me on
Facebook that grow from your heart
podcast and find me on Instagram it's at
Irie underscore genetics that's all I've
got for you this week you guys be good
to one another take a bunch of fat dabs
shot it's my ninja Spence and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
teachers in ideological with one dirty
couch upon some under [ __ ] or no met
brother 92 this
[Music]
No
you'll sleep bleaching but make money
like religion or at least and brother
Dan so we can try
[Music]
Oh