[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back Canada's community
it's time for episode number 145 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a professional
grower a new smoker or a dedicated Dabba
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat coot and the entire mystic roots
crew hope everybody's having a great
week you guys this episode is packed
with information I'm gonna do an episode
about an email I got about making
feminized seeds and selecting phenotypes
for seeds and seed breeding and
feminized seed making this one was right
up my alley so I took a lot of notes
this would be a great episode in my
opinion I'm excited to do it but before
we get that far let's talk about the
secret sessions a secret session was
just a few days ago and in my opinion
this was the best secret session we've
done in Colorado
you know the session the secret session
on 421 the day after 4/20 that was
pretty [ __ ] fantastic
but that was the day after 4/20 there
were a lot of really cool people in town
that wouldn't normally be here we had a
lot of extra height because of 4/20
weekend a lot of extra momentum that
really helped us out it was a little
over overhyped and too big for me I like
a smaller more intimate event so without
all the hustle and bustle this was my
favorite secret session I think there
were plenty of people there the place
was packed but it was a little more
intimate there was more room to dab more
room to chill out I was a little quieter
you could go get some quiet space and
talk to some people if you wanted to I
really enjoyed that so huge shot it to
the grimy Gatsby for throwing a stellar
event big shout out to miles from
putting it together big shout out to
hunt big shout out to everybody who
participated in the secret sesh I'm
gonna go down a little bit of a list
here the Terps from Evo Labs good shout
outs a big huge shot it's my buddy Brett
Brett ah Mary's motivation on Instagram
make sure you follow him that dude
showed up with a pocket full of Terps
somebody said something my buddy Bobo
said something too to Brett and Brett
goes so you want some turps
and of course Bubba was like well of
course I want some turps and he threw
him a canister filled with little Turk
containers and bubbles eyes lit up like
a child at Christmas and I just happened
to have a bunch of packs of seeds in my
pocket that I was gonna give to some
friends to grow out and since I saw that
beautiful gift given right there I
decided to return some karma and I
passed some seeds Brett's way so Brett's
got some I read genetics seeds in his
garden he'll be growing those out before
too long and we'll talk about those on
the podcast so big huge shout out to the
trippy boy Brett Brett hooks it up with
the Turk he's just got his dad out he
had some super good flavors everybody at
the event had flu at the event had good
flavor shout out to our friends at the
Terp suite all those kids always bring
the flame is good to see Diamond Dave at
the event Dave I don't know if he
listened to the podcast a big shot I was
good to shake your hand and see you
haven't seen in a long time just seemed
like we weren't getting along on
Facebook for some reason bow bro and
it's a good to shake your head and
[ __ ] put that behind us so welcome
back to the crew my friend big shot it
to Lindsey and Chris Phil let me kind of
tag along to be their third wheel I had
fun hanging out with you guys
we'll get Lindsey on another episode
because I've got something I want to
talk to her about and then we'll talk
about sin and stickers to all you people
the wheel stickers do we did not forget
Mike and Lindsey and I talked about it
via text message I know we owe you guys
some stickers Fred your stickers are
coming a couple other people you got
stickers coming the people that
participated in the mullet challenge you
do have stickers coming I did not forget
about you the people that hit up hash
tag I like it when you ramble you've got
stickers coming nobody forgot about you
we're just dad we're blazed and confused
we're doing what we can to keep up so
back on track here shot it to Adam ill
Adam mill comes all the way from
California flies in from Burbank all the
way to cut to Colorado here to hosted
the secret stash wish with us it's a big
shout out to my boy adam l wha if you
don't know about oil make sure you
follow him it's at Adam blunts I think
so he always has to change his social
media they always shut down a social
meeting has to restart new [ __ ]
search Adam mil on Instagram I think
it's Adam blunts on Facebook check him
out he's the hostess with the mostess
also big shot it's my buddy giddy up I
haven't seen giddy up in a while and
giddy up was at the secrets a shocking a
mohawk building a stage great dude that
giddyup guy makes you guys support emo
tech i dude just moved to Hollywood
California he's young and rich and lives
in Cali now good luck with that one bro
things hope things go well for you big
huge shout-out to my buddy Jason
Margulis it was good seeing you
they're sorry I missed your lovely lady
would have been good to see her and give
her a high five and a half hug
you know those one-armed pugs it's what
we do really good to see her but it's
good seeing you bro next time bring the
lady with you we'll all hang out take
some chirpy dabs I think that's all the
shoutouts I've got for the secret sex
you guys I turned down edibles this time
I did not eat any edibles if the secret
sesh I shot it to TNT extracts he gave
me some 200 milligram bacon yeah he
handed me bacon wrapped in parchment
paper and I was like hmm okay then and I
walked through it acted like I was gonna
eat it but of course I gave that to her
buddy Bobo I shout out to Bobo Bobo
blaster Co all the edibles I was given
that night I passed him right over to
Bobo if people if the session people
just walked by you and hand you edibles
they're like yo you need some edibles
bro and I will take but then if I'm not
an edible zone that night I just pass
them on to friends Bobo got all of my
excess edibles he was a lit up that's
pretty fun I'm afraid you guys I ate a
bunch of edibles at the last secret
session I I don't even know a lot of
edibles I had a lot of THC in my body
I'm gonna guess somewhere between 800
and 1500 milligrams of THC in my body I
was challenged I was having a rough time
and then our friends at teensy TNT
extracts gave me a 1000 milligram edible
and I ate it for breakfast the next day
on my way to work and by the time I got
to work it felt like I had wrapped a
vise around my brain and I was trying to
function on half speed all day so I've
been afraid of edibles since then to
tell you the truth and I haven't eaten
any it's been quite a while I don't know
if I'll do it for a little while
probably go see fish and eat a couple
hundred milligrams at the fish that
might be what has to happen all right
you guys let's get to the point let's
get to the point the point of this
podcast I received an email from a
friend let me open up this email I've
got a save right here on the phone this
dude signed his name as just a noob
trying to learn and then he called
himself ban so noob trying to learn this
question was great you asked a lot of
great [ __ ] and you really sparked a
great podcast in my opinion so let me
read the email the email goes like this
greetings Jeff first off I want to say
thank you for the kick-ass podcast and
then you have taught me so much in these
weekly sessions they make my Monday
morning commute tolerable dude that's
why I put him out Monday morning so your
weekend doesn't hire you sue your week
doesn't have to start with a shitty
Monday you start off with some kick-ass
podcast material I'm glad you noticed
thanks for checking it out so he goes on
to say while I have yet to grow by
because of where I live the topic none
less consumes much of my thoughts and I
tried to learn everything I can much of
the gained knowledge has led to
practices that have benefited my outdoor
vegetable garden even still I have what
may seem to be a stupid question dude
your question is not stupid I was so
excited when I read this I was like oh I
know a lot about this and I'm gonna get
to ramble on for a long time so I'm
gonna continue with email it says it
seems that many strains are named for a
special phenotypically Express trait
that manifests any particular smell
flavor or color now if you're lucky
enough to find one of those desirable
phenotypes the strain is known for when
popping seeds it seems that you can
enjoy that treat continually if you had
the foresight to take clones absolutely
correct that's why I encourage everybody
every time you grow a seed every time it
gets big enough to take a clone you take
a clone off of it before you flower it
because you don't know if that seed is
going to bear the most amazing cannabis
you have ever smoked in your life and if
you don't have a clone of it you might
try to kick yourself in the ass and
you're gonna be kind of mad about it
it's heartbreaking when you don't get a
cut of your of this super amazing herb I
grew some excuse me for the throat
clearing of course that's a bunch of
dads sorry about that
I grew some Holy Grail cush from DNA
genetics and it was honestly superb
cannabis if you can get your hands on
some Holy Grail cush seeds I recommend
that from that from another breeder
that's not even my brand get that from
DNA to genetics and maybe a reserve a
privada project by now but a Holy Grail
cush get the real deal the old-school
[ __ ] from DNA genetics it's amazing
cannabis I could not get the phenotype I
selected would not make clones they
would not root for [ __ ] I put them in
rock wool they'd shriveled up I put them
in a cloner they got funky and fell
apart I could not get that [ __ ] to clone
I'll never get to taste that flavor
again my friend pops is an old guy he
says that was one of the top-five best
pots he's ever smoked and Pop's isn't
all dude and hard to impress so the Holy
Grail cush was some special [ __ ] I could
not get it to root I wish I had a clone
of that it is gone one of my favorite
strains ever was the pea 91 and there
were some serious raids of large grow
facilities in the p90 one rumor has it
was lost in that raid somebody claims to
have it but I really don't know if that
is what they have got anybody can claim
to have it
so let's talk about something else you
said in here it seems that the strains
are named for a special phenotypically
expressed trade yes that's why the Sour
Diesel is called Sour Diesel because it
smells like diesel fuel I think they
tried to name the Girl Scout cookies
that because they wanted us to think
that it tastes like Girl Scout cookies
it's a little bit they called the Thin
Mint cut if he could the Finn mint they
tasted the Finn mint cookies and the
Thin Mint cut it could be close so that
part is totally accurate now here's
where what I really uh what I really
like to get into in this part of the
email it says ah
if the traits are passed from mother to
clone would it be likely that the same
traits would be present in nearly 100%
of the seeds if you were to make
feminized seeds from this plant you
would hope so because of logic but that
is not accurate and I took a bunch of
notes and I'll get into that I'm gonna
have to take a break here in a second
take a drink but let me keep reading the
email and then I'll take a drink take a
quick break just cuz you guys don't
wanna hear me clear my throat a thousand
more times the email goes on to say my
logic may be way off on this as I am NOT
a botanist or geneticist but if if it
does play out like this then why don't
the seed companies grow out several
plants to find that rare phenotype and
then make feminized seeds from that
plant any knowledge you can drop will be
greatly appreciated thanks bro from just
a noob trying to learn then he signs it
Ben noob this is a great question I'm
gonna press pause for just a second here
take a drink and then I'll be right back
all right you guys I'm back took a big
fresh drink I feel like I'm better I'll
be better for a minute I'm gonna take a
DAB and [ __ ] it all up again but I'm
better for now alright let's get back to
this email the part that got my
attention here at the end said if the
traits are passed from mother to clone
would it be likely that the same traits
would be present in nearly 100% of the
seeds no a clone you're taking a cutting
from an existing plant and that plant is
making a root of course right and then
you're getting a clone so all the traits
are passed because there is no
opportunity for any other chromosomes or
genetics or traits to be introduced into
that cut there's nothing you're not
gonna pull DNA out of the air to change
the trait so yes that one will be
exactly like the mother that it came
from now when we're working with seeds
we have the opportunity for variation
because we're using pollen that has
chromosomes from the grandparent
you're not only giving parents not
you'll not only getting chromosomes from
that selected phenotype but you're
getting chromosomes from whatever that
plant is a cross up so let me back up a
little bit something that I want to
mention we do search for those selected
phenotypes that you mentioned right now
I'm making a rise f2s which means I made
in a rise plant or rot and a rise strain
which I took Daybreaker as the male and
I put Daybreaker pollen on a golden goat
female and I took those seeds and what
came out of that I named that arise so I
found a beautiful male I've got a studly
male he produces the structure I want
the aroma I want he makes resin this
male plant is a stud so I've got that
and then I've got I think right now I've
got three or four gorgeous arise females
that I need to pull it pick one of those
because I want to take that a rise male
and I want to put that pollen on that
arise female and make a rise f2s and I'm
doing that by selecting the perfect
phenotype of the perfect male and the
perfect female to bring out the traits
that I'm looking for now I could screw
that all up I could bring out a bunch of
recessive traits and it could be a total
disaster and I'll have to go back and
find a different male and female and do
it all over again but that's why I grow
out a bunch of them myself before I try
to sell them or give them away to
anybody I make sure to dry probably a
hundred of those by myself before
anybody else will even see them so we do
look for those phenotypes we find those
perfect phenotypes and sometimes a cross
will be made that wasn't intended to
smell like something I don't think that
tangi I don't think that the guy that
made tangi I think that was Crockett I
don't think Crockett was like I want to
make tangi I think tangi should be Caleo
and this whatever the hell are used I
forgot but this orange plant uh I don't
think he was like I want to make tangi I
think he crossed some [ __ ] and it came
out and tastes like tangerines and he's
like that's tangi I think that's how
that came I don't think Sour Diesel I
don't think anybody was like I want to
make it strain that tastes like diesel
feel I think it was actually named
because of that so they selected that
one now let's talk about something else
you said why don't we use those selected
phenotypes we do and then if I'm gonna
make feminized seeds from that selected
phenotype I'm going to treat so I'm
gonna take two clones of the same plant
the selected phenotype that has the
traits that we like the one that so
we'll say grateful dog I've made
feminized seeds of grateful dog
I've grown a bunch of my own grateful
dog seeds I found the one that is
stellar so I take two clones of that I
reverse one and I put that reversed
pollen onto the female grateful dog and
now I make grateful dog seeds now
sometimes those grateful dog seeds look
like chem dog and sometimes those
grateful dog seeds look a little bit
more like San Fernando Valley OG Kush
but a lot of them look very much like
the grateful dog clone that I reversed
and started with and then will get a
little a little bit of variation that's
a little closer to the chem but more og
and then a little more og but closer to
the cam and then you'll see blends of
the traits it's kind of like making kids
you know like your sister might look a
little different from you but you could
definitely tell you're from the same
gene pool it's just gonna vary a little
bit more from so you're gonna see traits
of grandmas what I'm saying you're gonna
see traits of grandpa's what I'm saying
and sometimes you might see great
grandparent traits so let me refer back
to my notes here to keep myself on topic
because I'm getting way way off of what
I'm trying to say so we do search for
those phenotypes so that's how we make
our f 2s and then we do reverse those to
make our feminized seeds I breed with my
second and third generations from those
select I make my second and third
generations from those selected plants
and I was talking about picking one
female and one female something else or
one male and one female something else I
also do I will take multiple females of
the same strain and one male of that
strain and hit three or four different
females with that male pollen and that
way I've got I can see the variation I
can see that this girl produces more
resinous offspring I can see that this
girl produces tall and lanky offspring
so I don't want to breed to that one
again let's go ahead and get rid of that
I could see that this one over here
produces really lanky plants that stink
really well but don't make a lot of
resins so maybe I don't want to breed to
that one so I'll go and hit multiple
females so that way I could find the
best breeding plants that I can use so
I'll also hit different females of
different strains in that room with that
male so I'll put four females so when I
do this over eyes f2 it's about to
happen pretty soon I'll probably put two
maybe three females of a rise in there
to be honest and then I'm gonna probably
put seven or eight maybe nine or ten
females of other strains in there there
will be a grateful dog in there I'm
gonna put
Goldin go in there to take it backwards
a little bit I've got some other stuff
that's gonna go in there I've got some
crosses I made that'll go in there then
I'm gonna hit all of those with pollen
and then we'll see what comes of all of
that progeny there'll be a whole bunch
of great stuff in it all right let's get
myself back on track he said my logic
may be way off on this but I am NOT a
botanist or geneticist which I like they
said but if it does play all like this
then why don't the seed companies grow
out several plants to find the rare
phenotypes and then make feminized seeds
from that plant well that's kind of
exactly what they slash we do my friend
I hope I explained that in a way that
makes a lot of sense to you one thing I
want to go back over is the word
phenotype I hear a lot of people say
phenome it's a fimo Phe and fnot
phenotype a phenotypic expression
fino not phenome just just to make you
something cooler in your circle so when
you're making seeds and those seeds do
come out of course variation is natural
that's something that we expect we can't
control it completely if you want to
make something that I did that I didn't
even realize I was kind of I was doing
something out of the norm
I made feminized seeds and then I found
my favorite my favorite phenotype out of
that batch of feminized seeds and then I
hit that feminized plant with the
original pollen that I made feminized
seeds from and the progeny from that was
super stable and I did it again and then
I tried to reverse one of those plants
and I could not get it to reverse I
could not make the plant herm I could
not change the sex of that plant to make
more feminized seeds with that
generation of that progeny and it was
super impressed with the stability of
that plan that plan is still around it's
been named GD 77 a lot of people ask me
about my naming schemes they're very
random grateful dog was Gd 1977 is one
of my favorite years of the Grateful
Dead so GD 77 it's the Grateful Dead 77
female I love it it's in the mother room
right now that's one of my favorite
keepers I've probably had that one for I
don't even know how long I really can't
remember I've had it for a super long
time long time eight years I'll say
eight years I've had that clone
let's get back on track here I like the
variation that's what I'm saying
variation is cool when you're making
seeds I like variation I don't want
every seed to grow out just like the
picture in the package because
everyone's got that one I want a little
bit of variation that means that the
grower down the street that bought those
seeds doesn't have the phenotype that
I've got and that means that there might
be something better in there that means
you can always keep growing more seeds
that's why always that's why I love see
you might find something better than
what you've already got
sometimes if somebody loses a plant or
if something doesn't root when you try
to clone it I always look at the bright
side that means I get to grow more seeds
because see the way to go seeds have
vigor you can find new [ __ ] in there
every every strain that you're smoking
every clone that you've ever grown that
came from a seed right it had to so uh
the variation of course you could
stabilize that just by by breeding make
f2s make f3s by the time you get to have
five those seeds will be super stable
you'll start making seeds that produce
almost clones once you get to the f6
generation probably 90% of the seeds
that you plant are going to look just
like the picture on the package if the
breeder did it properly alright guys I'm
gonna take a DAB in a drink and I'm
gonna get another email to you before I
do that I want to give a big shout-out
to our buddy the newb that sent us this
email I really appreciate it I like
talking about feminized seeds I like
talking about making seeds I like
talking about breeding that's some of my
favorite [ __ ] so if you have more
questions about that send him to me grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I will
read your emails on a future episode
guys I need a drink and a dab bear with
me play some reggae music Andy and hang
out for a second
[Music]
music
Wow sometimes that means the light maybe
that's all the time it's gonna be easy I
saw it tomorrow wanna and get still hope
the weakens and fly
I'm feeling very good about myself a
belonging feeling good damn that's there
from there my smoke the marijuana yet
say your bone Dobie kids
[Music]
Marie Bona
alright ladies and gentlemen I am back
took a drink did not take some dabs this
time I think I have a voice I think my
throat was gonna hold up for at least a
couple more emails alright let's get you
another email
this one says Rasta Jay recently
discovered my latest batch of girls are
not as innocent as I would like yes they
are flat ass full of seeds my question
for you is if there are any dead
giveaways to determine if they were
pollinated or simply herm I did have a
sneaky male get by me until about week
three I had him labeled wrong and stuck
him in the flower room I'm hoping this
is the case and not a her issue then he
continues to give me reasons why his
plants may have harmed and Doody out of
mail he [ __ ] up you got a boy in there
that male at 3 weeks he busted or not be
pollinated your girls do you know what
that male was that's my question now if
you know what that male plant was you
may have accidentally just bred some
[ __ ]
keep those seeds the draw them out see
what you got yeah I'm pretty sure that
that maildrop pollen it only takes about
14 days for some of those studly or
males to just start blowing pollen
everywhere so if you had them in there
until about week three I'm pretty sure
that's who hit those girls with pollen
from the list of things you mentioned
that may be reasons why those plants
harmed it does not look like Lee to me
the recent switch of lighting that would
not do it the site Fox sailing emission
that's cuz they got too hot I don't
think that made them firm so you had a
dude in there you guys when you have
male if you were growing from seed or if
you have a male plant
I have males in my stable I got a couple
big fat male arise plants in there I got
Solomon just chillin he's kicking it
it's like three feet tall but if you're
going from Seaton you got boy plants
those boy plants will drop pollen I've
actually got a strawberry tangi banana
male plant in a very small pot it's
getting root bound and I can see male
flower clusters forming on the top if I
don't get that out of there in the next
ten days he will drop all that pollen
will come from there so if you're if
you're growing from seed keep an eye on
those pollen sacks and if you don't want
seeded plants if you don't want pollen
don't be lazy get those males out of
there this dude's a perfect example of
why you don't want to have males in your
garden he's got seeds now that brings me
to something I've wanted to say for a
little while and haven't had the
opportunity you're running a garden and
there's some [ __ ] that needs to be done
do it today don't do it tomorrow
why
why wait that's your garden that's your
love that's your medicine that's your
product hello if you're going for
commercial if you're growing from
medicinal if you're growing just for
love do that [ __ ] today those plants are
alive you wouldn't if your dog was
hungry and your dog needed water you
wouldn't make the dog wait till tomorrow
why do you make the plants wait all of
those plants they're yours you gotta
care for me respect the plants anything
that needs to be done in the groom if
that bulb is dirty or if that bulb is
dead that lens is dirty if that ducting
is funky don't do that [ __ ] tomorrow do
that [ __ ] today don't be a lazy [ __ ]
get in there clean your garden take care
of that [ __ ] do it today
love your plants that garden that crop
is only gonna be in flower for 63 days
56 63 maybe 70 days if you're going hard
why not make every day count get in
there do that [ __ ] right do it today put
some love into those plants I'll quit
bitching at you I'm sorry I feel like I
kind of got on you just love your plants
you guys get in there take care of that
[ __ ] you claim to love your garden love
it all right I've got another message I
want to read remember a few episodes ago
we had a listener send an email asking
about recommendations for dispensaries
in Denver and I took a screenshot of his
latest message he sent me this message
on Instagram and it says Rasta Jeff
wanted to thank you for reading my email
on your podcast and for recommending
natty REMS my wife and I loved our trip
I wanted to let you know that stitcher
has all of your episodes starting at
episode 40 all the way to the current
episode keep those beautiful Instagram
images coming from our friend fats
that's a great message to read there's
so much good [ __ ] in there ah man I'm
glad you enjoyed natty REMS I'm glad
Colorado was super kind to you I'm glad
that you and your wife had a great trip
I'm also glad to hear that all of the
episodes starting at episode 40 are on
stitcher that's awesome that means that
everybody can listen all the way back to
episode 40 it's probably 44 ish by now
it's 45 by the time this comes out that
means they're gonna keep a hundred
episodes on there that's cool awesome so
there are a hundred episodes of this
podcast available on stitcher you guys
if you want to go listen to 100 episodes
of the show I encourage you to go back
and listen to old episodes one of my
favorites I think is the scheduling your
perpetual grow episode that episode that
should have been a million dollar book
idea so make sure you listen to that one
for me if you haven't heard that one go
listen to it that's that's a great
episode I think it's number 72 I'm gonna
be a responsible podcast host and press
pause and go make sure what number that
is
alright I found the information I wanted
to find but I want to let you guys know
something funny that I just did my buddy
John hunt gave me a pencil dabber it is
made out of green Stardust glass and
it's got some colored tips and a colored
eraser and or a colored tip where the
pencil mint would be the color tip of
the eraser and would be it's made out of
glass it's meant to be used as a dabber
and my high-ass just picked it up and
tried to write a [ __ ] note on my
notepad with the dabber pencil so
shoutout to cannabis and THC for that
[ __ ] you guys the episode I was actually
referring to his number 73 make sure you
check out episode number 73 it's
scheduling a perpetual grow feel like
that episode should have been a million
dollar episode while we're going through
it check out number 76 about phenyl
hunting and then if you want to learn
about outdoor our friend Jesse comes by
episode number 79 definitely go back and
check out 73 and number 55 is one of my
favorite episodes if you're new to the
podcast make sure you check out 55 you
know I've thought about going back and
releasing some of the older episodes on
like a Thursday like a midweek episode
so maybe you want some of those older
episodes fall out of the feed once I put
so many episodes in that there's like 50
more that I can repost I'll go back and
put those up on a Thursday or something
so that they're still in the feed you
guys can listen to them cuz there are
some great episodes that need to stay up
for a little longer
alright let's get the show back on track
you guys big shout out to our friend
fats I do appreciate the interaction
dude next time you're in Colorado give
me a heads up we'll get together we'll
smoke some turps we'll take some selfies
we'll have a good old time you guys if
you want to send me a message or an
email or if you want to hit me up
somehow email me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll read your message on a
future episode I will answer your
questions if you want to follow me on
instagram it's at ireon der score
genetics if you want to follow me on
facebook just search for the grow from
your heart podcast I would appreciate it
in an upcoming episode my buddy Sammy
sent me an email asking about easy
cloners I'm gonna talk about that a
little bit and I will also talk about
how to set your email to the appropriate
Tempranillo question about my dream grow
I'm gonna kind of talk about that on an
upcoming episode then I also have an
episode of another question from a
listener I've got an episode about
identifying issues in your garden and
then in a future episode I will talk
about how to treat and prevent most of
issues and/or problems so if you guys
have some content that you would like me
to talk about I encourage you to send me
an email most of the episodes lately
have come from listener questions this
podcast this comes from my heart but
this podcast is for you this isn't for
me this is for you and I love doing it
so if you give me some content I would
love to read your stuff on the air could
you guys go and get you grow and help
you guys out if you got something that
you like the seigneur not even all that
social media stuff all you gonna do is
email me grow from your heart a
hotmail.com you can remain anonymous and
won't see your name on the air I'll keep
you safe I don't know what state you're
in so I don't want to get you in any
trouble you guys make sure you check out
the podcast on iTunes and stitcher don't
forget that most of the episodes are
available on ira genetics colorado
dot-com i think that is all i have got
for you this week that's all I got for
you guys I'm gonna give a big shout outs
manager Spence also a big shout-out to
Rasta Seb make sure you check me out in
seven days until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
right
do it for the Terps
you