[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 147 to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and Congress eat
and try to feel a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
rock - Jeff - thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots been hoarding their
music on my podcast big shot - cat - the
entire mystic Reece crew
hey guys I'm starting this podcast off
kind of bummed out I'm disappointed in
myself I'm disappointed in technology
you guys I [ __ ] up you guys I recorded
a marvelous podcast with the davon
granny with Bret from Evo labs and of
course our friend Lindsay the traveling
stoner this evening I pulled out my zoom
h6 I took out my trusty memory card I
threw it my macbook and the files are
all there I can grab the files and I can
move them to my macbook but for some
reason none of that [ __ ] is playable so
none of the material that I recorded
with Gavin granny will be aired on this
podcast unless one of my tech-savvy
friends is able to get this SD card and
pull this information off of there in a
usable format because so far I'm [ __ ]
I tried for about an hour all I did was
frustrate myself I was not able to get
it going so let me turn down the music
and say this a little bit better you
guys the dab and granny podcast that I
recorded is lost it's available on her
Facebook we did a Facebook live video of
it but I think that's the only way
you're going to hear or see any of that
episode granny I apologize technology
[ __ ] me I don't know what else to say
Brett I apologize Lindsey I apologize
the bad news is the podcast is lost and
gone for [ __ ] ever technology aided
Technology kicked my ass you can't win
every time the good news however is that
Davin grannies got to come back to the
show and Brett's got to come back and
Lindsey has to come back and we have to
do another podcast I think I want to do
a podcast with granny by herself and
with Brett by himself and then a podcast
with the group together I think granny
should be on the podcast kind of
frequently because she has a lot of
great [ __ ] to say so I actually think
granny needed she had so much to say I
encouraged her to start her own podcast
was something that actually said when
she was here so I apologize you guys I
advertise that like we're gonna have an
amazing episode for you today it's not
going to be the episode that you
expected but I'm going to do my best to
make it amazing so everybody that was on
the episode that [ __ ] up I invite you
guys all to come back it was a great
episode we hung out at the canna Canyon
we smoked so much hash that it was
ridiculous we had a few friends stopped
by poppy and chosen one
pop deep glass art and chosen one glass
art showed up hung out with us took some
dabs Aaron hung out for a little while
so shout outs everybody that tried to
make that podcast happen I'm gonna move
forward and quit talking about that
let's talk about some positive things
more positive stuff you guys the other
night I got to see Joey Coco Diaz it
comedy works in downtown Denver you know
anything about me you know that I love
comedy you also know that I love comedy
works in downtown Denver I think that
Comedy Works downtown is probably the
best comedy club on the planet if it's
the second it's the second best to the
comedy store in Los Angeles California
other than that Comedy Works is the best
comedy club in the world now since I'm
talking about comedy you guys our son
Joey Coco Diez that is one of my that
might be my favorite damn comedian right
now that dude blew the roof off of
Comedy Works hey guys Joey Diaz walked
out onstage and he grabbed the mic now
before he could get to the mic
he got a standing ovation Joey walked
out to a standing ovation he grabbed the
mic and he said what up you bad
[ __ ] and that's just the way
Joey starts the show and I knew it was
gonna be a party from then he had this
little strut in his stride the whole
time Joey was killing it the show was
hosted by a comedian whose name I cannot
recall he was a new guy he's got some
dreadlocks
he's a very entertaining dude there's a
another comedian whose name I cannot
remember who was the opening act then
there was a feature act whose name was
Rick who I've seen several times he's
pretty good he did say everyone's trying
to do a bunch of weed jokes in Colorado
hey guys if you're a comedian and
aspiring comedian a touring comedian if
you're a funny guy you're coming to
Colorado chill out on the weed jokes
we've heard it all we've heard every
[ __ ] weed joke you're gonna tell
unless you got some super creative weed
joke we've heard it trust me that's for
the pros that's for the noobs we've
heard all the weed jokes so the opening
acts they both all three did a couple of
weed jokes that hosted a couple of we'd
joke so Joey barely talked about weed
but Joey smokes more weed than you Joey
eats more edibles than you and Joey
still is able to go onstage and put out
an amazing [ __ ] comedy show Joey had
me laughing Joey Coco Diaz you guys he
is the host of a podcast called the
Church of what's happening now he was in
a movie called The Longest Yard he's an
amazing comedian he's Joe Rogan's
favorite comedian if that tells you
anything
he had me laughing so hard that the size
of my stomach and ribs were hurting my
back was hurting in a weird way my
cheeks hurt there's a little spot like
right behind where my sun glasses would
rest on my head that [ __ ] hurt it felt
like tumors just squeezing my head it
was from laughing so hard and then I
told my buddy I was like I'm laughing so
hard I think I'm gonna cry
and I think Joey might have heard me
because when he heard I was gonna when
he heard that I was gonna cry think Heda
started hitting harder he's like oh
you're laughing now [ __ ] watch
this I had tears coming out of my left
eye my right eye was twitching weird I
haven't laughed that hard in a long time
and I probably won't laugh that hard
again cuz Joey was [ __ ] incredible he
blew the roof off of Comedy Works much
left to Joey Coco Diaz much loved to
Comedy Works and also a big special
thank you to my friend Baker Baker I
truly appreciate what you do for me I'm
always treated like a VIP at Comedy
Works I appreciate that
also shout-out to my friend buzzy for
buying the tickets you guys I got a
sweet deal with my buddy buzzy he buy
his tickets and I Drive uh and then we
go see comedy shows and it's [ __ ]
amazingly fun so shout out to everybody
involved that was a great night shot
it's my new friends that I made that
night let's talk about other positive
things that happened in my life last
night you guys I got to see one of my
favorite bands
Joseph Israel and the Jerusalem band
they were in my hometown of Pueblo
Colorado they were ten minutes away from
my house at the Bruges Ale House all I
do is drive over there find parking
March on in and get my reggae on it was
local it was amazing
I shot it to the Bruges Ale House that
club is great it's probably the best
venue in Pueblo right now ah there are a
couple theaters they compete but I'm
gonna give that place the number one
venue for the vibe I they got a back
door that rolls up you're right on the
Riverwalk you can see the river right
behind you the sound is good in there
the vibe is good it was a great place
the band oh my goodness Josef Israel and
the band tour yeah because I've been
seeing Joseph Israel for probably I've
been watching his band for probably ten
years this was I've seen several of
their shows I've seen this band progress
and come a long long way and last
night's show is the best show that I've
ever seen them do it was the second to
last show on their tour and you could
tell that they just played until they
were done tonight's show they're not
gonna have a lot of energy cuz they wore
themselves out last night whoever sees
them tonight I'm sorry I drained all
their energy ah my favorite album from
Joseph Israel is an album called gone
are the days I think it was his original
release they played there probably 15
songs on there I think a couple of more
like dub remixes so there's like
probably 10 songs in there they must
have played seven or eight of them and
they played all my favorites that I
could yell out of song and they would
play it for me
they weren't gonna play a song called
the truth is one of my favorites and
there was a break you know when the
musicians are like tuning their guitars
they're all talk and it taking a drink I
yelled out truth and I was like right in
the front row so Joseph looked at me
like oh yeah
and they talked about it for a minute
and they said we haven't played this we
don't practice this we haven't played
this since we recorded the gone are the
days album and they started seeing the
chorus they just started doing like a
really cool acapella harmony version of
the chorus and then once that chorus
ended the guitar player started playing
the guitar lick and they played the song
truth for me it wasn't tight and it
wasn't perfect but you know what it was
beautiful that my friends tried to play
that song for me so much love to
Joseph's Israel and the Jerusalem band
and the entire crew at Bru's Ale House
had an amazing time I got to smoke after
the show with a couple of the guys
something I should mention I have been a
huge fan of a bass player by the name of
Chris Meredith he plays with Joseph
Israel in the Jerusalem band but he's
also known as a recording artist in
Jamaica and he's also well known for
playing with Stephen Marley I walked
into the building and Chris Meredith was
just standing there talking to Joseph
Israel and I realized he was gonna be
the blade bass player for the show that
night they put a huge smile on my face
because he recorded Joseph's album with
him he went on tour for the first tour
and then he had to go back to Jamaica
and he took off for a little while so he
didn't see him on tour with Joseph it
was great to see Chris and the original
drummer back together in the rhythm
section I actually got to meet the
original keyboard player from the gone
are the days album we got to talk about
the recording we got to talk about a few
things got to talk about the tuff Gong
recording studio Jamaica
really nice to hang out some Jamaican
rastas some some faithful folks folks
with good vibes folks with positive
energy with good things to say you guys
I recommend that you listen to Joseph
Israel in the Jerusalem band I just
talked about for like five minutes we're
gonna move on from that but big shout
out much love much respect much good
vibes from Joseph Israel the jerusalem
band last night i had a great time shout
out to the friend that went with me i
had fun dancing we got to laugh at some
some crazy drunk people drunk people are
super entertaining i am so glad i do not
consume alcohol anymore i just smoke mad
cannabis there may have been a little
smoke session in the back of the club at
the end of the night that was a good
time
shout out to everybody alright let's
move on to some grow knowledge you guys
been talking about my weekend and my
week long enough
let's talk about Gro knowledge a few
episodes back I was asked how to handle
grasshoppers and what I've noticed is
everybody is getting bombarded with
grasshoppers and their outdoor cannabis
grow this year the number one way that
you can get rid of your grasshoppers is
just to clean up if you can mow all the
grass mow all the weeds get rid of
anywhere for them to live get rid of all
the stuff for them to eat the
grasshoppers won't want to come around I
understand that your neighbors probably
have a big-ass pile of grass and leaves
and [ __ ] in their yard that you cannot
do anything about it's illegal to go
over there with the torch and just burn
that [ __ ] down so if you're having
problems with grasshoppers somebody
recommended to me garlic and fermented
garlic sprays to help keep grasshoppers
and other pests away I assumed that this
would work on most insects and most
living creatures if you ferment some
garlic or mush garlic up into a spray
and spray that around your plants on and
or around your plants and on the
perimeter of your plants most bugs are
going to stay away from that and
definitely you will not have any
vampires so if you're worried about
vampires in the garden you could double
up on the garlic spray you'll be just
fine so shout out to the person that
told me about fermented garlic sprays
and using them in my garden to keep away
grasshoppers outdoors because I don't
grow outdoors myself very much but a lot
of our friends do and I think you know
the next episode may feature our buddy
Jesse and we're gonna talk about some
outdoor stuff shout out to Jesse if
you're listening to this call me dude
let's plan this episode so we can get it
recorded well record it at my house
we'll use my computer we won't use the
zoom h6 because I'm paranoid to that
thing I'm afraid it's gonna break and
not record the damn show again so
probably won't do that ah grasshoppers
yes emails I've got some emails here at
my phone people have asked some
questions you guys asked great questions
I want to give a shout out to everybody
that sends me an email I'm gonna try to
read all of the questions over time on
the air but I'm a little bit backed up
so I'm gonna have to record more
episodes anyway here is an email they
came from let's see how did he sign it
he signed it as our 4/20 so shout out to
Mazza 4/20 his email says hoping you can
read my questions on the show been
loving the show helps me get through my
day at a mind-numbing job with robots do
you work with robots or just like people
who are unaware and people who are
programmed to act like robots I'm
curious you know he said questions for
the show when you flip to twelve twelve
or eleven thirteen DJ short style how
long till you want to go from
metal-halide to HPS
now I want to talk about this 12 12 or
11 13 DJ short style thing what Mazar
420 is asking is when I change my light
cycle from my vegetative stage either 24
hours on or an 18-6 cycle or maybe a
16-8 depends on where you are I when I
change my light cycle to my flowering
phase which would normally be 12 12 or
he says the 11 13 DJ short style let me
talk about that for a minute
DJ short is a well-known breeder he's a
great speaker he's an author is well
educated and very passionate about the
cannabis plant
DJ short breeds amazing strains he is
known for the blueberry DJ shortbread
the flow so there's something in DJ's
shirts catalog that you have smoked and
you have enjoyed they came from all DJ
now DJ does a trick when he is flowering
his plants he does not run them for 12
on 12 off he does 11 hours on and 13
hours off
his theory on this is that you will see
broader variance in fee no typical
expression from your plants so if you're
a breeder and you're looking for
phenotypes this extra hour really lets
the plants express themselves and show
the variation and show their potential
it also will save you one hour of
electricity over a sixty-five day cycle
which is gonna be 65 hours kilowatt
hours that you're not spending on your
lights
it's also gonna be an hour resting off
of your air conditioning it's also going
to some people think it increases their
yields I tried it I didn't like what it
did to some of my plants I did like what
it did this some of my plants so it's
very plant specific it's strains
specific it may be phenotype specific I
have not experimented enough to know but
a lot of people in the community are
switching to the 1113 method it saves
money it saves time and if you've got
the right varietals it will work for you
one thing I've noticed some of my
heavier sativas didn't like it in the
beginning it took him a while to get
used to it
I liked my sativa is on twelve twelve
and then toward the end of the phase
that's when I would start dropping down
the timers they didn't seem to really
like it when I went 13 hours of darkness
right away so that catches us up to
speed on the DJ short 11:13 method now
he says how long once you do this flip
do you want to go from metal halide to
HPS that's his first part of his
question generally I let it go 10 to 14
days rocking the metal halide when I see
the bud starting to form when I see
those little pre buds and the pre
flowers just starting to pop up they're
getting a little dandelions that's
usually when I switch in that bulb if
you if you really want to go crazy do it
three weeks because I think when you
flip those plants are gonna stretch for
about three weeks and keeping that
halide bulb in there really I think
helps prevent them from stretching so
much so keep that halide in there for 10
to 14 days if you want to go extreme go
21 days but you may slow down bud
development at that point I like to
switch it in there about that 14th day
because that's what my buds are gonna
start happening one thing that you can
utilize that I've done and had great
success with is mix and match spectrums
use a little bit of metal halide and use
a little bit of HBS if you can so I had
a I've got a reflector it's called the
Gro Zilla and I haven't used it in a
long time I should fire it up and do
some experiments with it just
fun but this reflector holds two bulbs
and they say not to put more than a
thousand watt total in there it may say
1200 total so you could put two 600
bulbs in this one reflector what I did I
put a 600 watt high pressure sodium and
a 400 watt metal halide in there and
hung that bulb in a 5x5 hydro Hut and I
put nine three gallon pots under there
and honestly I grew some of the most
photogenic and most aromatic most
flavorful and most potent cannabis I
have ever grown came from that 5x5 Hut
with that mix spectrum light there was
some very impressive cannabis the only
problem was it didn't harvest what I
wished it would have uh when I heart
when I use a thousand watt HBS in one of
those huts with proper ducting and
venting and air conditioning I can pull
a pound and a half really close to two
pounds it's hard to hit two pounds in
those huts because you're really limited
on height and space so you gotta like
top them out and pull them out real far
and train them you can get a pound and a
half out of one of those huts when I did
the HPS metal halide combo I got right
about a pound in a corner so it didn't
do what I would expect I think that 600
watt light kind of didn't let it push
but the flavor and the aroma and the
potency made up for the lack of weight
because it was for me I was growing it
from my own head stash so I didn't need
a whole bunch all right so that's the
first party good question I would do it
somewhere between 14 and 21 days 10 days
if you're trying to go early 14 days is
about ideal 21 days if you're really
trying to keep those plants short
because that's that halide lamp is gonna
keep them from stretching on you as part
of why we do that so he also says also
was wondering how long once under 12 12
do you wait to switch your nutrients
from veg to bloom he also says hope to
hear my questions get answered on the
show sincerely massive 420 so he's
wondering how long from the day we
switch to 12:12 do we wait to switch our
nutrients from veg to bloom I kind of do
a slow transition I believe that your
plant is going to absorb somewhere
between 80 and 90% of its nitrogen that
all that all of it's going to observe
there's whole life it's gonna absorb
most of that through the vegetative
stage once you hit flowering once you
get to that second or third week of
flowering you're not gonna use a whole
lot of nitrogen just enough to keep the
leaves green and keep the plant moving
so nitrogen is gonna kind of fizzle out
so you can switch the nutrients right
away if you'd like to or
you can keep those nutrients going
slowly and taper so if you're if you've
got grow and you've got bloom maybe go
seven to ten days with that grow before
you pull out the grow nutrient and throw
in the bloom it or you can just switch
right away it's up to you it kind of
depends on the strains also Gorilla Glue
really likes to eat so I kind of stick
with my veg nutrients for an extra week
or two with the gorilla glue things like
flow-flow doesn't require a lot of food
flow will just grow like a
son-of-a-bitch so I'll switch flow right
away when I go 12:12 that day they get
fed their bloom nutrients they start
getting basically your first day of
bloom nutrients aren't very far off from
your last week of veg nutrients so it
shouldn't be too abrupt of a switch
either way but somewhere between that
first day and about 7 to 10 days in is
when I will totally have switched from
vegetable um nutrients it kind of
depends on the plant it kind of depends
on what I'm doing it kind of kind of
depends on the room the strain the brand
of nutrients if I'm using botanic or
bottled newts my switch from my veg
stage to my flower phase like I said is
not very different it's a base nutrient
it's cal-mag liquid karma and maybe a
little bit of what else am i using in
there potassium silicates and there
wouldn't be a whole lot else oh there's
a dog resting on my feet and I just move
my foot came from right in the head I'm
sorry puppy I didn't mean to do that boy
I'm sorry I apologize big shout out to
make the dog you guys make the dogs been
hanging out with me for a couple days a
cool-ass dog you guys would like him
sorry I just kicked your a the head boy
I feel bad everyone on the show hears me
apologizing I won't do it again buddy
I'll pet you so uh yeah my fedja newts
there'll be some what did I say bass
nutrients which would be the botanic air
pure blend pro grow and then you've got
some cal-mag in there maybe a little bit
of liquid karma and some potassium
silicates that's basically my veg mix I
would add something in there for roots
some sort of root inoculate use whatever
you would like you can use either the
plus life from veg bloom big shout-out
to veg bloom you could use the rhizome
mix the botanic air makes you could use
what am I think there's a there's one
product I'm really thinking I can't say
the name Oh G bio war use some OG bio
war on that [ __ ] to get your roots
going so add that to it for roots and
you got pretty much everything you need
there week one a flower you basically
want to feed the same thing that you've
been feeding for the last couple weeks
of veg
because your plants are just gonna start
transitioning so week one you've got the
option a week one to switch out that
pure blend Pro grow to the bloom formula
or you can do it at the start of week
two or definitely do it by week three
your plants are gonna need that much
nitrogen by week three and if you keep
going with the grow formula you may burn
them so you can go the first week or two
with your grow newts and then by week
three definitely switch all the way into
your flowering newts you don't need to
add everything by week three you really
don't need a lot at week three you
concerned introducing things slowly
maybe get some sugars in there at week
three you don't need a lot at week three
by week four or five and six that's
where things really start cracking
that's when you're gonna want to start
adding bud boosters whatever you gonna
use to make the weight a little thicker
or whatever you gonna use to sweeten it
up four or five and six is when all that
[ __ ] comes in so if you're running a
strain that likes a lot of nitrogen keep
those nitrogen nutrients coming keep
that base grow new coming for the first
couple of weeks if you've got a strain
that's got plenty of nutrients if your
leaves are nice and lush green if
they're dark green don't even worry
about that grow new go ahead and switch
it over to the bloom nutrients alright I
hope that answered your question I know
I used a botanic hair as a an example
that's the brand that I use in my
small-batch personal growth for myself
if I'm gonna smoke it it's probably
grown with botanic care I do plan on
doing a side by side between botanic
hair and veg bloom in the near future
and I will be completely honest about
what I see and I will share my
experience and my results here on the
podcast you guys make sure you support
botanic hair and veg bloom I've used
them both in different environments in
different scenarios that are both
wonderful products I can't wait to run a
side-by-side I've got a 5 by 5 Hut and
another 5 by 5 hydro Hut in a room with
very similar light with the same lights
they're on a flip box every 12 hours one
comes on one shuts off so we got a
flowering chamber that's always being
used I'm gonna do veg bloom on one side
I want to do botanic hair on the other
and I will completely post a ton of
pictures to my Instagram and I'll let
you guys know how it goes alright I want
to thank our friend Masdar for 20 for
sending me a great email that gave me a
lot of information to ramble off at you
guys I'm pulling up the next email here
on my phone the next email comes from he
signed it with his real name I don't
know they says hi my name is Kelvin I
let's see let's read this we have spoken
before but I have another question so I
live in Oklahoma City where
he gets pretty hot it can get into a
hundred or above in my garden room I was
wondering if a bigger carbon filter
would help me out any right now I'm
running a 400 watt high-pressure sodium
and a metal halide Apolo light with a
four-inch carbon filter and inline fan I
was thinking about getting an air
conditioner but I don't want to if I can
lower temps with the carbon filters
during the day the temps get from a
hundred and ten to a hundred and fifteen
thank you Jeff growers love dude 110 and
115 in your grow room that is
tremendously warm for your plants your
plants are freaking out development
stops growth and development stops
production stops inside your plant
around 85 90 degrees unless you're
introducing co2 if you're inducing co2
if you've got very high levels of co2
your plants can tolerate in the 90s 110
to 115 you're expressing the [ __ ] out of
those plants the buds are starting to
spread out your getting Airy buds
they're gonna be fluffy they're gonna be
small the plants are gonna be stunted
growth the humidity is probably getting
[ __ ] ridiculous in that room with that
type of heat the good thing about this
is you're not gonna have any bugs no
damn bug in the world is gonna want to
hang out 115 degree grow room so your
main question let's get to the point
here your question is well a carbon
filter help cool that room no not at all
carbon filter does not provide any
cooling you need you you need to
introduce cooler air into that room and
you need to remove the hot air from the
room a fan won't help you because it's
just gonna blow hot air around you need
to exchange the air you got to get that
heat out of there
maybe bigger ducting and a bigger blower
to blow the heat out but a bigger carbon
filter won't help you cool the room you
need an air conditioner ifit's a large
room get yourself a window model like
the window kind if it's a smaller room
and you don't have a window for it get
yourself one of those portable rolling
air conditioners I really like the
soleus 14,000 BTU portable air
conditioner they do not pay me they do
not sponsor me it's what I buy if I need
an air conditioner or rolling air
conditioner for a home grow or a small
grow that's what I go get is one of
those soleus 14,000 BTU it's a heater
it's an air conditioner and it's a
dehumidifier all in one unit
it's about waist-high it's only about
three feet tall it looks like
little r2d2 you guys and it's got a duck
that runs out and I think it's got a
duck they can come in also if you choose
to ducked in but I don't ducked in I
just let the air conditioner recycle the
air in the room is where that air comes
from so that air is already cool kind of
that's going into the compressor and
then it blows the heat through a duct a
four inch duct and you can mount that
duct wherever you want
I usually board up a window cut a four
inch hole through the window put a duct
mount onto that window and run that four
inch air conditioning duct right out of
there
that 14,000 BTU unit would be overkill
for your 400 watt HBS and your metal
halide apollo light i'm assuming that
your small grow room is inside of
another room since it's so small and I'm
not I'm not I'm not worried that you
have a small girl band I make it funny
but I'm just wondering is this grow room
inside of another room do you have this
like did you construct a small room
inside of a bedroom or this maybe a
closet also but if it's a small room
maybe you can air-conditioned that room
a little bit better and then duct the
heat out of your grow and just
air-conditioned the outside environment
so that you're bringing in cooler air
you just need cooler air in that room
carbon filters not gonna cool off the
air a fan is not gonna cool off the air
you actually need some freon in there
you need an air conditioner bro so I
hope that works I hope answered your
question big shout out to our friend
Kelvin he says we've spoken before I
remember seeing your name I remember
you're reading your email address bro
thank you for the email I encourage you
to send me more emails I will read your
questions and answer your questions on
the podcast all the time if anybody
wants to send me an email I would love
to help you out send me an email let's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com if
you want to follow me on twitter it's at
gfy each podcast check me out on
instagram you guys I post a whole bunch
of quality cannabis photography on
Instagram it's at Irie underscore
genetics i reaiiy rie underscore
genetics check that out you guys I have
to press pause for one quick second I'm
gonna take a DAB in a drink and I will
be right back with you yeah I just took
a big old fat dab of pineapple jack
shatter from tur pax and I dunked it in
OG ghost rain haze fresh Terps from our
friends at Evo labs but I feel like my
brain was put on a rocket and launched
into outer space and
it blew up like one of those beautiful
fireworks and then it all just came back
together and floated down into my head
but that's what happens when you dunk
your dad's in Terps and you take big ol
fat dabs whoo shots everybody involved
in making these Terps happen I had the
lab manager from Evo labs on the last
podcast and that's the one that the
memory card ate and we cannot listen to
so sorry Brett I wish we could have done
that but Brett that means you got to
come back on the show and smoke some
turps with me
I owe a huge thank you to dab and granny
and I owe a huge thank you to Brett
davon granny showed up with enough Terps
to dab out an army and Brett will try to
compete with that so big thanks to you
guys were showing up to the podcast too
well prepared also thanks to the canna
Canyon for letting me invade the small
corner of their facility I had four
couches and a table occupied and nobody
can hang out in that region because
we're doing the podcast I didn't mind if
people hung out but when they saw the
microphones come out and they heard me
talking they all just took off to be
polite I don't mind if they hang out I
like it I think it's cool I like the
ambience and the vibe in the background
all right I am rambling like a
[ __ ] hashtag they like it when I
ramble I wanted to share with you guys a
little progress on my most current
breeding project if you follow me you
know that I am a breeder
I am the head breeder for I read
genetics I am currently working with a
male plant that I call a rise the strain
is known as arised the male plant
himself has been named Solomon that is
King Solomon he is going to father many
children he will be the grandfather to
many children but Solomon is my male
plant
he is a and a rise plant which is a
cross of a golden goat female that was
pollinated by a Daybreaker male
Daybreaker came from gage green genetics
so much love and respect today - gage
green the Daybreaker is Joseph's og and
Kim D so there's gonna be a little bit
of og cush and Kim dog lineage in there
and then I crossed that - I put the
pollen from that male on to the golden
goat the golden goat is Island sweet
skunk and Romulan and a Hawaiian sativa
so you got that tropical tasty flavor i
pollinated it with that cushy skunky
funk flavor a little bit of everything
in my opinion mixed it all together and
it made a strain called a rise
I found three or four really great
phenotypes of the arize there's a very
golden goat reminiscent phenotype of a
rise I do not keep that one because I've
got golden goat it's too similar I get
rid of it there's one that's got this
sweet skunky funky you can't keep it in
a baggie without all your friends in
smoke some of that weed with me kind of
smell to it that's my favorite female of
the bunch then there's one that makes
really long skinny buds and I don't know
where it came from but it gives you this
hazy high I don't know where the haze
came from in the genetics but it just
makes your head melt your eyes just get
[ __ ] squinty you go dumb you just
start stuttering it's that phenotype is
great but you know there are three or
four key key phenotypes that I found I
have put all three of those phenotypes
not the golden goat dominant phenotype
but I've put my three favorite
phenotypes in a room with a male of this
same cultivar but the male of the same
strain from the same seed pack they're
all F wands so I put the F ones the male
and the female in a room this male I've
posted pictures up into my Instagram he
makes male flower clusters as long as my
arm which is very amazing for a male
plant to make buds like this it's
incredible it's got a little bit of
resin on it it smells very pungent it's
got a hint of vomit to the smell as a
breeder vomit is a good trait if you've
got a male plant that smells like vomit
or feet or a bar trash can
that is a good breeding plan that's
gonna pass on good good aromatic traits
so I've got that male and then I've got
let's see what else is in there there is
a golden goat female because I'm gonna
do a little bit of a golden goat
backcross there's a lemon skunk female
in there because I want to see what this
arised does to the lemon skunk and there
is a grateful dog female so there are
multiple themed phenotypes of the arise
so there'd be a rise f2s coming out very
soon it'll be tested by a bunch of my
people before they're available to you
guys but a lot of people get to test
them out then there will be grateful dog
to arise which doesn't even have a name
there will be golden goat to arise which
would be like a golden goat backcross
kind of and then there'll be lemon skunk
cross to arise which who knows what
that's gonna do that's gonna be amazing
both of those plants make a lot of resin
both of those plants have a really nice
structure I really see a lot of great
things so I'm excited about that they
are currently the date today is I'm
pressing my button on my phone it's the
14th they went into flour on the 3rd so
they're 11 days in the mail plant is
getting big old balls
his balls are starting you know when the
male plant starts to flower out the
balls point up but now they're starting
to hang his nuts are starting to hang
which means within the next four to six
days I'm gonna have pollen coming out of
there which may be a little earlier than
I wanted so I'm gonna move him over to
another room to keep him away from the
girls because the girls their pistols
the little you guys call him Harris
probably the little white pistols the
hairs on the plant that looks like a
dandelion
I want those nice and thick and stout
before I put that pollen on there so I'm
gonna move this boy to another area just
to keep him from dust and his pollen on
these girls too early and then once I
see all the girls have their pistols
nice and hairy nice and furry
I'd almost that tarantula look then I'm
gonna bring the boy over there and I'm
gonna just leave him in the room with
them overnight and then in the morning
as soon as lights come on I might give
him a little shake and that pollen is
gonna dust all those plants and then I'm
gonna do that probably four or five days
again or four or five days later I'm
gonna do that again
just let the lights come on and walk in
there and give him a little bit of a
shake and just get that pollen all over
all those plants so when I see a little
bit of a shake guys if you grab a male
cannabis plant that is in full flower
that's got pollen sacs hanging off of it
you could flick it like listen to I'm
gonna flick the microphone stand that's
all you got to do you flick it that hard
pollen goes everywhere everywhere so
after that I'll have to take a shower
off to change clothes I'll have to go
spray down any female plants that I do
not want receiving pollen it'll it'll be
some work but it'll be definitely
definitely worth it I have to change
clothes wash my dreadlocks before I go
to anybody else's garden I wouldn't
disrespect anyone else's garden like
that I'll put on specific clothes they
cover me up most of the ways that I just
drop them right in the washer it's a
chore but that's where my breeding
project is you guys the male is just
getting ready to draw a polity I'm I
just kicked the dog Ian I'm sorry boy
I'm sorry dude I didn't mean to kick you
his heads right here on my foot so every
time I get excited I move my foot give
him a good head kick
this ain't no UFC over here I apologize
so my plants are the breeding project is
11 days the males are just dropping
pollen the male is just rot starting to
drop on the females
almost ready to take it I'm gonna
separate them for a little bit just to
put some tension in the room then I'm
gonna reintroduce them together in a few
days and then once they pollinate it's
probably gonna be about six weeks before
those seeds are ready for harvest I'm
gonna let them go about seven I don't
wanna let me go too long but I want them
nice and done I want them hard then
we'll cut down the plants we will set
them all in individual areas over
individual containers and just let them
dry for a couple few days once they I
will will pre trim them at that point
will give them I will just take off all
the big leaves when we cut them down
most of the families will be gone so
well dry it we'll hang them we'll let
them dry and then you just take the
plants and you cut basically cut one
stick off and I put on rubber gloves and
hold it over like a pie plate and just
start crushing up the buds and you can
just hear the seeds fall out it's like
you're smoking old-school Mexican brick
weed and all those seeds respond
tainting to tainting to take they tink
tink tink into the pie plate just
crumble them up with my fingers and then
I push all the weed up to one side and I
tipped the pan and all the seeds roll
down to the other side and I take those
out put them in a jar it gets carefully
labeled of what it is I leave the lid
open for a couple few days just so that
if there's any moisture in there that
those seeds will try out so now I've got
a mason jar full of well labeled seeds
and then once I've got all of them I'll
weigh the seeds get a good estimate of
how many seeds I've got then I'll send a
lot of those seeds out to friends of
mine with a note that says these are
testers please test these take a lot of
pictures make a lot of notes let me know
what you got I will give some to local
people and the requirement is if you
find a champion I get a clone of that
sucker you've got something good I get
that I get a clone of the best one
please that's kind of how that goes I'll
give you some tester packs it'll be uh
probably looking at 12 weeks before
anything will even be done from this
point but there will be seeds in twelve
weeks they'll be testers people check
them out I'll post pictures of what
comes of it because I'll grow a bunch of
them by myself the dog just got up in
life because I kicked him in the head
I'm sorry boy sorry I didn't mean to
kick you
hey guys don't ever kick your dog in the
head love your dog scratch your dog and
breed good cannabis ladies and gentleman
that is all I've got free this week I
wanted to update you on my breeding
project I hope you enjoy following along
with my breeding project I'll give you
another update in a couple of weeks and
let you know how things are going you
guys I'm gonna wrap up the show if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast send me an email it's girl from
your heart at hotmail.com I'd love to
hear from you make sure you follow me on
all of the social media you guys and
also now that the show is over go to
iTunes to go to the iTunes Store search
for the podcast sections there's a
review section no wait I [ __ ] that up
you got to go to podcast then you got to
go to grow from your heart then when the
girl from your heart dissection pops up
there's a little just a little icon of
the show click on that one and then go
click on ratings and reviews and then
type in a review let me know what you
think of the show and I'll read your
review on a future episode
while you're there you've got the option
to give me some stars you know I want 5
stars but I'm not gonna beg for five
stars give me the amount of stars that
you feel I deserve and I would truly
appreciate it
because I want to thank everybody for
listening to the show once again big
shout out to make the dog shout it's my
Buddy Baker shoutout to Comedy Works
Jonathan Joseph Israel shout out to Joey
cocoa Diaz shout out to each and every
one of you you guys love one another
because I'm gonna sign off for now
shout outs my ninja spin sand until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
let's rule of
tribute things gonna be right when it's
right there Jules
[Music]
why don't we begin some of a lot the
most time
[Music]
they made millions off the slave
[Applause]
[Music]
summons a pestilence awarded money said
I know
[Music]
the race might be hard but it must be
[Applause]
[Music]
you