[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 148 grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
new grower if you're a professional
grower the good news smoker are a
dedicated dabber if your cannabis
activists reason someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Ross - Jeff want to thank you guys again
for joining me as always I want to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic wreaths band for letting
me use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew hope everybody's
having a great week ladies and gentlemen
this episode features myself and our
buddy white Mike make sure you follow
white Mike's Facebook page Pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws make sure you
support all the sensible cannabis laws
you guys I don't adieu too long of an
intro I'm just gonna let the music play
I want to get right back I'll be joined
by our good friend white Mike hangout
[Music]
I think that's how the podcast is gonna
start is with a big fat [ __ ] blue dream
so you guys we are back we're here it's
gonna save the studio this can this
officially be a studio I think when all
the gears that we can call it a studio
that's fair so today we've got the
pocket studio we're recording on the we
are recording my mouth is [ __ ] high
my brains not as high as my mouth I
think we're recording on the zoom h6
handy recorder you guys I'm doing a
little test run I want to make sure that
I've got this figured out because I'm
gonna go record with dad and Granny
again so here on the podcast with me in
the the makeshift pocket studio is our
buddy white Mike welcome back bro
thanks man let's do this part that I
always like to do tell everybody that's
listening where they can stock you on
social media so that they can check you
out while they're listening
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook and at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter
web low for sensible cannabis laws what
kind of stuff are we gonna see if we go
to the Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
Facebook page pretty much any marijuana
news related event I can find that's
even remotely relevant to the US gets
linked up there
I appreciate what you do for the
cannabis industry and for the cannabis
community thank you man I'm not I'm a
working man and I'm always at aggro
anybody that listens to the podcast
regularly knows that I am the lead
cultivator of a hundred light facility
so that keeps me busy I've got a day job
most of the politics happens during the
day so when there's politicking to be
done when there's uh people have to go
to City Council meetings and speak and
show support when that stuff is to be
done Mike is the guy that goes and does
that in my place because I am stuck at
the grow so thanks for doing that kind
of stuff thanks for having a Facebook
page to keep our community together
thanks to all the people that helped
with Mike Mike organizations and all the
people that join up with Mike to go to
all these rallies to go protest things
big shout out to all those people if
there are a couple of protal what's the
word activists in town I couldn't think
of the word act there are several now
it's kind of nice that I'm not totally
alone anymore do you want to give two or
three of them some shoutouts anybody
that may deserve a big fat thumbs up
Juicy J has been doing a lot of stuff on
social media that I love
there's a guy named Brooks that's been
doing a ton of stuff on social media
right now lots of great infographic
memes for our side and our flight down
here he's been doing some amazing work
and I really appreciate it
some of his work shared to my page has
gotten record views and shares and stuff
like that so nice juicy J and Brooks
thanks for supporting the cannabis
community you guys we need people like
you on the team Mike dude awesome you
showed up with this orange flavor e
citrusy grapefruit hashed it's a little
more about that lemon thyme sugar wax
from rock and extracts it's a new Pueblo
company I really like it I took it to uh
just as something fun to take along with
me to a meeting of several uh
jab kids is the wrong term but it's the
closest one we got I guess but several
folks getting together davon and it
ended up being the talk of the table
which I thought was funny because we
were dab in raw herbs on distillate that
night - is this a fresh frozen product
how much do you know about that I'm
actually not sure on that particular
step the big part the big pitch of this
company is this it's a proprietary mix
gasps okay extraction that explains a
lot to me somebody that knows a lot not
a lot but that smokes a lot of different
types of concentrates I can tell that
this that's why I asked if it was live
resin because your color and texture
color and texture are not what I'm used
to seeing from a butane extraction
unless it's live resin it is very very
close to what I see you call that color
it's a butterscotch color that's a
really good description of it it's not
orange it's not yellow and when it was
fresh it had a little more orange
yellowish pop to it okay but it's a
propane butane man yes I can see the
problem it's this is legitimately the
first propane hash I've ever dabbed I've
seen it made there's a great vice media
documentary where they go and interview
a guy building a propane extraction rig
in the the hash that comes out of that
is like frighteningly orange like cheese
at orange okay well what I've smoked a
bunch of propane hash oil from our
friends at altitude organic medicine
excuse me for that you guys I've smoked
a bunch of propane hash from altitude
and it's always white like completely
white and it's real lot it's kind of
mushy and it always stays really good
what I don't like about it is it kind of
makes my lungs feel sort of heavy it
gives me a butter long sort of feeling
um I over dab myself with some of this
one night I I way overheated my banger
and took an insanely hot dab just not
paying attention the last one I'd taken
a little cool so I was a little you know
job trying to make oh yeah and not while
I was coughing the cough seemed to go on
quite a while and for a minute I
considered is it the mixed gas but from
everything I've seen all the lab testing
it's it's totally clean okay like we
talked about lipids and plant fats and
all that kind of stuff on an episode
previous so I wonder if there are plant
paraffins and lipids and stuff like that
left behind in there that they're not
taking out either way it's marvelous
hash is what I wanted to get to the
flavors oh my goodness yeah it's like ah
at first it was like orgy and then I
waited a few minutes and as my mouth
dried up it turned to grapefruits just
straight-up grapefruits on my tongue it
was really delicious I didn't want to
take a drink for a while but I had to
except the grapefruit coating now it's
really nice nice good job on bringing
the good hash big shout out to rockin
extracts you said they're a Pueblo
company yeah they're the right at the
street from the shop that's pretty cool
yeah the good guys they make several
different products the other deliveries
better always be on time yeah they're
never let them over it's cute what the
manifest
can you walk over a product yep all
right um they uh they make it a couple
different products than I'm enjoying
right now they've also got the first
vape pen cartridge I've actually not
felt bad about spending money on
nice does it come in flavors or is it
just one flavor right now it's just a
single extract run so it's a mixed batch
no strain specific sativa or indica a
hybrid blend of course they just threw a
bunch of [ __ ] together yeah I have a
feeling it's half Clementine House Blue
Dream is honestly what I think it is but
yeah I've been enjoying the hell out of
the sugar wax super tasty hash high
quality so I'm highest you guys going to
your local weed store if that's the
thing where you are asking what what new
stuff is in and check out new stuff
don't don't get set in a total routine
there's a lot of new cool stuff coming
out you should check out what's new you
know I kind of stepped out of my little
box I was I was really familiar with
chirp X I mean I grow the product a
green and healthy we take it to turf X
they turn it into concentrates for us
why wouldn't I buy that you know what I
mean but lately I've been buying the
craft extracts the craft makes really
good products I've been getting extracts
Inc I think that's what they're called
extracts again they make really good
products I had some Darth cookies the
other day it was really tasty stuff like
I've been stepping out of my normal 7/10
labs a really good ship viola you know
if you get the right batch of viola
it'll taste really good yet check out
new [ __ ] don't be don't be afraid to try
new stuff you're gonna get a quality
product I'd been I'd spent a lot of time
going through the edible section making
tried tried kind of one of everything
and I'm doing the same thing with the
hash lately and it's it's a lot of fun
it's fun watching you step up your hash
game it's so expensive piece by piece
you started off basically I think I gave
you your first stab probably yep I would
assume yeah it was the hot oil days yeah
the syringe of black co2 oil on the
dabber
oh those days when they were selling us
dental pick dabbers at the events for
like the price of dab tools and they
were just old dental divers from
Pakistan yep yeah oh man so but it's
good to see you stepped up you went from
taking little tiny dabs of just booboo
to now you take pretty good sized dabs
of some Clementine sugar wax bro right
it's nice I got you a decent sized dab
of some pineapple jack set up there
that's gonna make you coffee good the
last pineapple Jack who which company
made this was it sir yeah this is from
the turf
the the shop got in a shipment of that a
long time ago and I ended up with like
eight of them at home by the time we
sold out I had a a back stash I probably
grew that it was delicious yeah that's a
really great strain it grows very well
very very well it's uh it's actually New
York pineapple Diesel is what it would
be it's a pineapple diesel cross on
accident I think but there were a bunch
of seeds and that's what came out is
that phenotype and it grows like a
[ __ ] savage super sweet it's a great
it's a great plan so we've been talking
for quite a while here I don't think
we've gotten in the any sort of topic at
well I'd say since debut let the
listeners know yeah yeah well the first
stop I'm gonna read a couple of email
maybe maybe two depends on how long we
go I'm gonna read one email we'll talk
about that I should find my phone
because it's on there I wanted to remind
everybody that I did promise everybody a
podcast about the dab in granny
featuring the davon granny I recorded
that podcast at the can of Canyon and
unfortunately I got home and my memory
card would not let me pull the files it
would let me drag the files from the
memory card to my desktop but they will
not play they won't play from the memory
card they won't play from the desktop I
even took the zoom h6 and ran the USB
cable to the computer and tried to open
the files that way and use it as a file
reader it will not do it so far with my
tech skills that that shows lost so what
I have done is I set up another show I'm
not gonna tell you when cuz you might
show up that's creepy but in the future
davin granny myself
Brett Lindsey and maybe a couple of the
folks are going to congregate at the can
Acadian Mike is gonna cough his face off
turn purple again but we're gonna record
the Gavin grannie podcast so stick
around that will be coming up in the
very near future
uh we're gonna read that email I said
that the one thing I want to talk about
with Mike the main thing because Mike is
our smart friend that comes over with
smart [ __ ] ladies and gentlemen the DEA
has failed to reschedule cannabis is
still considered a Schedule one drug
which let me tell you what that means
schedule one drugs are the most
dangerous drugs with the most potential
for abuse and psychological dependence
so
Cannabis still is in the same category
as LSD as heroin and ecstasy there is no
medicinal value Mike how do you feel
about that I saw it coming a mile away
but I'm still disappointed it's 2016 so
about 90 days ago the DEA said that they
were considering rescheduling cannabis
they taunted everybody they teased us
they made us all think that there may be
a change and then in 90 days they just
said oh never mind sorry we're not gonna
do that well there was a change and it
is big it's just not as big as the media
made it sound they didn't reschedule
cannabis but they did open up more
research growths production sites for
cannabis for pretty much everybody
listenings whole lifetime the feds have
been growing marijuana for research
purposes at the University of
Mississippi sorry I'm still dabbed out
but that's the only farm that grew it
and if you've been watching Sanjay
Gupta's weed 1 2 &amp; 3 specials on CNN
they covered the research restriction
topic pretty well basically there's only
one farm growing research marijuana in
the u.s. which means there's almost no
variety of cannabis to research in the
US they've only got four strains or some
really restricted numbers sorry my lungs
are still going a little nuts good dad
good we can hear it but you're good
you're saying you're making enough sense
to make it matter yeah I hope you guys
are following along I'm trying really
hard not to watch it right into the
minds do it really well to see the look
on his face so this makes you dumb it's
nonsense you're just stoned you guys
I've seen the cannabis that they grow at
that facility there in Mississippi and
it's garbage they don't have a proper
growth facility they don't have proper
technique I don't think they have good
genetics I've seen what they're doing
and it isn't it's an embarrassing growth
my girl looks like that I would put
matches to it they should be ashamed of
what they were producing when I saw the
last footage in there there's you can
pull up some footage on YouTube what a
lot of it looks like and when you listen
to the researchers talk they tell you oh
we can produce
anything that's requested we can mix a
batch of 19% THC or 10 percent or 4
percent or 12 percent whatever you want
and when you look at what he's talking
about he's basically like well we just
grind up enough leaf and stem in there
to bring the 21 down to 12 or the grind
enough but over the 4% until it's a 9%
and it's yeah it's not pretty
I've seen their facility and I don't
think they ever passed 15% the feds have
run a medical marijuana program since 82
where patients get mailed 11 ounces each
of pre-rolled joints every month and
like a coffee can like a really cool
coffee tin that's actually a bizarre
collectible in the u.s. now because you
can find them on ebay from time to time
in one of the federal patients that does
a lot of public speaking we'll give them
away for charity events like silent
auctions and stuff but the marijuana
that those patients get is from this
farm and some of the video of it
especially that was taking away
conferences in the late 90s early
thousands the quality is just atrocious
if they have to unroll the pre roll
joints rehydrated in the fridge like old
hippie style with a piece of lettuce or
a piece of bread to bring the moisture
content up real quick and then reroll it
like Mexican brick weed from America yep
why don't they need to hire somebody
that hey guys in Mississippi hire me I
know how to grow cannabis let's do this
yeah it's gotten better since a lot of
that footage was shot I hope so
did you see the CNN footage do you know
it well enough to discuss quality from
that I think that's the footage that I
saw they walk into the room with like it
looks like a shitty LED and they've got
like a small hydro table and the plants
just look sad the plants totally looks
yeah it's definitely not like Colorado
commercial production quality it's
definitely not home grill quality yeah
yeah remember the guy we went to his
house and he had those super stretchy
plants with the UFO light above them
that's what it made me think of you know
I'm talking about right away yeah
I was like oh that guy's grown over
there [ __ ] some struggle buds yes
struggle buddy very very good quality by
the looks of it so they're the DEA
claims that cannabis does not have a
currently accepted medical use in the US
and there is a lack of accepted safety
for its use under medical supervision
and it has a high potential for abuse
all of that is [ __ ] you guys what
what why aren't worried Mike why is it
the DEA smart enough to see that all of
that is [ __ ] oh they totally do so
what's their was there it's not it
doesn't have anything to do with
marijuana itself in everything to do
with seceding power in my opinion
marijuana being illegal is an amazingly
powerful tool it does several things
that they want to keep happening if they
lose that stick they lose a lot there
are a lot of things that are built on
that pyramid they crumble after is it
the pharmaceutical industry there are
definitely financial interest is this
president is it the prison industry um
there's been some good reporting lately
Washington I don't remember which paper
but looking at major lobbying efforts
recently against marijuana rescheduling
against marijuana legalization and a lot
of that's coming from alcohol and
pharmaceuticals alcohol pharmaceutical
prisons okay well there's a big report
out recently that legal marijuana states
in medical marijuana states huge
reductions in Medicare and Medicaid
prescription billing oh wow
and it was an in enough states and over
the same time lines to draw causation
conclusions not a one-to-one like
mathematical conclusion but enough to
infer that where people have easy free
legal access to cannabis they can just
swing by a store and get it basically
they consume significantly less
prescription drugs and that's a huge
loss to a major industry same thing with
alcohol when twenty-something males have
marijuana that they can go buy at a
store
they consume significantly less alcohol
on my mic sounded really hot sorry
honestly when I got my first medical
marijuana card I told myself and my
friends and my family I was like you
know what I can smoke all the cannabis I
want I'm gonna quit drinking and they're
like [ __ ] and here it is probably
six seven eight years maybe later I
haven't drank since I started using
medical cannabis since I was able to go
to the dispensary and point at that jar
and say let me get an ounce of that
tastiness right there and go home and
roll up and puff down as hard as I want
without any worries cuz back in the day
I didn't know where I was gonna buy my
next weed you have to deserve that outs
cuz you paid way too much and you don't
know if that dude is gonna have good
weed or not next time now you can
medicate as needed I don't need to drink
any alcohol I don't like being drunk I'm
no good I don't know if I'm really good
at it or really bad at it I'm not sure
I'm not sure what the case is but I know
that it's not my friend I don't wake up
hungover and regretful when I smoked
cannabis I've got a very similar story
it's not I quit drinking before I had a
medical marijuana card but essentially
the same thing is I got really good at
drinking and I decided that I didn't
like some of those character traits so I
was gonna take a couple days off couple
days became a week and now it's been
like eight years like I went to Mardi
Gras two years ago and had three beers
like just like with dinners just because
I was there and I was at sea level and I
wouldn't feel the repercussions of it
the next day like I would have had I had
up three beers here is that where Davey
happened bro no we found out we found
out about Davey the day after we got to
New Orleans sort of how we found out the
the day we got there she took a sip her
first drink and got queasy and was like
man and then the second day the same
thing and after the second day she was
like go to Walgreens
oh-ho yep so we were in New Orleans for
10 days and we found out we were
pregnant on the second day you get to
celebrate while you're there kind of we
did it was a it was great we celebrated
the whole time we had a truckload of
good food neither of us were real heavy
drinkers anyway so it's not like we're
missing out on anything
yeah but ya had a great time and I had a
lot to celebrate but yes I don't really
drink and a lot of it has to do with I
can relax and unwind with cannabis and
it's a much better unwind there's no
there's no penalty the next day and
that's what I hated about drinking is
the incredibly bad decisions that would
make while drinking and then waking up
the next day getting while you're drunk
right just figuring out how to get home
DRI am I gonna drive I'm gonna take a
taxi am I gonna jump in one of my drunk
friends cars ah so many nights I
somebody so many mornings have woken up
saying I am so thankful that I made it
home last night I talked to someone
today who's like I quit drinking this
morning and it's like yeah the point
we're at here is people are consuming
less cannabis are consuming less alcohol
they're consuming less pills because we
were able to access cannabis safely it's
it's there's a lot of people who don't
want that to happen and there's a lot of
people who don't want to lose that lever
of control on people it's an immediate
excuse to get to further a car stop I
smell marijuana there's there's not one
video on YouTube where the cop goes I
smell heroin I want to search your
vehicle I want to smoke cocaine or I
smell cocaine I want to search your
vehicle right that video doesn't exist
it never gets said I I think I smell a
gun I want to search your vehicle I
think I smell someone you're smuggling
in your trunk I want to search your
vehicle that video doesn't exist every
single video is I think I smell
marijuana when that steps away
everything for law enforcement gets a
little bit harder that is so true
because I recently got pulled over I
talked about it on the show and the
first thing that cop said was do you
have any marijuana in the vehicle and I
had to reprogram my brain real quickly
because first I was weak no sir there's
no weed in here but then I was like wait
a minute it's 2016 bro you've got your
badge on you've got your purple card in
your pocket and I looked him straight in
the face and I go it may be because I
wasn't certain but there may be there
could be weeding here he's like it
smells really strong I was like oh I
work in agro and just being honest with
them
that she's everything he had no problem
to mess with me now so you're right that
does take all the stress I'm not a
criminal anymore yep the only thing I
used to do wrong was have a bunch of
weed in the car those first couple law
enforcement interactions are bizarre it
you dude it's almost a genetic response
with this community at this point right
because if we admit to being part of the
cannabis community or having cannabis or
supporting it in any way we subject
ourselves to all sorts of horrible
things in Colorado that's not true
anymore and as those realization sets in
it's awesome
have you been to an event or a place
where you have consumed cannabis near
law enforcement then they've watched you
many for it was legal I I was up in
Denver and Boulder during the heydays of
the Boulder Prasad on 4/20 in the Civic
Center gatherings on 4/20 where tens or
hundreds of thousands of people get
together all at once everybody lights at
the same time sort of as a dare go ahead
there's 10,000 of us arrests 11 of us
see what happens right I'm like we're
gonna peacefully sit here and smoke pot
and play bad music and then cheer at
4:20 and all smoke pot together and
there'll be a big cloud and by 5 o'clock
we'll all be gone the shops in the area
that sell food will all make an extra 5
grand 10 grand that day everybody's
happy
everybody except people that have to
take public transportation or commute
during those hours anyway
but uber drivers are making mass
anything downtown Denver a hundred
thousand people just convene at Civic
Center the the cops stand by and they
always had and just kind of made sure
everything was calm and collected and
nobody got out of control and it was
fine but at post legalization only a few
okay
it's just I've been too busy I always
end up working those it's not the guy
that goes to all the events you're not
that dude there I desperately want to go
to like the next secret session I need
to get out and enjoy a few events now
August 22nd now that Davey's a little
bit older I can start doing that a
little bit yeah
yeah he's gonna be so much fun pretty
soon so I remember the first time we
used to go to smoke nights at the cloud9
hookah bar here in Puebla I've talked
about him on the podcast way back in the
early episodes cuz that was back in the
in the day here since then they've shut
him down we can't do that here in Pueblo
anymore but we were at the cloud9 hookah
bar and I was sitting I was at the bar
which is it's an old bar but it's now
turned into a hookah bar but they didn't
change much you know it still got the
bar seating they just put hookahs out I
was sitting at the bar and there was one
person and then me and in front of me is
my little oil slick pad my rig my torch
my little variety of hash I was hitting
a ball or a tow ball I was into Bowl
that night I had a bowl some flowers in
it had a bag of weed next to me I was
just chilling just sitting on the
barstool and the cops walked in three of
them together and I heard the radio you
always hear that and then they walk in
and I was like ah what do I do
and I thought [ __ ] sit here dude
you're a 21 year old you're over 21
you've got a red card in your pocket a
purple card now cannabis is legal the
owner of this place is who's gonna have
to [ __ ] deal with anything yep those
cops walked right past me and they went
and talked to the owner the owner nodded
and smiled a couple times they all shook
hands the cops walked past me and they
kind of looked at my what I had sitting
on the table
like they looked at it more curiously
they were like huh okay that's what
smoke and hash supplies look like and
they walked past it and they nodded I
mean they kind of smiled like hey what's
up stoner like one of them kind of
condescendingly smile like what's up you
weed head you're high as [ __ ] and the
other cheek just kind of nodded politely
they walked out one of the kids that was
there was younger dude just just being a
typical dude I probably would have said
the same thing [ __ ] 15 years ago but
as soon as they got outside he goes man
[ __ ] the police and I looked at him I
was like bro unfuck those police they
didn't take my hash and we didn't go to
jail cuz you were the first [ __ ]
they saw when they walked in here like
they didn't do anything so yeah it was I
had to remind him like we didn't go to
jail for that dude like two years ago
they would have threw me on the floor
like just for having that [ __ ] there
there are a lot of people who don't want
to give that out and yeah that's why you
see thing the DEA make decisions like
this it's it's it's just silly it is
silly if they if they would have
rescheduled cannabis to a Schedule 2
substance what that would have mean what
that would have meant is it would have
now been allowable for person
Asians by all medical doctors so they'd
be able to write you a prescription for
cannabis basically well and they'd also
it makes research significantly easier I
mean I hate to keep going back to CNN's
specials because CNN's usually obnoxious
as all hell but their marijuana
reporting that they've done has been
spectacular it's easy to research
cocaine in the u.s. because it's a
schedule 2 drug it's easy to see it's
easy to research schedule 2 drugs
because their schedule - if their
schedule one significantly more red tape
right much much harder to research and I
mean it takes years of going through
approval meeting since submitting
paperwork years to just begin your study
and then in studies take years to
complete they take more years to write
the conclusions examine the data all of
that and then more years to publish and
when you add another decade of red tape
at the beginning of all that marijuana
research is something that's not going
to happen it's a world net and that's
because it's a Schedule one drug and
moving it to schedule two changes all
that any competent researcher can submit
the paperwork and and within a
relatively reasonable amount of time
begin researching and none of those
changes were made and so even though
they created more places to grow it in
the selection of research grade cannabis
that's available to be researched will
it be expanding access to that material
won't be and that's really unfortunate
and this is why I rant and tell people
to vote because none of this [ __ ]
changes until a most of the people
involved in this have gotten old and
died like we just have to wait until the
generation that's so tied to this has
seceded power to our generation and it's
just going to take another couple of
decades and in the meantime we need more
people in our generation politically
active so many members of our community
tuned out because if we spoke up about
what we believed in we went to jail I
scared dude back in the day you would be
like come to these City Council meetings
with me and I was like no I grow and
that doesn't scared well and that's part
of the reason I became the politically
active one down here is because I didn't
physically have the space to grow or the
money for the startup equipment and so I
didn't like go ahead and show my house
warrant there's only 12 square feet
start with the dirty laundry prick like
I didn't care I like I could have cops
show up
I could have cops pull me over and
demand to search my car and I'd be okay
most of the time but I was able to risk
it where a lot of other people in the
community simply weren't in a position
to do that but one of the one of the
really interesting things that I noticed
when I spoke out is that it gives you a
shield when you go to City Council
meeting reporters for the local paper
there if you live in a major city
reporters from major papers are there
when the guy that comes down to City
Council or give the County Commissioner
meetings and makes really coherent
articulate arguments in the appropriate
manner and setting for marijuana gets
his house raided they break a bunch of
furniture rough him up shoot his dog and
don't find anything that [ __ ] makes the
front page the Washington Post every day
for a week and they know this and so it
doesn't happen and that's not
universally true it's not being granted
immunity by a judge but it does provide
you a significant layer of protection
because by becoming mildly public you
you're granted some of that protection
yep all right so the DEA failed you guys
that was my point on that topic now I
want to move on to another topic here
Mike thanks for having a whole lot of
info on that one for supporting me on
that well just learned a lot both both
happened it is now Wednesday August 17th
is we were recording this it just passed
midnight right now it is August 17th
happy birthday Gibbs Gibbs I don't know
if you listen to this podcast bro I love
you it's great being your friend I miss
you oh we should hang out more I hope
everything is go
while for you happy [ __ ] birthday
giblet also today marks the anniversary
of the first time that my friend Amanda
and myself took dabs together
amanda has been in Colorado for one year
now Amanda I don't know what Colorado
would be like without you I'm so glad
you showed up yeah [ __ ] friends
forever there dude not to get all sappy
on everybody but some some landmarks to
to note so shout-out to Gibbs and Amanda
love you guys I draw my roster um I said
I was gonna bring an email to the table
to read I took a screenshot of it cuz
it's much easier than going and
searching through [ __ ] let me read this
message to ya I've got two of them this
one says first of all he said sucks that
uh sucks about the grannie podcast he
said you killed it with the emails
though and we love your updates on your
genetics I should give you guys a quick
update on that cuz I said I would do
that the mail plan we are now the date
is now the 17th so we are now 14 days in
you guys the mail plant just started
sprinkle in a little bit of pollen a
little itty bitty bitty bitty bits of
pollen are coming out of them the girls
are just starting to go into full flower
you can see their calyx pistols are just
going nuts right now the stretch phase
is in full fledge they'll quit
stretching in about a week I'll let them
get pollen in about seven to ten days
they'll start getting a lot of pollen on
them I've got pollen in a jar for backup
I've also got that male throw and pollen
they're gonna get pollinated so they're
looking great everything is going
beautifully on the breeding project
everything is on schedule not a whole
lot to report other than the male his
balls are big and he's just barely
starting to dump pollen so this message
says I was wondering what you know about
Fox tailing I don't really understand
what is happening and whether it's a
good or bad thing when it happens maybe
a good show topic and I replied with
great topic so that was a message that
actually came from a friend on Instagram
the emails been killer lately right I
get a lot of topics a lot of content
from the people that are sending me
emails I really appreciate that send me
your emails guys send them to me it grow
from your heart at hotmail.com that's
the easiest way to reach me grow from
your heart at hotmail.com it's easier if
I filter all the questions through that
one channel I'll read your questions
wherever they come from honestly because
I know you're not some of us are friends
on Instagram on Twitter and whatever
wherever we're friends I'll read it but
it's easier you got more of a
it's if you hit me rolled from your
heart at hotmail.com right so this guy
wants to know about fox tailing fox
stealing is when you're growing a bug
some buds and they start popping off
like little bit fox dales at little
fingers they just get they start
spreading out a little bit I call them
cheeto fingers - cheeto fingers yeah but
yeah Fox tails is the appropriate sir
some strains its genetic
if the bud stays compact if it's tight
and it's doing what looks like a fox
tail more like a crown that's genetic if
it's if the bud is Airy and you're
getting fox tail II that is most likely
from too much heat that's usually what
that's from your plants are probably too
hot they're probably a little bit too
close to the light also coming with that
Fox tailing you may see a little bit of
taco leaf your leaf will look healthy
it'll look cool except on the edges
it'll be folding up like a taco shell
like you could just make a little taco
out of your leaf right there both of
those are visual descriptors yeah so if
you're seeing both of those it certainly
is too hot in there I've seen it most
often when we call it kissing the sky
where the plants grow up into the light
while they're in bloom yeah that's
probably what's happening - this guy's
poor plants yep if that's not the case
Fox tailing could be from too much
humidity they're trying to spread out
this is the grossest description I could
give you but it's completely accurate
Mike knows where I'm going with this
imagine you're in Las Vegas in the
summer it's like 114 degrees outside
your man junk tries to just move away
from your body these plants are doing
the same thing it's too hot your balls
want to get away these plants are too
hot they want to get away from each
other they're starting to sweat they're
getting funky they're just trying to
peel off of each other so they're not
getting sweaty and funky and compacted
in there the plants just trying to make
some air room for itself so it's trying
to get spongy it's Fox tailing out a
little bit it's gonna get fluffy it's
gonna it's getting heat stressed it's
probably what's happening or you could
be over feeding it that also could could
make Fox tailing happen if one of those
three it's it's nine times out of ten
your plant hit the light yeah some
Jillybean phenotypes like to make a
crown shape fox tail strawberry-banana
tangi likes to make some crown shape Fox
tails
tangey I guess it's a lot of things
cross to that Kali oh they're worse with
the Lemon Haze you know that did it
pick out within eight inches of the
light it was a [ __ ] okay but it was the
plant with drip and so the grower
wouldn't get rid of it because it would
just literally when you were harvesting
it would just drip THC it was insane
that's awesome I think I know that plant
talk about it the closer if it got into
the light it would foxtail like mad so
chances are bro your plant is getting
too close to the light it's a little bit
too hot if that if that's not the case
send me a follow a message and we'll
figure out what's going on we'll talk
about it on a future episode I truly do
appreciate the interaction with my
listeners send me more questions more
messages I love it you guys I like it a
lot alright I wanna read one more email
this one's gonna be quick I'm finding it
on my phone here I did take another
screenshot this one says hey I was
listening to the podcast today and I
heard you answer my questions on the air
this one's from mazza 4:20 by the way
and he said it was a trip and then he
said thanks for that bro when I see I
work with robots
I just meant they act like robots cuz
remember I had a real robot to these
people that act like robots then he said
I kind of like office space but
different he said I got another question
for the show I was hoping you could
shine some light on then it says show
questions number one what are your
thoughts on monster cropping and he said
I read that it's great to use first
scrog honest I don't know a lot about
monster cropping all you got to do is
send me another message and tell me what
monster cropping is and I'll tell you my
opinions on it I'll learn about it just
tell me what's going on there I don't
know what you mean by monster cropping
there's a couple things that could mean
you could mean like snapping the stems
and bending them if that's what you mean
that's cool but it takes too long for my
type of growth ah number 2 question he
said I was curious to hear your thoughts
on LEDs any experience using one I don't
have any personal experience with LEDs
so I don't have a lot to tell you I tell
it I can tell you that it changes the
way your plants function they've use
they do everything they use their
nutrients differently they drink
differently I've seen friends run side
by sides with LEDs and HPS lights and
the LED plants and the HBS lights looked
completely different being fed the same
thing they photosynthesize differently
they want different nutrients it's a
whole new thing to learn I don't have
any experience with it personally
I can't guide you on any lights to use I
don't know enough
spend a lot of time researching light
spectrums and their effects on plants
and yeah that is something I've only
seen them really successfully regularly
used as an auxiliary color augmentation
right when they're a primary light
source every harvest I've seen has been
miniscule I'll give a shout-out to my
friend Nancy bud well she grows with a
very specific brand of LED lights and
she kills it her plants are gorgeous
yeah but I've only ever seen the the
cheaper ones in action right never seen
like the $1,800 version the lights that
the Nancy are using those lights are
quite expensive they're a thousand to
1400 all our lights but LEDs can be
extremely expensive but allegedly you
pay for it in the first year and
electrical savings right what you're
gonna save yeah you gotta throw it down
on the table to walk out with that light
but you're not gonna have to pay the
electric bill every month like I do with
my HPS lights you don't have to run as
much electricity on an air conditioner
to cool it off also yep there's a there
are power saving there it's just I've
never seen them effectively used alone
check out Nancy bud well on Facebook or
Instagram and she is a representative
for a specific lighting company and she
has great pictures and she will guide
you through your purchase of an LED
light if it's something that you're
really interested in he's got a third
part to this question it says also
wondering what are your thoughts on
hippy buckets and deep water culture
what are the pros and cons and your
likes and dislikes I am not super
experienced in deep water culture do you
remember our friend from Hawaii that
dude grew some deep water culture
buckets and did some great work the
problem was if something goes wrong
everything goes wrong if your pump goes
out on that deep water culture pump and
you don't spray for three or four hours
if it quits spraying all your plants are
gonna die that's the the major dislike
to it I thought it was awesome our buddy
had 5-gallon deep water culture buckets
and his plants were taller than me and
I'm 6 foot 5 and they were putting on
weight they were packing it up the only
problem is he had a lot of fungus gnats
all the damn time he could not get rid
of the fungus gnats I've never done it
myself so I don't have a lot of
experience but that's what our Hawaiian
friend was experiencing from what I saw
I spent a lot of time researching
different growth method
and this one scares me because of its
complexity it's the same thing with
Hydra the more complicated it gets the
more random things might fail and cause
your crap just suicide when you were
only gone for six hours that's why I'm a
soil grower yep and honestly soil is
insanely forgiving and part of the
reasons for that or what make me favor
it so let's talk about deep water
culture a little bit because there might
be people out there going what the hell
is deep water culture basically deep
water culture is a five gallon bucket
this is just a one you can do multiple
site deep water culture buckets and you
can have a main bucket that feeds or a
main reservoir that feeds multiple
buckets but for a one plan deep water
culture bucket you've got a five gallon
bucket and then there's a lid type
device that goes on top of the bucket
but it's got a little mesh basket cut
out of the center of it and you fill
that area with rock wool cubes and you
put not rock will the hydroton clay
balls unclear boy put your rock your
clone that's in a rock will you just set
it in there and then it'll root and the
roots will hang down inside of that
5-gallon bucket inside that 5-gallon
bucket you put a sprayer there are a lot
of different types of sprayers available
there are so many different ways to do
it they sell a circular it's a circle
sprayer that's got spray jets this
shoots straight up and it's kind of a
mister type thing so you're misting this
is essentially a long growth version of
the auto climber
yeah it's it's a real big easy cloner as
basically what it is you would have
missed those roots from the bottom real
heavily and you put nutrients in the
water and a lot of oxygen heavily
oxygenated and nutrient and water
spraying from the bottom so that those
roots hang down into that and grow into
that spring water cuz gravity makes the
roots want to go down I think gravity
does I don't know if they just want to
go down or if it's gravity both they may
just want to do it naturally but so the
water spraying up onto there and it's
growing and then I put it on on a timer
so that it stops every once in a while
so the roots can kind of dry so that
they don't rot and then you just keep it
cycling so every like 15 min every 45
minutes it shuts off for 15 I'll let
your water cool down so that the pump
doesn't overheat your water because the
oxygen pump and the [ __ ] moving it
pump is gonna make that water huh a lot
of people throw a chiller in there to
keep that water cool it's a lot of work
it's a lot of Technology and if one
piece of all that tech goes wrong your
whole thing could die yep the production
is amazing
it
the plant seems to really love it when
everything's humming but it's one of
those things where if you're setting it
up the one the one bucket version on the
cheap like that's the quality of the
parts you just require constant
attention and you have to understand
that you like your plants got a gun to
its head the hammers [ __ ] one piece
fails and that trigger gets pulled and
you start over period and that's why I
read that far in the book it was like I
know enough next chapter so mad sorry I
know I couldn't answer a lot of your
questions but at least I kind of gave
you the answers that I had I don't know
a lot about monster cropping tell me
what you you think monster cropping
means cuz if you google it there are
several different takes just cuz it's a
that's a very common word so let me know
what you're thinkin I'll talk more about
that LEDs no experience dude I told you
what I saw from my friends deep water
culture we ranted on what I saw from my
buddy
called him pineapple Express because
he's from Kauai I used to come all the
time but as our 4/20 thanks for the
email please send me more emails we will
talk more about this stuff on a future
episode just blank II was staring into
them I know the rigs looking at me do
you need a dab you want to take some on
the show I did I'm gonna dab the rest of
what is on this parchment paper this is
some pineapple Jack from our friends at
FX by last quarter gram yeah it's
probably quarter gram but I'm gonna take
this and then I think they want to wrap
up the show after that Mike got anything
pointing it to say just we're gearing up
for November make sure you can do it
online most places make sure you're
registered to vote make sure you know
what election issues are coming up in
your area take a minute to actually
research them it's gonna be a hell of
election all the news is focused on the
circus that is the presidential race and
honestly it's the local stuff that
really really really matters that's the
stuff that's really gonna impact your
day to day and that's the CJ today I did
and that's that's the local issue stuff
of the the things that tend to really
matter to most people take a minute to
figure out what those are the local
issues are now set what County voters
will be voting on one marijuana question
whether or not they want to ban the
industry city voters will be voting on
three marijuana questions the first one
do you want to ban the REC industry yes
or no the second question do you want to
allow recreational stores yes or no and
the third question do you want to tax
those stores is it like four and a half
percent kind of a confusing set of
questions and there's reasons for that
like a lot of complicated reasons for
all of those three questions and peirong
freddo puebla city voters but you need
to know which questions which you need
to know the wording so that you don't
accidentally vote the wrong way and it's
important that you know that stuff
regardless of whether you live near me
or not because whatever the issues are
in your area they will impact you
personally make sure you know what's up
and make sure you vote
have you gone to your Facebook page your
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
Facebook page and kind of typed in
guidance on which way to vote since it
is worded awkwardly there's already a
beautiful infographic that helps with
that that the pueblos Pope did they've
been doing some amazing cannabis for
John Rodriguez Lisa wheeler and I don't
know the other reporter's name okay
thanks Lisa wheeler and your colleague
who are helping us out in the cannabis
fight not so much that it's just doing
solid honest reporting and when that's
done it leans far to the pro cannabis
side because that's just the reality you
can be a good reporter it not end up
reporting that truth but know the issues
in your area it's not that difficult
doesn't take that much time and it's
incredibly important folks get out and
do it Mike always knows what's up he's
always got the right thing to say if
you're listening and you're in the
industry you should think about some
sort of a show up with your I voted
sticker get a dot dot dot
you hear that think about it awesome
promotion motors store managers people
that voted get a something like a
percentage off today a free pre-roll if
you spend something I don't know go vote
go to go to the dispensary and celebrate
your freedoms all right you guys hey
Mike thanks for coming and hanging out I
know you got that little guy at home I
know you want to go hang out with him
yeah man it it'll be good to get home
but I love the podcast I I'm happy to
get over here and I love doing it thanks
for coming on but I love having you on
the show you're always a good material
that people love it when you ramble a
good content you guys the next episode I
have planned well I don't even know if I
should talk about Jesse coming Jesse
says he's gonna come over tomorrow Mike
might go pick him up and make sure he
shows up we wanna make sure that so the
next podcast will either be myself and
Mike or Jesse and myself or myself Mike
and Jesse you never know how it's gonna
go in these parts there may may not be a
podcast recorded tomorrow it may or may
not be epic it's outdoor season so you
never know what could go on right now
but I hope to have Jesse not tomorrow
Mike you know you're invited back after
that you guys I will be recording once
again with the dab in granny I can't
wait to have her back on the show
it's tentatively scheduled that's the
intro about the gear we're test running
everything to make sure that this goes
smooth this time for 48 minutes in of
this part of it before it works things
look good yes it looks good so far so
far so good
all right let's quit while we're ahead
Mike thanks for coming yeah I'm gonna
wrap up this part of the show and I will
be back in just a single and I'll put a
bow on this [ __ ] all right everybody I
want to thank you guys for listening to
another episode I want to thank Mike for
coming to joining me
you guys I owe a huge shout out to my
friend Chris Baker make sure you listen
to the broadcast geeks podcast and
support my Buddy Baker Baker's a great
dude he's got a great podcast we owe him
a high five in a favor so make sure you
support his podcast you guys I wanna
thank everybody for listening I'll be
back in another week with another
episode if you have a product you would
like me to review or if you'd like to
sponsor the show all you have to do is
send me an email it's girl from your
heart at hotmail.com
I would love to get you all of the
information that you need you guys know
that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the review section
give me a 5/5 star rating that's hard to
say give me a five star ratings I've
been a little comment and let me know
what you think about the show and I will
read your comments on
future episode I would love it if you
follow me on all the social media sites
I am on almost all of them just search
for aggro from your heart on Twitter
it's @g fyh podcast if you've got
something to say and you're not into all
the social media you can simply email me
girl from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you don't forget
the shows available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is always and
forever archived on ira genetics
colorado com the show is also available
on Tok Radio make sure you support Tok
radio and listen to all the other great
podcasts on their big shot it's my
friend Lucy and her podcast Lucy in the
sky also shadows my buddy citizen Jay
you guys that's all I've got for you
this week I'll see you in seven more
days the next episode will be Jesse on
an outdoor episode Jesse and Mike join
me and then episode 150 will feature the
dab in granny we're gonna do that one
again so join me for those until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
Joey no we've all sinned but leave us
snap destroy these
[Music]
from the chuja no destruction for
children
[Music]