[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 149 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to fear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff want
to thank you once again for joining me
as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band to letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew
I hope everybody's having a great week I
hope you're smoking a fat joint I hope
you got the email turned on I hope
you're taking a DAB if you're smoking
some good shatter maybe some good live
resin maybe you're smoking some rosin
with me whatever you're smoking I hope
you get them hi ash it having a good
time with us ladies and gentlemen this
episode features our good friends white
Mike and also Jesse Grose's back we
talked about a little bit outdoor
growing we talked about a whole bunch of
randomness this is a really wonderful
episode in my opinion you guys I did
drop a Thursday episode if you didn't
catch the episode that came out on
Thursday make sure you go back and check
that one out number 148 is available it
came out Thursday I usually post every
episode on Monday I have had a bunch of
content so I felt like I could put one
out on Thursday for you I hope you
listened I hope you enjoyed it send me a
tweet let me know what you thought of
that episode find me on Twitter it's at
G fyh podcast I would love to hear from
you you guys I'm gonna let the music
play and when we get back Mike and Jesse
will be joining us at the table
enjoy the music for a moment
do it Mike you wanna bust a freestyle no
it looks like you're about to let one go
no I want to hear freestyle rap I want
to hear the white Mike freestyle rap not
a white Mike freestyle rap rap no City
Council make sure you register to vote
city council slang etiquette excellence
I have Press report you guys we were
recording at this podcast ladies and
gentlemen welcome back to episode number
149 as promised sitting to the left of
me is a repeat offender a returning
champion ladies and gentlemen welcome to
podcast our good buddy Jesse grows
welcome back brother hey what's up you
guys Jesse showed up with raw Terps
today he's got some distillate he's got
some shatter he's locked and loaded and
ready to go bro thanks for showing up
ready for sure yeah use your microphone
voice I started talking to him
the cottonmouth killer yeah being a
cottonmouth we're taking some serious
dads here today Jesse before we get too
far tell everybody on social media how
they can stock you while they listened
to your sexy voice Instagram
Jesse gross and then also you can check
out my podcast we've got a Facebook page
Colorado podcast on Facebook the
Colorado podcast you guys make sure you
check that out support that it's a great
show I've been on that show a big shout
out to make the dog ladies and gentlemen
make the dog will be joining us also on
this podcast right now he's taking a
comfy seat underneath the table if
you're a regular listener you know the
other day I kicked the dog apologize it
did not mean to do that Jesse thanks for
joining us everybody make sure you
follow Jesse grows on Instagram take a
look at his photography while you're
listening to the show check out him out
see what he does we're gonna talk a
whole lot about outdoor growing you guys
also across the table from me another
repeat offender a returning champion the
guy that was here just last night
recording a show with me I missed you
bro welcome back Mike everybody white
Mike is on the podcast if you're not a
regular listener you can check Mike out
he's at an emo Punk 15 on Twitter and he
is also Pablo for sensible cannabis laws
on Facebook make sure you check out that
group page I get that right perfectly
been trying to train that in my brain
that's a lot of words for my STONER
brain
Pueblo for sensible cannabis social
media someone else's thanks man thanks
for doing that for us I told you on the
last episode we need you out there
fighting that part of the fight
I'll do the breeding Jess he'll do the
growing you get us legal fight for us
welcome back to the show I appreciate
having you here taking time away from
the baby the family the dogs you're busy
dude it's great to have you here
you were supposed to trim all night so
I'm glad that you ended up trimming all
night and then that got waved off so
yeah back for the podcast I love it here
with Jesse finally this is a first it's
not gonna say we've done celebratory
sound yeah like fifty and AH but I think
you're both here for those yeah I think
we did one before too as I met you at
the stable of doing the podcast that's
how many I've done I dab that memory
away completely it's hard to remember
some of those early early episodes right
there funny I had people remind me of
things I've said and done on those
episodes this is the first meaningful
one how about there right Oh bro
oriented one this is episode one forty
nine you guys a hundred and forty nine
episodes into this podcast I haven't
missed a week in two and a half years
every month as a podcast to listen to in
some Thursday's it's been incredible
I've been running 20 episodes nice I was
honored to be on one of those episodes
you guys we did a I call it a swap cast
I learned the phrase swap cast from Doug
Stanhope but it's when two podcasters
come together and record one podcast and
then they both put it up on their feed
so that everybody gets exposed to both
shows at the same time I did one of
those with the Colorado a podcast make
sure you check it out it was good fun
it's a little bit of chaos but it is a
great show listen to it on their feed so
that they get to click so you guys yeah
the Colorado podcast page and listen to
that episode on their feed because they
can use the traffic we post them up
we've got some internet problems so
there's some website problems at the
moment so I'm not sure they'll be able
to find that difficulties mate well this
episode won't come out for a few days so
hopefully you've got hopefully your tech
guys on it if not I know a guy that'll
work on that
before yeah all right I was I was gonna
say I'm excited because episode 150 it
has been confirmed episode 150 is going
to feature the dab in granny once again
I know I recorded the episode before I'm
still heartbroken that it failed
everybody's when everyone has been real
supportive and encouraging everyone's
all about coming back and re-recording
that podcast
davin granny went and bought special
hash to smoke with me to show me that
she doesn't mind doing it again so
tomorrow night at a secret location I
will be recording with the davon granny
you guys it'll be at the can of Canyon
by the time this goes out it'll be too
late process but tomorrow night at the
can of Canyon it'll be myself Deb and
Grammy Brett from Evo labs and Lindsey
the traveling stoner and probably boba
blaster Co we'll be there hopefully miss
Camille will be there hopefully Aaron
will be there hopefully Biddy and Sirius
will be there we'll try to I'm not even
gonna try to mimic the show we did last
time that's [ __ ] to try to do there
would be things that get left behind
we're just gonna have a conversation
like we did some of that is lost forever
you know it was babban granny's first
podcast and she wasn't sure how to go
about it right away so now she is
completely [ __ ] comfortable and she
knows what to do on a podcast so it was
a practice run you guys please 150 will
be the davon granny that's kind of a
cool way for a karma to land on us
that's not a bad deal that's gonna be
awesome yeah all right we're gonna talk
about how door growing guys I wanna talk
about these dads it's distillate and
these Terps no bro you showed up with
some delicious [ __ ] Jesse remind me
what's in each of these little vials you
got here we got critical mass critical
mass Terps just to the rod distillate
this is the ovm ovm orange orange
vanilla milano shout out to the garden
of Weeden for an amazing breeding
project that was his first run Chuck and
pollen and those [ __ ] that strain came
out amazing yeah yeah I had 12 females
of it so I don't know how much he's
growing it out but I could tell him a
little about it I could use a pack of
those Spence some of them what's this
last one here that is gorilla glue
gorilla glue raw Terps so you guys have
figured out how to take a plant a
cannabis plant probably takes more than
one plan but take a large batch of
cannabis and extract the terpenoids from
that specific batch that one plant and
then you can get the essence the flavor
via
the taste you can get it all in your
face and all in your palate just with
one little droplet on a dab and it's
amazing
it can actually be overwhelming it is
that some require far far less than a
droplet Durbin poisoned dad's over very
very little very little I overdone it on
some that I took the other night and it
was just too much that was way too much
Durbin poison on there this this glue
was like okay really overwhelming I
really think the terpenes are really
contributing to my high also it makes me
skyrocket to that next level that became
crystal clear when I started playing
with the distillate in the Terps it's
you're taking the same THC but cereal
and when you add it just something like
the critical mass you go one way hard
when you add it to something like the
Durbin you know the other way we are oh
yeah and you're not changing the THC
content right it's the other parts of
the plant that really shaped that on
that entourage effects this interesting
effect what Gupta talked about yes it's
exactly evident and when we're using the
Terps like this yeah dude good job
you're kind of your company's
experimenting give your company a shout
out so that we can hype them up a little
bit it's the Uncle Bud company the Uncle
Bud company based in Pueblo Colorado you
guys we were pulling raw Terps out here
in Pueblo Colorado can I have no - you
know zero THC Enys terpenoids zero to
your lab proven zero THC yeah so these
it would not be hypothetically I'm not
gonna do this don't [ __ ] ask
hypothetically we could make these
available nationwide because there are
no cannabinoids in there yes awesome
diverting it out of metric is a whole
nother story
right right making them so it's it's
virtually impossible for that to leave
the Colorado marijuana enforcement
tracking system that is stuck you're not
gonna get it you guys well as it can
store once you once if you purchase it
in a store if there's no THC they can it
travel yes I would believe so yes that
was also my assumption is there's
nothing that's terpenoids terpenoids are
not illegal it's a glass vial you're
gonna spend a lot of time explaining
that I just smells like weed officer
stop hating me good vitamin cottage get
yourself some [ __ ]
theoretically it's also legal to ship in
the mail I wasn't gonna go there just
but yeah theoretically since it's just
her Pinoys I mean you can buy chirping
noise bought vials of liquid in the mail
that's that's the thing they're big on
well I wouldn't folks but if there's
really no THC in it I think there's a
loop here to be played with if necessary
there's actually a whoa
we might got too hot there's a website
called just chirps calm or something
similar to that where you can purchase
terpenoids you can buy limonene you can
buy all of the terpenoids separately is
that the big pretty we live scene
probably but those Terps are not derived
from cannabis those are pulled from
things like bananas and roses and
oranges and other fruits this is just
the Terps and you would people that are
not able to smoke this quality cannabis
would be able they'd have to get some
dad's or some distillate or something to
carry it you can probably put this in it
like a vape pen cartridge you can mix
that up with some VG some vegetable
glycol or something all day long all day
we've tried it yes it's actually pretty
amazing it makes a vaping a little less
gay yeah yeah you could put that in a
vape pen and then you can actually taste
gorilla glue you could taste this ovm
you could taste the critical mass you
could taste
I've got ghost train haze over here I
had lemon OG or lemon G that lemon GU
guys people do crazy [ __ ] for me for the
lemon G they'll stare at you like kid I
get wondered a lemon g dabs they look
like they got them white lips for the
Friday 5:00 o'clock free lemon
something about the lemon G Terps are
amazing I had oh gee cush chirps there's
paradism Terps floating around here
somewhere it's so delicious to taste
these cannabis terpenes we're getting
spoiled it's actually it's really not
that hard to extract them either it's
just the right equipment the right
knowledge
yeah I was gonna say tell us what you
feel comfortable sharing I don't want to
pry too much information out of you but
if there's something you want to tell us
that we would love to know some of your
process I'll tell you this if you get
with me and give me a hundred bucks I'll
walk you through the entire for us
a hundred bucks I can even I've already
proven I can do it you can trust the
Serb how to do it our consulting fee
just for showing up brochure 250 bucks
it takes it takes an investment in
equipment and I'll tell how much would
the equipment cost for a small operation
so maybe I had five pounds of plant
material to run how much equipment
should i buy what would I be spending
for a five pound run yeah good equipment
you're looking about 600 bucks and
you're gonna be doing five runs instead
of one five pounder okay well so about a
pound at a time and it's 600 bucks in
equipment yeah I'm gonna go to the store
me how to do it just be sitting here
covered in Terps I don't care it's a
solvent list process completely and
totally organic it takes a little bit of
a chemistry background or I know that
guy or you just need to know someone who
can walk you through the process that's
what I've been told it's alright between
you and Bret maverick I should be able
to figure it out oh yeah
shout out to Bret maverick well yeah I
mean like I said I taught em how to do
it okay so that's the roster Sam also by
the way yeah I don't know if I'm ready
to answer your facebook messages yet
robot shout out on the show I'm just not
ready to interact yet I brought Jesse on
the show because jesse is my outdoor
expert it's a lot of pressure on you bro
my outdoor expert you're reliable with
you've been some of my favorites so if I
were you at home John Randall's jr. get
out of notepad and a pen buddy right
there put down the Pokemon go buddy it's
time to take some notes about the Gro
that jar so I can wait Randall's we love
you bro
so outdoor growing yeah there's probably
about three weeks into flower you should
start seeing the pistols the calyx
pistols are starting to form on your
plants those little you guys call them
hares the white hairs those are popping
up on your plants if you've got girls
those are popping up something super
important and hypercritical your boy
plants need to be [ __ ] pulled by now
walk through your garden look for boys
look for hermaphrodites get rid of that
[ __ ] because how far can Paul and travel
at least four miles or so it's very far
yeah I don't I don't want everybody's
crop getting pollinated because your Wow
excuse me I just let it a full solid
burp on the podcast I was read I don't
need everybody's crap getting pollinated
because you're too lazy to pull a male
plant out of your garden so go outside
pull the male plants if you haven't
already done it you might be [ __ ] up
already I talked about it on another
episode of how quickly male plants drop
pollen I've got a male plant another
room right over there he is like 15 days
in and he has just blast and pollen
right now so it only takes 15 or 16 days
for serious trouble to start happening
yep doesn't take long I've actually I've
known a amateur breeder that pollinated
his neighbor's grow that was less safe
400 500 feet away oh man with with trees
fences houses all kinds of pollen is
amazing yeah that's its whole purpose of
life is to just land on the female plant
and climb up that pistol and get up in
there wants to get in the ovule there's
a couple of places that have passed
special rules keeping hemp and marijuana
grows like five or six miles away just
to make sure that there's never a legal
war between like the big hammer hit the
big marijuana yeah I totally know a
solution to that
I would I would grow my sensimilla of
grow right next to em field are you
willing to expose your secret on the
podcast I think I know you told me the
way you told me we tell us on the show
or do you have to keep that a secret him
plants only pollinate once a year or
they only release pollen once a year
okay so plan your your your bloom cycles
accordingly if you can yeah but also
most Tim promoters like to grow from
clones well there's a significant other
ways you can protect your own grow from
the next the guy next door who doesn't
know the difference between a male and a
female you just got a it's part of the
planning in the research you should have
done by now or he should have done he
should not have a male out there outside
in the first place I actually know a
couple breeders in California to do
everything outdoors and I just shake my
heads at them so you'll be getting buds
right about now you'll start seeing the
bud sights it's time to get in there and
kind of take off that lower [ __ ] yeah
screwed him up shave the legs in there
you guys get in there and clean off all
the lower canopy where the air is not
getting in something where like a little
squirrel could get help climbing up the
little ladder at the bottom take that
off of there
all that stuff that's gonna hang down
and touch the dirt get get rid of that
all those little sucker branches just a
little thin pale yellow branches that
are just shooting up take all those off
you don't need those go clean up the
inside a little bit you want to focus on
the tops of the plants that's where all
the magic is gonna happen so clean them
up a little bit
follow them out yeah hollow him out a
little bit pull them apart and spread
them if you can if you need to get a
giant stick and stick it in the dirt and
pull one branch this way in one branch
this way so that they're getting Sun
properly feel free to do it they could
take a beating go out into your grow
around noon one o'clock when the sun's
really high in the sky and everything
that's not getting direct sunlight right
then and there you know that's that kind
of use that as a guide of what to take
off so it's you know I mean not
everything's gonna be getting full
sunlight but you know things that are
just in the dark you know at the bottom
you know you can take that off things
that are you know a little further down
the side or bud sites that are further
down the side
they may not be getting full sunlight
but they're still getting sunlight leave
those there so you know just judge
accordingly but all that all that dark
stuff you definitely take that off
that's gonna be lower fee yeah yeah you
don't want to turn that and unless
you're making a bunch of hash and then I
mean maybe you leave that if you want to
but it's gonna take away from the energy
up top yeah all right so stretch face
should be just about over right we've
about the first three weeks we really
start stretching that should be slowing
down now so we can see kind of how big
our plants are actually gonna be gonna
get a judgement of how tall they're
gonna be how much panicking you need to
do on readjusting defense yeah well
people are growing crazy outdoor plants
here in Pueblo and it's completely
illegal to grow outside in Pueblo
Colorado is bad but there are people
that are doing it they're just building
a higher fence every week I see him like
had to put more plywood up I spotted
another one today there was an old
school giant back TV set prop to gets to
gate on the outside it's that time of
year you guys there it's gonna be all
over Pueblo you guys if you're growing
outdoors this year and someone tries to
steal your [ __ ] don't [ __ ] shoot them
grow more weed next year do we have to
do this episode every year but just it's
just we just let it go yeah it's
happened here though somebody got shot
trying to steal somebody's cannabis
outdoors and that medicine that was
supposed to be medicine became a target
of theft which became an attempted
homicide which [ __ ] that we don't need
that vibe attached to this plant at all
that's why we tried to make it legal
that's why we wanted safely accessible
so nobody's getting shot over the [ __ ]
we took it away from the cartels but in
the hands of the medical community let's
deal right yes it is not justifiable it
instantly makes it into criminal
criminal enterprise yeah yes no you're
protecting your illegal crop yes yeah
don't shoot anybody please you guys if
you're listening to this you're probably
not gonna shoot everybody you know
peaceful cool ass people is why you're
listening to my show so stretch face is
over you're gonna start seeing what size
plants are don't pop don't top anymore
I'm glad but that's one of the next
things I had written down is no more
chopping the hormones and the plants
have all decided where the tops of those
plants are gonna be and where they need
to bake the most energy where they need
to send the THC where they need to send
all the energy for budding quit topping
them no more topping you can kind of
bend them you can stretch them down but
don't cut anymore
off the tops of the plant so you take
all that bottom [ __ ] freely but the tops
where the hormones have climbed up don't
take that off of there no more topping
is it time now to adjust the nutrients
that we're feeding them
yeah for sure probably you know
especially by the time this comes out
but yeah last week most definitely now
but yeah go for it we can put this out
we could put this out Monday morning out
outdoor plants they'll use a little more
nitrogen then indoor plants will through
the bloom cycle so keep that in mind you
know keep that bottle of bloom or I mean
bottle grow around the way I do it is
I'd probably just if I felt they needed
a little extra nitrogen shot I just mix
up some some grow and maybe a little cow
mag and feed that in addition to a
normal feed so okay so add it on top of
what's normally feeding you know I saw
sub cool take a bottle of nutrients and
pour it directly onto the soil on his
outdoor grow and then just watered it in
I wouldn't recommend that but I saw that
[ __ ] and it made me shake my head like
some cool really did that bro like one
of the most reputable growers who could
find on the Internet and that dude just
poured a bottle of a nutrient I won't
even use straight onto the dirt and then
watered it in just fine you know the sub
cool is kind of kind of from the south a
little bit he's got that southern flavor
to him so he doesn't give two shits most
of the time I'll hold my tongue on this
time to adjust the feet he might want to
keep Jessie made a really good point
that I didn't think about these outdoor
plants are gonna use a little more
nitrogen than what we're used to so
increase your nitrogen feed if you're
not gonna be a bottle fed nutrient kind
of guy what kind of stuff can we add to
top dress to get a little more nitrogen
yeah now we're talking some neem ill
seabird guano is a great all-purpose
guano if if that's your thing I've quit
using it but I had a [ __ ] ton of it so
it's not going anywhere I gotta use it
up I'm just not gonna buy any more but
seabird guano gives you PKM nitrogen so
it's a real good one
there's something about whatever they're
eating the fish and the kelp that's in
that I think that really adds to the
flavor and the funky smell of good cushy
but I think help and seabird guano
really contribute I love oh
ocean products may make the best tasting
but in my pantry I've done began acai
have done you know the bone mills and
blood mills I'm everything and that's I
love my little my ocean style you know
kelp and crab shell mill seabird guano
works good with it yeah it's I like the
product SEAPLEX from organic hair
definitely as it's a cold-pressed blue
algae based product product and it makes
I think it makes the buds taste better
smell better they get more density and I
think there's something else in there
that just makes them grow better
whatever is happening in that kelp that
life that's in that kiln makes my plants
happier who definitely knows I'm a
little boost helps the fastest growing
plant on the face of the planet so yeah
there's all kinds of natural PTR's going
on there okay it works is I yes I know
toxins and cytokinins yeah auxins and
cytokinins yeah yeah yeah yeah some of
this stuff is not for everybody so
here's a quick little kelp kelp is also
a great bloom booster so you can take
kelp take put it in a mason and say
quart mason jar put a cup of kelp in
there go ahead and top it off with water
let it rehydrate for 24 hours strain any
extra water away if there is a little
bit run that kelp through your food
processor and that'll turn it into just
a mush at that point you can it
dissolves into water and you can follow
your spray it as a bloom booster right
there on your plant and then store it in
your refrigerator
in the back keep it as cold as possible
so that'll definitely make your plants
happy yeah would you add any fulvic acid
to that spray that wouldn't hurt a bit
but make it a little more absorbable
that's probably the recipe to a lot of
organic gluten booster sent them are why
they're alive Yeah right there any
foliar that you're spraying has got
kalpen is there so silica acid naturally
in cup like that it's over this high
silica acid comes in there's a little
bit but most of that or the big source
of that is ala beer that's really
popular right now yeah you could easily
add some aloe vera into that and that's
am I actually going to do that let's
really history thank you we just made a
new products that's went up here did
micro were brain that's in my grower
brain yeah yeah see back in the day we
were taught not to take too many notes
because if your door got kicked in and
there were notes that said feed on week
six feet on week seven you just left a
paper trail in your handwriting you had
to have those plants in there with no
[ __ ] notes and a good memory yep yeah
it was harder that time at that time so
many things changed in legalization and
that's just one of the really nice ones
that she not everyone even gets to see
[ __ ] I was scared to look at it on the
internet even like even to Google or
back then it was like Yahoo or American
were you part of over overgrow calm I
was way too scared to ever ask questions
or post on it but I totally read totally
trolled it look at it alright yeah I
used to go look and all that good stuff
I used to make up fake accounts on other
sites and just go look like that before
I was supposed to be doing it like
cannabis culture magazine had a really
good one too after they shut down and
over girl a lot of the people from there
went and that's I got into the forums
years later when I got my med card I was
like [ __ ] this but once I had my med
cards game the [ __ ] on yeah I think uh
and a lot of people may argue with me I
think that the OG Kush the og and OG
Kush could be og from overgrow calm cuz
if you met somebody from overgrow they'd
just say are you [ __ ] Jesse from og
and you
because you wouldn't want to say
overgrow because if it wasn't you then I
mean I just [ __ ] up they like from
what we just called it oh gee are you
guys all on Ogier what come on over girl
calm and so I think that people were
shipping seeds around like one guy had a
seed and he shipped some of them to
Jesse and then Jesse grew him and found
the phenotype he liked and bred to that
and then shipped those seeds to somebody
and I think that somebody ended up with
a bag of seeds and they call it to
overgrow cush there's so many stories of
where the OG Kush came from that's one
of the ones that I mean that's kind of
an adaptive adapt Jase you know of
another one I've heard okay that's that
one and then the one that involves the
bubba kush guy yeah Matt from Florida
that's kind of the same I mean it kind
of falls in there but that's the - I
tend to believe personally okay yeah
there are plenty of other stories of how
that happened I don't even bring up the
podcast I've heard them on hasn't the oh
geez I have I yeah I love oh gee I love
some good OG my Jeff Shoji has got some
flavor to it there will be some Jeff
Shoji available on the shelf at the
store pretty soon here that John
Randall's jr. trimmed up for us it looks
delicious
so we're top dressing with nitrogen
heavy products how about some ah no I
mean the atom in there okay Adam yeah
alright but don't go too hard yeah you
want to hit hard with your your P's and
K's peas and K's now yeah I remember it
takes a week to two weeks on a typical
top dress for it to break down enough to
be up take a bull by the plant so Rick
plan ahead and you know that's if you do
it right now we're in the morning
whatever it is you know that's not gonna
really take effect for at least a week
so think about that plant is already
yellowing you're chasing it by now yeah
yeah see you sure that you should have
done more nitrogen already so next year
do more yeah yeah and I would still add
nitrogen to keep it from getting worse
and that'll help your buds develop it'll
keep everything moving alright other
top dresses though knee mill is a
favorite of mine crab mill is good for
blue ink and then kelp I mean most
organic bloom boosters are made out of
kelp so that's really where you want to
go do you mess with the Quran Jamil oh
yeah yeah okay that's the neem a lime
mix I use it's okay great mix that'll
keep most bugs out of the soil most bugs
off the plants and you'll never notice
it when the finished product all right
so let's talk about defoliating because
at this point of the season it's time to
clean up a bunch of the leaves do you
like to heavily defoliate or do you just
kind of clean them up I'm more of a
cleanup guy on outdoors I get in there I
get in there and clean them the [ __ ] up
on an inner core I'll take off a lot of
leaves to where people look at you like
you're crazy but then they come back a
week ten days later and all the leaves
are back and they can't even tell I
actually have a plan I'm gonna try it on
this year I've got three of the same
strains planted in a row so the one in
the middle they're all about the same
size the women get tortured yeah what
strain do you have Northern Lights the
old-school Northern Lights number five
the cut that goes around in four shops
quite a bit that the limits been spread
- yeah nice it's a good cut I had that
for a little bit that's the code I made
uh my grape OG with - oh that's a great
cut make some donkey dicks for buds for
sure yeah make some huge huge [ __ ]
buds
alright so defoliant up in there
basically any leaf that looks like it's
gonna be blocking a bud site from
getting sunlight just go ahead and pull
that [ __ ] off and it's gonna grow back
because it's an outdoor plant and you're
gonna be amazed at how quickly the
leaves grow back yeah you'll pull off a
leaf the size of your hand and in ten
days you'll have one back bigger than
your head for sure it is grow and grow
they love the outdoors alright so we've
talked about feeding a little bit we
talked a little bit about top dressing
we talked about defoliating you
mentioned specifically that we need to
talk about caterpillar prevention
so this is the time it happens every
year you know what do we do to get rid
of caterpillars and they've already got
full-blown or full-grown caterpillars
inside your fully developed bud your
[ __ ] there's nothing you can do aside
from just manually picking through and
pulling them out yourself
now now yeah it sucks
yeah now is the time to apply those
preventative things that will keep them
away and you're gonna have to spray your
bud sites spraying your sorry
I just heard voices in my head jump
[Music]
trying to fix it but you fix yourself
you're good you need some buds ight for
that BT to be on to to ward off the
parent from laying the egg in there in
the first place so BT is what I
recommend that's like Captain Jack's
Monterey Spray okay back back c-lister
cider but sillas thuringiensis yeah i
think i think i should google that you
keep talking i'll google that one that's
what I recommend for for getting rid of
any kind of bud warm and now is the time
to apply it so also the garlic oil
ferment that you were talking about yeah
it's very good for that too even just a
central garlic oil from the health food
store would probably have some of the
same properties in it right there yes
it's bacillus thuringiensis I was really
close so yes that's that's available
from Captain Jack's it's available in
Monterey Spray it's a very very popular
product used for keeping away insects
and it's also usable you can use it in
the soil it will not cause any problems
the mosquito dunks that you buy and
whatever Lowe's or Home Depot it's
that's the main ingredient in there you
can crush those up you can put that in
some water you can water that directly
into your soil that will get rid of your
fungus gnats that'll get rid of most
sound creatures
Teno vein is uh is another brand name
that's a dry powdered product but it's
same active ingredient natural has the
same thing you guys if you're gonna use
any of these powdered products beyond
the dunks the dunks are just fine
probably to use without a mask if you're
gonna use natural or act innovate please
wear a mask to research everything
before use yeah when you get a new
pesticide if you take that little
booklet that's on there I know it's
crazy nobody does this that little
booklet if you open it up it tells you
all the safety precautions it's the
truth
I love readin it tells you how much to
apply on certain types of crops it tells
you how long between applications it
tells you what kind of safety equipment
you need to wear any kind of whether you
need to apply it in right because I
matter because if it's gonna rain and
you apply certain things it's just gonna
wash right off and you just wasted that
whole application time and the expense
on the product also in there it tells
you the re-entry interval how long from
spring this product should you avoid
this room without wearing protective
gear because some of the chemicals and
products that are available to Hydra
store much more toxic and dangerous than
you realize they expect you to be a
responsible adult that can read that
label [ __ ] that bare stuff the bear
spray they sell for your outdoor house
it Lowe's that can kill you that can
completely kill a human if you [ __ ]
around and do it wrong so pay attention
to the labels you guys read that [ __ ]
read the safety sheets and then it's
really important I know it sound like a
preaching to you but a lot of the things
that you can get from these products you
won't notice until ten or twelve years
down the line you'll start getting a
facial tic or something and it'll be
from that time there's a brief Laura
might into the fan and it came back into
your face that's how they affect you to
its most they nervous system and
reproductive systems it's the exact same
thing they do to the insects exactly did
to kill yeah she was gonna take a little
while longer on you because you're
[ __ ] 160 pounds
alright so caterpillar prevention use
that bacillus thuringiensis spray it's
available in Captain Jack's Monterey
insects spray has it you guys a very
good recommendation for E they do not
pay me they don't sponsor me in any way
there's a company called RB code comm
ARB I co.com they sell all types of
horticultural supply gardening supply
type stuff you can buy almost any type
of sprays you want you can buy organic
sprays you could buy crazy they sell
anything from styling oil to flora might
in this one catalog they also sell
beneficial in sir they sell beneficial
insects that is something I was gonna
talk about on a future episode with you
but let's jump into it for a minute
beneficial insects is now the time to
release my whole bunch of beneficial
insects yeah yeah I mean that'd be
totally cool party termites and ladybugs
for sure lace wigs I'd go for ladybug
larvae especially outdoors okay
the larvae are a lot more productive
meaning they eat more [ __ ] okay they're
still growing yeah yeah okay and there's
a they'll hang around longer - all right
Thank You ladybugs - stick around is
there a trick to that I've heard some
pretty awful things for me you know
outdoors is where I use the most and
just having a nice welcoming environment
you know that's there's not normally
many pests on the plants but there can
be pests found in the mulches and the
garden beds around so I think that works
to keep them around stick around there -
okay how do you feel about a praying
mantis they're awesome they're hot [ __ ]
tonne of them okay so are bucco calm
happens to sell praying mantis larvae
you can order them set the larvae on a
plant they will hatch and come alive in
your garden you can watch it happen it's
kind of cool I haven't seen it happen
but I've seen videos of it because I'm
kind of an internet nerd but yeah
checking about that company does not pay
me anything but I mean they've got all
the products that you need if you want a
preventative to keep the bugs away if
you want something a little stronger to
destroy them or if you want to go full
[ __ ] madness nuclear they've got the
product for you you can order it from
there they'll ship it to you quickly
right check them out I use that product
I use that catalog all the time just for
plenty of research to compare those what
does this versus this which is better
you just hold the pages and see what you
like better and read them yeah they've
got everything in there but again if you
get some floor might if you get
something crazy
get yourself a Tyvek suit and some
gloves a mask suit up
go all Walter White style and that [ __ ]
do it properly don't get soon
and I also think you're bastards for
spraying that [ __ ] outside yeah don't
don't ever spray it outside there don't
kill bees that [ __ ] wipes eyes out it's
just personal opinion without the bees
you don't have any food right especially
me I'm a vegetarian everything I eat
grows we don't know everything I eat
either grows or eats eats something that
grows your food eats my food yep it's
not fair
it'd be a pretty shitty place without
pollinators yes absolutely
so we want ladybugs we want beneficial
predators predatory mites is what I'm
thinking we want some of the preying
mantises what other kind of bugs can we
put out there to help us out
worms in your soil okay oh yeah put
worms in the soil yeah is it spider good
luck in your garden is it a good thing
to have one or two spiders we've got a
few wasp we've got those too okay
they're gonna cause any problems are
they no not really
I've actually watched a wasp carry away
a full-grown bud warm before Wow
okay here in Colorado we get something
that I don't know if these happen
anywhere else Michael remember these my
microphone cover is bright orange we get
these orange blood worms I've called
them I've heard them called melon worms
before yeah do you do you get those in
your buds around here I've never had
those ones I get like they're like a
brownish green color okay but they're
all I mean they're all beetles of some
kind I believe all right it's is the cat
I've seen the orange ones is the Captain
Jack's and the Monterey Spray gonna keep
that [ __ ] away
it'll yeah our hacks them all equally I
mean for the most part if you got
something really exotic and crazy you
know I don't know but I know here in
southern Colorado it takes care of
anything so so if somebody is local if
they're here in the Pueblo Colorado area
where can they go pick up some sprays to
take care of their insects one love
garden supply
let me see if I can remember the address
it's 116 East 4th Street right 618 618 I
had the right numbers I was close as
close as dyslexic or some [ __ ] on there
but yeah 618 East 4th Street go support
one love garden supply for sure burns
down there she's a great lady she'll
take good care you go say hi to my
beautiful wife yeah go say hi go support
that place go support local businesses
if you can't guys pursue that awesome
alright we've been gone for like 40
minutes talking about outdoor growing if
you guys have any outdoor grow questions
that you would like me to ask Jesse send
them to me
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you
I will compile the questions I'll take
screenshots into my phone I'll put them
all in one little section and then I'll
get Jesse back over here and we will
address your question specifically so
that we can help you out with exactly
what you need kind of dial it in and aim
it a little more at you specifically and
get what you need one other quick thing
plants are gonna start using more water
so don't just give them what they'll
take and what they need to stay perked
up if you want big fat buds you got to
get them lots of water lots of water I
guess that that mainly applies to
inground plants but same same you know
same for a potted container it I mean
it'll only take so much water but right
but as soon as it dries give it some
more oh yeah don't be shy don't don't
sleep in and think you can water those
plants later nope you can't you got to
get out there and water them right now
if you're not want to stay on it don't
start it that's the truth if you let
them dry out its a noticeable chunk out
of your harvest yeah it's I'm sure it's
a noticeable percentage so it's like
that an indoor or outdoor yeah how do
you feel about using a drip system in an
outdoor girl awesome awesome okay
it's I've promised the listeners that I
would talk about building a drip system
but it's not a lot of plant involvement
and I don't want to spend too much of an
episode talking about building PVC pipes
that actually kind of be a hard episode
cuz it's not really hard right just
something that just go do it just get
your hands dirty yeah I'll just there
you go that's perfect I'll give them
like a 5 or 10-minute primer yeah like
here's what you need you know pump some
tubes and a [ __ ] octopus head and
some tubing and some sprinklers and you
build that it seems really daunting
tutorial yeah just get just like Jesse
said just doing it because you got to
get out there and measure you need a
tape measure
and PVC pipe cutter and just got to go
to town and learn how to build it's like
Legos basically I bought these two $30
kits from Lowe's and like I'd never this
was last year never really done a drip
system before I was a little nervous and
by the afternoon I'm like I'm a [ __ ]
expert
boys playing with LEGOs is essentially
what it is they have all of the parts
over there at Lowe's if you go to that
little section and look around your head
will just start spinning and you'll know
what to do I'll do a quick lesson on it
in the future here I might let you come
hang out with me and also it'll be fun
all right guys we've gone 40 minutes is
there anything funny want to ramble and
talk about chaotically randomly that you
want to make sure that people hear on a
podcast anything you got coming up that
you want to share with people I just put
you guys on the spot and you both
looking me blankly secret sessions
coming up you guys August 27th I cannot
reveal the location but it is coming up
I should be there it's the same days
reggae on the rocks so I've got to go to
reggae on the rocks but the headline I'm
not into the headlining band I'm just
not feeling it so I'm gonna leave during
the headlining band and then I'm gonna
go over to secret session Mike I wish I
could tag you in for the headlining band
bro it's your boys now that they're able
to play reggae Mike's favorite those
guys they're playing with I raishin it's
311 and I raishin doing a set together
oh man at Red Rocks Cerreta is such a
beautiful yeah yes like the first time
the plebeians snuck into the roman
councilors brig and the rocks has been
not as reggae every year it's the
lightest way to say that but the band
has got slightly more two of my two of
my favorite reggae bands ever are
opening the show steel poles of course
if you're a reggae fan you know good old
steel poles if you've ever hung out with
me you know I love steel poles and
Morgan heritage is also there and those
are my two favorite like if I had to
just pick two reggae bands it like
defined what I like about reggae those
would be the band's yes
so that's that's a great show for me
it'll be the afternoon I'll get all
sunburned I'll have a good time nice and
when it starts getting all 311 e yeah oh
my god 311 is gonna come on cool I met
311 nice backstage at Warped Tour one
time I went tickets in the
meet-and-greet from kilo that's [ __ ]
yeah it was cool the dopest thing was
this dope ass JanSport backpack I got in
the cave of 80 cuz I've got a tournament
anything actually there's a 311 used to
actually get in fistfights with sublime
which is my favourite band and I know a
lot of people they sound like the exact
same band but so I don't like 311 and
the whole time I was bringing up all
these fights and these guys are like man
these guys are lame and just kind of
wandered off I was like 19 years old so
nice you weren't as polite as you are
now either no no I'm sure you're having
a little more fun with them then then
you're lighting on them a little bit
before trolling people was a thing
totally all right let's remind everybody
how they can check out us check us all
out on the social media of course if you
want to follow me on Instagram I am at
ireon der score genetics most other
things just search grow from your heart
you'll find me if you want to send me me
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com Jesse tell us about your
podcast one more time and how everyone
can find you on the social media check
me out on social media
Jesse grows on Instagram and then you
can check out the podcast on soundcloud
that's Colorado podcast and we've got
some of the episodes up there and then
you can also check us out on Facebook
just Colorado podcast make sure you
support him guys check them out and
we'll have our website back up soon
which is Colorado podcast column so do
you guys get hacked forgot to pay the
bill oh well that's easy to fix
yeah that's easy enough all right yeah
dude thanks for coming taking some time
away from the garden taking some time
from the Uncle Bud Co thanks for
bringing turps yeah for sure yeah I
don't get to see enough bro so thanks
for coming
also Mike let's remind people about your
your Facebook page and how to stalk you
on the social media ah you guys
me at Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
on Facebook and at neo-punk 15 on
Twitter thanks for thanks for coming
thanks for taking time away from the
wife and the kid the dog this is a great
show thank you a lot of fun I love these
outdoor groep assad's I've got notebooks
full of notes from other shows from
these episodes so yeah listeners enjoy I
hope you guys got some useful
information I hope you took a bunch of
good notes I hope you had a great time
I'm gonna wrap up this part of the show
if if you're listening this would be a
good time for emails about tips and
tricks for harvest oh there you go if
you got any harvest questions we have
time to answer for you to prep for that
outdoor harvest can battery overwhelming
don't be somebody that from their
Facebook post looks like they're a wee
bit overwhelmed oh I know two people
that still haven't turned all their [ __ ]
from last year and I'm not even kidding
and they put themself in an even worse
predicament this year Oh sounds like you
know them very well all right don't be
shy you guys I would love to answer your
questions on the show Jesse would love
to come back and have questions
specifically laid out for him to answer
Mike would love to just come be on the
podcast and take some dads and hang out
I love bringing material so bring it I
would love to have it send me your info
send me your questions grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you guys I'm gonna
wrap up this portion of the show where
I've got friends with me you know I'm
gonna play some reggae music for a
couple minutes and I'll be right back
and I'll do the end of the show thanks
for hanging out you guys
[Music]
yeah I want to thank you guys again for
listening
I want to thank Jesse and Mike for
joining me make sure you follow my
friends on social media I also a huge
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band thanks for let me play all
your music on my podcast to truly
appreciate that make sure you support
the mystic roots band ladies and
gentlemen I will be back Monday with
episode number 150 podcast number 150
will feature a dabbing granny the
podcast also features Sam from THC
magazine Brett from Evo labs Lindsay the
traveling stoner and boba blaster Co the
podcast was recorded at the canna Canyon
make sure you check that one out it will
be available on Monday August 29th um if
you guys would like to sponsor the
podcast or if you've got a product you
would like me to review send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I will get you all of the information
that you need now that the show is over
you guys please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart podcast find the review
section type in a little comment let me
know what you think about the show and
give me a star rating that you feel I
deserve I'm not gonna beg for five stars
give me however many stars you feel the
show deserves everybody else's left five
stars so far I'm confident I'll get five
without begging of course I would
appreciate it if you follow me on all
the social media outlets I'm available
on Facebook it's the girl from your
heart podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast on Instagram I use my other
company name it's Irie underscore
genetics I RIE underscore GE and ET ICS
I read genetics that is my seed company
make sure you support that on Instagram
I post a lot of great cannabis
photography ladies and gentlemen if
you've got something saying you're not
into the social media of course you can
email me it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and almost every
episode is archived on ira genetics
colorado dot-com ladies and gentlemen I
appreciate you for listening to the
podcast I'll be back in seven days with
another episode big shout out to my
ninja Spence and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]