hey what's up podcast world that your
boy Rasta Jeff before I start episode
150 I wanted to drop in and say thank
you to everyone that listens to the
podcast and everyone who has ever been
on the podcast 150 episodes means a lot
to me and I appreciate all of the
support also this podcast was recorded
live at the canna Canyon from about six
minutes till ten minutes it gets a
little noisy I tried to fix it the best
I could but it sounds a little crappy
and I do apologize after ten minutes
it'll be crystal clear and you'll enjoy
the show once again thanks for the
support
and now here's episode 150 of the girl
from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 150 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations it's right if you're a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat to the entire Mystic Krewe
ladies and gentlemen this is episode
number 150 of the podcast I am proud to
have made it this far thank you guys for
joining me for this mini episodes
episode number 150 was recorded live at
the canna Canyon I owe a huge shout-out
to my friends at the canyon big shout
out to Camille and Aaron for letting me
do my podcast there they let me invade
their space for two or three hours
I truly appreciate it you guys thanks
for what you do for the community and
thanks for letting me be a part of it
ladies and gentlemen this episode
features dabbing granny THC Sam Brett
from Evo Labs Lindsay the traveling
stoner and Bobo blaster Co I'll have
them on in just a couple of seconds but
first they need to give a huge shout out
to my friends at elevate glass shout out
to elevate glass at 517 South Bay Hill
in beautiful Colorado Springs Colorado
if you need a new elevate glass check
them out let them know that rasta Jeff
sent you they will get you set up with
everything you need music play for just
a couple of seconds and when we get back
[Music]
there are six people here there are four
microphones everybody welcome to the
girl from her podcast one hundred and
fiftieth episode whose happy let me
introduce everybody here ladies and
gentleman to my left back again to try
to get this right this damn time I
apologize for schooner the first time
but joining me there's a beautiful dad
and rainiest to my left welcome back to
the show honey Oh Jeff I'm so excited to
be here thanks for having me so good to
be here with you again thanks for coming
back thanks for being patient with me
no it was terrible that my sd card
failed but I'm excited that everyone's
back again it's kind of exciting so
sitting to the left of davon granny is
my new friend they call him THC Sam
here's Sam from THC magazine dude thanks
for joining me
to me the Evo is responsible
[Music]
we've been enjoying and we truly
appreciate we're gonna try it here in
the future
but across the table last time it was so
wonderful she got more for us coming
available from Incredibles she's gonna
be down on Nevada in my high heels
[Music]
Monday through Friday 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.
all donations to dab and granny on that
corner post
do not go through I'm gonna put this
show back on track a little bit we're
here live at the cannon Canyon Canyon
Colorado Springs is premier social
lounge where you could come and if
you're 21 and over you do not need a
medical marijuana card if you're 21 you
have an ID and you're not a dick you can
come here you can hang out you can sign
a member agreement there may be products
available that if they share with you
you may reimburse them for the products
that are available here oftentimes there
are some tasty hashes there are tasty
flowers here come check it out make sure
you tip your bartenders be kind to
everybody and clean up after yourself
come join us you might come and get take
some dads with boba blaster coat with
dab and granny you never know who could
be here the Traveling Stonehurst owner
is here quite frequently you might get
to meet biddy the dog you may mean
serious come check it out this place is
cool as [ __ ] it's classy as [ __ ] the
couches are comfy the air conditioning
is kicking in it's the summertime so
this is the place to be davon granny I
see you here a lot now that I have
bumped into you I met you this is my
favorite day blonde Rufus is like
somebody's living room
social lodges have TVs and everyone just
zones out into a TV or there's pool
tables er this is like mine sitting down
daddy talking exchanging knowledge and
giggles lots of giggles today oh my
goodness exchanging Terps exchanging
grown knowledge I made a new friend my
friend Sam over here has also
experienced a head injury and he's
writing a book about it can we talk
about your book a little closer a little
cost you're good we'll get you
introduced when do you play it up a nail
and then I started talking to you you're
gonna miss that dab opportunity I
apologize when do you expect your books
to come out over the next few years okay
when you have that book prepared I'd
love to read it and have you on the show
and talk about it because it's great
talking to other people that have
experienced traumatic brain injuries
well thankfully you know I grew up in a
you know my parents were pretty big fans
of holistic medicine so I didn't really
they weren't too big of a fan to put me
right on any kind of pharmaceuticals
thankfully thankfully that was a pretty
great decision on their part and
actually to speak something else just
become something else besides head
injuries when I was in college I pull
out some ligaments in my knee so
cannabis is much more of an effective
pain reliever than a lot of the opioids
that you get prescribed so quickly and
in such large doses so cannabis is
really just something that a lot of
people should really be more aware of
and if even not aware of just more
accepting us right and no addiction
right and you don't go down that black
spiral of cannabis cannabis is good for
you thank you so much I'd love to read
your book when it's available thank you
thank you so much and also if everybody
could check out the sore so we actually
recently just went national we have
copies of the new national the new
summer edition in Barnes &amp; Noble's
across the country on the lookout for
that lots of content everybody wants to
follow they have connoisseur on
Instagram as well we'd appreciate that
we're trying to get everybody kind of
more aware of hemp and everything that
it can do as well as everything that
cannabis does we're kind of trying to
really spread the message sorry it's our
sister plant yeah absolutely nice
everything thank you guys very much we
appreciate it
Brett let's talk about terms buddy I
just love
[Music]
like you're walking smile terse is much
that's probably the best compliment I
have ever gotten I appreciate I liked it
I like this so tell us more about so on
that we recorded this podcast before and
I asked explain to me what a Turk is
nice and easily so that everybody keep
in mind a bit more than fifty percent of
my listeners are from a place where
cannabis is illegal so they know very
basic knowledge about cannabis so let's
break it down to where variable follow
along with us definitely definitely
well terpenes are in basically every
type of well there's two different types
of things that could be in fruits or
vegetables and stuff like that terpenes
or esters but a lot of stuff that you
get off either smell from or taste from
comes from some type of terpene
combination and terpenes are apples
oranges bananas everything that they
also are in cannabis now from my
understanding as of right now there
hasn't been any esters found in cannabis
but there are tons of terpenes and there
are over a hundred and fifteen terpenes
150 terpenes that make up kind of a
plant profile yeah right now the best
labs can maybe test for thirty of them
okay maybe 30 for maybe the best labs
and I honestly don't even know how
accurate those 30 tests those 30
terpenes the testings actually how
accurate they are but and then after
that there's some companies that can go
for 15 or even 10 so I mean it's it's
that's basically there's a whole bunch
of different terpenes that make up a
plant profile so the Terps are basically
what give a cannabis
it's smell it's smell its taste but also
there's a lot more than just smell and
taste to it and this guy stand next to
me knows a lot about the health benefits
and actually knows a lot about terpenes
and that's what actually the big article
in the magazine is about and he knows a
lot about the health benefits there is a
lot of stuff to do with the floral the
smell of it the taste of it and that's a
little most people that buy it only
understand but I have learned a lot from
Sam about it I like to waste I wouldn't
say I'm a total expert but I've
definitely had a chance to learn a
little bit about terpenes on a little
bit of a different level which is cool
that's one of the articles in the summer
edition of the hem connoisseur excellent
and terpenes you worked in okay so
basically as popular as terpenes are for
flavor they do a lot more medically I
actually had a chance to talk with max
Montrose he's the head of the trichome
Institute and he is you know he is
probably the beats her pinhead beats her
pain expert so he gave me you know
really nice little education and you
know terpenes are basically the way he
describes it in the way that I kind of
explained it in the article is basically
like a glass of beer so when you have a
fresh cannabis plant that's a fresh
glass of beer with all of those bubbles
floating off all that carbonation
floating up to the top over time that
disappears over time with a fresh
cannabis plant those fresh oils those
fresh terpenes on the end of the plan
are gonna disappear over time okay and
those not only add flavor but they also
add depending on the terpene a lot of
medical benefits some of them are
anti-psychotic they're anti-seizure
they're anti-inflammatory
they do a whole lot of different things
that we're just real starting to learn
about also depending on what time
harvest you do with the plant you can
also pull different terpenes of the - I
know that Jeff I don't know if you I
mean you grow a lot more than I do but I
know that if you chop plants certain
plants earlier certain plants late you
can get a higher CBG or cbn rate uh rate
usually and in the end what terpenes you
pull off the ten cents so also the heat
how much has affected how much and
really what fascinated me most i think
about my conversation with max Montrose
is really that what people think is the
medical benefit coming from cannabinoids
might really be coming from terpenes so
it's really kind of you have to really
combine the two to really get a full
picture of really what's happening cuz
every strain has CBD CBN CBG depending
on the distrain to some ratio but what
really differs what really
differentiates excuse me a lot of
strains is that terpene profile because
not every strain is gonna have that
certain combination of terpenes so the
combination of you know that terpene
profile and the cannabinoids in that
specific strain kind of contribute to
the overall effect in the overall
medical seems talking about and i have
read about it I do have talked to max
and when I do know that there are still
more studies hopefully that there's
gonna be even bigger studies going on in
obviously with the advancement of
cannabis in this community hopefully
more studies but what Stan was seeing
with is really true how without terpenes
can can't cannabinoids might not
transfer in your brain or transferring
your body the same way so that's what
kind of might there's still studies I
I'm not don't quote me obviously but I
know that there's people talking about
without the terpenes you can't get the
same effect and it's kind of true
because I felt it I mean you don't get
the full wouldn't a good example be
taking the distillate or which all the
Terps that pulls out so when you smoke
that by itself which you're not supposed
to do we're not honest sometimes but
honestly sometimes not I mean I don't
mind raw distillate and I know Jeff
actually took a nice you try to take a
nice just like who wants to take this
right now to the dome and Jeff honest it
was like okay but I do want to say wow
nice pressing look at that it's all
about this awesome awesome let's let's
give a big shout out to this local
artists recycle e-waste me of course
iron matches yeah
those are adorable tools and is perfect
[Music]
iron your clothes cuz there was two
purple ones granny got one of them and
there was another one I was like oh man
I should scoop that cuz it matches his
rig and I was like yo he's not gonna
want that he's like why'd you buy me an
iron and now you love and I'm like crap
that one's gone so bad it can be I do
believe you get a better medicated
feeling once you add any of the Terps
like I like in the morning I like
that lemon gee oh god you know the ghost
train haze that's wonderful for in the
Moors are my two favorites granny Oh
night Zen berry or that blackberry Kush
definitely duh
I mean that's what I was saying I know I
personally feel that without terpenes
cannabinoids wouldn't transfer in your
your body the right way the same way as
I don't want to say the right way the
same way as they do right now when with
terpenes I know one thing as I love
Terps
[Music]
he got mics every direction it was like
gasps you my question I forgot the
question I know do you examples of like
what specific terpenoids work for
specific conditions what they may help
with because we already know a lot of us
know that like high THC strains will
work well for seizures high CBD works
good for like epilepsy oh he's got an
article in his hand to refer to I love
it when people come with research this
is gonna be awesome cuz we're gonna
learn what terpenoids
will help with specific ailments he's
pulling out a chart helping them find
the right page shot to do his page
turner brett over there what we've that
kind of smell like hume Leena's
commented a lot of sativa strains and
basically it's antitumoral antibacterial
it has anti-inflammatory properties and
steep hill labs has done a lot of
research on individual terpenes and
their benefits that's another place that
i've done some research exactly one
thing I can tell you about you Moline
it's also a natural you don't want to
eat it's like it's like a diet pill
almost yes that's it examples maybe one
or two more cuz that's really
interesting to me and I'm sure listeners
you can read all of this in THC mags yes
yes I'm not trying to make every just
won't magazine but I wanted to get at
least two or three this is a quote from
steep hill actually Lionel was a
critical precursor in the formation of
vitamin E it has been used in the
treatment of both psychosis and anxiety
and as an epileptic and as an as an anti
epileptic agent excuse me
what does that one smell like Lionel was
very floral like lavender okay alright
that's probably my least favorite turf I
really do not appreciate the smell of
lavender and Lyle acts it drives my nose
crazy for some reason my nose grows ice
cream different beans are definitely
useful for a lot of different things
were only really just start we love it
so much because we helps us not be
anxious and helps us not be depressed
yeah that's trains really uplifting with
depression exactly that's probably what
Brett what's your favorite term I'm
gonna say Lyman or probably mercy okay
mercy I like mercy this one time in a
way if you've got a sativa strain that
has lemony flavors and lemon
characteristics and you want to bring
out the D limonene terpenoids
let it get a little bit too close to the
light and it will panic and it will
start treating D limonene as a panic
response and defense and that'll bring
out your lemony flavors and I learned
this on accident by getting my plants
too close to the light too many times
and I'm like we're always still lemony I
was like with those are the plants that
almost got burnt and I'm 90% sure that
that's what's happening that's from my
experience I think getting the plants to
close to the the HP s light will bring
out the Lima needs to do it on purpose
drop your lemon Jeffrey get the light
real close to that lemon Jeffrey thank
you for sharing that
Joey thanks for coming on the podcast
you know it was just what you just did
is the reason I started listening to you
it was your enthusiasm through the
[Music]
podcast
grab your friends phone and subscribe
them to the girl from your heart hey
guys by the way special shout out to
Rasta Jeff for this podcast that aired
on Monday I mean this guy pulled it
together and it was like wow what a
great podcast you are a pro thank you
and what she's referring to you guys is
the computer but the part that we
recorded the cannon into a show then put
it in outro on it post it up I pulled
out my memory card and it said files are
unreadable so I had to pull a podcast
together it was about 8 or 9 o'clock and
the podcast usually drops at midnight so
I had three or four hours to put
together a podcast recording edit it up
air it get it up on the website and I
pulled it off it was up there by 11:59
so I was like wow or two shows in
advance actually there's a show that
will come out before this one
1:48 came out today this is 150 so I've
obviously got one of the can ready to go
so yeah shot it's my friend to help me
record podcasts all the time I
appreciate all of you guys the games are
here and not here Lindsay's Donuts were
medicated I know
well last first of all I tried to give
you a time Starfire edibles they are
made with solvent less hash and they are
incredible she makes amazing different
flavors she makes cake cones I won't go
into it too much but Starfire edibles
shout out to them shout out sure that
sounds you like it fresh like you like
it that was my favorite right now
actually nice alright I'm afraid of
edibles the people who listen to the
podcast know that I way too many edibles
one-time shy since then
alright I wanna go this direction again
I was telling granny about how how I
found her
scroll through Facebook one day and
there was no sound in the video so I'm
gonna cut the sound out but they like
check out this lady and it was just
somebody reposting your video you took a
big-ass dad like a dad that I would take
probably a half a gram at least 0.3
maybe 0.5 you suck that dab and you held
it in you chug the beer you chug the
shot and then you grab do you blew out
your dab and you grabbed your your
nectar collector and did another yes you
should not be proud of it but I am
because really can you see your mother
or your grandma doing a knockout and
smiling and then most people think oh
she's laid out I'll come back and do
another big dab for you
she's a we've been we probably smoked
six people here in this group we
probably smoked three or four
we've been hanging out here for the
shows in fact everybody needs to take
big dads that's how I found granny was
watching her do strikeouts and then
somebody was like she lives in Springs
and I was like what and then like she
Shops at elevate I started following you
and I was like this lady and I cross
paths we go to all the same places you
shop it green and healthy wellness
occasionally you support all the
dispensaries in town which is yes I do I
love that you don't just go pick one
place I am a representative for the
cannabis community and so I'm gonna go
all over I'm not gonna give one
dispensary my plant count because that
wouldn't be fair it wouldn't be fair
person I'm a free agent
so everybody what we're talking about in
Colorado if you're a medical marijuana
patient you were allowed to grow a
specific amount of plant plants based on
what your doctor feels is appropriate
based on your medical condition or
honestly based on how much money is in
your pocket it just costs more honestly
so you pay for an elevated plateau at is
what we call it then you can that allows
you to grow more plants and also to
possess more cannabis when you go to a
dispensary in Colorado Springs we are
medical cannabis only and the way that
those dispensaries are able to grow is
those plants that those patients have
they can allow the dispensary to grow
those plants for them we call it signing
over your card signing over your plants
you become a member so that's what
granny's talking about is she's not
gonna let anybody have her plant count
she's in charge of that she is her own
she's a free agent she grows on her own
none of these dispensaries own her they
don't have her plants they can't brag
about it and hopefully granny's got a
nice garden overall but that's none of
our business unless she wants to tell us
I don't know the first thing about
growing has helped me with a lot of good
tips I could show you give me the idea
to become the davin granny
well I've uh I've always I've always
smoked I've smoked long before it was
illegal and this dabbin thing was pretty
new about what maybe two years ago and
at the dispensary I was going to they
kept saying you need to try this you
need to try this I know y'all are young
boys with slapback hats I'm not gonna
try this uh this is not for me I'm an
old lady well then actually it was the
owner of the canna Canyon Erin and Pete
they were like come on try it you have a
high tolerance try it when I tried it
but I wasn't too big on it cuz I didn't
know what I was doing then November I
got a portable email can I tell that
story you could definitely tell any
story I'm gonna shout out gabato up and
in Denver because they're the ones that
encouraged me to go in front of a camera
when I didn't know what the hell I was
doing and do dabs and smile and talk and
when I was like but why should I do it
they're like cuz people will like you
people like me I don't know you can
handle it and so there's several things
that intrigue people especially the
normal people that are in Colorado
taking dabs and the people that don't
get to dab the people then when they do
take dabs it's a pea-sized and they get
high because they rarely get to dab
they're blown away by this but now
everybody wants to dab yeah everybody
wants to dab with you yes keep it quiet
that you're coming here because
otherwise this place just fills up with
people trying to beat granny I have
learned don't say where I'm going yeah
in the August issue of the hub
connoisseur had the chance to do an
interview with davon granny over here
and we got to talk about she started
with cannabis exactly what you just
talked about kind of how she's changing
what it looks like to consume hash and
it's changing to take a big changes what
people's opinions look like of you know
what a high tolerance looks like what
actually functioning on that high
tolerance looks like I woke up this
morning to 151 your told me she only has
[Music]
no and if you just say 150 150 1000
followers in one I know it's amazing
but you know the best thing about being
dad than granny what this right here
look how many young people I have
brought together tonight
exchange the conversation I think we
might have heard you Chris I love the
vibe in here right now there's some
revolution playing in the background yes
I needed butane what dad doesn't need
buting not to blast dabs but for my
torches so I was on Hancock and Delta
and I seen Rasta colors and it said pops
crops gift shop no red card needed okay
butane right yep I walk in the door and
there's somebody on a couch and it's not
the can of Canyon vibe it's more like
dad lounge family joint kind of vibe
y'all bar room kind of vibe and a person
on the couch goes you look familiar
I'm the davon granny and I wasn't
Tooting my horn or anything so I said
yep butane and the girl goes yeah and
she was kind of attitude with me Anna
she said if I turn you on to a DAB can I
record it and I said sure I don't care
so she's recording and she goes she says
she's famous I hope it was worth the
wait
she dabs me doesn't kharbut and lifts
the damn joint off the pipe and I just
go peace you're not supposed to carve a
nail no you just lift the drop down
right off the nail right it's just weird
it was very weird they didn't like me
there I don't know
she says she's famous I'm like
yeah don't go there somebody was just
killed in the parking lot there last
week those were hard words for bringing
people snacks and being awesome that's a
granny for bringing a good taste
obviously that's great know what else
caught I actually really wanted to blush
that day in the car with
[Music]
so I'm gonna let him try to chew these
real quick why inside Joe it's about the
car honestly just trying to make you
blush back we did experience one thing
in the car though I don't like it when
the person in the seat behind me tries
to use a dab torch like four foot long
dreadlocks and that freaks me the [ __ ]
out completely
that's funny cuz then on the last
podcast when someone was sitting behind
me on the couch and they were using a
torch and I looked at you and I was like
okay you're right that's weird I don't
like that like wore my dreads down how
is there one of them loose right now we
have three dreads to three non
dreadlocks would you like to explain
what's happening to us I am taping up I
have some viola I don't even know what
it is it's some biola shatter
I like the paper oil slick by the way
that's how I got your note oil slick cuz
I admired this beautiful shatter paper
those are good friends
shoutout to Josh the entire oil / find
anyway so I got to know him because of
the parchment paper anyway so some Biola
which needs to be kicked up a notch it's
not real flavorful so our good friend
the Turk pimp has some Durbin poison I'm
gonna that's my life it's like my second
or third favorite right there it's so
distinguishable it's one of my favorite
flowers to smoke exact that's why
honestly and I don't enjoy the Terps it
hits my tongue where it just it's
overpowering to my tongue what was the
combination you had last week that you
was like oh it was the Durban poison on
some shatter I don't remember what the
shatter was but there there's that
licorice anise flavor it's too
overpowering within the Terps the
flowers are amazing I love the lemon G
the ghost train haze the OG Kush the
paradism
whatever there's a berry with Zen berry
[Music]
last week the ones you brought to secret
stash loved to every one of them the
Durbin poison my tongue doesn't agree
with it the Brecon taco myself no that's
why I'm kind of having issues over here
I'm like which one do I talk into granny
is now taking a - there's no healthy
sized AB there that's got to be that's
point 2.25
[Music]
Braham vile like a quarter dram violet
he nailed it I'm out of her eyes but yes
to tears of Terp Terp tears tears how
long she's been consuming cannabis as
soon as she quits Chokin on this mini
dab since she was 14
never happened no I'm telling you since
she was 14 I think I know that it is
it's Lindsay is correcting my giveaways
are trivial I call
glassblower
[Music]
they actually depend on their to sell
their income off of the social media
whether it be glass or clothing or
whatever bred out for being such a kind
loving person in the cannabis community
when I jumped on the scene back in
November I didn't know what the hell I
was doing and none of you in fact most
people were like where the hell did this
woman come from I still have this this
note that Brett wrote me with one of his
first slaps as the people call him could
just slap them up on everything
his light bulb Mary's motivation that
just encouraged me to keep being
positive and silly and I have so thank
you Brett just for kind of saying I was
so happy picture cuz I don't think he
believed that I really kept that letter
for that long but I this is how positive
and just happy you always are and like
every time I see you you're never upset
you just alright let's do this let's
here's Terps let's do this I'm you know
like so positive all the time
is Instagram it displays exactly that
guys follow is it mary's underscore
motivation or mary's motivation
underscore motivation check him out in
the morning he takes a morning Deb he
doesn't silly dance
he's I tried three times okay I just
don't like yours right to your mouth
what the hell is that that was so
perfect I was like dude I'm never gonna
do that I don't have a rig that's it was
just perfect hi I was what did it I was
just looking at a stone looking at the
rig and I was like how can I take a
funny day and I looked at my Bob Marley
poster on the wall or tapestry on the
wall and I'm like well I Rick kind of
curse maybe I could do a headstand it'll
reach right my mouth and and honestly a
first trial like honestly tried my first
trying to work outside the box I'm not
gonna lie but my will not pop up over my
head so I asked grumpy grandpa will you
give me a lift and he said you are not
one of those 25 year old kids no I will
not help you do a handstand dad can I
help you
[Music]
oh crap back upon two things I'll tell
you when I first started doing dad than
granny I have to blow my nose
Deb you know that's the best he was like
have fun but I don't want to be on the
camera and I respected that and I was
like well
what do you want people to know you as
and he is like well just just call me
grumpy grandpa and I was like ok
actually because he has such chronic
pain and chronic illness some days he's
pretty grumpy compute 11 huh but
considering I've been with him since
1974 and he still makes me laugh every
day he's not that's awesome yes he is my
life partner that's awesome you know
it's good things and bad things as every
relationship is right I like that he
watched out for you didn't let you do a
handstand for his love today he was like
you're not gonna do that but I want to
make it look like an upside down make
something happen for you all right what
state did you live in when you started
consuming cannabis at the age of 14 I am
an Iowa corn [ __ ] I think that might be
better than Terps let some Hornets from
Illinois were either we talked about
earlier does exist how hard was it for
you to get some cannabis when you lived
in the corn up in the corner actually I
started meeting guys coming back from
the Vietnam wha you told us about you
know I was exposed to first cannabis and
then many other things
arrests yeah okay and at this point in
my life I can truly say with life
experience don't mess with that other
[ __ ] I can agree with that I mean okay
you all you young folks say you need
your spiritual experiences with
psychedelics I respect that
I'm not gonna do it and as far as like
math and stuff
oh man that's poison stay away from that
crap anything that anybody has to make
stay away from that I know that sounds
contradictory cuz we smoked Earp's but
we're extracting something from groan
suddenly alright thumbs up there we go
we're gonna do some yoga
over here alright so granny me granny
meets these handsome young man coming
back from Vietnam and starts smoking
cannabis in Iowa out in the corn raisin
hell being a youngster when did you move
to Colorado I've lived here 24 years now
oh so you were here before the cannabis
revolution yes okay but did I smoke
cannabis yes Oh far before the
Revolution of course
I lived in Europe before I came here oh
they didn't have cannabis but they had a
lot of flowers and you know this has
been a long time ago and I'm telling
things I'm telling secrets but I would
every now and again get my hands on
cannabis oh boy did the Europeans love
American cannabis oh I bet and I always
I just have always found people that
consume or like-minded folks we like to
you can always find it's like we if you
get a new job if you go to a new school
if you move to a new town if you go to
the new whatever if you join if you're
an arch into archery when you go to that
new archery class whatever it is if
you're a glassblower you walk in your
class for everyone smokes bad example
but if you walk into most places you can
look around the room and be like ah that
dude over there he's a Terp or just like
me
hang on kind of feel the waters out but
it's break time it so you want to go uh
[ __ ] get some 420 on you can always
just find the like-minded pot heads in
the group it's it's just because we put
a vibe outward where's a few haters in
the community but you know that's like
every every sect of life you're gonna
have a few bad people of course but for
the most part the people in the cannabis
community are happy people were loving
people we want to help each other we
want to help other human beings and we
love the earth we want to respect it I
mean we're all pretty like-minded we're
all connected in that one way we if we
don't love it if we don't take care of
the earth we can't grow cannabis
cannabis makes us more peaceful it makes
us more connected it makes it easier to
love each other I'm never angry you can
be angry at somebody and know it's ugly
[Music]
you know you're so angry at your
neighbor whatever it's an anger is a
pretty ugly emotion ah does your
neighbor know that it's eating you up
probably not who's it hurt yeah
he's renting space in your head for free
let it go go talk to him yeah all right
granny you're awesome to have on the
podcast I like some of the stuff you say
ezel you said a second ago that you're
telling your dark secrets what's
something you've never shared with
anybody that you want to tell us here on
the podcast I'm gonna put you on the
spot like that cuz I wanna know what
you're gonna say hand on the chin looked
up at the sky I like this lady
okay I will say that I obviously I've
done a lot in my life and I I have no
criminal record I'm still alive and that
amazes me when I think back at some of
the things that done so I'm Destin I'm
destined to be here right now as Deb and
Grammy guaranteed we're all destined to
be right here right at this moment yeah
so my favorite friends even Sam the new
guy bro I like your vibe I like what you
know thanks for coming we've been going
for almost an hour it's time to I do
that thing where we talk about everybody
social media connections and I think
everybody come for coming so davon
granny tell everybody how everybody can
find you on all the social media let me
know about the YouTube Facebook
Instagram everything
I'm on Facebook and I'm kind of liking
this live stream and on Facebook you do
great Facebook live videos it's only a
few people and they do they probably
take a DAB on Facebook live as the end
of this recording and obviously because
I am the dab and granny I consume a
large amount of Medicine I have to have
a few sponsors some first ones are
debate oh I know they take a lot of
grief about their product but as far as
I'm concerned there's many of those
portable emails out there branded under
many names any one of those companies
could have come and said hey we like you
we're gonna help you they didn't divide
Oded
I liked Abbado who's 420 they had pens
they have silicone things they make exit
bags which you have to have at every
dispensary here in Colorado and then I'm
gonna be reppin mega toke which is
smoking cannabis so this is gonna be
smoking flower which is kind of
different for me so be watching for me
to be doing some more mega tokes
chokes granny how much hash do you smoke
in one day on average about 4 to 5 grams
4 to 5 grams of good quality shatter or
live resin every day you guys that's
impressive she keeps up with me if she
doesn't do me to the sponsors I love
that this community is willing to
sponsor each other and help each other
out
it makes the wheels go round that's
right Andy thanks for coming on the
podcast I look forward to having you on
future episodes because I love your vibe
you need to have your own show I hear
that may be a possibility in the future
I'm going to encourage that I'm being
told not to talk too much about it but
you need your own damn show that's what
I think I've said that before you need a
show Thank You death anytime we're gonna
hang out do some dabs we're gonna do a
Facebook live together Sam thanks for
joining me dude your first podcast these
guys's first podcast dude kind of 1.5
first ones the practice run remind
everybody where they can find you on
social media and then tell us about the
magazine connoisseur awesome check my
you guys make sure you follow the hem
connoisseur it's a great magazine well
made well printed brats time grab the
mic but I'm gonna actually seen you
before
this isn't I go way back like this
before we even met so he's intimidating
he's like a 6 6 6 dude
[Music]
and when you actually know what he does
and who he is he be intimidating I
actually saw him at it was some cannabis
event it was ahead of be uh think champs
possible here in Denver and I do Rasta
Jeff that I have followed his genetics
in [ __ ] for a while and I couldn't even
say what's up because I didn't even know
it just talked about and even out of
protein but now like look at me I'm just
like let's take a dad yeah bro yeah I am
so appreciative that you have asked me
to be on your show like you have no idea
this is a dream come true so thank you
so much man Bret didn't this teach you
that every one of us were all alike I
appreciate the admiration and the
respect I completely appreciate that and
it's returned bro you are a lab manager
for a well-known lab that makes one of
my favorite products like Eva Webb co2
and Instagram we do have a lot of good
Turks you guys on again to do an
in-depth episode about terpenes how
Terps are made I got the perfect person
we're gonna go in-depth so we're gonna
get you guys more real knowledge we're
gonna get beyond that we're just gonna
go real real nerd like so that only a
few people even understand the
terminology cuz some those are some
people's favorite episodes Brett thanks
for coming dude I look forward to doing
more podcast with you and you both
cannot wait yes yes thanks for being a
fan boy
yes if you see me in an event and I'm
pretty sure I could speak for everybody
at this table we're just people we get
thirsty when we wake up we gotta pee in
the morning we like to take dabs around
six o'clock I want some food
or does normal people walk up you do not
say hi to me and you know who I am I
will be very upset because I know
eventually I will say what's up to you
and if you say the same thing I've said
and you've heard this and you say this
thing I'm like yo bro I've told you cuz
this is me talking you people are so
come say what's up what's Deb honestly
that's obviously not that shy I get that
I'm six five and I've got dreadlocks
down to my almost my knees yeah yeah I
get that I could be intimidating I
usually got three or four people hanging
out with me when you know what you're
doing deep radio voice oh my god what
what is behind that voice come say hello
and I'll be your friend we can hang out
we can take some dabs we can take some
selfies now no that doesn't happen don't
do that please that's weird we gonna do
squash
smash on Facebook I posted this so I
posted to Facebook that I was setting up
to record a podcast with Gavin granny
and someone on Facebook the first
comment was y'all gonna smash after what
smash I know no probably not
sorry but if we do there will be video
and we'll post it to Facebook and you
guys are get to check it out
[Applause]
[Music]
all right Chris you got a microphone in
your hand tell everybody your Instagram
and or snapchat and or social medias and
then also tell us a whole bunch about
burn ature okay well I'm Bobo blaster co
Bo Bo blaster co finally on Instagram my
snapchat I don't even know my snapchat
and they honestly I think I might have
it listed on my co2 you can fire me that
shirt tell me about that
oh yes the brown shoes I have a whole
bunch of sweet little furniture ideas
all night ideas I have a whole bunch of
products that are available on furniture
Big Cartel dot-com and basically I make
coffee tables and tables
I have shelves that with basically
emails built into it so you don't have
to have a clumsy little pod because I
need one yes yes that's why he is not
all over social media rasta Jeff he's
too busy building wow yeah how long ago
did you give me my table that was over
you're just talking about the other day
on the podcast I still work yeah no
problem
that was like an original original just
a decoration I sent it over to him for
was to really get that that work into it
that was one of my first original ones
on sighs get the og furniture I know and
I've seen like really just dads and
Jeff's that guy
yeah ideas you want to come to me when
you're stuck in [ __ ] traffic between
Denver and Springs for an hour
can you move 10 feet because there's a
wreck up there nobody cares if you're
taking a damn you're not gonna drive for
an hour anyway why can't I take a DAB
officer I just yeah you just definitely
gave white Mike a panic attack while
he's listening to this sorry that was so
unfair Mike is like oh my god I'm like
where's dad sometimes the traffic is
horrendous Mike I'm sorry all right
thanks for making the killer it's great
to be in you can have candy cane and
stuff like this be able to have and be
able to meet so many people I wants it's
great the canyon is a great place you
guys states that are passing
legalization for medical please keep in
mind
not go strictly rock I mean there's
people that really truly need medical
please keep that in mind
secondly remember you need places to
gather and consume you have people that
have leases that they can't medicate in
their own apartment where are they gonna
go
you need places like this we have
learned here in Colorado so listen to us
we're trying to help you
we're not being arrogant but just put
some forethought in a couple of things
granny's completely right in Colorado we
messed up when we wrote the bills here
we did not include consumption areas so
there's a gray area these places can be
shut down at any time this canna Canyon
where we sit are allowed to sit here at
this table and gather peacefully and
take some dabs and have a podcast
together this could be stopped at any
moment with just a letter all that would
have to be done as a letter written and
a judge says no more and it could be
over so when you do get around to
writing the legalization bills in your
state make sure you include these types
of places make sure you put so many of
these places available in so much
locality and write rules for them
because if you don't write rules when it
comes to make rules for cannabis
legalization in your area the rules will
be written for you and when they make
the rules for you you get really [ __ ]
they say okay nothing then if you let
them write the rules they don't give you
[ __ ] if you make the rules yourself you
can have experienced people on there
that understand what this community
wants it needs encourage you you'll be a
part of that make sure you get the
social clubs in the legislation get your
[ __ ] together
remember people knowledge is power on
the March yes just because we're getting
a recreational Eagle in some places
doesn't mean we can get lazy with it
thank you thank you the beautiful
Lindsay Chris is better half lovely red
dreads cleaned up a little bit today I
liked it it was getting bad take their
little fillies off
I actually like it better coming on the
podcast Thank You fracture most of our
listeners know how to find you by now
but remind everybody all of your social
media connections um so my Instagram is
the traveling stoner my snapchat is
travelling stoner without the G my
twitter is the travel stoner and my
periscope is the traveling stoner you
are one travelin stoner that's me I like
it give anybody that is sponsoring you
that you need to support while you're on
here yeah I mean she Jazz is just the
bomb I can't speak highly enough of her
and dank essence CBD infused bath bombs
as well bombs so reason for duties I
think actually I tried many of them I do
like thang essence because they are high
in CBD x' and up to me okay school I
used to just soak with some Epsom salt
now I use these bath bombs and they work
Colorado Springs young men of Colorado
Springs you dab dudes are sitting on the
couch on a [ __ ] Saturday taking dad's
watching dab and granny do videos go do
her yard work go mow her lawn for her go
pick up the trash go pick up the leaves
just hit her up on Instagram say davon
granny I'm gonna come clean your front
lawn because Ross and Jeff said so and
I'm a respectful young man there's no
need for you to be out there cleaning up
you're too awesome get up off the couch
go help out the davon granny then after
that go help out someone else's granny
and clean up some [ __ ] leaves clean
up their yard help somebody else do you
know I always send my youtubes every
morning by saying make it the best day
you possibly can be your own personal
best and always try and do a kind deed
for somebody at the end of the day I see
no reason to not in this podcast on that
[Music]
just call in on face time somebody put
your mic up to them so kabuki Jay Fox
just happens to call writers were
recording it's so awesome kabuki you
gave me a gift the other day and I
appreciate it thank you brother
it's really a piece signed and said I'm
welcome at any time so that's awesome
[Music]
he is great with the CBDs I always talk
about I see his Instagram pictures and I
salivate guys I love you every one of
you thanks for joining me on the podcast
you're welcome and thanks for joining us
on the podcast is glad to find out
you're coming heard you're coming
alright somebody told me you're coming
I'll say that's gonna be rad cuz Sam
school I've heard a lot of cool [ __ ]
about you already want to do a podcast
any of you you're bored you want to hang
out say let's podcast I'll put this gear
together and we'll do this this is rad
[Music]
if you have interest in the cannabis
community you've got something you'd
like to talk about don't be shy I'd love
to hear from you we'll put you on the
podcast send me an email that's the best
way to get a hold me you guys send me an
email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you've got something you
want to talk about or if you've got a
product anything I'd love to hear from
you content is amazing I want to hear
your opinion I want to know what you got
going on in the cannabis industry thanks
to the candy cane Ian we're on Colorado
Avenue I think I don't wanna give you
the wrong address
15:03 park in the back parking up front
is crowded so go in the alley park in
the back it's a great place you cannot
walk in through the back you have to
come through the front door if you're 21
and over we invite you if you're not a
dick if you want to come smoke some
cannabis you want to come smoke some
hash you want to come be a cool person
and hang out we'd love to see you here
you guys I'm gonna sign off everybody is
getting distracted because the hash is
spinning around the table everyone's
getting excited thank you all for
listening I'll be back in just a couple
of seconds to put a bow on this [ __ ]
for joining us again thanks for having
me and you know I'll come back any time
Jeff she's gonna be back a lot you guys
a person stop now or we'll just keep
going all right podcast world I hope you
enjoyed episode 150 of the girlfriend
Hart podcast I wanna thank you for
listening to this long episode again I
need to apologize for the shitty sound
quality for about five minutes there I
tried to fix it the best I could there
were some things I couldn't edit out I
hope you were able to get through it I
want to give a big shout out to the
davon granny thanks for joining me also
big shot at the THC Sam also shout out
to Brent Lindsay and Bobo blaster Co
also shadows at the can of Canyon and
elevate glass also huge shout out to
everybody that listens to this podcast
and also to everybody who has been a
guest on this show I completely
appreciate each and every one of you
alright guys now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart podcast find the review section
type in a little comment let me know
what you think of the show and give me
some stars and give me one through five
stars give me as many stars as you feel
like I deserve I would appreciate your
rating so far everybody has given me a
five star rating and I appreciate that
if you leave a comment I will read your
comment on a future episode I would
appreciate it if you stalked me on the
Internet
follow me on Facebook at girl from a
heart podcast find me on Twitter it's at
G fyh podcast and check me out on
Instagram I use my seed company name
it's Irie underscore genetics please
check us out I post a whole bunch of
great cannabis photography I think you
would enjoy it
if you've got something to say it or not
into the social media thing you can send
me an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com if you'd like to sponsor the
podcaster if you've got a product you'd
like me to review once again send me an
email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you need
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher and most of the episodes
are archived on I read genetics Colorado
comm you can catch the show on Tok radio
every Tuesday that's right check us out
on Tok radio.com they play the show
Tuesday at 1:00 p.m. big shout out to
citizen Jay and everyone on Tok
radio.com it's all I've got free this
week ladies and gentlemen thanks again
for listening I want to give a huge
shout out to my ninja Spence it's all
next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for
[Music]