[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 151 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff on to thank you guys again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic Roos crew ladies and gentlemen
welcome tips on 151 this episode
features a new guy we brought Juicy J to
the table he comes and hangs out with us
also white Mike and Lindsay are back I
hope you enjoy this episode this episode
is brought to you by our friends at
elevate glass that's right elevate glass
517 South Tejon in beautiful Colorado
Springs Colorado if you're in need of a
new smoking device if you need a new
smoking accessory if you need a case if
you need a nail
whatever you need go check out elevate
elevate glass gallery 517 South Day home
they've got everything you need to get
nicely medicated before we get too far
you guys only give a huge shout out to
my friend at Stone trikes make sure you
follow at Stone trikes on Instagram
shout out to my brother on trikes are
you guys I'm not the music play for a
couple of seconds and when we get back
we'll be at the table and we'll be
joined by Lindsay the traveling stoner
we'll have Mike Nemo Punk 15 and Juicy J
from North Carolina we'll be at the
table hang on listen to some music
welcome back to the podcast to my left
is a returning guest a repeat offender
my buddy Mike welcome to the show buddy
thanks man
Mike tell everybody I'm sure most of the
folks know but remind everybody that's
new how they can stock you on these
social media you can find me at pablo
for sensible cannabis laws on facebook
or at nemo punk 15 on twitter you guys
also uh make sure you support his public
for sensible cannabis speech because
there's a lot going on in puebla right
now once you listen to this you're gonna
want to go there and you're gonna want
to read all the stuff he's gonna post
your
it's gonna be a huge marijuana election
folks stay tuned yes huge huge huge and
the new voice that you guys are hearing
kind of in front of me to my left just a
little bit over there on microphone
number three is my new friend Juicy J
blaze we're gonna call him J today
welcome to the podcast my friend thank
you and thanks for reaching out you
reached out to me on facebook and asked
to come on the show I love it when
people do that
I appreciate it welcome to the show
sitting to my number right number four
microphone before I don't know what
where that is over there it's kind of my
in front right ish my number right
number yeah we're gonna get there we're
all high I just a minute ago it's been
that kind of day
microphone number four trolling me
already welcome to the podcast honey
thank you thanks for coming back and
joining us thank you for calling me and
asking me to come on OK when I realized
there was an open mic I was like let's
do a Lindsey over here I was super
stoked I just picked up food and I was
like nah never mind we're gonna just
this joint is running like Usain Bolt if
you want to fix that when I pass it to
you all right so welcome to the podcast
everybody everybody listening thank you
for joining us there's a lot going on
before I get to that I want to talk a
little bit about my weekend ladies and
gentlemen I had a good friend bless me
with a front row ticket to reggae on the
rocks if you've never been front row
right down the rocks that's a damn
experience go check that out it's
different it's way different when you
got to state lines go for it I just
bought my first concert tickets to Red
Rocks today actually are we gonna see
I'm gonna see gez on the 22nd so I'm all
know I have no idea Mike and I were
discussing earlier that how we're in the
way different music than a lot of people
Mike's like 10 years older than
everybody he works with I probably I'm
the same age as Mike 10 years old
usually when I take over the radio work
that's been happening for a while
well that's funny because I had a front
row ticket and the headlining band was
Mike's favorite band which is 311 love
it guess how much of 311 I stuck around
for
not a second so the band that I wanted
to show I probably did I probably did
they set it off at Red Rocks that's one
of their favorite places to play that's
one of the best it is one of the best
venues in the country I am a spoiled
brat I've probably seen thirty Red Rocks
concerts and that's no joke probably 15
of them were widespread panic
I was working that night and I caught a
couple Facebook it was like I wish I was
there I remember that you would probably
had just left a lot yes so I get to see
I got to see Morgan Heritage that's most
of the people that listen to the podcast
frequently know that my favorite reggae
band currently it will change and does
just my taste change I'll here's
something that'll catch my attention but
Morgan heritage has been my favorite
reggae band for a couple a few months
here probably the past year or so they
were awesome they played at 4:45 I got
to catch most of their set they sounded
fantastic they played a bunch of new
[ __ ] that I didn't know which was kind
of cool I kind of wanted to hear some
familiar [ __ ] like you know you want to
hear your favorites but I also like
seeing them they do kind of a jam band
thing they start off with one song they
don't stop till about halfway through
they're said they just segue song to
song to song so that was kind of neat
that kind of did a medley what's your
favorite song by them Joe it really
depends on the mood I'm in that's a good
question right now like not like this
moment I'd probably throw on like Jah
seed is one of my favorite songs by them
but then strictly roots is also a good
one and then there's a bunch of like
remixes that they do because they're a
reggae artist so it's always don't put
out a single all the time but strictly
roots is a great one so I got to see
them they ended then I was in the front
row and I looked back toward the sound
booth just looking into the crowd and I
see one of the band members hanging out
I was like ah he's over there I was like
I'm not gonna go bug him but he's right
there and I turned around and his
brother Peter Morgan was walking right
past me and Peter Morgan is probably my
favorite reggae singer if I could sound
like anybody if I could sing like a
reggae artist and probably be Peter
Morgan I know that sounds really weird
cuz he's got a high-pitched kind of
voice he's kind of squeaky but that you
could [ __ ] sing and if I wanted if I
could sound like anybody probably be him
him or Ritchie Spice but uh it's just
the kind of reggae voice I wish I had
I know I don't let its cool but that
dude walked right past me so I just put
my hand on his shoulder and that dude is
beefy bro like you know any touched some
people they kind of move that do did not
move he's one stout [ __ ] Jamaican I
put my hand on his shoulder and I was
like bro thank you and he just turned
around looked me straight in my eyes and
he stuck out his right hand and he shook
my hand and he said respect and then he
kept on walking because he didn't want
to get mobbed you know if I would have
stood there for three seconds he would
have got crowded so he just kept not
moving so that was cool I got to meet
pretty much my favorite reggae singer at
reggae on the rocks that was awesome so
he walked by ah time went on and then
Steel Pulse came on Steel Pulse might be
my number two favorite reggae artist so
is great seeing them I'm heading to
joint you guys steel poles was great but
they were a little slow everything just
seemed a touch slow they're getting
[ __ ] old like all the dreadlocks are
super gray in steel poles those are
getting great they're really long but
they're getting gray so shut it's my
anonymous friend who got me up front row
they're a reggae on the rock so truly do
you appreciate that that was a good
[ __ ] time I'll never forget it thank
you so bring in the rocks
oh I gotta keep going the band after
that was I rationed about a song and a
half and I was like let's get the [ __ ]
out of here and we left I raishin was
not entertaining me one bit I didn't
like the sound if you like I ration I
apologize I like roots reggae that I
raishin was not doing it for me that
night so I left and I drove to the
secret stash my buddy Adam Hill for
hosting the secret sesh Adam it was in a
really good mood there's a really great
time I got to meet Adams wife for the
first time I see her she follows me on
Facebook we follow each other on all the
social media so it's cool to finally
shake her hand and give her a hug shot a
- Adams wife I bumped into Lindsay there
I ran into the Devin granny I saw Bobo a
blaster code there saw Brett for a brief
moment I saw the Grammy Gatsby the great
event you guys if you're ever able to go
to a secret session didn't recall urado
make sure you get on the list make sure
you go do it come take some dads with
Lindsey myself - Devin granny yeah it's
a good ass time shout out to max for
that big ass debut gave me those
delicious shout-out to max for every
time that we see him and every time I
see him is so take
dad here's some bacon here's some
educated he makes medicated bacon you
see people grubbing it at the event and
they look satisfied bro
he gives me some well I mean I can't
speak I think his is in the crust I
think he puts like a cinnamon I mean I
could be wrong on that really so don't
quote me I've never eaten it because I'm
a vegetarian yeah yeah I would assume
you have to like cuz I mean cooking it
in the oil wouldn't do enough because
you were ready to tell the dosage it's
real crispy and it's coated in something
because I've he handed me some and gave
it to me but I just gave it to Bobo
blaster Co because I don't need bacon
when I told him that I'm a vegetarian he
kind of looked at me and he felt bad
that he had been offering me bacon he
felt like legitimately guilty like [ __ ]
I'm sorry man no it's cool man he goes
here here I got this though and he gave
me a big-ass dad like a really like a
manly sized dad when I told him I soak
it all in one chunk I'm good on that
little one but thank you thank you what
did we just smoke that was space cream
okay that I had a good flavor a good
smooth burn nice white ashes I like that
packaging can you tell me about that
company and that packaging the springs
shout out to our friends at altitude so
this dude showed up with two packages of
pre-rolled joints the weed was good yeah
stone from it these guys yeah one of
their managers is a very good friend of
mine and I trust that place because of
her so cuz I know she wouldn't represent
a place that wasn't I wasn't worth
representing she's got too big of a
heart so shout it's altitude that's
really cool it's great packaging this
new package is a pre-rolled joints of
quality joints oh yeah presume that you
know I don't know why a lot more
companies are
I like it it says sativa and indica on
the top that's rad
cool great packaging good idea you guys
over at altitude I like that the first
place I saw that was a place called
pride in medicine in Denver but they
fell off on all the new rules came in a
couple of different places doing
something similar and I like the way
that this project turned out those are
sleep I get a chance to try just about
every product out there on the market
being able to travel the whole state oh
yeah I'm a sucker for name-brand and
marijuana you know I've tried to Snoop
Dogg but Willy I got to give a shout out
to him he's the his model he actually
grows his weed in house you know unlike
like Snoopy just comes to write a name
on the Strand likes Willy actually this
is his company grew it and I went to a
blue sea sky in Denver and they had a
little room set up at guitars albums
where he'd sign all kinds of merch and
then is that a recreational or a medical
place okay so anybody that's coming from
out of state make sure you check out
what's it called again Willy's Reserve
Lucy Skye and you can check out Willy's
Reserve there and it's a dispensary
where they got some Willie Nelson
memorabilia and merchandise that's kind
of cool okay he's got concentrates and
edibles - I haven't tried those either
struck a couple of pre-rolled joints
I've just seen the packaging the Patchen
packaging look intense intense you pull
it out and there's another pre roll tube
in there and it's like a Russian doll
trying to buy cannabis now exactly
that's all right Lindsay what did you
just bust out they just threw some of
some snacks here on the table what do
you got for us
this is the incredibles monkey bar oh
[ __ ] square is 20 milligrams I'm gonna
move these right out of my reach I
appreciate you I love you more than
turps but I have any edibles since my
experience at the CP I know I'm kind of
trying I'm trying to every time I know
I'm it's it's once I get on a streak I'm
really weirdin I like to stay on a
streak I don't know man I'm on a streak
I got five milligrams in the car yeah
whenever I pick a streak whatever I'm
doing I'm really stubborn so if I commit
to something then I just like to once I
made it like a week or two and I've
broken the desire or whatever then I'm
like it's easy let's just see how long I
can go on whatever I'm doing here
whether it's not eating meat which has
been 20-something years now or not
brushing my hair which has been almost
12 years or you know I don't miss either
one of those nice and close here so you
got almost you could almost brush your
beard just to make your no edible Street
fun I even showed up with edibles this
time I've got a bunch of high end
chocolates that we just got into the
shop that I just felt like trying so I
they come in a sample pack so I brought
the sample for us to play with
I had the person that got me those
regular on the rocks tickets that might
be her favorite edible that you brought
they're the tiramisu one there I had a
bunch of people asked before and that's
the one I plan on trying but you know
how I act for lemon G dad's that's how
she gets for those terrorists see there
edibles the packaging is impressive as
[ __ ] they're totally compliant with the
new rules - which I like is a lot of
stuff that I'm even that I'm getting
samples of right now isn't packaging its
yeah I think they just plans we really
get yeah and I I mean I haven't tried
one yet but so far packaging and
presentations at home run remember back
in the day when we had a dispensary and
the packaging was basically one of these
Ziploc bags with the product name and
written on it
literally places steal that sell weed in
baggies oh that's funny yeah we would
get the owners owner one of the owners
would walk in with a laundry or not you
know like the sweater storage bin the
big plastic bin for like under the bed
was one of those Tupperware things the
thing that a lot of people make an easy
cloner out of and it would be full of
like slices of banana bread individually
wrapped in ziplock bags with just a
piece of scotch tape taping the flap
down so it fit taut and that was what
went onto our shelves like yeah it was
exactly that and you know where they
stayed when we closed at the end of the
night right right there on that shelf
nothing get away there longer than like
three or four like he's glad like we've
advanced to where we are now because I
it's a good thing that the health
department is overseeing edible
production but I do I never pictured
something like the product I'm holding
in my hand I mean even three years ago
let alone five or seven it's like
something that you would get from a
really fine hot chocolate company
through the mail or something like I
figured the company that they get some
exotic friendship you know that's
probably just somebody making it up but
they've definitely got a high head
chocolatier working for him these are
impressively [ __ ] I've paid a lot of
money to give these two girlfriends
throughout my life it's just not
medicated I've paid the same amount for
these that I paid for unmedicated
chocolates more than one holiday so
since we're - I'm up let's give a let's
give him a quick shoutout they didn't
pay for any advertising but they seemed
to be the talk of the show for a couple
of seconds here Kota signature truffles
the signature truffles they're packaged
very nicely they come in a black box it
looks like a condom package three
different flip doesn't it looks like a
fancy condom box is what it makes me
pink
more than one person described it is
that so it's the logo it's not the box
it's the logo it makes a circle and it
yes but I had heard about these long
before I actually got um I got to see
them in person and one they were at the
shop Lindsey just threw a medium-sized
at me I'm gonna have to take this one
so something slows down for a second
just know that we're getting higher for
your do you guys dive in if you want one
the flavors are kind of listed on the
box here how many milligrams is each
piece each piece is ten milligrams so
it's only 60 so you guys can really dive
in and try a couple the starter step
keeping my streak I'm just gonna keep
thinking that infuse it with some acid
or some some THC how much does that
package cost if you're not an employee
at the dispensary I honestly don't know
what a snobby [ __ ] are you know
surprised I haven't learned yet the
[Music]
price range it's about 23 okay worth it
worth it that's probably worth yeah if
you were a dude and you were in trouble
and your girlfriend's a pod and you
brought those home to your to your
girlfriend you promised okay this way
you gotta save it till you already done
[ __ ] up wait so she already knows when
you're in the dog house already and then
show up with those this is uh I screwed
up good don't call my momma combatable
did your wife call your mom when you
[ __ ] up
no look like
Jeff was really concerned for you my mom
called my wife which it's weird that
we're talking about that now on the show
but these are delicious just so you know
gross do do that they call their
significant others mother I mean like in
30s and 40s to tattle and like get them
in trouble just saying yeah my mom and
just laugh and hang up honey I know
sorry mama
so you guys we did come together for an
actual podcast we're not gonna talk
about dads and chocolates and all that
[ __ ]
pretty much Mike called me similarly
today for Mike and I it might have been
early for most do folks is probably well
into your day I was just thinking to
myself I bet to this conversation happen
at 1:00 and I was still had an am
attached to it Mike's 59 and he's like
hey ah this is what's up this reporter
is looking for somebody to talk to
because there's this news story going on
and he's like would you like to speak
and I was like new and about two seconds
later my phone blew up with a whole
bunch of other people asking me would
you like to speak for us would you like
to speak for us cuz I'm well-spoken I
guess I'm well-known amongst the
cannabis community and they felt that
I'd be a good representative so sure
that's all the people that message me
and wanted me to contact this reporter
for hey that's cool I passed the baton
over to our buddy Mike because I don't
want to be on the news talking about
that I grow cannabis I just don't want
to do that so I let Mike do it and
Mike's well-spoken and eloquent and well
now there's a reason caregivers don't do
interviews yeah it's a really good
reason
Markowitz effect I didn't want to name
it on the show legitimately the
Berkowitz effect the one and only
caregiver in Colorado to really do an
interview paid for it severely yeah is
still paying for didn't in many very
real ways and it's been a lot of years
and in pueblos that means that we had no
caregiver advocates down here is sort of
for lack of a better candidate that
became me a long time ago thank you
you're welcome it's a fight that I care
about
I'm caregivers have been part of
for more than a decade we've never been
part of the problem and I say we in a
very general term because I am NOT a
care giver but they're very much under
attack again right now in Colorado from
a number of different angles people
they're going after the doctors right
now and looking at plant counts there
every county is restricting the number
of plants you can grow in a home or
looking to limit the size and scope of
your garden for in one way or another if
it's not by plant count directly
it's a rough time I predicted a couple
years back that caregiving wouldn't be a
thing by 2020 we saw this happen in
Springs less than a year ago and now
that's basically the same rules are
trying to implement Springs are trying
to do here it's it's even more than that
they've already done it here and what
their what the what's going on right now
is our Board of County Commissioners is
talking about putting a question on the
vote this November on the ballot that
says should we go to the state and
continue to lobby for a statewide cap of
18 plants per house and even even if you
have a medical recommendation from your
doctor to grow an increased plant count
of say 60 plants the didn't [ __ ] your
medical card [ __ ] your needs [ __ ] your
condition yes roll this the new rules
that they're talking about wouldn't
affect the card that you get written it
would just affect your ability to grow
on that card okay
you'd be limited to that number of
plants unless you had a specific type of
property which I haven't just seemed to
find anywhere it's just not in a house
or a residence and because of what
caregivers are and what the other rules
around caregiving are in Colorado that
means you can't be a caregiver and have
more than 18 plants period because of
your caregiver you can't have a
storefront or a building or anything
like that you have to do it at your home
so essentially these new rules statewide
means no more caregivers and your
extended plant count card could still
exist and you just be excited assigning
that extended plant count to your
dispensary which feels like is what
they're trying to do with most of
the patients are trying to take away the
caregiver and send it all to a
dispensary so they can make some tax
money off of it and not worry about
what's actually needing to be taken care
of that's been the goal statewide for a
long time
caregivers have been the scapegoat for
all continued black market activity in
Colorado for the last eight years
anytime a home girl gets busted they're
like oh my god these medical rules are
so confusing
and I go back and reread the article in
the paper and it's that there was no
paperwork it wasn't a caregiver that was
breaking the rules or manipulating the
rules or hiding under the rules it was
just a black market grower that's been
here for forever doing what they've
always done the only thing that's
different is that caregivers also exist
in the same state but caregivers are the
public face of home growing and so they
take all that heat at the same time the
state has gotten a taste of recreational
taxes and they've gotten a real look at
the sales totals by volume in the Med
markets still eating up half of what
Colorado period is selling and they
would love to tax that at the higher
rate so medicals kind of under attack
under all fronts right now which is why
I'm telling people to register to vote
for eight months something then you can
clear up for a lot of Colorado folks
people in Colorado have this thing that
they think this since as an adult
they're allowed to grow six plants if
they get their basic six plow plant
medical marijuana card are you allowed
to grow your six + or six or are you
just limited at the original six it
depends on where you're living that is
confusing ash it it really really really
really okay so here in Pueblo it matters
city to County this city doesn't care
what your plant count is I worked
incredibly hard for a very long time to
make sure that the city of Pueblo did
not implement a plant count limit just
we found sympathetic ears inside city
government and myself and a caregiver
here in town who isn't willing to go on
the news but is willing to work with
city government people
managed to get them to hear reasoning
and not do a plant count limit so they
did a square footage limit and require
air filtration we couldn't get them to
hear reason on a number of other rules
they implemented that I don't support
nearly as much but in the county they've
already passed an 18 plan count limit
which means if you live in Pueblo County
versus City you're limited 18 plants
period if you live in a residential area
there are some exceptions to that and
you'll have to look up your specific
zoning your residence and then what the
specific rules are for that zoning
designation but before I could give you
a hard answer on that so yeah answer my
question because somebody came into the
dispensary the other day and told me
that Pablo was an 18 count County and I
was like what are you talking about I
was like no it's not mean is like yeah
it is he's like look it up and I was
like I remember that fight and there was
not much public support against it
carriers are really busy people this
state put the squeeze on them several
years ago with a couple of statewide
limitations that mean in practice
caregivers don't have a lot of free time
to lobby City Council's and when they do
they tend to get treated pretty badly
because they're there for one specific
issue they don't have six months to
learn how to play the insane game you're
required to play to do things like that
it's often unfortunate that the system
works that way but that's how it works
and so caregivers have had a rough go of
it in Colorado and it looks like one
maybe two more elections and they're
gonna be something that's in our history
books
we need caregivers so if you can really
do if you're a part of the vote make
sure that you wait for this to come up
on the ballot and you do not allow them
to limit our plant count to 18 plants
this is an example if you've got a four
by four train you've got one light it is
very feasible it makes a lot of sense to
run
sixty-four plants in that 4x4 tree that
sounds like a lot of plants right but
here's how you do it you cut 64 clones
as soon as they start popping fat roots
you put them in the 4x4 tray you put a
little capillary mat down for those
roots to grow into you do it's like a an
ebb and flow system you fill that tray
then you drain that tray every hour fill
it drain it fill it drain it you got 64
little plants and there you flower them
they're about six inches tall they
finish off about 12 inches tall and you
pull about 6 or 7 grams for a plan
that's a pound of weed but you got 64
plants you do the same thing with one
plant or four plants under 7 gallon pot
just depending on how long you want to
veg it it takes a lot longer it's way
easier to pull that pound of cannabis
for Mike's medicine with 64 tiny tiny
plants than it is with a whole bunch of
big pots and bigger plants that you have
to veg for a longer time so it makes a
lot of sense it's not like 64 plants is
not like cartel numbers kicking out
although that's way that's one pound
just one example
I mean people when they see something
like ninety nine plants is the state
limit they picture the plants they've
seen in the newspaper that are the size
of a Volkswagen bus the end they just
don't realize that immediately the
numbers cut in half because only half of
those planets can be flowering right
when you're talking about a caregiver
with that's growing ninety nine plants
it's often because their caregivers four
or five patients often five patients and
then themselves and each patient
requires two or three strands each
strain requires one or two moms when you
start dividing out over life cycles in
two different rooms all of a sudden
you're you're just struggling to stay
under 99 and you're barely producing
enough marijuana for just your patients
and if you want to run a seed pack to
find something new then you're really
already over numbers as soon as you pop
those ten and get them planned it gets
very complicated and when you're number
six it's it's in almost impossible you
you're basically left with plant a seed
pray it's female maybe keep one and
rotate five I mean it gets very
complicated quickly and
it's not productive and it doesn't do
anything to combat the things that
people that are writing these rules are
hoping it will it's not gonna do
anything to the illegal growers it's not
gonna do anything to the smell of
marijuana in neighborhoods move shitty
gross with no carbon filters it's just
gonna make life a lot harder for
patients who rely on caregivers for
medicine at a price they can afford
it's gonna force them to go to a
dispensary it's gonna force them to
maybe find a ride they don't have a ride
maybe they don't have time maybe they
don't have money because I know that
what if you've got a caregiver what you
are reimbursing your caregiver compared
to what you are paying at the dispensary
is a huge huge drastic difference the
difference is massive almost 50% yeah I
mean just the cost to the the patient is
50% at least so here's something that we
should think about Mike I've been your
caregiver for how long now so it's
probably 2010 ish give or take so six or
seven years I know your cannabis needs
very well I'd like to think yeah I've
watched you evolve into a little dabber
lately it's been kind of neat to see
it's a time saver I can name strain I
know which strains you like I know if I
walked into my garden I'd be like I
gotta throw a couple of these into the
room for Mike because he's gonna need
this in about 60 days I gotta get this
ready for him yep
Lindsey's a budtender she's a very good
bud tender she knows you but how much do
you know about Mike's cannabis needs
right now yeah nothing wrong with that
that's not your job that's not your
responsibility I'm assuming actually
that you need a variety but CBD yes it's
curse tonic when your streams I curse
tonics one of my favorite green you know
I mess with it in the daytime I'm not
gonna get that thing done but that's
exactly what I needed to do for me in
the evenings but we we're wandering
caregivers are important damn it
yeah but my point is that I know what
Mike needs know I have a schedule I've
got flowers pretty much prepared when
Mike needs them I know like Oh should I
better put that into flour soon cuz Mike
got this from me a little bit ago he got
this that means pretty soon as jar is
gonna be empty he's gonna be like
where's my grateful dog bro and I'm
gonna need to have something that ready
for him and no offense to you you're not
supposed to know that but you don't know
that [ __ ] you're the you're gonna be the
one providing his cannabis if they
eliminate me from the chain and you're
gonna have to learn all of these people
that do not have a caregiver anymore
you're gonna have to try to learn their
medicine you're gonna have to try to
have that product on the shelf can they
grow it green and healthy wellness
supply those flowers that Mike needs the
juicy needs that I need that you need
the people in that room need people in
that house over there need can we
[ __ ] supply those specific flowers
like a caregiver can no because they
don't have that many mother plants and
they don't have the time the part of the
equation that really worries me isn't
really the part that affects me directly
a lot of the people that use the
caregiver system in Colorado are
consuming massive amounts of THC
concentrated oil and CBD concentrated
oil and in the medical or the rec market
this is gonna cost them hundreds of
dollars a day per dose when you price it
out recreational several hundred dollars
a day per dose two doses a day so you're
looking at twelve thirteen hundred per
day in medication and in the caregiver
market with the plant counts that are
under attack right now they're getting
that same dose at the same quality if
not better depending on the production
and in a far cheaper price pennies on
the dollar because of how its produced
and where it's produced they didn't need
the million dollar machine the two
million dollar building the hundred
thousand dollars in permits and so they
don't have to pass that on to the
epilepsy patients into the cancer
patients that are taking a thousand
milligrams of CBD twice a day or a
thousand milligrams of THC twice a day I
had a caregiver give me a
bottle that was I think 648 milligrams
of pure THC what would that cost me at a
recreation 648 oh no way more than that
does your rec rec you're looking at
around sixty to ninety eight gram for
good for good like co2 oil if it was
pure CBD teacher a little bit CBD
tincture CT oil and THC I mean you're
still looking at maybe 300 bucks okay I
exchanged a 10 pack of seeds for that
team sure because it was a caregiver to
caregiver transaction for a child
um I mean recreationally that would have
cost a fortune
yeah for 160 milligrams you're looking
at I mean like 60 and I'm sure he would
have given it to me if I didn't even
offer him the seed pack in exchange
right I was like you get something you
know like there was stuff here so you
get stuff for my stuff it's how it works
um I mean the caregiver system is where
the people that really really need the
in high quality high dose medicines
that's where they get their their their
product if I have to I can deal with the
recreational market I've got a job I've
got access to enough cannabis product
selection to keep myself on my feet and
healthy enough to work but there are a
lot of people who can't say that in
Colorado that rely on caregivers and
that's why I don't mind standing up and
doing press or advocacy for caregivers
even though I'm not one I definitely
appreciate it oh I'm sure a lot of
people just don't want to be seen even
though it's more seen walking in to a
dispensary right to purchase it there's
still very much a stigma you can still
very much lose your job like the pork
chop
what's the ID yeah it's the same thing
as walking into the porn shop for some
people they just can't be seen doing
that yeah yeah I like hope somebody sees
me walking in there the porn shop or the
dispensary if they stalk to you and
watched you go know that you're gonna go
home and have a great day there's
definitely a stigma attached for a lot
of people I still run into irregularly I
run into customers who are from other
states who are like I can't use the ATM
in this building because my bank might
know that this address is where a pot
store also is that I mean like a handful
a day it's not rare well because in the
large parts of the rest of the country
doing what we're doing what we're
talking about at this table will land
your ass in jail for an incredibly long
period of time these delicious
chocolates we were just eating are like
a serious felony in some parts of the US
because in Texas concentrates in what
state well that's a great way to say
rolled your own cigarettes look I said I
used it for you talk a little more to
the mic for that I'm just gonna make
sure we get this part again okay I told
the cop I said well I'll use those for
[ __ ] so I don't get [ __ ] stains in my
underwear
coming up my [ __ ] and it still didn't
work I said in court too by the way
you know it's really embarrassing he
gave me 45 days in jail so 45 days of my
life was taken away oh these are rolling
rolling papers man I remember those days
though when when I was in band in like
seventh grade they told us to buy
rolling papers for something I don't
even remember what about the instruments
but the paper specifically was good for
something with the rap you read in it
yeah yeah I mean that's how little I
think a little bit but I remember the
speech in class they're like alright
what you're buying now is currently
contraband if law enforcement contacts
you about these you can explain that
it's for your instrument and that
hopefully you don't get a ticket for
having what we're telling you to have
and that was like 20 years ago and
there's still places in the country
there like that I was in that hail man I
mean it was and I went back about a year
ago I don't have a paranoid feeling here
now you know what I'm saying yeah a cop
gets behind me you know I was that
paranoid feeling came back and I hate a
little bit palms get smooth I starts
twitching a little bit in the corner
you're like [ __ ] I'm going to jail no
the gym going to jail I'm going to jail
you know I hate that feeling I hate that
[ __ ] so what brought you to Colorado
from North Carolina having that fear
yeah yeah well welcome we're glad you're
here I like your vibe I'm glad you came
on the podcast yeah I'm glad you reached
out to me you said you work as a courier
for a company yes I work for Stratus
it's we make THC pills okay and we do
medical and recreational we have
probably the highest dose CBD probably
on the market when you say obtain two
ones so you just drop these straight
into your drink and it dissolves and
then you drink it there's that that's
the brand-new product
we don't have the the the brand newest
scent on our shelves yeah just the
Stratus pills I was pretty damn cool
they're uh brand new product on the
market last what six months yeah they've
been in business for about a year but
they exploded everywhere across the
state about six months ago I really like
them personally they're they're a great
low-dose medication option their their
CBD products are really convenient and
they're available recreationally
yes relationally around 100 milligrams
and medically 3 different kinds the
relax is like a it's a hybrid the
energies the sativa and then we have
also one asleep the sleep I get more
feedback is it just real heavily
activated THC a yeah okay that makes
sense that makes no sense and these are
sins absolutely he just medicated a
Snapple yeah I watched him dropping
people and shake it up as I could you
got in there and he's like THC we
discussed medicating my Mountain Dew and
decided that was not safe around all
this electrical equipment from what I
understand you can medicate any beverage
[Music]
it works like a kind of okay and yeah it
fills up and there is kind of a taste in
like a carbonated beverage I can taste
it but like in this tea and I've tried
use as well there's not really a mild
flavor yes nice mom for sure that the a
lot of drinks have a heavy flavor so an
option that I can a medicate whatever
beverage I want without adding tincture
which is always a little weird
I do like sodas but you can taste that
medicine you can
demanda see and then they're also kind
of we teach a stand out you know I like
my head will like these kotas right here
they don't have that right I'm not a
horse I don't need to eat the flowers
yeah I just needed to get that THC in
there yeah I was just laughing I was
halfway through it and I was like damn
Jeff's gonna call me out on this but
like man Brett really had it right in
the last one when he did like the
stretches in the middle he kills it on
Facebook
Brenner or on Instagram post the
greatest [ __ ] on Instagram shut sheva
Theo labs at Mary's you know he has a
fake so make sure you follow the right
one yeah Mary's motivation yeah show to
the correct Mary's motivator he's only
got two posts it's the fake one don't
follow him you should know how to spell
motivation yeah so you're a courier and
you get to go to probably almost half of
the dispensaries in the state what's
that like we had an episode a great
variety Medical am recreationally part
of that makes me real jealous it's a
gorgeous state and I would love to spend
part of my day everyday driving around
it but after a while keep in mind it's
September now so yeah it's no fun in the
winter social media feeds are the photos
are amazing so we did an episode you're
a podcast listener so you probably
listen to it we talked about the
craziest [ __ ] that people have seen in a
dispensary going to all these
dispensaries I'm sure you've seen
something crazy like what do you mean
crazy just something that stands out
something that you'd want to share with
a bunch of people that listen on a
podcast anything you've seen either at a
dispensary or like a smoke lounge or a
smoke event whatever craziness you've
seen at an industry event or facility
yeah give me a minute to think about
there's a few things i'm trying i gotta
narrow it down I'll let you like that
joint
he's lighten up one of V he's got these
sativas from altitude organic medicine
premium Kanak owns five high grade cones
so there may be health risks associated
with this product [ __ ] you'll feel
really good it'll kill your cancer and
you'll have a smile on your face oh the
head Rosenthal super bud nice that's a
great strain I know a dude they drew
that for several years yeah yeah I'm
looking at looking I'm at the end of the
table guys and I'm looking down the
table and I see at least eight
mainstream cannabis companies I mean
different companies products vastly
different types of products yeah and
just this afternoon I was reading an
article that was saying Colorado doesn't
have real legalization um it hurts their
there are people that are gonna vote
against legalization this November
because they're worried they won't make
enough money when their state ends up
exactly like Colorado is now and it's
insane I can't believe you'd have vote
to risk going to jail and keeping it the
way it is because of something silly
like that there's a lot of change I was
a black market grower for far too long
and it's much more comfortable having
shifted to having this badge around my
neck all the time and knowing that what
I'm doing is not shady you know what I
mean like if I'm doing something I'm on
a camera you can watch me all day this
is what I'm doing is where I was it's so
much easier that way let's do run a bit
but they hit pretty nice for a pre-roll
just pack a bunch of cones
I've made 900 pre-rolls and a shift
before like after you pay I was just a
monkey in the corner might spin that
monkey me to buy also make sure that
sure that they roll and burn a little
bit
we're a judgmental crew the first bit a
little bit I saw the first one Usain
Bolt that first one could've ran the
Olympics it was running so fast this one
is kind of so you know sorry
altitude we didn't mean it just
completely bash you're pretty good I
rolled worse when you're at a concert
you're like I'm gonna fire up this joint
you like the other side and then that
part falls apart like this one just did
yeah yeah yeah actually I couldn't
smoked any weed the front row reggae on
the rocks for a little walk and sneak
off by the trees and smokey a little bit
of lead exactly shake the bottle of duty
reggae on the rocks
I asked a couple of people I was like
how's the check and like oh they just
gonna Pat you down they let you through
[ __ ]
they almost got the gloves out they were
taking [ __ ] from everybody at reggae on
the rocks but they were cool about it
because they pull your pipe out or pull
whatever you whatever they found they
didn't find my [ __ ] pull it out and
they'd be like all right check it out
I'll give you the option to take this to
your car you're not bringing this in but
when you come back if I find this on you
again we have to call the cops like
we're turning you in to the police and
like in the camera right there and the
camera right there just saw you so I can
do it again that's cool yeah so you get
the past at least as long as your show
the one little chickens like the pass
it's just for the record pretty sure
that one security guard lady was a
prison guard by day or a prison guard by
night and every stop [ __ ] around a
concert venues along yeah she's like
arms up take your sweater off your ways
to put your take your hat off
first I'm gonna touch you here then I'm
gonna touch you here then I'm gonna
touch you here now I want to check by
your dick is that okay
yes because a couple people got injured
I don't remember exact some rocks rocks
that was a couple of years ago timers
but right before that they'd really
started looking at security and making
some improvements inside it's a
completely my first Red Rock Show I
think was fish in ninety five six nine
ninety five saw fish there and it was
basically a hard judge of enya's
security from the night fish play dude
it was a it was a giant dirt field it
was a giant dirt and cactus and [ __ ]
brush fire waiting to happen type of
field and if we're a hippie wearing
sandals it was just a big toe [ __ ]
dirty spot
I remember Red Rocks when I was a
teenager and it wasn't just a concert it
was an adventure it's still slightly an
adventure if you're not into uphill if
you got weak legs and I kind of
challenged myself a little bit I was
like I'm just gonna do this [ __ ] let's
go and I I did well I I can control my
breathing quite well and I've got
[ __ ] these climber legs cuz I'm so
tall I got a lot of leverage so you just
go up that hill all day [ __ ] long but
well I just go prepared like I'm not in
fitter in shape I just know that I'm a
little bit before I get might get to my
seat because a lot shirts at E shirt a
long-sleeve shirt a rain poncho a bottle
of water it's the [ __ ] i-65 hours on
those stone steps waiting for the doors
I did that once waiting for fish I 95
but I ate so much acid that I didn't
know where I was anymore so it didn't
matter floating around it was great yeah
no idea what was going on it was a great
time but now Red Rocks looks like it
looks like a state park it looks it's
really cleaned it's cement it's all
cemented everywhere a lot of the parking
is now submit it's not used to be in 95
it's completely different in 96 I snuck
over the back of the stage and watch the
Allman Brothers Band from the rocks
behind the stage for free this year I
saw somebody up there and I'm 99% sure
security [ __ ] climbed up there and
arrested those [ __ ] and they
got like if $10,000 ticket
you can't do that [ __ ] anymore Red Rocks
has changed they almost got the glove
out and I was waiting I was like so
you're gonna get the glove or what
because you didn't find what you're
looking for you I've got clubs I got the
black pH gloves
that's gross oh man yeah Red Rocks how
do we get there that's crazy
it's been a long a stretch hashtag I
like it when you ramble do you think of
a crazy dispensary story man you gotta
you gotta hit a concert the only
concerts have been in the Colorado is
the little okay yeah I haven't been at
the concerts there but I've been to the
DAT plenty of the dab boys I'm actually
I've got tickets to see Jeff Tate and
Emma Arnold at the dab lounge this
Thursday so by the time this podcast
airs I think I will have seen that show
it was [ __ ] great you guys you should
have been there it was awesome tomorrow
night [ __ ] that's tomorrow that's why
we're recording tonight it's tomorrow
night I think the shows at 7:10 you can
get your tickets on a friend of Mines
Facebook page I'll link you up with them
or just go to the dab line just Facebook
page and there's a link it's in like
five bucks dude yeah I think it's like
seven bucks at the door so you're not
gonna spend too much money
that's a comedian named Jeff Tate and
his friend Emma Arnold and they are
doing a show called good cop bad cop are
you your microphone is I know how to fix
it but I need a screwdriver to do it
okay sorry well I didn't mean for it to
do that to you it's never done that
before mic stand
it's all it bears now
strangest yes this actually happened in
town oh of course it's there's one spot
but it's geta okay so so okay this is
gonna it has a well I'll probably give
it away right here but there's a
laundromat beside so we go two weeks ago
we go birthday joint shopping because it
was my friend's birthday and she was you
know some places give you birthday
joints we're coming in and shopping my
soul's birthday yes it was happy
birthday so if you listen to the podcast
or not but happy birthday so it was her
birthday and we went to this place and
start walking up and this guy comes from
out of nowhere soul said he come out of
there walk the laundromat I don't know
but he just kind of popped up on us and
it just blew my mind there was nobody in
the dispensary but him he didn't know
anything about any the product I'm like
so you know I asked him they had some of
our product and I said what do you know
about these are here so all the little I
don't take pills he was the worst
salesman I've ever seen it's not hard to
sell a joint you know yeah yeah you
telling everyone reason not hard to sell
a joint I can confirm the [ __ ] out of
that and you know that's the most with
it just snatched his badge my badge of
honor like fitty cent taking someone's
chain so I just avoid you guys I don't
have bullets very often and I just took
a hit off of a blunt I actually have a
very rare picture on my phone geoffery
hitting a
funky but I swear to god he was like
moving in the picture in his blurring I
don't care cuz you can clearly see you
can clearly see it's him so like I was
trying so hard so fast to get it because
he did you tell it's Bigfoot account
yeah for sure
shut it's my boy an appeal my friend
Adam bill is sponsored by backwoods and
he smokes a lot of backwoods and he
rolled up a big yes yeah yeah and he
licked some he licks it up like his
school he said something it was like
extra saliva or something
yeah he used to chew them Thanks that's
pretty much what Adam does you choose
the end of it while he's smoking on it
oh he would break a piece off and shoot
him oh man your Grandpa's a damn man he
was I'm gonna get a stomachache thinking
about that I wasn't even gonna come back
when men were men and the life
expectancy was like 46 yeah to the damn
thing
no but I've met people that do that
before that either just not directly on
a backwood or use that as chewing
tobacco people that I don't know how I
grew up in tobacco farm land that's
where I'm from I'm from Victoria so you
know that was kind of normal you know
what I mean he I'm sure he grew he
raised tobacco my mama sit there tell me
how she used to pick it was just five
years old I just felt so bad for cuz
this is some rough work yeah so uh I'm
sure he's probably just threw a whole
leaf in his mouth yeah it was pretty
rugged I get really lit up when I smoke
blunts something about that tobacco leaf
just really makes me spin around and get
so I've barely been smoke joints I
mostly just abs is my world lately
trying to be polite I try to have some
fun
I'm highly offended that you're not
eating any of the edibles there finally
just ran there's somebody there's people
in the house that are not on the podcast
and when they were offered some of the
Stratus they just took off if you want
that it's over here we can reach it all
you gonna do is come eat that we're
gonna peer pressure you think that's a
winner dude these won the Cannabis Cup
this year if you guys want any of these
I've got all the flavors dive in stop it
work I had the day off and I had to stop
at work for something and I'd had people
ask me for or asked me if we carry them
and so I just grabbed both both kinds
that we carried and brought them for fun
dive in did you try that Monkey Bar
not yet but it's on the do list they
don't pay me to say this at all but that
monkey bar from Incredibles is one of my
very favorite edibles that's ever been
made in my how much did you eat so yeah
this is this is this is why I hit this
twice within a 12 hour period I consumed
over 2,500 milligrams of edibles
yeah yeah so I'm just taking a break I
can't go over like 30 or 40 okay myself
cuz you know like six or seven hundred
was hard for me that was what I was
going in and then I completely stage to
you exciting movement a little bit i'm
ralphing run right into a CI go real
light with edibles to ten ten I don't
really feel it just it makes symptom
management significantly better that's
what I like about the Stratis
specifically but other stuff thirty
twenty five thirty milligrams is fun any
more than that and I'm like not fun in
public high still high I was still high
when I woke up my eyes I'm wearing my I
read genetics logo shirt and this red
print is dark dark red my eyes were that
red yeah that's where you brother enjoy
that you can see the bubbles isn't like
alka-seltzer kinda to you we're gonna
watch this happen I like to eat the
smallest physical like thing with the
highest milligram so like those oh it's
very similar this means the one gummies
that are 100 milligrams or that that's
me all day I don't want to eat a whole
bar and get a hundred milligrams I want
to eat a hundred milligrams real fast
I like the exact opposite thing about
the five milligram goings because I can
sit there and pop six of them and have
that is like I'm gonna get really
toasted dose and I actually get to like
chew and enjoy the edible most of my
gripe about edibles is they're delicious
but now they're the size of your like
thumb joint and you take one tiny little
brownie bite in like I'm a big guy when
I take a tiny bite of a brownie most of
the rest of my body that's not true
in that moment starts looking for more
that [ __ ] browning and when all of
the brownie has weed in it that can get
dangerous fast but yeah that's why I
like this is the lower dose stuff
because I can have a couple pieces and
enjoy because most of them are insanely
good now I've got a new idea for an
edible company let's sell let's just
copy our favorite edibles and we'll sell
those and then right alongside those
we'll sell the same thing without any
THC in it it's people have been joking
about it for a minute the first company
that does it well is gonna make it nice
just one company that did that already
that didn't have a lot of there's more
than one company that does a larger
piece they just don't do it in a
multipack successfully they need to make
like a dozen of cookies right and they
need to have one packaged in the front
of it and that one is a hundred
milligrams just slowly
only if everybody knows did you see
somebody the secret session did me an
edible and I passed it on and they
looked completely offended I was like
sorry I'm on a thing and they just look
like that's cool but I mean what the
[ __ ] why'd you give it away and so they
giving it back like oh no wait I forgot
sorry I'm not doing those drugs anymore
here you go I'll do it again
it's just I'm I'm just stubborn and it's
funny it's more of a joke to me now that
I haven't done eating any edible since
this time it's secret session when I ate
like twenty five hundred milligrams and
then I tried to go to work it's just
[ __ ] always eat too many edibles a
secret stash and I swear to God every
time we have the conversation like we're
not gonna
animals and I feel like the last two
times you followed through on that
obviously the last two times I have not
it was 9:30 at secret sesh and Bobo
blaster Co Chris bought me a cookie and
I was gonna bring this up I'm like
eating the cookie it's like 9:30 night I
have to open the shop the next day and
the guy was like I'm eating it he's like
yeah these cookies were like 300
milligrams that's what I've been telling
everybody he's like but realistically
they might be like I was like I'm three
for three thirds cooking I'm like I'm
gonna finish it now doesn't matter now
but like man I wish I would have known
that before I started eating X I would
have only eaten a quarter or one of the
things I like about the rec market over
the Med and there's not a lot on that
list but the the dosing and the lab
testing them to perfection it's coming
to the medical scene very it'll be there
in less than a year probably but I heard
November I was supposed to be July and
then they said November so we have to
built the labs yeah bringing creating
this from the ground up which is like
why we're joking about like different
models for edible companies if we're
really watching it happen in front of us
it's fun I had the honor of giving
Lindsey and her better half mr. Bobo
Blaster Co a ride home from the secret
session first of all that cookie killed
me second of all I swear
all right Jeff wanted to do a podcast on
the way home and I was totally down to
do a podcast and then we were all
smoking and I guess I had said I was
gonna wait to do a damn and I've said no
I don't want Chris thought I said that I
was gonna wait so apparently we're all
waiting for me to take it down I fell
asleep in the back of the car and then I
woke up and I was like all right I'm
gonna keep eating so that I will stay
awake and then Chris started trouble you
both started trolling me about how much
I was eating in the back of the cars is
like [ __ ] isn't going to sleep because
she wasn't asleep everyone yeah
we're talking to her and she's just
blank no answer and then she goes why
are you guys picking on me it's like
five minutes ago and she's not even
asleep then where is the torch and she's
like it's on the floor yeah I was
totally back there yeah I know but Chris
always makes fun of me for sleeping
everywhere so I always try to be like
I'm not asleep some people could just
sleep in the car
I'm not that person that's why I Drive
everywhere shout-out to Dabin granny for
coming to the secret session that was so
fun Dannan with dead she's got so much
enthusiasm she's you know oh man she
doesn't even I mean she's it's already
there she's just her she's got more
Instagram followers than all of us
combined literally she's going I think
the last time I check is like 156 and
[Music]
it's funny because I was listening to
the last podcast and she was like oh
yeah I just hit a hundred and fifty one
and I was like let gets it going alright
we've been go for uh just a little over
an hour you guys huh Jay just said
something that made me think about
something you want more people to follow
you on Instagram you can tell everybody
listening right now how they can stalk
you say it right into the top of the mic
[Music]
but I do have where can anybody stalk
you if they want to if they want to
check you out while they're listening to
your sexy voice they can go to
I don't have a Twitter yeah there you go
tell them about Twitter yes use the
hashtag tweet that Adam guys okay I'm at
chicken fish
ch f cken pH chicken fish I like it I
like it
chicken fish follow them on Twitter you
guys sent him some good stuff hashtag it
like it when he rambled tour this is
[Music]
that is a fish with the band fish or
just happen to have a pH yeah oh you're
a fish fan oh why didn't we just start
the podcast like that oh what's your
favorite show uh what year what era
I just stumped him 99 okay that's a good
that's a good run
yeah saw a bunch of 99 shows I mean that
really what was funny I've heard of them
and I knew that swimming around the fish
but you know back in cleaner back in the
90s I couldn't just go to a torrent site
and grab the whole catalog or some band
that I've heard of you know yeah yeah oh
so busy nowadays my friend won tickets
my friend won tickets to the fish show
the next day on the radio and I heard
him I actually heard it on the radio so
I went over we still have pay phones
back then so with this called him up and
said hey you're taking me to that one
song I know that song they didn't play
it by the way but I knew that once I was
prepared to sing along with them but
they didn't play if you go to see fish
do not expect to hear your favorite song
[Music]
now after I got into him I went see him
again in Charleston Virginia drove all
the way up there not Charleston
Charlottesville where the University of
Virginia is okay so I'm in there this is
ten years later you see what I'm saying
and I felt like the old guy there's
there was an older couple behind me but
somehow
older than neighbors and the one thing
my wife women went with me this time
shout-out to you baby Santana oh dear
but uh bring her next time I will I will
she wanted to come this time but she had
some things here to do that's life and
that's way it is but anyway I told her
about you know soon as I went to the one
edy winston-salem North Carolina the
first one as soon as the lights went out
joints lit up everywhere and I was like
sitting that's [ __ ] cheap and I said
yo man let me hit that me he gave me the
whole joint fire up another one nice 14
- so I kind of felt obligated you know I
was above age I wasn't 21 but I was 19
something like that another one sorry ad
me truck my money didn't smoke so he
would let me burn no weed but anyway I
come prepared the second time and I told
my wife I'm like soon as these lines go
out you about to see something see all
the joints fired up she's like oh yeah I
can dig this and you know seen all the
people dancing around I told her all
about that she tripped out I'd love to
go see them against out here the enemy
they'll be here this weekend I'm doing
my best do my best people say yes to
you're sold out yeah it's old the [ __ ]
yeah well if you got a lot of money
you're gonna have too much damn money
how much I like a8 package I mean you
know you're probably looking close to
200 bucks one night per person and
they're doing three nights he just put
his head down and defeat just here they
come once a year okay they come to
Colorado once a year they usually hit
Dix yeah it's where they're at this year
the giant soccer field bro they sell out
that giant soccer field three nights in
a row yeah never missed a Sunday show
that's my advice this podcast to come
out the Monday after so while you guys
are listening to this I'm probably
hanging out with Doug Benson I'm gonna
see Doug Benson Thursday I got the Jeff
Tate thing
Friday Saturday Sunday is fish at dicks
and then Monday Doug Benson at Comedy
Works so probably taking him out for you
right yeah Doug's my homie after the
show after the show [ __ ] him up one
time he called me out on stage he looked
at me he's like you got me - hi raasta
Jeff a little bit excuse my coughs also
sizzle Kalonji at
servantes September 19th that's gonna be
a fun one if you're a Rasta if you're
into that regular rattles getting
awesome it's just continuous now I've
never seen sizzle I'm pretty excited for
now I remember a time here when you had
a few good concerts at the beginning of
the summer and a few good concerts at
the end and that was it there was no
concerts during that not beginning her
end of summer if it wasn't those two
like three week sections of time there
wasn't anything going the dirty fish kid
in me used to just pack up the car and
go where the concerts were yeah but now
it's continuous here we've always got
something going on yeah you know I've
been to almost everything but the
Telluride Blues Fest bluegrass I've
never done that one yeah yeah that
little mountain stays busy yeah it was
an amazing time I would play the lottery
just to win an extra house in Telluride
and your coolest [ __ ] and you're tired
of it
my buddy Juicy J will trade you he's got
two packs of pre-rolls gram I'll throw
one gram a hash table everything on the
table you can have it the email can go
to if we get Juicy J spa up until your
ride so that he could get the [ __ ] out
five rooms until you send me an email
girl from your heart hotmail.com we'd
love to take your offers for free
housing until your ID
that'd be great they used to be very
much seasonal it's a good thing I think
people just give you a house you think
that'll work that's true that is true
there you go all right Lindsay it's time
for you to do your plugs tell all the
people that are still listening how they
can find you so my Instagram and my
periscope or the traveling stoner wow I
almost [ __ ] up so my Instagram my
periscope or the traveling stoner my
twitter is the travel stoner my snapchat
is traveling stoner without the G I
think it's everything actually I'm sorry
where do you go oh um well I actually
started out in Jersey and moved down to
Florida I'm out here in Colorado and I
kind of just like travel everywhere
Serena how many states have actually
been in yeah oh man I haven't like
actually done a count since I came out
and everything I'd have to do a recount
I'm smarter joint
in 48 states I've even snuck over into
Mexico but that's probably for a later
podcast you're gonna be back yeah and
but anyway I've smoked to join Mexico
snuck over in a limousine
so alleged alleged limousine can you say
snuck
it would going further would be a bad
legal choice Mike couldn't follow the
rules I don't want to get you in trouble
but on the other hand I really want to
hear the rest that story it's pretty
long story that'll be part two it gets
pretty vulgar at times I mean we can
handle this it later episode I love it
it's a whole other show okay it's I just
got jotted down so the odds of yep it's
gonna be a future episode sorry I was
loving your 65 um I do want to give a
big shout out though to like in the past
couple of weeks I've been on the podcast
a lot these past couple months actually
um thank you for that and I have had a
lot of people message me about the
podcast and say you know great podcast
you know listen to it this morning loved
it like the day it drops like by 7:00
a.m. there's usually one person that has
messaged me and said already listened to
it it sounds great so I just want to
give a big shout out to everybody that
has been listening and messaging me to
say that the podcast has been great
that's awesome Thank You Linds for
supporting the show since you and Granny
and Brett have been on the show
frequently the listens have gone up my
Instagram and Twitter followers have
gone up on all of the accounts the rasta
Jeff the IRA genetics and the jf YH
account so thanks for participating your
social media skills are [ __ ] awesome
so yeah you're killing it there thanks
to all those people that message Lindsey
and don't message me for some reason big
thanks to all you guys for listening to
the show and participating with lens
that's really cool I get so many
messages just keep messaging her that's
cool and I only huge showed it to that
one mountain girl
I she's messages me and tells me how
great the episode is before I wake up
yeah that's awesome yeah almost every
Monday morning it's like getting ready
and it's like the girl from the heart
you can hear it in the back in the back
she'll be taking her morning dabs or on
her morning hike or whatever yeah love
you girl it's on snapchat
her name's that one mountain girl think
her snapchat is Mountain smokes it is
that's why I couldn't find her today yes
and her Instagram is that one mountain
girl but shout-out to you girl I hope
you're doing good in Washington yes I
love it shout-out thanks for supporting
the show yeah everybody if you're
listening to the show we've been going
for an hour and 18 minutes that means
with the intro I put on this we're
probably about an hour and 20 minutes
ish and I love all the people that
listen this far we really appreciate it
thanks for hanging out at the table with
us it feels like you're here I put these
light bulbs in the chandelier and it's
like a whole new place it's amazing it
woke up the conversation it made
everybody a little more talking about
this is a great show yeah yeah I want to
figure buddy for listening I want to
thank Mike for coming taking time away
from his dinner his wife and his baby
and his band thanks for coming and
hanging out you CJ thanks for joining us
on the podcast was this your first
podcast ever yeah this is gonna be a
regular thing bro cause you got good
stories you got a good vibe you're gonna
be here often taking down with us next
time kind of a local celebrity here
[Music]
thanks again for coming I appreciate the
support shout out to uh to bubble
blaster Co for I'll let you hang out
with me all the time and huge shout out
to Jo buzzy I don't know if you listen
to the podcast on a regular basis but
you've taken off you've taken new
ventures in life and I wish you nothing
but the best on your new endeavors but I
hope that works for you you guys we're
gonna wrap up this portion of the show
shot of the people that are in the room
that don't have microphones I've just
been hanging out smoking blunts with us
and taking dad's I'm gonna wrap up this
portion of the show and of course I'll
be right back to put a tail on this
fishy did I really just say put a tail
on this fish that was [ __ ] weird you
guys thanks for listening to the podcast
I truly appreciate all of the support
you guys if you have a product you'd
like to review or if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast send me an email
it's a girl from me
are at hotmail.com I would love to hear
from you want to thank everybody for
joining me big shout out to Mike big
shot at the Juicy J big shout out to
Lindsey thanks everybody that was in the
room smoking blunts and having a good
time with those people are taking dads
and smoking blunts off Mike it's kind of
fun having extra people in the room kept
it a little chaotic kept things moving
I'm gonna get off microphone quit
talking it's been like an hour and 20
minute podcast so catch me in about
seven days and until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
see
[Music]
I'm thinking time to leave
to
[Music]
[Applause]
for the time
[Music]
[Applause]
leaning on me
[Music]
[Applause]
you