[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 153 of the
growth from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation your new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew
ladies and gentlemen this episode i'm
joined by white mike and we talked a lot
about CBD the episode was kinda long so
i'm not gonna waste a lot of time imma
let the music play and when we get back
Mike and I will be at the dab table hang
out with this I just now did so you
seriously are gonna cough that was all I
got oh there it is all right I'm
coughing - don't worry we're good I just
got a pretty funny text message now they
may hear the air conditioner in the back
just cause of what I got set up
BAM that's a good man and I think we got
there me too I'm trying out scoff from
the microphone again everything set up
here I think we are ready to do a
podcast ladies and gentlemen we're just
gonna go from here seat backs and tray
tables folks in the upright position
nobody's in in any upright position here
we no no kick it back and drop that tray
it's funny [ __ ] work tools out if you're
listening working just move on what I
wanted to talk about first is everyone's
talking about this honey bee thing on
Facebook people are claiming that this
dude in France is has trained his honey
bees to make THC Laden honey by
collecting THC from cannabis plants now
I'm not a bee expert but I don't think
that's how this works
i I'm here to say that I don't think
that this is real I think it's [ __ ]
to tell you the truth I when I first saw
it online I was like oh that's really
cool I want to wait bees collect pollen
yes trichomes collect pollen yes they
are not themselves blowing the pistils
collect the pollen to be more to be more
accurate but the
and is actually used as a defense
against insects and they do show
pictures of bees on the canopy on the
female cannabis plants and what somebody
says in one of these debunking websites
because I did do research before I came
on long checked it out on a podcast and
said that it was [ __ ] I did do some
research to back myself up they claimed
that they just simply sprayed sugar
water on the budding female plants to
encourage those bees to land there yes
maybe a little bit of THC as a marketing
ploy for homeys honey I think so yeah so
in his video they do show male plants
yeah so what I think may be happening
and I'm gonna back up a little bit this
guy says he's getting THC honey from
cannabis plant he can be doing that he
maybe that's totally a thing it's just
not gonna be psychoactive right he may
be getting pollen from male cannabis
plants those bees are gathering that
pollen they're flying back to their hive
they're putting that pollen and little
thing that they put it in a little
honeycomb and then they actually bees
actually chew up the pollen in their
mouths and they regurgitate it and
something in their regurgitation creates
the the nectar to turn into honey so
this is why I don't like knowing how
everything's made yes
nature's [ __ ] gross I really like
honey now I'm gonna have to try to not
think about the fact that it's bee vomit
yeah it's straight up bee puke so bees
your pukes pretty tasty yeah and it's
got some really cool medicinal effects
it's way better than mine bro so they're
[Music]
side note side note totally random side
note Jelly Belly has created some new
flavors and one of their new flavors is
vomit yeah right who wants it vomit
flavored jelly Belly that's not funny
so these for these flies these bees are
gluing and they're collecting they could
be collecting the male pollen from these
male plants and flying back and creating
honey out of that that is very feasible
do I do not see how they could land on a
female cannabis plant with trichomes on
it and gather trichomes and fly enough
trichomes back to the hive to make
cannabis honey that doesn't seem
feasible to me well I don't see them
purposefully gathering the Tritons
either so any sort of Trico gathering
it's gonna be incidental or accidental
yeah completely and I think that it's
private you ever been trimming and rub
your eye super yet
it burns we spent like the first half
hour at a new trim gig warning the dude
the new people not to do that right and
somebody will do it somebody's brother
time it happens it's a the plant gives
off pheromones sometimes people have
allergy style reactions to it and
sometimes your face gets at you and your
chairman that's just a thing and so you
rub your eye and it burns you only make
that mistake once it's like getting
maced and it sucks oh you can't make it
quit because your fingers are sticky cuz
you're trimming so you got to deal with
it I think that the pH was far too hot
for these bees to be able to handle and
I think it would burn the bees I think
they would just be like nah [ __ ] this I
don't want anything to do with it see I
don't know if it would be too acidic or
to like burn them but I think that this
thickness of the tackiness would annoy
the [ __ ] that's definitely part of what
the trichome is designed to do it's too
partially to keep those bugs away from
there so you could see this totally bit
like this there may be serious benefits
to bees collecting male cannabis pollen
and turning that into honey but it's
definitely not like weed honey is as
advertised right it's a very cool
marketing ploy it is a very cool video
but I think it is inaccurate I think
it's misleading and I don't think you're
getting THC honey i I want to see this
happen you know what I mean I want it to
be somebody said earlier they ain't
gonna do it on the honor system I want
to watch them make this honey and then I
want to watch the bees do their thing
and I want to take that honey to a lab
and let's deep he'll test that honey for
me and see what type of cannabinoids are
in there well that's what I was thinking
when we were kind of talking about this
before the show is for that to happen we
would have to bring this little homie to
Colorado with his bees and his cannabis
plants because that's the only place on
the planet where we could really collect
and lab test that in a controlled way
without him going to jail immediately
after I think you can do it in Spain man
he's in France so he's just a boarder
jump boy I think spins grow home girl I
haven't looked at it from anything Spain
cares because they have spannabis and
there's a hillside in Spain I forget the
name of the place I feel bad that I
can't remember the name of the region
but there's a small region in Spain
where they do not care about cannabis
growing there a lot of people go there
they might have the ability to grow but
do they have the access to the same test
and kind of slabs that we do that's a
very good question because both in the
same area are one of the things that
make Colorado's cannabis market so
awesome dude come to Colorado bring your
bees bring your bring your gear we'll do
what we got to do we want to see this
happen we want to test your bees you've
heard honey do did on a mildly related
note the dude in Oregon that's doing the
Hogs no yeah you know how here the waste
from the cannabis grow you have to do
specific stuff with it so it doesn't end
up right
teenagers hands or whatever we ground up
into little tiny pieces run through a
wood chipper and then mixed with other
product right a shop up in Oregon
found a hog farmer to take care of a
farm perfect and so they take all that
plant material and I I'm not exactly
sure what he what the farmer does to it
between picking it up from the shop and
dropping it off with the pigs but I'm
assuming it's not much and they chat out
on that as a primary food source for
most of that life
that's the Rocky Mountain worm company
in Colorado Springs has a deal worked
out with the very well-known vape pen
company open they grow their products in
their warehouse they chopped down their
plants and the waste from their plants
is then it's mixed properly so that it's
meed compliant and the media's approve
this transaction they send all of the
waste to the Rocky Mountain worm company
and the Rocky Mountain worm companies
feeding that back to their worms and the
worms compost that and then the Rocky
Mountain worm company in turn sells
their worm castings at a discount back
to open vapes groves brew and it goes
full circle yeah so it's getting reused
and reef ed back to the worms it's kind
of keeping it a little more eco-friendly
we need to learn as growers as
professional responsible growers it is
time to figure out how to reduce our
carbon footprint I don't know how to do
that very well well a lot of the places
the the laws around cannabis make that
specific topic incredibly brutal right
in Boulder I think they have to run
solar to offset all of their electricity
or something passed a law and Boulder
saying 104 you marijuana businesses had
to be a hundred percent energy neutral
which means they can't consume any power
they don't generate and immediately
after passing that law they real
how unenforceable and I are not
unenforceable but unfeasible it was to
require that immediately and so they've
been given some time to upgrade but it's
one of the things that made puebla so
popular is that we allow green house
denver does not agree now this boulder
does not allow the green house and we
have the prime green house area here his
perfect green house country to beautiful
country here to grow cannabis or hemp
yep we designated a whole bunch of water
it just kind of set it aside for you
know that's all will lease to marijuana
grows at the beginning of this we've
barely touched that number cool so
there's a ton of that still kind of in
reserve even with the industry as big as
it is down here that's one of the
hardest things to do is to get the water
rights once you get something set up you
think is a water a lawyer there was
something nobody thought of until about
a year and a half two years ago when we
finally finished the rules and regs
process
you can't just hammer out a well and go
to town down here in southern colorado
we've got a lot of rules when it comes
to water here yeah well they know they
know that big commercial growers are
coming and trying to use up the water
and they want to keep it for you and i
had a drink
which was yeah you know they've got a
good water plan down here so all that's
taken care of the it's one of the more
recent anti pot talking points is how
much water the plant drinks or how much
energy growing an indoor cost is like
well you know if you didn't prohibit it
in 46 of the 50 states more of it would
be grown under the sun will be using
significantly less power to produce all
this if we could just grow it outdoors
like a normal crab but oh no
when do we vote on the city elections
for 200 and 300 and the presidential
okay november november november 8 we
will put out a podcast i'm making a note
yeah we'll do an election podcast at
some point people this is not that
episode we need to guide people on what
to vote on locally specifically do that
in a whole nother show we'll do a little
segment on it just for them what's the
date today is today the 9th today may be
the 9th okay so yesterday was the last
day for people to submit ballot issue
paperwork so the final election ballots
they're all hammering out that paperwork
now so we'll have all the final
information for november you know we
could do so that's perfect
perfect
we'll do an episode to teach you guys
locally what to vote for because the
wording is confusing I do agree with
that there's gonna be it's more way more
than one question it's not just via
yes-or-no vote yes for we vote no
against wheat it's gonna be much more
complicated than that yeah all right so
this episode I want to put this back on
some some educational topics
yes back on some rails Mike's had a
headache he's really his color came back
he's more relaxed I can see that the
headache has kind of gone away a little
bit you feeling better bro I'm feeling a
lot better where's the proper container
because I got three of them to look
alike the product I'm consuming right
now is three percent THC 1.3 percent CBD
38 point nine nine percent CBD a and six
there thirty six point three two percent
THC a and an additional six percent CBG
so this has got a a bizarrely wide range
of cannabinoids in it and really get on
headaches other things pain inflammation
as well
what kind of hash would you call that
what kind of um it depends what
temperature it is it's intended as a
shatter at about 65 degrees it's a
pretty nice shatter it shatters real
nice it's 70 it's really sticky taffy
okay you take two pieces you pull it
apart it just kind of stretches I want
you to try to get it out of there it can
be a little tricky to get a dab out of
there it it above like 65 so what he's
talking about is a smokeable concentrate
it's some hash some chatter with a
pretty good CBD to THC ratio yeah it's
about 50/50 you could tell Mike was
hurtin about 20 minutes ago he had a
pretty good headache and he told me that
I put on his headphones like all right
dude let's record a podcast so the CBD
definitely reduced of the pain and your
headache and it improved your attitude
because of that oh yeah I feel a hundred
percent better now that I've put
something that's half and half THC CBD
into my system for the day my knees feel
better my neck the tension in my neck
feels better
I had a wicked headache when I got here
folks that was uh we're sitting at the
table kind of catching up and dabbing
and I'm basically just staring at
we'll rub in my eyes and my temples cuz
it hurts so bad I'm thinking I might not
podcast tonight I might just have to
bail after a day or two and go home so
I'm hurtin and the addition to some CBD
into my world has reset that completely
I've been a big fan of CBD for a long
time it's good for what ails you I'll
put it that way that's the truth
one thing that I and I've said on the
show I'm not a huge smoker of CBD I
don't use a lot of CBD product when I
smoke I prefer a nice THC Head buzz I
want to get high I want to make my head
spin
I want to get confused I want to get
goofy only a talkative that's what a
good sativa does to me when I smoke too
much CBD I honestly just get lazy and it
kind of ruins my high ah yeah I'm not
stoned right now and that's I took four
not all THC dabs here a minute ago
and I had a nice little buzz going on
but right before the show I didn't want
my headache to come back so I took two
more half and a half THC CBD dabs and it
it brought me my high back down I liked
it - nice jack if you want to dab of
that feel free to reach in I'm gonna
pull this piece off right here for
myself but here's some shader piece it's
like six of my dabs it looks like a flag
there's a model train that dad would be
American flags there you go perfect yes
it would it's probably about 0.3 ish I
don't know so I I don't use a lot of CBD
products but one time listeners of this
podcast don't know uh over a year ago in
April of 2015 you Lube incident with no
when I hit my head and I was having
issues my head hurt for three weeks
like honestly my head was throbbing I
was [ __ ] up I had a traumatic but I
have a traumatic brain injury I still
have post concussion syndrome I have a
lot of it's been over 18 months and I
still have effects from that concussion
I knocked myself clean the [ __ ] out I
was out for a good 30 to 45 seconds like
unconscious on the ground people had to
pick me up get me going again
it [ __ ] me up my head hurt for several
days I could not get right when I took a
DAB oh you weren't yourself for six
weeks after yeah no I was myself for six
months after it felt like there was a
substantial improvement after about six
weeks but yeah I mean it took half a
year before you were feeling like
yourself all the way in
yeah but so Spencer would invite me over
just to check on me
he'd be like bro come hang out come Kiki
you've been like you could tell I was
getting depressed cuz when you hit your
head in have a traumatic brain injury
you get depressed in chickies you're not
the same that you used to be my skills
weren't where they were and I was bummed
out yeah
so my friends really hanging out trying
to help me out it's all my friends it
helped me through that head injury but
Spence would invite me over and one
night he's like bro I made some CBD hash
oil for the cannabis cup and this should
actually won the best CBD concentrate at
the High Times Cannabis got liver
wonderful but he gave me a big fat dog
hit this because when I would smoke
normal shatter like THC or sativas my
head would throb even more it would just
feel like and I can feel it and it felt
like I had it felt like I had a belt
around my head or like my hat was way
too tight is what it felt like all day
every day for a couple for like weeks
and Spence gives me these CBD dabs
and I breathed in with the dab and I
blew out that dab and it felt like you
just undid that bail about one notch you
didn't like fix it but it totally undid
that bail a notch and Maddy and Spence
looked at me and they go wow did that
help and I was like yeah how could you
tell I'm like you sat up your neck went
straight again and I was like what do
you mean I like even like slouch and
weird and you've been like crooked I was
like well let me get another dad like
that and after like three or four of
those CBD dabs I was like I haven't felt
this good since before I hit my head
like it really did something to me it
fixed and so they gave me some of that
stuff and like dad this like damn it
everyday it is gummy it really did help
I found a good half THC half CBD mix
about oh maybe two years ago and it was
really hard to come by back then but
I've got a lot of inflammation in like
my knees and my neck where it's just for
one stupid medical reason or another
the bones grind on each other firm and
the tissue gets swollen
we're both overs you're like six four
right yep I'm six five you probably
weigh good to 30 I'm guessing I'm not
good at goodbyes that reaction I'm right
about 200 pounds most of the time these
knees bro God our knees get there's so
much leverage sizes legs how many times
have you stood up into like a heating
duct
oh yeah and just cramped you're next
when I busted my head I really jerked my
neck back completely so that retinol and
I've been in car accidents I grew up in
Colorado there's a lot of fun stuff here
that you can tumble down cartwheels with
skis on releasing on my feet was one of
the really fun ones that led to no
cartilage in either knee icicles as a
kid in California but though the end
results all this trauma over the years
of having fun in Colorado is that
there's a lot of inflammation and a lot
of swelling into places that press on
nerves and then that causes phantom
nerve pain are basically the same stuff
amputees get with like they lose a
finger and then the finger tingles or
hurts those nerves create or or make up
or feel that they're getting signals
they're not really getting and it can
feel like it's tingling or tickling or
it can feel like it's on fire or stuck
in a car door or it'll go numb and when
I first stumbled on medical marijuana
that was one of the things I liked is it
would help me ignore that sensation but
it wasn't until I found something that
was a good ratio with THC CBD that I
really started to attack that
inflammation and bring it down to a
point where it doesn't hurt anymore like
it's hard to explain to somebody when
you're at work and they're like why are
you rubbing your hand and it's like well
because the the three small fingers are
numb and my thumb and my index finger
feel like they're stuck in a car door
and it was like that when I woke up and
I can't make it go away but like which
Jackie did you want to try on it's just
one of those things that sucks that you
just have to deal with until I
found something with there really help
that inflammation I was just taking
random pills that the doctor gave me and
going to the chiropractor and the pills
didn't do a [ __ ] thing other than
mess with my stomach in my liver but the
chiropractor was helping some but when I
found something that's half THC half CBD
that inflammation really started to calm
down and I started having lower pain
days lower crazy sensation days and then
slowly but surely I started getting
pain-free days and do those first couple
pain-free days were the dude I was
looking was a teenager yeah like it
never happened
yes your endocannabinoid system back in
line and now that the rec industry has
progressed where it is there are several
places in town where I can go in and
pick up half THC F CBD concentrates and
like when I get home from a end of a
long day my knees are swollen a little
bit my feet hurt my back hurts I've
eaten enough bulls to ship for the day
and I'm in kind of a foul mood two or
three dabs of that will have me feeling
like none of that happened physically
and it's just a wonder again for the day
now CBD for the win yeah CBD ramble no I
love it that's right that's why I
brought to Doug who's been on the
episode before - I saw Doug today shout
out the Doug Doug it looks great it's
good to see you doing well um CBD has
changed his life a hundred percent right
yes medical marijuana has saved Doug's
life for sure I don't know if I honestly
I and it's it's hard to think that stuff
like this right now because we've lost a
lot of people this year but I don't know
if Doug could still be here without
medical marijuana you know mentally
spiritually and physically Doug would
not be the same person without medical
marijuana I mean III saw some of the
same stuff I was going through in his
world like I mean listeners if you don't
have a lot of pet like physical pain in
your life or if you've never really been
injured for a while it's kind of hard to
understand what people who do have nerve
damage and pain like that go through and
it's the best way I can describe it is
it's like a sound and it gets louder and
louder and louder and it gets louder
the world around you gets smaller and
that sound presses in on the world and
there are some days where there's
nothing but that sound like it's just
pain it doesn't matter that if you don't
pick up the phone you're not gonna have
a job later it doesn't matter that
you've got to go to the bathroom it
doesn't matter that you had something
really important to do that day that you
have to get up and go do now for or it's
you know you're gonna lose it forever it
doesn't matter all there is is the pain
and you'll do anything to get away from
it or make it stop for a while you'll
give people of ridiculous sums of money
because they claim to have a treatment
that works and for the most part nothing
helps
like I was wearing a thing that
electrocuted me slowly like a TENS unit
and it works okay for some issues but
for mine it was literally just an
electrical shock that scrambled the pain
and pulse on the way to my brain dam
like that was the best that Western
science had for me and then one day I
hit some high CBD hash and about half an
hour later I was like wait a second
nothing hurts I'm and I kind of drum my
both my hands on the table and I was
like and I can feel all my fingers and
none of them hurt like what is that
where did that come from where'd that
guy with that vial of station but yeah
it's CBD is absolutely wonderful
and a lot of people are starting to
figure it out so much so that there's a
lot of scam and fake [ __ ] around yeah
unfortunately that Chinese imported CBD
[ __ ] it's not you're not buying stuff
with a lab test on it from a very
accredited retailer you don't know what
you're getting I'm I'm sorry to inform
you yeah unfortunately it's there's a
lot of research going on in to CBD right
now hopefully in the next ten years we
know a lot more about its medical
applications but I can vouch for its
ability to calm a headache and lower
inflammation and swelling in your nerves
or around your nerves and your joints so
that those pain signals aren't just
ability produces vomiting and nausea for
sure I smoked some CBD it'll take that
away
it suppresses seizures that's something
we've talked about on the podcast before
it'll make you not have convulsions and
seizures hopefully that's like the most
part of everyone but it's there's
several different forms of epilepsy
right that THC work on and that CBD work
on and then that the two together work
on that's a good all that sexy - oh yeah
it'll stop here it doesn't stop it will
slow down your PTSD and your nightmares
and your thoughts if you have PTSD I
always sleep amazingly well when I've
been consumed yes I hopes with anxiety
oh it's an anti-inflammatory we talked
about that it's an anti antioxidant it
helps with degenerative disorders which
is pretty cool it's act as a protective
hand side tumor it'll it'll and will not
destroy your tumors I think you need THC
to destroy it - there's slow a tumor for
sure um there's a lot of very very very
recent cancer research on THC and CBD
and CBD slows tumor growth majorly is
what they're seeing in mice trials which
is huge if if we can slow tumor growth
that gives us a better chance to fight
it yes yeah the good news to that corner
or that equation is that THC has been
shown to kill it um which is kinda the
you know the the first real medical
research into Rick Simpson oil style
products that would be it concentrates
of both that's why those are so
effective and I'm a little bit baked
from that last tiny dab I'm gonna take
it down ramble on but as the medical
research that we're starting to get I
mean it really isn't it symphonies its
bitsy folks I'm not saying that if you
have cancer and you find some of this
you can cure yourself real easy that's
not what what I'm saying here but um the
research is promising and honestly in
our lifetimes we might see legitimate
packaged perfectly dosed you've got this
kind of cancer we're gonna start you on
this much THC this much CBD style try
it's exactly in our lifetime which would
be oh that would make me so happy
did you smell that Dad that I just took
little bit oh that smells it tastes so
good I tasted in a minute ago that's the
Tirpitz pineapple jacket yeah the nug
run chatter that was delicious
yeah man another thing I wanted to
mention that CBD does it's an
antidepressant which you know I think it
it's got its own antidepressant
properties but also if a dude's not
hurting every day that's gonna work as
an antidepressant if you're not having
PTSD symptoms and panic attacks you're
gonna be less depressed
I mean honestly most days when I wake up
and I'm not hurt and it feels like my
birthday
still cuz they're pretty rare most days
I wake up at least a little stiff a
little sore something somewhere screwed
you're only getting older I now write
well though when I was a teenager I had
more than one doctor go if you don't
knock this [ __ ] off it's gonna hurt when
you're thirty yeah and I was like shut
up put a cast on it yeah but I got [ __ ]
to do you gotta go where my roller
blades go cuz I got like I was a
teenager in Colorado in the 90s we were
still free to like ride our bikes off
roofs and stuff remember like before
everything was nerfed yeah we didn't get
trophies when our team didn't win in the
future it was the last generation that
really got that yeah we're the same age
I was right there with you but I
remember more than one doctor notice
gonna hurt when you're thirty if they
were all right it does but the days that
are paying free most of those I can
accredit to last night I was I was
hurting a little I knew I was hurt and
so I consumed a whole lot of THC CBD
concentrate instead with my normal mix
of predominantly THC flower and shatter
and I wake up feeling a lot better
really restful sleep and really really
nice work on the inflammation while I
sleep one thing we should totally
mentioned is CBD buyers by itself will
not get you high no you can consume a
lot of CBD and you may get a little grin
but I don't think you're gonna get like
any psychedelic psychoactive effect it's
not a high the the mood improvement is
like you were saying when the pain goes
away your mood goes up a thousand times
like it I mean if you don't know what
I'm talking about
think about getting a bee sting when you
get that stinger pulled out or a
splinter pulled out or you've got a big
painful zit that finally pops like in
that relief of pressure imagine that
like through your whole arm like if your
whole arm felt like it was on fire and
then one moment it stopped feeling like
that it just felt like your arm again
the sensation is incredible when we
finally get there you know how well it's
working another thing that we can talk
about is CBD will reduce the effects of
THC so if you're a little too high if
you've had too many dads if you're new
and you take a big giant dab a THC and
you're just spinning you're [ __ ] up
you take a little dab of CBD in it will
calm you down a little bit it'll balance
out your high there's some company that
made a product they work on rescue pills
it was just the CBD capsule CBD filled
gel cap that's pretty cool um so yeah if
your buddy took too many dabs and
they're freaking out a little bit just
hand them this and it's good you know
good mug for half an hour wait for this
to kick in some Doritos and you'd be
just fine a friend of mine makes for a
relative he's a carrier before he makes
CBD capsules and he does something to
the oil to make it a little more
bioavailable and I was taking those at
night for a while I had a few and oh
good lord that I feel wonderful thanks
dad I'm just pain-free and and just in a
really really nice mood it was really
nice there are a couple of companies
that are making CBD dog treats which i
think is really cool because a lot of
the Shepherd breeds are known for their
dysplasia and hip problems there's a
shepherd dog that stayed at my house for
a little while now and he gets some CBD
treats occasionally and he seems to be a
happy little dog doesn't seem to cause
him any problems and it's gonna keep him
pain-free keep his little hips happy
I've got a Malamute that's pushing for
thirteen and a half now she's almost 14
breed expect life expectancy is eight
and so her knees hurt her ankles I've
basically every joint is shot and you
can see when she doesn't want to go up
and down the stairs I've been adding a
little THC CBD teen sugar food
in the days that I added she's five
years younger nice you can see it
helping with the pain and inflammation
uh it takes about twenty minutes half an
hour to kick in for her then you can see
the change overnight yeah I had five or
six customers come in looking for
something for their dogs before I
thought to try it and yeah I'm glad I
did there are companies that are making
specific edibles for dogs now there are
things available at hem stores that have
CBD for your dog that are made in
America with actual hemp products there
I can't say there's anything wrong with
that as long as it's made with real real
hemp or real cannabis you're basically
in a brick and mortar retailer in the
United States it has to at least contain
what the label says um recently the the
DEA just sent out a thing to a bunch of
CBD only companies and the internet kind
of freaked out was like oh they're just
attacking weed like they always do it it
was they were targeting the people that
are selling like cod fish oil and
calling it CBD oil because people don't
know any better and you can't take this
stuff to lab and get it tested as a
civilian but yeah you're just getting
scammed out of money on the internet so
be careful if you're ordering online
folks with this the if you've got a
number of different ailments
you should get online and check out to
see if there's any research on what THC
and CBD can do for those for your
specific ailment yeah and then check out
the laws in your state and see if and
where you can get this stuff and if you
have to come take a vacation in Colorado
I see a lot of the people doing exactly
that they come they visit at one of our
rec stores and a good rec store will
have a decent selection of CBD products
at this point they might not have a huge
selection or a wide selection but I
should have some you can go to more than
one store whatever here so you'll find
several to check out weed maps you can
check out Leafly there are menus
available to see what you want
unfortunately on the mobile apps they
cannot show you pricing anymore did they
take that off the mobile yeah all the
pricing has gone on all the mobile apps
but you can still find them on the web
if you use your computer it's uh weed
maps calm and Leafly le AF ly if you're
coming to Colorado I think those are
effective in all the marijuana states
yeah
pretty much nationwide now yeah so if
you want to search for locations of your
favorite favorite strains or products or
topicals or whatever you're looking for
go to those websites and you can find
information on the products you're
looking for and you can find specific
locations that have them don't get mad
at me if a dispensary does not update
their weed maps menu sometimes these
about to say is like weed maps and
Leafly are great places to start your
search but if you're looking for a very
specific product or even kind of a
general product you're looking for
something with a certain ratio of
cannabinoids some THC some CBD something
like that
check out weed Maps relief lis make a
list of possible shops and then go ahead
and give them a call and just real quick
ask them hey what's your your selection
of blah yeah what do you have in for CBD
options right now yeah black pigpens
yeah but like be specific in what you're
looking for as much as you can and then
narrow your list that way because I mean
the industry is weird right now and you
never know when somebody's gonna walk in
and say give me all of that so what's on
their menu might not have anything to do
with what's on their store shelf and
brightest moment it might just be stuff
that's been on the store shelf in the
last 30 days I was shopping at green and
healthy the other day and I was
frustrated because I wanted I bought
something and the guy behind me was
frustrated because I had purchased all
of it and he said I want that and she
had to say it's gone and he said why is
it on the list and she's like he just
bought all of it sorry so that's how
quickly she could sell out I bought her
notes and I cleaned him out I took the
bottom of that I watched a dude buy a
hundred and sixty things of hard candies
once I'm Jesus um and it was just like
okay let me get you a box and sweep all
of these into the box and like for the
new the rest of the week we had to tell
people sorry we're out of that
particular product line and there were
likes there's something wrong with it
it's like no it was something amazing
with it apparently honestly every every
month I've worked in a dispensary that's
happened with at least one product line
once I mean sometimes it's only the last
eight or ten or twenty units or whatever
but it happens I used to go to you went
with me we went to the clinic in Denver
and they had Durbin poison wax yep
and they had vortex wax I
loved from the clinic on Mexico in
Denver it's still open they don't have
these products anymore they've changed
their game but they used to have this
looks three two half years ago the
vortex tasted like cranberries and dirty
feet and rotten fruit I don't know why
you liked that feet smell oh man I just
love that in my weed but the high that
he gave me I couldn't focus on anything
it made my eyes jump around like I was
on a bumpy road like it was really crazy
and that durbin poison just I love the
flavor of good urban poison wax and that
head-high is just so amazing so back in
the day we'd go to the clinic and I
would save up as much money as I could
afford to save up and I'd walk in there
and I'd say how much did that Durbin
poison do you have and they'd say
there's about 14 grams and I'd say I'll
take it and then I'd say how much of
that vortex do you have and they'd
usually have somewhere between 14 and 28
grams I would buy it I would clean it
out the guy behind me would be like oh
yeah he brought a lot of that I want
something they be like sorry he bought
all of it yeah I did it the other day
with those delicious truffles I they cut
me off eventually I was smoking it
should I love it I was two and a half
hours away from my house at the time I
had to go stock up I got the last four
boxes of coda and I watched the lady
behind me coming and go but yes so
forgive a shop if they don't have
something that they did have advertised
on there we maps menu but yeah a good
shops gonna keep that mostly updated but
you're gonna want to call and
double-check yeah something a pro tip I
don't a pro tip ever but if you want to
sound like you know what you're talking
about
don't say CBDs say CBD yeah its cat boy
dog are the initials there's not an
apostrophe s you don't see th seize this
strain has a lot of th C's in it you say
this strain has a lot of THC why would
you say this like Sanjay Gupta [ __ ] that
up on this weed special I didn't catch
that no it wasn't him that started it
but like it's a common mispronunciation
or herb yeah mispronunciation yeah just
CBD you guys there you wouldn't say I
want a glass of water you just say I
want a glass of water and you know that
there's a lot of water in there there's
a measurement with that contains a
specific amount of water and you're
looking for CBD CBD
because it's not a group of things it is
it's just one thing it's it's CBB and
you don't you don't see CH C's no and
you don't take corns I want some corns
you say old some corn they don't eat
cereals you eat cereal no it's one of
those things we their here they like sad
of an indigo that just cringe we're
gonna do an episode in the future about
sativa and indica and the differences
and the benefits and balances and the
growing styles everything of each so
we'll talk about set of sattva and
Indigo's sativa and indica and phenotype
phe note4
type while we're on it string so oh my
gosh you want to do that Saahil arias
post the other day social media that was
like I love all those ninety percent THC
strands out there oh man I I just about
died laughing yeah that's my boy Cooper
Watts he made a short educational video
on the difference between strain and
strand strands are ropes or fibers
strains are different varieties of
cannabis if you want to be technical you
can call it a varietal or a cultivar but
let's let's go with strain instead of
strand as a start you guys it's a try
comb and not try Chrome was a good
Segway speaking of battle I wanted to
talk about Nate Diaz from the UFC and
you go there you go Real American Hero
yeah I'm not gonna talk about my opinion
of the fight that doesn't matter but
those dudes through the [ __ ] down to the
end it was a it was a it was a decision
it ended with them both standing so they
beat the [ __ ] out of each other food
eleven minutes walk out of each yeah
from the the I didn't see the fight but
I did see the press conference we're
about to talk about it holy [ __ ] he
looked like a side of beef getting ready
to hit yeah yeah he got punched in the
face a lot of times Conor McGregor's got
some punches so one thing I want to talk
about when they're interviewing him dude
just Street pulls out the vape pen and
starts taking vape pen rips and one of
the report the video here lashes play
this video it's only a couple of seconds
long here to play this video and then
we'll talk for a couple of seconds and
we'll wrap up this podcast but he pulls
out just so you guys know if you haven't
seen the video it's uh your standard
concentrate vape at I've got a million
different versions of this on a store
shelf I work at I'm gonna bring the
volume up slowly so it's right back here
[Music]
are you just for the record smoking this
is true it's true the truth company it's
a CBD it helps with a healing process
and inflammation stuff like that so you
wanted to get these four before after
fire training and make your life a
better place and then one last one C BP
oil if you don't know what that is a big
part of this story to hear that the key
right there make your life a better
place that's what he's beautiful man I
didn't realize I've watched this video
several times he [ __ ] up where he said
it's good to use before and after the
fight he shouldn't I said before the
fight [ __ ] up right there buddy but
still well there there's he might be an
atomic trouble for doing that yeah
that's that's what I wanted to talk
about him glad you said that it's uh the
specific rules bar cannabis consumption
period until six hours after the fight
is what I was reading in random press
coverage of this I like I don't follow
the sport it makes sense in all of their
rules
if you catch that from my intro to this
story is that you Sado rules or is that
rules from the local governing sporting
agency those rules with an s rules
whose rules they are but MMA fighters
can't use any sort of cannabis product
until or any sort of banned substance
which marijuana or cannabis products
would be on the list until six hours
after the fight I'm pretty sure I
already know your answer here but do you
think a dude that just spent twenty five
minutes of
getting kicked in the dick and punched
in the face should be allowed to take a
couple of rips off a CBD vape pen at the
end of the night almost the most
assuredly I'd offer him a DES dab of
this wonderful half an out all this
grand that's left over if he wanted
money after being like that anything
that's gonna help you recover faster and
you with that level of trauma is
encouraged by me he says it reduces
inflammation and swelling and that dude
that his face looked like a
jack-o'-lantern
it did and honestly I incur a plot his
use of anything other than heavy
narcotics is what these guys are usually
isn't that what they usually throw at
him you know I don't I don't know what
they do to deal with the pain at the end
of that but I did make a joke he said
I'm going to a party and Conor McGregor
is going to the hospital I don't know
how accurate that was because he get his
face punched in I I can't even talk
about who I feel like won that fight
that doesn't matter at all in this
podcast that's not what we're here for
alright I didn't see it all I know is
that Nate Diaz took a hell of a beating
and that during the press conference he
was ripping a CBD and blatantly ripping
it - he looked took like two or three
big fat rips off of it so he didn't
cough like I do yeah right no he took it
like a champ he doesn't smoke cigarettes
all day bro I thought that was the key
to his success was tobacco yes what
makes him the enemy if I make some tough
as nails where the nickname wheezy comes
from right yeah they call him young
wheezy so I feel like this dude should I
think I feel like every athlete I feel
like almost everybody should be allowed
to consume see everybody why not let's
consume CBD eticket was about last night
the new episode that aired was a medical
marijuana use in the NFL to deal with
the chronic concussion syndrome or
whatever it's called no one helps I'm a
victim of a head injury and I know we
talked about that 42 minutes ago yep
that definitely that CBD changed my life
and it helped me get out of my funk that
I had wasn't focused on CBD but that's
sort of what they were inching at is a
part of the story that were telling was
THC and CBD are both neural protections
my next question was going to be do you
think
cannabis use is a performance-enhancing
drug
what's this performance fighting kicking
people of fighting UFC fighting how
about football
no not performance-enhancing at all how
about recovery enhancing how about
basketball no no I'm trying to play
devil's advocate here how about video
games yeah yeah I feel like when I smoke
if I in a long time there's a lot of
things I would put it on the list
see then in my mind since I am so
comfortable I've got a TD my mind
wanders you can tell by listening to the
podcast my mind is [ __ ] carts around
all over the place man
when I smoke some hash it does help me
focus a little bit there's a moment
there for the first 5-10 minutes where
my brain just spins but once it lands
back in its place I'm pretty well
focused and so I mean I've got mild ATD
as well and that's one of the things
I've always enjoyed about cannabis is it
helps slow down the this cool better I
could shoot basketball better I could
probably I don't play football I could
probably throw my football with more
accuracy after I took a couple of dabs
ah I'm a musician I've played drums for
20 years I've had drum lessons I've been
on tour I've played in big bands I
played in small bands sometimes smoking
a little weed makes me play a little
better sometimes smoking a little weed
[ __ ] me up to tell you the truth so I
don't know how like alters unless you're
talking about like just helping the the
athlete of the performer tune out other
distractions and focus on the
competition in the moment I don't see it
you know making you run faster and jump
higher and that's what I think of when I
write performance an answer yourself
full of blood so that your your heart
can move more oxygen yeah taking more
testosterone so I'm faster mean or lean
or quicker right a steroids so that you
have more physical muscle mass but like
THC doesn't do any it doesn't able to
kick you in the face any harder it
doesn't make me give you more damn it
helps me recover from that face kick
faster but like that's not a performance
enhancer that's a recovery enhancer like
that's very different
a UFC fighter and like we're gearing up
for the fight the music's going Rogen's
all out there oh my god this is the
fight of the [ __ ] night everybody and
Rogen's just going nuts with this bald
head
this is [ __ ] too much alpha brain
does yours have a little dab fighter
right on the UFC fighter I'm getting my
I got my [ __ ] hand wraps on I got my
gloves I got my tape coming on I got my
gloves on I got my ankle wraps on I got
these long chicken legs and they come
out in like Ross and Jeff you got to
fight in 30 seconds you ready for your
pre-show dab and I'm like let's get it
and they drop me like a half a gram with
some pineapple Jack nuh grunt shatter on
there and I blow it out you know what I
want to do after that not fight how do
you medicate and want to fight at all no
I'm just see this is how little MMA I
watch you couldn't manipulate no you can
manipulate the rake huh because they've
they need their fingers to grapple
I was thinking boxing style well you've
got one manager holding up the smoke
buddy one manager holding up the rig
another manager working the nail on the
car cap yeah
this seems complicated for a pre-fight
dad I would use one of those
the Hitman hinge nails so you do with
one hand I can do with my glove on I
figure this out do the announcers
microphone comes down Jeff's rig comes
down I am one of those guys that if
there's a DAB to be taken I will make
sure that happens the diver that's
awesome I'm glad we got to work the Nate
Diaz clip into this episode that was
gurus I saw that and I was so blown away
I was like that's gotta be photoshopped
and I clicked the volume on it and they
start talking about it I was blown away
yeah shut up - Nate Diaz for
representing cannabis and tough decision
loss - he goes up all chest out proud to
lead the way about medical cannabis no
way politically correct or gentle no I
just got kicked in the [ __ ] head I'm
gonna smoke some CBD to help it out it's
gonna help don't be mad at me that's
cool I like that but both of those
brothers are gonna end up banned from
the UFC and banned from fighting for
life if they keep playing the way that
they do and that's gonna be terrible
because I like to see their performances
yes you guys it is random I'm a red
large hippie Rastafari and do
but I love to watch some UFC I think
about it this way those dudes weigh 200
pounds and they're [ __ ] Jack they've
got more testosterone and then their
body been most people should have and
they want a break [ __ ] I'm glad that
they're in that cage breaking each other
then out at the bar or at the dad lounge
trying to break me yeah III condone that
go to battle in that cage let's see it
that's cool that's skill Jiu Jitsu we've
both known people who were just built to
brawl yeah that's just yeah some people
are here to drum some people here a high
five some people are here to brawl we've
all got our skill um
and it's good that they have an outlet
and I'm a fan of em imagine don't care
enough to pay attention I think I am
accidentally an MMA fan because of Joe
Rogan and because of Joey Diaz and it
all rubbed off it just rubs off it's you
Bravo Joe Rogan puts out the fight
companion to him and a bunch of his
friends and I also listen to fight her
in the kids so that's more MMA they gets
pumped into my head but they put out a
fight companion where two guys from
fighter and the kid and Eddie Bravo and
Joe Rogan sit around and they watch the
UFC and they talk about what's going on
they drink beer and smoke we didn't get
[ __ ] up and talk [ __ ] to each other
but they're watching the UFC and they
tell you like in the match they're like
all right round three of this match
we're at 29 28 27 seconds and you can
sync up your computer and watch that
video and so it's almost weirdly like
you're hanging out with Rogan and the
crew watching the fight I'll see I'll
watch it if it's on some where I'm at
but I don't like actively pay attention
yeah I pay more like if I'm over at your
house and it's on the it'll get more
attention out of me than like football
or basketball and I uh I took a little
karate when I was a youngster so I've
always been fascinated with that type of
skills to conclusion - for several years
and then pong pseudo karate for even
longer I was just doing for us to do his
rep and CBD and I like that he had a
little CBD vape pen that was set up like
an opener and what any of the other
major vape companies just rip it on some
CBD oil took like two or three good
maybe three or four good rips all right
like we've been rambling for almost an
hour I think it's time to wrap up this
show what do you think miss any other
points on CBD we covered it's basic
medical applications I crossed out all
the stuff on my list except popular CBD
strains so that if people wanted to
Oh cannabis that was high in CBD just a
few strains I would recommend anything
Harlequin canna tonic Taurus ooh Tora
Bora ac/dc the Tora Bora is really
wonderful folks that I've had a lot of
personally and I know I went over that
list really quickly those were just off
the top of my home the other thing I'd
like to touch and I think before we wrap
this one up is for at least for the pain
and inflammation that I'm dealing with
THC and CBD together in roughly 50/50
mix work two or three hundred times
better than CBD alone or THC alone the
two of them together works it's not one
plus one equals two it's one plus one
equals seven as far as I'm concerned the
effect is amplified greatly cool last
man I know it's wonderful when you when
you mix THC and CBD the medical
applications are wonderful I'm sorry if
I sound a little stoned and I am pretty
tired but I feel clear-headed I feel
like alert and present we're gonna
wasn't true when I got here I was
hurting so bad I I seriously almost
didn't come folks and I really liked it
and I didn't almost didn't come because
my head was pounding I'm glad you made
it
I'm glad you pulled through I'm glad
those CBD tabs fixed you up yeah I
should have just started to have in CBD
earlier in the day I just I was out and
about and didn't get a chance all day
that's how life goes sometimes you got
to get home and get the dad bread going
bro remind everybody how they can follow
you on social media and absolutely
remind us about your Facebook page you
can catch me on webelo for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook give us a like
comment share we really appreciate that
we're reaching more and more people
every week on that it's I mean the
viewers that I get per week spike and
change topic to topic but as we've been
getting closer to the election the view
counts been going up steady that's been
nice and I like to think this show has
something to do with it so if you're
checking us out from the show go ahead
and send me a message say hi or if you
just want to hit me on Twitter it's at
Nemo punk 15 on Twitter and e/m opu and
k15 just like it sounds and yeah look
forward to hearing from you yeah make
sure you follow them
you found him on the podcast and
shout-out to Barry oh I'm glad you liked
the last episode
fast Barry what's up buddy thanks for
listening bro you've been listening to
the podcast since the beginning I
appreciate that and we see those
messages merrily appreciate yes we do we
see all of those messages you guys if
you send me a message and I have not
responded to your message yet I'm
getting to it trust me we do one Episode
a week I get 20 up messages a week I
have try to filter out my favorite or
the most relevant for what's going on in
our lives right now that's how I handle
the emails so I'll be back with more
episodes with more email content I love
the listenor generated content that lets
me know that I'm getting the information
to the people that need the information
I'm giving them exactly what they want
makes me feel great we are we know way
too much about cannabis folks and we
spend hours debating which little nugget
of our our vast cannabis intellect to
share with the listeners this night and
it's when we have an email that's like
hey I was wondering how to block it it
sparks some awesome conversation so my
favorite episodes man our listeners with
specific grow questions absolutely I'll
be going through the phone and I'll get
an email and it'll say a show question
and I'll read it you can see me light up
like oh yeah because now I get to ramble
for 45 minutes about one of my favorite
things and a whole bunch about it so it
always makes me good to get those
messages and honestly from where we are
in Colorado especially if you're in
Pueblo it's hard to understand what you
need to know now in Florida or Drive or
wherever you happen or alia we have
listeners all over the place and so you
send it in a question that lets us know
where you're at and how we can help you
helps us clue in on the information to
give you and I absolutely love those
episodes there's so much fun to do the
last two email episodes were fantastic
I've got plenty more coming guys don't
be afraid to send me some emails don't
be discouraged if I haven't replied to
you I get so many messages that it's
honestly overwhelming somebody told me
to hire an intern that would be [ __ ]
because it's all about talking to me
they don't want to talk to my intern
they don't want a pre typed answer they
want to actually communicate with me I
do my best to do that I try to keep up
with it because if you don't know how to
get in touch with me this is how you do
it if you have a question for the
podcast the easiest way to get your
question acknowledged is to send it to
grow from your heart
mail.com you can follow these sweets
that's the sweet spot it's the easiest
you can follow me on twitter it's @gf
wih podcast you can follow the podcast
on facebook search for grow from your
heart podcast it's on Facebook I would
love to hear from you on any of those
platforms but like I said my favorite is
the girl from your heart at hotmail.com
email I'll answer all your stuff if you
want to sponsor the podcast if you've
got a product you want me to review
anything like that reach out to me there
also you guys I am on instagram my
instagram page is Irie underscore
genetics I own a seed company we breed
feminized and regular cannabis seeds you
can see a lot of my grow progress right
there on high ryu score genetics on
instagram check that out i've been
posting some cool pictures of a breeding
project great lately yeah thank you I
appreciate that that picture I posted
with the female grateful dog plant with
the male arise flowers and pollen on top
of it it drops little flowers and the
pollen dumped on there and it's already
showing seeds that picture got 400 and
something 50 something likes at the last
time I looked it's probably close to 5
or 600 by now we're really getting some
notice on the Instagram please follow me
there you guys I think we're gonna wrap
up the show Mike thank you for coming
dude now man I had to for the CBD
episode that's honestly what with the
final decision-maker for leaving the
house and coming over and doing the show
was was I wanted to do another good
episode about CBD the you myself and
Doug did one a while back yes and I've
had Fox on a couple times also we've
done yeah you've done two with Fox Jay
Fox CBD crew yeah that was my who I was
hinting at when you said let's do a CBD
episodes like we want a third you were
like now let's just do it
you and me showed him yeah he lives in
Denver now so it's harder to do yeah
but he's sort of the CBD go to that I
know of down here when I have a CBD
question that's who I send a message to
yep yep all right you guys yeah if you
guys have CBD questions or any other
questions please sit us up any questions
at all you guys we're gonna get out of
here it's time for us to take some phat
dad's make sure that ninja Spence and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
we hire you serious time you can't seek
what you redefine you can't when you
hear me design my whole rhyme on the
page some kind of setup set minimal time
on the stage but I don't wanna play
myself
my whole brain
[Music]