yeah welcome back cannabis community as
time prep zone number 157 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
the threat if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always you need to send a
huge thank-you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shots
a cat coot and the entire mystic
ladies and gentlemen to my left a repeat
offender welcome back to the show
Lindsay the traveling stoner welcome
back honey thank you for having me
I also right in front of me he's usually
white Mike with today's kind of red
welcome to the show bro Mike took a dad
gone for about 15 20 minutes the cops
make you feel like people are there with
us there you go let it fly bro let it
fly everybody at this podcast we're
gonna talk about some new purchase
limits here in Colorado
we've been restricted sorry babe we've
been restricted on how much hash we can
purchase here in Colorado also they've
changed some rules on some edibles and
also in Oregon they have banned some
popular strain names we'll get to that
in just a minute
first let's talk a little bit about this
secret sesh I was at the secret session
on Friday Lindsey was also there Mike
couldn't make it he had much more
important things to handle I finally are
now working for a secret session
birthday to the wife thanks secret
session secrets happens every month
twice birthdays only once and once a
year happy birthday to the wife I know
it's it's a late but still yeah so
Lindsey and I and a whole bunch of other
people had the pleasure of attending the
secret stash
would you think about session honestly I
had a lot of fun at this one we kind of
squatted up a little bit on some couches
invaded some space yeah yeah there
weren't enough tables so a bunch of
people brought super fancy glass the
Dino was a Dino jopi collab yet I had
his elbow Joe Peters
whole web super snazzy yeah and then um
max had his Matt Robinson is that a Cola
I lost the thing was gorgeous I have no
idea who maybe I know that the shape of
it is Matt Robinson I think it's a cola
I'd have to there's a green giraffe I
bet you Brett and Chris are both
listening this episode screaming it's a
collab whoever made it both of those
pieces were fancy fresh and these dudes
pull out these fancy rigs and there's no
table yes like a heady zoo and there's
nowhere for the zoo to like so we had
some staff finds table space for us we
made a little bit of table space through
some hash down we got down pretty well
we got down big shout out to Ty for that
huge as dab you can catch that on my
Instagram first time first time I got to
hang out the tie that dudes a soldier yo
ty is insane big shout out to Earl
tycoon on Instagram and THC chocolates
which is his edible company as well nice
he threw me some stickers so big shout
out I got those stickers they're gonna
go on something cool probably a case of
some sort do that for me at the secret
stash our good friend max sat down next
to us I've been trying not to say good
friend remember a long time ago this is
gonna be our friend Max from TNT
extraction sat down next to me at the
secret stash and he knows I don't eat
Macon and he's felt bad for offering me
medicated bacon at all the past sessions
so he pulls out a banana pudding
Shumate bar it's 100 milligrams of THC
and he hands this to me he's like here
bro you want this and I was like oh you
know what have any Venables
and it's been four or five months since
I had eaten edibles yeah and I broke
that banana pudding bar in half
I ate half of it did a little selfie
video with Miss Lindsay here I passed
the other half of it to Lindsay I think
she split it with Bobo I did so I am
back on the edibles wagon I eat edibles
again if the secret session was Friday I
ate the banana pudding bar ate a couple
little smaller edibles that people gave
me like candies and such like a caramel
or something oh and then I ate something
else we're gonna talk about later on on
the show and then Saturday I ate a 100
milligram Claudie bear a cherry one
honestly not to diss any Claudie bears
but the cherry are absolutely not my
favorite flavor I didn't like the cherry
when it had a little bit of a mediciney
funky aftertaste the cherry that a lot
of the candy companies use has that yeah
prefer I like the root beer is [ __ ]
delicious they've got an apple one
that's really good I like the ones that
they and they're like a raspberry that
they actually dip in chocolate those are
[ __ ] delicious
but the cherry didn't it's gummy high as
[ __ ] I slept like a baby but I did not
like the flavor I wouldn't buy that one
again then today I ate from Gaia's
Garden edibles
I ate a 100 milligram milk chocolate
cherry truffle which was quite delicious
and I had to go slow to try to say what
that was because because it is obviously
working back in the edibles game
I gotta go slowly because I catch myself
just becoming way over medicated on the
edibles I can't do that to myself again
I don't want to get all [ __ ] ruined
and slow on edibles so secret session
was a great time shout out to everybody
that hung out yeah absolutely
Brett Max and Ty for sure them three and
twisty twisty is where I was headed yep
Dwayne Dwayne yes we had a nice little
crew there yeah uncle stoner hung out
with us a little bit the dude and the
vest that was filming everything that's
uncle stoner he's kind of well-known
he's got his own show check him out if
you're interested yeah there were a lot
of cool people Adam ill came in holds it
down he's a really cool host he's the
kind of host at all there was a band
playing and as the band played he just
came and kick it with us roll the back
hood
those took some dads with the crew
flirted with a couple of chicks and then
yeah sure that's a hunt hunt throws a
hell of a party yes this time it's
secret session I did something that I
don't usually do i was given the VIP
gift bag forgiving us both one of those
yeah let's just real quickly go through
the gift bag and talk about what's in
here there's a bunch of really cool
stuff a couple things I'll do it like
Christmas I'm gonna start with the
things that are least impressive to the
most impressive to me a company called
healing nations LLC cultivation
consulting cultivation systems and
nutrients through in a small baggie of
cannabis it's a little bit of buds it's
it's okay weed and it's not impressive
weed but it was a gift so I appreciate
it we're gonna smoke this here later on
but yeah they threw in some weed also
next up the lazy lion threw in a real
big flyer and a small baggie and they
threw down a pre-roll so if you guys
want to smoke a pre-roll joint that's
probably a gram and a half two grams of
weed in that joint we could smoke that
oh I owe somebody a shout-out totally
random off the cuff here but somebody
gave me an 18 gram joint
I was given an 18 gram joy if it's
rolled and supposed to smoke it at the
secret session I was having a scary day
and I did not take it to the secret sesh
with me shout out to our friends in New
Mexico shut up it's Charlie Torres ah
and his son and also big shot up to Tim
and everybody involved in organic ax
down in New Mexico I love you guys those
guys grew some arise and it tested at
30.8% yeah so that's golden go across to
the Daybreaker I gave them some seeds
I've got two strains that have been lab
tested by steep hill they've tested over
30 percent THC and the jobs two
different labs one in Colorado one in
New Mexico same company the link to that
is both strains are golden crosses lemon
Jeffrey is the lemon skunk crossed to a
golden goat reversed mail so it's a
feminized seed that one hit 31 percent
then the the theorize is the [ __ ]
golden goat sorry
Goldin [ __ ] full of [ __ ] right now
I'm gonna have to edit part of this
because I'm saying this all wrong ah
limits gonna cos lemons
yeah the lemon Geoffrey is the woman's
going to the golden go and the arize is
golden go to Daybreaker so it's a
basically the non feminized version of
the lemon Geoffrey and those of both
they've got the golden go parent in
there and those are both tested over 30%
now so shout out to my friends down
there in New Mexico shout out to Charlie
Torrez and organically grown hand
trimmed perfectly cured perfectly rolled
18 gram joint it's gonna get everybody
hiya [ __ ] wherever we go they said they
smoked one the other night at another
event and it went around for over an
hour so we're gonna get lit wherever we
go it smells delicious it smells amazing
I haven't smoked it yet but it's you can
probably see that [ __ ] baseball bat
sittin over there
so shout out to our friends in New
Mexico they passed through here the
other day gave me some dads with some
rosin I shout out to woody checks with
the whole crew I appreciate all you guys
so I'm gonna continue on with this gift
bag there's a coupon in here for 15% off
any purchase at a specific dispensary
that didn't pay me for an ad there is a
another sticker there's a sticker from
Gaia's garden let's see we're movin on
up there is some some cannabis in here
too to small nugs probably a good gram
of weed from mile high dispensary this
is some New York City diesel aia looks
it looks like I approved so far it's in
like a vacuum sealed bag so I can't
smell it but it looks quality ones he
smoked some of the last night would you
think to get I yeah actually I had
something else and it went out after the
first half the joint I know that New
York City Diesel is one of Mike's
favorite or at least the Sour Diesel is
way up on my list any of the New York
alright well if you guys want to smoke
that or the pre-roll whichever you feel
there might be a pipe here somewhere
that might be clean in the little pipe
moving on up the ladder it's like
Christmas the gifts just keep getting
better our friends at Incredibles
extracts through down a half a gram of
sour band zero nine fresh frozen
so it's live resin concentrate I was
kind of like a sappy shatter sorry you
guys I'm burping excuse me
so Claire so gorgeous it tasted Graham
so I did was but it's accurate I was a
half a gram so I basically did it all in
one dad because that's how I am but I
inhaled and I started to blow it out and
I was like oh it tastes so good and I
tried to like catch my exhale so that I
could exhale real slowly and just savor
all of that dab flavor because it was so
tasty sure so shout out to Incredibles
extracts shout out to Derek that [ __ ]
was delicious
I approve that's a great thing to throw
on a gift bag for a VIP I really like
that yes thank you then my next favorite
in here was from guys garden cannabis
creations this was a caramel apple
double karma edible this had 200
milligrams of THC and 20 milligrams of
CBD and in this little package it's one
of these uh like the pop top Church pop
it there you go on these pop top
containers there were two Tootsie Roll
size and shape products in there wrapped
in cellophane one of them was green it
was the Apple the other one was caramel
colored and it was obviously the caramel
I took a little nibble off the Apple it
was [ __ ] delicious it's like sour
apple Jolly Ranchers it tastes really
good and then I nibble off the caramel
and it was good but not my favorite kind
of caramel ever it was a little bit
milky maybe might be the description but
then I pinched a little of both off and
threw them both in my mouth and when you
mix that Apple and that caramel together
all I was [ __ ] delicious so this
edible is really good 200 milligrams of
THC 20 milligrams of CBD in a shop this
probably would have been a twenty dollar
eighteen twenty dollar edible it was
delicious and I approved so shadow it's
a guy his garden I really liked that
then my favorite thing in the bag this
is last thing in the bag and then we'll
move on because I've been going for way
longer than I wanted to on this I was
surprised to see this Dutch girl
cannabis seeds there is a six pack this
is all packaged up properly for Colorado
retail this could be on the Shelf I
heard that this was available this
actual product was available at a local
dispensary this is a
called the animal it's a hundred percent
sativa and it is a cross of Jabberwocky
and ghost train haze so I got a six pack
of seeds we may have to grow those in
the future here and see what comes of
this so shout out to hunt shout it to
the everybody from the secret stash
shut up two miles Jeff - Adam hill
shout-out to DJ dougie
yeah everybody treats me like like a VIP
like we've gone to so many sessions that
everybody knows us now they see us they
high-five us when they walk in they know
who we are I know who they are it's
really fun so shadows - the secret stash
we should move on from that because
we've been going for a really long time
Jonna - [ __ ] Lindsay and Bobo and
Bret and all the people that just let me
come kick it with them when I got there
the party was already started when I
walked in everyone's like scoot over
make room for Rasta Jeff had like Bobo
had a gift for me Brett had part two of
the gift for me so they like come here
try the gift and then there was a
podcast listener sitting there who I
only know you by your Instagram name I
cannot think of your real name right now
but he was sitting there he's like bro
what's up he wanted to shake my hand
right away Johnny be from no goo wanted
to run over and shake my hand right away
Jayson margulies wanted to come over and
say what's up and get a hug that dudes
always on the move such a cool brother I
have really quick Jason did the funniest
thing I he was telling me how much he
loves oh jeez so I brought him this huge
dab of some og 18 that I had and I
forgot a carb cap I had I had heated the
nail and everything for him and I forgot
a carb cap so as he's taken the dab I'm
like Jace and I'm horrid I forgot a I
forgot a carb cap there was the
countertop that was like granite
and he goes underneath it and caps it
like moves himself up and down and caps
thanks it was great I was like I'm glad
to see that the MacGyver spirit of the
community is alive yes it's awesome
walking into an event and being treated
like a [ __ ] rocks yeah yeah I wish
somebody would have told the people at
the door who I was but I wasn't on any
list or anything
uh-huh I told me you just come through I
got you and so when I got there like
you're not on any list and I was like I
know go go I know hunt though and like
we don't care it was like no before row
you you whiff
I tell huh you turned me away he's gonna
be [ __ ] pissed he better go let him
know I'm here and the guy came back as
well you're all square to go bro I'm
sorry to be a dick like hunt told me
personally his name so it shows of his
number and you can compare it to yours
pretty close to me like you just want to
read my messages dude but they let me in
but yeah I got to have a good ass time I
don't think I left that one seat other
than to take a piss once or twice shut
up for the nachos thank you I needed
that oh yeah vegetarians yeah I don't
like jalapeno see you perfect I
mentioned it's a gift that Bobo made for
me there is a new thing let's talk about
this new thing and then we'll actually
get to the main topic of this podcast
the new trend so I've been talking about
turps here in Colorado a whole bunch in
my hand I've got a half DRAM vial that's
a small vial those small vials with the
screw on lid I've got the shortie one ah
it's some ghost rain haze liquid turps
my friend Tim from New Mexico my friends
Tim and Charlie showed up from New
Mexico with this device that looked like
a large pipette it's real skinny on one
end and it tapers and gets thicker at
the other end and it's got like a
mouthpiece made onto it and they were
dunking it into the Terps and then
letting the excess drip off back into
the container and then without any fire
you keep it tipped down like you would
have straw and you just draw through
they call it a Terp straw just draw
right through it with no heat while it's
cool you pull air through it and you can
taste the turps incredibly strong and we
were able to put what I would normally
dunk onto a dab four people took two
good drawers off of it before the flavor
went away and I don't know that I got
any head change cuz I was already high
and we're smoking rosin and stuff but
it's an incredible way to experience the
flavor and the essence of the turps
without any fire or without any waste I
really thought it was cool so I was
talking about this to bobo who is now
learning how to blow glass he was coming
along super [ __ ] quickly you guys if
he could see what he's doing I don't
want to talk about
spill his beans he's got an idea he's
got a project that I think is really
cool it's the new [ __ ] it is the new
thing I think this guy's gonna kill but
he made me a Terp straw so shout out to
Bobo for the new sip interp straw it's
got some red golden green line work it's
got a little Colorado mili is that a
million is that what that is an
implosion it's a million I don't know he
did a little like flower implosion but
he did it with the Colorado yeah it's
really sweet I really appreciate it he's
making a modification to it because it's
a new product he's gonna modify it
perfect it for me but he's making a
little modification that I requested but
shout out for that I totally appreciate
that but you're gonna see more people
taking cold sip chirps at events and
things in the future here I think is
gonna be something that will catch on
also I owe a shout-out to a glass artist
who's Cameron Reid that's hard to
remember
I knew the name I just had to say it
slowly which is funny because we'll talk
about this but shout at the camera and
read glass so I'll save that for another
episode because that's gonna get long
let's work on some of the main topics of
this podcast so let's quickly go through
the band names in organ they have
medical marijuana available and they
have recently banned some of the names
I've got a they legalized marijuana for
all adults a lot a year and a half ago
and they're just now getting through to
implementing regulations yeah they've
had stores and like zoning for a minute
and one of the new regulations is some
common strain names are going away in
the state of Oregon I've got a short
article I'm not gonna read all of it
because the second half the article is
not even related to anything involved in
what this is they just ramble on about
some stuff this comes from The Oregonian
and the headline says no more Girl Scout
cookies and other popular names on pot
packaging state says and this is by Noel
Crombie and the article goes like this
popular names such as Girl Scout cookies
in Charlotte's Web won't be allowed on
the labeling and packaging of medical
and recreational marijuana in Oregon
under rules approved by the state Friday
the Oregon liquor Liquor Control
Commission said it had reviewed about
500 marijuana strain names and
identified about 20 that may appeal to
children
commissioners saw
a rule change after hearing from members
of the public who objected to the
child-friendly names I'm gonna interject
here the [ __ ] is a kid doing in the
dispensary anyway how's a kid gonna see
that on there I think they're talking
about on the packaging at home Lindsay
is the voice of reason today one of the
arguments that iPod people have really
been able to get legislators around the
country to listen to and so when we get
to the Colorado rules in a minute the
reasons they were implemented are
essentially identical and I I agree we
need to keep cannabis products out of
the hands of children
it is a medical condition that they need
it right right I just don't want my kid
taking my cannabis but somebody else
getting access to my Shumate bar and
taking this to school and get your kid
and your kid [ __ ] freaking out at
school and you sue and me and the school
[Music]
I want to go fast before we totally
train right this [ __ ] so there's some
strain names being banned in Oregon now
and yes don't worry the the strains
themselves haven't been bad right right
yeah yeah completely there have been
some breather breeders have been talking
on Facebook forums and such about this
the article goes the rule approved one
day before the state licenses
recreational marijuana retailers
prohibits words that refer to products
that are commonly associated with minors
or marketed by minors chairman of the
Commission called the new requirement a
common-sense approach if you walk
through a toy store and you can identify
things that are straight names those are
probably inappropriate he said it's also
as simple as that the agency also won't
allow strained names that refer to
illicit drugs such as LSD and blow LSD
is just lemon Sour Diesel it's just way
easier to [ __ ] write and blow is a
stupid [ __ ] name for a straight name
so cool I'm gonna want Green crack yeah
yeah it will get to that list a list of
outlawed proper names
ah Girl Scout cookies Grape Ape
Candyland Charlotte's Web Cinderella
Doctor Who bubblicious Smurfs
Bruce Banner Death Star Skywalker and
Jedi cush those strains will still be
allowed in organs recreational shops
retailers and marijuana producers and
processors can use initials or some
others shorthand reference instead of
the full strain name okay yes so let's
say it doesn't have to get renamed or
anything right yeah but it's pretty
gentle but it's also pretty silly it is
kind of silly but you can't have
Skywalker or Jedi Kush okay I mean I
don't know how they're doing it in
Oregon but in Colorado it's blocked
printed in black lettering that's how
the screen name gets printed on pretty
much every product that leaves a legal
dispensary I mean it's never down the
front with the toys-r-us logos different
colors what's fought for kids eyes it's
just computer printed on a packaging
label with okay let me be the voice of
reason again we are still able to
legally buy weed in the shop so is it
that because you're a hundred percent
right I just feel like in the in the
Marin excuse me in the marijuana
industry and community we have such
bigger battles to be fighting than the
fact that we can't use the name Girl
Scout cookies I'm not being mean I'm
just saying like to me it just feels
like we can all buy illegal weed like I
get it it's a bummer and it's a big deal
but at the end of the day it's not like
you have to rename the strain to be you
know something completely ridiculous
that that's nothing to do with cookies
you know what I'm saying like they're
not saying you can't use any cookie name
or any they took like 20 names out of
500 which in the grand scheme of things
is probably so much do you think Bounty
Killer would make this list the Bounty
Killer mad aloud I feel like a la
I feel like a lot of like Colorado
strains would be bald I was thinking
about the different ones we've care or
I've had on a shelf in front of me I've
been working in the legal industry I
think about maybe 20% of them oddly
enough Green crack is not on this list
yeah when I read the list I was like
well there's a bunch missing like if
this is the criteria so maybe they just
got the super blatant ones and they left
the others girls make sense for sure I
was when you said then I was like oh
that makes absolute sense that's a
children organization Grape Ape
Candyland Charlotte's Web that's all
children stop selling kids book
characters there's a company that's
spent on us a fortune in like half a
decade marketing Charlotte's Web around
the country right yeah [ __ ]
Cinderella I mean oh absolutely
so Girl Scout cookies we're just gonna
call that GSC and it also says
derivative strains you can't use
Platinum Girl Scouts or Thin Mints
either yep so Ulsan then you probably
can't use dos eidos Dossey dozer band
well yeah every I I saw something the
other day that was snickerdoodle is the
screen name the fruit names I mean how
many different ones vaguely meet like an
item a kid might have for dessert also
right sour lemon sherbert doctor who was
taken because it's a fictional character
currently marketed to children basically
any fictional character like I was when
I first read this I was like well some
jackass made an Obama crush like is that
gone too because kids know the president
like I mean how far they go on with this
particular and that's why I have an
issue with it because as a regulation
it's a little bizarre right I'm like you
can ban cartoons from the name or from
the logo you can do a lot of other
things to make sure that the products
the target children but banning stuff
that's gonna be like just words in black
print like some of them makes a little
bit of sense but some of its it's just
gonna be a regulatory pain in the ass
down the road for sure just more hoops
to jump through just just more bitching
and complaining for them to do about
campuses a lot of it's subjective
yeah and that's what makes it a
regulatory issue in my mind any
get to some Colorado rules here in just
a second that it's not subjective let's
let's jump right to that then that's a
good segue Mike since we're like 27
minutes in let's get to this about
halfway through the show it's a perfect
time to move on to my my favorite topic
of the show
Colorado recently until a few days ago
until the first I was allowed to walk
into a dispensary a medical dispensary
or recreational dispensary and I was
able to buy without any special
paperwork I think to the best of my
knowledge I was allowed to buy two
ounces of concentrates I means I could
buy two ounces of shatters that correct
Lindsey says yes mike exactly in a
medical shop yes in a wreck shop just
the one okay so in a medical shop I
could get my two ounces I'm a medical
patient and a recreational shop I was
allowed to buy one ounce concentrate
which is is enough concentrate that's
that's not a lot of concentrate I mean
if you're me I mean but there was
[ __ ] two pounds of [ __ ] rosin on
this tables two couple of days ago but
announcer two is a substantial amount
and now the new rule is no matter who
you are no matter where you're shopping
eight gram limit the original I'm pretty
sure that's on the medical side too I'm
pretty sure it's just wreck I'm uh the
article that I read has misled me and
I'm glad you guys have corrected me um
recreational for a hundred percent sure
you can only buy eight grams of
concentrate now and there are other
rules for edibles and think other items
that are sold by the milligram like
edibles and vape pen cartridges so if
I'm not mistaken I'm doing this from
memory everybody else's are fun out
cheater notes back check for the
audience fact checking like Wow right
now you keep talking go slow uh edible
and vape pen limit is now eight hundred
milligrams it used to be twenty eight
hundred and concentrate limits are now
was seven or eight eight eight grams a
concentrate is that edible limit changed
on the medical side as well I don't as
far as I know these are just
recreational rules I think the only
thing that changed
medicos I was compliant some edible
compliance labeling rules and imprinting
on bars so there are two different rule
changes in cholera three different rule
changes in Colorado one limits what
people can buy one limits the shape of
certain gummies yeah animals period and
but mostly affecting gummies right now
market wide and then the last rule is
edibles in Colorado now the actual item
has to carry a stamp and I actually took
notes today post had an interview with
Larry wolf the head of the Department of
Colorado Health and Environment the CDP
AG and somebody from the top of the meed
the marijuana Enforcement Division the
edible symbols there's two exceptions so
like every piece of chocolate has to
carry a little if it's recreational and
yellow diamond with the letters THC
exclamation point in it and the medical
just has the M right for medical no it's
the same diamond and it has to say th oh
they might have dropped the color that
was one of the original things and
people were like well how do we make it
yellow on a brownie without frosting or
somesuch it took a while for some
companies to get this implemented I've
seen one company that they just made a
disk out of sugar so it's a hundred
percent edible but it has the logo on it
and then they've affixed it to the top
of their product with like melted
marshmallow it is weird in practice but
it's pretty tasty but the only
exceptions to carrying that symbol are
liquids the liquids manufacturers
managed to get the legislature to see
reason and make a specific exception for
liquids so that you know you you can't
stamp a liquid and they were literally
tough for a while talking about making
it having gold style show longer
floaties that said THC in it or some
such
or only doing single serving packages of
liquids so it could only come in a 10
milligram serving recreationally which
would pretty much kill recreational
liquids but they carved out an exception
it can still be a hundred milligram
liquid container as long as the
measuring device is part of that
container and stuff like granola now has
to come in single serving packages
anything like any edible that can't
carry the snap has to come in
individually individual serving size
packages with the label affixed to that
packaging so that you can't leave it on
a table and somebody come along and pick
it up okay which is a felony in its own
right before we came up with the label
it's still a felony with the label it's
like leaving a loaded gun on the table
like it's it's wildly inappropriate
adult behavior yeah that's the basic
edible rundown did you find yes the
article I had to go through three
articles to actually find the truth
medical marijuana will remain unchanged
only one article said that the first
article that I was reading was actually
sponsored by a dispensary so they were
trying to leave medical marijuana out on
purpose I think because of the way that
it was worded it totally made it look
like it was happening all over the board
so I'm glad I'm glad that the medical
market industry's been talking about
this for a year now felonies for the
past four days just me this weekend so I
was the only one commitment felonies a
lot of people are sweating this because
so far in Colorado not a single licensed
dispensary has screwed up the purchase
limit rule no one's been cited or fined
for selling over the limit yet yeah I
was only been a couple days well no
we've always had period in Colorado no
shop has been cited for that and that's
sort of it's one of those little random
points of pride for a while our team our
teen ID checks things where we were in
9 percent which is unheard of in liquor
tobacco yeah and we were real proud of
that and then we had one bad round and
got knocked down to 92 just like alcohol
and tobacco and that hurt but they don't
even check alcohol and tobacco they do
but it's not nearly what they do with
with marijuana they were doing it was a
real ID in the person and the ID was
wearing a hat and the person checking
the ID was supposed to catch that that
was the last ID sting that I heard about
performed on a marijuana store that's
sketchy trying to [ __ ] with us I know
that's checking compliance to the nth
degree
marijuana shops also face ten times the
fine that a tobacco or alcohol retailer
would of course um it's ten grand if you
add so cigarettes or alcohol to somebody
underage is the possible fine with
marijuana that's a hundred that could
ruin a business yeah I could just close
you down no matter how big your
dispensary is a hundred thousand or fine
cuz I guess that way can be careful
alright so now that's why one of the
reasons that never have recreational
shoppers can now only buy eight grams
yep does that mean that people that come
to do that means the ounce Till's are
gonna go away at the REC shops no more
cheap ounce deals because you can't buy
an ounce of hash yeah I'm just cheap
because I mean you'd see concentrate
deals for like four twenty five hundred
forty pounds well and there's no end
either and so you can't get your your
limit in flour and your limit in hash
and your limit in edibles there's
actually a chart that's been going
around that shows how the breakdown is
how many grams of hash equals how many
grams of flour how many grams of
milligrams of edibles equal how many
grams of flour I don't pay attention the
charts I'm not working at a budtender
station there was this great like three
month period where bud tenders didn't
have to do pointless math in their head
all day long like counting to seven over
and over in different fractions
depending on what the order was or
whatever we was just twenty eight was
the limit and it was real simple and now
there's this that they are we all have
to keep in our heads it sucks just more
regulation to follow do you think is
just gonna make people go to more stores
people that are smurfing yeah but this
rule really isn't for them there hasn't
been a lot of that that's why they just
recently upped the out-of-state purchase
limit to an ounce
okay when this rule was originally
passed they were talking about out of
Staters can only buy one and a half
grams a hash I laughed the first time I
read it because I looked down at my case
and I was like everything comes in one
gram containers yeah you can buy one
gram or we've got to talk to all our
distributors and see if they can do I
have Zeo
but they hammered it out and then just
recently a couple months ago they upped
that limit so on I don't think they're
worried about smurfin they're just
somebody in the legislature was like
wait we let people buy 28 grams a hash
or 208 what was it 2,800 grams of
edibles it's 28 of the 280 of the most
potent edibles sold in a wreck shop well
I have to [ __ ] ton of edibles
yeah I've seen people leave the spot
with [ __ ] bags I used to every now
and again I say I'll go get you a box or
yeah I mean it happens throughout the
industry security would follow them to
the car but it happens from time to time
it's just one of those things and now
with these new limits it's just anybody
that's looking to do that it's just
gonna have to make more stops but it's a
weird set of rules like you can tell
it's not the same group of people
writing all of these can I ask you a
completely random question that's off
topic sure you guys have both been bud
tenders you have plenty of experience
behind the bud counter and ringing
people up what is the largest ticket you
have ever rung up a single person for my
largest personal take yeah 700 damn at a
rec shop yep okay
lenz do you remember do you want to say
it does it beat Mike 1,700 and I'm
pretty sure man
it's a medical shop you can buy so much
more do I know the purchaser I can't I
can't do that because different rules
that I do that's true I just work it
like basically a store in the mall are
the rules I follow other than the
d checks she works in a medical shop
this she's gonna write down the numbers
she's gonna write it down and we're
gonna gasp she just kept typing zeros
what the [ __ ] okay she's got me beat by
an order of magnitude folks it's five
digits yes that's but I hope that came
was just gonna ask if anybody tipped you
or to carry you for that right those
frugal people's how they have all that
extra money it'll [ __ ] tip the secret
session that's weird we didn't see Molly
I just realize that Molly had fun she
was hiking somewhere excitement hope you
had a great time Mike did you get to
cover all of your edible stuff that you
wanted to talk about um I thought I
think I hid all the new rule changes we
covered the the purchase limit we
covered that oh shapes are changing you
can no longer do human shapes animal
shapes fruit shapes anything that
resembles a candy that's on the shelves
yeah or anything that's identical to its
non-medicated market counterpart so all
of your gummies are now squares Oh which
works out well cuz it's really easy to
imprint the new symbol into a ruler
yep what else how are they handling the
sodas you can still do 100 milligram
beverages in the rec market the
container has to carry the new label and
the dosing instruments so it has to come
with like a an equal medicine top okay
so that you can dose out your 10
milligram dose that's how do we chats
with your friends that's pretty much a
sign when I was selling those all day
have you ever drank like the can
apologize to Keith's Cola oh yeah do you
feel like you get high more quickly to
liquids definitely
and your your stomach doesn't have to
break down the brownie yeah right it's
just absorbable quicker it's like you
drink it and then you go to do whatever
you're doing and then you turn your head
to one way to look at something to go
hole-high with can a punch check the
label there's a range of THC in the can
of punches I drink a 200 to check the
back of the label it might be like - 30
milligrams I'm gonna make a difference
in the rack market there's like it's a
10 15 20 milligram swing that you can
see on the back of those in fact as soon
as we get done here on the table and I
was really pumped to see that it had lab
testing for potency on the back that's
the medicals coming along with that and
I love to see it
totally random interjection there pretty
soon everything will be lab tested go
ahead we had a customer appreciation day
at the shop and I chug to Keith's Cola
100 milligram orange soda before it not
thinking like anything of it and I was
like 45 minutes and I remember a
conversation I had with buzzy a couple
days before that about how like drinks
are sublingually and they like hate you
harder and I was like wow you're an
idiot Lindsey you just chug that thing
right before you came in not even like
it didn't taste that hash she said we
got a bunch of 10 milligram samples at
one point and I took the four flavour
samples we got home and without thinking
about it drank all four of them and
liked it jot it down a little flavor
review about each one and just myself
I like being edible ruined to an extent
yeah I think about 250 milligrams right
now is just about perfect for me I don't
want to go too much far faster because
that's when I started getting a little
goofy start getting a little hazy but
I'm back on the edible horse so when I
see you I will not it probably not funny
I think
well that too I'll take any edibles you
have he didn't say he was gonna be here
he was back to being inedible or he said
I'm back on the edible or which is who
are you hashtag can I get on it -
hashtag troll the host I think my
edibles are working I think the dad's
role working oh there you go drop a dab
buddy Instant Karma all right right now
tell us here tell us how to find you on
social media Mike ID neo-punk 15 on
Twitter or on Facebook you know when I
wrote this episode when I wrote the
notes I really thought that everybody
was limited to 8 grams of purchasing so
it really changed the impact of my
attitude of this show coughing syllable
words are hard you guys we're making up
our own words here in the podcast
get your own podcast set up some
microphones get a feed and you can make
up your own words just say them into the
microphone there's got to be some sort
of rule if you say a word more than 6 or
7 or 12 times and it's got to be a word
now competitions I can say rational yeah
I'm gonna leave the vape kids alone they
have enough trouble Lindsay my friend
how can people find you on social media
let's hear about all 37 of your accounts
I know she's not laughing around just
like it is when you read it it's not
true
I'm the travelling stoner and Instagram
and periscope and I am the travel stoner
on Twitter and yeah hopefully the next
time I'm on here I'm in the midst of
constructing my websites and hopefully
the next time that I'm on here I'll be
able to talk about that I would love to
troll your website sharing with
everybody you already know you guys
thank you both for coming on the show
Mike I hope to get you on the next
episode Lindsay we may have you here too
somebody asked me a question and it
directly says I hope you and Mike can
answer this so Mike you're here for that
one good listeners more feedback the
better we know what we know what to dig
up in which part of our ridiculous
amount of cannabis knowledge to throw at
you that's the truth if you've got
questions that you would like me to
answer or Mike or even Lindsay you can
send me questions grow from your heart
at hotmail.com let me know what you'd
like to know we will talk about it here
on the podcast we'll give you a shout
out if we don't happen to know a good
answer to your question we'll find the
person in the community who does and
drag them onto the podcast Mike you were
like my volleyball partner you set him
up and I will spike him bro speaking of
not knowing the answers to some things
people have asked me to do an episode
about LED lighting I personally have
never grown with LEDs I don't know [ __ ]
about LEDs I've got two friends they
claim they're gonna drive from Denver
and do an LED episode with me battle boy
I know one of them will show up I know
him personally the other guy I don't
know so I don't know if I can get him to
drive he lives about 130 miles from here
if he's willing to drive to the podcast
I'd love to get him on so maybe I'll get
both of those cats on and we'll do a
quick episode about LED lighting also
I'm trying to get in touch with the guy
that makes the 315 s I think I commented
on one of his Facebook post he did not
reply I'm not even sure it's the right
dude so I'm gonna get in touch with the
dude that makes it 3:15 the LEC is the
light emitting ceramic so we'll get that
guy on the podcast we'll talk about
those in the future also check this out
you guys have asked for an episode about
cannabis and pregnancy
I have done a lot of research there is
so much stuff out there I honestly I'm
not qualified to do an episode about
cannabis and pregnancy I'm not a doctor
I I'm not a woman and those are two
things that I feel like I should be at
least one of to do an episode about
pregnancy if you are either a doctor or
a woman or a woman doctor or if you've
got experience with cannabis and
pregnancy you know more than I do and
you're more comfortable with the subject
I'd love to get you on we could talk all
about it yeah I do only thing I could
throw in on that topic is the relevant
laws you might be breaking and the
repercussions you might face legally and
how that system works in places like
Colorado because I used will know I used
to read this all the time and in
patients charts when I work with locked
up teens so it's something that's gonna
follow your kid around for that life oh
man um if the hospital chooses to drug
test you or your baby during the
delivery and if you've got dreadlocks or
if you look like me as soon as it comes
out for the for the most part the system
works it's just if anybody involved in
the birthing process like that whole
hospital stay decides so yeah let's drug
test that mom and that baby then it
happens and it's just if anybody happens
to make that decision the local anti-pot
group down here they're working with one
of the hospitals and one they've got one
month worth of data and they're like
half the babies we tested came back
positive for THC and that's the end of
their statement if you dig a little
deeper ten babies were tested during
that period five of them came back
positive for THC doesn't tell you what
was up with the other five but it's part
of the National legalization
conversation like it could be a cool
episode we can find the right people
yeah I'm I don't have it's not my
wheelhouse I guess you know I literally
just had to look up all of these laws
because like I worked in the league or
work in the legal industry and had a kid
while I did that right what do you do
both of you who have been but tenders
Mike I don't know if we should or no
longer a budtender you worried but
tender Lindsay is about tender what do
you do if a pregnant customer comes in
and tries to buy cannabis it's perfectly
legal
to purchase it because he it will like
what happened with us is that I don't
are we gonna do this for this show
there's just something you brought up
randomly and all of a sudden this is
like a two-hour show now quick answer
what happens if absolutely they serve
turn no issues look when my wife was
pregnant she stopped at the gas station
a couple of times and bought me
cigarettes and like the second time she
did it she's like I if I could doing
that again what like I just wasn't
paying attention it's just something
she's done for forever
and I was like what and as I said what I
was like oh people judges yeah it
probably looks like there's a whole
bunch of stuff that you doctor tells you
you shouldn't consume or do while you're
pregnant and it's all legal
well not all cuz like heroin and coke
and [ __ ] around that way right but like
99% of it's legal and it's just not
advised so well if you are please you
know or even have more education on it
than I do and you're more comfortable
talking about it than I am I feel like
that's more of a woman's topic and I
should have a woman involved in this to
help me through this so that I don't
sound like a sexist dude that's
uneducated so let's get a doctor or or a
lady to come help me out this one I
would love to do this episode I'd love
to do it a lot of people have questions
I've gotten probably more than three
emails on this probably three to five
emails or questions about cannabis and
pregnancy so I'd love to get some help
on that one
you guys I think that's all that we have
got for you in this episode I want to
thank my friends again for coming and
hanging out with me thanks for having us
anytime I want to give a huge shout out
to max for getting me back on the Edible
bandwagon shot to shoot my bars banana
pudding hundred milligram THC bar set me
straight also shot it's my friends at
Gaia's garden jannat to make the dog
some kind of alarm going off it's it's
like shut up and see you in the show you
guys all right it's all I got for you
ladies and gentlemen I'd love it if
you'd send me some questions girl from
your heart at hotmail.com if you've got
a product you'd like me to review or if
you want to sponsor the show I'd love to
hear from you make sure you check out
the show on talk radio the shows now
available on Tok radio Wednesdays at
1:00 p.m. big shout out to my buddy's
citizen Jay also the show is available
on iTunes and stitcher and you can catch
the most 100 recent episodes on I read
genetics Colorado doc ladies and
gentleman that's all I've got for you
this week big shot at the bubble blaster
Cove big shot it's my ninja Spence and
until next time take the fat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
and Charlie
No
[Music]
much others
[Applause]
[Music]