welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 158 of the girl
from Earhart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if your new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated davor
if your cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jephunneh
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
whooping to letting use their music on
my podcast
big thanks to Kat - and the entire
mystic roots crew ladies and gentlemen
across the table from me once again is
our buddy white Mike how you doing today
bro I'm good bro I'm glad you recovered
from that dad you're not quite so purple
anymore yeah cut cut my breasts doing
good shout out to our friends at tiara
concentrate spoken on some Austar dogs
chatter what's the dab that you just
gave me a dab of the candy cush the
botanicals live resin Kent you know does
pretty tasty chef to those guys as well
Louie delicious
my mom about 200 milligrams deep on some
edibles right now we've been taking
plenty of dabs we're gonna bring you an
amazing podcast I promise you in this
episode we're gonna talk about an email
that I was sent a friend of ours in I
think he's in Michigan we'll verify that
in the email Michigan he is awaiting and
anticipating the legalization of
cannabis in his area and he wants to be
properly prepared and he wants to know
how to get a jump on things basically
and then he also he's got a legislation
question lined up for Mike and then he's
got a grow question lined up for me so
that'll probably take up most of the
episode and I'm also going to read a
Facebook post from somebody in the
cannabis community and I also hope to
get to an email you know we'll start
with that one cuz it'll be quick I hope
to get to an email a message that we
received from Instagram we'll probably
start with that but before we get that
far it might let everybody on that's
listening let everybody know how they
can stalk you
social media so they could check you out
while they listen to your handsome voice
you can find me on Twitter at at Nemo
Punk 15 or on Facebook
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws make
sure you support pueblos for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook you guys he
posts a lot of great stuff there give us
a like if you see something you like
give us a share we'd appreciate it help
us build the cannabis army all right
thanks for coming yeah man I I got a
pump well you said you had an email that
specifically requested you and me to
answer some stuff this is gonna be an
awesome question for anybody who's it's
moving forward with their marijuana laws
they called you white Mike specifically
so anyway I need you for this
yep they know it's a good question you
guys you're gonna want to listen to this
especially if you're in Michigan but
also if your state's just looking to go
medical or even recreational yes
everywhere that is getting ready or has
not yet this this could be informative
for you there's a lot of listeners I'm
bettin that could use the information
we're about to cover today yeah all
right before we get there I want to talk
about the breeding project that I keep
telling everybody about I am making I've
got an arise male if you haven't been
updated yet if you don't listen to the
show regularly I am breeding I am I
region it's breeding cannabis plants
yeah some breeding cannabis they're not
they're not goats or children if you
haven't been listening let's catch you
all the way about breeding
piranhas I'm breeding cannabis plants I
made the arize arises a strain that I
made it recently tested at 31% THC a it
is a cross of golden goat and a day
breaker it is a regular seat it is not
feminized IDUs test at 31 percent THC I
searched through about a hundred seeds
maybe more than a hundred to find the
male plant that I want I've got a really
killer male I have also got a few
phenotypes of females of the same strain
those are all in a room together the
male has been removed his pollen did its
thing the male has been pulled out of
there there is also a lemon skunk plant
in there there's a golden goat plant in
there for experimental reasons and there
is also a grateful dog plant in there
because I wanted to make the arize
crossed a grateful dog because those are
my two flagship that I'm known for right
- my favorite yes a lot - of a lot of
people's favorite so I put them together
we'll see what happens to that there
will not be any retail
dog to arise seeds for a long time I
made a very small batch of the project
folks yes do you rise however I just
made f2 the arize male hit the arise
females and I made f2 and by hitting
multiple phenotypes of the females I
have made a nice option for selection
for variation for my f3 so I'll get to
see what that plant what that what that
plant expresses in a lot of different
ways so I'll be able to pick a very good
male and a very good female to make the
f3 I'm actually my goal is to take this
to f5 and I'm trying not to rush it I
want to go through and find the exactly
the more time and the more plants is
sort of the better is the rule of thumb
in these projects yes you know my
encouragement is to go slow and as big
as possible selection is key when it
comes to this nope so I won if I believe
that if I hit multiple females with one
male and then I pull seeds from and I
keep them separate and then I find that
golden male I don't have to use say I've
got the females are labeled actually
what they actually are is there's number
4 okay the keepers the ones that are
going to survive to another run are four
eight and one that was lettered e from a
previous run those are the three that
are amazing phenotypes of a rise they
will answer those are your ladies yeah
those will stick around for a while
those that's the i3 the Irie three
around a little bit in the mail I call
him solemn and it's a rise he's a male
his name is Solomon I feel that alpha
shoo I'll see diversity and I may pick a
male from number three or II and then I
may pick a female from number four and I
may breathe that way which that's still
the same finial generation and it's
still the same genetic so I'm still
making F threes but it gives me a little
show a lot of variation and expressions
than you would have otherwise because
you're going as big as you are and I'm
trying to narrow it down to where it
almost looks like clones when you grow
these seeds by the time I get to f5 I
want to be able to say yeah it's gonna
look like this and it's basically a
clone that's that's my goal so that's
where I'm taking that they listens if
you're if you're not quite as nerdy as
we are what the long and the short of
what we're getting out of here the goal
all of this is to find the best of the
best of the best
yes and basically what that takes is a
lot of trial and error and a lot of
willingness to kill off plants and
towards the end or at the end the goal
is you'll be able to put a ten pack of
seeds in the ground and have all of them
come up very very very similar very
stable and that's what you're looking
for were for a market ready product and
that's not often what you get when
you're buying seeds a lot of what is
fair I'll say that that's fair a lot of
what is available and even a lot of what
I am making and what is available for
myself Aref ones which means that they
have not been f2 which means yeah it's I
took a male of one strain and a female
of another and I put pollen on it and it
made seeds and I tested them plenty
before they were released there are a
lot of seed companies that do that but
that's what a lot of my stuff is but
guys like DJ shoes the market standard
that's kind of yeah that's how cage mean
genetics does it that sort of [ __ ] my
head a 10 pack that's one of each strain
and it's like oh like her greenhouse
will sell you well I've seen it from a
number of the major companies where
you'll get it in one form and I've seen
it it's ten little plastic baggies right
here's one og so here's one Sour Diesel
here's one Northern Lights yeah like I
get one seed of that I mean just a trial
and error with germination alone makes
that silly yeah but when you know as
much as we do about like phenotypic
expression and plant stabilization and
that this is likely an f1 or maybe if
I'm lucky an f2 like god only knows what
I'm getting you know if I've only got
one C it'll make [ __ ] work well I've
seen people Bank on it like it's lemons
gunk that I have my lemons gunk that I
have came as a gift seed from somebody
else and I got one of them and it was a
gift from green from somebody else did
and they got it from green house seeds
and they got one I've grown a few killer
one offs and mud as well
and that that one that I kept that I
have is what I have bred the lemon
Geoffrey and cascade from one of your
first big breeding projects had a plant
I can never remember if it was the
Bubblegum with a grapefruit some of the
best stuff
smoke to this day and it was just the
one off that we couldn't find again
right yeah I say sometimes if I don't
like the way stuff grows or whatever it
is I remember it grew atrociously with
the flavor of it was just all the so up
my alley was the grapefruit yeah I
remember that one being a date I didn't
like the way it did its think plan I got
you if I don't like way plant grows I'll
just get rid of it because like we're
saying I've got so many seeds when I
just run more seeds to replace that and
have the best of the best you don't want
something that if you can find a 10 you
don't want a bunch of sevens around very
very true yeah all right so the breeding
project I am speaking of is
approximately 62 ish days tomorrow will
be tomorrow will be the start of week 10
so it's 63 days it's 9 weeks in which
means it's just about done I've been
taking out one I've taken out three I've
taken out four seeds now the fourth seed
looked completely ready so I'm letting
it ripen up and then tomorrow is Monday
hopefully if I get all of my work done
at a reasonable hour by the end of
Monday I may go in there and start
chopping down plants of the new arise f2
project I'm loving it
I'm excited for it it's just a small run
it won't take me a lot of trim in the
way I'll do it is I'm gonna cut down one
plant and then these ones uh yeah yeah
yeah the little time they're pretty
small plants yep so I'll cut them down
take off all the big leaves hang them
upside down let them dry until they're
fairly fairly crispy basically and then
just cut off a branch hold it over
either a Tupperware dish or a pie plate
and crumble it up just like a just like
a great crispy when you're harvest and
see ya just like you're gonna roll up
old school weed and just crunch it up
and let the seeds fall out and then pull
out the seeds pull out the material we
mason roll some joints with the dried
material but then a lot of its gonna get
turned into concentrates will have some
BHO coming up here in just a little
while but then all upset the seeds aside
let them dry out real well get them nice
and hard and then I will put them into
little packages I need to get some
packages from le containers calm and
then get those lined up get a few of
them into some packages and get them out
to my friends that test them out for me
and then I will grow a shit-ton it up
myself and I will see if the arize F
twos are worth growing worth making more
of or if I selected the wrong mail then
I'll go back and find another boy in
[ __ ] try again but since I've used
multiple females I'll keep all the
female separate keep the seeds separated
and I will run comparisons of batch a
batch B batch C and I will see which
ones I like better so that I could find
my breeders I'm gonna do a lot of
research and a lot of work and a lot of
look in before I even continue we funny
even think about making an f2 I want to
really see what the f are before I make
an f3 I wanna see what the f2 s really
really do so it's almost time to take
those down probably tomorrow night when
I get done doing all my work then I
would you guys know how they grow you
know I'll talk about that on the show so
anyone looking forward to it me too me
too I'm really excited about this if you
can't tell I've been talking about for a
long time so I want to talk about one
more thing before we get into some of
the main topics a couple of so let me go
way far back about a year and a half ago
club we're coming up on two years almost
a year and three quarters ago I hit my
head I hit the [ __ ] out of my head
ah long story short I hit my head on a
low doorway I'm six five the doorway was
probably six three I was walking fast
enough to her when I hit the top of my
head on this doorway it knocked me clean
the [ __ ] out I was walking to some
stairs I hit my head knocked myself out
completely unconscious I went spaghetti
and fell down the stairs while I was
completely unconscious I'd have a couple
of friends wake me up carry me up the
stairs get me in a chair trying to get
my [ __ ] back together I was broken you
guys I had a traumatic brain injury I
had some serious problems my vision was
not right my brain was not right my word
association wasn't happening properly ah
my my name's I couldn't remembers
people's names like my best friend's
would be sitting at the table I couldn't
tell you what the [ __ ] their names were
I was broken I was having problems I was
having physical problems related to it
like my body would not regulate its
temperature it was wintertime uh and I
was running around in just like a
t-shirt and everyone's in coats and [ __ ]
and they're looking at me like do kind
of drugs or you wanna look head injury
no drugs I'm just [ __ ] sweaty all the
time now like it would not stop being
overheated but something that was also
funky was my vision my vision would get
wobbly sometimes like if I would watch
certain like animated [ __ ] or certain TV
shows filmed a certain way my vision
would get weird and I just have to quit
watching it certain video games and [ __ ]
with my head if I don't really play
video games but if I watch other people
play some games have messed with my head
ah nothing's really messed with me for a
little while I was having dizzy spells a
little while for a little while but
everything's pretty much back to normal
I think I'm back on track from all that
until I recorded that episode at elevate
a couple of weeks ago if you guys listen
to the podcast I want to elevate and
recorded a show there is a rig there by
an artist named Matt Cameron no it's not
man yeah his name's Cameron Reed let me
correct myself
I think Matt Cameron is a drummer that I
watched a video from the other day but
the dude's name is Cameron Reed Cameron
Reed glass on Instagram this dude made a
rig and the work is called read a cello
already work is what they call it and
it's just clear glass with white lines
through it and it's [ __ ] beautiful so
I saw this rig and when I stared at the
rig it started moving it had kind of a
Christmas ornament glass kind of quality
to it if if that helps describe it for
the listeners it's trippy to my brain
dude it makes my brain do weird [ __ ]
when I look at it it looks like it's
moving all of those wines look like
they're spinning around like Tron it's
like wah wah and when I started
everybody kind of looked at me like I
was crazy
and I was like oh you gotta quit looking
at that like cuz you're the only one
seeing that okay I'm gonna walk away
from this but then I posted on Facebook
basically my experience is like I fell
in love with this rig unfortunately you
guys this rig is I looked at the price
tag from underneath because the price
tags on the bottom and the glut the
shelf it's sitting on his glass so I
could see through it
it's either twenty one hundred or twenty
four hundred dollars I couldn't read if
that was a one or a four ah that's not
in my budget to spend on a glass rig to
tell you the damn truth I would be
awesome to have I would just stare at it
and take dad's out of it and stare at it
some more so I mentioned this on
Facebook I posted up to Facebook and to
Instagram I pretty much told the same
story hit my head yeah my eyes were
[ __ ] up and then I saw this rig and I
was mesmerised in that I'm in love with
it so I posted a picture of the rig and
the artist that made the rig contacted
me and sent me a sweet pendant he sent
me a disc pendant it's probably the size
it's bigger than a silver dollars just a
little bit bigger than a silver dollar
or yeah a little bigger than a silver
dollar it's got some great ready work
it's got a it's gonna [ __ ]
it's gonna open the middle of it I
always forgot the name of the opals it's
gonna opal in the middle of it I wore it
on a chain to the secret sesh the other
night and everybody told me how dope my
pen D was and you know what guys with
blue eyes
all of my friends with blue eyes and
blonde hair or like close to the ginger
side of life all of them would look at
it and they would make the same [ __ ]
memorise mesmerised face that I make and
a friend of mine is she does I stuff I
always say the name for a career wrong
but she does I stuff and she's like well
I could teach you why it was like no I
don't want to learn about my eyes cuz if
you tell me what my eyes are doing I'll
start feeling it and it'll [ __ ] with me
I don't want to know you say I stuff are
we talking like American Medical
Association
no no she wears scrubs and rub some nog
chomp on your face and she works with a
very well-known doctor here yes she's
professional she's mad as [ __ ] what she
does she's proud of what she did so
shout out good work I love that there's
a style oh yeah but but she this my
friend knows why blonds yeah she knows
she can explain why it's something with
the rods and cones and my blue eyes that
do it but Cameron Reid glass dude thank
you for the sweet pendant I loved it I
thought it was dope as [ __ ] it does move
it spins around just like that rig that
you made bro so it's awesome if I hold
it still in the palm of my hand it looks
like it's [ __ ] spinning and it's so
awesome I love it thank you thank you a
lot I hope you hear this I hope somebody
takes really dope or tells you to listen
to this podcast somehow I appreciate it
also show all my friends at elevate
glass cuz that's where I saw it make
sure you guys follow Cameron Reed glass
he makes sweet glass and he's a cool ass
dude so Chyna I appreciate that was a
cool [ __ ] gift to open up the mailbox
one day and find this cool all my
friends loved it too the secret stash so
and the dopest pin at the sesh alright
oh let's get to the the main topic of
this podcast
holy screenshots here because I like to
screenshot the messages it makes it much
easier for me to find them it really
does we've got a really quick message
this one came from Instagram um usually
I don't see the names but this dude he's
from North Carolina and his name is
Carolina cannabis so follow him on
Instagram he says what's something I can
use for food for plants beside by
besides buying nutrients in a bottle
growing outdoors in North Carolina only
a few weeks of flowering left
surprisingly buds are decently fat but I
know she's probably hungry for something
I'm gonna try to get this episode out to
you as soon as we can
because you need this information pretty
quickly pronto um you say only a few
weeks left of flowering so you need to
be can't do anything in a bottle so
you're looking for like around the house
but but then the grower in me says Jesse
is on the coast right now having a good
time I think Jesse's in Portland is
where I think he is so boy shout out bro
hope you're having a good time yeah so
Mike Mike nailed what I thought most
people would say you want to use some
guano's you're gonna want to use some
alfalfa meal you're gonna want to use
something like that but you've only got
a couple of weeks left so you don't want
to pump a whole bunch of stuff into the
plants and if most of those organic
products are gonna take at least two
weeks to four weeks to closer to six or
eight yeah there's some good news though
net nature wise the plants supposed to
have used up most of what's around it by
now yes like that's as intended so but
there are a couple of things that you
can do if you don't want to go buy
bottles you've only got a few weeks left
so keep in mind that you're gonna want
to flush even outdoors you need to flush
your plants you need a time period where
they're not receiving any nutrients so
that they can start to get rid of the
[ __ ] that's stored up in them so that
your buds burn and taste and smell
perfectly at the right time so keep that
in mind
give yourself hopefully ten to 14 maybe
15 to 16 maybe 20 days I like to flush
for a long time well if you haven't been
feeding up to this point either you
don't want to hit him with too much now
you'll shock down you probably if he
says he knows there
probably hungry for something and if he
hasn't boosted them up they probably are
and what I would recommend if you want
to feed them something like I said
earlier some guano's would be cool some
stuff like that would be cool but some
comfrey would be nice maybe make up an
iced tea that's probably your best bet
make a tea um a tea with some worm
castings somehow falfa meal in there
maybe put a little tiny bit of molasses
in there just to keep it moving and then
any sort of kelp meal or something make
a tea out of that and this is just
coming to me so I'm trying to go as
smoothly as I can here maybe put some
I'm not sure what all you are willing to
use either but kelp meal would
definitely help you get some bulk and
some flavor maybe put some fish Hydra
sleights in there that would help you
all with some nitrogen and that's a pop
if you make a tea like this brew it up
for just a couple of few days and if you
need instructions on making a tea send
me an email and we'll try to get Jesse
on here to help us with that but I'll
answer you you sent me this message on
Instagram so send me a message on
Instagram and hopefully I can run you
through making a tea it's really easy
but make it tea feed the plants the tea
if you can't make a tea then some basic
fish hydrous lates in a bottle I would
work for that put some water into a
five-gallon bucket put a little more
than what the label says a fish hide
relates in there mix it up real well put
some molasses in there mix that up
and then maybe some kelp any sort of
kelp product that you can put in there
liquid kelp would be more available but
that's a bottled product if you don't
want to do that I think a tea would be
your best way to go Jesse and I have
done episodes about making teas that is
a thing that's available if you don't
want to search for that send me a
message I'll either find it for you or I
will reply to you on a delivery I was
just doing the math in my head this is
gonna come out um if this show doesn't
come out immediately
um he's he's only got three weeks from
when recording it at most of Gro time
left if he's on the East Coast if I've
got my numbers right my ass some of our
friends in Colorado are actually
harvesting this music I started having
higher up in elevation than we are down
here in Pueblo that are a little further
up into the foothills harvest began last
week
and I mean they're dipping below 50 at
night this just what's up the plants are
done you should see him they're huge I
actually went to two different grows one
that was about 700 feet higher up in
elevation than the other and I went to
the higher one first buds were almost
done they they were gonna give him three
more days at harvest I drove down the
road a few hundred feet and buds were
three weeks from harvest Wow just a
little bit closer to the Sun yep in
which change our side okay so we did we
both had to think about that yeah
because well the mounds are west and so
I had to quick do the direction I'm
going people like how do you always know
where you're going mountains are right
over there all the time if you've been
in Colorado since Mike was talking for a
second I got a chance to write this down
if you need to make a tea get yourself a
five gallon bucket get a clean bucket go
to Lowe's pay a couple bucks get a clean
bucket
I'll get yourself go to the hydro store
or the fish store get some an air pump
that pumps out quite a bit Eric it's
yourself one of those air stones put the
air stone in the bucket where fill the
bucket with water if you can put the air
stone in there and get that air stone
pumping that water with a lot of oxygen
for 24 hours before you do anything your
goal here is to get the chlorine out of
that water that's what you're trying to
do so bubble that get the chlorine out
the next day
add some worm castings add some alfalfa
sprouts add some kelp meal and add a
little tiny bit of molasses let that
bubble for like 24 hours it's gonna get
foamy expected to get foamy it will foam
up like a beer and go everywhere if
you're not careful it may or may not it
depends on your witch's brew the
proteins in the fish hydro slates I
didn't write fish I dress let's put fish
hydro slates in there the proteins the
fish poo this smell out of this carp at
one time so just fair warning listeners
be careful with your witch's brew does
the first time you make it because
sometimes it foams up like a song yes
what I would recommend this will make
enough so if you use this 5 gallon
bucket you could probably cut this in
half or if you're going outdoor you just
put a little five-gallon bucket on there
if you want to but it's getting toward
the end of the season keep that in mind
it's
huge so take take your five gallon
bucket pour the buck put the bubble fill
it with water put the bubble in there
bubble it long enough to get the
chlorine off then you pour in the fish
Hydra sleights worm castings alfalfa
sprouts is that the right one is that
what I want to use I think that's what
you want
kelp meal and molasses pour those things
in there there are more things that you
could use you can use crab meal you can
bone use bone meal you can use fish meal
if you want to those things are not all
necessary put that in there let that
[ __ ] stew around in that bubbles for
like 12 to 24 hours it's gonna make a
bunch of foam us do it in the garage if
you have to do it somewhere it's easy to
clean up door you're not worried about a
bunch of foam if it does not fall up
that does not mean it's bad let it
bubble up then go outside and pour it on
your plants not on the plants zone and
water your plants with it don't go near
the stock go out because your roots that
eat the most and drink the most are the
ones that are on the outer perimeter of
the plant not right there at the stock
the part of the stock is always gonna
have some moisture down there at the
bottom go on the outer edge that's where
you're growing or it's are the plants
are reaching out for stuff so keep go
out there a little bit so your best bet
is to make a tea water with this tea and
then hopefully you'll see a little bit
of boost in there the fish hydro slates
are gonna give you a little bit of
nitrogen the worm castings are gonna
give you microbes and it's gonna help
everything the worm castings will
provide a little tiny bit of nitrogen
but they'll also speed everything up the
alfalfa meal is going to give you
nitrogen that's readily available to
kelp meal I just think that that makes
everything stink it makes it smell
better it makes it taste better and it
adds tonight so organic growers one of
the first thing that comes up is killed
yeah the ocean products are always gonna
make your stuff taste better in my
opinion
and then molasses molasses will actually
feed all of the worm casting microbes
and it will also feed your plants a
little bit as well so that's what you
can do outdoors but also keep in mind
bro it's time to start flushing so
you're right at the end of your clock
but and sorry we didn't get this
question sooner and out to you sooner
I'm not blaming anything on Jessie but
man Jessie was busier [ __ ] this year so
we didn't do many outdoor episodes
Jessie next year you know Jessie let's
just sit down and record a whole season
of outdoors get him once and do 11
episodes yeah he's hard to nail down he
came by the other day and smoked me down
with some distillate that his company's
making
the last time I saw him in person I
asked and how's it's going any went on
for like 45 minutes about projects he's
currently working on
I mean he's easily one of the three
busiest people I know
yes Shaza to our friend Carolina
cannabis on Instagram makes you guys
follow him check out his beautiful
cannabis growing skills and photography
and dude thank you for the message feel
free to send me more messages I want to
see how your grow comes out I want to
know if I answered your question in the
way you needed to answer to anybody else
that has a message please send it to me
it would be easiest if you initiate a
conversation by sending me an email to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com if
we're already corresponding on another
social media platform keep it going it's
easiest just to keep one conversation
happening because if you jump to another
platform I'm gonna forget confused but
if your new go-to girl for me aren't at
hotmail.com that's the best way to get
in touch with me and I'll get your
questions on an upcoming episode I'm
trying to get through the questions
quickly because I know some of the
questions are urgent cuz you got plants
growing or need [ __ ] to happen so I'm
trying to get on it trying to do more
episodes for you so I've got another
thing I want to read before I get to the
basement and legislation question that
I've got I saw something on Facebook the
other day and I thought it was very
entertaining right after I did an
episode about trim machines on a recent
episode we talked about trim machines
and I kind of bashed the [ __ ] out of
them somebody said which trim machine to
buy and I said don't buy a bunch of
[ __ ] scissors and get your friends
over basically what I told them cuz
that's really what I think you should do
that's preach it brother
somebody on Facebook I don't know if he
wants to be named or not he's known as
soda pop ah
he says upcoming crop Tober helpful
hints and we call it crop Tober yes
October is crop Tober in Colorado
everybody needs a trimmer everybody got
some [ __ ] trim yeah every californiaís
so I've seen trimming trimming grant
memes trimmed rents are coming so a
helpful crop tober or upcoming crop
Tober helpful hints and this dude says
number one if you want to process your
trim into quality meds
please do not use a machine trimmer oils
from machine and the beaten trim lead to
unsightly slabs so he's saying that
there's oils actually in the trim
machine on the blades of the trim
machine on the metal parts of the trim
machine that
it's got to be looking so firmer I have
ever used yep so those oils will end up
on your trim and and that beaten-up trim
like I said before it turns into
basically mulch and that when the trim
is cut into so many pieces it's um when
you cut it with scissors you cut it one
time you cut that leaf off the plant
I mean maybe three or four I mean it
must but you're not you can like you
know you're not turning it into pet
you're not lawnmower yeah this true
machine is hitting it to picture and
just mulching all your little pieces and
that leaves that many spots for moisture
that much surface area for moisture and
that many spots for chlorophyll to come
out you want you want to hit it with
scissors but so then I mean it's it's
not good it does juice it and then that
juice ends up in your hash and it tastes
like [ __ ] and looks like [ __ ] and then
number two he says if you plan to
process the nug please flush correctly
and no spring or pesticides whatsoever
these chemicals and nutrients tend to
leach into concentration and lead to
unsightly slabs so he's saying flush
properly flush correctly he's using
slightly and there's a lot implied there
especially in a market like Colorado's
yes if you've sprayed your plants with
just about anything while they're in
flower and it's processed into a
concentrate that concentrates not gonna
pass testing and make it onto the market
most of the people he's talking about I
think he's talking about these black
market street growers right I had no
spring but absolutely if you're gonna
make concentrates think about this you
guys you're gonna spray some [ __ ] okay
you're spraying what's what does
everybody use in like a Xamax is
probably one of the most popular things
when I worked in the dispensary our area
every I've toured a couple of
dispensaries and all of them have a
Xamax on the shelf that's what like the
most common spray and we're gonna talk
about something that has a max is gonna
do in a future episode that I've got
written down but everyone's got the azza
max
I'm sure now you spray as it's kind of
waxy it's kind of oily you spray as max
onto your plants it like probably I
don't know week two week three that
shits in the middle of your buds as your
bud grows around it that waxy oily
concentration is still there and the
buds just grow around it and it's still
inside there then the buds dry and he
grind it up and you run it through an
extraction machine to wash it off
you can actually see that little layer
of a Xamax
right on top of your concentrate
sometimes I've seen it I've seen it
float to the top I have [ __ ] tasted
it like I've been in rooms that have
chives spring I've I didn't know any
better when I started growing but
remember back in the day when we did not
know any better who would spray whatever
the [ __ ] the dudes the Hydra I've got
this problem spray this okay and then
you read five years later like this
causes immediate blindness if you touch
it like oh [ __ ] I used to spray that
like I've sprayed these things I've also
smelled them I did because other
people's products neem oil is a big one
it's God it's something a lot of the
organic or the natural people who like
to use at one point or another
if you flour my face puckered out a
little when you submitting its everybody
that the consumes cannabis at one point
or another has hit a bowl and all they
tasted for the next hour was neem they
might not have known what it was but
it's I mean that's incredibly common
just quit spray and [ __ ] that's in Flour
terrible terrible terrible
manjo environment yeah so uh flushed
correctly and don't spray [ __ ] on
your plants if you're trying to make
concentrates out of it you know that's a
general rule if you're trying if you're
going to use if you're making medicine
or something you want other people to
consume flush properly and don't spray
[ __ ] on your plants number three take
proper care of nug and trim that would
be you for use in extracts proper cure
care cleaning and basic hygiene of the
plant and material are critical for
quality meds you guys one thing that I
don't see enough of is people wearing
nitrile or rubber gloves where are some
gloves you don't want all your finger
skin in my concentrates
or on my flowers when you're trimming
that [ __ ] is sticky where are some
gloves please I don't want to smoke your
skin flakes we're bros we're friends I
love you I do not want to smoke your
[ __ ] hands also take care of stuff
just cuz it's gonna get turned into hash
doesn't mean you can trim your trim your
leaves and do a tarp on the floor and
have the whole crew walk on them during
trim time and then sweep them up and
make a shadow that's [ __ ] gross trim
that into a container take care of it
that's somebody's medicine you may make
edibles out of it
think about like looking at all as
something that you're going to put into
your mouth and if you're one of them
dirty [ __ ] people to Lygia off the
floor
look at it is something that a princess
has to put in their mouth because it's
got to be clean products also cure your
[ __ ] just cuz you're gonna blast it I
understand live resin let's get it on
well there was that weird thing at the
beginning of the butane hash days where
you made BHO with this stuff you
couldn't use the stuff that was trashed
right I remember people saying some
crazy [ __ ] like oh that's moldy just
blast powdery mildew doesn't exist
anymore since we have pho right but if
you want to make good concentrates you
really have to produce bud that's ready
to go on a store shelf
yes and then make concentrates from that
out of that bomb and I see so many
people that [ __ ] up that last step it's
like buying a Lamborghini and Wrekin it
like in the light you're not even off
the lot yet any record if you spent nine
weeks flowering and then you just spend
a week harvesting and I'm just gonna
[ __ ] it up yeah you continue to roll up
the trash once you flush that plant you
can cut it down and knock off most of
the big leaves and if you plan on
blasting the entire plant
hang it up let it excuse me amber pent
up some dr. pepper hang it upside down
let it dry and cure cut it off the
sticks take the sticks out of there and
then you've pretty much got blasted bull
material you can't really [ __ ] that up
so just take care of it keep it clean
wear gloves you wouldn't believe some of
the stuff that I have seen and heard of
coming in from like grows coming into
extraction labs people have found
cigarette butts scissors razor blades
Forks from launch like all kinds of [ __ ]
in the material it was so bad
two years ago when we started
implementing lab testing that a number
of extract companies just went out and
bought the hundred thousand or two
hundred to three hundred thousand pieces
of equipment so that they could in-house
test [ __ ] as it came in because it was
some of the stuff they were processing
was so nasty
it was [ __ ] up their machines and so
they processed the dude for the first
guy or the material for the first guy in
the morning it dirties up the machine
everybody else that gets run that day is
taking home a piece of that trash that
came through in just a little residual
sink so now they're testing all before
it goes into the end of their
machineries so that none of that's
possible anymore
that's disgusting thinking about
somebody another farm running some stuff
and this is mazza max in there and then
my farm run on this clean organic
product in there and just mixing it up
and now I've got your as a max residuals
that's gonna grow so completely that's
when I see stuff like black market stuff
whether like just got some awesome SAP
and you look at it and it's black and
soupy and it god only knows what's in it
I mean we're so lucky here that we've
got lab tests
so let's some regulation that we can get
away from that I wish it was more
available to the recreational grower lab
testing isn't as available but in the
future it will be yep that's one of the
things that we're I'm gonna hit coming
up in this last question all right so to
speak perfect timing we're 36 minutes
into this podcast and we have not gotten
to the main topics so ah
shout out to soda pop for the cool of
Facebook post at the end heat hashtag
that the Machine knows the truth so
supports my claims that trim machines
suck don't use a trim machine take care
of your plants and take care of the trim
and ugh if you plan to make x-ray she's
good luck out there this crop Tober
season i hope your plants made it I hope
but none of them got stolen I hope yeah
it's that time of year we call it crops
over we also call it holy season right
now yeah Ripper season I've seen some
social media stuff already if they took
your [ __ ] they're not your homie well
right now it's it's getting close to
harvest if you're growing outdoors in
any way shape or form it's smelling
you're freaking out just take some deep
breaths relax your [ __ ] getting stolen
is not the worst thing that can happen
to you
if you did take your [ __ ] I hope they
left part of it for you I hope they were
a cool theif and if he had four plants I
hope they only took one it's it's just
unfortunate that we still have to deal
with this yes
all right so I wish we could just go
outside nobody comes to steal the
tomatoes in the backyard why are they
stealing cannabis when cannabis is
somebody's cancer medicine you know that
shitty it's just worth so much in
certain places it's I mean it's like
leaving your your bank account in the
backyard at some place yeah nobody
ballistas to the show would steal any
plants well let's jump into this email
that I got this email the student signed
his name dabbe Smiths and he says hey
what's up Rasta Jeff huge fan of the
podcast as I've said before he said I
had a few questions I thought could be a
podcast I'm in Michigan and we just
passed three bills pushing us into a
seed to sale system based on Colorado
system I'm gonna quickly talk about that
in Colorado we have a seed to sale
system everything that is for sale
recreational or medically in the state
of Colorado has been grown from seed or
a clone underneath a Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division camera inside of a
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
regulated facility also known as an
optional premises cultivation facility
everything that happens in there every
square [ __ ] inch of this facility is
on camera they have it set up to where
if you can be in that building and there
is a spot where you're not on camera you
have to put another camera if you can
hide around this little partition or
behind this door they want another
camera in there so that you cannot hide
anywhere so everything that happens in
there is on camera which that's where
the seed part starts if you grow a seed
it's on camera if you grow a clone it is
on camera it is a given an RFID tag we
call those a med tag you have to tag
every single plant and put it into a
system known as metric then they are
tagged they are accounted for they are
part of your plant count that you're
allowed to have um when a regular walks
into a room they've got a tool they can
just hold up and press the button and it
tells them exactly how many plants are
in that room yes because of the RFID on
those plant tags I mean everything is
tracked out ridiculously ridiculously so
as those plants grow there they are now
cloned in my computer system if they
when I put them into bigger pots now
they have to be
in two veg if I move them to another
room they have to be marked in this
little tab on the computer what room
they move into when I move them into
flower I have to move them I have to
change their room I have to change their
status and I have to mark that all the
tags are still the same numbers
everything stays on camera when it's
harvested all of the trimmers are in a
room guess what they're all on camera
everything is done on camera it's
trimmed the trim is kept in one area if
the trash is weighed all of the trash is
weighed before it's thrown away so that
we know and everything is weighed I cut
down the plant put it on a scale hand it
to the trimmers they separate buds and
sticks and trim we weigh the buds we
weigh the trim we weigh the trash we
throw the trash away the trash is
documented in the marijuana Enforcement
Division computer which is known as
metric so everything is on camera then
it is put into specific weight packages
the packages are documented in a
computer with the tag number on it that
tag again has an RFID code on it then
they are put into what's called a
manifest a transfer manifest then that
transfer manifest has the vehicle
operators name driver's license number
license plate number vehicle make model
description then you have to type in the
exact route that you are traveling
leaving this street turning left on this
street right onto this street to the
destination then once you get there it
is unpacked and checked on camera by the
dispensary that it's taken to then it's
put on a shelf all under camera then it
is sold all under this day yes
everything is recorded and covered and
there's absolutely no room for leakage
the only time that anything could happen
is in a vehicle but if you're following
marijuana enforcement division rules
every package that leaves the growth
facility is vacuum sealed in a vacuum
bag with a marijuana Enforcement
Division sticker on it that has a
specific weight written on it with a
stream name on it and then that is also
on a paper that matches that tag number
that has the corresponding X I can't
even tell you how many hundreds of
shipments in my day and not one of them
was off by anything ever right yeah well
you can't if they're in those vacuum
sealed bags and I open it in the car
while I'm driving there's no way for
this is laser night
yeah so that's that's and that's the
only opportunity really and it's not
gonna happen nobody's gonna get away
with it you're gonna get caught if you
do that stupid [ __ ] highly highly highly
highly regulated is what we're gonna get
yes now that was one of the three bills
they just passed is a seed to sale
regulatory assist and it works it
actually works so this it sounds
stringent and it sounds ridiculous but
when we have problems like we've
recently talked about on the show there
have been batches of concentrates that
have been made with flowers that were
sprayed with pesticides that were not
allowed since each plant was tracked and
when we apply a pesticide we write down
every tag number that that pesticide is
applied to or a foliar spray or any type
of everything that happens to them so
they could see that everything grown in
facility number four zero three
extracted by extraction company four
zero two and there's be dashes at the
end of those everything from that batch
was contaminated at plant tag number one
thousand six five five five through
1,000 in the stage whatever releases the
list retailers check the serial numbers
on their product and you know instantly
if you're carrying some tainted products
campus or hash or edibles or topical
defense we'll also you can follow all of
it from or agenda to retail and back so
it's absolutely helpful even though it
seems really weird it seems you know
once it took me a couple of months of
working with but after like a month or
two of doing metric every single day I
was like this is easy it's just what you
do it becomes part of your routine no
you just treat your workday like chess
moves yeah and as soon as you accept
that you're good to go well I would make
notes on a little piece of paper of
things that I needed to do in metric as
I did it and then I would go to the
office and just catch up metric right
before lunch and then go back and catch
up metric right before I leave at the
end of the day or when it got down to
cutting clones and doing things that
needed a lot of metric attention I had a
little cart and I would just take my
macbook to work and sign into metric
right there and just do it on the card
it was it was second nature by the time
I was done there so the seed to sale
system is definitely helpful I think
it's gonna work I'm gonna continue with
the email because this is gonna be a
long damn podcast if I don't he said
mission
we passed three bills pushing us into a
seat of sale system based on Colorado
system I was wondering if you and white
Mike could touch on the subject like how
do I go about finding out information
from the city about how many license
facilities they will allow and then he
also says what's the biggest hurdle
going from a basement grow to a
warehouse which i think is more directed
at me then he continues to say I know
you have recently made the switch from
soil to cocoa and any advice on that
transition I am planning on running veg
bloom and I'm already in a basement but
do you add anything else to the wine as
well what are some things you didn't
expect going to such a large scale and
any other advice you may think one would
need to know about taking a leap into
the big leagues thanks again for such a
great podcast I hope you can answer some
questions for me and other other
questions others I'm not sure how you
wanted to end that but yes will answer
your question bro all that might go with
the first part I've got a lot of stuff
to say first of all lawyer up if you're
gonna give me the canvas not [ __ ]
with you and then get a lawyer to keep
an eye on your accountant you know get
to your lawyers in an accountant to make
sure they're all [ __ ] keeping an eye
on each other that's that's my first bit
of emphasis that should really be like
the first half of like every business
school 101 class yes lawyer and don't
let it be too good a friends make
hopefully your lawyer in your accountant
don't seem like they like each other
because then they can't team up on you
um they don't you don't want them
embezzling from you just keep them
watching each other I think he's
stealing from you I think he's stealing
from you just keep him like that people
watch it so Mike the first question how
do we go about finding out information
from the cities how many license
facilities they will allow before we
before we hit record we I jumped online
we jumped online and checked out some of
the stuff about your law in Michigan
local control is part of it and so and
this is from the cannabis
surprise-surprise reported here in
Colorado but according to the cannabis
the local control part in Michigan's law
is growers processors shippers testing
facilities and dist
dispensaries
could not obtain a state license unless
their local government adopts an
authorizing ordinance municipalities
could cap the number of licenses within
their borders and assess no more than a
five thousand dollar fee per license a
state board would charge application and
renewal fees to cover costs including
for substance abuse programs in law
enforcement so basically what that means
is you're gonna need two licenses to
open any sort of marijuana business in
Michigan and now we're talking about
medical marijuana businesses here
recreational is not quite legal in
Michigan yet I don't think so
if your local area does not create some
sort of licensing process for these
businesses you can't get a state license
to operate in that area so how do you
find out what those rules are in your
area the first step is head to your
local Planning and Zoning hop online
spend a few seconds with Google figure
out where you're planning the Zoning
Department is and while you're there you
can want to look up City Council or
county commissioner whichever sort of
governing body decides the land use
rules for your area for example here in
Pueblo Colorado in the city we have a
city council who makes those decisions
and then in the county of Pueblo we have
a Board of County Commissioners these
people are totally separate and have
totally different rules for marijuana
businesses because they're totally
separate governmental entities I assume
it's very similar in Michigan so first
step is figure out which municipality
city county whatever you want to have
your marijuana businesses in head down
to planning and zoning or City Council
or whatever and ask is is your first
step and because this is brand new
you're likely to get to be met with a
confused look which means you've got
some work ahead of you if you're lucky
the area you're in has favorable
government officials who saw this coming
and have already crafted some sort of
land-use code
I'm specifying which zoning designations
the property for these businesses have
to carry distances from schools
libraries churches those kinds of rules
if they haven't gotten that far yet
you're looking at a year or more of
public hearings while these rules get
hashed out so like I said you've got
some work ahead of you this is where I
sort of got my activist credentials in
pueblo was helping pueblos do all of
this so when you've checked with
Planning and Zoning to see a if your
area has these rules yet and if not how
they're being created the next thing to
do is get yourself involved in that
conversation it's really easy to do
especially as these rules are being
crafted whatever governmental agencies
crafting this rules will take a lot of
public comment so you get the
community's input how far they want them
from schools how high the licensing fees
should be if they want to add any sort
of other rules and regulations for
example there's an area in Colorado that
requires marijuana businesses to be a
hundred percent energy neutral which
means they can't consume electricity
they don't also generate wrap your head
around that one in a county that doesn't
allow outdoor growing but get involved
with these in this conversation now and
that way you can help nudge or guide the
regulator's as they write the rules for
your area if you're smart you'll help
them steer clear of business number caps
and things like that that's really
really really bad for business
it just creates monopolies right it
immediately creates a monopoly it forces
the local municipality to to do a bunch
of obnoxious things like having a
license lottery and some sort of review
process for applicants that's
additionally unnecessary I mean it
creates a real legislative and practical
nightmare for the the government agency
trying to do it and yet in Colorado they
continue to do it all over and over and
over again but just give
all that this conversation now and now
with in all likelihood you'll be able to
steer whatever local government agency
that's writing these rules into crafting
smart rules for your agencies so that
you're not looking at huge licensing
fees I like that they have a cap in the
state rules at five grand I've seen it
as high as 50 here in counties and
cities this state only charges five or
seven or ten depending on the size of
your license but I've seen individual
counties charge much much more than that
so he's gonna need a ton of money a
lawyer an accountant no he said Planning
and Zoning and City Council he also
joined forces with his local marijuana
activist groups that that depends on the
climate in your area if you go down to
Planning and Zoning and are greeted by a
really friendly person who hands you a
printout of the rules they've already
crafted and all you have to do is fill
out the application and find a piece of
property that's zoned appropriately and
get a rental agreement will Congrats bro
you live in a really enlightened area
but what's likely to happen is you're
gonna be met with a confused look and
they're only gonna just be creating
these rules now and so if that's the
case your best bet is to start attending
County meetings zoning meetings just
watching how those meetings take place
I'm getting a feel for the people in
charge of those meetings who's on your
City Council who's on your Board of
County Commissioners or your Zoning
Board
what are they like and dislike and I
basically it just takes a lot of sitting
and watching I mean watching walls get
made is incredibly boring but they're
legalizing marijuana across the country
we have to write all those laws if you
don't want really really messed up laws
written by people who don't understand
what we're doing and what we're working
with
stand back and wait for somebody else to
do it
I mean some of the rules that were
proposed here in Colorado during this
process we're asinine and it took a
while for people like myself to explain
to legislators why it was asinine
because I face value a lot of them
seemed like a good idea
when you take it into practice like the
last episode we talked about edibles
labeling they were ready to get rid of
all drinks just we'll get rid of them
period it's never been a problem
anywhere but we're gonna cut out a
massive majors edibles industry um just
for no reason at all or the people that
are making these rules are not consumers
they are not producers they're just
people they're a lot of time so they
don't know anything about it their best
their background is in like finance and
they were a dentist for 20 years or some
[ __ ]
they don't know anything about mass
production of cannabis retail rules what
those rules might be for alcohol and
tobacco retailers why little tweaks to
those rules are appropriate for cannabis
I mean getting them to understand all
that can be quite a bit of work
and it probably got some fear in them
also well yeah they've you have to go
into this knowing that most of the
people you talk to we're the hall
monitor not to be a dick about it but
that's yeah when you start going to city
government meetings you're like that's
what happened to all those people from
high school they just disappeared from
my world after graduate they've got jobs
in city government that's where they all
went yeah they're all Jeff went on tour
all these people got jobs at their local
zoning department and have worked their
way through the ranks of city
bureaucracy for twenty years those are
the people you're dealing with and
they're not bad people most of them are
wonderful but they don't really know
anything about marijuana they don't know
why we consume it they don't know why
it's fun at concerts they just know it
gives them a headache when they go see
popular music and that's really the
extent of their education so getting
them to understand that moving all
marijuana production indoors is
incredibly bad for the environment when
especially when cannabis can be grown so
effectively outdoors how that
conversation we fail that having a lot
of places in Colorado which is why
Pueblo County's so popular with
production facilities right now we're
too loaded yep one of the few places you
can grow outdoors and we're one of the
few places you can grow in greenhouses
and we're one of the few places where
Lane isn't ridiculously expensive I mean
we've got the trifecta down here and
that's why we have so many companies
locating and it's changing B the whole
landscape here you could tell that
there's some money here now we didn't
have any money here before and you can
tell that there's actually some future
for this place
had our county commissioners followed
suit with Denver and Aurora and Boulder
in Longmont
and Lakewood in band outdoor growing
band greenhouse growing pushed it all
indoors the economic recovery we have
enjoyed has been berry or would have
been very different
and so in Michigan I know you guys have
been taking economic hit after economic
hit for the last my whole life sorry
this can really be an economic engine
for for growth and prosperity and it's
not a tidal wave of money that's gonna
fix everything I watched the video on
Detroit not too long ago where people
with disassembling skyscrapers and
selling parts of scrap I'm like like
active skyscrapers are old skyscraper
like an old one okay as long as I still
people in them the amount of recession
in Detroit is is significantly different
than what we see here even it even
though we've got the blow and Detroit
have gone through similar things the
scale is very different
in a state like Michigan marijuana
really could be two or three or twenty
or thirty thousand jobs oh yeah it could
bring it back now these people aren't
all gonna be making 75,000 a year a lot
of them are gonna be making 1015 our
1215 our fourteen an hour but that's
still thousands of jobs you're still
talking about hundreds of millions of
dollars into improving properties and
bringing them up to code and when Jeff
starts talking about is what what do you
need to know going from green house to
warehouse the improvements that are
required in a lot of the warehouses to
get them up to where he's gonna get at
that costs a lot of money and that
improvement is massive for the area we
had a excuse me we needed to upgrade our
air flow system a little bit of green
and healthy and I was getting some
estimates we're trying to connect two
rooms two sides of the building and just
run a through one air conditioning thing
and handle some humidity and some air
control through one thing yeah probably
six to eight thousand each side to make
that happen just for a small air
exchange set up so just it's going from
the home to the commercial that when he
said eight thousand each side I was like
oh this is gonna take a second just the
economic boom a state can feel if this
is done correctly if it's done smartly
and and to have but have it done
correctly really takes people willing to
do the lake work to go to City Council
meetings to go to state legislature
meetings and make sure that they don't
do thousand-foot from everywhere rules
I remember here in Pueblo the the first
proposal I saw for for buffer zones the
distance your marijuana business has to
be from other stuff there were like 25
different businesses on there
yeah like nursing homes right all kinds
of different churches liquor stores
farmers it was a specific business name
rehab specifically seek out adults with
developmental disabilities
[Music]
as employees these oh yeah that's that
companies kind of niche is giving that
whole segment of the population a great
job and our original legislation had a
thousand feet from their property and
then in the middle of all of this
Colorado redefined what a thousand feet
from a school meant they changed how its
measured halfway through the game and it
wasn't like feet 2 inches kind of
distance but it was what they call as
the crow flies versus walking and so
originally dispensary owners walked out
their front door and took the street on
foot version right to the nearest school
and then applied that way saying that
there were a thousand three hundred feet
from a school and then they changed the
rule to ask the clothed crow flies and
it turns out the nearest pieces of their
property lines are only 600 feet apart
because of a mass that was literally
only mass shut down of business in
general ad in Colorado is because that
rule changed and so I mean for you I
when Jeff first told me this was a
question I was like dude that's a whole
podcast we can't do that as part of a
thing because where your state is right
now and honestly this applies to like 14
different states across the country
depending on what happens in November's
election 14 different states will be
going through the process we're talking
about right now or are about to be
depending on how the election goes so a
lot of you need to start thinking about
this who makes these decisions in your
area what kind of process is that what
does it look like how do I get involved
in that if you don't make those
decisions and start writing those rules
somebody will write them for you yep
and unfortunately for you and what this
wasn't as bad when Colorado was doing
this the anti pop movement is very vocal
now it was just the DEA in the police
and law enforcement in the prisons and
police unions when Colorado was doing
this now there are parents groups
freaked out and when you get into this
mainly you'll find that the anti pot
groups are just people who didn't have
anything in their world and needed of
something in trying to remind us all
that in eighth grade we learned that pot
is bad has become their goal in life
right and they're not
very good at research or arguments we
just got a male or a liar in the mail
but the one thing they they really
really are is vocal yes and when you do
get involved in this process in your
area one of the first things you're
gonna realize is that the old dude who
shows up to every meeting and won't shut
up about whatever their topic is
everybody that's involved in city
government knows that [ __ ] topic
intimately they know every in and out of
it and they're sick of hearing about it
for one reason because that dude shows
up and makes a lot of noise and that's
what the anti pop people do they'll
rally 35 or 40 church moms they'll show
up in force to two or three hearings and
all of a sudden your city doesn't get to
enjoy any of the economic benefits of
legalization and every marijuana
consumer in that geographic area that
wants to participate in the legal market
has to drive to the next county to do so
because of who showed up at a meeting
you really really really need to start
taking a look at this especially if you
want to be part of the industry as an
owner you've got a chance to get in on
the ground floor right now if you're
willing to put in serious legislative
legwork
that's my half of the question I just
glanced over a second I was like we're
in an hour in two minutes I'm almost
tempted to make this a two-part question
and cut this dude off now and make
another episode this your half of the
question is huge
because there's a lot of stuff I mean we
can give them the glance over if you
want no I think we would there's enough
I mean he asked like four questions in
here so I think we're gonna make this a
two-parter are you down to record a
little bit more with me I totally am and
I could use like a two minute break I
knew you needed a stretch break a
cigarette break I could use a fresh
drink and a couple of dabs so ladies
miss podcast is yeah this podcast is
going just over an hour
I would rather record two episodes out
of this so Mike and I are gonna take
some dabs let's do this if you have not
before your listeners because we kind of
do us on the fly can I twist your arm
and make this a Thursday episode or
what's gonna happen we're gonna put
these out one is gonna be a Monday one's
gonna be a Thursday so that was I don't
know if this is for me this is more than
interesting enough to do a week teaser
and I think our listeners are that
dedicated but I want to hook them up and
do it closer if we can this is I've been
trying a lot of times I try to do two
episodes a week but I can't commit to
that I can't dedicate to that so I
haven't made the promise I would do
we're we have trouble getting one of
these together a month now just cuz
we're both busy adults right but we're
gonna make sure that these two episodes
come out on a Monday and a Thursday
back-to-back quick like that you guys if
you like this content that comes from
listeners and listener generated
material send me an email let's girl
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you I'm gonna wrap it
up quickly make sure you follow Mike on
social media it's an emo Punk 15 on
Twitter follow the podcast it's @gf wih
podcast on twitter I've got a Facebook
page it's girl from a heart podcast I
think that's all we're gonna do for this
week Mike sneaking away to go use the
men's room he's gonna grab a cigarette
I'm gonna take some dabs and we're gonna
record another episode so ladies and
gentlemen until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
no siree
me
[Music]
by a name
[Applause]
[Music]
get done
[Applause]
[Music]
you