yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 159 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations it's right if you're a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
Babur if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross - Jeff
wanna thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout to
cat to it in the entire mystic roots
crew ladies and gentlemen this is part
two of last step the last episode I
almost said last week's episode but
it'll still be this week because I'm
gonna put these out back-to-back I won't
make you wait too long just a couple
maybe three days little wait yeah Mike
is back sitting across the table from me
Mike had a couple of cigarettes one a
cigarette that's pretty quick keeping it
quick pretty quick so welcome back this
is actually uh it's one 58.5 and we're
gonna call 159 to keep the feed going
one 58.5 part two part deer yeah so uh
dude welcome back and it's getting a
little bit chilly out there Mike and I
just hung outside got a cigarette
it's getting a little bit crispy we had
a hoodie while I was out there all you
outdoor growers your shits gonna get
purple it's that time of year
everybody's gonna be carrying the jacket
around all my friends are sleeping
outside their outdoor girl I feel for
you right now
yeah you start a campfire some Sh I hope
you got your dog out there keeping you
warm no campfire no campfire light white
plants I don't know I know is that light
it's light is that the right kind of
light it's like I really don't know all
right so uh yeah hopefully you're warm
outside if you're listen you're
listening to this wall you're trimming
down your outdoor seat outdoor crops
it's just about cropped oberst outdoor
seasons time to harvest depending on
where you live in there
now and what strain you're growing if
you got some flow over some blueberries
down while you're listening to this you
better be flushing or watching yeah
flushing for sure all right let's put
this trainwreck of a podcast back up to
was really two minutes and 30 seconds in
we're already rambling ladies gentlemen
this is part 2 of an episode that we did
a few actually recorded like an hour ago
you heard it a few days ago the there
was an email and it started off with
questions for Mike and then there was a
part two that had questions about going
from a basement grow into a large
facility so let me catch you up on the
email I'll read it all the way from the
beginning it says hey what's up Rasta
Jeff huge fan of the podcast as I've
said before I had a few questions I
thought could be a podcast I'm in
Michigan we just passed three bills
pushing us into a seed to sale system
based on Colorado system I was wondering
if you would white Mike could touch on
the subject like how do I go about
finding out information from the city
about how many license facilities they
will allow that part we handled on the
last episode I hope you listen to it if
not press pause go back listen to number
158 and check it out then come back and
see us so the second part of the
question what we're going to address
today he says what is the biggest hurdle
going from a basement grow to a
warehouse I know you've recently made
the switch from soil to cocoa any advice
on that transition then he also says I'm
planning on using veg bloom I'm already
in the basement but do you add anything
else to their line as well what are some
things you didn't expect going to a
large-scale and any other advice you
think one would need to know about
taking the leap into the big leagues and
he says thanks for such a great podcast
I hope you can answer some questions for
me half of it let's get into the second
half of it the part where I need to jump
in it Mike thanks for doing such a great
job with the first half of this dudes
question you really [ __ ] nailed it
for them thanks man I hope I hope I
answered your question if you need
further elaboration on any point hit me
up on social media please do we love
hearing from all of you from everybody I
love listen or generated con this is an
amazing question so we had to do a
two-parter episode to answer it you can
send me your emails you guys it's girl
from your heart at hotmail.com
I'm gonna get into the question it goes
if I didn't say thanks again for the
killer question yes they think the app
is a great question we've we've gotten
old we're gonna get two hours worth of
content out of this question he
ah where is it what is the biggest
hurdle going from a basement grow to a
warehouse there are a lot of things to
think about there one of the biggest
things that I noticed was different was
the airflow a large building the air
doesn't feel like it does in a small
room you can change the air out in a
small bedroom in a matter of minutes
with a small blower a large room you're
gonna have hotspots you're gonna have
cool spots you're gonna find humid spots
you're gonna need to learn how to
control that temperature and the
humidity all throughout a large room
it's the the scale of the increase is
where every time you've got many legal
retailers and production facilities are
still problems shooting their their
multi-million dollar grows because the
difference in scope from a basement grow
or a smaller grow to a huge warehouse is
monumental a good reliable HVAC company
in Colorado that will come work on a
grow and knows what they're doing
we'll make you wait three months just to
come give you an estimate because they
are so backed up with cannabis growers
right now if if I had enough money to do
anything I wanted cannabis business wise
I would build from the ground up because
I've seen what so many companies have
had to go through attempting to improve
an existing structure to where it's not
giving them problems so many people that
I mean they thought they had everything
under control
and then as the season started to change
one whole wall was the temperature
change in that wall was causing major
problems and it grow I mean that's not a
unique problem that happened to a lot of
people if you're one wall you're
whichever whichever side gets the most
Sun or the least Sun it just kind of
depends on your environment when the
seasons change in Colorado but you'll
usually see in a grow that you've never
been in before you have to find out
where the powdery mildew is going to
happen when the first winter comes you
just got to find out where it's gonna
happen because it probably will if you
if you haven't designed your room
flawlessly you're on one wall
you're probably gonna give you in an
exterior wall you're gonna get powdery
mildew that are one the seasons you and
I can problem shoe a basement grow or a
bedroom grow in like 20 minutes
in our to I mean in by troubleshoot I
mean like find the problems and suggest
easy ways to fix them I can walk in a
home like a basement growing point out
ten things in ten seconds we can improve
your grow and make it button ocean you
know where house grow part of its just
put in the time right to get through the
cycle where you're huge means of heating
and cooling a lot of people don't aim
for enough cooling they don't think
they're gonna need enough cooling and
then they put plenty of cooling or they
don't think about enough airflow you
have to evacuate humidity out of there
so that's got more on AC units than they
did on building building no I know that
place yeah I know I know where yeah I
know that place it's not one outfit in
Colorado I'm sure that's true for a half
dozen or more I just happen to know the
one so the airflow is gonna be a huge
thing also you're gonna be feeding on a
much larger scale or you're gonna build
a drip system are you gonna be watering
by hand every time you run that drip
system you're creating more humidity in
the room that you're gonna have to deal
with every time you water my hand
there's gonna be more humidity do you
have a drain do you have a floor dream
that's something I would definitely look
for if you're moving into a new building
a floor drain treating water is a huge
deal
treating water you're gonna have if
you're moving into a warehouse at the if
the green and healthy warehouse we used
to add a thousand gallons of water every
other day ish you're gonna need to treat
that somehow I would recommend a really
nice reverse osmosis machine because
something I noticed was we were using
the water they came from the meters have
more buckets and boulders oh my god it's
the scale is what we're getting at here
guys is when you're talking about a
basement grow you're talking about one
employee you're talking about a thousand
dollars worth of equipment the little
warehouse you multiply those numbers by
a hundred right well we were using what
let me get back into smart we were using
the municipal water from Colorado
Springs and as the temperature would
change this smell of the water would
change
I could smell chlorine in it on some
days I could smell other things on some
days and I would do a simple pH test and
on some days the pH would be seven some
days it would be nine and it would just
be days apart from that and then I would
do ppm tests and sometime
be really high sometimes it would be
really really low and we're feeding
cocoa where our plants are in cocoa so
it was really hard to predict what water
you're gonna get tomorrow or the next
day or the next day so an RO machine
would really be really helpful in a
large grow that's something I would
highly recommend is you're gonna need
clean water you're gonna need a lot of
it have more RO water than you think
you're going to need available because
if you get too much he's anywhere
guaranteed there's stuff in your
municipal water that you do not want to
feed to your plants through your
watering system bugs if you get a
problem like bugs or powdery mildew
you're going to have a larger problem
than you have ever thought of having
because hopefully you're running a
perpetual grow if you've got a large
system and you're gonna have plants that
are in full flower at the end of flower
if you can't treat those for bugs so be
highly prepared for pests and pathogens
and powdery mildew be on the lookout be
ahead of that don't bring anybody into
that grow unless it is absolutely
necessary it's you have to get clones
from somewhere but when clones come in
quarantine them treat the [ __ ] out of
them almost kill them you're treating
them so hard for pests and mold because
you don't want to bring any of that
stuff in I know a lot of facilities that
have just they've given up trying to
treat clones and their seed only now Wow
I know a few outfits that have just
given up entirely and I know a lot of
home growers that are that that's been
their policies since the last time they
got a gift clone scheduling and getting
everything on track in a big grow is a
challenge in the beginning unless you're
a guy like myself that is kind of OCD so
you're gonna need to get a good schedule
happening you're going to need to get
veg plants then you're going to need
flowering plants then you're going to
need clones and you're gonna need to
keep in mind that these flowering plants
are going to be done in this amount of
time and I need this many veg plants to
replace them immediately because you do
not want downtime and that's gonna kind
of segue me into something that I can
really rant about personally the hugest
caveat of going from the basement to a
wire house grow is often the
relationship between the money person
and the actual grower or their so
oftentimes there's a middleman you're
going to have an investor
an owner and you're gonna have a grower
I'm not sure which position you're
planning on taking please get all of
those people on the same page because I
see a lot of grows fail because an
investor throws down money and he wants
money back in [ __ ] 60 days because
you're growing weed where's my money and
then you've got an owner that's rubbing
his balls to keep him off you for a
little while and he's like give me 120
days and so now the owner will say how
long do you need to grow this crop and I
know that the crops that I'm trying to
grow take me I'm gonna say 150 days this
is hypothetical I need 150 days to make
this crop happen the owner of that
facility is gonna look you dead in the
face and go cool I'll see you in 120
days and it should be done and now
you're saying to yourself these are
[ __ ] plants I can't cut 30 days off
of this cycle there's no way it's gonna
happen so you've got an owner bitching
or investor bitching in an owner and
owner Yellin or to grow or a grower that
wants to do the absolute best he can for
these plants because that's where the
passion is but the owners got to make
money he's got to return the investment
and then you've got an investor that
only cares about the money so the
hardest part of a commercial grow is
getting all of your people on the same
page you need your owner your investor
your master grower then you need whoever
else you've got in there if you've got
somebody working the bedroom and the
flower room
those two people need to have a meeting
every couple of days if you've got a
trim crew your master grower and your
assistant grower and your trim crew
leader all need to communicate you need
to know what plants are coming down you
need to know how long you have to trim
this until there's more plants so that
you can schedule for the trimmers to be
there those are some of the things that
you may overlook it's just so the scale
and the scope are so much more
complicated than a basement grow I mean
with a basement grow you're getting
ready to harvest you check out your
plants every day every couple of you
know days for a week when they get to
where you want them you just start
harvesting maybe you call a buddy if you
maybe make a little plan and have two
friends coming over when you're talking
about an industrial scale you're talking
about like 15 or 20 people that need to
be scheduled paid w-2 trained I believe
two or three people could run one or two
people can run a hundred like gross of
fish
ah two people pissed right but when it
comes time to trim then you need a small
trim crew you need five or six people
that's when you need that trim crew
manager maybe that assistant grower now
becomes also the trim crew manager but
you're gonna need somebody that can
delegate somebody that can man you need
a director that can direct the facility
that can direct the employees that knows
about the plants that knows about people
that know and then you need like I said
in the last episode a lawyer and an
accountant those are some things that
you're definitely gonna need in a larger
grow that you didn't think as much about
in the other grow also
[ __ ] goes wrong everyday in a large
scale grow well in a lot of times
investors don't necessarily know any of
that which is where a lot of headaches
and a lot of partnerships break up is
the money man doesn't know anything
about marijuana and so they doesn't
realize that something so simple is when
we were doing trimmer interviews we
walked a dude through the grow and we
think he gave us trips and that's why
this crop is a third smaller than it
should be ah like there's there's stuff
that comes up because you're dealing
with plant growth and you're dealing
with a live plant and a medium where
mistakes can mean millions in lost
revenue or delays this we really can't
get it out of enough the scope is so
much different the attitude and the
skill sets are different
one of the biggest traits for a basement
grower is secrecy the ability to hide
and stay hidden that keeps people with
shotguns away from your door whether
they be law enforcement or rippers
that's one of the biggest skill sets you
can have as a basement grower as a legal
marijuana business owner you need to be
very out front loud and proud about what
you do how you do it and the fact that
you love to follow the rules I love to
follow the rules and I make sure all of
my employees love to follow the rules
needs to become your mantra and you need
to get used to sitting in front of TV
cameras especially if you want to be one
of the first marijuana business owners
in your area
in Colorado we have somebody that's
known as a compliance officer and his
only job is to make sure that you're
following all of the rules he gets
emails from here we have the meed the
marijuana Enforcement Division he gets
emails from them every day saying that
you know that this is a new rule this is
a new rule and it's his job to go
whether it's the retail or the grow or
the extraction facility it's his job to
get the employees together and say this
is the rule and he has to oversee that
that happens the rule changes like that
a frequent here in Colorado and until
nationwide we really good legalization
handed out or hammered out it they'll be
common in your area too so uh yeah be
ready so I did in the past I'm sure that
we did an entire episode on going from a
basement grow to a large-scale grow and
pretty sure that we did an entire
episode on that I will leave that in the
show notes there will be a link to that
in the show notes or if you go to the
website
I read genetics Colorado comm and scroll
through the shows I'm sure you'll be
able to find it on there I cannot recall
the episode number right now and I do
not want to scroll through old episodes
while we're recording so look for that
it's a whole episode about moving from a
basement grow to a large-scale grow one
of the the things that we haven't really
hit that you have available now that
wasn't available to us when we started
this is you you can come to Colorado now
and hire a consultant or go visit a
couple of legal businesses and see how
they do it and get an idea of what's
gonna be required of you and where you
want to go and I know a number of people
out here in Colorado have been hired to
travel out to other states and help
people navigate some of the things like
planning out where house grows I mean
just the logistics that go into these
things will blow your mind the amount of
cooling that's required for a one-story
warehouse grow is typically greater than
like a 30 story office building I mean
the amount of equipment that's necessary
is just insane learning how to maintain
all that equipment like we're talking
about pot growers they know how to grow
pot the amount of information that needs
to be learned and adapted to his money
man that's something that's something
that I quickly learned is I'm not
just a pot grower anymore I learned how
to build drip systems with PVC I learned
how to work on pumps I learned how to
work on air conditioning I learned how
to work on the humidifiers now I know
how to work on the security camera
system now I know how to build [ __ ] that
I never thought I would it and it's just
all because I went and helped with a
giant commercial facility and I learned
a ton of things well no and it's you you
need such a varied skill set because
little things that don't have anything
to do with growing marijuana can affect
your legal ability to do so if you see a
camera down and they grow and you ignore
it you might get hit with a compliance
violation because that camera was down
for an extra half day and have your
business shut down quickly that quickly
all right so he's got more parts of this
question I don't want to harp on the one
part for too long cuz the last episode
got long that way that I just say harp
on it jeez how old am I getting so he
also said I know you've recently made
the switch from soil to cocoa any advice
on that transition
he also says I'm planning on running veg
bloom and I am already in a basement but
do you add anything else to the veg
bloom wine as well um so that's kind of
a multi-part question there I've made
the switch from soil to cocoa any advice
on that transition yes I use an easy
cloner and I take my clones from the
easy corner and I put them into Solo
cups the Solo cups have got holes in the
bottom of them so that they can drain
plenty of water in the water doesn't get
stuck in there I usually fill the cups
with a aerated soil something like Fox
farms either ocean forest or the happy
frog and I put the clones into there and
then I water them with my desired
nutrient solution I did so this time but
I used cocoa instead of the aerated soil
and 50% of my clones died they [ __ ]
hated going into cocoa they were not
happy about that the cocoa seems to have
compressed and smothered them they did
not get a chance to get their legs and
they got crushed and killed so my
thought on that is put your clones into
soil if that's what you're doing because
they did not like the cocoa go into cups
of dirt put those cups of dirt into the
cocoa in the future that's what I have
learned because my plants were really
really pain you can go dirt clones to to
cocoa plants easy enough oh yeah they
just drive right in there they love it
just gonna give a don't mind in the
transition once those
strengthen up a bit right yeah well I
know all the the weight of the water in
that Coco compressed the Coco real tight
yes new roots and they've just got
crushed in there so that's one thing
that I learned also you can water a
whole heck of a lot more more you can
feed more frequently is what I think I'm
trying to say I'm sorry you can't water
a lot more you can feed a heck of a lot
more when I was running soil I would
feed maybe twice twice a week now every
time I am watering the plants they are
getting nutrients okay so let three
maybe four times a week these plants are
getting nutrients and they don't show
any signs of burn and they are growing
vigorously at the coco not holding your
newts as well right the Coco it doesn't
hold on at all the nutrients just yeah
so then you don't get as much burn and
you can feed more frequently it'll eat
what it wants better for your plants but
not your wallet well maybe in the end it
will pay for it I'm thinking if it's
gonna eat that much there's gonna be
that much more weight that'll make up
for it which isn't a bad thing
time to do some math something I'm
thinking I don't know if I'm convinced
on a hundred percent Coco I may start
doing a 50 percent soilless mix like a
honestly not an expensive soil something
like roots organic or maybe even two per
or the Fox Farm ocean forest wouldn't
hurt my feelings a 50 percent mix with
the soilless mix and Coco put the cocoa
in there I know a couple of people that
started doing that a while ago and they
all seem to rave about it yeah I think
I'm gonna try that next
that's next I'm gonna run I'll run one
light with the cocoa one light with the
soil and then one light with the cocoa
soil mix and we'll see what happens so
that's that's something I feel about the
the soil too cocoa switch and also I've
noticed if I overwater they take really
long to dry out and the plants will kind
of slow down I thought that I could yeah
I thought I could water the [ __ ] at home
with the cocoa but I've noticed that I
want some aeration in there if I
overwater them they really started to
get really like that aeration they do
they like air I've noticed that right
when they start to dry out is when they
really take off with the most explosive
growth so they're getting kind of dry
I've only ever seen one good aeroponic
system in motion and I was blown away
with this dudes timelines
the next part of his question he said
I'm planning on running veg blue
and then he said do you add anything
else to their line as well yes actually
I've got a screenshot here of a
conversation I had with a rep from veg
bloom and he says this is what we are
recommended to use he said four to five
grams of base nutrient per gallon in veg
five grams per gallon and flour so
you've got your base nutrient it's
probably the HD or the RO or the dirty
whichever one they selected for you
hopefully you had a consultation with
them and had your water checked out is
if you get your water tested send them
water test results they will recommend a
base nutrient for you but four to 5
grams of base per veg R per gallon and
veg five grams per gallon in your
flowering stage Benny says 1/2 of gram
per gallon of plus life once a week and
that's their routing inoculate the plus
life I really like that stuff half a
gram per gallon of plus life once a week
through veg and flour and then taper
that off in late flour so like around
week four or five you can start pulling
that back and then he says shine
starting in week 3 so at the beginning
of week three add shine put one gram a 1
to 2 grams per gallon of water is what
he says the shine starting in week 3 one
gram to 2 grams per gallon of water and
then you can kind of increase that a
little bit as time goes on from what
I've seen so week 3 do a gram to two
week four increase it a little bit week
five increase it a little bit six and
seven increase it a little bit and then
start flushing from there and then he
says push foliar feed every five to six
days honestly I would cut out the push
foliar feed maybe spray it one time at
the beginning of week five and then pull
off of that and he says the push foliar
to spur a 50 milliliters per gallon of
water so maybe if you've got a small
crop just makes up a half gallon and put
25 mils in there I also think that
pa-ching that water before you spray it
may help you but be careful what you use
to pH because you don't want to go
killing off the live there's so silic
acid there's calcium and there's seek
help in there so be careful what you're
using to adjust the pH also you asked if
I add anything to that mix yes I put a
little bit of oh so 28 in there I like
some potassium silicates to the mix I
think that is the plants more vigor it
makes them a little bit more robust and
then once about every once a week once
every 10 days ish I'll hit them with
either hybrid or carbo load just to
speed up some carbohydrates in there put
a little bit of a boost in there so
that's when I add to the veg blue mix
it's not too expensive that way and it
is highly efficient it'll put some shine
on your plants it'll make them beefy
they'll taste good they'll be high in
THC you will have quality flowers so
that's what I add to the veg bloom you
also said you're already there in a
basement what else well what are some
things you didn't expect going into such
a large scale honestly be the demand I
was expected to put out a specific
amount of cannabis and a specific amount
of time and I didn't know that there
would be obstacles I didn't expect there
to be a problem every day when you walk
into a large commercial grow when I
would train new people we trained a few
new guys and they said so what's the
first thing we do when we get in here
because I like to you know everyone's
like excitingly
the first thing we got to do is find
what [ __ ] up last night and I was like
what and I was like there's so many so
many moving parts something in here just
broke and it's funny that's the size and
scope thing I was hitting at earlier
it's in any grow you need to keep an eye
on the moving parts your timers your
plugs your palms your hoses connections
all of it the bigger you grow the more
those equipment checks eat up in your
time when you're talking about a hundred
light or a five hundred light massive
warehouse checking to make sure none of
your drip system plugs have come loose
and you're spraying water towards your
ballast wall like it takes half the day
sometimes I spent honestly the first
half of my shift when I would walk into
the growth in the first hour would just
be making sure that none of the cloners
are clogged know that the no the
sprinkler system is clogged
none of the pumps are clogged none of
the breakers have flipped all of the
fans are on their wood all of the
humidifiers are running and none of the
filters were clogged up I would
seriously spend an hour checking all of
that equipment just like that I got a
text message back from a buddy of mine
maybe a month ago that read can't talk
have to lie stick come on this morning
ouch and it was just that
two-sentence way to let me know he can't
talk right now and he's gonna be busy
all goddamn until he figures this [ __ ]
out
I yeah I mean that's a game-changer
that's your you've got a half million
dollars and the fires getting closer
it's really uh it's really neat in our
industry we run multimillion-dollar grow
facilities that are responsible for I'm
not bragging on Facebook by the owner of
the facility I was growing for posted
one time that I pulled three hundred and
twenty something and a fraction pounds
of cannabis from eighty five lights
which is three point something sounds
pearl-white more the hell I was headed
with what was I saying
just so there's that much product being
grown three hundred and something pounds
at somewhere between eighteen and twenty
two hundred dollars a pound proximately
two thousand dollars a pound
I had three hundred of them times two
thousand dollars I produced that uh and
we rely on like ten and twelve dollar
timers they could [ __ ] everything I find
it really funny that we've got like this
eight dollar timer from Lowe's that
makes all of this get fed if that one
timer [ __ ] up the whole facility does
not get water for a day in a basement
your your timer screws up you don't
notice it for three days one growers out
you know six thousand eight thousand
depending on how bad the problem got
before it got found same thing happens
in an industrial grow someone's out
several million in everybody getting
fired
yeah there's a whole dispensary that now
has to go buy retail weed well no and
take this a step further there's 365
days in the year and a shitload of her
[ __ ] holidays you want to be with your
home with your family um somebody's got
to be at the grow every day to make sure
all your lights went off when I started
a great healthy wellness monster
spraying everywhere and I'm no longer
there I don't know if everybody listen
to every episode but I no longer work at
Green and healthy wellness I'm not
involved in a large-scale production
facility at this time I'm pursuing my
own endeavors right now but when I was
in green and healthy wellness for the
first crop I did not take a day off for
the first harvest was we were in flower
for nine or ten weeks there were some
strains the lemon Jie went for eleven
weeks and then there was a little bit of
veg time before
that I did not take a day off for 79 or
80 four-ish days because somebody had to
be there
so that's that I did not expect but it
was willing to do you can't be even
tangentially involved with the legal
industry before the lazy stoner
stereotype evaporates yeah I mean the
amount of work put in the industrial
grows like the legal industry in
Colorado Colorado we did a billion in
sales last year we're gonna do like 1.2
this year maybe more the amount of days
like 12 15 hour days that people around
the state put in to make that true is
just astronomical can I spend a billion
dollars buy a country and people are
running showers on hash okay you could
do this for minutes on drum gear can I
come to that party yeah I imagine the
drum kit I build oh man I can't decide
which color oh okay but just when you
when you make that step from from gray
market or the basement up into the legal
industry everything changes in ways that
you can't predict or imagine in I mean
you guys listen to this lucky you know
this going in we learned this [ __ ] the
hard way
something I gotta jump in and talk about
it had something I did not expect that
was overwhelming uh harvesting drying
and curing it's not [ __ ] prepared for
that you need space for however much
blood you've got growing you need that
much room for hanging buds
basically yeah because you can't just
crush it all together because it's gonna
get funky you need I've seen people I'm
in controlled room for drying and curing
that much herb that is something I
totally did not plan properly for when I
was a green and healthy wellness I've
seen people try to put a
football-field-sized grow room into a
bathroom sighs drying area it's like
dude you're not gonna do it there's no
way right that air is gonna get stuck in
there all the humidity is stuck in there
it's not gonna go anywhere you need
somewhere for the freshly cut buds to be
for the older buds to be if you need a
drying and curing hanging trimming
system that is sufficient for your space
so do you make sure you work on that the
amount of like when you're doing any
size
the best thing you can do to ensure
success is to plan upfront and when
you're talking about the size and scope
and the legal industry that's
astronomically important I've seen
little little oversights lead to
multi-million dollar fuck-ups and
businesses collapsing I mean just silly
stupid decisions or little things that
people overlook the cooling thing I've
seen multi-million dollar grows sit idle
half the year because the there isn't
physically enough cooling on site to run
during the hottest months of the year
and the business just needs to make
another 300 grand before they can buy an
air conditioner big enough to cool their
home and it's like having a dope like a
Ferrari or a rocket or a Tesla but
missing parts you just got it where I've
seen other gross just say [ __ ] it and
grow when it's way too hot and put out a
super Airy product and then they just
have it all blasted in ash I'm so
excited that the winter is coming we get
free air cooling just filter that air
that comes in you guys you know you
don't want to bring it you don't wanna
bring in ice crystals and fungus from
outside but filter that air the
temperature swing in the the giant
concrete wall that you didn't think
about once while you were planning
causing massive powdery mildew and mold
growth because of the temperature swing
I mean how many people didn't see that
coming in their original plans right and
what are you gonna how do you heat a cut
a foot and a half thick concrete move
the one house that had a basement with
one concrete exterior wall and the first
time that I grew in that basement in the
winter guess what white rhino plant like
a 5-ounce plant it looked like a frosted
Christmas tree it got all funked up with
powdery mildew and went bye-bye I I
watched another guy his what he thought
were the best plants in the harvest when
we finally got back to him the section
of wall that they were up against was
ice-cold oh yeah and they were I mean it
was the craziest look in pink mold I've
ever seen but I mean just found us it
was because of the temperature swing
when you multiply that I mean that was
like maybe a $400 loss to that grower
but if that wasn't an industrial setting
would be for 2,000 yeah it would
going right down that row all right so
those are a lot of things that you can
look out for and you can expect
he also said any other advice you could
you may think one would need knowing
about taking a leap into the big leagues
keep a positive attitude shit's gonna
happen like I said every day you're
gonna walk into that ground you're gonna
find some [ __ ] and you can either
freak out you can throw your arms up in
the air and you can be like ah what the
[ __ ] happened in here and you could kick
some buckets and you can throw some [ __ ]
around and make more of a mess or you
can go get the [ __ ] mop you can mop
it up figure out where that pump broke
could go get some PVC pipe and a saw and
fix all that [ __ ] that you got to fix
and just put some glue on it and hope it
doesn't break again because you still
got work to do plants need to be grown
shits gonna keep going so that's what I
could say keep a positive attitude keep
your head up also pay attention make
sure you're getting paid what you
deserve to be paid and if there's some
[ __ ] in the grow that can be done today
do it don't wait until tomorrow just
[ __ ] do it
never in the grow I mean little things
that you can get away with it home I
mean sometimes four weeks at a time you
can get away with at home do not fly in
an industrial setting there's just so
much less room for error and things are
gonna stack up you're gonna think I've
got eight hours worth of work to do
today I'll knock that out I'll do eight
hours worth of work tomorrow while
you're doing eight hours worth of work
today something's gonna [ __ ] up no one's
prepared for the level of work at
harvest you're gonna you're gonna have
to go and clean up something and now
you've got nine hours worth of work to
do today so you're gonna say I'm not
gonna get this last part done I'll do it
tomorrow now tomorrow you've got nine
hours worth of work to do something else
is gonna go wrong somebody's gonna
interrupt you somebody's gonna call
piece of equipments gonna break you're
gonna have to take a poop someone's
gonna take a little extra time you're
gonna have to go to the store and pick
up a part now your nine-hour day just
turned into a 10-hour day and you don't
even get a lunch break and now you're
hungry and grouchy and so when you go
home and try to take care of your plants
they're gonna look like [ __ ] and it's
just gonna keep catching up with you so
if there's some [ __ ] you can do today do
it today sweep that [ __ ] up spray
whatever you gotta spray clean up that
dirt be looking not for pests look out
for mildew every day and just be
prepared and get you some method seven
so you don't go blind that's probably
one of the best things I could say good
sunglasses in yes so method sevens keep
your skin covered I think that covers a
whole bunch man this guy asked a whole
bunch of great stuff
you like the $5,000 console fee in an
episode and a half there you go
you can send donations to my email no
I'm just kidding man I think that's all
that we've got for you said I hope you
can answer some questions well I think
we handled that for you yeah if if you
want more information on any part of
that there's a lot of information and I
know this applies to a lot more than
just the guy asking the question so feel
free to choose for the questions that
the evil Jeff keeps giving you yeah
everybody I want to hear I love
generating I love creating listened or
generated content that's how I know I'm
giving you what you want it's like you
went to the restaurant and you ordered
exactly what you wanted and is able to
whip that up like the chef and bring it
out to you and serve it hot it's super
fresh for you so send me email grow from
your heart at hotmail calm it's really
easy to get in touch with me I check
that email very frequently it goes to my
phone it jingles in my pocket when you
send me an email I like it so sue me a
message I would love to hear from you
there Mike tell everyone how they can
find you on social media so that they
can go stalk you you can find me on
Facebook at Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws or on Twitter at at Nemo Punk 15
Nemo Punk 15 how'd you come up with that
bro
I've always no one I've literally had it
since 15 this was 15 since I was 15
that's with 15 come from comes from Nemo
is just no one and I liked that when I
was 15 and then Punk because I was 15
and I thought it was cute is you world
and then little polish for 15 six years
later Finding Nemo camp comes out I just
never got around to changing it that I
when I went to create a twitter handle
it was like do you want to use the hobby
like I've had since you were 15 I clicks
sure why not now a hundred and fifty
nine episodes in and I'm so with it it
works
Nemo punk 15 fallen because I am at gfy
age podcast on twitter you can also find
me at Rasta Jeff 420 you guys I just hit
8,000 followers I hadn't story it'd be
really cool if you follow me on
instagram i'm i really underscore
genetics money before i was about 20,000
and they deleted me they took me down
but you know what i like it because now
none of mine I can't say none but my
followers are not bots and I'm not
following a bunch of [ __ ] account so
I kind of got a refresh or restart it's
cleaner I get more I get more likes now
than I did before fastest over lines
into that nasty little cloud yeah so
follow me on instagram you guys ireon
discouraging
i RIE underscore genetics I would
appreciate that check out all the great
cannabis photography that I've been
posting all the stuff that I talk about
on the show the breeding project the
flowers that I grow the commercial girl
facilities I get to visit the teas I
brew up some podcast pictures secret
sash pictures all that [ __ ] ends up on
my Instagram so make sure you do check
it out Mike's phone is beeping so that
gives me a hint that it's time to start
wrapping up the show you guys I'd love
it if you send me emails girl from your
heart at hotmail.com thanks everybody
that has sent me messages in the in the
recent times and in the past all of you
thanks for the messages I appreciate it
I'm gonna give a big shout-out to my
friend Jackson's to the ceiling and also
a huge shout out to Johnny B Johnny no
goon on stick it's good bumping into you
over there at the secret stash my friend
also you gotta remind you guys listen to
the podcast on Tok radio every Wednesday
at 1:00 p.m. you can hear new episodes
of the girl from your heart podcast on
Tok radio.com shout out to my friend
citizen Jay over there at O'Grady also
make sure you check out Lucy in the sky
the podcast on Tok radio comm with my
friend Lucy Mike you got anything else
to say to all these people have a great
night everybody thanks for listening I
hope we hammered that question home for
you hit us up on social media everybody
love it I would love it also now the
show's over you guys please go to iTunes
go to the iTunes Store search for the
girl from your heart podcast find the
review section type in a little comment
let me know what you think of the show
and give me a star rating based on what
you feel I'm not gonna ask you for a
five-star review if you feel like I
deserve five stars give me five stars
give me what you think I deserve I would
love to hear from you I'll actually read
your comment on a future episode I would
completely appreciate it
ladies and gentlemen that's all I've got
for you for this episode thanks for
listening to this bonus episode I will
be back Monday with another episode for
you Mike's about to say something say it
say it you got some point in to say I
could tell by the look on your face let
it out I'm fighting the urge to do your
closing line oh you want to do it know
you want to do it together do it thanks
for listening to the bonus episode
everybody we uh we appreciate you
loyalty we sure do ladies and gentlemen
thanks a lot for listening big shot it's
my ninja Spence and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
kids don't try this at home
alone
again talking about the Queen
indoor-outdoor yes we are in California
the place we Plaza in the car
proposition 215 it's a medical need
tell amount and all its mouth we partner
in Topeka we call it can listen to the
song I got a small ball me help me my
ganja bag is empty
help me and me I got a bat should be
plenty proposition 215 and semantics
I've seen these the weed weed
I
[Music]
weed weed weed weed weed weed Paulo
wieder hard I love the weeds the
founding fathers father
[Music]
don't get me wrong I love the lead now
they coming from back the rules now they
go into Santa Cruz chick smokin weed
[Music]
the weed I love the weeds
I love the mouse has just smoke is stash
[Music]
wheats are yeah
you