[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 161 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right if you're a new
grower if you're professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always you need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat coot and the entire mystic
roots crew happy Halloween everybody I
think this episode comes out on
Halloween I hope you're all dressed up
if you're having a fun time hope you got
a cool ass costume send me a picture of
yourself in your Halloween costume I
want to see what you wore I want to see
what you look like speaking of Halloween
costumes I want to give you huge shout
out to my friends at elevate I went to
the Hetty Halloween party sponsored by
her friends at elevate glass it was that
where was it was it the black sheep in
Colorado Springs I need to turn that
music down I could not even focus that
was really loud in my brains I had a
Halloween that was a great party of big
shout-out to Beca a big shot to elevate
a heavy Halloween was the Halloween
party thrown by our friends at elevate
glass they threw the party at the Black
Sheep I had a there was a DJ there were
a couple few bands there was a bunch of
people that had booths there that had
live glassblowing it was a really good
time they had a costume contest and
guess what you guys I won first place in
a costume contest that's right I've got
a Chewbacca costume
it is super dope I bought it at a
costume shop it took him a long time to
get it in stock it took like three weeks
to order that thing it was kind of
pricey you know it wasn't the cheapest
costume anybody's ever bought but it was
well worth it because I've had it for I
think I've had it for four or five years
and I wore every other year and every
year I went at least one costume contest
in it so it is paid for itself I at the
elevat-- party I won a dope new rig it's
a it's a Halloween themed rig
it's orange it's a brighter orange than
normal orange but it's like orange a
little brighter than orange crayon it's
got a pumpkin on the back of it it's a
just a straight tube it's about that's
probably it's almost the same it's the
same height as my Dr Pepper bottle
almost the height of a water bottle so
it's a straight tube it's got a round
ball
pumpkin looking base and then it's got a
straight tube and then another orange
kind of a pumpkin looking spot and then
a straight piece and then another
pumpkin looking an orange bulb with a
green top on it so it looks pumpkin II
it takes a 14 millimeter banger so I got
a 14 millimeter banger on it they came
from elevate and I've also got a carb
cap on here that came from elevate so
shot it's my friends elevate you guys I
know it sounds like a fix that I won the
costume contest but guess what the
people from elevate did not decide that
I won the crowd had decided that I won
the costume contest so it could not be a
fix it was based on crowd applause and
it was clear that they liked my costume
so big shot it's everybody that was at
the costume contest that voted for me I
appreciate that big congratulations to
Becca she was a little nervous about her
party she was messaging me throughout
the week she's like are you coming I
hope it's a good turnout and then by the
middle of the night we realized that she
sold that place out so that was pretty
rad congratulations on selling the place
out big shout out to Matt Z who made the
rig also I gotta mention that we're
gonna wrap up the shout outs here and
get to the topic of the show just a
second I'm gonna give you huge shot it
again to Becca huge shot it to get
dabbing granny for hanging out with me
at the event I had a lot of fun with dad
and granny I was taking pictures and I'm
always the tall guy the tallest guy in
the damn party and I was wearing that
Chewbacca costume which makes me another
I'm six five already you guys honestly
I'm probably 7 - on the Chewbacca
costume because the mask is real real
tall so it makes me a little taller ah
we're taking pictures and granny's a
tall lady but we're taking submissions
she was right in front of me and she had
to bend over to do a pose or something
she did something and then they told me
to squat down cuz I'm too tall and they
couldn't get my head in the picture so
granny and I were kind of gonna hang out
a little close there and she made some
jokes about it was really funny Grammy
is such a hilarious lady it's really
funny hanging out there you guys no
matter how old you are she can [ __ ]
keep up with you she can smoke more dope
than you
granny's a rad lady's a big shot at the
Devon Grammy her Halloween costume was
awesome
she was a cannabis done hey i stuttered
when i said that
excuse me she was a cannabis nun that's
what I meant to say cannabis nun yeah
she wore a nun outfit that had ganja
leaves hanging off of it she had cool
ganja sunglasses she changed her
sunglasses three or four times
throughout the night I think or I might
have been real high
honestly it was hard to see [ __ ] through
that Chewbacca costume so shout-out to
granny shoutout to Lindsey and Chris
boba blaster Co they were oh [ __ ] the
citrus drop chick I think that's what
it's called this there's you guys know
that soda commercial with the the
awkward ginger girl and she wears the
drop the shirt the tank top with her
soda on it it's a lemon-lime soda and
some short shorts
they were both that so it was kind of it
was silly cute I shout out to Fox he
hung out with me a little bit on the at
the Halloween party his costume he
looked like a UH it was hard to tell it
hey yeah horns and yeah look like a
Viking sort of thing also Logan and Cody
hung out I saw Lydia
Abigail looked adorable Kinzie looked
adorable you guys I'm just gonna rattle
on a bunch of names the big chef to
everyone at freakin the heady Halloween
party that was awesome I had a great
time thanks for having me I hope we do
that again next year
alright I want to get into the main
topic of the show there's one more thing
I have to talk about before I get into
the main topic excuse me for all the
throat clearing I just notice something
I put a new mic cover on this microphone
you guys I try to replace the microphone
covers on these mic so that not
everybody spitting into the same thing
and rubbing their face on the same [ __ ]
for a long time and I just gave myself a
fresh new one and it stinks it smells
like like shoe polish or something funky
whoo that's pretty terrible but for some
reason I keep sniffing it I'm not
exactly sure why
so yeah let's what do I have to do next
I have to give a shout-out to my friends
at the dank team.com you guys a lot of
people have been asking me of course I
am
I read genetics I breed i bred the
Grateful dog the lemon Jeffrey right now
I'm pretty much known for the arize is
what's been going on this real popular I
just made a rise f2s I've got cascade
available anyway I am I region etics and
a lot of people know that and they ask
me for seeds if you were local in
Colorado and you can find me maybe we
can do that but I cannot ship seeds to
any
but my friends at the dank team they can
ship you seeds so dank team.com check
them out they've got I read genetics
products in stock right now they've got
head sniper they've got cookie stopper
they've got blue stomper
they've got flow stopper they've got the
Kings cure they probably have some black
cherry Kim they probably have some arise
they may have I'm not sure what else I
can't promise you what else they may
have because they only got a few packs
of some things they may have some dub
wise I'm not sure what else is left over
there at the dank team.com especially by
the time this episode drops but the dank
team calm th e da NK te am calm the dank
team calm go check him out let him know
that you listen to the girl from your
art podcast and at some point when
you're checking out there's a coupon
code time make sure you put in promo
code dank cannabis and that'll get you
12 percent off your entire order and I'm
pretty sure you're gonna get free
shipping with the dank team com so check
them out they've got brands like alpha
chronic mile high rare dankness gauge
green genetics they carry I read
genetics they carry a lot of my friends
they carry a lot of trusted brands it
got Sin City over there they've got a
whole bunch of great stuff so check out
the dank team com they think by now they
will have some Brothers Grimm seeds by
the time this podcast drops so make sure
you go check them out I fully endorse
the dank team.com all right guys let's
get into the main topic of this podcast
the main thing I want to talk about I
was on a forum the other day yes I do
read the forum's I roll around I do not
use a name that anybody would recognize
me by so you won't find me on there I'm
also at a bunch of Facebook groups but
I've uh I've had to check out of a bunch
of the Facebook groups because honestly
I see so hmm
I apologize for all the throat clearing
you guys I was taking some fat dabs of
some live resident has just got me all
clogged up but we'll deal with it we'll
get through a podcast it'll quit right
about the time the show ends I see a
bunch of [ __ ] and Facebook groups
you guys I see people recommending the
shittiest advice and then I go look at
the person that gave that advice I look
at their pictures of their grow and I
can see why their growth looks the way
it does and why they're giving the
advice that they are giving they're not
qualified and it kind of frustrates me
so I had to leave a bunch of Facebook
groups I'm not in a lot of them I but I
do go trolling or browse around the
forums so I see what's going on and
lately a topic I've seen more than once
or twice is pee
we're talking about ways to determine
flowering times of new seeds and new
clones that they've gotten that they
don't have any information on maybe
somebody got some bagged seed and they
don't know how long to let that bag seed
flower or maybe somebody was gifted a
clone and they don't know anything about
the clone from the friend they gave it
to him
so they were like hey Ross - Jeff how do
I determine how long to let these plants
flower so that I don't [ __ ] up my crop
so you guys I'm gonna get some water
here to fix up my throat you know I'm
gonna take a couple more dabs and then
after that we're gonna talk about how to
determine flowering time of new
cultivars all right you guys I am back I
promised we would talk about ways to
determine flowering time of new
cultivars so maybe you got some seeds
and you don't know how long those seeds
are supposed to take maybe you maybe you
had a bunch of pack 2 seeds and these
got mixed up or mislabeled or weren't
labeled at all or maybe they came out of
a bag maybe you've got seeds that you're
running you have no idea what they are
you're gonna need to know how long to
let those plants flower maybe your buddy
gave you clothes maybe you bought clones
at the dispensary
maybe you cut clones and you don't know
which clone that is you need to
determine how long to let that plant
flower so obviously the way to the
easiest way to do that would to be
flower that plant out and then around
week seven or eight maybe eight or nine
I have to say about week seven get in
there and start looking at that plant
with a loop or a magnifier of some sort
of a magnifying glass some sort of an
eye you need at least a 60 to 100 times
magnifying glass to look at these plants
you want to see the trichomes that are
on your buds and look in a few different
places on the plant don't just look in
one spot so what I use hooks up to my
computer I've got a let me see I can go
right here on my computer it'll remind
me the brand
it's from Dino scope I've got a Dino
scope a little it's a scope that hooks
up it's a magnifying scope that hooks up
it's a USB port goes right into my
computer I works with a Mac it works
with a Windows machine I use it on a Mac
so I promise it works it was a [ __ ] to
get it started but once I downloaded the
driver and got it working it works
beautifully every time now I can take
screenshots of what I'm seeing but this
little scope I basically I can take I
take my chair
cuz it rolls and has wheels and I put
the MacBook on the chair because I'm
clumsy and I like to drop [ __ ] so I
leave the MacBook on the chair and I
roll it around and then I use the scope
it's got a nice long cord and then I use
that scope to go find the spots that I
want on the plant and then I look at the
screen and I can see if the trichomes
are amber or if the trichomes are clear
or if they're milky or if they're busted
ruptured open and got [ __ ] dripping out
of them I can see that clearly with the
scope I've got I can see bugs [ __ ] if
there is bug [ __ ] in my plants I can see
any insect in the world with this scope
that I've got so I like to pull leaf off
randomly and look at the underside of
the leaf and see what's going on look
for eggs looks for bugs look for bug
[ __ ] look for signs of bugs so what you
need if you can't get that type of a
thing for your computer they sell the
420 scope is okay I think they call it
the dope scope or the 420 scope that's
okay there's one sold at the gross store
that is made by Hydra farm which is the
one that I like I have the 100x little
scope it takes a double a battery at
full they may take two batteries but it
folds it folds together real nicely when
you unfold it it lights up and then you
can see through it real well that one I
really like but get yourself a scope so
that you can look at the trichomes at
least 60 X 100x magnification is better
it's most obvious way to tell when
plants are done when within your view
you're probably gonna see a certain
amount of trichomes it's gonna be hard
to count them but you want about
twenty-five to thirty percent of those
twenty to thirty percent of those you
want them turning amber you want it to
kind of look like the color like maybe
you dipped him in dr. pepper or maybe
they got a little they're just you could
see it it turns amber orangish color
they'll start off clear then they'll get
milky and then they get like a silvery
color and then from silver that's when
they start turning amber but when thirty
percent your items are amber that's
usually when you want to harvest most
strains so it's kind of up to you you
can go a little early you can go a
little late it's not that huge of a deal
a lot of people way over stress the
harvest window in a production facility
we say this string gets this many days
and then we're cutting it the [ __ ] down
because we have another crop coming up
right behind it so and that the weed
comes out pretty fabulous in most of the
production facilities and we just pick
something like 60 days or 70 days I like
to say 63 days because that's 9 full
weeks of flower and most of the strains
were
running nowadays nine weeks is perfect
but let's talk a little more because
this scope you're looking at the
trichomes is really gonna help you out
but you're going to need to know a
little earlier in the game when to
harvest because you're gonna need to
flush your plants about ten to fourteen
days before you start cutting down i
heavily stress flushing your plants it's
free and you've got to water the plants
anyway so why not just pour a bunch of
water in there and clean the plants out
so let's talk about some ways to
determine how long those plants are
gonna take you need to figure out how
indica or sativa dominant those plants
are and a huge indicator of that is leaf
shape and size if your leaf has really
long slender fingers it's probably
sativa dominant and you're gonna lead
more toward the nine to ten week range
maybe even longer if your plants have
big fat broad leaves if they're real
wide if the the wider the leaf probably
the shorter the flowering period is
something that I've learned it's not
always true but it's usually a good
thing to follow so if you've got good
wide leaves you're looking at eight to
nine weeks now if you've got a eight or
nine week plant the first time you run
it I recommend going nine weeks why not
try that extra week to see what happens
you may get more bulk right at the end
you may get more resin right at the end
it may harden up it may do a lot of good
[ __ ] in that last one week so let that
happen it's not gonna over ripen too
much but it don't worry about a little
over ripening it's not that huge of a
game especially if it's your first time
that's something I wrote down that I
wanted to wait a little while to mention
but this is hopefully not your last time
running this strain this is your first
time running this strain which means you
can [ __ ] it up because you have another
time and another time and another time
after that to run it hopefully if this
is a good genetic good cultivar and you
can keep it around you're gonna be
running it a bunch of times so this is
just your test run this is your first
date you'll be ok so leaf size and leaf
shape will give you a big hint on how
long those plants are gonna take if
you've got an eight or nine week plant
like I just said like the eight or nine
weekend to go let it go nine weeks
because you want it to go to full
maturity if you've got a plant with long
skinny leaves that's a 90
ten week plan I would recommend lighting
that plan go ten weeks the first time
why not you want to see what the
potential of that plan is a lot of those
sativa plants really do magical [ __ ]
toward the end of their growth phase or
at the end of their flowering phase they
bulk up they resin up they really put on
some flavor they get better at the end
they're probably swelling up because
they want to be bred too and you're not
giving them any pollen so they're just
getting bigger and bigger and stickier
and fatter so sometimes it's better to
let those sativa strains go longer I
like an 11-week sativa it doesn't scare
me to run a 77 day sativa dominant plant
flower it when it's real short be ready
to have some sticks and supports
available and get that sucker going
don't be afraid to grow something that
take seventy seven days or even maybe a
little bit longer it's well worth it
you're gonna get more potency you
usually get more weight and everybody
loves that good sativa buzz and it's
harder to find everyone's grown those
shorter indicas so if you're growing a
heavy sativa you're gonna stand out from
the crowd
medical users are gonna appreciate it
they're gonna want more recreational
users are gonna love it they're gonna
want more so that's gonna help everybody
out
so the basic leaf size is a good
indicator of how long your strain may
take from the very beginning if it's
real broad you're looking at eight to
nine weeks if you get some skinny leaves
go nine or ten weeks maybe even a little
bit longer the thing is if you start
flushing a little bit too early that's
okay if you start flushing too late
that's when you start overdoing things
you'll be okay so if you've got these
plants that are gonna end up taking
thirteen or fourteen weeks and you've
already started flushing to be prepared
for week 11 you'll be okay
they're just gonna start looking a
little ragged they're gonna turn a
little bit yellow but they'll keep going
if you're growing a really long sativa
something that I should mention if
you're a new grower and you're growing
along sativa longer than eleven weeks
you will be lucky if by the end of that
grow that plant has any big leaves left
those plants like tip they're they're
finicky and they will lose a lot of
leaves they'll look like [ __ ] but you'll
have amazing medicine still because
they're Hardy and a plant that goes that
long is meant to survive a lot of
experienced growers have a long a hard
time with a longer flowering plant
because the feeding regimen is kind of
confusing you're not sure when to phase
certain nutrients out and when to face
Sutent certain nutrients in because
everything happens at a different time
than what we're all taught about these
nine week plants everybody all the
nutrient companies that sell you stuff
most of the stuff you see
online when they're recommending feeding
they're basing that on about an eight to
nine week flowering phase and most of
them don't even give you enough time to
flush most tell you to flush for one
week because they want you to keep
pumping [ __ ] product into your plants
so my points all this is that you can't
really over flush so be prepared to
flush flush like normal and if the
plants look like they want longer let
them go longer you can tell if they want
to go longer by using the scope that's
pretty much the only way you can get in
there and tell also something that will
give you a hint of how long the plants
are going to take is the basic structure
structure my words are hard to say today
I apologize the basic structure of your
plants how how tall they get how quickly
how much they branch out how bushy the
plant is is it growing straight up if
that plants going straight up and not
making a lot of side branches you've
probably got yourself a sativa dominant
plant that's gonna take a little longer
to flower it's just gonna keep going
straight up if you've got a plant that
is growing really long lanky branches
and it's just going really really fast
that plant may take a little longer to
flower if your plant is staying short
and stocky and real squatty and just
getting wider and wider as it grows
you've probably gotten indica dominant
plant which is also you're gonna have to
put that trait together with your leaf
size and kind of put those two together
and let those two things kind of give
you hints of how much indica and how
much sativa and those plants and how
long you should let them go if you've
got seeds in the breeder pack says that
they're done in eight to nine weeks I
recommend you let them go nine weeks
maybe even let them go a little bit
longer if you can I like to let stuff go
I'm kind of weird I'll it I like things
to go nine ten or eleven weeks just cuz
I it's easier to remember I know a lot
of strains that I run sixty-three days
is perfect for most of them alright you
guys so that is basically ways to figure
out flowering times of new seeds and new
clones that you've got check the
trichomes if you've got a scope if you
can hook your scope up to your computer
I recommend you check in three places
check at the top of the plant that big
top bud check that one check in the
middle of the plant so you know how you
got the top and if you didn't do any
topping you got a top and then there's
buds that come up right underneath that
the next part of the crown the next part
of the bouquet check some of those check
like right around that ring there and
then go down a little bit further in the
plant and check down
and see how the difference is going you
may be really amber down at the bottom
you may be really clear at the top I
like to harvest one about 30% of the
total trichomes have started to show
amber so it kind of looks like you got a
little bit of dr. pepper on them or a
little bit of root beer or something and
they're just starting to turn a little
bit brownish if you wait too long they
all start turning that color I feel like
they kind of the plants lose their
flavor you can cut them a little bit
earlier they're gonna taste better
here's part of the deal you cut them
sooner they taste better you cut him a
little bit later they probably get
heavier and more potent so that's that's
something you want to balance on
yourself
most people are focused on getting as
much as they can from each light or each
square foot or each square meter or each
table however you're growing nowadays
and however you're doing the measurement
for your own business plan so most
people want to let it go that extra few
days and add on that extra bulk and I
mean you can they just get more potent
in my opinion as you let them go so guys
that's mostly ways to kind of
predetermine how long to let your plants
flower all right you guys I wrote down a
couple of more notes that I want to talk
about that I was inspired to rant on
because of this topic but before I get
that far I need a dad I don't need a dad
but makes me sound weird when I say that
I need a dad I felt weird I would love
to take a dab with you guys so if you
were in a safe place where you can smoke
start getting a DAB ready I'm taking the
lid off of some golden goat shatter from
tiara concentrate this golden goat
shatter is amazing there's very little
left because I really like it
I keep aah I keep coming up to the to
the table where the email is and I'm
like I'm gonna take a little dab of that
golden go and I just get a little dab it
and I take it bad and I get the flavor
on my mouth but it saved us such a
little dab that he doesn't really get me
high because I take a lot of dads you
guys I take a lot of big dads so be like
[ __ ] I gotta take another little dad
I'll take the little dad I feel like two
or three those little like you know what
[ __ ] it I'm just gonna take a big dad
and I'll take a big dad that I should
have just started with and then I end up
really high it's funny I like it so this
gram of golden go shatter has not lasted
very long at all good job do whoever
drew the material and then a really good
job to our friends at tiara concentrates
this came out wonderfully it is just
straight shatter I talk about different
consistencies of hash this is like a
little pane of glass wrapped in
parchment it's not that sharp because
it's more like Jolly Ranchers it's like
if you had a sheet of joe
rancher it would just be snappy like
this I'm trying to fold it back up so
that I could put this away all right
I've got the hash on to the dabber I've
got the hash put away putting it back in
my child proof child safe container I
just like keep it in that container
because it's labeled got a couple of the
flavors over here all right so you got
me a DAB I'm gonna heat up the nail
right now I'm smoking on a quartz banger
so let's talk about some different nails
a lot of times you see me using the
email if you've ever watched me on
Instagram it's a nail it's made out of
titanium and it's got a cord attached to
it and actually attaches to a box and
that box keeps the nail at the
appropriate temperature for taking dads
all the time I'm not using that right
now it is right here next to me it's
turned on but I want to use this rig
that I was uh that I want so I've got a
quartz banger it kind of looks like a
normal bowl like a pipe bowl or it's
it's basically just a little dish it's a
quartz dish
it's pinky deep it looks like a thimble
it's almost like a thimble you guys but
it's quartz and uh so it's course it's
gotta of course it's got a little piece
that goes into the ring and it goes into
the rig just kind of like where a bong
bowl would go and then of course I'm
using the rig I won from elevate it's a
pumpkin looking rig so with a little
pumpkin on the back which is the coolest
part so I'm gonna heat the Banger it's
gonna be hard to hear me probably while
I do that I got a lot of compression
going on here but I don't think it'll
cut this out but while I heat it make
sure you check out the dank team.com
they've got a fresh crop of ira genetics
and stock so make sure you check them
out for feminized and regular cannabis
seeds means all right you guys are just
a couple of seconds something to take a
dab of this golden go and then we'll get
on with this podcast I do appreciate you
dabbing with me I hope you're heating
the nail right now my nail has got the
cool excited it's way over heated it's
kind of cleaning off some funk so I'll
hold the nail cool all right guys let's
dab together here we go
feels cool let's do this
that's a pretty big dad maybe bigger
than I needed for a podcast but what
could go wrong right I just gotta say
her talking to a microphone oh yeah yes
excellent work to my friends or to our
concentrates this golden go shatter is
amaze balls I approve all right my head
will quit spinning here in just a couple
of seconds then we're gonna move on with
the parts that I wrote it down I'm glad
I wrote them down cuz I would have
forgotten by now let's take one last
drink here then we'll get on with this
guys I hope you took a fat dab with me
if you're dabbing with me while we're on
the ball you're listening to the show
send me a tweet let me know what you're
smoking on tweet me at G fyh podcast on
twitter at g f YH podcast I'd love to
know that you're smoking with me and I'd
love to know what you're smoking on
alright so let's get to the notes that I
wrote down who I wrote down that
phenotype variations will take different
times to flower which means if you buy a
package of seeds not every seed in that
package is going to take the same amount
of time to flower you may get one strain
that takes or one phenotype that takes
nine weeks and you may get one phenotype
that takes ten weeks to flower out of
the same package now the reason for that
I'll explain a little bit why that comes
to do when I talk about f1 and f2
breeding and f3 and f4
when you make an f1 it's got a very wide
variety of traits it'll bring out traits
from the mother plant and the father
plant they were used of the female and
the male so the girl plant they received
the pollen and the male plant that threw
pollen those traits are gonna show but
also the grandparents so whatever female
you used the male and female used for
that are going to show up in your F
wands and whatever you used for the male
the male and female used to make that is
gonna show up in your f1 seeds so you're
gonna see grandma you're gonna see
grandpa and then you're also gonna see
Grandma and Grandpa on the other side
and then you're also gonna see mommy and
you're also gonna see daddy so you're
gonna have a lot of different phenotypes
popping up from
laughs once this is a possibility so you
may get one that takes eight weeks you
may get one that takes ten weeks and
this is very possible so when you make
those F ones there's a lot of variation
so what we do is breeders we find the
most desirable female that you can find
out of all of your seeds out of the f
wands you want the one that is whatever
you're looking for the best stink or the
best growth or the best resin you want
the best all-around girl and then you
want to take pollen from the male from
the same generation and throw that
pollen onto that girl and the seeds that
come from there will be called f2 f2 s
will be a little bit more stabilized
meaning you're not gonna see as much
representation of the grandparents pop
up in the seeds but you're gonna see a
little bit closer to the mommy and daddy
and you're gonna start narrowing it down
a little bit more closely to what you're
trying to make with that seed line
something interesting that happens with
an f2 cross is called transgressive
segregation you actually see the the
kids outperform the parents is generally
what happens you'll see it'll also go
the other way also you'll see weaker
traits also but we call those as
breeders hopefully so you'll see if you
put a gigantic male and a gigantic
female and the male makes super stank
and the female make super resin you put
them together you just may make the
super Hulk by on your f2s
because you're gonna see that
transgressive segregation come through
mostly in the f2 generation is where I
find a bat so then I would find my
favorite f2 right the best looking girl
of that f2 that's got the traits I'm
going after hopefully it was very
similar to the F ones you know what I
mean you found the one that looked like
you were going after and then you go
find another one that looks like that
that's an f2 or that's improved and then
you hit it with the pollen from the f2
male now you have to find a male and a
female and then you hit the the female
with the male pollen and when those
seeds come out you have now made f3 now
what I'm getting at is every time you do
that if you do it correctly sometimes
you have to go back you have got to keep
a bag of seeds from the old ones that go
back and re hunt but if you do it
correctly when you go through each time
you're going to make that strain more
stable and more stable so you'll start
off with like five different phenotypes
and you
again and now hopefully you just worked
it down to like three solid phenotypes
and then you breed it again and then you
got two solid phenotypes to wear when
you grow these plants your fifty-fifty
gonna get this one or this one you know
what I mean that's what it's gonna be
kind of like and then hopefully you can
breed it down to where by the time you
get to f5 which takes a long time you
guys that is years of breeding and years
of developing because you got to find
the males and the females and then
sometimes you don't find what you're
looking for so you finish a crop and you
just start over and I actually searched
through I'd say 250 seats to find inner
eyes male and I threw away a good
portion of the females that popped up
because it wasn't what I needed at the
time so by the time you get to an f5
you'll be growing out these seeds and
they will look like clones if you do it
correctly five or six I think
yeah if five is about where they'll come
out really close f6 will look like
clones but I wouldn't want to take it
that far because then nobody else could
breed to it it would just be whatever
you bred to it would come out looking
like that
all the time but just be real dominant
genes so every time you breed to it if
you do it correctly it makes it more
stable so what I'm getting at is a lot
of the breeders on the market right now
are selling UF ones which is not a bad
thing I appreciate it
gage green sells F ones and one of my
favorite brands to buy is gage green
genetics because I love the variation
that comes in the f1 I get to see a lot
of neat stuff I actually had the honor
of being a tester for gage green so I
get to see a lot of great [ __ ] come out
of their garden I got to test a lot of
great seeds I loved F ones because of
that so you may get an f1 that takes 8
weeks you may get an f1 that takes 9
weeks from the same exact pack of seeds
now you've got a decision to make do you
want to cut that one down early and
change your feeding regimen and have two
different plants that you've got to feed
or do you just want to let them all go
that 60 days sixty-four days
56 days it's up to you you get to decide
that stuff but that's a decision you've
got to make if you can tell early on and
flower that one is kind of taking off
and getting a little bit taller than the
others I mean you may have some thinking
to do right at the beginning there that
may give you a hint so different seeds
are the same seed packet different
phenotypes you may have different
flowering times
I really love searching through seed
packs and finding the phenotypes because
depending on what you're working with
you may find some really great [ __ ] you
may also find some ridiculous stuff but
in the same pack I found completely
purple buds that were short and compact
and plants make purple bright purple
buds and I've also had plants that make
tall velvety bright green buds and I
couldn't decide which phenotype to keep
so I kept them both and I called them
just different phenotypes so female
hunting is fun I really love it that's
one of my favorite things to do so
expect some variation also something I
wrote down is different flowering times
in different rooms and environments so
if I gave you clones if I gave you
clones and I gave one of your other
friends clones and I gave a couple other
guys clones and you guys all took it to
your grow room you may see that your
room wants these plants to flower in 58
days they may be perfectly finished in
58 days if I give somebody else plants
they may need 63 days if we're getting
right down to it so environmental can
have a lot to do with it you guys
also indoors and outdoors you're gonna
see huge differences in different areas
our buds are gonna look completely
different if we're growing them in
California if we're growing them in
Colorado altitudes make a huge
difference environmental factors like
that will play a huge difference in your
flowering times yep alright I think I've
gone I'm filling enough you guys we're
at 32 minutes now so I think I'm gonna
wrap up the recording ladies and
gentlemen I appreciate you for listening
to this long of an episode of just me
ranting it feels like I'm talking for a
long time when I do a 30-minute episode
by myself so I truly appreciate you guys
hanging on for it if you've got anything
you'd like me to talk about on the
podcast I would love to hear from you
send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
I love the listener generated content it
lets me know that I'm hitting my target
with the information that I need to be
delivering I know I'm at least helping
one person at a time out there when I do
this so please send me an email if I
have answered your emails on any
episodes I truly appreciate it thank you
for the content if you've got a product
you'd like me to review or if you'd like
to sponsor the podcast you can also send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you guys I would love it if
you go to iTunes go to the comment
section actually you gotta go to iTunes
go to the iTunes Store so
for the girl from your heart podcast
click on the girl from your heart
podcast go to the reviews section the
ratings and reviews section type in a
little comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on a future episode while
you're there you have the option to
click on some stars give me as many
stars as you feel I deserve so far
everybody has given me a five star
review I've got thirty five five star
ratings at this time thank you to
everybody who's gone there and left a
comment and left me a review I will read
the ones the reviews that I have not
read I will catch those up on a very
soon upcoming episode you guys that's
all I've got free this week I hope you
join me in a few days big shadowplay
ninja Spence and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]