yeah welcome back cannabis community let
me clear my throat for episode number
163 of the girl from heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross the Jeff
onna thank you guys again for joining me
as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat coot and the entire mystic roots
crew ladies and gentlemen thanks for uh
dealing with the clogged up throat it's
Jesse's fault I blame it on Jesse Jesse
showed up with good hash and liquid
Terps
welcome to the show Jesse thank you
please and Jenna and Jesse grows is back
if you're not following Jesse on
Instagram follow him on Instagram it's
at Jesse grows I'm pretty sure yeah yeah
follow him there also he's got a podcast
tell everyone how they can find your
podcast bro SoundCloud yeah it's the
Colorado podcast HollyRod dope podcast
you guys check that out
he's got despicable D on there he's got
44 on there and sometimes dude named
fetus that hangs out on the show I
actually mentioned tater yesterday yeah
dude a long time in Colorado again I
thought he was gone so what's up tater
we're gonna have to get together I owe
you a high-five in a DAB we got a
hangout bro there you go shut up
dictator if you listen to the podcast
two episodes in a row you got ya got a
mention bro um so Jesse's back hey
something I got to mention you guys I
know I know I'm gonna get a whole bunch
of [ __ ] messages I said the wrong
episode number at the start of the last
episode I did not have any notes in
front of me with the episode number
written on it like I normally do I wrote
it down this time I think I got it right
although I did have to clear my throat
we did the best we could please stop
with the tweets I know I said the wrong
I love you guys thanks for trying to
keep me on the right path
so before we hit record here Jesse we
like to hang out before the podcast we
get nice and medicated we get into a
talking little zone here he's gonna on a
Clint hasn't been taken a lot of dad's
hasn't been consuming a lot of cannabis
so when he took the first dab I watched
him he's a big dude and I just watched
him kind of melt a little bit after the
first dab he brought over some liquid
sfv some San Fernando Valley OG Kush
Turks uh and some Durbin poison wax I
dunked a dab of what am i smoking some
jack flash yeah I dunked a dab of Jack
flash into the Terps I was trippin Delic
it was amazing dude thank you
turpitude oh I think that might be my
word I might be the only one that says
stupid Ella
Webster's new word of the year Webster's
swag Harry so we were talking before the
show as I was mentioning we're getting
nice and roasted and medicated taking
dad's off the email and Jesse was
telling me that he went to Oregon and he
was actually ballsy enough to take his
medicine on the plane with him a whole
bunch of it a whole bunch of it will
tell it tell everybody what you traveled
on a plane with I took my breasts um
this is gonna sound ridiculous
I took a library as water hash rosin
some flour a little bit of clear some
turps and a couple of the doctor's
orders of a pen cartridges did you have
a ring with and two rigs pretty much
everything but a torch yeah yeah I knew
not to ticket or yeah you cannot take
the torch they'll taste it torch that is
very similar to a bomb it's already a
bomb essentially yes they don't they
don't want that on the plane so I took
all that well the rigs were in a locked
case so and I put the rigs in my
check-in baggage okay all the product
that I kept it on my purse or in my
carry-on it was back sealed and then in
a ziplock baggie and I took my med card
and a copy of my driver's license and
put it in there so it was the first
thing they would see they totally went
through my bag and it went through the
x-ray scanner and everything and I flew
there and back with with it all okay and
nobody gave you any harassment at all
never so you get to enjoy your medical
marijuana's while you were in the great
state of Oregon and Washington and
Washington I flew out of a different
Airport oh that is cool
somebody had a great vacation yeah it
was very much needed what was your
favorite part getting to see my best
friend from high school and lifelong
buddy get married to a woman he is
absolutely crazy about was very cool but
the Oregon coast is just absolutely
unbelievable it's so stunning nice yeah
I highly recommend checking shout out to
the new to the new married couple
hundred if they listen to a podcast but
no I'm glad you're back I'm glad you had
a great time I've been trying to get you
on for a little while you've been a busy
dude you've got a new job there we were
talking about how many plants you run
well was on yesterday will was running I
think he said 640 plants is what I think
he said on his own and now we were
talking too near runnin you've got beds
of 500 plants sections of 500 planets so
everybody's been killing it commercial
growth
it's awesome to hear it's a lot of work
this is uh but basically I've had I've
ran little med shop grows and now I'm in
a big yeah it's a lot of you were saying
earlier that it took you all day to cut
three to four hundred clones yeah yeah
people there were people that would
probably they probably heard that that
went [ __ ] man I could probably cut a
thousand calls today of grade a you know
perfectly chosen right perfectly chosen
and you said that you don't keep mother
plants that you take the clones off the
veg plants you've got to run through the
veg area with a cup or a container of
water and get cuts
gather them up and then go back to the
cloning area to consult back with with
the schedule I've got to look at the
schedule of stuff that's already been
harvested and I got to look at the stuff
that is gonna be before it so that we
have we have a specific program to
harvest four strains a week out of our
16 strains so that we always have extra
non-hand and to keep in track with all
of that also is it's a lot of work man
it's things that people don't think
about is trying to keep the variety
coming consistently
because in aggro you're gonna want to
put let's do this whole row of Sour
Diesel per se just because you want that
whole row but then when it comes time to
put it on the shelf now you've got a
whole bunch of Sour Diesel so if
somebody comes to the dispensary to buy
product we gonna should turn a sour
diesel if that's all you're interested
in and then see where a wholesaler so
that makes it even worse
so the dispensary buyer comes to us and
you know we got a whole bunch of Sour
Diesel even if it's bomb you know
they're probably just gonna go on
so that's rain big reasons we have to
have a everybody like the variety that
31 flavors yeah that's what keeps them
coming back if you could probably if you
could probably sell 10 pounds of that
sour diesel but if you had five other
strains you could probably salt seven
pounds of each one of them just because
of the variety yeah yes a variety of
this kink that's gonna people don't
think about what it takes
I've been talking a little bit about it
on the show about commercial growing
people don't think about what it takes
it's good to hear you come in and talk
about just scheduling the clones cuz it
starts at the clones you got a schedule
two clones to know what your variety is
going to be in about a hundred and
twenty days yeah so it's more like
ninety four for my situation but you
know these don't it's yeah planning
preparation and then everything you do
this is something that I got sidetracked
on when I was talking with will
everything you do has to be documented
in metric pretty much if your scissors
touch a plant you have to open up a
computer and make a note somewhere in
the damn computer that something
happened we have one person spends 40
hours a week doing nothing but that man
yeah I know I mean that's this MacBook
on a cart was actually a trash can with
a piece of wood on top of it excited
trash bin on wheels and I pushed around
to water one of the smaller areas it was
like for water in small plants I put the
board on top of that and put the MacBook
on top of there and that was my metric
station roll that around and just do my
metric right there just made 900 clones
of this just harvested this if you cut
off so there are varying different
different compliance officers will tell
you different rules on this if you cut
off something on a plant it needs to be
weighed and documented in metric you
have to go to that plant tag number you
have to say I manicured
point four grams off of plant number
nine zero five five five and then you
have to show on camera that you
destroyed the part that was manicured
off the plant it's but it's very tedious
and metric very tedious all right so we
talked about dabs on a plane Jesse got
way I was taking [ __ ] on a plane and he
looks like an ogre - and they didn't
even then we talked about you knew gross
space let's talk about what we brought
you here for the main top of the G whoa
when we talked on Facebook you're like I
want to talk about reminding people to
clean up their gross space after the
outdoor season for sure yeah so what do
you want to tell us about that that is a
super good topic I mean it depends on
how you grow I guess but you know I'm an
organic grower kind of homestead style
as a term a real farmer yeah yes a term
I've been using lately I picked it up
from a person in Oregon so who should
give that person a shout-out did you
mention the podcast at all yeah I'm not
surprised
hippie Mary she lived on the coast down
the road from the place I was staying
and it's normally not like me to go out
and just randomly start talking to
strangers but for some reason I there
were some huge tomato plants at her yard
that kind of attracted me to her so
ended up making a friend out there but
that's the true farmer in you
yeah the tomato plants made of plants
are done in Colorado they've been
harvested and eaten by now and she had
Tomatoes up there and Jessi was like oh
yeah no that's uh I told her how she
grows or how I grew she actually had a
couple plants out back too but uh I - I
told her how I grew and she called me a
homestead farmer so a homestead grower
so I kind of like that term I like that
it feels good sure but my situation I've
got living soil I've got a whole bunch
of plant waste the the leaves the stalks
all that so I've taken all of that and
ran it through a chipper into the
compost pile okay so by next you know
summer that will be nice black compost
and
I'll have you know all the nutrients
that we're still in it and this is the
this would be the third year we've done
this but it just all goes right back
into the system again that's awesome
so I up my soil real good I've I watered
it down real good and I've got it
covered with plastic to store it over
the winter um that gonna make it nice up
mycelium layer happened in there funk
okay on and that's a good thing you guys
when you start seeing a lot of people
see that white fuzz they'll make you
super soil or there or they'll make some
compost yeah and they see that white
fuzz and they freak out that's what
you're working for that's the goal that
white fuzz is magic yes sir
that's what's gonna make all the [ __ ]
happen covered yeah we got all that
handled the plastic is good for several
things it helps insulate the soil on
really cold days I mean on really cold
days it's it's gonna get cold
there's nothing you can do about that
but on days when it warms up and then it
cools off again it can the the warmer
the soil stays the more breakdown
happens the more healthy is alive yeah
so it protects it from that it protects
it from getting blown away drying out
and blowing you know all the precious
topsoil off and then also something I've
noticed last year is it keeps the damn
neighborhood cats from yeah neighborhood
cats love to piss and do their thing in
your in your nice fresh garden soil so
it keeps them away too
perfect yes cats probably helps keep the
birds out possibly Oh birds wouldn't be
so bad but yeah but yeah so I'm shaking
shoot into there oh yeah well that goes
into the compost pile so it just all
returns back to the do you use a bow
coffee bucket at home yes
before that Bokashi bucket right into
there do you have another use for it um
normally I put it in the compost pile or
I'll just bury it directly in one of the
beds okay oh nice but here lately I'm
gonna go ahead and compost it inside
after it's done in the bucket I'll put
it in a little
miniature tumblr I made and that'll be
to redo or make it less acidic okay and
then I'm gonna feed it to my new worm
inside warm bins so awesome yeah you and
Spence are both doing worms Barefoot's
doing worms everyone's going worm life
it's awesome I love it it's good to see
everybody doing worms have you tried to
use the stuff from your Bo Kashi bucket
the drainage that they call it the
leachate that's a stinky foot smell and
juice that comes out of there if you
have a clogged drain pour that [ __ ]
right down the drain like probably two
ounces down a clogged drain it'll
dissolve if you got like a hair clog or
whatever is in there it'll I've got
these dreadlocks down to my [ __ ]
knees so I get some hair clogs and
there's the drain the shower just pour
that in there it'll clean it right up
it'll stink you gotta pour it in there
let it soak all through a give it like
an hour and then just go to run the hot
water kind of push it down and get rid
of the smell it eats it right up nice
yeah remember you told me you clean the
clone machines basically dissolves all
the funky layer that the cloner gets
covered in calcium and stuff yeah you
guys take good care of your cloners I
had a cloner since I didn't clean it out
good enough I got clogged up and fried
itself so my fault yep all right we're
talking about compost pile sorry I
totally set transcended track you
another thing on that's on the bow Kashi
liquid that is basically I've been told
this from two people that really know
their stuff that is basically em1 yes so
it's like great white shark yes actually
yeah I've been using em1 all summer and
I I've been getting it from a friend
I've been making it myself and I'm out
so for the last couple weeks I've just
been using bo khosh II bucket juice when
I normally would use the em1 and I see
no noticeable changes it's other than
the the rotting trash can be king foot
smell there's such great stuff smells
like a a bard dumpster yeah it's bit
that has food to it somebody threw up in
yeah all right so you're composting all
of your stocks all of your big leaves
that aren't usable for any product it's
all going into the compost pile
chicken shits in there nitrogen all your
food waste that you've been eating all
the time goes into your Bo Kashi bucket
so you're making fertilizer out of that
that gets buried we've got our soil
covered up got the soil covered up you
can actually breathe em if you're you
know I'm not necessarily no-till wearing
that so you can go ahead and actually
re-emit now and put all your amendments
you would put it in the spring and it
just makes everything better how much of
that old root ball do I need to get out
of there before I do that I leave all
over them you just chop the stick and
then kind of dig another hole later
yeah and yeah if you keep the soil wet
and active throughout the winter in the
span the early spring there will be no
root ball when you come back to it
everything if you let it dry out and you
don't cover it the root ball will still
very much be there okay okay keep it
moist in the earth we'll eat it yeah
reassimilate it turn back in the booth
okay all right so you can read now in
the winter and that stuff will hopefully
rebuttal colonize and keep producing
itself right then you'll have even more
potent soil by the time it's time to
grow outdoors yep okay so and then at
that point the only things I would add
in would just be like kelp and alfalfa
things that are they're gonna break down
all the way through to where you know
there's basically none left for it so
you know go ahead and hit Hayes really
stumbled all over that's early
go ahead when you plant go ahead and do
like a micro eyes that inoculant and
then add a little kelp and this is when
you're landing yeah I'll kind of little
alfalfa to the soil I'm getting ready to
roll so nice we can talk more about that
later shows yeah we're definitely gonna
record a whole bunch of outdoor episodes
for next year so that we've got them
prepared yeah we were both so busy this
year yeah these big commercial girls
keep us on our feet my summer next year
is looking to be even busier how do you
already know that
well because it's only a few months away
that is true so yeah that's after
November well we'll know if it's got to
happen
so we're just wait until then but we
have an out and this is a whole nother
outfit we we have an outline we have
property they have licensing everything
like that so excellently waiting to pull
the trigger
everything you seem to get involved in
seems to take off and go to get a good
launch so yeah I'm sure it's gonna work
for you I've been uh yeah I stumble into
all these startups it's kind of weird
because you're a guy they can get [ __ ]
done and people need somebody like you
they can get [ __ ] done true yeah and the
girl store doesn't hurt either and I
know how to grow and I know how I know
how to do things but I don't know as
much on how to get [ __ ] done as you do
so I need a guy like you to [ __ ]
build the walls and build the tables and
then once you get the tables built and I
can come in and build the watering
system and run the plants that's why
you're on the move and I'm on the move
yeah we run it a few times they decided
we need to remodel and rebuild and so
call Jesse back I'll take a few months
off and go somewhere else and Jesse
couldn't rebuild then I'll come back and
regrow and we'll just keep playing dance
around and build [ __ ] all grow go grow
it places maybe we'll get you girl out
doors this summer that sounds awesome
we can't do it here I mean my backyard
fences oh no no I'm talking like 3,500
blasts let's do it I mean let's go game
okay I've been albino for long hey we'll
work in the shade of the plants there we
go yeah girl tall enough where I could
be shaded under him that's rad I'm so in
so you guys Jesse mentioned he said we
will wait till this November to decide
if that's gonna happen
there's an election coming up we may get
a president that doesn't want medical
cannabis or recreational cannabis at all
that may might put a kibosh on some of
our plans but more locally what jesse is
talking about we have amendment 200 and
amendment 300 here in Pueblo Colorado
if those pass the marijuana industry in
Pueblo Colorado will be forced to shut
down in 17 they get a full year D to
keep going but after that it's over so
no new licenses he's not like these
people even though they have a license
they've never grown before
and and it's kind of a change of
location for him to so they went under
the new proposal they wouldn't be able
to let it happen yeah good luck I hope
everything is it's probably gonna be too
late by the time this episode comes out
I hope you voted please I don't give you
huge shout out to Mike to white Mike
[ __ ] you Nemo Punk everything he's done
yeah he's been putting huge efforts in
for the no on 50 no on 200 campaign the
no on 300 campaign he did more
groundwork than anybody else I saw shout
it to everybody else that participated I
know I'm giving Mike all the credit I
know there's a bunch of you but Mike is
a person that let it in my eye I know
there are more of you but Mike is one of
my best friends I saw him doing it
he owes a huge shout-out I can name a
few more names but I can't name them all
so right yeah yeah yeah there's a couple
people I know that deserve a shout-out
but I don't exactly know their names but
I know they're all Mike's team so Mike
spread the love let them know they're
getting shoutouts from the podcast
thanks for what you do bro we're gonna
get you on a podcast here in a couple
days you can't notice you can't be on
every damn show Janet's white Mike in
the family okay
hope you guys are having fun on the
couch this evening it's a warm fall
Saturday it's so warm it's like 80
degrees in my house because we expected
winter to come I covered up my swamp
cooler so that it would because it was
cold the other night there was coming in
there and freezing me when I was trying
to watch Marcos no be more oh yeah
they're gonna do a Cali cartel which
isn't nearly as exciting right it'll
still be pretty I wasn't I had an
attachment to that show oh yeah 20
episodes was not enough I love anything
drug smuggling culture I just eat it up
I've read a few books I've watched every
documentary I mean yeah the dude The Big
Lebowski will be at a the chronic condo
meet him and take your picture with them
smoke a J with the dude
yeah all right so let's get a little bit
back I don't think we finished up
talking about cleaning the garden so
we've got a top tray or kind of Riya
mended for next year we filled it with
some kelp and some alfalfa meal and then
when it comes time for season we're
gonna dig a little hole and we're gonna
put some michael rises in there some
more kelp some more alfalfa maybe some
crab meal yeah maybe some warm castings
oh yeah okay our or just warms
themselves themselves yeah guys get the
worms going the worms are so if you've
got the compost pile you know by all
means use it up so that yeah put that in
there put that in your holes so that
sounds so gross but then in the holes
where you're planning your plants so
that all that compost that rich compost
can feed those plants even if you're
sorry to cut you know go far even if
you're grown in pots you can still
utilize that that compost even if you're
using salt based chemical nutrients you
can still utilize yes I love the trend
that I'm seeing on Instagram and social
media and even the forums of people
they're recycling soil and running
no-till and you're seeing them top dress
and decorate their plants to keep like a
layer in their tour they can keep the
moisture in putting stuff like alfalfa
sprouts and other sprouts on top of
there and I'm loving the way that it
looks in a nice indoor garden with these
there's other growth on top of your play
a little little eco sphere on top of
your plant there sure and then you got a
pot plant growing out of it and out of
it is dying and actually feeding your
plant it's such a it's such a neat
little thing to learn and see happen
it's like a miniature environment yeah
it's that permaculture is that the word
I'm looking for
no they'd be no-till which is a
permaculture value but permaculture is
hard to wrangle into one set you know
one definition okay it's just a way of
looking at things so I learned something
today all right so we've got our plants
so now we're still at the end of the
season let's keep ourselves kind of on
track we're at the end of the season
we've cleaned up we've got our compost
pile everything's chipped up
everything's covered we put some stuff
where the old plants were now what
should we focus on other than that
cleaning up your trash you know
inevitable every grows got a little bit
you know
beer bottles or you know old netting dr.
pepper bottles yeah you know it's the
exact wrapper yeah get get all that [ __ ]
cleaned up it looks bad
get your cages put away if you use those
if you're netting or whatever get that
I'll put up any kind of shade cloth if
you want to reuse it next year you need
to store it away and get it out of the
weather same with like your water
barrels your air pumps any kind of
liquid nutrients you had outside you
need to get all that inside and in a
warm place you know and don't bring it
inside to your grow area yeah don't do
that
don't bring the bugs and mildew into
your garden put it in the shed outside
clean it if you can take some time and
clean it yeah just polish it up if you
had a fan or something outside take it
apart clean it please clean it with some
h2o too or some of that I think it's the
same thing but the thirty percent
hydrogen peroxide clean it with some of
that I don't know clean everything wear
gloves you guys
or even like enzymes complete or hires I
more so yeah or some of the Bokashi
juice yeah yeah you know clean your
stuff up be creative you know use what's
at your disposal dr. Bonner so but I
mean some of that was so like what's
like some pine oil and some or something
like that in it would that's gonna kill
anything so you know yeah I like the dr.
Bronner's yeah wash my dreads with it
you can wash everything with it yeah
it's perfect
alright so clean up get out there and
clean everything up take all the
equipment out of there make it look like
there was never a grow there yeah okay
if you're if you grow in pots and you
want to reuse all your soil even if
you're not if you're growing pots and
you're not reusing your soil throw it
away like you know it's just if you had
any issues they're still lingering there
you know if you are gonna reuse it get
it all in a pile get it wet cover it
with plastic it's the same principle we
were talking about with covering the
with the raised beds and everything so
you know if we had some fungus gnats or
powdery mildew is that going to be kind
of destroyed in the composting process
order or is that kind of compound fungus
gnats if you get it heated if you get
the pile heated up enough
which means you've got to add a
considerable amount of raw green
material and just organic matter to it
for it to heat back up it will most
definitely kill the fungus now okay
powdery mildew I have no idea okay so
now we might we might be killing
ourselves trying to do both because I
think if you put the green in there
the PML girl in the green but I don't
think the PM can grow on things that are
not leafy for sure well I mean green
matter could even be like green manure I
mean a guy he could be cow shed it could
be anything that's gonna heat up grass
clippings if he feels it leaves an old
pot leaves yeah okay
I mean poop yeah oh yeah chicken poop is
just such a great amendment I know it's
funny that I say that because I'm a
vegetarian I don't even eat the chickens
but I've noticed that when chicken poop
goes into a compost goes into plants it
really does something and then see bird
poop also yeah any sort of sea bird poop
anything from the sea is really really
rich oh I love the way see stuff gross
yeah it's that's why that Kush smells so
good see Kanaks if I ever had to label
the way I like to grow you know that's
Sikh annexes you want me to edit that
out to know that nobody steals that cuz
that's it might be a phrase you want it
no because there may be someone on the
coast that's like way more worthy of
easing that I'm not worried about it
some girl around the coast that wants to
make some sea but you better be getting
like your own kelp in your home purchase
impress me don't do that you did not
hear that
man there's kelp laying all over the
beach in Oregon if it's okay you're
probably gonna get in trouble if you
collect it I don't organ it stinks okay
yeah I'm pretty sure people wouldn't
mind get it put in some bottles and ship
the first tester batches to Jesse I'd
love to try it rinse all the salt off
first please
please I could just see the plants just
forget to rinse the kelp we are way off
topic but we are still on topic it's
amazing how we do it
clean this is something I deal with
every year and I [ __ ] did it this
year
clean out your your outdoor spray
bottles because like mine have T's go
through it which has a lot of molasses
and they always clog up oh yeah and then
in the spring I'm just like [ __ ] and
end up throwing it away and go and get
in the new pumping you guys ready yeah I
cleaned them all out with super hot
water this year I'm good to go for next
year you guys by the pump sprayers that
have the nozzle on it where you can
release the pressure with you want to be
able to release that pressure because
otherwise you'll pump it up real hard
and the [ __ ] the nozzle gets stuck
you'll never get it off of there now you
can't refill it and you just throw it
away because you'll try to pop it open
with something you're gonna break it
some of the plastic somewhere will spin
or trust me get there with the kind the
type that happens the pressure release
valve so you can once it's pumped up and
pressurized you can take that pressure
off it's really scary trying to undo it
when you got like neem oil in there you
don't just spray up in your face I saw
that happen with someone that had a tank
full of for might once oh god I could
backpack tank oh they're pumping it
pumping it and they didn't have that lid
screwed on all the way right yeah that
was back before anyone well lots of
people knew better but we didn't yeah
before we knew that floor might was a
no-go if you got to do something if you
get a brand new clone and it came from
somebody and you really really want it
but it might have something hit it if
you need to mother that out take clones
from that yeah go smoke in the Florham I
did one at least try to get a generation
from there alright so we've cleaned up
everything we've got we want to cover up
the holes for night the area for next
year do you just want to leave it
exposed oh you want that cover okay
cover that up so that all the stuff can
process in there get some heat in there
you got your compost pile going
we got everything cleaned up it doesn't
even look like a girl happened in that
yard or that field anymore right yeah
just make it look nice and good yeah and
it's all it's a clean slate for you to
go back next year and then as soon as
the snow melts and you're thinking about
growing the next thing to do is
there and fix all of the holes in your
fences and go check that fence go make
sure that that thing is super secure go
pick up all of the [ __ ] I'm sure your
dog or one of your buddies dogs been out
there drop in deuces go pick that up you
know coming around because a dog poop
out there as soon as it gets warm that's
the stuff you got to do then and uh I
mean to pick depending on how serious
you get I actually I know of a couple
people that are already growing their
plants for next season but you know if
you're a small you know 25 35 plant or
less outdoor grow you can get away with
you know you can start your plants in
February probably if you're growing from
seed and you want to do a female
selection I suggest starting now but if
you're grown from clones
you know February you can start you know
start them up if you're going for trees
so start them up get huge you don't live
and I don't let them get root bound and
I ever yeah cuz they will start to
flower on you they will start flowering
so bedroom inside get them big top them
get them loved don't let them get root
bound to the pest free don't run yeah
keep them pest free do not run them on a
24 hour light unless you plan on putting
them outside underneath the 24 hour like
see I would have never thought of that
yeah yeah I mean if you got a hoop house
and you can run a little all it takes is
like just a little fluorescent right if
you can do that sure go for 24 but in my
experience running them 24 and then
putting them outside under not 24 is it
just it either stunts them out sativas
it'll throw them into bloom
I mean indicas it'll throw them into
bloom you know so just and then then you
get two weeks of going into bloom and
then going back into veg and then edging
and then going back into flower and then
he got plans to just look like hell and
they're mad and you have a very funky
looking plan yeah and your trimmers hate
you maybe some seed maybe some seeds man
is there anything else that we should
mention when it comes to cleaning up
your garden at the end of the season to
prepare for the winter and the next year
nothing major if you have locks on gates
or something like that
put them inside unless they need to be
out there but it just keeps them from at
least around here it keeps them from
getting arrested up and crap like that
so just a lot of the things I do is so
that I don't have to spend money on it
the next year and so that my tools last
awesome or you know first several years
not just one season at a time so I think
a lot of that comes with age or getting
older for sure we're getting tired of
buying the same damn hammer I left it
out somewhere if you leave it somewhere
it's [ __ ] gone it could be they'll
almost take the [ __ ] out of your hand if
you blink long enough sorry I did not
mean to bash this town but [ __ ] dude
drugs are bad okay yeah drugs are real
bad and the town north of us has the
other drug we got the drug that makes
you go real slow and sleepy and then up
north they got the ones that are making
you go real fast [ __ ] ridiculous all
over the place lately everyone's [ __ ]
flipping out that looks like such a good
idea
you guys Jesse's taking a big fat dab of
some Durban poison sounds like it's my
turn to take a DAB I'm Jesse do you have
any final words to the podcast you want
to put out to the listeners before we
wrap it up shout out to one love garden
supply come check us out Denver or
boulders Pueblo my fault my fault shout
out to the awesome people in Oregon oh
that's something I meant to tell you
customer service out there is ridiculous
they are so nice really it's yes they
don't seem like they're mad at you for
wanting a sandwich at the sandwich place
no not at all they're actually glad to
see you that's pretty rad even in super
small little podunk towns like is the
every time we had a great customer
service experience out there I would
think of your rants on Facebook about
how horrible they don't like you [ __ ]
right yeah actually they're like hey
welcome to our establishment where
you're going to pay our wages can we
help you properly yeah like oh [ __ ] they
know about service here awesome oh I'm
glad you got taking well care of
shoutouts all the nice people on the
coast for sure
awesome awesome experience that's rad
Chuck Chuck your wife for letting you go
on that adventure and we're also hooking
me up every time I go to the gross store
good carry me I can send her a Facebook
message and let her know what I need
when I get there it's on the damn
counter waiting for me
she makes life very easy so shut up to
burn I appreciate that that's some
customer service yeah service check out
my podcast Colorado podcast at Facebook
or on Facebook as Colorado podcast and
then we have a Instagram too and you can
actually find the show on soundcloud
SoundCloud check him out the Colorado
podcast on soundcloud I endorsed the
show I listen we've actually done a
crossover episode where the Colorado
boys came here and invaded my studio and
acted a fool for an hour and a half to
do a new one with our new format oh you
got a new format yeah yeah more comedy
yeah yeah yeah yeah if you ever need of
an outlet for your cannabis talk I've
got a microphone that you're always
invited to come ramble in tour sure all
right you guys make sure you follow my
buddy Jesse check out his podcast big
shout out to the boys on the Colorado a
podcast big shot at citator despicable D
big shout out to 44 big shot at to fetus
big shot it's everybody that's been
listening to their podcast and my
podcast I appreciate you guys ladies and
gentlemen if you would like to sponsor
the podcast or if you've got a product
you'd like me to review or if you've got
questions I've got answers get all the
info for you send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you I'd appreciate it
if you follow me on social media find me
on Facebook it's just I'm stuttering now
searching for a girl from your heart
podcast follow me on twitter at g f YH
podcast and on instagram i am at about
eight thousand seven hundred and fifty
followers right now so give me a follow
on instagram it's ireon der score
genetics that's the seed company check
out all the cannabis photography i've
been posting been posting a bunch of
great stuff in my opinion oh just follow
me there I think I ran out of breath
trying to do all the plugs at the end
make sure you go give garden of Weeden
2.0 a follow to oh yeah the Instagram
police have been shutting people down so
good follow garden of Weeden 2.0 that's
Spence and Maddy that's a perfect way to
end the podcast let me give a huge shout
out to Maddy and Spence until next time
take a fat dad
and give him a hug for me
[Music]
now
[Applause]
[Music]
you