yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 166 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower have your professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
Babur if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jephunneh thank you guys again for
joining me as always I wanna give a huge
thank you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots been flooding use their
music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew also congratulations
on the little one that's coming up soon
you guys proud of you of them excited
for you much love in that family a whole
bunch of positive folks in that family
you guys I'm proud of Lindsey also
across the table she just mapped the
entire intro perfectly you failed at two
or three times now I'm proud of you oh
my god you sent me a video of us Face
Swap video and I almost had a nervous
breakdown it was the weirdest thing I'd
ever seen it was creepy as [ __ ] for some
reason lovely voice you just heard to
the left of me is the dabbing granny
welcome back to the show honey thanks
Jeff hey thanks for driving all the way
from Colorado Springs to Pueblo oh my
god it's so far we're not gonna have any
tech issues no tech issues this time I
did not take any gear we're doing it at
the home studio everything works
beautifully I love it it's great thank
you for coming granny brought an Easter
basket filled with turps hash everybody
at the table got a gift people that are
not at the table that are gonna be here
later got gifts she's got green crack
terpenes she has got sleeping monkey
hash there is some Panama punch on the
table there's no dream
there's a blue tree over here we had a
little conversation about the blue dream
there's some solvent let's hash I was
gifted a sweet new pencil dabber from
our friend tater glass it is a UV
reactive it's clear it's UV reactive on
when in it has got like a cobalt baby
blue which is actually honestly one of
my favorite colors if you know much
about me the tip has got some blue in it
it's also already got a little piece of
hair and the reclaim that stuck to it I
don't know how our lives are so hairy
but that's how it goes so shout out to
tater glass and granny for hooking me up
this sweet new pencil dabber I love it
it's beautiful
thank you guys I love it honestly it's
one of my favorite colors that's similar
to my daughter's eyes color but honestly
that was one of my favorite colors
before she even was born yes that was
awesome granny carries around a UV light
you guys said that she if you've got UV
reflective glass it's a new reactive
glass it's a new thing we talked about
it on the show it's pretty much a
blacklight but you hold the rig
underneath this little light granny's
got and if it's got UV in there
Illuminati glass it will glow it's
dopest [ __ ] I love it I can't believe
she carries that around she's got a
literal Easter basket full of treats
it's granny's basket granny's basket I
love it I love it shut up for coming all
the way from Springs I appreciate that
thanks also in front of me is the lovely
traveling stoner miss Lindsay welcome
back boo boo thank you for having me
always told you could be on the next one
yes and then over here a quiet guy but
he'll talk yes yes blaster Co also known
as Chris yeah you guys follow boba
blaster Co on instagram because he has
started making glass dome carb caps yeah
I'm starting to dabble in the glass game
yeah dude you are a hell of an artist
you were a tattooist before I knew you
yeah I've been doing art for do a lot of
so clay sculpting so glass is kind of
like second nature was really fun really
interesting you're good at it I've seen
you excelling quickly so good work yeah
I did yeah check out
ah gnome and omae glass all right gnome
glass check it out you guys follow him
because he makes cool glass or little
gnome carb caps
we got some cool ideas for him to yeah
up in the future launch the progress
jump in now while he's new and then you
can see him see him get better and
better and better it was at a gobble
glass pendant you're rocking there that
is do that is gobo I don't know how to
say he's wearing a pendant that actually
has cannabis seeds inside of it and then
it's got a little B on the outside cross
nice nice I've got one with silver 99
seeds in it nice it doesn't have the
drips or the stuff on it's just the
straight-up pindy with the seeds yeah
these are nice these are a nice little
like pinata and it's because like worst
comes the worst of it breaks you have
like a present afterwards like oh it's
got some a little bit of water nearby
that I can take the salt out of and we
got some soil that I can put some salts
into well we can make this happen one
thing if it's got a hole in it because
I'm pretty sure it's got a hole in it
because the way that he makes his glass
don't wear it in the shower because your
seeds will germinate oh man for real
well all that moisture the humidity in
the shower you'll get water in there
eventually and it just takes a little
tiny bit of water to germinate some
seeds and that'll be the C to actually
watch you see what I do see you know
somehow try to grow out of it alright
Joey you gotta send us another one so
science project here I'll just get some
seeds and put them in a vial and what
happened let's do a podcast you guys
today is cause for celebration we should
always gonna say we should all take a
tab you guys take a tab I'll keep
talking today is the dab in granny's
one-year anniversary yesterday
I find it quite amazing that you have
come this far in one year
how many Instagram followers have you
got this morning it was two hundred and
fifteen thousand yes you didn't hear the
microphone smack against my forehead let
me do it a little harder yes
two hundred and fifteen thousand it
makes no sense to me year yeah in a year
I had an account with nineteen thousand
it got deleted now I'm almost back to
ten thousand so I would give myself
credit for twenty five thousand
followers you know what I'm saying she's
got ten times what I've got but it's not
just it's people from all over the world
yeah when I was doing the periscope I
did a gram dab for a celebration come on
watch me on periscope took a gram 4:20
this afternoon yeah was did you see the
person came in from Russia talking you
know we're so glad Trump is the
president you know if there would have
been world war if Hillary and I was like
I know your leader really felt that way
and okay but I think it's amazing that
people from Russia come to granny dad
yeah that is pretty amazing so you took
a gram dab at 4:20 here it is 820 right
now damn good shape I saw your video
this morning when you were talking about
you were excited to come be on the
podcast that was early this morning
that's when you replied to one of my
Instagram messages yep yep so yeah she
this lady could dab you guys she could
keep up with you she can probably out
dab you she probably has more Terps and
better Terps than you do she showed up
with gifts too you can't beat that it's
a one-year are you on youtube I am on
YouTube I don't have a huge following on
YouTube but I have a very loyal
following that it's like grannies
reality TV they ask a lot of questions
about my family and stuff so they know
that I've evolved and I don't have an
hour every morning to wake and bake so
if I do a YouTube once a week they're
happy to have my low presence Aaron I
just find it incredible can they find
you can my listeners find you just by
searching for dabbing granny yeah I
think it's dabbing on most of my social
medias are dabbing underscore granny
alright so I was on YouTube
periscope Instagram Facebook and you
know I'm like in Facebook again and
people are finding me I like that
live-streaming and I like the intimacy
of Facebook like periscope my room fills
up pretty quickly a couple hundred
people real quickly Facebook might be
1015 people okay and we can have nice
conversations I don't you know the
people on Facebook is what I like better
about the Facebook well I don't yet
okay I know more people on periscope
I've been doing it long I only have
Facebook friends on my Facebook account
it's mostly people that I know
personally that I've hung out with so
when I go Facebook live it's all my bros
it's these guys yes and so that's a lot
of fun no not for me happy one-year
that's a look at my friend the traveling
she's got a nice chunky dab there she's
throwing a carb cap on she's hitting the
sweet rig from our friends at elevate
glass Big Shot to tour friend Becca and
everybody over at elevate glass all the
lovely elevate dolls I'm gonna share a
secret about the traveling stoner and I
she's like notes for Breast Cancer Month
here we do yes we did it was probably
one of the most painful things I've been
through in a while these lovely ladies
went and got their nipples pierced
to raise awareness for breast cancer you
guys that is some dedication these are
some badass women okay this is truly I
didn't do it for like oh let's go get a
tattoo or a piercing this way I thought
about it because I know some people that
had breast cancer and I thought it's
Breast Cancer Awareness Month and
somebody shared some stories with me and
I thought you know what if you have
breast cancer and you're going through
chemotherapy
goddang life probably sucks and every
day is a battle just having your
mammogram done is enough uncomfortable
experience or any woman it just is
you'll get your boobs squished heard
about that and so I was like come on
Lindsey let's do it what's a few minutes
of pain compared to someone how do they
do it if you don't have a boot like if
you're lacking in the boob region what
do they squish I don't know for yeah I
know I just took a weird turn on this I
was just like wow how do you I thought
you were for the piercing for a second
oh no no no
I don't know you think we did but you're
higher than me okay sorry of course that
you were on a path you didn't want to go
get a tattoo or no I didn't want to get
his hat too I mean really I didn't and I
will share something personal I've been
married to my husband for over 40 years
almost 45 I know my husband very well I
knew he would not prove some of you or
be like oh but wouldn't every man like
their woman's nipples pierced no my
husband is very conservative about your
Bible so I didn't tell him he knew I was
hanging out with Lindsay he knew what
was going on but I did not tell him and
I thought if I tell him immediately
he'll say take him out so I waited a few
days and he knows how bad a piercing
hurts
so this is how I told him he was sitting
in his chair and I had fun band-aids
didn't I travelling stoner okay so I put
on I had little round sad face emoji and
AZ's and was kinda graphic but the round
part fits over a woman's areola
perfectly and so he is sitting in his
chair and I said I have something to
tell you and he said what oh my god I
know you're not gonna like it and he was
like what did you do now can I lifted my
shirt and there was them two sad faces
looking at him and he said you are not
25 years old like those kids you're
hanging out with that I said but it was
to raise breast cancer awareness he said
I don't want to hear your
rationalization no I don't like it but
yeah that's what kind of cute it's a
win-win for everybody
Lindsay wouldn't let me give her a hug
for like a week and a half the couch for
a week every leg
the dogs and like even the the sheets
would get you know wait do you fast do
you guys well the other day I was
putting on a onesie really fast and I I
sipped it up and I was like Shh oh my
god oh I saw that that one hurt my
German Shepherd jumped up on oh I got a
titty twister
just when the left one was almost healed
and it was like 360 oh gosh we're
talking about periscope and stuff I was
gonna talk I was gonna mention like you
put a lot of your life out there aren't
you like don't you want to keep anything
to yourself but I don't even need to ask
that question cuz you don't give a [ __ ]
no I don't what have I really got you
know secrets are bad that means
something dirtier or bad and I don't
think anything I've done in my life is
really dirty or bad
everything's been a learning experience
and I'll share it with you and hopefully
you'll learn if I did I was young and
dumb once I did some stupid things that
young and young people do dumb not dumb
and I'll share that with you hopefully
you'll learn from the things I say
because they do have a lot of experience
behind me I'll try to learn you know
exactly what I do i do I completely do
yeah I find well being a podcaster and I
also used to put myself on periscope a
lot I don't seem to be I don't like
sitting down as much I like to be on my
feet doing [ __ ] periscope makes me feel
like I get anxious for some reason after
work look how much you're dabbing right
right I look up at his building 20 to 30
minutes and I'm like oh should I only
meant to spend five minutes here
time does get away quickly wise but
putting that much of myself out I'm
accountable for what I say I can't fit
at all because however many listeners
were listening listened and it's on
record and the pod every episode is
available like I've said before I'm
gonna start putting on old episodes even
have you learned that the power of your
words you really sometimes have to stop
and think I because people take things
literally I'm really lucky that I had a
starter podcast I had another friend
that had kind of a comedy slash
community based podcast shout out to
wait really you guys check out wait
really he's a comedian we had a podcast
together
and I kind of got to be his co-host so I
got to say a couple of dumb things on
episodes and realize oh I can't say that
kind of dumb [ __ ] like it you have to
figure it out but that's how I learned
it was by it [ __ ] it up that's why I
was laughing when I said I'll try to
learn from you but I mean the way I
learned I have to fall in crash that
sucked you know I'll try to learn from
that one I've learned I'm very
accountable for the things I say because
so many people do watch me we have to be
and you said something on your social
media this morning about when you become
as known as you are you will you are you
way more than myself but everybody at
this table has a little bit of notice
but you've got times we've got when you
get to your level of insta celebrity or
insulted instafamous it's slightly
instafamous you've got to pay attention
to what you say and who you talk to and
what you share and why did you get
caught up in yes yes it's so much easier
to get caught up in [ __ ] when you've got
250,000 people in your hair oh just in
our cannabis community alone just in
this small community absolutely I catch
myself in it they catch myself
everybody's choosing sides all the time
in this industry and it seems like we're
all just a bunch of potheads having fun
but that's how it should seem
backstabbing and I don't have time for
pettiness no no we're getting too old
these kids are too old for that [ __ ] too
already and I think I think all these
young people will learn don't get just
Jeff maybe you said something shitty
about boba blaster over there you know
that was me granny you know he's just a
rotten person well I'm learning that
some of these kids will take what you
said to heart boba blaster over there
might be damn good person but you have a
personal vendetta because some girl you
liked
he liked yeah yeah he said she no
[ __ ] his glass business and taking
money off of there and I'm just using
you that's an example you know that yeah
Chris is awesome no beef ever so unless
somebody's done me wrong you can you can
gossip and and talk about somebody all
you want
rest assured granny is not gonna listen
to your [ __ ] I'm always a bold
enough and wise enough to make my own
decisions about people you told me
earlier that you just trust your gut and
you're 90% of the time you're right is
what I think you said I agree with that
usually is a pretty good judge of what I
shouldn't shouldn't do with other folks
I think Lindsay's the same way secrets
don't make friends you guys what's
happening over there actually passed me
a DAB so I'm gonna grab the email here
I'm gonna take a DAB okay hash did you
just give us some Terps herpes some
turkey Slurpee I am in I'm in so these
ladies yeah that's why they call the
turkey Slurpee yeah these lovely ladies
the davon granny and the lovely
traveling stoner here they came because
they are going to do a food drive slash
new toy drive new toys you guys new toys
in packages for kids we'll give you an
age range I'll let these ladies handle
it while I take this tab but would one
of you ladies like to tell me all about
your food and toy drive go ahead you
talk for awhile Linds
okay so we have set up a food and toy
drive here in Colorado Springs so far we
have 17 different places as drop-off
points and at each of those locations
you'll be able to get some sort of
special like deal or offer something for
bringing in either a canned food excuse
me a non expired canned food or
non-perishable canned food right
something y'all would eat no expired
garbanzo beans and if you like garbanzo
beans I'm sorry
or like Jeff said a brand new toy in a
packaging on any age range honestly we
don't know we don't care you know a toys
a toy we're not gonna know we're not
gonna put a limit on it like that but
yeah if you bring in an item - one of
the one of the places that will list off
you can get a and each place is doing
something different so you'll have to
ask the specific place what they're
going to you know do for it but we will
we'll have a flier and everything for it
that will be posting and stuff with each
place that we have so we have seventeen
places right now confirmed and we have
three spots open four places
yeah we decided to keep it at 20 cuz
we are going to be the ones that will be
going by the dispensaries picking stuff
up I have a warehouse to store things in
until we distribute them and I think we
picked a good organization you know we
we wanted we wanted to somehow keep it
in the cannabis community but this year
on such short notice that's just not
going to happen
so what we have decided to do is I got
into contact with the Marian house and
the Marian house is down on Bijou and
they feed and they clothe a lot of our
homeless community and to me that's a
lot of veterans it's also a lot of young
people moving here because of cannabis
um you see a lot of young people down
there yes so I reached out to them they
will be happy to take anything we have
and then there's second organization
that under the Marian house is called
the Family Resource Center and they deal
with families that are totally displaced
homeless families that they're getting
set up in apartments and stuff and these
are why we're saying we'll take toys
because there's children involved in
most of these cases and so that's why we
decided you know so many people think oh
people that smoke cannabis they're bad
they don't do anything well guess what
you're wrong we love giving back to our
community yes and we want to start small
this year we just want to do it in
Colorado Springs but we're hoping to
have a really big turnout this year and
be able to make it into something even
bigger for next year whether that means
we stay in the springs and just make it
bigger next year or we you know try to
do something even bigger but we're
really excited about this and the
different plate do you want to list off
the different places that we have I'm
just gonna throw one more thing in there
now we at first we were just going to do
we we had talked about money and stuff
when we decided no but what we are going
to do all the different places that the
20 places we're going to put a gallon
mason jar there and you can drop off
gift certificates because like I say the
Family Resource Center say we get enough
a meal together we get everything
further and this is for Christmas we get
their Christmas meal together what if
they don't have a roasting pan guess
what the Family Resource Center can say
here take this gift certificate go get
what else you need four or I think the
other thing we might want to include is
diapers yeah I mean diapers are really
really expensive yeah so I think we
could expand you know the toy yeah
diaper and food yeah absences looking at
me like god we didn't discuss this no I
as long as we're doing good things right
yeah I'm listen anything that's not like
expired or bad or something we really
couldn't donate like don't be ridiculous
please don't bring us like you know okay
go to the health food store and get some
of that Amy's organic chili get some
soups [ __ ] that people want to eat like
something that you can actually open and
consume instead of like some green beans
I mean you can do that but who wants
[ __ ] green beans for dinner you go
get some soup some Campbell's good [ __ ]
some chunky [ __ ] yeah yeah I'm a
vegetarian so I'm gonna get some of that
[ __ ] veggie soup with a meaty soup
please we gotta feed people that's the
idea well well then those gift
certificates can be used like we're just
doing non perishables but you need milk
you need butter we need eggs a Walmart
gift card yep if we had more time we
could probably solicit grocery stores
and stuff for turkeys but this year not
to share right next year guys yep we're
gonna make it really really huge yes
would you prefer them wrap or not wrap
the gifts for the kids
I say not wrap well let the Family
Resource Center do that I think we'll do
this and then turn it over if you want
to donate wrapping paper so that they
can be wrapped to go for that but don't
wrap them I kind of said that because I
want to see what's in there so that I
make sure your and besides out how do
you know that there's not a youth toy
wrapped unfortunately we're gonna
distribute the boxes next Friday isn't
that correct Lindsay sorry next Friday
wasn't that our timeframe we were gonna
put them out next Friday action boxes so
okay beyond that Friday oh yeah I know I
done [ __ ] up and
it's next Friday the 18th and the drop
off no later than December 16th yep okay
I'm just making notes because I want to
make sure that this podcast comes out at
the right time I'll put this out on the
17th okay try run down the drop up and
we're thinking about we haven't
fine-tuned this where we're still kind
of kind of work on it but we're thinking
we could make this and do like a little
competition some of the the drop-off
spots one of them being elevate already
said well how about if every place put a
little gift in there I'll throw
something in and then at the end the
person that collected the most gets the
little prize package from the twenty
drop-off spots and granny goes and
spends a day with him doing something
fun at their facility we could turn this
into a fun competition should be a lot
of fun you could win on a date with
granny you know and like I know some of
the dispensaries are gonna go penny
pre-roll you know I know that there's
already some specials okay so we'll go
through that the people we have like
Lindsey said there's only three spots
left so if you want to get one and fill
one of the last three spots I guess I'd
be in Colorado Springs yes you do you do
need to have a place where you can
collect canned foods a high-traffic area
you got to be able to participate with
the cannabis community and be proud of
the cannabis community if you've got any
fear or hatred for the candidate or
community please don't respond to this
ad and we're not gonna junk up your
facility if you call and say the box is
full somebody will be there to pick it
up and your Lobby or wherever you have
the box will not be an eyesore I promise
you that and it's a win-win situation
because you get you get free publicity
on my social media that's one of the
things I was gonna say you have to be
okay with granny publicizing your area
your your facility or store wherever it
is if it's a head shop if it's a gross
store if it's a dispensary if it's a
glass shop I think I said head shot but
I'm high as [ __ ] so I might not have
anything anywhere the cannabis consumers
or
counterculture folk Millennials may roam
coffee shop yeah okay I'm down for
anything as long as your cannabis
friendly well I bet you by the time this
comes out you'll have your three slots
filled because you are a your networking
young lady is what I seem to do yes a
higher elevation has got to be on your
list of course let me run down the list
let's hear the the 17 glass grinds there
I know they're located down on the south
end of town right somewhere I film art
then of course the traveling stoners
place a business green and healthy
wellness mm-hmm
canna Canyon they're over on Old
Colorado the weed pimps they're fun guys
they really are they make me laugh every
time I seen it elevate and hemp there
will be a box at both locations epic
remedy there's one down on the circle
they have one up on Academy both stores
will have a box grow life natural
mystics caregivers they're downtown
what's up Joey DBK glass the family
joint the dang curry they're in new
dispense
can I tell you something funny about the
Dan curry I think it's funny okay yes as
long as it's funny and not derogatory
it's not at all you know I once managed
a nonprofit on our military installation
in Colorado Springs and I was let go
because of dabbing granny nobody there
ever talks to me anymore cuz I smoke
cannabis new friends I've met what all
my life has gotten much better I mean I
like what I did but box mix I ran into
the dang curry just cuz it was a new
dispensary and I was with one of my
friends they took a picture cuz they
were very happy to see the dabbing
granny one of my former volunteers cuz I
was a volunteer organization
got in touch with me and said Gail Gail
is my real name you're at my son's
dispensary today that was just
absolutely wonderful and I said in
almost a year you're the first person
that has reached out to touch to talk to
me and she says she was very happy I was
at that anchor II kind of funny that
sucks if people just just shunned you
yeah but look at the great friends at me
that's true you've replaced them oh yeah
truthfully people somebody asked me one
of my comments today they said did you
ever think at your age you would be this
important person in the cannabis
community and I said no I pinch myself
every morning I'm like how can this be
how can this be I embrace it
no security clearance to get in here it
was easy what would you do lindsay dude
I didn't do anything she got her own Deb
she set herself up she heat her own now
I didn't do anything sheshe in there you
can I think she's puking but she I can
hear your casa hold it for the bikes to
not like die this I talked about you
earlier did your ears ring because Chris
said I watched you do that dab and you
just kept going in and you didn't cough
it's so mesmerizing water so you have
Jeff to thank for that
I don't even know if you know this you
when I I think it might have been the
first time we met at the first podcast
and we talked about coughing during yeah
yeah and you said well I very rarely
caught because you own your lungs you
can tell them what to do so when I feel
that tickle and you all know what I mean
when I say it feel that tickle huh I
hear that your voice in my head and I
almost meditate with my eyes open but I
am NOT going to cough yep yeah
all right I've never talked about this
on a podcast I've only told like four
people in my whole life this granny was
one of them I take giant dad you guys
when you feel like you're gonna cough
when you feel that thing that goes like
you you blow up the dab you sort of go
do you feel that [ __ ] when you're when
you're walking at the mall if you get a
little cramping or like you know this
[ __ ] fall down something you do I'm
sorry
she's got a condition most people don't
just fall down but most normal folk if
you get a cramp you know just [ __ ]
fall down and spaz out in the middle of
the mall in my opinion that's what my
lungs are doing I'm coughing they're
throwing a fit like a [ __ ] mad child
to cramp ah I feel that cough come in
and I either inhale or exhale as hard as
I can distract them like when your dogs
trying to run away to cat you just pull
the leash and put a treat in front of it
it forgets about the cat it looks at the
tree goes on tree I liked it I just
breathe in real hard my lungs like air
instead of trying to cough I don't know
if that's good for me or bad for me but
it works cuz it's got to be better than
to coughing so hardened blowing out my
face and get red eyed and I've cops all
blown up [ __ ] blood vessels little
cops that's just a [ __ ] coffee I don't
let those every known again I've smoked
strange product and get wet lungs pho
that's in my opinion when I smoked pho
yeah I know that sounds weird a lot of
people in random places but that you can
make quality cannabis concentrates with
propane if you do it properly but it
comes out like live resin it comes out
really moist in when I smoke it my lungs
feel heavy and I spit up all cough up
the next morning I'll cough up a bright
green or a bright yellow yes golf like
you're sick oh my god do I need once it
comes out I'm marvelous but it was wet
in your eyes in the morning yeah yeah oh
we should finish our list I was gonna
keep you on I'm sorry
we immediately hashtag they liked it
when we ran let's get back to the
podcast um new-age medical I think
they're up I don't know the gods thanks
cool that's Bailey big shout out to new
act medical yes Rocky Mountain dapper I
love her tweed leaf tweed leaf is really
um I'm glad they're on board because
they actually once a month wanted to do
a charity event nobody seemed to want
cannabis money yeah that's the hard part
about it we found Grover vets finally
took money but it was really really hard
to find anybody that will take cannabis
the vets you always need help and it's
always great to help the vets and
take it so if you ever need some more to
send stuff I've got a guy who runs a
veteran our organization that will
always need contributions well she asked
me again can we do once one Saturday a
month were 10% of everybody's purchase
goes directly to a charity so shout out
to Renee at tweed leaf so it's pretty
nice dispensary - I'm sorry Lindsey oh I
love you I know it's not it's not yours
actually it's not even I don't but you
do know one thing about me is that that
sense of loyalty I have it's just I go
it happens I do primarily shop at Green
&amp; Healthy but I visit other dispensaries
and I go into other places like they
don't agree strand in the world Orange
I like to go to other places I like I
just have to I cannot go to one
dispensary because of the different
drops and I and y'all know I've
developed great taste buds for different
products I was complimenting you earlier
on your your ability to shop everywhere
that I can recognize concentrate you
kind of get around in a good way yeah
and it's I enjoy it I enjoy being able
to tell people you know this is really
good product go spend your X amounted
every everyday in the late afternoon
around 2:30 3 o'clock you can open up
Instagram and see where granny decided
to shop today there's one or two shots
of her and the cool but tender there
they would treat her politely I love it
I love it when you pop up so I can
almost tell where you are like oh she
went to elevate and that she had alright
alright
altitude meds there downtown I believe
yes there are several locations
okay well wherever they are we're gonna
have boxes in all their locations
Emerald City wellness the pink house and
stained glass LLC so that leaves three
spots get in touch with me DM me on
Instagram dabbing underscore granny I
think those spots will fill up quickly
though and not just this spot we'll
probably have those filled this comes
out and like seven or ten days from now
so these seven
and is it probably be filled up
hopefully with much faith what we need
now is people to go to these locations
with a non-perishable canned good that
you would eat hey guys that you would
put in a pan and heat up yourself and
sit down and [ __ ] enjoy like a meal
by yourself don't bring us a bunch of
random side [ __ ] thousand people and you
know what maybe you're not a big shopper
that's what that mason jar is gonna be
for and guess what the cannabis
community is the most honorable
community you can drop your money in a
dispensary you will get it back you can
leave your badge or your ID behind
because we're all stoners and if we drop
some [ __ ] we hope that you're gonna hand
it to me also
I've been lucky but I hear it's pretty
pretty often that people always get back
Thursday yeah yeah with that said though
if you're broke and all you have in your
cabinet is something and all you want to
bring you want to bring something in
like we will please don't feel like
we're sitting here and saying don't
bring anything in like if you know like
believe me I've been there I was making
lobster lobster and live rats I was just
sitting there thinking like oh god three
years ago I would have been like well
[ __ ] I'm not bringing anything it we're
just trying to flip maybe turn a few so
you might have been one of the people
that hopefully was benefiting from our
little food drive most people
unfortunately are right at that line
where they don't need the help but they
can't afford to give any help I'm saying
it's like we're both yeah the folks are
right now making crucial decisions do I
need this or do we want to eat at the
end of the week my ass we get high this
week I can walk to work not get gas
let's figure this out just give me a
sinking feeling recreational cannabis oh
I'm gonna do when you said Medicaid or
wipe your butt
I'm afraid that's what Californians are
facing yeah I tried to stay out of a lot
of California yeah
I yeah I I see both sides of it and I
try to stay that's California so
Colorado we did all the things right we
did it right here in my usual we thought
that we had lost we thought that we had
lost an initiative here in Pueblo and
they are recounting and still counting
and it turns out that we may have
actually won three of the four major
cannabis initiatives we may actually get
to open recreational cannabis facilities
within the city limits as well though
before too long here Andy you want a new
job it'll be fun well both go work in
our new dispensary bud tenders it'll be
so much fun did white my portal anything
to do with this was he quite the
activist for all the things that were
going on white Mike did a lot of
groundwork and a lot of internet work
and a lot of podcast work so yeah if you
want to give Mike a shout out you might
have pretty men once but yeah shout cuz
I listened to your podcast where I
gained so much knowledge I appreciate it
and I've listened to Mike and even
though I met him one time in person
where he was so quiet he's not that way
on the podcast he's quiet
until he gets a read on you and knows
how much of him you want to hear and
then enough he's he's polite like he was
yeah he was taught to speak when spoken
to and shut the [ __ ] up dude he's a
smart dude he's passionate about
cannabis so thank you white Mike
continue the fight yes we're lucky to
have such a good team like we've got
growers and we've got activist and we've
got City Council representatives we've
got glass makers so that we can consume
our products we've got Lindsay over here
promoting us and keeping us medicated
whoa that was a bubble fish trolling
Lindsay in a minute throwing up from
your dad just some cops
I took it way too hot that's what it was
it wasn't even that it was a big dab I
mean you know I was like she got her own
- she get her own now oh no I remember
when I grabbed cuz I had actually
forgotten it was the dad was fine it was
after I sat here for
second I was like oh that was really
friggin hot and I was like that really
hurt my chest and I was like oh yeah I'm
gonna call for a while now you can mic
it up in here you can cough like Mike on
the podcast for 10 minutes I just reach
over turn Mike's microphone down when he
starts doing it it gives me the he
points down I got you bro I'll turn that
down for a minute
yes all right so we've got a canned food
drive toys also guys toys are rad bring
some toys some ninja turtles or some
[ __ ] something that you'd want to play
with I understand you don't all have a
bunch of extra money this will end the
drop-off date will in December 10th so
you've got nearly a month from the time
that this episode comes out pretty much
December 16th December oh sorry I just
can't read my own damn writing I'm sorry
that is the six I will correct that
that's a week before Christmas get it to
these folks over the weekend that week
of Christmas excellent yeah make some
happy kids make some bellies happy make
some folks happy brighten up some
holidays whatever holiday you celebrate
share some share some joy helps people
live the winner gets cold and shitty
here just the cold the snow the slowness
the the [ __ ] bet that vibe makes a
lot of people depressed and sad anyway
and then you got a shitty Christmas on
top of not doing well and really [ __ ]
things up if you got kids on top of that
that's just the icing on the damn poor
cake so help some people out make them
make them have a little little kids
don't know any different right yeah yeah
and if you if you don't break them early
they get a chance trying to help them
out I'm serious I mean yeah yep you
don't want to raise strippers and serial
killers
granny turned red and blushed I have
never seen granny blush
[Music]
I wrote down just a one-word note and
I'm prominent wait till you get done
taking that drink cuz I don't want you
to spray it all over the table it all
over me all over Lindsey she's looking
right at you what the new trend in
cannabis that I have been catching on to
the suppositories you know what I'm glad
you brought that up may I steal some of
your green crack tabs to place on my are
Terps thank you oh this is gonna do me
just fine okay there's green cracked
herbs on the what kind of shattered to a
has nice okay chief when I first heard
about them damn suppositories even I was
kind of skeptical but I have a pretty
sick husband so I thought okay this is
really gonna help waning them off the
morphine and all that with this pain
okay what I have discovered is most most
of you men are homophobic you met you
mentioned suppositories and I see you
visibly squeezing your butt cheeks
together she's right am i it's true
exact women on the other hand you know
we spit 10-pound babies out our vaginas
so what's a suppository let's use no not
me I took these home for my husband and
I was like what I brought you their
fifty percent THC fifty percent come
DVDs thank you had a brain fart and he
said you stick that up your ass like no
problem and I did it is at least twelve
hours of euphoria is the best way to put
it you can function you can drive you're
not intoxicated but you're euphoric I
used one the night we had our girls
taken care of and it ease the pain okay
so my thought was alright now these
things are really wonderful if you are
truly in my
the patient for real if you're
especially cancer patient if you're
vomiting right skip that whole part of
the body
exactly and you and I know that the
divine creator did not make our lungs to
ingest irritants some of us like to
smoke we know it's really not the best
way to medicate no way offends our butts
I like to smoke though if you truly need
to medicate there are so many membranes
in your anus using these suppositories
is a wonderful way to medicate cannabis
isn't the first medicine they've used as
a suppository no this is just the newest
and it's just on our realm so now it's
what we're talking about now it's been
used for hah I'm gonna say hundreds of
years I'm not certain but I'm sure
people have been boof and things for way
longer the best way to medicate so the
next week we'll skip okay so I I had no
problem with it I stick one up my butt I
stuck a couple of them up my butt by now
my husband had to have a colonoscopy the
next week and he came home he's a grumpy
after his colonoscopies and pain is
grouchy and I was like your butt holes
already stretched out try one of them
suppositories oh my god if he I'm so
glad he does not listen to this podcast
he tried one and he was like you're
right my lower back pain is gone
I don't feel the nauseousness in my
belly that I feel when I take a morphine
for pain
yeah I'm swimming from that dab I might
have put a little too much Terps but I'm
not complaining
just put a little wine across the dab
and uh it made my brain swim around in
my head okay like it should I tell the
story about the great and craic
[Music]
okay okay we're smoking on this stuff
called Green crack which is a pretty
sativa dominant strain when you all
agree I just took absolutely okay and
I'm not a real sativa but listen I'm
getting there looks like Oh okay
wouldn't you buy this um distilled hash
it solvent less it comes in a little
syringe it's not very big it's glass
it's glass it has a very small part
where you the medicine actually comes
out of the syringe like where a needle
would be I guess there's no no we don't
maybe if you have children you've used
them for pulling up amoxicillin or
antibiotic to get to your baby it'd be
good to feed a baby bird it would be yes
it's probably a really good description
to put the idea in his head it'd be
perfect to feed a baby bird if you had
rodents or mice or something like that
okay so I really do like these
suppositories for medicating and I'm not
gonna say where but about tender said
well have you tried that hash and I was
like no suitably you should try that
Green crack Emily okay she squirted so
when I went back to that bug tender I
was like my god I was bouncing off the
walls like I had consumed huge amounts
of caffeine and lots of other things and
he said granny you didn't do the whole
gram did you don't try that that's like
when I did all those edibles after the
secret session sure you don't have to
discourage too many people sticking too
much hash in their ass on the show but
if they were to try it how much of I
really wouldn't suggest doing that no no
okay however
I do them record okay I've given some do
the traveling stoner we can ask her what
her effect was I watched her put her
head down in blushes why I believe we're
talking about true medication the first
time I ever did one um I actually did
the foria once so I had gotten the for a
one's a sample that's so long ago and I
never used them
and then once Gayle started doing them
was talking about them I was supposed to
go to Denver and meet up with one of our
friends for her birthday and I was in a
lot of pain that morning and I was like
[ __ ] I really need to go to Denver like
you know we have plans and I really
can't let this like [ __ ] up our plant
you know plans for her birthday so I
said to Christ I'm like I don't know
what to do he's like you need to put one
of those suppositories and then just try
it the first time I ever took one the
forty ones are a lot stronger they're
like the 50/50 ones so the first time I
ever took it I was like Gumby and I
think I think because I was in a lot of
pain like I just I'm like immediately
was out of pain I don't know it was
weird but yeah like you can ask Chris I
was like I couldn't really move my lower
half and she's like I don't feel great
[Music]
pain medication how long does it take to
kick in Oh granny gave me some drops and
oral sublingual drops today and I felt
those within like 10 minutes and they're
pretty good for a tincture cuz a lot of
tinctures they're very ashy medicine it
was very it was a very clean almost like
a green tea but very light diluted green
tea flavor I actually enjoyed it and
then Lindsay was kind enough to throw me
some of a pumpkin of course pumpkin
spice the white girl incredibles edible
it was delicious and they're kicking
it's all working all working oh I'm so
proud of you that you jump back on the
edible bag band was needed to clean out
I had to kind of wash the edible system
I like to do that they
tallied I ate fifty two hundred
milligrams of edibles the Sunday after
the secret session we were was Max's
bacon oh yeah
shut it to max 10 pieces granny didn't
stop there going I to cookies that were
about 500 milligrams each those lemon oh
man
but then I didn't stop there were those
150 won't were the cupcakes only
remember those strawberry pink those
were amazing those ones you had gotten
we got the half dozen of the solvent
less second secret sesh ever in Colorado
it was in May you were in Florida you
weren't here for it it was you have
literally flown out the day before but
he's looking like I know the cupcakes
pictures strawberry lemonade secret it
was so funny because Jeff and I both
know when I walked in and I was like we
both looked each other were like we're
not gonna eat edibles first of all I
found Jeff in the corner animal brought
me on stage and gave me a to Gram dab
and then asked did he do one with you
no you we we kind of fixed it see he
knows that I like to take big dabs and
we're buddies and he was on stage and he
goes I'm higher than you cuz that's his
thing he like say I'm higher than you
why I'm higher than you why that's why I
develop and he grabs his shirt like he's
cool why and I pointed out Megan oh
you're not because I'm taller than him
so I'm always you're much taller than so
I'm always higher and I think him and I
was taller than Abby yes you are he's
I've got a really killer picture of the
two of you and my phone I'll show you
later okay you guys were talking and you
didn't know I was taking pictures I just
thought it there's two my favorite
people are so good picture of you guys
so uh
oh yeah Adam calls me he's like Jeff I'm
higher than you come up on stage and so
[ __ ] yeah that's my head available
right so he comes up and he's like you
think you could take a big dad like I
could hit a big dad he's like you ready
for this and stretches out to grams and
I was like oh [ __ ] I didn't know that's
what was coming and he heated the nail
to her it was white it wasn't red it was
white I was like let it cool and he goes
no just hit it and I was like no let it
cool and so I like hesitated like as
long as I could but then I just went in
cuz he was pushing it on there and I
pulled the whole thing then I blew it
out and he's like damn this guy's a
champ and it was like can you do a
bigger dad than him and people like yes
they would come up on stage and we would
dab together
you kept dabbing oh yeah yeah they
couldn't finish their dabs and I would
grab the rig from them and then I would
finish their dad for them and set the
rig down like now what's up
but honestly then only lasted for one
cent he calls it Adam does like a little
45 minutes and then goes and takes a
break walks around the crowd one of
those and I had to go sit upstairs and
eat there wasn't real food there at the
time so I ate about 12 bags of chips in
like seven bottles of water I didn't
want to do add a gram dab in that real a
thing we were in but I wanted to win so
max heated up my nail India's like let
it cool us no no I want to win I'm gonna
hit it he's not lying because I sat down
I'm sitting right in front of the email
it's at the other end of the table and I
was like but everybody's email is
different yeah and I I don't
Emily not as high and guys when you do
big dabs like Jeff and I do the
travelling definitely watch the email
struggle win just because you start you
start dropping it and you see the
temperature drops right would you keep
up yeah yeah and I'll I hear some of the
time I can hear my adapt hardening up on
the nail cuz it's late yep I can't keep
up either suck harder or slower or
this thing up stop Lindsey anyway see
the wheels in your sky turning it went
from suppositories to this really
quickly I don't know how did you finish
your story you figured out a better
dosage
yeah absolutely because I mean we've got
the smaller ones now and stuff like that
not for me I need to I'm going to a
hundred hundred hundred milligrams a
hundred milligrams of CBD a hundred
milligrams and edibles is of THC is
enough for most people to orally consume
and be just fine like I don't get
hundred milligrams 500 milligrams and
then take dad's like normal then I'm
like oh also but if just that amount of
edibles wouldn't have done it but the to
like kind of kind of boot it's like a
turbo makes your high turbo just gives
you a boost is that you jump I know I'm
not like a scientist but I pay attention
to the body and I know that kind of
stuff I care about physical stuff I know
how quickly your bomb is going to absorb
that much medicine and you're gonna
absorb all of it
you're not gonna poop any of it out your
stomach's not gonna destroy any of it
your liver and kidneys aren't gonna ruin
it it's just gonna suck all up into you
now when I do try that high of a dosage
that will be you know for me that's
gonna be even high for me I'm not going
anywhere I'm gonna test it out we
Facebook live it after after you yeah
gosh I'll even put on my new outfit that
the lady for most 420 bought me as a
gift you have so many cool friends to
give you so many cool gear okay now you
sit here you know me am I very girly
girly it was a very nice gift but it did
not call yourself in the last podcast in
Iowa corn [ __ ] yes she gave me a gift
back from Victoria Secrets but it wasn't
so bad I looked at it and
I was like really it's yoga pants it's
not too bad no in a thing that says US
army and gold sequence ring it's okay
trying to pull you back it's just the
Victoria's Secret's it was but it's not
that's when I told tater that he is I
said I've never been in the Victoria's
Secret but you know what he said
unfortunately I've been in many many of
them can you say that to Jeff
no I've been there how about you Chris
no no well this is my thought on
Victoria's Secrets truthfully I think
they're very expensive it is expensive
and naked always worked for me so why do
you need these fancy Ron's and just
don't need that [ __ ] I'd rather buy
medicine cause I wish you could have
seen the [ __ ] everything went wrong that
was great relax a Grammy gets tons of
great gifts is something I mentioned but
she's she's a karmic gift person she
brought me I've got a frisbee of other
gifts she doesn't just give them fully
candy so if you take dabs and you're
sitting there looking like you're
depleted she's like you want some milk
yeah to drop into the to the hot
chocolate it's gonna be awesome I'm in
all right guys let's recap seems like
everybody's high we've been going for
almost an hour
stupid recap a year on social media
congratulation thanks to everybody out
there that seems to like my silliness
and quirkiness I'll tell you I'm always
on the lookout for fun hats and stuff Oh
what I have found for Christmas you are
gonna love to follow her on social media
so that you can see it you guys
periscope and Facebook live because she
does a lot of stuff there she smokes
down there's a new app that I've been on
talked with and and this is kind of
because it's just people in the cannabis
community and what the end goal of this
app is they want to be able to have
multicam users so it wouldn't just be
you sitting there watching me smoke all
of us would be interact kind of like a
tiny chat sort of thing that sounds
great I would love to do that so I'm
kind of helping them promote this I
think I saw talked with and I actually
assumed that it was a pothead dating
service the green tinder so I'm not
getting high with like Grindr tinder is
for gay dudes if you need Grindr that's
okay I'm not a man a pass me my phone
cuz I got it in there oh hi there yeah
thank you
all right so yeah we're gonna give them
a free ad hi there it's a it's basically
a hook-up app for pot heads you guys go
check that one out I you will not find
me on that [ __ ] I am trust the [ __ ] out
of me three-strikes-you're-out
[ __ ]
[Music]
done did me wrong three times before I
put this pin in my eye
[Laughter]
by the way that is a stylus as well as
the pen I was noticing the
[Laughter]
[Music]
because they make me laugh that is the
pot brothers at law they're out
California it's Markie I think their
last name is Wasserman brothers-in-law
fighting for the cannabis community
Wasserman Wasserman they have five five
they have a twenty five word script
which I'll give you their business card
to put in your wallet that there's the
twenty five word script and it's
basically the cop says where you been I
don't have to discuss what I don't have
to tell you where I'm going I don't have
to end at the end there hash tag is shut
the [ __ ] up when your daughter's you
shut the [ __ ] up so they've sent me
their hash tag hat and I word and I love
it and people know senior hash tag STFU
had my friends so they could be was
eight five five was slaw but I think
wasp law is more appropriate but check
them out brothers at law shadow they do
have funny social media give him a
follow there was somebody else they were
saying that we needed in August house
was it my Enoch you know yes we've got
to give them a shout-out and actually
they're gonna be working with the family
joint he is cut he's from Lee
Pennsylvania everything is made here in
the United States um a really nice you
know I'm not a big email fan but it's
got LED light some really really nice
quartz banger that's wrapped from the
bottom up consistent keeps your nail
consistently hot he told me it was Pro
programmable by your phone yes you have
to have a smart phone it's caught it's
called the cube one and there's there's
only a few you have to order them okay
okay and they're not cheap this I know
but you can use my name as a promo there
you go I just remember that but you get
what you paid for just like if you were
buying Bobo blasters anything boba
blaster makes great emails I got one
sitting over there needs to be a little
cleaned off and used but you know
yourself if you're making it if you're
making American products you're gonna
get what you pay for
yes exactly in August house is America
have you ever heard about I have not
that's why I was happy that you finally
got it cuz you showed me them a while
back and it's very small I should have
actually brought it with me it comes in
a little box where you can take along
with you so a little black the nail
looked really cool yeah it looks pretty
sweet like I say I don't like emails but
y'all have been seeing me and I like
that I can put my clear rates on top of
that and make it cool let's got the
lights on the top that's fresh yeah you
circle just where your rig is kind of
shopping at Spencer's again jeans in a
t-shirt
what do you prefer for hiking shoes and
I was like DC's etnies I don't know
something similar as long as they fit
yeah snug them up real good yeah yeah
we've been going for an hour most people
want to check out by now guys let's give
out all of our social media stuff of
course everybody knows how to find the
Devon Grammy on all the social media at
dab an underscore granny on Instagram
there is I think if you google me you're
gonna find me yeah good google for you
guys watch the videos watch the stuff
with all the Russian comments from other
people and [ __ ] people from other
countries say the comments are my
favorite part sometimes people sometimes
are disgusting well you've got to if
you're on the internet expect that dumb
[ __ ] that's what I have come to learn
somebody thought Sam and I were a couple
THC Sam they said oh dude granny sex is
the best good luck as a couple yeah
that's funny we logged into facebook
life people asked if we were gonna hook
up when we were done it's just the
nature of the beast with the internet
people have no lives sometimes not
everybody's trying to do something
they're out there trying to get noticed
and that's their way to do it if you're
not if you're not part of anything
you'll do your best to try to create
something to be a part of yes anybody
say some profound [ __ ] on accident it
has make on Miss Lindsay the traveling
stoner remind everybody how they can
find you because I think you promised us
that by the time we record it again
you'd have a website ready to go yes I
heard that too so I have
on the 16th of this month so I will be
launching the website at the end of this
month actually for real this time I have
been working really hard on it so it
will be coming out at the end of the
month but for now I am the travelling
stoner on Instagram and periscope you
can find me on Twitter as the travel
stoner and you can find me on snapchat
as a travel and stoner without the G
what's your home address undisclosed
bunker the studio needs a name because
you know how Instagram has that little
story I deleted quite a few because I
actually I didn't even want to say the
name of the city because I have learned
people will try to find me oh yeah
so I just said that's being on your
podcast where you are and if you guys
found me through granny's feed by anyway
if granny if you learned of this podcast
through granny send me a message or tag
me in something and just say hey I found
you through the diving granny so that I
can give her a hug for every one of
those alright so follow the traveling
stoner she's gonna get her [ __ ] together
and get her website up got a cool camera
I'm not even being creepy wherever you
want to go give you the chance
pretty sure I want the Sun coming from
that way and I need you over there I
won't [ __ ] take pictures perfect I
usually just take pictures of weed to
tell you the truth Colfax Avenue a real
picture of me yes you didn't know this
you know that one hatpin no the tall one
where I'm holding that teapot yeah eh
see Sam and I had a photo shoot before
for THC magazine is 4/20 booze for what
kind of product is that it's this little
tea pot thing that goes on a panel I
catch
looks like a teapot love smoking out of
it okay do an Instagram video with it so
that we can see it no we're gonna go one
better when that billboards up we're
gonna do a group dab up under the
billboard I mean I'll take a seventy
show they used to climb up the water
yeah I've climbed up a few water towers
in my life
that's it Brett by the way yes yes hey
Brett
just for being awesome and for always
being so positive and loving his videos
I hope you're getting over it there and
you're feeling better by the time this
comes out I want to get with him and do
this cold terpene thing that I've been I
made the whole thing functional give a
huge shout out and a heads up to our
buddy THC Sam Sam wanted to come tonight
his life's been overwhelming he got to
interview Tommy Chong so he didn't have
time to make it here today
I guess sorry Tommy Chong us yeah he's a
photographer he works for a magazine
when somebody like Tommy Chong Cole
comes through town your job is to go
take pictures and do magazine [ __ ]
cannabis based magazines you have to do
that's your job go do that Sam you've
got an open invitation there are three
chairs here at the table that are
available one of them has got your name
on it whenever you want to come also
Brett I want to come get you I want to
get you to come be on the show here at
my house where we've got this good
studio the good mics where the equipment
doesn't screw up we can be comfortable
it's quiet nobody interrupts other than
you kitchen organized Buki Fox I've had
some real good conversations with him
about CBDs he's been on a couple times
he's due for another episode we need to
get him here again I'd love to have
Kabuki across the table talk about
certain doses of specific cannabinoids
for certain conditions so between the
CBDs
and Brett with the Terps we're talking
New Age medicine yes yes and Sam Sam and
I I'd love to talk about traumatic brain
injuries with Sam because of course
everybody knows that I've got a TBI that
[ __ ] me if you heard on the podcast
occasionally I just stop and start a
brand new sentence I also want to say
that Sam is actually running this food
drive with us as well yeah we forgot to
even like tonight exactly but yes Sam is
also another big part of helping us
getting this food charity as is over at
the glass I spaced out on her instagram
name I know it's black cloudy Cody yeah
mm-hmm
she's gonna help us with the fliers yes
I'm glad we caught up on that and didn't
skip people yes that's all right at
least we told them what the you know
food drive he's not concrete yeah we
have Friday get them absolutely yeah
yeah and you know we still have three
spots open for people so Bobo I did not
forget you Braille I pay attention I
made a mental nobody plugs things that's
still available on Big Cartel calm yes
no there that's still there still active
I'm still doing that I don't get too
many words so I'm not super super busy
but I'm still doing them they're still
available I still do custom stuff with
that as well focus in pretty heavily on
the new glass game yeah that's my new
glass page yes well a new glass page I
have no no me glass it's n om e glass
and you got to follow my normal
Instagram is boba blaster Co that's a bo
bo bo blaster Co and the same thing on
periscope and I think that's all I'm on
yeah that's about it you know those
people that's on every single now I'm
barely on those I tried to yeah but
you're like logging off right
yeah Jeff is here but was gone I was so
happy to see him today and I just
thought of somebody else we need to
shout out color me filthy artists I've
just become friends with on Instagram
and he's embracing my friends he's in
his name is Paul Color Me filthy ass
yeah that's pretty cool I like the
zombie photos I've been seeing of
everybody figures out all those I think
they're pretty cool what he's been doing
to my friends I think I'm addicted to
bit low jeez little Rasta Jeff
everywhere different funny [ __ ] so red
it's silver I'm obsessed correct you can
find me on I'm on all of the damn social
medias on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
is probably the best way to find me on
Instagram it would be really rad if you
follow me on instagram it's ireon der
score genetics hopefully by the time
this episode comes out I'll be at 10,000
followers you can find me on Facebook
the girl from your heart podcast I think
that's enough of that social media stuff
I don't need to pitch too many more of
them I think that's all we're gonna do
for today I want to thank everybody for
coming especially granny you've got an
hour drive home so we're gonna okay it
was worth it we're gonna let you sober
up so you're not medicated for the drive
of course not you know what I'm saying
and then yeah the rest of us are gonna
go hiya [ __ ] I have too far to go yeah
yes yes you have to be safe and sober
for your drive home I'm here at my table
so I'm gonna take a graham dab I'll just
have to have some green crack before I
go so I'm wide awake there you go
we may we may do a little Facebook live
video or something here since we've got
a whole bunch of cool ass people in the
building yeah yeah yeah all right so
we're gonna wrap up the podcast ladies
gentleman thank you guys for listening
for someone to say that thing more if
you want to go to iTunes and leave us a
review that would be SuperDuper cool I
will read your review on a future
episode if you've got anything you'd
like to say and you do not want to do it
at a public forum on social media send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you if
you want some grow lessons if you need
some advice if you just want to see
what's up gonna something go [ __ ] myself
I'm down
said it I don't hear what you have to
say good or bad I ain't scared I want to
know what people are thinking I'm into
it be honest with me I'm a blunt person
I like honesty so uh that's all I've got
for you this week
big shot up to the dab in granny until
next time take a phat dab and give her
mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
things not the same the fact it's
getting pretty
it's just not that great
I guess I'll go outside
and fly the weasel fluoride
[Music]
take it on down to the show
wallowing in fear the days and weeks
that you're not here
cause all the waiting in vain
the day that you arrive - leaving
[Music]
the day that you arrived my sleeping
monkeys revived
much
[Music]
but
[Applause]
all the truth
[Music]
the truth
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
you