welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 168 of the road
from Earhart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roof spin for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat good entire mystic roots crew
everybody's having a great day while
they're listening I did not put out a
Thursday episode I apologize guys it was
Thanksgiving I wanted to kind of hang
out for a week I'm actually recording
the day after Thanksgiving hope
everybody had a good holiday hope
everybody survived Black Friday maybe
you boycott it's like Friday whatever
you did hope it went well for you
you guys I'm hanging out just about 45
minutes ago I ate a Shumate bar a - oome
it banana pudding bar made with 200
milligrams of THC distillate it says
caution contains medical marijuana for
medical use only keep out of reach of
children
I could see why you guys about 40
minutes ago my life was different
I'm getting high as [ __ ] from this thing
decided I better get down on this
recording and get it done before things
get wonky in my world so big shout out
to our friends at Shumate bars I endorse
the banana pudding bar it's delicious
go get yourself one check it out at your
local dispensary alright guys speaking
of shout outs big shots were friends at
the dank team.com if you need regular or
feminized seats make sure you support
our friends is a dank team that dot let
me try that again
the dank team calm there we go that was
English the dank team calm they've got
brands like archive C bank they have got
mile hike an adventure
they've of course got I read genetics
they've got rare dankness they've
they've got everybody you can think of
they've now got Brothers Grimm seeds
which is a great thing because shout out
to Brothers Grimm in the c99 so make
sure you check out the dank team
dot-com let's see who else do I need to
give a shout-out to no more shout out
since we're talking about seeds let's
talk about my recent breeding pot
project you guys it has been time
yesterday I checked the male plants I
checked the female plants and they were
speaking at me bro they were like it is
time let's sprinkle some pollen anybody
that's paying a bit been paying
attention to the show knows that I've
been running a breeding project
continuously I've always got some
breeding going but right now I've got a
male a Ryze plant and I've got some
female plants what's in there I have got
a grateful dog female there's a lemon
Jeffrey female there are several
cookies-and-cream females what else is
in there there's white widow and there
are some others things in there some
there also are Rice's in there so I can
make some a rise f2 seeds there's a
bunch of stuff in the room but yesterday
the male plants are huge there are male
colas the length of my arms on these
male plants and they're just pollen is
just falling out if you breathe too
heavily pollen goes flying across the
room so I didn't want to drag the whole
plant across the room to where the
females were so I cut off a few select
branches that were quite large carried
them over to the male plant the female
plants and gave all those male plants a
nice shake there was a huge cloud of
pollen in my grow room for quite a while
I tastes like pollen everything tastes
like pollen around me my whole mouth was
just coated in pollen I had to take a
fat shower I had to clean everything up
there was a lot of pollen in the air so
in about 50-60 ish days we're gonna have
some new seeds some new creations it's
gonna be some great stuff happening I'm
excited for that so let's see what else
can I talk about we talked about that
I'm just making I've got a check list
you guys cuz I get stupid high and
forget to talk about chitin I talked
about [ __ ] that doesn't even matter
instead um let's see what did I do I
kinda want to brag a couple of days ago
on Friday night I got to take my lovely
date Jenny Beth to comedy works to go
see Joe Rogan was the headliner there
was a comedian named Doron Horton that
opened that dude was [ __ ] hilarious
you guys I'd never heard of or seen him
before when he came on stage he walked
in made a presence and he crushed for
like 30 or 40 solid minutes and then he
wound down and he looked at the crowd
and he was like I think I'm done
and he said ladies and gentlemen Joe
Rogan and Joe Rogan came out and crushed
you guys Joe Rogan just did his new
comedy special for the year and when a
comedian records their special the way
they do it they kind of record that
special
and they throw away that material once
your comedy special comes out on Comedy
Central or Netflix or wherever it goes
see so seems to be the new [ __ ] once
your comedy special comes out you throw
away that material you don't perform
that anymore and you work on your next
hour and then at the end of the year you
want to put out your whole new special
of our material then you do that all
over again and that keeps the commedia
on his toes but Rogan just put out a
special so he's only had a couple of
months to work up new [ __ ] maybe a month
and he was here doing new [ __ ] he went
for an hour and a half and about 45 to
an hour into the show he kind of looked
up at the crowd with this look and he
goes I just ran out of [ __ ] about like
three minutes ago I don't have any more
material and he just started making [ __ ]
up on the fly and kind of joke in and
he's still crushed it he did a little
bit of crowd work but he destroyed for a
comedian I love Joe Rogan style I love
the way he does comedy and I agree with
like 97% of what he says so that's
always a great show so Joe does his show
he wraps up we're giving him a standing
ovation he walks off the stage and less
than 40 seconds later he comes running
back onstage it had to be like 15 20
seconds later he ran back onstage and he
grabs a microphone and he said sit the
[ __ ] down
ladies and gentlemen Dave Chappelle is
here he said you guys Dave Chappelle is
here and me and my date looked at each
other like what cuz what that's what
probably one of our favorite comedians
both of us I've never seen Dave
Chappelle she's never seen Rogan or
Chappelle I've seen Rogan before but for
Chappelle to walk out was awesome
Chappelle was [ __ ] up you guys
Chappelle was intoxicated luckily since
I've got some friends at Comedy Works I
happened to be front row and as you walk
out onto the stage there are a couple
stages a couple seats actually on the
stage but then if you go a few more feet
those next two seats that are in the
crowd are where I was sitting and where
Jenny Beth was sitting so Chappelle just
was [ __ ] up so he just walked out
barely onto the stage so he was on the
stage and he stood directly in front of
her and I and told jokes for about 30
minutes and Shane smoked cigarettes and
drank corona beers he did 40 solid
minutes of grabbing by the [ __ ] jokes
and material about Trump and the
election he did some Dave Chappelle
jokes he did a little bit of weed jokes
but mostly grab him by the [ __ ] jokes
for like 40 minutes by Dave Chappelle it
was hilarious big shout out to Jenny
Beth for going with me she was an
incredible date we're having a lot of
fun with her
so big shout out that was a great time
glad she was able to come had to get her
off work a little bit early for that and
glad it worked out super huge shout out
to the [ __ ] traffic oh my god usually
i-25 can lick my balls but that night it
was smooth I can't believe it that was
awesome everything was super smooth that
day big shout out to Baker at Comedy
Works big shout out to Comedy Works big
chefs in the entire Comedy Works crew
Comedy Works has the podcast you guys
it's called how Comedy Works if you care
about comedy if you're a comedy fan I of
course am obviously check it out how
Comedy Works hosted by Wendy the owner
of Comedy Works and a comedian his
name's Rick Kern's he's almost famous
you know he's kind of on the cusp
everybody's really funny and he's got a
great personality so check him out let's
see where else are we on this list of
things to talk about I want to give one
more shout out and then we're gonna do a
couple things here with the podcast I do
have some real content you guys I always
shout out to my friend at the spliff
cast
ladies and gentleman there's a podcast
called the spliff cast they gave me she
gave me like a minute and a half
shoutout and an endorsement the other
day and I listened to her somebody told
me hey this podcast shouted you out and
so I checked it out and wow that's a
great show so check it out it's hosted
by a lady named bone Ellis she's not as
hyper as me and she doesn't take as many
dads as me so she's a little little more
focused if I'm too much energy for you
if I'm too hyper and [ __ ] you will
definitely enjoy her she's calm she's
more mellow than myself and she puts out
a great show so I endorsed that fully
thanks for the shout out thanks for the
support and you guys support my new
friend at the spliff cast all right I am
going to open up iTunes here I've got a
couple of new iTunes comments you guys I
love the iTunes comments and the reviews
I would appreciate it if you go to
iTunes if you're in iTunes use if you've
got an iPhone if you got a MacBook
whatever however you're using iTunes a
lot of you guys are using an Android
with stitcher but if you've got iTunes
go to the iTunes Store search for the
girl from your heart podcast when you
find you got a scroll down to the bottom
there's a little tab with the logo it's
got the red gold and green logo with my
face on it click on that go to ratings
and reviews would be super awesome if he
types in a radio review and then gave me
a rating everybody so far has given me a
five-star review I've got 39 five-star
reviews I'd be cool if you kept that up
but hey give me what you feel I deserve
that would be awesome I'm going to read
the two most recent comments this one
just happens to be from bow at the
spliff
caste they said she said one episode in
and I can tell this show is solid can't
wait for the new ones and to go digging
through old ones I can't grow but in
theory and you got all kinds of delivery
on the theory thanks man
well you're very welcome I appreciate
you for listening to the podcast it's
great hearing other podcast podcasters
complement your podcast that really
means a lot to me all the compliments
mean a lot to me but she complimented on
her show she complimented the sound
quality other than me clearing my throat
I apologize for that
she complimented the sound quality and
that means a lot to me so thanks for
noticing I appreciate that and thanks
for noticing the show overall so a big
shot at the bow with the spliff podcast
our next comment comes from dab Smith's
dab Smiths has become a good friend
lately we've been talking a lot the
comment says I'll get a five-star review
also in the commets says great show is
always buddy you should try to do two
shows a week on the rag thanks for the
good podcast to listen to every Monday
morning when I start the daily grind I
usually get the show while I'm prepping
my work for the day keep up the good
work amigo you know I wish I could do I
wish I could promise you two shows every
week sometimes time doesn't allow it
this week of course being the
Thanksgiving week I just took it off I
wanted to hang out spend some time
actually worked on my garden a little
bit I hung out with that girl Jenny Beth
I've been talking about so much hung out
with some family hung out with my kid oh
yes I do have a daughter I don't talk
about her a lot on the podcast cause I
mean she doesn't want to be talked about
I'm pretty sure on a podcast but hung
out with her a little bit so it kind of
took took the Thursday episode off I
promise you the Monday episode I will do
my best to get you Thursday episodes as
frequently as I can I appreciate you for
listening I'm glad that I can make your
Monday's better that was why I put them
out on Monday
Monday's are generally shitty for people
who don't like their jobs or don't have
the best jobs you little get the girl
weed people that aren't artists or
musicians your Monday probably sucks if
you're in the service industry your
Monday sucks so that's why I put them
out on Monday morning I try to make your
day a little bit brighter I'm glad I'm
doing that for you dad Smiths thanks for
listening yeah I appreciate it you guys
I would love your comments or if you've
got something else you'd like to say and
you don't want to say it on a public
forum you can send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
totally love to hear from you speaking
of emails you guys that's what we're
gonna get to I've got an email from a
guy dude I'm gonna hit pause and take a
drink so he can quit
you hold on for just a second you don't
have to hold on keep listening it'll
happen through editing all right I feel
like that's a little bit better of
course it'll come back because I took
some dabs and I ate this uh
I'm not blaming it on the banana pudding
bar but it is kind of making my throat a
little uh it's getting minute that
buttery thing but anyway let's get to
this email let's start it off with an
email from a dude who said call him
Roscoe he says hey dude it's Roscoe I
message you for advice which I got from
you from your episodes and it was great
stuff dude keep up the good work I catch
up every Monday at work on your podcast
and have done so for over a year now
when I came across it in fact dude it
was around that time you said he'd put
money in a pot for your curse words so
you guys a long time ago I didn't find
it very professional to use any
profanity on my podcast and when I would
drop f-bombs in other words I would try
to throw I forgot how much money I said
I would put in a jar and we actually
donated that to a good cause but I
filled up a jar with a bunch of money
you guys and then somebody was like
that's stupid be yourself I hate it when
he tried to restrain yourself and so I
decided you're right [ __ ] it and now I
say [ __ ] on the show is it's a lot but
it's more of me honestly it's more
comfortable and I hate trying to censor
myself
it's how I I don't know maybe it's not
professional but that's how I roll and
it's me I'd rather be me than not to
tell you the truth so he's continues to
say anyway safe to say due to your
podcast and the educated guess you have
on I have successfully grown a lot of
nice bushy plants awesome I'm glad to
hear that he also says I've saved a ton
of money thanks to you guys thanks to
you guys seriously not buying from the
local riffraff has been a weight lifted
off of me anyway I've been thinking for
a year now about doing a podcast much
similar to yours bar a few things but
I've got to back up that's something I
don't think about he says that I've
saved him money and a big hassle not
having to buy from the local riffraff
I'm six foot five and 200 pounds and I
don't worry a lot when I used to have to
go buy cannabis but I can only imagine
if I were not this stature and I didn't
have this type of upbringing where I'm
from and I had to go into my old
neighborhood where I'm actually from the
go buy weed I could just imagine how
that would feel to be some of those
people in the stress that that would be
I'm sure people get robbed and beat up
and [ __ ] and get sold terrible product
that isn't even weed that's gotta suck
so I'm sure I could lift a lot of weight
off people's shoulders if there
to grow that is I can only imagine that
I didn't even realize that just thinking
about the the people you can avoid by
not having to buy herb that's helpful
anyway he goes on I'm rambling today you
guys I apologize I'm gonna blame it on
the 200 milligrams Schumann bar that I
ate and the like 16 ounces of dr. pepper
together whoa that's a combo you guys
I'd be feeling it he says I've been
thinking about doing a four I've been
thinking for over a year now about doing
a podcast much similar to you similar to
yours bar a few things then he says I am
in the UK and there's not really a
podcast out here for the UK people and
you have inspired me to want to be that
podcast the law is changing slowly here
the NHS are testing it for the first
time now and all the MPs want to advise
our new prime minister mr. May
to legalize cannabis oh that's awesome
there's a lot of amazing stuff in that
one paragraph I have inspired somebody
to want to create a podcast for their
fourth in the UK for the entire UK about
cannabis because there isn't one
that's awesome I am that I'm honored
that I inspired somebody to do that also
I'm glad that I inspired you to do that
but that's gonna lead me to part of my
reply to your email it's also great that
the law is slowly changing there I know
some areas in the UK have really strict
shitty cannabis laws I'm glad that
they're easing up on that I love that
the MPs want to advise the minister that
they want them to legalize cannabis when
I'm pretty sure that's the military
police I'm not sure exactly I didn't
research that but whoever when other
when other people are like hey do this
that's really helpful so this guy goes
on to say I want to educate people and
teach them how to grow small secret
setups and have fun doing it UK cannabis
news culture education chats and more if
not illegal to encourage on a podcast
you know I don't think it's illegal to
encourage on a podcast but where you are
you may want to talk to a lawyer because
I don't know the rules in the UK that
could be completely different I've been
told that I'm safe as long as I'm
careful and we try to be careful here on
the show so check on that yourself
that's the best I can say there but you
go on to say could you give me any
advice on doing this any tips tricks et
cetera to a successful successful
podcast and he said thanks dude much
love rosco and they also said PS don't
mind if you read it on your podcast
which is good because I just read the
whole
email on the podcast first off thank you
for the email second I'm glad that I can
inspire you to do a podcast about
cannabis third thanks for being so
passionate about cannabis because it
sounds like it's illegal there and
you're risking your life and your safety
and your family and your freedom and
your finances in your future for this
plant because you're in love so thanks
for being on this team and that leads me
to my answer my part of my reply I know
that you're the right person to do this
podcast because you have taken the
effort to reach out to me to say what
should I do
so that tells me right there you are
supposed to be the guy doing this
podcast be the confident dude that you
are when you go to make your podcast
talk to the people just like you did to
me in this email because this is
comfortable and it sounds like you're a
cool person and it sounds like you can
connect with people so do that on your
podcast just be yourself that's the best
advice I can give to any person trying
to do any podcast be you if your fake
your listeners won't know it you won't
have any fun it won't feel good and
you'll come across fake and people can
spot fake and they won't listen to fake
and you'll get more shitty emails than
you could ever imagine so chill out be
yourself edit a little bit but don't
take out all of your mistakes I I
stutter I say dumb [ __ ] I say the wrong
[ __ ] and I talked over myself all the
time but that's me and I've learned to
accept me and it makes a good podcast
just being me people don't want me to be
a Paula I'm not the president I don't
need to come out you out here up here
and speak some perfect [ __ ] to you do
you have to grow weed so be yourself be
comfortable get some good equipment
that's something I really should say you
don't need to spend a lot of money my
favorite set up is the zoom h6 on-the-go
I use a zoom h6 and I run four
Sennheiser 835 ee 835 microphones into
that I'm not sure what's available in
the UK you could probably get that or
very similar it's a great recording
device a lot of people use that for my
big setup there's a lot of stuff
happening but sound quality is certainly
important people if when people do phone
calls on a podcast or if they Skype in I
don't even listen so get good quality so
I'd really stress on good quality sound
good sound the best you can make sure
that there's no funky noise in the
background or if you're gonna do in a
coffee shop and you want that clunky
like dishes
waitress sound vibe kind of thing go for
that if that's your vibe I don't like
that I like it quiet I talk when I don't
talk there's no noise in my background I
love that sort of feel so sound how you
want to sound achieve your sound figure
out how you got to do that be yourself
and then find content that relates to
the audience you want to hit which is
obviously cannabis and news and culture
and education and chats so find some
people in your community that you can
get on a show and build a relationship
with what I found is the people that
come back to my show the third and
fourth time they come back they forget
they're on a podcast and they're now
hanging out in my little recording space
and we just happen to have headphones
and a microphone on and we really get
talking about cannabis in a way that we
love instead of a way that feels podcast
II and interviewee like you guys notice
when Jesse comes back the first time
jesse was here you guys a hundred
episodes Jesse talked like this like
said like four words like okay yeah and
now when Jesse comes on you can't get
him to shut up you guys so just get kind
of build a relationship with somebody
that you can get on the podcast try to
find people that are experts in certain
areas of cannabis like I've got a guy
Jesse's my outdoor guy of course Sean is
kind of the organics guy even though
he's hard to get ahold of lately Spencer
is was our extracts guy even though he's
moved so try to have guys that you can
have like special like you got guys for
everything in your life you got a you
know weed guy you know you got a
fireworks guy you got or whatever guy
get those guys for your podcast also so
that's something I could recommend
here's something that I could talk about
from being a podcast nerd if you want to
be noticed in iTunes get at least 8 or
10 episodes put together before you
launch into iTunes because your first
eight weeks in iTunes is when they will
notice you and that's if you get good
ratings and you pop out with a lot of
quality content iTunes will put you in
the new and noteworthy category which
will get you a lot more views and/or
listen so try to get eight episodes put
together drop a lot of quality content
and eight weeks and you'll get up there
in iTunes
I feel like another guy they listen to
you guys a lot of what I've learned
about podcasting I got to give somebody
a shout out here because I feel like I
just turned I channeled this guy there's
a guy named cliff ravenscraft he was
known he is known as the podcast Answer
Man if you go to the podcast Answer Man
comm cliff will teach you
a lot of stuff about podcasting there
was a lot of paid content on his website
he will want you to sign up for his
podcasting A to Z courses he'll try to
get you to pay for a lot of online
courses I have not paid for anything and
I have learned a tremendous amount about
podcasting just through cliff
ravenscraft free stuff through his
Twitter feeds through his email groups
just stuff like that so you could always
contact cliff ravenscraft or podcast
Answer Man comm that is a wealth of
podcasting knowledge all right
so Roscoe I feel like I have given you a
lot of podcasting information and this
is a cannabis podcast so I am going to
try to wrangle my listeners back up I'm
going to read an email about cannabis
next Roscoe I truly appreciate your
efforts I want to know how your podcast
goes if you do get this podcast launched
or if you need any help getting this
podcast launched send me another email I
would be truly delighted to help you get
your podcast going I'll give you all the
advice I can things are gonna be a
little bit different because you're in
the UK some of the setup may be
different but we'll get it going we'll
figure it out between the two of us
we're smart enough to get this going I
can't wait to hear your show and also
thanks for listening and thanks for the
email I look forward to hearing your
show in the future don't put it off
because if you keep putting it off it'll
just fall to the wayside you'll forget
get it going all right you guys I need
to take a quick drink and I'm gonna read
another email about cannabis all right
you guys I got a quick drink took a fat
dab I'm ready to read another email this
one comes from you know I don't know if
he wants me to say his name let's see
I'm looking I don't have any indicator
so I'm not gonna say your name dude but
big shout out you know who you are I
appreciate you for sending an email now
I will read your message it goes like
this it says hey bro loving the show
been listening for over a year now first
I want to thank you for spreading the
knowledge and being a voice for the
cannabis community awesome man first off
thanks for listening second I guess I'm
glad to be that voice for the community
I guess I'm just the guy that grabbed a
mic and wanted to do that I never
thought of that trying to think about it
then it'll put too much pressure on me
anyway he goes on and he says my
question I hope you can give your
thoughts on is a term known as bud
washing I had a good friend telling me
to try it in case you're unfamiliar with
the term it's where you take your just
harvested butts that are still on the
branches and you dip or wash them in
water I read it's supposed to get dust
particles off of your herb and make it
cleaner tastier smoke then he also says
turning me on to Ritchie spice I heard
you mentioning him on a previous episode
so I searched him out and then he quotes
some Richie spice oh man you're glad all
right you're welcome I'm glad you like
Richie spice oh you guys I'm hiya [ __ ]
tonight this Shumate bar is kicking in I
ate this an hour and a half I should go
and yeah I'm floating around on my chair
here 200 milligrams of THC distillate
will get to you plus I've had a few dabs
so kind of floating around I like it I
love it try out so I'm gonna kind of
talk about what he asked here he said is
blood washing a term that I am familiar
with yes I learned this from Jorge
Cervantes Jorge didn't do it with just
water
Jorge took a five-gallon bucket of he
used reverse osmosis water you can use
water from the hose if your water is
okay if you don't have funky ass water
you can use water from your hose so fill
up a 5-gallon bucket of water and then
Jorge was putting 25 I've seen people
put more you guys but 25 is probably
what I would recommend 25 or 30
milliliters of 30% hydrogen peroxide
into a five-gallon bucket of water not
the hydrogen peroxide that your mom's
got in the cabinet the stuff that you
buy you can get it at the Hydra store
probably and get it online but it's 30%
maybe 33 maybe 35% hydrogen peroxide
it's not expensive but you put about 30
milliliters of that 25 30 mils in a
5-gallon bucket stir it up real good and
then you harvest the branches and you
leave is like kind of long branches you
know six to eight inch long branches and
wear rubber gloves and dunk the entire
branch into the water and give it a
swirl like freshly chopped you want to
chop the plants down cut off all the big
leaves trim it up like you're gonna trim
it up again later like you're just
cleaning it up you're not manicuring it
you're just kind of trimming it
I've been dunk that into the water
solution the peroxide water solution
give it a good swirl so that if there is
perhaps powdery mildew on there you can
knock that powdery mildew off that is a
really good way to get powdery mildew if
you don't have the PM on there I guess
that would knock dust off if you drew it
outside and it got dusty and [ __ ] but I
don't see how much it dust is really
gonna be on your plants if you grew
indoors in a good
grow environment but I've heard of this
being done by Jorge Cervantes and I've
seen it done by other people for powdery
mildew and other problem
like that to clean that stuff off so
brought a little bit of peroxide 25 to
30 mils and a five-gallon bucket to
clean water cut the branches into six or
eight inch maybe ten inch sections it's
got to fit in that five-gallon bucket
dunk it in there give it a good shake
then hang it up give the buds plenty of
space when they're hung up on there that
way and they're just gonna drip onto the
floor you guys all that water is gonna
drip all over the floor
and it is gonna run right out and then
it'll dry keep a fan in the room maybe a
dehumidifier in there pay attention to
the conditions in your drying area but
if you're gonna do this you got to pay
attention I don't let it get to you to
humaid in there a lot of people are
gonna say you're gonna soak buds that
were just harvested you guys if you
think about it cannabis plants grow
outside and if it weren't for us getting
in the way they would get wet all the
damn time I don't think that every
cannabis plant that ever got wet outside
got destroyed I'm pretty sure that a lot
of them got stronger and they got
tougher if you look at the shape of a
cannabis plant it is kind of shaped like
an umbrella when water hits a cannabis
plant the leaves pushed the water in an
outward direction and it spreads it out
so that it falls down now that tells me
that you should water the plants around
that area because that's where the roots
are gonna grow out because in nature
that's where the water is gonna land of
course you want to get it in toward the
stock with the outward area is a little
bit more aware you want it because
nature would spread it out so cannabis
is gonna search for roots out that way
because it knows that you guys also the
resin glands on your plant will protect
it from the water you're not gonna bust
that off by just giving it a little dunk
it's not gonna come off there these guys
that make ash they're using a washing
machine and ice to pull those trichomes
off of your buds so a little bit of a
dunk isn't gonna gonna pull those off of
there if you've already got a little bit
of PM or if you had an issue this is a
good way to get rid of it it's funny
because in Colorado I make the joke that
nobody gets powdery mildew anymore ever
ever since anybody infinite or figured
out how to make BHO everybody just
[ __ ] blast it even though it's got
powdery mildew on it but I wouldn't
recommend using a hole if it's got a lot
of powdery mildew don't don't use it get
rid of that product get rid of that
material but if you've just got a little
bit of a problem like people in Oregon
this year got pummeled with powdery
mildew and other molds this will not
handle your Brown mold this will not
handle [ __ ] like that but a little bit
of powdery mildew this peroxide solution
will get rid of it
yes you can do it if you want to get the
dust and the dirt off if you drew out
a lot of people find like cocoons or
caterpillars silk on their buds that
would be a good way to get rid of that
stuff just give it a good dunk that way
you know it's clean just make sure you
getting plenty of ventilation plenty
airflow when it dries it's gonna dry up
like normal it's just gonna take a
little bit longer you won't notice a
difference I'm pretty sure you can take
a bud that did not get dunked in a bud
that did get dunked and dried properly
and trimmed and cured properly and you
can smoke them both and you will not be
able to tell the difference that's my
opinion on that so yes I've heard of
this I've seen it in practice I don't
know that I have personally tried it but
I've seen it done I've been places that
have done it it's kind of a semi common
practice and commercial grows to tell
you the truth because it is legal in
Colorado to do that two buds grown in a
commercial facility all right I think
that's all I've got time for I don't
want to start another email because I've
been going for close to thirty minutes
and it's hard to do a long episode by
myself I feel like I just start
chattering get way off course so I'm
gonna start wrapping up to show you guys
I want to know what you guys know about
a web site known as patreon you guys
feel like you want to contribute to the
podcast patreon is the way to do it you
guys a lot of people have send me a
message like hey on the website you used
to have a donation button and that is
gone what happened to that PayPal did
not like having their service attached
to my website that was about a podcast
it was about growing cannabis they felt
like that was inappropriate and they
didn't want to be involved so they made
me take the PayPal link off of my
website so that's gone but what we can
do we can set you up with patreon I'm
gonna pull up the website right here
I've got it stored so that I can make
sure to give you the right link it is
patreon patr
yo n patreon.com slash grow from your
heart if you go there you can find out
how to become a member of patreon how
you can sign up and you can contribute
to the podcast you can sign up and you
can contribute it's like a monthly
service if you want to contribute
monthly you can throw as little as one
dollar in every month I would totally
appreciate it honestly you guys what
that is going for is it will pay for the
web hosting for my website I regen etics
Colorado com it does cost me a little
bit of money to keep that running on a
yearly basis I have to pay that fee and
that's what keeps the girl from your
heart podcast feed alive so that's all
I'm asking for I'm not trying to get
rich off the podcast I'm just trying to
offset the cost of my web fees I've
already bought the equipment some time
ship brakes so maybe I'll ask on patreon
for help with that but so far I'm just
trying to pay for the cost of the
website I would appreciate if you
contributed I'm gonna quit begging cuz
it already feels a little funky
alright guys I wanna thank you guys for
listening to another episode of the
podcast I want to give a huge shout out
to my friend Baker at Comedy Works also
shout out to Jenny Beth also a huge
shout out to everybody at Comedy Works
who always treats me like a king every
time I go there
ladies gentlemen let me right remind you
again that I would appreciate it if you
go to iTunes click on the iTunes Store
search for the girl from your art
podcast click on it there's my face on
there click on that go to the ratings
and review section type in a rating no
type in a review that's a type and
review let me know what you think of the
podcast I will read you'll review on a
future episode everybody so far has
given me a five-star review you can give
me as many stars as you feel I deserve
if you want to be a weirdo and stand out
don't do 5 but they could be cool if he
gave me 5 like everybody else ladies and
gentlemen this shoe MIT bar is really
kicking in hardcore if you want to prove
it I can't even talk now if you've got a
product you'd like me to review that's
what I was trying to say or if you've
got something you'd like to say you can
send me an email girl from your heart at
hotmail.com
I'd also like it if you follow me on the
social media I'm on Facebook it's girl
from your heart podcast I am on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast you guys I got to
10,000 followers followers on Instagram
its Irie underscore genetics on
Instagram I am at ten thousand and one
hundred followers now thank you to
everybody that followed me and thanks to
everybody that will follow me
because I am high as giraffe [ __ ] I
think it's time to wrap up the podcast I
want to thank you guys for listening
big shot it's my ninja Spence it's all
next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
well this is dedicated to the most high
volume in the ice-sub I come to tell yo
tell everyone I'm recommending some
protection
I never mahir money destination but will
be young man too and I'm recommending
some protection honey mama here mama de
stay me and Shannon what - now I'm free
I'm a dancer they gone wrong
well I fired my swanee Messiah
appreciation is the Creator hot creation
cut to me and come cause when a patron
comes second but some of us an angle he
bangs and I'm a free hugs them but
they're not really great one coming
night them walk in the footsteps at
Seattle we are mix and mingle with
corruption so see they know don't live a
life in Lafayette destruction bottle and
fill my hide
protection you are near my mini money
they sting me and shine
what soup now I'm feeling it answered
live on young fool ever seeking a new
job full-time them
riccati community almighty is near and a
long time me
[Music]
Joe you Fratelli people themself in lodi
division and again with a pitch - a
fourth religion
yo i will have here comes one decision
young
we are both concatenation if we love my
Angela I am inside protection
I'm a medium and me wrong
I know
[Music]
Crytek shining fine Amamiya might be
testing me a shiner but to know I'm in
assertive on wrong
[Music]
yes
I mean he just India China but no a
preeminent serve me gone wrong wait
[Music]