yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 170 to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
let's light a few new growers with your
professional grower appear a new smoker
or a dedicated dabber to tree cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat coot and the entire mystic
roots crew oh sorry
let's try not to cough tried so hard not
to cough it reached up return to the
music and coughed at the same time I
sped through the intro ladies and
gentlemen also welcome to the podcast
sitting across the table from me looking
sharp in his sweet new the great white
shark grass roots he'll ladies and
welcome to the show
Jessi Witt is back thanks for joining me
bro make sure you guys stock Jessi on
Instagram while we were here he is at
Jessi grows check him out
does the Colorado podcast have an
Instagram now yes he's been posting some
cool ganja pictures what's the stream
you posted here the day the Smurfs
Jasper what's the cross on the Smurfs
it's some blue tie something it reminds
me of a strain yeah is gonna get alright
sounds like we need to cut this part of
the conversation Jory moving forward
ladies and gentlemen make sure you go
stock Jessi while he's here also go
check out my friends at handmade apparel
go to handmade apparel dot biz because
this part of the podcast is brought to
you by our four good friends at handmade
apparel you guys my friends at handmade
apparel made me some hoodies they have
the girl from your heart podcast logo
right above the left breast it doesn't
have my face on it
and on the back it's got the girl from
your heart podcast logo with my big
cheesy face on there these hoodies are
sweet you guys they look super cool if
you're interested in one send me an
email I've gotten two emails so far
I took on a new project and I have not
replied too many emails I will get back
to you probably after I record so if
you're interested in hoodie
send me a message jesse picked up the
hoodies and made the big cheesiest smile
that I've seen in a long time
pretty cool there pretty cool look and
it's kind of weird to see a hoodie with
my face on it but people will be wearing
them and I'll have to adjust it's a big
shot it's my head my friends at hand big
shout to my hand this is gonna be an
interesting podcast we've been taking
some big fad dad's from cascade shatter
it's gonna be a fun show but big shot
it's my friends at handmade apparel if
you need some shirts made if you need
something printed if you need stickers
if you need some hat pins made go check
out handmade apparel table is there
great people great folks I love those
guys thanks for the hoodies you guys
they look great said it once before but
I can't get over that logo it looks like
Jesse said the punk rock thing so once
it fades and doesn't look brand new is
that what you're gonna like it
let's see what else did I want to make
sure to mention something I thought
about the other day on the podcast and
I'm sure that Jesse will I will agree
with what I'm gonna say there was
another word I was trying to turn to
fine but I can't find the word you guys
I owe you a huge thank you for trusting
me you guys listen to me and I give you
advice about your cannabis plants which
are used for your medicine to keep you
healthy or in another way to keep your
wallet fat
however it's happening I'm helping you
out and you trust me with your financial
and your medicinal investment and your
time and your energy you trust what I
say and that means a lot to me so thank
you for trusting me and thanks for
trusting me sure that's it thanks for
believing that my guidance is correct
and thanks for believing at me thanks
for supporting the podcast ashes
coalition I realized the other day that
there are a lot of people out there
let's say I have a question about
cannabis ask Rasta Jeff so just thanks
for believing in me and trusting me to
guide you through your garden all right
I think that's enough rambling for the
start of the podcast Jesse's here and he
wanted to talk about composting he sent
me a message and he
I have had composting on my head all day
and I said I don't think compost is
quite what's in your head but it's close
so here we are we're gonna talk a little
bit about composting yeah where do you
want to start bro do you want to jump
right into it with anything okay well
the first note that I took was buh Kashi
yeah yeah so okay let's do it that way
so buh Kashi is for anyone that's not
familiar it is a grain that has been
inoculated with an e/m one culture an
endogenous microorganism yes yes yeah I
think they spray like a barley okay
possibly a dairy product that's how you
end up with the em1 okay fermented milk
okay so you take a culture you collect
and you mix it with milk and it uh it
ferments and that's how you end up with
what they call labs lactic acid bacteria
correct okay and from that you can turn
that into em1 and you can take the em1
inoculate your grain fermented it again
let it dry out and boom you've got both
Kashi great okay so are you making the
Bokashi are you buying the Bokashi
pre-made I'm getting the bow Kashi right
now from Victor with innovative organics
up in Denver okay
it's really good and it's pretty damn
cheap so and he's a small local business
that is that's taken food out of the
look you know landfills oh isn't it very
good so it's so let's teach the people
about the Bokashi bucket a little bit
then since you said taking food out of
the landfills that's gonna make people
have a lot of questions I've got a book
coffee bucket I can see one from where
we're sitting so it'll be advantageous
to describe it it's basically a five
gallon bucket with a spigot on it
there's a little collection tray in the
bottom that prevents the solid particles
from getting in the way of the spicket
and basically I fill that thing with my
vegetable scraps I don't need any meat
products so all my vegetable scraps the
tips of my carrots the ends of my
avocados the avocado pits go in there
and they disintegrate completely stuff
that goes to waste
yeah anything I would throw away it's
sitting near the trash can to encourage
me instead of putting in the trash it
goes in the Kashi bucket I fill it up I
fill up a bowl like a glass bowl and
then I dump that glass bowl into the bow
Kashi bucket because it's much easier
that way and I don't have to open it as
frequently because it smell so you've
got a five-gallon bucket with a lid that
seals on it it's gonna speak it I
usually put a little late a thin layer
of newspaper in there just to prevent a
good idea yeah cuz some of that particle
stuff will clog up the drain thing there
so you put put the paper down and then
you I just put like a couple banana
peels I honestly in there to get started
so you two [ __ ] ton of I used to eat a
[ __ ] ton of bananas two banana peels in
there to get it started than a handful
of the Bokashi grain because that is a
bio activator and then you just start
throwing your all your scrap in there
and then once you get a nice layer maybe
an inch or two thick then just put a
little another handful of that Bokashi
grain on there and repeat just make a
lasagna basically of scraps Kashi scraps
Kashi
I think it's an inch and a half that
they say okay I put in yeah so every
inch and a half throw in more Bowl Kashi
great and don't press it down you guys
cuz it's going to expand in there no you
do what a press you do want to press it
down yes okay
yeah all right so uh most PO Kashi
buckets come with a little longer masher
thing oh it's when you push it down that
it farts and makes a horrific smell yes
correct okay he's also you could squeeze
a [ __ ] ona of chili delete juice yeah
have you ever tried to clean a drain
with that juice
I actually just tried it the other day
Dave's work for you know but it's pretty
[ __ ] close okay I poured I even made
sure I had enough
I poured oh wow one client that's like a
hair clog that would have done it you
got something serious in there would you
eat boy all right so then you pack it
down and then you seal it up and just
leave it in there and then
after about ten or twelve days it'll
start making juice and you can open up
the little spigot and I use a glass
mason jar to catch the juice and then I
seal it up and I cover it with honestly
with just a rag to keep it dark because
you want to keep that away from the
light and then I put about an ounce per
five gallon bucket when I go to mix up
some nutrients put about an ounce of
that crap in there and a five gallon
bucket with my newts and I can see the
plants start up taking oh yeah much
better and when I go ahead it's just
full of nutrients it's all the nutrients
from the plant right I mean it's just
that that's all I'm using now in my
growth that's amazing even at the big
grow we've started using it quite a bit
and it will save on trash yeah save on
nutrient money it's full of humic acids
fulvic acids lactic acids
it's got bacteria and fungi in it a lot
of the things that you probably forgot
about and that your bottled nutrient
company probably missed also speed up
the root zone speed up the metabolism of
your plants so this is just the Bokashi
bucket you can get that lactic acid
bacteria juice out of there so it'll
start growing this white funky foam
these big gross looking brainy bubbles
that is perfect you want that if that's
happening you did it perfectly keep that
going because once you've drained it a
few times you can drain it a lot of
times you can leave it going and keep
draining it mash it and drain it and
mash it it'll go for a long time but
eventually what I like to do after I've
harvested I'll take my old dirt and pour
it into a big like a big are like a feed
trough for horses I think pour all the
dirt into there then I'll pour that
Bokashi bucket into there all that funk
and mix it in and mix that in with my
dirt and cover it and put a little
moisture in there and then it spreads
and I feel like that stuff the whatever
I made in the Kashi bucket grows
throughout my soil it will just go stir
it occasionally and I'll try to do it
I'll try to get to full Bokashi buckets
in there by the before I go start to
reuse it yeah
and the smell is intense we do you know
it kind of smells if you're indoors like
somebody threw up in the bar trashcan
after drinking all day it's sort of
rotten milk ice cream and then drink all
day then threw up in the bar trash can
that's what that's seriously it's bad
you can just drain a little Mike can't
be around it
white Mike it's on the podcast often he
can't he's like oh if you're gonna do
that I'm [ __ ] going home like you
won't even be here the guys at work
loved it when I the Bokashi people on
instagram actually there's actually a
company called Bokashi they use
55-gallon drums of the mixture and then
they use a forklift to lift it up and
dump it and I could just imagine what
that smells like just 55 gallons of dead
body Victor's doing the same thing never
with the innovative organics okay yeah
that's [ __ ] what was I gonna say oh when
you were talking about putting a lot of
banana peels in there so cool thing
about boat or doing this process is the
compost that the Bocage you will
eventually make the pulp itself and the
leachate from it are both they contained
the nutrients that the plants contained
and bananas for instance are super high
in potassium so if you want a custom
tune bo costs bo khosh e-juice I mean
you know look at the nutrients that are
in the plant if you filled that thing
with with bananas and banana pills i
guaranteed behind guarantee decays yep
yeah if you put berries that are darker
in colors we're gonna have a whole bunch
of like hue mix and stuff like that in
there I'll assume yeah okay
so you've got your book Oishi bucket you
got this whole fuzzy white mess of stuff
you've got jars of lactic acid bacteria
then you said your next thing that you
got going was your worm program let's
talk about your worms so I started with
100 forums back in the summer a
potential vendor brought them in and
just gave them to me it was like nice
nice red wigglers yeah a clerk shows 100
of them and like you know like let's go
on fishing yeah exactly
all right so I took it home and dumped
him in a smart pot full of food scraps
initially I put it just straight peat
moss in there because that's something
they eat and I also did I think some
newspaper then and I kept him through
the summer
I wasn't like real actively feeding him
or anything but now that winters came
around I took I think it's a 40 gallon
container and filled it with all the
worm or you know all this stuff
necessary for a good proper setup of
warm bedding and I've been dumping the
Bocage he pulled in there and they go
[ __ ] nuts for that [ __ ] but I've got
so I mean I'm just it's cool it's fun
making all my nutrients at home
basically we we tell us a little bit
about what's in your warm bedding yeah
so I use I got some used phone books or
well I think all phone books are used I
don't even know why the [ __ ] they still
make it's true just the waste of trees
yeah it's worth I shredded them up and a
bunch of newspapers I used wood chips I
have a comfrey plan at home so that's
indoors so went ahead and chopped all of
that oh guys like uh so they're gonna
turn that up for you turn that into
useable nutrients yeah which that's a
whole nother part of my little homestead
style cuddling with the comfrey that is
but uh I put some of that in there and
then a full bucket of bocaj she stuff
Wow they're gonna love all that and I
figured out it so the bow cause she
stinks like hell when it's in a open
warm bin
yes so this time I put a whole bunch of
wood thick layer wood chips on the top
and then a bunch of wet newspaper
trap it in there and the smell went I
can't smell it okay that's helpful yeah
in the winter like this it's cold you
guys it's probably 12 degrees here in
Colorado maybe lower I'm not I don't
want to cause my dad yeah it's been
tonight it's gonna get stupid cold in my
garage I'm guessing it's gonna be in the
teens would I be able to keep my 40
gallon worm life container in the garage
right now you know I don't really know
okay I have a similar situation but my
garage is heated I know it's around 65
degrees and they don't give it like do
it almost think I would assume that that
dirt is gonna be hot anyway cuz it's
bioactive in there yeah that's like the
the little warm farm I have most
definitely it creates its own heat it's
more established the big one I just set
that up last weekend so I'm sure it will
start waiting up I'm not gonna like just
say oh yeah you'll be fine so okay one
thing I would for sure do is lift it off
the floor okay so that's not that cold
your plants want to be off that cold
concrete really sucks for plants unless
it's a real fancy heated floor right
he gets so cold yeah so I'm cold so fast
it's a heat sink it actually stills heat
out of things that are sitting on it so
oh wow I never thought of that
yeah like when you're drunk anyway in
the bathtub to cool down yeah I have a
dimension so long but that was the first
first thing I could think of Wow
alright so you've got your Bo Kashi you
got your worms and you're using a big
forty gallon container how what else he
is going into your compost just kid
subscribes at this point once spring
comes around and it's not cold as [ __ ]
when I get my outdoor compost pile go
and I'll be putting all the chicken
bedding in there that's mixed with
chicken [ __ ] okay and do you put like me
products in there also no in a boat I
mean you can invoke Oishi but there they
say you can actually saw somebody the
Bokashi people put their entire
Thanksgiving dinner
their turkey like the carcass of the
uneaten turkey the mashed potatoes they
put the entire thing in there and then
they showed the process they and then
they took a the thing outside and dug a
hole and buried it and then they planted
a tree on top where they buried it so
it's claimed they could put meat in
there as well yeah this is longer
David's eight-foot feces in there things
I'm not brave enough to do and things
I'm not gonna do for my indoor right if
I had a big huge gigantic outdoor garden
I that would be an end-of-the-world
scenario oh yeah yeah what even dairy
cheese and stuff like that they say you
can do and put eggshells in there - oh
yeah I told us I totally put it there
yeah coffee grounds even paper I mean
it's like coffee filters newspaper stuff
like okay so yeah it just eats that
right up disappears yeah you don't get a
lot of leachate off of it awesome I've
been putting all my cannabis scraps in
them so I've been when you've run them
through if I was to throw like the
leaves and stuff off my plants in the
garden into the open warm bin I would
lose most of the nitrogen and [ __ ] what
else and I would lose carbon through the
co2 that it emits as it dries out and
breaks down okay running them through
the PO Kashi bucket you retain all of
that Wow Oh Kansas permits at first and
it traps it in the plant so then it's
it's healthier food for the worms and it
makes a higher quality product richer
yeah much richer okay that fermentation
is what gives it that amazing smell
yeah that's Victor's been teaching me
about the wonders of bo khosh shoutout
to Victor yeah he knows what he's
talking about
um he we totally get him on the show
when they start victory really I have to
be on the phone okay we can I can I've
got a zoom h6 we'll go to wherever he is
nice if he's in Colorado yeah it's not a
huge where
full of [ __ ] boshy bucket so just go
sit on a bucket we all get a bucket is a
chair when you're a ganja grower this
smells kind of funky sometimes is it a
sickeningly satisfying thing like that
smells terrible I'll take five gallons
of it you know that that's gonna make
like fish hydro slates and like Bo Kashi
juice and remember Nirvana and piranhas
or what was it piranhas and tarantula
from advanced nutrients when they made
the liquids yeah oh those things smelled
like the women's bathroom at the park in
the middle of the summer it was so
terrible they worked you could feed your
plants very little of those things and
your plants would just go ape [ __ ]
I admit it back in the day I used all of
the advanced nutrients product I didn't
know any better that's what I've never
tried I just yeah not to bash anything
but that's one that I would avoid it did
they promise you that you'll get 30
percent heavier yields which it did it
gave me probably 30% fatter yields than
any other brand I've ever used
but all of my different strains looked
smelled and tasted the exact same yep
and they were all about I hypothetically
if all those strains hit 30 percent THC
with my regular regimen they all hit
about 2025 when I used advanced
nutrients but they were heavier you know
a lot more of it it just wasn't and I'd
rather have I'd rather to grow a pound
and a half of super day than two pounds
of me
they are extremely overpriced and I can
tell you that working with them as a
vendor and a company they are [ __ ]
nightmare every hydro shop and I've
tried to mess with has said that because
I would be like hey can you order this
new advanced nutrients product to people
just shake their heads to me like no
I'll take what they send me they send me
boxes of [ __ ] I sell that stuff oh yeah
you're placed in with psycho right yeah
I did a side by I've done a lot of side
by side this show just got off on a
wayside Trek I did not prefer psycho
either psycho gave me a lot of great
colors it gave me bud density and they
gave me weight but I did not approve of
the flavor the flavor was where it was
lacking everything tasted like grape
kool-aid that seems to be how
how all those multi-part lines right if
the bottles look like clear with
different dyes in them it's all probably
in my opinion I don't know this for sure
I should research this they probably all
come from one factory and they just get
poured into different bottles and get
different names put on them yeah
something or something similar I as a
rule of thumb when you're sure this is
just my opinion but as a rule of thumb
when you're shopping for a nutrient line
try to stick with an american-made
nutrient yeah those are by far the best
quality avoid Dutch nutrients of Dutch
growers grow a completely different way
than most Americans and the nutrients
are formulated differently and they
don't really work well with the way most
American growers grow I agree with most
of that I have seen some great results
though with a couple of those Dutch
brands might want mils if you follow
okay no be okay then I can think of
three brands that I would almost buy
their products if it came down to it I
mean housing garden is canna product
play draw a few people that are diehard
yeah we can get that yeah okay you're
right though about I've I've got a note
somewhere that says to talk about Dutch
the Dutch bred cannabis to be a [ __ ]
like because their grow rooms like the
way I see it cannabis happens on a Rocky
Mountain in Afghanistan where a goat
pissed on it the wind beat the [ __ ] out
of it the Sun beat down on it there's a
likelihood that a rock fell on it you
know what I mean on the side of the cush
Mountains in Afghanistan shopping still
super grumpy actually a rabbit lives
under it like it's covered in bugs [ __ ]
goes wrong thank you brain injury guys
sometimes I figure out the [ __ ] I'm
saying so then the Dutch the Dutch got a
hold of these plants like we want to
grow them indoors I have no idea what a
[ __ ] Dutch accent would sound like if
I tried to do it like we want a girlies
indoors they wanted to find the best
[ __ ] they bred it to be these really
skinny sticks that
really perfect buds now it's like roses
like tulips yep that's Dutch is all
about the flower industry yeah exactly
and over here in Colorado California the
states that are catching on we want to
grow dank robust plants we understand
about full plant health we're breeding
for complete plant structure not just
tulips with [ __ ] most of the time I can
pick out a Dutch strain or genetics from
duck or from touch from Amsterdam with I
mean roll a joint and smoke it you know
put two roll three joints put two
American strains in one from Amsterdam
in there and I guarantee I'll be able to
pick out though the whitewashed just
completely blended everything tastes
berries and flowers yeah nobody
structure okay I don't want to go bash
every website but yes I think the Dutch
have got a wheat and you know some
American breeders are probably
susceptible and guilty of it also
probably bred because we wanted to find
back in the day we didn't have a high
pressure sodium lamp or LED we probably
were using whatever finagled lamp we can
put together in the garage to make some
space to try to create a 12 12 flower
cycle out of the few seeds that we did
get from whatever we we got that we
didn't know where it came from but some
dude told us was tie stick but it was
probably from Mexico but we thought it
was cooler to tell our friends it was
Jamaican so your girl in these [ __ ]
maybe tie stick maybe Colombian may be
Jamaican seed there could be males could
be females could be who knows what it is
and they got to figure out how to grow
that so we may have gotten rid of the
good [ __ ] back in the day because we
didn't have the right lights we didn't
have the right knowledge we just wanted
something that finished quick and didn't
climb up into the lights
I grew for three years before I ever saw
a cloned or even made one so you just
did a bunch of seeds yeah why would kill
to have some
yeah oh yeah I thought about how many I
used by Mexican schwag weed back in the
day where I live Mexican schwag Revis
450-500 ollars a pound it was everywhere
and you could get a half ounce of seeds
out of it it looked like good healthy
viable seeds I almost wonder what I
would have gotten from them because you
know those Mexican crops were producing
a low yielding stream remember the lime
green Christmas but yes I grew out some
seats how did that come out it was lime
green Christmas play so it was just I
guarantee that was like to touch
genetics here we go yeah some touch on
Oh flowers there's something like that
yeah it was just it was alright weed you
know ten years ago what a what [ __ ]
head over heels for yeah it's funny that
you call it Christmas but cuz this town
is known for getting the light greens
Christmas Christmas yes that's amazing
now that I know more about growing and
everything that's I guarantee that's
probably oughta flour isolate season yep
but there there's a lot of talk about
the Mexican cartels using auto flour
strains so that they can keep stuff
going year-round and we talked about the
one crop that was busted and the forest
near us that was all Otto flowers knew
yeah that's so yeah that's how they do
that yeah they're there those grows our
cookie cutter there's every single one
of them is the same I mean there are
different locations but the way they
grow I mean that the cops I can tell by
looking at the pictures but also time
even the cops know you know the DEA
there's just a certain like [ __ ]
Willie and his crew were here again so
if you're ever going to bust the pickle
grow that somewhere find out what that
is and grow just like yeah it's a
Mexican food like buying foods in the
Mexican store with no English on the
labels and just store a bunch of it
there cuz I think that's what gives them
the first hint like it's a bunch of what
did they call Mexican nationals is what
they label them as in the paper so yeah
like how do you know that we found
tortillas good job police I used to get
mad when I found seeds of my weed like
good money for kind bud there'd be seeds
in it
come on I just paid like a half a
grandma seeds in here and I'm like what
happened to the seeds that threw out the
window on Phish tour I wish I had those
I uh when I was out in California one
time the first time I was exposed to the
whole medical marijuana scene and
everything kind of changed my life
actually I smoked some OG Kush out there
from my then girlfriends cousin that it
was full of seats and I brought him back
even and just over moved
moving from you know over the years I
lost them so that's yeah you'll find
them when the time is right hopefully no
they're long I just know you guys to
talk about my first experience with
medical marijuana because I just I've
got a cool [ __ ] story I'm not gonna
tell on this but it's another podcast I
just thought about that I saw four K
room it was a line down all [ __ ] now
that I'm a more experienced grower or
like total Cali style [ __ ] flood and
rating table nice cool slabs and
everything that's the way to do it but
the fast crank it just blew my mind it
was like the oh man all these things I
thought about that room then like just
how huge it was and how much money they
must make and all that how much work it
was and now I kind of chuckle but yeah
that's before lights huh okay to leave
the the first big [ __ ] room I ever see
ya know I I try to I remember the first
time they I walked into like a giant
commercial grow I had to like kind of
bite my lip and try to keep my face
Street he's gonna [ __ ] my pants are
getting a boner and now when I walk into
big gross people still try to like the
owner of a girl will walk in and they
Pikachu and they try to read your face
and I just try to keep that straight the
whole time like this is a cute bro when
sometimes I'm like oh my god there's 500
lights in this one room yeah that you
guys don't take it for granted go check
out some cool girls and appreciate it
we're jaded now we've been to too many
people too many hours in in too many
facilities I've been in more facilities
than I care to admit
didn't have the facilities in this great
state all right let's talk a little bit
more about compost you kind of got
sidetracked I want to ask a couple other
questions also but I just want to ask
you what was one a year what's your
favorite [ __ ] to smoke because we're
talking about seeds and I had a strain
in mind that I wanted to ask you about
and I was like I wonder if he'll mention
that so it was a Pueblo favorite what's
when your favorites to smoke I think I
know what you're talking oh you do I'm
sure you do I've got seeds of it yes
yeah was that pee bud the p90 one p90
one that's very pee buds the chem dog
dude yeah yeah I know that I remember
getting that but my favorite stuff to
smoke nowadays is just like oh geez
Yeti's okay okay well the p90 one was
amazing though Jesus yet he's a great
stuff to smoke I bet the p90 one was
related to like the deep chunk sweet
tooth was pitbull and there's bull rider
and the Northern Lights five I think Oh
remember exactly I could google it if
you want it would make the strain I'm
kind of think oh okay bull riders in
Afghani yep and Northern Lights number
five I believe is the indica version and
I could be completely wrong by the
Northern Lights I know it's bull rider
or pit bull which is they're similar and
it's it's from Stoney girl seeds is who
actually put that one out in seed form
in the beginning and then now there's
another company I think it was Gold
Coast genetics maybe who I got the seeds
from I've got a ten pack they charge me
way too much but for the nostalgia I was
like I need that [ __ ] I haven't I've
been real I hold the seeds like they're
precious and I want to pop in at the
right time for sure alright so I'm
expecting company are a good friend
Lindsey the traveling stoner abobo or
coming over
bubble blaster hose birthday was a few
days ago and he got a sweet new rig from
our friends rebel glass that's [ __ ]
dope we're gonna take some grads out of
that we've got some time left I just
wanted to give you a warning let's talk
about composting so that when they cuz I
just told them to show up so they're
gonna walk in eventually we may either
hand them a microphone or we'll wrap it
was gonna be very informal composting
until then sweet so we go ahead
I'm trying to remember where we were at
we've got the worms we've got the
Bokashi we're talking about getting it
in a 40 gallon container
you've got your worms living in
newspaper you got ground traffic phone
books wood chunks bark type stuff I
imagine comfrey come the Bocage you Popo
kashi bucket pulp and that's pretty oh I
threw in some oyster shell got some
malted barley seed okay moister shell
just to get some cal-mag and I was told
by a warm keeping friend that oyster
shell helps poke the worms themselves up
but make them fatter huh yeah make them
eat more and make them work a little
harder yeah okay so and part of my plan
with this big warm container is to
release in my garden in the spring early
summer so that I'm just I'm building up
the soil in my garden year after year
after year yeah if I can dump I mean
[ __ ] ten thousand worms or something
like that I might end up push you don't
even know that'd be amazing it has
turned that soil all day long
yeah yeah you and your dad go fishin
yeah but I know okay fly fisherman okay
purist
you don't want to just go sit there all
day gonna do something yeah no that's
not really my type of fish I understand
so now we've got well we've gotten dope
as compost now yeah what do we do with
that do we want to cut some of that 50%
25% with regular soil let's let's act
like we're gonna put it into a potted
plant to grow either indoors or outdoors
how much of that compost do you want to
use um if you're building a soil from
scratch I would recommend like 30 40
percent okay compost you don't have to
use that much that's just I mean that's
ideal 30 it's available yeah yeah if
you've got that you know you want to top
dress that or do you want to blend it in
when you start if you're building the
soil I would totally recommend blending
it
if you are top dressing I would do want
to say like a quarter cup per gallon
container oh okay so if you got a seven
gallon I would
come in three and a half cups yeah you
did the odd number to yourself I see you
know what I do yeah yeah what'd I tell
the guys at work and if you're
recharging the soil or like reusing a
soil like Jeff does I would probably say
like 20 percent okay five percent maybe
all right maybe even as low as 15 it
kind of depends on how much aeration
your soil has and if you want to add any
end or if or not so okay aeration is
important you guys we learned our lesson
I put some plants into cocoa and I did
not put anything in there to aerate it
and those plants pretty much gave me the
middle finger their whole lives you know
it's super compressed you gotta fill
that up with some perlite put something
in there to kind of air it up for sure
all right
you can also make teas with your compost
yes that's awesome yeah so with compost
make sure you have a consistent
temperature I've been told if you let it
get too warm you can potentially have
some funky stuff okay and your tea or in
the compost itself in your tea okay all
right
a lot of people talk crap about compost
or you'll find people that talk [ __ ]
about it one of the things they claim is
as ecoli in it which it possibly could
have ecoli in it okay but it also has a
million other [ __ ] things that are
way nastier than ecoli that don't harm
us wouldn't a large percentage of your
fruits and vegetables have ecoli anyway
when you purchase them trace amounts at
least they're shipped yeah okay it's so
would that mean maybe not to use a
compost tea as a foliar feed well that's
that's the way to get around that right
just feed it to the roots and not the
foliar yeah I personally would never use
an actual compost tea for foliar either
yeah I would strictly save that for worm
castings okay yeah for sure
all right so that's the way to get
around that you know worry there feed it
to the soil magical happened that you
call it goes away
yeah and also with compost you can make
it concentrate where just take your
compost put it in a cheesecloth
massage it in water or underneath water
for about 10 minutes like you know put
it in a bucket of water just kind of rub
it out a little yeah okay that's
actually what you're doing you rubbing
it out you need it like a loaf of bread
okay yeah all right perverts and then
that makes a compost or worm casting you
can do either one a concentrate and it
has a longer shelf life than an aerated
tea okay Wow yeah that's useful
something I just learned yeah you're
taking old food scraps and recycled dirt
and putting it in cheesecloth and
squeezing it and making your own
nutrients yeah why not do this let's
stop making waste let's stop wasting
[ __ ]
let's stop spending money on companies
that do not really support the cannabis
movement or us or our wallets yeah let's
stop making trucks drive across the
country with bottles of water because
that's you're paying for what when you
buy whatever brand to use I love
Botanica but still every time I buy a
bottle of pure Belen pro where liquid
karma I had to pay a truck to drive that
[ __ ] from Arizona to Colorado then I had
to pay some dude or the hydro shot with
a mullet to [ __ ] sell it to me and
then I had to buy it home and measure it
out I probably could have just taken
some kelp and seabird guano whatever the
[ __ ] else is in that product and I could
have made my own probably even bench
less blue yeah I mean if you wanna grow
salts you could still be good it's kind
of environmentally friendly yes yes what
I'm getting at is I could make that and
I don't have to add to that truck
driving that emissions though water
being shipped the gas the exhaust like
we could do it ourselves and not only
that you're diverting food from going
into the landfill exactly so you're just
you're basically money from going right
into the same landfill yeah yeah put it
back into your crop back in your wallet
you're
using something you're not depending on
someone for that little tiny bit of your
life you know it only may be that part
but I love you know trying to be a
producer not a consumer you know it may
sound a little weird but it there's a
good feeling knowing that my vivacious
healthy green vigorous cannabis plants
are on nearly the same diet as myself oh
for sure it makes me think maybe other
than all this freaking dr. pepper I'm
addicted to maybe I'm green and
vivacious and vigorous as well keeps me
going keeps me strong all right dude
we've been dumped like 40 minutes you
got anything else you want to talk about
composting before we get a doorbell ring
and we get some new stoners showing up
[Music]
yeah you're getting good at podcasting
by the way bro you're really comfortable
now other than being a little cold in
here I'm just I'm trying to build my
schedule I've got a busy life that was
all of a sudden well I don't know I've
always had a busy life but in you know a
few months ago just all of a sudden like
really stepped up that's good um yeah so
it's good but it's bad for my podcast
and I have all these ideals and the you
know just plans and everything I'm just
trying to adjust into my schedule
I understand expect a kick-ass podcast
coming from me besides the Colorado dope
podcast are you gonna new I will come in
yeah excellent so mo go with go ahead
and hit but it's going to be the
high-grade homestead I like that so and
it'll be more than just cannabis growing
so talk about gardening and chickens and
all kinds of [ __ ] stuff you'd find out a
homestead I love it I love it well if
you ever need a cannabis expert on that
show oh yeah I'll come on your show
planned out for you to the rest of the
Colorado podcast boys a little bit also
show it to burn thanks for letting her
husband come hang out for a couple hours
and get I got them stupid hi gonna send
him even higher yes still on the
I haven't really been dabbing diet oh
man well there's another dab weight
tried to be as coherent as possible burn
also takes great care of me when I go to
the hydro shop she's always excited to
see me she gives me a big hug she's
super friendly
great customer service so big shout out
to Bern
thanks for letting me borrow your
husband for an hour to do a podcast I
look forward to hearing the homegrown
homes to high-grade homestead there's a
lot of letters to put in my brain but I
look forward to hearing that I hope my
listeners follow you all not that
podcast nice I'm sure they're gonna
follow you on Instagram it at Jesse
grows they're also gonna check out the
Colorado podcast Instagram page while
they're at it they're gonna go follow me
on Instagram its Irie underscore
genetics dude oh thank you for joining
me on the podcast we even have your two
hours I appreciate that I'm gonna do a
couple of wrap ups make sure you find me
on all the social media guys I'm on
Facebook it's the girl from her podcast
I'm on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
also you know I would love it if you go
to iTunes that leave me a rating and a
review I'm sure you know how to find the
ratings and reviews by now everybody so
far has given me a five star review you
know it'd be cool if you follow suit but
if you feel like you want to be
different do what you need to do also
let me remind you about a new service
I've signed up for it is called patreon
patreon is a service that will allow my
listeners to make a financial
contribution to the show if they feel so
inclined if you feel like the
information or knowledge or friendship I
have provided you or just you want throw
some money around go to
patreon.com/scishow beat as little as $1
I honestly don't think there's a limit
to the amount of zeroes you can add to
that yeah so however many zeroes you
want to add to that dollar sign go ahead
put a 5 put a 9 in front of there
however you want to do it no I would
appreciate though if you sign up for
patreon you can contribute $1 to the
show it will charge you every the first
of every month and then that will send
that right over to my PayPal account and
honestly I'm not trying to make a bunch
of money off my friends and my listeners
what that will do that will help me pay
for the cost of my website you guys I
read genetics Colorado com
cost me about three hundred and fifteen
dollars per year to keep up there and
that is how I deliver you this podcast
I'm not trying to get rich I'm just
trying to
set that I'm not trying to pay for that
out of my pocket ah not begging either
so if you would like to go to patreon go
check it out patreon.com slash grow from
your heart I would really appreciate it
yeah Jesse says do it and he's a big guy
so did it even yeah Jesse did do it
Jesse was my second contributor to
patreon that's where I was headed next
big shout-out to all three of the people
who have contributed to my patreon so
far I appreciate all three of you I'm
not sure if everybody wants to be listed
by name so you know who you are big
shout out much love much respect I
appreciate the support even if you can't
contribute to patreon you guys I love
you and I appreciate you just for
listening to the podcast you'll have to
give me money you don't have to give me
anything to be my friend I love you guys
I appreciate you being there and
supporting the podcast I extra
especially to support thank you for
supporting cannabis you guys I had a lot
of caffeine and abs my brain is going
too fast but I appreciate you for
supporting cannabis and like I said
earlier I completely trust you or thank
you for trusting me to be your cannabis
and guru it means a lot to me it sounds
like I need to wrap up the show because
my tongue is tying itself in a damn knot
so I think all I have to say now is a
big shout-out to my friend the Barefoot
grower and it's all next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
she came to my high school she caused
quite a stir all the kids at big-time
high wanted to be just like her make
lots of money tell you
[Music]
if you used to teach at my high school
he caught quiet
[Music]
they were the topic that made erupto
great went to the future to take the
songs and I said it's not too late when
we asked them about their car
[Music]
you