welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 171 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
it's right here a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated Danner if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots bed for
letting me use their music on my podcast
big shout out to cat food in the entire
mystic roots crew yeah
please and gentlemen across the table
from me a repeat offender returning
champion ladies and gentlemen white Mike
is back thank you joining me bro yeah
man if you guys want to stock white Mike
while you're listening to him make sure
you follow him on Twitter it's at Nemo
punk 15 also remind everybody how they
can check out your Facebook group its
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook folks Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook Mike I'm gonna
turn your microphone up there's no
reason maybe getting a head cold some
sounds a little monthly I apologize
listeners if it's monthly I hope it's
just mine in your head or is it in the
gear yeah because the music sounds good
but my voice sounds stupid so it's just
it's just my head I apologize for that
folks I'm gonna get over it we're gonna
do a podcast thanks for joining me dude
yeah make sure you guys support Mike on
the Twitter and follow Pablo for
sensible cannabis laws check out what
he's posting there on Facebook we truly
appreciate the cannabis advocates dude
did you hear granny give you a shout-out
I did I did I appreciate that granny
it's uh it was fun meeting you the one
time we got to meet the Kanak Union and
I can't wait til we run into each other
again I will get you guys here together
on this podcast it'll be a good time
right I'll do my best I was good too man
she will get you high as giraffe puss no
grannies awesome does the basket of
magic the basket yes granny and her
basket of magic granny got to meet
Action Bronson the other day
as I've ever seen Debbie Murphy in
Action Bronson so shout out to davon
granny also since we're doing shoutouts
I need to give a huge shout out to my
friends at handmade apparel it's right
if you guys need any sort of t-shirt
printing some stickers some hat pins you
guys I fully endorse and support my
friends at handmade apparel check out
handmade apparel dot biz or check them
out on Facebook there is a Facebook
group and a Facebook page you guys they
printed me some grow from your heart
podcast hoodies they've printed my IRA
genetics t-shirts I have got a bright
red handmade apparel hoodie I've got a
green handmade apparel hoodie
I've got hat pins I've got stickers that
these folks made and everything is
top-quality it's made in America by
Americans it's made by dab kids who take
dads they dab just as hard as you and I
do so I think it's great to support the
community I think it's great to support
our friends that are doing this with us
I really like these people they're good
friends of mine and they make great [ __ ]
so please support them as much as I do
handmade for all your printing needs and
get that sweet handmade apparel logo on
the side of your shirt like I've got we
could all be in the same handmade gang
that's pretty awesome
big shadows of the handmade true ladies
and gentlemen go to handmade apparel dot
biz and check them out it's stuff
printed I'm a big fan of the quality I
typically shirts that are printed with
logos and stuff the logo goes first I've
did all of my handmade stuff the shirt
is going a little before the logo the
logo still looks fresh you know I wear
if you know me I'm kind of a cartoon
characters what they call me I've got a
hoodie diary genetics logo and I take
off my hoodie and underneath that is a
hurry genetics t-shirt I've been wearing
probably I have not thrown any of them
away I've been rocking these t-shirts
for probably five years now and from the
first one I have not thrown it away the
logo is still crispy the shirt however
is getting it's getting that black shirt
Dinge to it but the logo looks like it
was freshly painted it can only hold up
for so long I mean I beat the living
hell out of mine and the logo still
looks fresh
they're sweet shirts so I think we've
given them a huge shout out big thanks
to my friends at handmade apparel for
all the stuff they've printed you guys
they have the best rates for hat pins if
you're getting your hat pins made go
through handmade apparel I went through
I tried a lot of companies handmade
apparel was the most reliable they do
the art work in-house and they have the
Pens made so it's all one
one group so you don't have to have
different people working together and
[ __ ] you up they do great artwork I
love those guys so shadow much respect
big hugs all that stuff to our friends
at handmade apparel make sure you check
them out how many apparel biz I think
I've said that enough times well if you
want to chatter about before we get into
our main topic my car do you want to
jump into feels like so much this
happens I was on here let's go to yeah
let's start off with the letter from the
DEA that came out just a couple of days
ago and then we will do if we have time
for it we will do a couple of election
updates because I know you love get into
that listeners have asked for longer
lessons that was me clapping I don't
class yeah listeners a lot of listeners
are like hey bro I want a longer episode
you guys I've taken on a new project I
don't talk a lot about this project that
I'm doing I've kind of kept it on the
down-low
but it keeps me busy for 45 or 50 hours
a week so I haven't been doing too
podcast episodes I apologize I'm gonna
do my best to get longer episodes and I
know that the past couple episodes have
been a little not as informative I was
over [ __ ] well and you guys it's the
holiday season super busy yeah yeah I've
got a kiddo I've got friends I'm doing a
new project I was hanging off my mom
earlier today for quite some time
talking about Christmas presents and
stuff and don't feel guilty you just
wrapped a killer outdoor Grove session
again yeah that's true big shot it to
Jesse for coming and helping us do some
outdoor grow lessons so I'm sure that
series every year I feel like I got a
pack so much info into every single
episode those are when I don't give a
full informative episode I feel like I'm
kind of cheating myself and the
listeners right there are episodes where
I've had to stop and pause repeatedly
while I take notes
they're so hyper detail that's fantastic
I've got and I know I keep saying I've
got those podcasts in the works the ones
we're gonna have I've got the folder
right here my hand you can hear this
this is all this page gets more
impressive every week yeah I'm gonna do
those I'm just I'm trying to perfect
them those are episodes that are gonna
be in-depth and I'm kind of a
perfectionist so when they come out like
that they're really good but on this
episode we're gonna talk about like I
pulled that background I've been
podcasting a while in this podcast we're
gonna talk about a letter that the DEA
sent who the hell did they send it to do
they just publish it or was it actually
mailed to people this was the big dust
of this
the the letter clatter that everyone
freaked out about over CBD did your face
just break this story almost broke me
the big dust-up is basically saying the
DEA just made CBD illegally game and
that's silly because it was never legal
right we're gonna get to that let me
read this and then we're definitely
gonna talk about why it's silly and
we'll talk about a lot of details there
are a lot of different versions of this
article the main part that I want to
focus on is a quote the store is a great
example of just how fake news can be
right look there are different degrees
of [ __ ] they can work their way into
a press story I've read it in three or
four different locations and the part I
want to focus on is mainly quoted from
the DEA themselves so that can't be
wrong and then the the buffers around it
we can talk [ __ ] about a blot on every
website so this one I chose the one the
Leafly article looked like a crock of
[ __ ] to me I didn't like the Leafly
article so I chose to go with the
article from the Green Rush daily I
shout out to the Green Rush daily the
headline is the DEA just banned CBD and
here's why and then there's a giant ad
and then I finally scroll like seven
Scrolls and I get to the article it says
the legality of CBD is no longer in the
gray area in fact the DEA just banned
CBD cementing its place in the list of
schedule 1 substances CBD or cannabidiol
is a compound or cannabinoid in cannabis
that won't get you high what it does do
though is stop seizures and aid in
suffering from dilib delipcious I'm the
one that wanted to talk [ __ ] about an
article and I can't speak English words
debilitating is the word I was trying to
say I nailed cannabinoid and can a video
but I can't say debilitating you guys
see the question how full especially on
a phone yeah especially after all those
dabs that the dabs never help with
reading aloud that's true um I I may be
the exception to that rule I'm an
introvert and then sometimes when I
smoke a lot oh yeah yeah okay so we'll
keep going this is so why is the DEA
putting it on why is the DEA putting it
on the list of the most harmful drugs
available to man
probably the same reasons they
temporarily banned the herbal pain
reliever trade on earlier
here they're both alternatives to more
dangerous prescription opiates that are
plaguing the country
the DEA action seemed to protect Big
Pharma's pockets more than the health of
American citizens that's not the point
that I wanted to get to there talking
about it was they were doing so well and
then they went off into [ __ ] lands
yes yes well just just that quick it was
somewhere I wanted to venture into later
in the episode I didn't jump right into
it into the target Ville because I think
that maybe have something to do with it
they see that if there are
pharmaceutical companies working with it
they don't want us having that market
they want a corner that before we do so
there you're just gonna shut us down
like oh no you can't even play so now we
win they just landed on free parking by
[ __ ] us but I want to keep going the
archaic spelling of the word marijuana
with an H is used in the text in federal
and the Federal Register announcing the
rule probably to avoid turning up in
marijuana related search results oh wow
is that true they think that no it's
just how the [ __ ] feds spell it you
[ __ ] conspiracy refresh daily I was
like ah [ __ ]
and then you said at the top and I went
I should have liked me cuz yeah and I
knew this was going okay I think this
will be helpful for our listeners yep
because I'll spawn women age
yeah it's that's just how the feds spell
marijuana the and this is where what a
lot of the fake news is oriented around
basically everybody has heard of CBD by
now coast to coast the is CBDs a
household term now people have seen
through sanjay gupta's specials and
through YouTube videos and Facebook
posts how helpful it can be with
Parkinson's with seizure disorders with
deface syndrome with pain management
with the change in federal policy with
the Ogden memo and the Cole memo that
led to marijuana markets like we have
here in Colorado where they're legal
some of those like Colorado's included
legal hemp and so last year the year
before the Fed
just like the : Ogden memos did for high
THC cannabis they put out a little blurb
in the farm bill covering industrial
hemp and putting a definition for what
industrial hemp is and so under the
guise of that legal loophole a number of
companies both domestic and foreign
started selling TVs or CBD extract
online in all 50 states making it
available pretty much everywhere
companies like CBD life water have
sprung up that are trying to get
distribution in all 50 states and it's
under a gray market loophole created by
the farm bill it is in no way legal the
feds have always considered every part
of the cannabis plant it doesn't matter
if it's sativa indica have ruderalis
they don't give a [ __ ] it let me jump in
right there because that's right or am
in this article and they spell it
marijuana with an H why because these
laws are based in [ __ ] racism and
that was a lot of where that the
original basis for these comes from so
when the feds write a new marijuana law
it's on the backs of all the old
marijuana laws and they keep the same
racist ass smelling alright look like I
know well let me finish the article
you're fired up and I like it but I have
to get through this article to make the
show show it says the reason given that
the US is complying with the
international drug control treaties wait
the reason giving is that the OKs is
that they are so the deploy a stated
reason for the the change this week is
to help them comply with international
narcotics trees then they say before
this elaboration CBDs legality was in a
gray area it was assumed that CBD
extracted from medical cannabis was only
legal for medical marijuana patients any
illegal to the rest however CBD derived
from industrial hemp was being sold
across the country as if it were
federally federally legal well
apparently the DEA has always believed
any form of cannabis extract to be
Schedule one okay
if I handed you a CBD molecule a
scientist to CBD molecule and I said did
this come from hemp or cannabis he'd
probably tell me to go [ __ ] myself cuz
it's the same thing he would say it's a
molecule so the DEA claims if there are
small
of cannabinoids in every CBD extract
they cite this as another reason to keep
CBD on schedule one for practical
purposes all extracts that contains CBD
will also contain at least small amounts
of other cannabinoids however if it were
possible to produce the form of cannabis
plant I'm sorry they wrote this weirder
there's an ad right here I'm skipping
through it let's see produce from the
cannabis plant extract they contain only
CBD and no other cannabinoids such an
extract would fall within the new drug
code so basically the DEA made
extracting CBD completely illegal
whether it's from hemp or not whether it
is pure CBD cuz they are wrong right
there when they say that you can't get
pure CBD because I know I'm thinking
counting I can put five fingers up and
confidently say that I know five people
that I could call friends that can make
CBD isolate that is ninety-nine point
eight or nine percent CBD that one or
two percent is atmospheric conditions
there are things like oxygen in there
that they cannot control yeah it's you
can get a hundred percent pure CBD lots
of different places the the DEA is
position on it doesn't have anything to
do with their being trace cannabinoids
in it that's just something they happen
to mumble during the press conference so
it's always been but have you always
been illegal just like every part of the
cannabis plant is illegal federally the
seeds are illegal though the leaves are
illegal the root ball is illegal the pot
you grew it it is illegal it doesn't
matter if it's industrial hemp every
year I'm just to be safe every eighteen
months
some Drug Task Force somewhere like East
[ __ ] Texas makes the announcement
that they've just found the world's
biggest pot farm and they're raiding it
today and they they didn't catch any
growers and it's headline news on Monday
in its headline news on Tuesday and then
there's nothing about it in the press on
Wednesday and next Friday comes out that
it was a wild Hempfield
on some farmers back it's 400 or 400
acres in the middle of nowhere and it
was the weather conditions that spring
were perfect for feral hemp to go nuts
and the DEA will spend $100,000 ripping
all of that feral hemp out of the ground
and burning it because it's the
dangerous marijuana plant it doesn't
matter that it's growing wild it doesn't
have any tea if you smoked any of that
stuff if you harvested dried and cured
it properly all that [ __ ] would do is
give you a headache there's an Indian
Reservation I want to say it was in New
Mexico somewhere hot and kind of
miserable to live where feral hemp was
just everywhere they couldn't do
anything about it it was an issue and
they'd found a way to basically build
whole houses with it with hemp creed and
a couple of other products and they were
doing it all on site and the feds would
show up every now and again and burn
their hemp down because it's dangerous
hemp I mean this happens all over the
country the DEA wastes small fortunes
ripping wild hemp plants out of the
ground that are left over from the 30s
and 40s when hemp was grown as a crop
all over the US when there's a terrible
heroin epidemic everywhere right now
like Colorado Springs is littered with
crystal meth meth is everywhere in
Springs people are driving around on
bicycles looking at [ __ ] trash cans
all over Colorado Springs Pueblo it
Pueblo is dead it's Friday night right
now you guys it's Friday night at 10:30
it's [ __ ] quiet all the people that
used to be out raging doing heroin not
all but I mean a good [ __ ] portion of
our young people are out doing heroin
right now and the DEA is worried about
[ __ ] with plants that keep us cool I
mean not even cannabis fun cannabis that
gets you stoned and it they're hemp
just stuff you make jeans with houses
bricks
textiles necklaces right there's an
infinite number of products you can make
with with hemp and that was part of the
the reason they they included the
exemption in the farm bill last year the
year before to to designate what exactly
is industrial hemp because everybody I
mean everybody everybody understands how
absurd our hemp laws are but as far as
law enforcement is concerned cops can't
tell the difference between hemp and
weed and they're pretty sure you can
grow the two next to each other so you
could heart hide your high THC plants
your hemp plants which anyone that's
ever growing either crop knows how
insane that is but law enforcement
across the country still argue [ __ ] like
that in federal court well to keep the
DEA noted since all surgeons like this
Ansel is growing a bunch of it's all CBD
plants and it looks like killer cannabis
plants if they told me that that was
White Widow or something I honestly
couldn't tell the difference on their
plants they have got can't very cannabis
looking some of them can be very very
similar it depends what the hemp you're
growing has been bred to do yeah yeah
and if I understand what son Saul is
doing is they're producing CBD extract
it looks like it grows just like phyllo
and that's that's the type of hemp you
would want for a high CBD extra
production but that I'm guessing that
amp strain would be crap if they tried
to make fuel oil and fiber it's not
fibrous um I mean that's one of the
great things about cannabis is it can be
bred one way or the other to achieve an
infinite number absolutely of final
products but as far as the feds are
concerned every single part of its
illegal the only legal hemp or marijuana
products that are federally legal in the
United States are hemp clothing produced
in other countries are produced from
fabric that was grown in other countries
and silly loans and hemp seed oil oh she
and I mean products that were produced
with plant material grown in other
countries everything else is at least
gray market the FDA and a couple other
national safety organizations release
the thing we even did a blurb about it
on the show about the foreign companies
selling god knows what is CBD extract is
usually erotic random [ __ ] in there yep
they were testing it and it didn't have
a lot of CBD in it or maybe it did but
it had a lot of crap in it you didn't
want us along with it is filler that's
what you get in a gray market you get a
lot of knockoff products you get a lot
of mislabeled products and this is why
I've been freaking out about getting
people politically active disease just
doing this for their own financial gain
do you think the pharmaceutical
companies are
planning something with CBD products um
there's a couple in Great Britain and
around the country that are already
working with THC CBD products GW
Pharmaceuticals is working a couple of
different product lines but there's
still five ten years from market okay
I'm sure the binnacle industry don't
that don't want THC and see like they
would prefer to I as an industry I'm
sure they would prefer to have control
of all medications that people carried
yeah but that's not physically possible
they don't want to make it better they
want to mask my symptoms and keep
feeding me a pill to make me a customer
and greed is like the one conspiracy
theory you're gonna get me to buy into
anywhere but with a decision like this
this is just business as usual this is
the exact same I mean this has been true
since nineteen forty and people are
freaking out about this decision today
because they issued it it's a own serial
number so they can track the caesars
separately and I mean I encourage the
move because tracking [ __ ] separately is
helpful right now any anti marijuana
group is going to tell you that ten
years ago fifteen years ago the average
THC content in marijuana was one to
three percent and they can back that up
with DEA seizure numbers and the reason
that's true is because they've been
seizing fields of [ __ ] barrel hemp
every year for decades and I mean it's
always been illegal this is nothing new
tracking it separately helps us figure
out okay exactly how much did they waste
ripping up half out of the ground how
much money did they waste making sure
Kansas didn't get their hemp seed last
year how much money did they waste
rounding up hemp seed off the inner or
hemp oil off the internet off the side
of the highways you drive to New Mexico
I mean it's nuts there how many people
since they've got these companies that
are shipping CBD
they're gonna have to like the people
there's a company I don't I don't know
if I want to say anybody's names I don't
get any people in trouble but I know
people personally and there are
companies in
Colorado that will ship CBD products
nationwide you can be in Maine name in
California and they will send you a
bottle of CBD t-shirt uh how are those
people that were relying on those
medicine what are they gonna do now
that's who I'm mainly worried about
they're screwed yeah but they were
always like their access was only
obtained through a gray market and if
they were paying attention they knew
that and they've been lobbying for a
different way to access whatever product
they desperately need in their area I
would love to say come to Colorado and
we've got CBD for you but there is a CBD
drought yep the only way like everybody
thinks they're gonna come to Colorado
and go to a medical dispensary and get
Heidi CBD medicine and they are highly
disappointed there is not much yours is
expensive because it's it's there's a
shortage and there's been a shortage for
a while you've got to find yourself a
private caregiver
who they're trying to squeeze out of the
system now anyway or you've got a girl
yourself and then you've got to find a
CBD clone or you got to find seeds or
something high CBD and then you've got
to grow it and you've got to get it
tested or I don't know people focus a
little bit too much on testing when it
comes to personal medicine I think I'm
gonna do an episode on this I'm gonna
write this down I think that the
medicine I think if medicine works for
you it works for you don't pay attention
to the lab testing there's a lot of
elaboration I want to do on that but
we'll save it for another there's a lot
of stuff that lab testing brought to the
community that's just bizarre um people
focus on all the wrong numbers and
that's I mean I loved watching the CBD
industry explode over the last two years
I don't take that from what I'm saying
because I think that should be available
to everyone everywhere I think this
society would be a lot better if more
people were adding CBD to their diets
regularly as a supplement it helps with
a bunch of stuff I'm a huge CBD advocate
I use it daily what's your daily dose of
CBD right now I'm restricting myself
because the product I'm using I'm
limited on accessing any more of it ever
won't happen it's gone the person that's
making it is gone and so I'm kind of
making it lasts always the worst part
about the products yep and right now I'm
at two or three CBD dad's a day okay um
and I spaced them throughout the day and
it depends if I'm not hurting that day
maybe I only take one maybe I'll take
just a little itty-bitty one maybe I'll
just use some of the pain cream I've got
left and started but that's on purpose
I'm purposefully going slow before then
or like when I was taking it is
milligram pills it was 50 milligrams a
day you take 25 in morning 25 at night I
was my next question okay 25 so 25 to
keep you pain-free a day 25 to get you
sleeping through the night well just
making it easy cuz I never kind of went
wild with it because I liked it half and
half THC CBD and I didn't want to be
eating 50 milligrams of THC before like
I went out and did my day so I was
keeping it 225 and then adding more
during the day if I needed to okay but I
can consume human huge amounts of CBD
when I'm hurting like I've got an issue
with two of the vertebrae in my back and
it doesn't happen often but every now
and then they twang off each other kind
of like a rubber band and that feeling
is pretty excruciating and then the area
around where those two twang will get
inflamed and hurt for several days and
to a degree where I can't really bend
her work and if I feel its twang and I
eat a whole bunch of CBD likes cuz 300
milligrams right away it won't inflame
to the point where I'm down the next day
that's I was yeah I've heard a lot about
if you get on it as soon as you feel it
yep like as soon as you feel it get that
like get that CBD edible in you and if
you can take a dab because dab is it's
instant absorption yeah dab is instant
not just dabbing but any inhalation
through the lungs that that makes it to
the bloodstream incredibly quickly
you'll get relief in seconds yep it's
it's seconds and if you eat it you're
looking at I mean half hour
hour and a half two hours before you
you've got full effect to what you've
consumed the effect of what you eat is
gonna be a little stronger but that
delayed if you're taking it for pain you
can't wait two hours for your pain
totally kick in right but CBD was never
legal in all 50 states like you just
called that back like a professional
Khadijah
it was a loophole that everybody was
operating under and I mean it was so
glaringly obvious a loophole that
Chinese companies know fall over it and
obviously that was gonna get shut down
at some point and that's not even what
this was this was this was just the DEA
assigning its own serial number for when
they do seizures they didn't even
release a letter saying we're gonna go
after the people selling this [ __ ]
online it's just a reminder that all
parts of the cannabis plant are illegal
most of our community is still not
politically aware let alone radically
active but that's what we're here for
that's why I bring you on Mike because
you can remind them you can try to huge
I mean huge segments of the population
not just the marijuana community got
this story wrong I'm freaked out about
it and they're tying it to every
conspiracy theory there is against
marijuana legalization like I read a
whole on a fairly reputable news site it
was an opinion piece that they chose to
publish about because they used the
marijuana with an H spelling in this
that it was that was because Trump was
elected in racism is now openly accepted
and that this was a medication or the
DEA was gonna round up the stoners and
the Mexicans and this was published in a
pen and I'm reading this like okay Jesus
like we've come so far we've just had a
huge night on election night marijuana
won big in so many places in the first
thing we do to celebrate is give
ourselves a black eye and then another
in another in another in another
another and we didn't need a fake news
shitstorm this week there's enough real
news that we should be focused on and
because so much of our community isn't
aware of the legalities nationally for
this plan we all love this stories
spread like wildfire I've seen half a
dozen businesses down here post it and
it's like you're a marijuana store you
should have known this better than I
right yeah yeah the businesses the CBD
businesses that we're sending this [ __ ]
through the mail their lawyers should
have made this perfectly clear to them
that they're operating in a legal gray
area through a loophole in a [ __ ]
farm bill I mean that as far as the feds
are concerned all parts of the cannabis
plant are illegal regardless of THC
content it can be just the root ball of
a hemp plant that dried up or the most
harvested two years ago and it's still
illegal you can still be charged for the
federal crime for having it wow that's
scary yep and that's that's just the
reality of our situation that's why I
have so much respect for even though the
marijuana business owners I really hate
because they're standing up and risking
a lot for us for everybody yep shoutout
to everyone in the marijuana industry
working hard every day getting it going
alright so we've talked a lot about this
DEA letter it's been a long so I hope
that clears that up and calms you down
ideas send your yes and all the positive
stuff can grow from your heart at
hotmail.com alright so thanks for
listening to the DEA part we're gonna
move on to a little bit of updating
stuff of things we've talked about in
the past because um on our post-election
episode we mentioned that a a it was the
little bit of bad news we had for for
Pueblo for our election night there was
a election question should we allow
retail marijuana stores inside Pueblo
city what's it called on the ballot
what's that initial
is that an initiative is that what I
voted on what's the thing I voted on
initiative amendment there I think I
remember which one the question is how I
tend to defer to it we thought it did
not pass on Allah when we recorded our
post-election show it was it was failing
by like 150 or 200 votes and by the time
they got all of the provisional ballots
counted and all the ballots that were
stuck together and what not counted we
won by like 5 or 600 votes nice so we
will be able to have recreational
cannabis stores within the city limits
of Pueblo um December 27th I believe the
City Council is the Tuesday after
Christmas city council will be voting on
the final rules and regs package for Rex
Rex shops I have learned a good mood
after their Christmas break
unfortunately I've been involved with
this for a long time so I know way more
about it than I should even the people
that are working on it right now I
probably know more about it than they do
the ordinance that they're about to vote
and probably pass on passed into law was
written by a Zoning Commission that was
very dead set against allowing marijuana
businesses in the city at all and in a
certain point they discovered that with
one or two zoning buffer rules so 1,000
feet from schools and 300 feet from
residences that they could essentially
limit the number of marijuana businesses
in the city to about a dozen because
that's all the property that's
physically available it makes sense yeah
if they they include those two buffer
zones and to make that even more
restrictive they've decided to limit the
total number of stores in the city to
eight for north of the river for south
of the river they've the city is
preparing for a wave of applications and
they've come up with a point system in a
timeline for that application process to
take place so hopefully by the end of
the year we've got at least a couple of
reach
marijuana shops open in puebla that'd be
cool
yeah I I wish the the rules were that
we're about to pass are different or
we're different are different but that's
very unlikely I'm doing what I can to
get some of the craziness tweet taken
out of them but there's only so much
changed at their wound to make right now
they're catching on they're kind of
slowly evolving so this is a very
different City Council than the one we
had a year or two years ago I mean this
is a full process that started four
years ago it's been four full years that
the city has been working on this
particular set of rules and regs that's
how long I've been working on it do you
think since we had the first shop do you
think we could get just first in line
like hey yeah nope believe me back come
on just play that card okay we was here
most of that part of the city is blacked
out due to schools because the
thousand-foot from schools rule isn't
just classrooms where their students if
the college owns an empty apartment on
whatever street then there's a thousand
foot buffer around that apartment around
that empty apartments property line yeah
yeah does the library in such count not
for not for these this rule package
tends not to matter um there were
several other buffer zones listed around
our medical shops which is why they've
been allowed with no store cap for four
or five years and we only have three
I'm rezoning rules you can really limit
the allowed businesses in an area and
this is why if your area passed
legalization recently you really need to
brush up on local politics and get down
to planning and zoning in City Council
or County Commission meetings now
because these rules are being decided
for your area right now
I mean if you're not involved people who
do give a [ __ ] enough to show up it's
their voice that helps craft these rules
and if it's two people that really hate
weed for one reason or another in one
person that loves weed but is really an
articulate expect ugly rules yeah if you
know how to grow and you were all about
talking with City Council go down there
represent them tell them why they're
there guidelines aren't gonna work for a
typical girl yep
you know I was thinking about I think uh
I cannot recall buying cannabis in a
Pueblo dispensary since the legalization
of recreational cannabis that's the last
time I can remember shopping in a Pueblo
dispensary I rarely shop in a store but
I'm not sure to get out to the stores as
often as possible just to see what
everybody's doing but as far as supply
goes well I know your caregiver he does
a good job this casting a shatter is yes
yes and also our good friends at elevate
glass and and so uh that was the good
Pueblo news that we screwed up on
election night that was our big blooper
from that show yes the next thing I've
got written down you can see it it says
Maine if you want to tell us about Maine
go for Maine Maine voted to legalize
recreational marijuana the vote passed
by a very very very very slim margin
like statewide it was like fifteen
hundred twelve hundred votes or
something it was very very close
so the anti-pop people forced a recount
costing the state half a million bucks
that recount is underway now it's paused
for the weekend they've counted all of
the cities in county areas that the
anti-pop people were sure we're gonna
give them the numbers to reverse the
vote and the the outcome hasn't changed
legalization is still winning
and the really funny part of the story
to me is uh so in Maine the election
rules if you push for a recount and you
get it the pro side and the anti side
for whatever issues getting recounted
have to send ten volunteers every day to
the recount
office like you know it still cost the
state half a million dollars to do this
even with using volunteers from the
campaigns and the anti-pop people in
Maine can't get ten people to show up
every day and so the the recounts taken
a lot longer than it should have
election staffers have had to stand in
and cover for anti legalization
volunteers that weren't able to make it
on time or were late several days a
couple days in a row when this first
started and it just happened again here
at the end of the week they didn't have
enough people show luckily the pro pot
people have had extra volunteers willing
to work and have been willing to work
some longer hours to make sure that this
gets recounted correctly correctly and
accurately so that the recount is still
on tractive to finish up when it's
supposed to
but the anti pot people were so
convinced that they had this in the bag
I'm so convinced that they had the
majority of people that they forced the
recount in a million 1/2 million in
taxes to be spent they can't even get
ten volunteers that's funny come on now
how many how many things are still being
recounted nationwide um total election
why there's a bunch but it's all little
stuff okay it's statewide issues there
well there aren't that many that are
still accounts for full weeks right
since the election recounting is a huge
process because it's done by hand and
basically so in Maine the ten people
from each side pair up and then they're
given an election an election person and
then those three people go sit at the
table and you look at the ballot in both
of the the Pro and the anti people agree
that that's a yes vote and the third guy
they're from the Election Commission is
there to make sure that the to the anti
and the pro people don't fight nice and
follow the rules yeah I mean I mean this
prayer it takes an insane amount of time
on election night they're just funneling
these [ __ ] throwing machine and you
can do thousands a minute or thousands a
second unless you're pueblos crash your
[ __ ] shitty service
but the recount is an incredibly taxing
process but there aren't that many that
are still going I'm typically by now one
side is gone okay the vote clearly
hasn't changed we're down to just the
tiny towns or the areas that voted
strongly one way or the other it's not
gonna matter let's let's let it go and
they've conceded at this point the anti
pot thing or the anti pot group in Maine
is one of the few holdouts that are
still fighting they don't have a chance
um so what this means if you happen to
listen to the podcast and you live in
Maine Way first shout out for listening
we appreciate it I'm second get involved
locally cuz in a couple of weeks when
all this is said and done and it's
official and marijuana is legal um at
best you're gonna be talking to local
government officials who will be saying
over and over and over again well the
vote was really close so we hear what
both sides are saying we're gonna give
the anti pot people nine out of the ten
things they want and we're gonna give
the pro marijuana people 1 out of the 10
things they want because it was a close
vote and if you don't get on top of it
now and figure out exactly how these
rules get made in your area I mean
you're gonna be driving a really long
distance to the only dispensary in your
area and it's gonna be crazy expensive
to buy weed though if it's mean it won't
be that far then it's still cold I
honestly have no idea exactly how big
that state is but I don't want to drive
45 minutes to the weed store no I don't
want to drive 20 minutes to it doesn't
mean you gotta drive 45 minutes home
before you can smoke that new weed yep
and if there's I mean you just give me a
nostalgic feeling remember one needs to
go to the dispensary I don't have it now
I'm sorry I'm jaded but I remember the
feeling I just took a fat debut guys I
apologize for the chokes while Mike was
on his rant there I took a couple dabs
remember you just go to the dispensary
and you'd be like oh you want one here I
got you man I've got the hash if you've
got a dad to love the carp cap yeah you
just done don't use that email because
it's kind of Chloe's dit to be quiet and
I use a torch all right there's a dab
there's a dabber there's torch and
here's rigged with a bucket
yes stranded to our friends at elevate
for keeping me stocked up on fresh
bangers remember that feeling when he
would go to the lake I would I would do
Rob kind of a nerd I would do research
online and find out what the hottest
strains are in Denver or in Colorado and
I would go find that if it was a Bruce
Banner I'd go find where they had some
Bruce Banner what was the strain that
they had at the Denver relief they had
the biodiesel I don't know if they're
got the biodiesel the vortex that's not
from TGA sub cool I was going to the
clinic on Mexico in Denver and I was
getting the vortex wax and I would say
how much do you have of that and they'd
say this much and I'd say I'll take it
yeah they started setting limits because
it means any purchase but I remember the
first week they put those purchase
limits in place the girls screwed up
when we were there and we still bought
it all yeah thanks Brittany yeah we do
that was actually when I bought my
hitman rig but uh so I remember the
feeling I would get when I was leaving e
to spin through with that specific
strain that I was so excited about going
to find it's like like skip it's like
almost the feeling was a little kidding
I'd get a new video game whenever the
new Zelda or Super Mario came out and
I'm like oh I got it I gotta go home and
show my friends and you'd go home and
call one of your buddies and this is the
same thing would happen with weed he'd
go home and call your friends like bro
Mike you gotta come over like got some
biodiesel bro you gotta come check it
out and you'd drive over and I'd try to
keep that Jar Jar closed until you got
here so that when I cracked it open it
was just [ __ ] Oh
biodiesel in the face and then we grind
a little bit of it up and smoke it
together to be like that anticipation
from the car to the house of like oh god
just mike meet me at the house don't
even make me wait bro I missed the drive
home from picking up weed for sure hmm
when that was like an hour 20 minute
drive that was stressful like by the
time you got home that adrenaline high
you're not allowed to take more Dan's on
the show
was a good one but that adrenaline high
from driving home with a bag of weed and
then sitting down the sweet reward it's
like I finally made it and it was like
you I felt like I almost it was more of
a reward I used to get higher than like
cuz you had that like oh I [ __ ] did it
I went because it used to be a struggle
it used to be a mission a STONER mission
you'd have to find do you have weed
there'd be two or three guys would be
that first guy you'd always want to try
and he was my friend with bad eyes and
his name started with a a if your if
your my Korean hoped I might hit that
guy first all the time see if he's got
that Sour Diesel if not and try a couple
other dudes but if you got to find out
where they are if they got what you want
and if they can meet you somewhere then
you got to meet up somewhere and you got
to sit in a sketchy parking lot or go to
a sketchy house and then you got to get
it I always had three or four people and
on my way to work I would head up my
favorite and my lunch if I ain't heard
back I would head up the other two yep
there you go by the end of the day
guaranteed one of them would have hit me
back and then I'd go way too sketchy
parking lot yep I don't miss those days
I kind of Miss that extra high from the
adrenaline and Drive and the
anticipation but I feel it every time
that I do hit a dispensary now or even
when I come over and pick up for my
caregiver when I get back in the car
there's no like where am I gonna put
this process right there's no oh man
this is dank as [ __ ] like it was the
other day when I picked up from my
caregiver the last time when I got in
the car I was like is that nope that's
my bag in inside is a proper packaging
inside my shoulder bag in the back seat
of my car is still stinking out the
whole cab back in the day this was this
is when the adrenaline really kicks in
yes down and drive home in 20-degree way
you make that meeting with the dude as
soon as that bag and
exchanges now you're like [ __ ] I just
went from like gotta get this gotta find
it where is it is it gonna happen is it
deal gonna go smooth too now I gotta get
this [ __ ] home right now or somewhere or
to whoever's house we're partying in
tonight and then you got to make that
drive and your heart starts going and
then you see a cop I'll give you this
[ __ ] see a cop you could be going the
other way 90 to 90 miles an hour oh [ __ ]
the cops and you gotta like check
yourself and be cool yeah so by the time
you do get home and you start getting
that grin you get a you park the car cuz
you're not gonna get pulled over once
you park the car you pretty much got
home you take the keys out and you're
like oh and by the time you come on a
tour you're almost you can your hands
start doing the grinder motion dick I'm
gonna grind this weed up and by the time
you light it your heart is like in this
special place and that first puff just
puts you like it's like a mission
accomplished it's like you just rescued
the [ __ ] princess and that princess
was sweet Mary Jane I'm nostalgic for it
but I wouldn't go back to it for all the
money in the world like there's nothing
that could get me to go back to having
to do what [ __ ]
I love getting I mean on the off chance
I get pulled over and I've got weed in
the car I love being in vertigo is there
we in the car yep yep I got pulled over
and the cop was 10 feet from my car
before he goes - sir do you have
marijuana in there because he could
smell it yeah and I just looked him
straight in the face and I said yeah
probably there's probably some weed near
I'm not gonna even try to lie and he was
once I said yes that cop was like cool I
got pulled over leaving a big production
grow that I was trimming at for a while
and so like I didn't have anything on me
but I probably had think 8 or 9 grams of
just like marijuana juice not oil or
extract or anything but like just the
pulp from the fan leaf stem like just in
my shoes just soaked in through the
bottom and i stunk to high heaven
because i've been trimming for like 10
hours I was there we in the car
no but I work in the industry I've been
harvesting all day I understand that I
stink to high heaven
if he was like which are all clear eyed
and [ __ ] so let's just see your badge
and your driver's license and your other
thing cool let me bring your car
information you're gonna have a nice
night yeah um just just so you know I
can smell you like four cars date behind
you I could I knew someone in front of
me was just thinking it's like yeah yeah
sorry like sober as a judge
yes working on the harvest time you can
really sell that bartender friend who's
been pulled over several times it's like
I swear to god officer what you're
smelling right now is my socks thank you
I'm sober I just I work at a bar oh yeah
I used to hate that as a musician I
wouldn't drink like I quit drink it for
plenty don't don't get me wrong I think
[ __ ] plenty but I learned not to hit
the club clean and up or whatever and
somebody'd spill some beer on you or on
your equipment or whatever here in the
card it just reeks that beer smell
they'd be driving home like [ __ ] I smell
like beer terrible it's so nice that is
it was literally the only part of my
life where I was way out of whack with
legal
I've actually been kicked out of
restaurants or denied served they didn't
even kick me out there's like no why
don't you guys go take a shower and come
back I had someone walk up and they went
to do the so table for three and they
went so takeout yeah yeah carry out at
the skirted heifer in Colorado Springs I
wasn't gonna say the name of a
restaurant but and like I don't blame
him the entire trim crew like it was I
we were going to dinner we were trimming
and put down the trim to go to dinner it
was more or less that we're working a
caregiver gross so we like we didn't
have any of the like protective layering
that you wear at a production facility
so we had like trim matched you know
issues at that facility we pretty much
sat around a table just like this in our
t-shirts and shorts and trimmed with
rubber gloves on and then we would go
smoke at a friend's house cuz it was so
dope you had a friend that lived between
the grow and downtown j'zargo stop over
there at the apartment get rekt and then
we drove right to the food place and we
go okay we need and I know you guys are
gonna eat outside
we're like what and they're like no your
table is outside guys and we're like aw
[ __ ] it's like four degrees out here so
our high ass is all outside because they
wouldn't let us sit inside the
restaurant but the place was filled with
families like
you could see people looking at us
offended like I can smell your weed over
the burgers in the skirted heifer and
listeners yes I am a vegetarian the
scripted heifer serves a quinoa burger
that is marvelous so don't get me wrong
I don't blame restaurants with like I
don't care what you do for work all day
if you're if you're funky you know from
it to funk out a whole restaurant
you probably shouldn't go straight from
work to the restaurant like I don't care
what you do or why you stink some
restaurants back in the day when I
noticed before we had legal cannabis
legalization and it was a known thing I
would show up to restaurants with my
scuzzy looking friends because I know
I'm not the cleanest looking person I
bathe on a regular basis yes but I do
look like - Bacchus [ __ ] baby cousin
I've got dreadlocks past my ass almost
to my knees I've got a fuzzy beard you
can hear it that's my beard I got a
goatee I got a mustache I wore a crooked
hat and a t-shirt and Dickies and
skateboard shoes and I walk into
restaurants and back in the day and I
smell like wheat I just constantly smell
like herb if I'm growing it smoking it
whatever I smell like cannabis I would
walk into restaurants and they would
kind of roll their eyes and be like [ __ ]
let's sit these weirdos in a corner now
that the industry is the way that it is
they know that kids it look like myself
and you and Kev bro and whoever else
used to roll with me to places they
treat us like [ __ ] rock stars now bro
in the grimy Gatsby and I would go to
dinner in Colorado Springs that waitress
would be up our butts cuz they know it's
like these are weed industry people and
they get paid well I'm gonna be super
[ __ ] nicely that's not they get paid
well they get paid well now and in the
near future in the very recent past they
worked a job where tips or at least
service was a big part of it right um so
when we go out to eat now we understand
that the person serving us our food is
making less than minimum wage and that
if one or two of her table stiffs are
throughout a shift she's gonna have
trouble making ends meet and so if the
service is good we always overt it yeah
yeah just as a community we kind of take
care of it I can always when I was doing
food service I could always tell
which one of my tables which customers
also worked in the services right I've
heard every one of my foodservice
friends has said that before yep you can
always tell and you can tell who's like
no one and their families work in the
service industry in a couple of
generations but you can tell those
[ __ ] too from a mile away and it I
mean it makes a big difference if you're
a server to know who to treat a little
better I love it when you take a girl
out to dinner when the dinner is over
she starts gathering plates and sets
them at the edge of the table like I did
you're awesome but you you're not at
work right now you can chill out anyway
yeah that's so rad to see like you're
[ __ ] awesome good work all right Mike
I don't know how we just ended up on
this [ __ ] ramp we're in a random
field table join us yes I took a couple
of notes that I want to make sure to
mention some other bullet points let's
hit let's say I'm just gonna tease them
because we're gonna do these in another
podcast show yeah well no we won't do
this one tonight but these are just
coming up I want to talk about in the
future somebody you touched on earlier
and I wrote down male selection somebody
sent me an email about male selection
and you talked about breeding we're
gonna talk about male selection in the
very near future we're gonna talk about
the difference between lab testing and
how the cannabis actually works for you
yeah and that reminds me that I want to
give another shout-out to my friend beau
beau Nellis at the spliff podcast we
talk a lot about growing we talk a lot
about cannabis culture we do it from
sort of a dudebro sort of side of things
I understand that that is that's who I
am and I please don't ask me to change
but if you're not into the dudebro
culture dab kids sort of thing that
we've got going on here bone Ellis has a
great podcast called the spliff podcast
and she does it from a much more I
described it kind of like as it's
learning cannabis from my kindergarten
teacher but she's [ __ ] educated and
she is learning more and more as she
goes on with the podcast she will talk
much more about specific cannabinoid
dosing for specific conditions and she
should call some of her episodes a
hundred and one ways to use mic
an abyss because I'm all about dabbing
excuse me I'm all about taking dads I'm
all about smoking some flowers I like
some edibles bo doesn't waste a thing
she uses every bit of cannabinoids she
can pull out of everything and I
appreciate it that's just not my style I
know someone locally that they were the
first person I ever met that was juicing
raw cannabis like when they D foliate
okay take all that leaf material and
juice as long as they toss the crunchy
but when they do foliate is the grain
they juice all that grande material
which uses the stuff that she's
vaporized
she makes a teacher with coconut oil out
of that or a topical with coconut oil
out of that she makes a cannabis lotion
she has been making cannabis products
for her cats recently like so if you
guys want a different perspective on
cannabis if you get tired of hearing our
bro culture over here which I understand
some people aren't into being called
dude and bro on the listen to a podcast
all the time but if you've gotten this
far and you must be into us but if you
want some more a different perspective
on cannabis from a very well-educated
professional sounding woman if you want
a woman's perspective on cannabis I
highly recommend listening to the spliff
podcast from bone Ellis she does not pay
me to say that I [ __ ] a perception
listeners out spell it all you got to do
is search for I'm gonna open up my
iPhone Eric's it's right here on my
podcast screen it is simply I gotta get
to the top I'm scrolling it is because
it's spliff the spliff
yes and pot not pod right it took me
like a week to find this podcast just
because I was hearing split and PAH okay
and I thought it was the split podcast
like this isn't a thing
spliff SPL iff the spliff podcast p OTC
AST and her name is bo bo h nellis and
she's a great host she's a cool person
Bo one day I hope we get to take a DAB
together that'd be fun I'm gonna make
you take like a half gram Dada make you
choke forever because that's how I do it
but you guys you would appreciate this
show if you like my show I feel like
you'll like buzz show she is got 63
episodes up right now nice I am
30-something episodes in and they're
getting better and better as they go
she's really good at recommending
specific dosages of cannabinoids and
she's much uh she doesn't over consume
cannabis the way that I do
so she's much more on the beginner
consumer side which I'm not even bashing
anybody I miss my lower tolerance right
I was able to do some really amazing
things with some low-dose cannabinoid
changes and most of that spectrum I'm a
little ridiculous I'm Chewbacca's
freakin cousin and I like to over dab I
like to overmedicate so if you but
that's enough of a shoutout for Bo I
support that show listen to it it's
[ __ ] great I like it so that's
something that I wrote down and then
we're gonna read an article about
particles per million and Colorado
concentrates on one of the next episode
ppm Ross yes because I think it's
something that needs to be talked about
you got now or to stick around make sure
because we we kill our phones to do we
really try to dedicate an hour or more
to you guys when we record this and part
of that involves killin our phones and I
have no idea what time it's 11:20 p.m.
right now that's a 50 degree or better
swing today folks it was nice but windy
when I was outside getting [ __ ] done
earlier yeah it was still with shitty
called a little bit crazy windy we like
semi flippin windy here alright let's
put this podcast back in some rails
we've walked onto a it's just one of the
fun things about Colorado is our weather
psychotic and you need to plan your grow
for like I'm [ __ ] with you I leave to
go to this new project I'm going to I
leave the house around 6:30 in the
morning and I'm wearing
seriously pants with shorts underneath a
t-shirt a hoodie a jacket a hat that
covers up my ears with my dreads down to
keep me warm I get to where I'm going I
take off the jacket the hoodie that I
put on a different hat then for lunch we
go to lunch and it's nice and warm
outside so I put on shore
and skateboard shoes and a t-shirt and
tie the hair up and put a little small
dread hat on and I wear that for the
second half of the day when I leave the
facility that I'm working with it is a
little after 6:00 so then I put on again
all of the layers every day and it's
cold it's colder than than it was all
day so I we run the full weather gamut
here
I mean daily ago you get most of the
seasons daily all the new people that
haven't been here for a solid year are
sick right now they're all they're all
walking around with that head [ __ ] going
on and all the growers that moved here
from far away and I mean even the ones
that have been growing cannabis one way
or another for years I just fight for
their first two years here trying to
figure out how to to control fur I mean
every day it's it starts out at zero and
then it gets to 65 and it's at zero
again how do I not get pm in this how do
i kir my buds in this how do i balance
the humidity anywhere I watched a guy
design like 2 million dollars with a
floor heating at one point to try to
combat some of the weather here wow it's
just fun way to do it different people
experience especially with I mean we've
never seen an influx of people like this
it's crazy drastic is getting shitty I'm
getting people asking me like the how
the [ __ ] do people survive this question
do they make highway 53 lanes up there
what happened Mike and I are gonna turn
off some microphones and not do all this
to you guys I want to thank everybody
for listening to episode 171 of the girl
from your heart podcast that means a lot
that you guys listen for 171 episodes
that's incredible I keep saying that I'm
gonna put our episodes Thank You Clint
said the same thing today shot - Clint I
keep saying I'm gonna post old episodes
I keep having more content I don't yeah
I don't feel the need to post all them
but I'm gonna do it you guys keep asking
for old stuff all the emails you're
sending me I am responding to them
slowly but I'm getting to them you
wouldn't believe how many emails I get
lately it's Christmastime everybody's
trying to sell me [ __ ] so I just keep
getting so many emails I'm just writing
a note right now Mike it you're looking
at me like this is part of the show but
it has nothing to do with this episode
that's for the future but I'm getting to
all those emails please send me more
emails I love it I love making listener
generated content that lets me know that
I'm getting something out to at least
one person and if I'm hitting one person
and probably hitting a lot of people
there's one person spoke up from you so
send me those emails it's real from your
heart at hotmail.com I'd love to hear
from you make sure you follow Mike on
social media Mike just took nearly two
hours out of his night he's gonna take a
little longer we may record another
episode make sure you follow him on
social media it's Nemo punk 15 on the
Twitter and Pueblo for a sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook there's a lot
of cannabis news that we simply don't
have time to work into a podcast or that
is only a minute or two worth of news
they liked it so a lot of that stuff
gets I post a ton of that stuff to my to
my Facebook page every day lots of local
cannabis news national stuff
international stuff we were gonna talk
about it a little tonight and we just
kind of went long
Canada's doing some amazing stuff a lot
of stuff about Canada
Tennessee that floppy there's a lot of
really awesome marijuana news stories
that we haven't gotten on to the podcast
yet that are up on my social media so
check it out please a couple more things
a couple more things we're gonna wrap
this one up patreon you guys I would
love it
patreon is a service that you can go to
patreon.com/crashcourse is this show
will always be free free freedom I bring
you a free podcast because I love you
and I love cannabis I want you to grow a
better cannabis I want cannabis to be
legalized but what you can do you can
help me pay for the cost of my website I
read genetics Colorado is the website
where this podcast is hosted it cost me
a little over three hundred dollars per
year to keep that website alive I am
paying for that out of my pocket right
now because I love podcasting it's
something that I've chosen to do if you
would like to help me with that a little
bit that would be sweet I don't want to
beg you for it patreon is there for that
go to patreon.com/scishow
grow from your heart you can contribute
as little as $1 or you can contribute as
much as you would like you can sign up
for a monthly service to where you can
contribute one dollar per month then
every month on the 1st of the month
isn't $1 to the podcast and that will
help me not have to cover all the cost
of the podcast out of my pocket
everybody that shows up for the show
gets a bottle of water I try to buy
these little microphone covers these
things here I try to replace these quite
frequently because you guys coughing to
them and they stink and I don't want
people having to share that funky [ __ ]
I've made that trip to the store with
you yes yes and if you're really dying
for old content this is a way to help
make that happen
reason it's not up there right now is
because it would like double or triple
the cost to maintain the web hosting to
go all what are we 171 its 171 now you
go 171 deep that kind of volume and
storage cost a pretty penny I don't want
to make that promise yet I've still got
to get somebody did make the proper
patreon contribution it may said post an
old episode [ __ ] that's the way to
get me to do what you want
like money [ __ ] money talks it's
Christmas time and money talks it's
armsan but yeah but I'm not trying to be
that way I'm saying one dollar goes a
long way if you don't have a dollar to
contribute I do not I do I'm not
offended I still love you I still want
you to listen I still want you to grow
amazing cannabis I do this so that when
I'm old and too tired to do this like on
our own that I'm hoping that enough
people know how to do it well that I can
just hit a store buy at a reasonable
price that's a good way to look at it I
guess
that's all I want is that so by the time
I'm too old to fight this fight anymore
that it's taken care of enough for me to
just enjoy the ride there you go all I'm
asking for is help paying for the
website and buying these little
microphone covers and water bottles and
that's all patreon.com slash and grow
from your heart that would be super
awesome because I've got one more super
important thing that I need to include
in this episode this episode comes out
on Monday so that means guess what happy
birthday miss JB Jenny Beth I love you
hope you have a great birthday hope
everything goes your way um yeah I think
that's all we've got for this episode
Mike you got anything else to wrap it up
with
Merry Christmas folks merry holiday
whatever holidays holidays I don't
remember what the number is tons of them
Christmas is the next big one in my
world but happy holidays everybody I
hope you have a wonderful holiday season
and hopefully we have another podcast
for the first of the year Oh we'll get
it we're gonna they're gonna hear from
us again before Christmas
this one comes out love it 18th 19th so
then that means we got seven dollars it
might be I'd completely forgotten about
in my world it's not Christmas until I
eat a specific type of Christmas cookie
that a family member makes and I don't
like it's just a thing in my world I
went to Hobby Lobby doesn't happen yet
so as far as I'm concerned it's like
August are far far away because I
haven't had that cookie yet will be
joining everybody the day after
Christmas so Merry Christmas everybody
happy holiday Happy Hanukkah whichever
one it is you're celebrating I'm not
sure what all of them are I don't want
to sound defensive but have a great
holiday season eat some good food with
your friends and family if you don't
have some friends and family go to my
facebook page send me a message we'll
[ __ ] chat it down like that watch
some fun tell me what's up don't send me
pictures of your food no I'm not
we're gonna wrap this episode up a
hashtag they like it when we ramble I'm
so glad they liked because dads
because dads don't I think everybody
wants to get for listening I want to
give you a huge shout out to miss Jenny
Beth and until next time take a fat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]