yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 175 of the
girl from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right for your new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
Babur if you're a cannabis activists
treat someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross - Jeff
wanna thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge
thank-you shoutout to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to kat coot an entire mystic roots crew
i did it i got through the whole intro
without coughing oh my goodness I just
took some monster dad's of some
distillate over here I got some ninety
two percent THC distillate
it just made my brain spin a little bit
and it made my lungs to try to wobble a
little bit ladies and gentlemen I
welcome to the podcast my friend Sammy
the painted chef welcome to the show
brother thanks for making the long drive
down a long time listener and a longtime
friend here in the podcast haven't seen
you in quite a while it's been it's been
way too long I apologize my fault you
know we were just talking for a long
time here we're both parents we're both
proud Papa's a beautiful girls so we let
them consume consume our lives which is
definitely priority yeah big shout out
for being a good father
yes yes number one thing yes go give
your kids a hug I always talk about take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug
go give your kids a hug kiss kiss him on
the forehead how no matter how old they
are where a girl go embarrass the [ __ ]
out of them yeah that's the best thing
brother man how can people find you on
social media so that they could stalk
you all day listen here I mean choose
bro I was clowning in town them give me
a name
me Sammy chanclas kind of you know the
chocolate with you guys go follow my
friend the painted chef check him out so
that you can see how sexy he is so that
you can see his beautiful garden
he's a wonderful ganja grower I can you
know that's my favorite thing about you
you were saying a minute ago that you're
trying to get your name in the industry
and get your foot in the door basically
and get to be known I love that you are
a humble dude and you're not so worried
about getting out there and getting
known you know that when the time is
right for you it will happen and you are
a ganja soldier you are a warrior and
you're doing it kind of behind the
scenes and low-key but you're doing it
with a lot of heart and that's what
matters Instagram followers are cool but
put hard into you know to mean you're
making progress for patients I just try
to focus on me and doing my thing of
course my little family you know that's
that's the main motivation you know I
know a lot of you who've been affected
by cannabis and need cannabis helped or
are against it and I'm just always
trying to do there you go
well the girl from your heart well
everything is really awesome awesome so
man I want to thank you I already
thanked you for joining me but I wanna
thank you for backing me up on Facebook
the other day Sammy and I I was a member
of a Facebook group I don't know if Sam
is likely Sam or Sammy was something
close to Sam so uh we were I was in a
Facebook group I'm no longer a member of
that group but I don't have any issues
with that I was trying so I don't want
to sound like an [ __ ] but people post
the dumbest [ __ ] like I've got spider
mites what do I do and I'm like you
should be in your plants yeah and then
put baking soda and vinegar on
everything and I'm like why is that
happening people I don't know no one
wants to or do anything for themselves
the beginning but that's why I get mad
that's why I'm like why are you asking
if what you can do with this when you
know you can go google this it's this is
101 if you got a one on one thing go
google it it's probably any book that
says cannabis growing on the front of it
if you just bought a cannabis growing
book you could go to the glossary or
they index look for your problem find it
turn to that page you'd find try it in
truth solutions instead you want to go
to face
and ask some dude with the clever
[ __ ] name who doesn't even have
pictures of aggro questions and he's
like telling you to do the weirdest [ __ ]
and so I'll go in there and I'll be like
no you shouldn't do that and I will give
a factual reason why and then I will
state a positive way to improve your
solution so that that way or improve
your situation so that way you're not is
a lot of the things they say will cause
you even more problems as you've started
with so I'm like don't do that do this
and people hate on me like you're an
[ __ ] just cuz you're an expert
doesn't mean we can all do that I'm like
you can yeah and I think they're afraid
of a little bit of work and spinning a
couple of bucks they want to make as
much as they can off of this crop
without putting any energy and money
into it that's why I jumped in it
because I'll see them going at you
calling you an [ __ ] yeah I can't
handle that because just when the best
dudes I know like I mean you know
whatever we've been friends or whatever
but when I see that happening I won't
allow it
I'll come in and I'll interject and get
your back and then they'll try to
challenge my knowledge and I might come
on I'm not I don't know everything but
you're you're messing with the big dog
here so they booted me real quick and
then you kept screenshot of me what they
were saying which was gradually they're
trying to say this bro but yeah I
appreciate you tried to back me up and
tell you you're like you don't you said
something about you don't even realize
the wealth of knowledge you just
eliminate you from this group and I
appreciate that that's great
and it's true a lot of those people they
have no idea what's even happening when
I'd comment they just look at me like
I'm they call me a know-it-all and try
to talk [ __ ] to me like I'm really
trying to help you yeah sorry if I went
over your head and I feel like a lot of
the problem is ego I bruised some egos
and then and I don't know it all also
and you know how I did learn I'll admit
a lot of the way I'll learn two things
was by [ __ ] things up yeah I've been
growing for a long time so I made a lot
of mistakes and I'm willing to admit
that and I'm willing to share my
mistakes with people and they don't even
realize that I'm saying I did what
you're trying to do and it doesn't work
so and they just get mad at me instead
of doing all the trial and error that I
did I'm gonna tell you how to get past
that but maybe it's not the nicest
because you're not understanding through
text but I'm gonna tell you
you know what to do not gonna lead you
astray and like mess your plants that
works just cuz you listen to me yeah
don't don't ruin your plants because
some dude on Facebook with the cool name
taught you to spray something on your
plants in week 9 a flower so that you
could solve your problem right it's not
gonna help you out so honestly I'm glad
that I've got cottonmouth is wicked bad
cuz I put my dry face on there was
another person here she took a DAB and
she is now tucked in in bed probably
snoring like a champion I was looking
forward to trying that I never have but
once you saw what he did to her you kind
of changed your whole mind so she's
gonna listen to this show later and be
like okay thanks but I'm kind of glad
that those people are failures on the
forums and on Facebook groups because
it's those groups kind of contributed to
me starting this podcast I was hanging
out at Maddie's house late at night and
answering Gro questions and that's what
contributed to it and there's another
podcast I would listen to and people
would ask questions and instead they'd
be like I have spider mites what do I do
and instead of saying fix the room find
the my it's cleanup and then maybe use a
type of product they would say oh go to
the store and buy this you could get
this store made by this company it's
only this much you can get it this
website for this much tell them that
sales this code which is my name you're
making a lot of damn money this isn't
even a real email from a real listener
to me and I could feel that from a very
specific show and I was like that's
dirty I don't want to do that to people
that podcast kind of inspired me to do a
show and then uh Tim Tim Martin had a
podcast for a little while there the JDR
the John Doe radio that inspired this
and then coral coral reef er of course I
wanted to fill the gap that she was
missing she did all the new stuff yeah
do the gross stuff and then uh Adam Hill
had a fun podcast and his what so kind
of join that vibe so that's kind of so
all that stupid stuff is what I'm
getting at is actually the Facebook
group sucking and all that stuff I
wanted to help people out so that's part
of why I started the podcast without all
those crappy info avenues the show
probably would not have happened so
maybe it's a good thing that the
things out there I guess some bad things
always come a good thing yes yeah right
inspiration that's I mean why not lead
people the right way you know in a fun
way instead of making it boring someone
wants to pay attention and it's so much
easier to listen than to read everything
you can absorb this show while you're
driving down the highway you can be on
your way to work you could be in your
cubicle with an earbud in whatever you
do yeah listen to a podcast to learn how
to grow a weed and meet Sammy The
Painted Chef I hope you guys are
scrolling through his Instagram right
now and checking him out some reason
that feels weird when I say that so uh
let's talk about your growing history
and stuff well let's give you some
credibility here on the podcast I know
your coolest [ __ ] but nobody else here
has met you before you know since I
first tried marijuana I always wanted to
grow it and once I was old enough to do
my own thing I started just dabbling
with it playing with it and uh reading I
read for about 10 years before I ever
put a seed in the ground okay you know
its power and yeah but something I
encourage reading first and then it just
so happened that I think I joined roll
it up or something one of the old forums
that existed back in the day discovered
some cool cuz me and my buddy were
looking for a soil recipe that's how it
happened we're up and down we're gonna
start growing gonna get going on it and
found that for um you know a lot of good
knowledge lassic yeah very classic for
Isaac I mean it's still out there if
anyone wants to check it out you can
learn a lot but anyway um it was that I
met a lot of good people through there I
met you I met all the guys over at geek
geek farms on Oregon's geek Mike Shanin
I love that guy and you out there all
those guys you know it's the Santa
Valerie while we're at it all Riya and
cats crazy um but I met all those guys
you know and you started talking on the
forum you know happens when I started
learning from them and taken what they
taught me applying it to my plans trial
and error doing my thing
yep having fun I think the first one I
grew was a purple coach I got the clone
of it was my own first happy my ex-wife
at the time surprised me for it gift
like I wrote it I was like let me grow
so I went full bore you know and yeah
that was one did that and then just
learn learn more learn more everything
progressed and I got to where I am
started working over at a concentrate
products in Denver okay great place to
work for how many lights were you
running over there oh it was eight room
seventy-five thousand watts per room oh
wow okay
was 2,000 plants at all times in there
and learned a lot learned a wealth of
knowledge over that I mean it had so
much fun the guys were good but you know
I'm not there anymore
looking to do everything that I can you
know just progress more that's pretty
much my story in a nutshell all right
yeah well you've got so much heart bro
it's one thing I love about you that's
one thing I notice about the cannabis
industry those people just we don't stay
in the same place for very long we go in
and you know I don't mind doing the
bounce around because I love seeing the
facility and learning as much as I can
and I'm like I've kind of it's like a
class you know what I mean like well I
made all the friends I want to make here
and I've learned as much as I can I
think I'm gonna go find another facility
now keeps me really happy
I keep they keep accidentally putting
bonuses on my paychecks I can't argue
with them they treat me really well
they're super cool people too you know
it's all the wieners wieners everywhere
every nook and cranny you know you can
find us always it's a blast I had we
nerd stuff wrote down to talk about
later but we can go that way if you want
to so let's introduce the people maybe a
lot of my listeners aren't familiar
because people are listening in
Australia and countries I can't even
pronounce they glad to assume everyone
knows so there is a guy a group of
people but mainly it's led by the the
ringleader is a dude by the name of sub
cool and he's on Instagram but they keep
deleting him so I'm not sure it's I
think it's up cool 420 now okay yeah by
the time this episode comes out they
will have deleted a Miller right have a
new account but so his name is sub cool
and he runs a seed company called TG a
sub cool seeds TGA stands for the green
Avenger they are known for strains like
space clean and vortex and Jillybean
Jillybean actually let's talk about
another member of TGA miss Jill MZ
period Jill made a strain called Jilly
bean it's not jelly it's Jilly because
name that named after Miss Jill that is
sub-cooled wife she's a badass girl
she's a cool lady she does some breeding
she made the Bryan berry coffee so that
is part of the the tea GSF cool family
there's also jinx proof who made the
nine pound hammer
he's a crazy chemist I like watching him
grow up Louis yeah he's a really cool
dude I love his be positive attitude
he's got a child with autism and he also
suffers from the seizure condition
so his B positive attitude is really
cool to see him use cannabis in a
positive way and educate everybody and
yeah so shut it to the whole wizard crew
but that's who we're talking about is
sub cool is the ringleader of the weed
nerds he's the leader of the TGA sub
cool seed company they've also got a
side company known as natural homegrown
wonders which are some of sub cools best
friends but the weed nerds are so he
does a show on YouTube called the wheat
nerd and you can watch him he does a
little head banging he does a little
ganja teaching he'll speak his mind it's
so I better give him some credit he kind
of inspired this podcast to on accident
I think without me even realizing it
because it's the same damn format now
that I think about it without sub I
wouldn't be I wouldn't be where I am for
sure my photography you could tell he
made photography what it is okay there's
another guy freebie t Curtis yes and
mister spliff a bunch of a bunch of
great cannabis photographers but so subs
got a show called the weed nerd and then
all of the folks that follow the show
and our on the show are considered weed
nerds and there's a weed nerd nation and
it's a big it's a big group of folks
have heart about cannabis that love to
grow and breed and support cannabis and
it's it's a bunch of weed nerds as
basically what it is so I endorse you to
go encourage you I said endorse but I
encourage you I'm high I encourage you
to go check out some weed nerd stuff
check out some sub cool stuff a lot of
people have a lot of opinions about some
cool than his products but go see for
yourself that's that's what I think
someone else's look past that and look
to what they're bringing look to their
message and you can learn a lot more a
lot of people probably don't realize how
many strains sub cool he's brought to
market that are amazing strains plush
mary was a sub cool creation the
original they're bringing her back yes
there's some stuff there but yeah a song
ice Jun was making a bunch of plush
berry seeds recently yeah
I've bred with plush berry I had a
really cool purple purple phenotype
scene that made the black cherry kill
yeah that's Julie bean - so we've been
talking on Facebook a little bit and you
actually wanted to talk a little bit
about LED growing okay um I use the for
veg when I'm got a full thing going I
use it because of course it saves power
and if you know how to use them you can
use them right you know I know a lot of
people who like to put them down real
close to the plant because they think
the closer the better but there's
actually a
opportun I guess you want to say range
there I think it's 18 to 12 or 18 to 24
inches away from your plant their beans
focus and you can actually tell when
you're adjusting your life if you look
at the shadow the way the color split
that's and once you do that they just
take off em that's actually right with
just about every light you have to find
I'll call it the sweet spot yeah like
when you get too close you can probably
tell yourself when you get too close
it's real hot oh yeah when you start
backing off a little bit you could tell
that's not too hot I can handle it then
if you go a little further you like oh
there's not a lot of light on my hand
your plants can tell the same damn thing
and they want that sweet spot so you got
to find that with an LED and you say
it's 18 to 24 inches I've been out of my
own grill for a while because I've been
bouncing around but I believe that's
what it is okay it looks right to me
from what I see in all the pictures a
lot of people don't realize that the
lenses have a different angle I think
there's like 60 90 and 120 so the way
the beam shoots out of the line okay
and yeah that's true the 90s of shooting
straight down that's what I kind of want
that's what I look for I go for nine
years so I know all that light is just
going straight to the play to your
leaves yeah and then if you can take
that into account get what you're going
you can do a lot of good with your LEDs
I think a lot of people are either
afraid or mad because they don't
understand how to really roll with the
LED right because they they bought one
for twenty five dollars off eBay put it
two inches from their planet and their
plant did nothing but give them some
little bit of frost you know yeah so I
mean people are afraid to try I say do
it okay I say go with it go for it the
new it the new plants the lights they
have coming out or doing some good
things I mean I'm not mister in the LED
light industry but right is there a
brand that you've had good experience
with or a brand
you would recommend to buy my head I
wouldn't want to just ramble I respect
that more than you trying to get
something out there you go you said
ex-wife earlier you're getting smart
never miss an opportunity to keep your
mouth shut right there you go all right
so what uh is there anything major I'm
gonna have to do other than finding that
sweet spot and the major difference
between growing from an HID like a
high-pressure sodium blunder into
watering is good okay because they don't
use as much it's not as hot in the room
so it doesn't evaporate as much
okay watch that I've done it myself got
some fungus gnats kick myself in the ass
tirelessly and fungus yeah yeah gotta
watch your watering you got let me see
what else did I adjust from doing that
to that um I guess he was undercut a
little more because there's the bottom
just getting the penetration okay so a
little what we mean is clean up the
underskirt there's a leaves on the
bottom of the plant that aren't really
necessary
just little shitty growth you guys will
know what I'm talking about it's a
little tiny just crappy veg growth it's
not gonna turn into anything you're
gonna have to trim fluffy stuff cut that
off of there the energy where that was
being wasted will now go up to the top
you'll get a fatter chunkier bud up at
the top of the plant so clean up that
underside sorry excuse me for clearing
the throat you have to clean up the
other underside a little bit more maybe
pull the plants out a little bit more
and spread them so you can get more
light to them do a little bit more
pruning probably like defoliant a little
bit and then water a little bit less
frequently you're gonna have to change
your feeding other than the amount of
water just a little bit later all right
okay I'm kind of like it they like it
rough I think treating them a little bit
rough the plants there they're meant to
be outside they grow yeah I've said it
before they grow on a rock like Afghan
plants in Afghanistan they've grown a
rocky mountainside where the wind would
blow on it and the Sun would beat on it
and it's get rained on and a goat would
piss on it like these plants are meant
to be durable you know to be they're not
a [ __ ] plant because weed for a reason
is what Mike always says anywhere
anywhere if you're doing it you can if
even if you have to try it almost kill
this plant
yeah totally you have to put it through
some stuff or I mean it may it may spit
out some seeds you don't want it but
it's still gonna survive the stress you
give it absolutely uh-huh yeah so okay
so you're dragging it right from the
LEDs under the HIDs is it gonna get
straight does it grow more stretchy or
just a bushier with the LEDs it'll start
to compact more and get more bush that's
it that's why I like it I'll give it a
couple weeks a little bit a little bit
more [ __ ] under the LED before I mean
the hid before I flip it and give it put
it into flour just get him a little bit
more used to the light you notice a
stretch is it stretch at that point the
stretches I don't know maybe it depends
of what I'm doing I try to keep him real
small so cuz what's nice are you using
just a curiosity little pots I'm
actually running a fee no excuse Mickey
burp and I keep drinking dr. pepper to
try to get rid of the dab throughout
hairnets that's making a terrible combo
of herbs and throat clearing I apologize
I'm doing a fee no Han Solo cups and
I've just got them in a little tray so
that I can water the tray and it absorbs
the water but it's working pretty well
I've never done it like that but you can
fit you can fit 28 cups in one of these
trays and then I eliminated close to
half of them because they're male and
female you know I pulled the boys out so
there's like 14 or 15 males per tray and
they fit beautifully in there and I just
pour water in the tray look he's got him
in Solo cups and I love a tiny girl like
that everybody every day once in a while
I like to do a solo cup challenge when I
was on the forums that's always one get
a bunch of people go in a whole plant
and I saw little cups you can do yeah
but maybe depend on how long I let them
go to three inches they'll stretch it
real nice real quick for me and okay
then I'll flip them alright it's more of
I guess it's more of a height thing for
me than a time thing I've never put
anything on a timer or anything I try to
have a height schedule but I just broke
my schedule by seven by five days a
couple of days ago because like these
plants are too tall okay just watching
them was like no these must go into
flower now the grower and me kicked in I
was I forget to schedule these plants
have to fall right I guess I turned an
Orisha fear in my head I just realized
but I got a flower these plants I never
I just listened to the plant that's all
I've ever done schedules are fine for a
good little
the plan will tell you what it needs
what it wants to do yeah can't can't do
what it doesn't want to do so yeah of
course it you can't you can force it to
flower that's about the only thing I can
force it to do I've learned to force it
to do some [ __ ] of first girls into boys
anyway the speaking of I just dragged
plants into flower you guys just to give
you kind of an update on some new [ __ ]
I'm trying I recently purchased the
entire set up of veg blue I got the base
newts I got the life I got the shine and
I got the push foliar spray and I just
put some grateful dog plants in to
flower and they are getting fed the full
veg bloom plus a little bit of aminos
from photosynthesis plus plus
occasionally they're getting a little
bit of humble honey is what they're
getting fed for carbohydrates and that
yucca extract just to give them a little
a little moisture a little fluff a
little taste yeah so yeah they just went
into flour a few days ago so in like
nine weeks I'll let you know my first
memory have used that grateful dog oh
yeah it's such a great strain I think
that's one of that strain so I'm gonna
put you on the spot top five I'm gonna
I'm gonna write grateful dog on here as
number five I'm not gonna put myself as
one top five is gonna be that one I'm
gonna have to say the blue jay was good
I really love the Bluebird with that
crosses from geek Mike he sent it to me
it was Jillybean the marmalade Fino
cross with organ blues organ blues yes
okay I love me a good urban critical
mass that's one of my most recent
favorites okay if we did critical mass
Durbin poison organ blues the blue one
that I can't read the next word from and
the Grateful dog but you can keep going
what else you got on that Doctor Who I
love me some doctor it was Doctor Who
from jinx proof doctor who was from OD
OD this organ boy yeah check them out
check him out on Instagram they do some
great stuff and then let me see uh Agent
Orange I had a really good taste of
Agent Orange
back in the day I don't know if you
remember him cannabis cannabis coal or
can a biscuit which everyone has a
sounds familiar yeah yeah
he live up in the mountains here in
Colorado and I went to see him one time
he gave me some tasty tasty Agent Orange
it tastes like I've been at Valencia it
was it was amazing yeah he's better
that orange velvet clone that miss Jill
has yeah I miss that guy he was a good
guy he kind of disappeared but you know
how sometimes we gotta just turn the
mountains or whatever but then let me
see a lot of the old-school growers from
like overgrow and from that generation
they all just disappear like they had to
there's just too much too quick is what
happens yeah uh-huh
let me see another one that just knocked
my socks off I don't know grateful dogs
all I've tried of yours I can't okay
well we might fix that before you leave
here I would not be upset yeah what's
your favorite strain to grow to grow
yeah to date my favorite one to grow and
probably be the UM the blue jay the blue
jay was a [ __ ] oh I haven't grown it in
a minute but it was easy it was it was
fun to play with the buds are nice and
pretty it's so tasty there's something
about an easy strain you know I mean
there's like easy grow another one
recently River Song that's what I've
been trying to get out of my head River
put that one on there cuz River Song is
what's the cross on there every song was
what was it a riot of a rattle about of
or organ it was what I loved that organ
blues out there yeah but yeah that's
what they're working on when I dug
buckets is working on one with that
River song called crooked City blues or
something it's the river song crossed
with a wash now I'm gonna jog like I've
been thinking about it I'll come to you
we'll talk about something different
you'll you be like all bro it's check
out that stuff coming out of organs they
got it all up they're so much fun to
play with
so have you reminded me when you got
here that I gave you your very first dad
yes sir man you're welcome I'm honored
to do that I that was like when
everything was first starting to get
going with the dabs and everything and
you know the butane and everything my
lungs whatever but give me a DAB I'm
gonna take a DAB yeah that day we that
was like our second time meeting were we
in line for the cannabis cup can I give
you a dab in the line right now for
smoking joints and I was like well let's
get down
I remember there are people like from
Florida around us and we're just doing
dabs and everyone's eyes like people did
not know what to think dreadlocks giving
dabs to his friends pretty red yeah well
you know I wasn't gonna be like that
about it your your person over here
taking dabs you helped me out with
something on that day I'm not gonna call
you out on air in the podcast Kazak yeah
but you helped yeah thank you I
appreciate that
Sammy saw a door that was open and
helped me walk through it probably save
me like a good yeah standing in line
sometimes for a cannabis event in the
hot Sun nuts and you paid a lot of money
to get into that place and you got to
just stand outside all day because
they're not prepared yeah do you have
any predictions or have you heard any
news for the cannabis cup in Denver or
Colorado or anything for yeah yeah
that's kind of how I've been to I'd like
to usually by this time of year I
started getting prepared I started
getting seeds on deck and packaged up
and having some ideas and knowing what
I'm gonna do and start looking at hotels
this is honestly the first conversation
or thought I've put into it so far yeah
there you go
High Times what's going on anybody out
there what's going on for the cannabis
cup this year I'm gonna throw in a
shameless advertisement because I have
to do an advertisement in this podcast I
didn't do it but I missed the podcast
because I don't get to see my friends
from handmade apparel I said the podcast
damn I tried to be smooth about it miss
the cannabis cup because I don't get to
see my friends from handmade apparel
those guys are so cool right Adam yeah
Adam is cool Adam Jackie's cool as [ __ ]
it's cool the whole crew that they bring
and then what's cool is they bring the
oil slick crew with them because they're
all friends and then you get the oil
slick crew and the handmade crew
together
yeah we all get goofy and take a bunch
of dads and high-five and shirts are
amazing I love them the I'm not wearing
it for a change I'm usually weren't I
read genetics or a hoodie or a girl from
your heart hoodie or something but their
printing is so perfect people don't want
a print I've had graphic artists turn me
down to print my stuff because it's too
many colors and it's too much like it's
gonna cost like 20 bucks a shirt I'm
like no but handmade apparel doesn't
very affordably yeah so that's what I'm
getting at you guys support my friends
at handmade apparel check out handmade
apparel dot biz I get some shirts they
will make t-shirts hoodies they will
print whatever you need printed they are
amazing they do the art in-house Adams
an amazing artist they can make hat pins
they'll make stickers they will do it
all go get some stuff made from them
tell them that Rasta Jeff sent you let
them know that you're listening to the
girl from a heart podcast they're
running a super great special right now
I don't want to call prices because it
may change by the time you listen to
this episode but please check them out
much love much respect to the handmade
apparel true and the oil sector I love
you guys out there on the coast miss you
guys hope everything as well they print
the all the industry shirts that's where
some cool gets in sure it's done it's
where I get all my shirts done I've got
the girl from your heart hoodies they're
sitting in a box over there behind you
the print on those things is so bold bro
it's so fresh it looks so good
it's kind of weird wearing a hoodie with
my face on not a lot of people have a
hoodie of their show by the time you
leave here you might have a hoodie with
my face on your back and then you might
have some eye region etics flowers and
your long we'll see how it goes like I
said I wouldn't be upset right make
everybody happy here man you know what
I've noticed and I'm trying to make it
sound organic but I did write this down
chefs bro chefs are always good not
always but a lot of good growers and
breeders are also good chefs and I know
you're the Painted chef and I just I've
made comments on Facebook one time I
said I burn myself and he told me to rub
mustard on oh yeah yeah you're like rub
mustard on it bro you'll be fine I
didn't do that I didn't all I had was
that French is crap and that's not
mustard yellow yeah oh is that mustard
is that really mustard that French's
[Music]
kill the swelling and all that so that's
okay I learned that from my grandma
[Music]
they're probably they're cooking
together showing the recipes okay
talking about chefs being good growers
that's where I was Jesus I threw myself
away talking about our grandmas that was
weird yeah we liked it when we Grandma
ramble yes
so chefs are good growers and breeders
do you think there's anything about that
is that the flavor or is that the work
ethic attention to detail I'm glad you
said that cuz I made some notes and that
wasn't one of the things I wrote if
you're well if you're a chef I'm not
gonna get on that whole cake cause
they're cooking a chef or two things but
if you got to put plates together you
got to get down into it and get
everything together and get the good
flavors coming out you gotta pay
attention to every detail every detail
everything have to look at every tomato
when you slice it make sure it's not a
little bit mushy or a little too hard
the chef de cuisine for a five-star
establishment at one point you know
that's why I call myself a chef because
I was a chef but um it was fun they gave
me my whole kitchen to run I was in
charge of everything but it was my
artwork on a plate so you had to be
there someone didn't do it right
watch out cuz here comes Sam you know
you know that's just how it is you know
you got to be a perfectionist you got to
do that and that just transfers over to
the world of growing super simple and
it's easier in the grow because you
don't have a time limit to do it you
know I gotta get this plate up in this
amount of time right so I think chefs
can make the adjustment better and be
better at this because it's less stress
and it's the same amount of work and the
same amount of fun if you're that kind
of crazy yeah yeah that kind of crazy I
like that because you write all of the
chef's I've worked with several several
chefs in the cannabis industry and I
have several chef friends everybody that
works in the kitchen loves to consume
some cannabis before nearing end or
after work so I am associated with a lot
of people in a kitchen environment they
are all that special kind of craziness
they can work a 12-hour shift and then
drink for eight hours right after work
and then sleep for like four hours and
be back at it tomorrow and I'm like how
the hell do you guys do that it's hot in
there when your house side the kitchen
with the chef you'll hear him saying I
hate the kitchen yeah but you get them
in that kitchen get get that pressure
going and every chef loves that there's
something about that pressure I love
working I'm not I'm no good in the
kitchen I know I wouldn't know the first
thing I'm lost in a kitchen you'd throw
me the hell out I'd cut myself
/ quickly but I love pressure I would
like to work under pressure I noticed
myself the guys at work look at me like
you should probably slow down because
we're gonna be out of work by noon if
you keep going that fast
yeah turbo is the way to go so much fun
getting work done and then you look back
and you're like leave all this [ __ ] I
just got done you're covered in sweat
and your back hurts but you're like yeah
and all the other guys are trying to
catch up like I've got puddle buckets in
yeah five tables behind you so yeah I
think I think chefs make great growers
and breeders that work I think that
attention to detail I was gonna say the
cleanliness I mean sick from a non clean
restaurant before I don't want to do
that again it's hard out I'm sure it's
not because yeah but it's mainly because
it's not perfect I'm pretty mad my
daughters are always like dad right it's
the hardest thing just to keep your
mouth shut not that I bowled out like
it's good ladies like that ya know just
I guess I'm different I just silently
eat in and get a bit leave thanks for
that shitty food I'm not coming back I
used to be like that till I got deep
into my chef I know it's already it
almost any restaurant where we live
around here it's all like pre-prepared
you know what I mean most restaurants
now pre-prep they just got to go in
there and pour the bags into the thing
and put the right sauce on top of it
bring it out you know like you couldn't
even put the three bags together and
heat them up properly for me come on
yeah I went to uh I'm not gonna call out
the restaurant but I'm go to a
restaurant bit they get rave reviews on
the internet and they are decorated up
like their fancy bro and they act like
they're real fancy they've kind of gave
that one person in there gave me like a
Oh sort of a look when I came in of
course I'm 65 and I have dreadlocks to
my ass and I was walking through a fancy
restaurant I get I get the look I had my
dreads tied up but they could still they
still looked at me like whoa
and I had bright red eyes cuz I just
took in a takin a dab in the car but
they served us what do they call
raviolis
as an appetizer but the plate came with
I don't know what it was it was a white
colored sauce with a dark colored swirl
and it was real fancy looking I just
smacked the microphone making a swirl
and then it had the raviolis on top of
that and there was a little side of
marinara and a side of another sauce and
then they'd put like fresh parmesan or
something on top of it I was like that
looks [ __ ] delicious I'm gonna grab
me one of them I took a bite out of it
and I'm 95% sure that it is the same
frozen ravioli that I bought at Sam's
Club that I had with my freezer over
there and I felt embarrassed for myself
for getting excited like oh that's a
[ __ ] but you were fooled yeah and
then I feel bad for the whole restaurant
I was like oh wait they just lost all
credibility to me it's an industry-wide
thing and that you know it sucks because
people are going out there thinking
they're gonna get this great meal when
you can go to Walmart and pick it up and
you know yeah I probably could have
microwave those things myself and not ya
know why I charge so much when you're
just doing something that someone can do
for themselves maybe you can do a little
better and make it taste better so what
don't charge so much get more people
than have fun yeah everybody Bunton was
money hungry so I don't see eye to eye
with a lot of people that's why I jumped
out to be in the show
I got tired of working working working
to put money in other people's pockets
when they were keeping me on the mum
wage and stuff so it was like thank God
for Colorado being smart and let me grow
cannabis for living you know love it
love Jeffrey letting us grow cannabis
it's so great yeah so yeah so so many
things lined up for being a chef and
yeah I love your eye for detail that's
in the passion I see it that's so
awesome man he's gonna sneeze I tried to
pause it season be smooth about it but
then my whole face just twitch they
saved the sneeze okay I'm not gonna
sneeze no microphone I can add it all at
a [ __ ] oh where was I now I don't even
have any more notes I don't think I know
what I was gonna say my brain will
remember I really don't even remember
what I was gonna say all right throw in
here or do you want to start wrapping it
up since we're since I'm gonna have to
do it editor here anyway which is not
anything rare we do a lot of it
that's what I was gonna ask you to I
wasn't gonna all right so here I'll just
be quiet for a half a second then I
throw it like this
all right brother the man will have kept
you for long enough I'm sure you've got
it like a two-hour drive to get home
from here right yeah yeah well I was
looking earlier and it says that we're
gonna get some snow so yeah it's 8:15
now so you're not gonna get home till
10:15 yeah sure you got a real life you
got to work tomorrow
spend some time with the little tiny
ones I really appreciate you coming and
hanging out driving two hours to come
hang out do a podcast with me that is
cool as [ __ ] any time you're passing
through my neck of the woods if you're
by that exit you better message me
somehow I'll give you my number right
now we're doing it through Facebook I'll
give you my phone number so you straight
text me we'll get you over here you can
hang out so people that are listening
make sure you follow the painted chef on
all of the social media if you want to
stalk him on Facebook you could do that
but yeah it's not so personal you know
we don't mean to be so passive
aggressive and/or aggressive we just
have a lot of passion for cannabis and
we want that [ __ ] done right yes all
right you guys I want to give a huge
thank you to everybody who is
contributed to my patreon campaign that
is super kind of you I truly do
appreciate that you guys might not know
what I'm talking about patreon it is a
service where you can contribute
financially to the podcast all you have
to do is go to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart and you can make a
financial contribution to the podcast
I'm not trying to get rich off of
podcasting this podcast is always going
to be free from my heart for you I will
put out one weekly episode because I
love you guys I love podcasting I'll
have cannabis it's gonna be free but if
you were able or if you would like to or
if you feel like this podcast was worth
a couple of bucks all you have to do is
go to patreon.com/scishow or from your
heart you can contribute as little as $1
and I really don't think there's a limit
on how many zeros or nines you can put
at the end of that so and it is a
monthly signup if you want to sign up
for a monthly subscription you will be
charged on the first of every month on
your credit card of choice and it will
send one dollar to my PayPal account and
what I'm trying to do is
offset the cost of my website my website
costs a chunk of change to keep alive
every year and that is where I host this
podcast so to keep it free without
having to do something I like charge you
guys or go find other sponsors just
asking for a little bit of contribution
through patreon so they're on the dollar
on patreon I'll use it to pay for the
website will keep the podcast coming to
you for free forever I'd like to commit
through forever but you know I'm gonna
do my best you know and if you can't
contribute I still love you I still
appreciate you keep listening that's you
that's how you're doing what you can do
and if you can't contribute and you want
to do me some sort of favor
go to iTunes go to the let's see how do
you do you go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from the heart
podcast find the review section there
you go and I'm back on track for the
review section everybody so far in the
review section has given me a five-star
review so you could throw up another
five-star review or whatever you feel
like a thorough owner of you type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the podcast and I do about once a month
go and read all of the iTunes comments
that I have not read on the air so you
get to hear your comment on the show let
me know what you think of the podcast
love it or hate it how most likely read
because you need just go make an iTunes
account once you get a big huge shout
out to our friends at handmade apparel
also again huge shout out to my friend
the payment chef I think that's all I've
got for this week you got anything you
want to say while you're on a podcast
for a whole bunch of people are gonna
hear you everyone out there just do what
you do with love we need more love in
this world that's pretty much my whole
stance for living right now love love
love I think we should just push stop
and court recording at this point that
was probably the best ending a podcast
could ever have brother I thank you very
much for spreading that message and
coming on the show with that thank you
for having me here on the next time
that's all we've got for this week I
wanna give a huge shot at the sub cool
and all of the weed nerds all you guys
out there you guys know who you are
every one of you if I've met you or not
much love and much respect and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
are you ready are you ready to go put
your hands together for this
[Music]
one child lost afar
[Applause]
[Music]
I'm gonna pass around just a little tiny
baby boy y'all the Smurfs
[Music]
[Applause]
California that's mr. Greenspan
yo welcome to Chico place where we
school the occupation and
[Music]
I decrease
you