yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 177 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right a good new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat coop and the entire mystic
roots crew I wanna give you a huge shout
out to my huge audience you guys the
podcast was ranked number 963 on
stitcher stitcher hosts I think they
brag that they have 50,000 podcasts
available on their service and the girl
from your heart podcast was recently
ranked number 963 overall so I want to
thank everybody for listening on
stitcher I want to thank everybody for
listening also on stitcher we were
ranked number 80 in the society and
culture category so we were in a top 100
section on stitcher makes me super proud
thank you guys for listening for
supporting the show iTunes doesn't show
me a lot of stats or anything
iTunes doesn't give a [ __ ] so I don't
know where i stand on iTunes but on
stitcher we are crushing it big thanks
to everybody also big thank you to
everybody who listened to the episode
with solvent list Shannon and davon
granny that was a great episode also
Lindsey and Chris were here yes they did
put some stuff in there but I got a
couple of messages that said hey bro as
soon as you guys started talking about
putting things in your butt I checked
out one of my friend said that he was
getting some mental images and some
visuals and he did not want to
contaminate his brain like that so he
listened to about three minutes of the
show and checked out I apologize if that
was too much for you but thanks for
everybody thanks to everybody they
listened to the podcast I appreciate it
also big thanks to some unless Shannon
and davon granny for coming and being on
the podcast I look forward to having
both of those lovely ladies on the
podcast again and you know we will get
the traveling stoner and boba blaster Co
back on the
show real soon shout out kids I hope you
guys are doing well let's see where else
mi hand made big shots my friends at
handmade apparel that's right this
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at handmade apparel if you need shirts
hoodies any type of clothing printed if
you need stickers if you need hat pins
any sort of creative custom artwork I
recommend my friends at handmade apparel
that's right check out handmade apparel
dot biz they make all of my gear they've
made my eye region etics t-shirts they
made my girl from your heart hoodies
they make my IRA genetics hat pins I
trust love and support my friends at
handmade apparel check him out handmade
apparel dot biz let them know you
learned about them from the girl from
your heart podcast tell them Rasta Jeff
sent you
they will take great care of you alright
I am pulling up a message on my phone
here but I've got an iPhone and it's
acted funny you know how that [ __ ] goes
it's like you're listening to music you
have to unlock me if did you ate other
things to get to the message you want
get the message here we go I want to
give a huge shout out to my friend
Mountain smokes a few episodes back I
didn't episode called follow your nose
and I talked about Sour Diesel and
Hispanic folks I felt like it maybe a
bit racist calling about calling out the
folks of Latin descent for liking Sour
Diesel but I felt that was something
that I noticed and my friend Mountain
smokes on snapchat sent me a message she
said oh my gosh the Sour Diesel bits so
true
being from Gunnison County another
heavily populated area Sour Diesel has
always been growing in the basements and
it was by far the most popular strain I
sold their spot on that she also says
also loved the podcast once again and
yes follow your nose so very true
so thanks for the message and big shout
out to my friend Mountain smokes on
snapchat make sure you follow her on
snapchat she's a cutie she smokes
cannabis she's a great cannabis activist
and she is learning a whole bunch and
becoming very knowledgeable and she
likes to share that stuff with her
viewers on snap so check her out and
follow her
ladies and gentlemen I'm gonna get right
to an email I've got a long email here
about powdery mildew and I feel like I
can really give some help so I'm pulling
up the email while I while I talk where
is it here we go alright the email goes
like this yo love the podcast a longtime
listener hashtag love it when you ramble
shoutout to white Mike why Mike you got
a shout-out bro hope you heard that you
guys will get Mike back on the podcast
real soon he'll be here he's got a young
child
wife it's got a life you can't be on
every episode but we'll get it back
pretty soon
shut up bro I hope you're doing well the
message goes on to say anyways I will
keep this short I work at a commercial
scale cultivation site and we have been
fighting powdery mildew for a year now
and would love some help we have sprayed
[ __ ] everything and I'm starting to
tap out it's indoor and it's in the
desert any thoughts and then he signs it
thanks and then his name I'm not sure if
he wants everybody oh he does he says PS
you can say my name we out here so
thanks Matthias
585 on Instagram its m8 eh hi US 585 on
Instagram follow him if he wants you
alright let's talk a little bit about
your powdery mildew situation there are
a lot of things we can spray and things
we can do to help treat and correct this
problem but what I'm mainly concerned
with is why is it there how did it show
up in the first place and is it going to
come back since you say you've sprayed
[ __ ] everything it makes me think
that you have issues with the room
obviously there is not enough airflow
you're not getting rid of the old air
you're not bringing in enough fresh air
possibly there are temperature
fluctuations there are a lot of things
like that that are going to be causing
problems are you running a hydro grow or
a soil grow if it's hydro you've got a
lot of water in there you're gonna have
to control the temperature if it's hydro
you may need to get some chillers and
cool the water because that'll prevent
the water from becoming a vapor which
becomes humidity which promotes the
powdery mildew if you're running with
rock wool cubes you may need to let them
dry a little more if you're running soil
you may be getting the soil too wet how
much water is in the grow facility
itself do you have water available to
evaporate to make condensation in there
that's gonna help you get powdery mildew
too much moisture too much water you
said you're in the desert so too much
moisture too much water the outside is
hot the inside is real moisture creating
a bubble filled with humidity in there
and that's going to contribute to your
powdery mildew so you need heavy
dehumidification in that room you need
to get that old hot stale air out you
need to get some fresh air in you need
some ventilation hopefully you're
treating the air that's coming in that's
something we should talk about you need
to get that old stale air out stale air
out of course but there's fresh air
coming in that fresh air coming in
need to be treated you need a filter and
also they make a UV light that is very
good at killing powdery mildew it will
kill any spores that come in they make a
light that goes over your ducting so the
ducting the intake ducting comes in and
then this light shines through the
ducting and everything that passes
through that duct is basically killed so
I would use HIPPA filters on all of the
intakes and I would use the UV lighting
on all of the venting and ducting if you
can if you can pass all of the air
through one thing and run a UV light
over it that would be ideal they sell
things called clean lights they're UV
lights that are designed for gardens
they're mostly used in like this
strawberry industry because strawberries
get a lot of powdery mildew on them they
sell handheld versions of these lights
that you can actually walk around the
crop and shine this light over the
entire crop and you just run it over I
just basically want to illuminate every
inch of the canopy for about a half a
second to two seconds so you just wave
your hand waving my hand over it right
now like you guys can see what I'm doing
but it's basically the same motion you
make when you're watering you know you
just move your hand around bla bla bla
back and forth like a windshield wiper
you do that with this light and you walk
over the canopy and just make sure that
the light shines on every leaf and that
light kills the powdery mildew it takes
several applications of that light to
get rid of powdery mildew if you already
have it but if you're persistent with it
that will help so the room needs to be
corrected there may be some water issues
you may need some equipment some
dehumidification you need some air
exchange temperature control is huge you
can't have huge swings huge temperature
swings in the night and in the day are
going to cause powdery mildew issues so
that's what I think about the room let's
talk about the plants how far apart are
your plants are they touching if the
plant leaves are laying on top of each
other in that little space imagine if if
we're sitting in a room and I just put
my hand on this sounds disgusting to me
but what if I just put my head on your
leg in my hot hand I'm 96 degrees or
whatever I am my head is just sitting on
your leg in about 20 or 30 minutes
there's gonna be a hot sweaty spot there
just from our body parts touching and
getting warm there's gonna be a little
bit of sweat in there that's sweat that
those plants create will cause powdery
mildew right there between those two
leaves and it'll start spreading from
there rapidly so something you can
really help
d foliate heavily when i'm in a large
commercial facility we spend days just
defoliating sometimes it'll be
defoliation day guys get super stoned on
your break because when you come back
all you're doing is pulling leaves for
the next eight hours just pluck every
leaf with the PDL out of that room if
you're I'm not sure if you're the
manager if you're the boss or if you're
the owner but if you were able to pull
every leaf that you can out of there
those leaves are where the powdery
mildew happens get it out of there so
that's what you can do for the plant
spread them out kind of take off all the
big leaves put some air on them fan them
around if the powdery mildew can't
develop because it's blown around too
much it can't develop if the humidity
doesn't stay stagnant the powdery mildew
will have a harder time developing so
let's talk about you said you've sprayed
everything I've hit your plants look
pissed off they got powdery mildew and
you're spraying them with stuff and
they're trying to fight the powdery
mildew and then they're getting [ __ ]
sprayed on them frequently but they're
getting mad I bet you're getting
frustrated as hell
stay positive bro we're going to beat
this [ __ ] um I'm curious what you've
sprayed because sometimes your sprays
are going to add more moisture it's
gonna add more humidity I've sprayed
commercial rooms thinking yeah I just
got rid of powdery mildew when I came
back the next day and the powdery mildew
was actually thicker drove me [ __ ]
nuts
so like I'm saying you got to fix the
room you have to spread the plants apart
if you've got a bunch of water on the
floor squeegee and shop-vac that [ __ ] up
get rid of that extra water so let's
talk about sprays what have you sprayed
I'm really curious um there is a product
called big-time exterminator that I have
heard works wonders on powdery mildew
it's organic and it is okay here's
something I should mention in Colorado
we are very limited on products that we
can use a lot of people will say go get
a bottle of Eagle 20 and spray that [ __ ]
right on your plants Eagle 20 will get
rid of your powdery mildew it may take
one application it may take two
applications but your powdery mildew
will be gone for 30 days maybe 45 to 60
days guaranteed I personally do not like
Eagle 20 there are a lot of deadly
dangerous shitty chemicals in there that
we do not need to spray on our plants
that we are going to call medicine to
give to sick people I do not recommend
eagle 20 in Colorado Eagle 20 is
completely banned we are not allowed to
use it and
recreational or a medical facility that
is regulated by the Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division is a banned product
I like that some products are banned it
keeps us safe it keeps our growers safe
it keeps the consumers safe we haven't
done enough research on a lot of these
chemicals to know what's going to happen
to us if we smoke it and a lot of these
things affect your body in a way that
say I spray my plants with eagle 20
today and we let them flower we harvest
them we cut them down that's probably
you know 50 to 60 days you let them dry
you smoke it there's probably still
Eagle 20 on those buds when I smoke it I
don't think I'm gonna notice anything
right away I may get a funky taste my
throat may burn but that's it but I'm
thinking that in like ten years is what
I'm gonna notice the [ __ ] up from that
I'm gonna get a twitch my left eye is
gonna pop out I'm gonna talk funny I
might get a limp or even a bigger fear
maybe it does something to my DNA or my
RNA and my I'm not I don't plan on
having any more kids but maybe you do
maybe it'll [ __ ] up your RNA and your
DNA and your kids will come out with
three arms or three eyes or one foot or
14 toes you know so we don't know enough
about what these these chemicals kill
mildews and they kill bugs so it's doing
something biologically or something it
depends on what kind of chemical you're
using but it's doing something and it
could be getting into your body and
[ __ ] up your body by smoking it so we
need to be really careful I know I got
way off topic just kind of want to rant
there but if you want a spray eagle 20
go in there hit that shoot with eagle 20
problem solved you got a little bit of
time to figure out how to fix the rooms
and then hopefully you can fix it again
and not ever have to use the Eagle 20
again I don't recommend that [ __ ] you
guys at all at all at all things that we
are allowed to use in Colorado a product
called big-time exterminator it's mostly
citrus oil or citrus it's citrus
something I think a citrus oil mostly
citrus oil extract it sounds like smells
like oranges it's kind of nice like
lemony smell orange II smell citrusy
smell to it I mixed that up I think I
put I did whatever the bucket says
there's an ingredients on the bucket go
the heavy route mix it up with some
water spray that right on the plants and
that stuff should calm down the powdery
mildew you may have to go for a few
applications of that that'll take care
of your powdery mildew another product
that I have seen work on powdery mildew
is
30% hydrogen peroxide I saw a guy put 50
milliliters of hydrogen peroxide in a
five-gallon bucket and sprayed that
directly he adjusted the pH and then
sprayed that directly on to the entire
crop and you could kind of see the
hydrogen peroxide breakdown the powdery
mildew she sprayed the entire crop and
then he went ahead and sprayed the
entire room sprayed everything down
everything smelled like hydrogen
peroxide it smelled super clean in there
it took several applications I think he
was going at it daily but by the end of
a week the powdery mildew was gone so
you can use p.m. wash you can use
hydrogen peroxide you can use oh sorry I
didn't say p.m. wash there's a product
called PM wash which I haven't used it
but I've read great things about it the
PM wash should wash the powdery mildew
off of your plants so peroxide PM wash
and Big Time exterminator are three
products that you can buy you can order
them over the internet you could
probably buy them at your local grocers
those products I'm told will get rid of
your powdery mildew I have seen the
hydrogen peroxide do it I've seen the
big-time exterminator do it it'll take
multiple applications you have to be
persistent you have to pay attention to
the plants they're gonna need a little
bit of love after this if you're gonna
spray them for several days with the
products like big-time exterminator or
hydrogen peroxide
I recommend give them a day of rest and
then spray them with push from our
friends at veg bloom they do not pay me
to talk about their products but push is
an amazing product it's a foliar product
it's a little hard to get it's a little
bit expensive but oh my god it's worth
every penny and if you're gonna do this
much damage and this much beating up to
your plants I think push would be really
helpful another product I can recommend
is a product called stylet oil silent
oil is not allowed to be used in a
recreational or commercial facility in
Colorado but I have used it myself and
it did take care of everything
stylet oil is an oil that coats your
plant and it will not allow the powdery
mildew to grow on the plant it will not
allow fungus gnats to gather on the
plant it won't let mites get on the
bottom side of the plant nothing wants
anything to do with styling oil
the problem with styling oil is it
strips the cuticles off your plant
leaves and it leaves them really
vulnerable and they look a little
leathery they get kind of sad at you
about it if you're going to use styling
oil
I would if your plants are small enough
I would dunk the plants into a stylet
oil diluted heavily don't go straight
into the oil sorry let me say that mix
up some style of oil I cannot think of
the dilution recommendations but it is
on the bottle go light dunk the plant
into the stylet oil get every leaf in
there give it a good wiggle pull it out
set it back in the grow area turn off
the lights let it dry give it about an
hour let all the plants dry after you've
dunked everything and then go back with
the sprayer and hose off every single
plant the stylet oil will dry and coat
and then you just want to kind of rinse
off the excess and all of your powdery
mildew and bugs should be removed within
the first application styling oil will
[ __ ] your plants up if they're not
strong it's gonna beat the [ __ ] out of
them maybe test a couple of plants
because it does beat your plants up
heavily but it will work I had almost
forgotten about the stylet oil where are
you located man I've got a huge bottle
of JMS silent oil that I do not think
I'm going to use if you're near me we
can work out a deal just [ __ ] I want
to see what happens when you use it
let's see where am I now another thing
that we can talk about our friend frosty
organics was on the podcast quite a
while back and he talked about lactic
acid bacteria spray frosty taught us
that he can make his own lactic acid
bacteria spray and apply it to the
plants and he says that one application
will remove his powdery mildew issue I'm
not sure how well that works I have not
tried it myself
but I do trust the [ __ ] out of frosty
organics so if you want to learn about
lactic acid bacteria and how to treat
your cannabis plants with it
you can google lactic acid bacteria and
then powdery mildew and then there will
be the word Clackamas in there Clackamas
is a city in Oregon there's a guy named
Clackamas coot who is from that part of
Oregon who wrote an article about making
lactic acid bacteria to treat for
powdery mildew if you google it it
should not be too hard to find guys
something else I want to mention in
professional horticultural applications
and environments what is commonly used
for powdery mildew is a product called
potassium bicarbonate it's available in
several different forms from what I read
they say that it mixes up very much like
a baking soda in water and you apply
that to your plants as a foliar spray
and that disrupts the pH on the surface
of the leaf which will get rid
of your powdery mildew and it is a
horticultural standard it's what they
use in large greenhouses for large
production so potassium bicarbonate from
what I read it's like it comes in a very
powdery form that's like baking soda
they say it's available in other forms I
check that out maybe that's something
that'll help you out if you're in a
commercial grow I'm not sure if that
will be legal so make sure you check out
all of the laws I don't know where you
are I don't know the rules so everything
I say needs to be researched before you
apply it another thing that people are
gonna recommend for you for your powdery
mildew issue people are going to say to
hang a sulfur burner in the grow and run
the sulfur burner for an hour or 45
minutes every few hours or something
like that everyone's gonna have their
own recipe I highly advise against this
you guys I do not like a sulfur burner
there was a dispensary in Colorado I
will not call them out they were in
Denver they were a very very well known
dispensary they had a very well-known
breeder working with them who actually
left and started his own thing that
facility was having a powdery mildew
issue and their solution was to run a
sulfur burner the results were for about
six months every time you would shop at
that dispensary everything would have at
first it was a flavor of sulfur he would
smoke it he'd like why does this taste
weird and it was sulfur II once somebody
would say I think there's a sulphur
burner your brain would go yeah it
totally tastes like sulfur so it was
really strong at first and over a few
months it faded out but you could taste
it for a long time they've gotten rid of
the sulfur burner they've corrected
their problem now it doesn't happen but
that's why you don't run a sulfur burner
in there it will make your plants taste
like [ __ ]
so don't do this all four burner that's
not something I would recommend
something that you can do that may help
you I'm not sure if you're using mother
plants or if you're taking plants taking
cuts from your vegging plants or how
that works but when you were taking
clones
I recommend dunking them I cut my clone
from the mother plant I put them in a
cup with water and a small bit of
nutrients and then I carried that cup
filled with cuttings to another area
where they are trimmed up and then they
are dunked into a solution and then they
are dipped and then stuck into either
the cloner if I'm working at one
facility or they're put into plugs if
I'm at another facility or they're put
in a
at another facility just depends on
where I'm working and who I'm working
with what I got going on but after the
cut I like to dunk the freshly cut clone
and trimmed up you cut off the leaves
you trim off all the extra then I dunk
that right into something I will change
my eye product up sometimes I use vanish
sometimes I will use the what's it
called the big-time exterminator you
guys I wrote down BTE and I can always
forget that stands for a big-time
exterminator sometimes I'll mix up the
hydrogen peroxide just depends on what's
available and what I'm treating for what
I think may I may be at risk for but we
know that powdery mildew was the problem
here so mix up a little bit of hydrogen
peroxide in your water I just use a
five-gallon bucket I mean anywhere
between 30 and 70 mils of hydrogen
peroxide usually seems to work for me
cut the clone dunk that right into the
five gallon bucket of hydrogen peroxide
give it a nice hefty shake and then put
that into the dip and grow or the clone
X or whatever you were using wherever
the hell we are and then stick that
right into the the cloner whatever I'm
going into and then I know that I killed
all of the powdery mildew so that I've
got a fresh start so that that clone can
root and have a healthy start then as
soon as it roots and it gets put into
its first pot I'll spray it with
something and then every I'll spray it
once a week with something and then if I
see powdery mildew or here's a here's a
hint a little bit before powdery mildew
starts you will see the little tiny
bumps pop up the leaf may start to just
get a little bit bumpy I don't even know
how to it just looks like a little
pimple or a war or something funky
coming up on the leaf but it's real
small so if you start seeing that then
it's time to start treating for powdery
mildew extra-strong get out your UV
clean light get out your hydrogen
peroxide get out the PM wash the
big-time exterminator the lactic acid
bacteria the potassium bicarbonate
something like that get it out there
start treating those plants because
you're gonna see the powdery mildew but
if I see that that's when I start
stepping up my game going a little bit
harder one more thing I should mention
is the powdery mildew could be on your
clothes you're carrying it around from
the flower room to the bedroom to the
mother room to the clone room it's in
your air-conditioning ducts it's in your
HVAC system it is everywhere it needs to
be taken care of it needs to be treated
if you've got those silly ducts that
have the insulation inside of them tear
that [ __ ] out of there
that could be a multi-thousand dollar
job for your facility but all of that
insulation inside of there is harboring
harboring that was a hard word to say
the insulation is harboring powdery
mildew and it will eventually be a place
for bugs to hide out once one gets in
there just takes two and those bugs will
start a party it'll be disgusting so you
could have the powdery mildew one or
close make sure everybody's changing
clothes properly I bet you've got a
grower that has a private grow at home
and he's got powdery mildew also and as
soon as he starts getting rid of powdery
mildew you get it worse and then as soon
as your facility starts getting it
cleaned up he gets it worse and you guys
are just passing that [ __ ] back and
forth and it's never gonna go away
so start changing your clothes get some
dedicated clothes dedicated shoes a
dedicated hat if you've got long hair or
dreadlocks get it wrapped up get it in a
hat and get it covered up you guys I'm
always going and re tucking my dreads
because I try to keep everything covered
up
I don't want dragging my dreads long
around the grow think it's gross I need
to be picking up bugs or leaving a hair
in the flowers just just keep your
dreads and your hair covered up if
you've got a big man look beard or if
you've got a hipster beard cover that
[ __ ] up too I just try to be clean you
guys another thing I really want to
recommend I did work in a facility that
was riddled with powdery mildew I won't
call them out on a podcast most of my
friends and listeners know who the [ __ ]
I'm talking about the place was riddled
with powdery mildew they fired a grower
I took over I walked in and I said we've
got bugs and powdery mildew to start
with and they're like yes we do help us
I tried to get rid of it you guys but
being Emmy deregulated I understand the
struggle that my listener here has it
was a pain in the ass everybody in that
grow got sick because of the powdery
mildew the mildew is gone you guys it
took two or three crops two or three
crop cycles to get rid of it but the
powdery mildew was actually gone we got
rid of it in a hundred light facility
that p.m. was gone you could not see it
you could not smell it you could not
taste it it was cleaned up so they did
their job they got rid of it but
everybody kind of got like a scientist
sort of thing everybody showed different
symptoms but everybody could agree that
it was messing up their noses their
throat and their eye region so wear a
mask if you've got a ventilator or
respirator or even one of those just
shitty little paper Asian bird flu masks
just wear one of those when you're
working with a powdery mildew because
you don't want to get sick from it I
tried to deny that I was sick
from the powdery mildew but once it was
gone I felt better and I could tell that
my allergy problem and my throat thing
was happening because of that powdery
mildew that's what was doing it so
please take care of yourself if the
plants are bad powdery mildew E you have
to think about if you want to release
that product to the public because you
don't want to be responsible for making
people sick so that's a moral thing
you're gonna have to think about
yourself something that they do allow
here in Colorado they will let you blast
the powdery mildew buds the marijuana
Enforcement Division has decided that it
is safe to put powdery mildew buds and
trim into a tube and run butane over and
turn it in to Pho hash dabs shatter wax
it turns into distillate eventually it
gets put into edibles eventually so yeah
they're deeming it safe so if that's
what you want to do with it do that
that's the best I can recommend with it
but honestly if it's coated in powdered
mildew think about this my friend Doug
is getting old and Doug's got a lung
problem and when Doug smokes regular
cannabis he coughs what Doug smokes
cannabis that's got something on it he
coughs a lot and gets really sick Doug
is smoking because he's sick and trying
to prolong and save his life we do not
want to give Doug powdery mildews and
mycotoxins and funky [ __ ] for his lungs
to kill him more quickly
I love Doug I [ __ ] want him here
treat everybody like Doug okay everybody
that's getting cannabis is my friend
Doug in my mind we all have to take care
of all of our patients like they are
Doug alright Doug is a real dude but I
kind of exaggerated his story Doug's not
that sick you guys just wanted to use
him as an example because he's a good
dude all right I hope I've given you
some information that kind of teaches
you how to at least control and harness
and get rid of this powdery mildew I'm
not sure what you can do where you are
so you can spray any of these products
that you choose to spray you can D
foliate things that I fully recommend
you do are get the old air out the fresh
air in dehumidified do some filtration
also space out the plants a little bit
make sure they aren't touching each
other and then control temperature
swings you're in the Des
and you're putting a bunch of water
inside of a building you're making it
excuse me you're making a big Tupperware
dish and it's you're making a giant comb
dome is what you're doing in there so
you need to evacuate the humidity and
get that out of the room don't be afraid
to throw away some plants if they're
starting to get too bad I know that
sounds terrible in a commercial
production facility I've been there
before trust me I have dealt with what
you're dealing with some days it makes
you want to punch yourself straight in
the face but I did an episode a few
episodes back called stay positive and
if you didn't have powdery mildew you
wouldn't be getting so many hours [ __ ]
would be too easy wouldn't be a
challenge wouldn't be fun anymore so you
got to go through some struggles and
that way when those issues are gone it's
gonna be like you're [ __ ] cruising
and the coolest damn facility ever and
you'll appreciate it that's what I think
stay positive don't pull your hair out
don't put yourself in the face keep
growing and dude if you have any more
questions please send me an email if
anybody out there has any questions
about growing cannabis about smoking
cannabis about anything cannabis related
I would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I'm easy to get a hold of I'm trying to
catch up and answer all of the emails
and do episodes about all of them but I
honestly get so many that it's hard to
keep up but I'm getting to your email a
lot of people have asked for episodes
about beneficial insects and pesticide
manage our pest management and
identification of problems in the garden
I am working on that that's going to be
a long episode I may do it in multiple
parts I've got several pages written
already I'm still working on that one
I've got an episode coming up about
seasonal effectiveness disorder or
seasonal affective disorder since it has
been winter time here I want to talk a
little bit about that because I've got a
bunch of great stuff coming up a lot of
it has been listener inspired material
which I truly enjoy bringing to you
because I've been going for 28 minutes
I'm gonna wrap up this podcast I want to
thank everybody for listening big shout
out to my friends at handmade apparel
once again if you need t-shirts hoodies
stickers hat pins any kind of swag
printed up custom designs with super
high quality printing and high quality
clothing make sure you visit my friends
at handmade apparel dot biz I would love
it if you follow me on the social media
I am on Facebook it's girl from your
heart a podcast on Twitter it's at g f
YH podcast and on instagram you guys I
post so many photos to Instagram my
phone is way over loaded with
photography right now so
instead of deleting the pictures I just
go shoot a bunch of them to Instagram
about once every two hours or so
whenever I sit down and take a couple
dabs I try to shoot a new picture up to
Instagram while I edit this podcast and
listen back I'll shoot a couple pictures
to Instagram follow me on Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics I are i
underscore genetics it's my seed company
I am a seed breeder if you're aware of
that
I read genetics Colorado is me make sure
you check out our Instagram lots of
great high quality cannabis photography
you can see what I'm doing there once
again if you have a product you'd like
me to review or if you've got something
you'd like to say or if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast send me an email
grow from your heart at hotmail.com let
me remind you about patreon patreon com
is a service where you can go and you
can financially contribute to the
podcast I'm not trying to get rich I'm
not begging for money I'm just trying to
offset the cost of my web hosting so
that I can keep the podcast coming to
you for free this podcast will always be
free free freedom I'm simply asking
people to help me pay for my website so
that I don't have to pay for it out of
my pocket there are a few people that
are able to contribute
I truly appreciate it thank you if you
can't contribute I still appreciate you
I still love you thank you for listening
to the podcast if you can't contribute
financially one thing you can do to help
me out you can go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the growth from
your heart podcast find the review
section type in a comment let me know
what you think about the show and I will
read your review on a future episode so
far everybody has given me a five star
review give me as many stars as you feel
like I deserve and I will truly
appreciate it you guys that's all I've
got for you this week I was lucky enough
to get to see Maddie and Spence for a
couple of minutes at the can of candy in
the other day they came to Colorado to
visit they invited me up I got to hang
out take some dad to take a picture with
Maddie I sure did miss those guys so big
shout out to Maddie and Spence and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
if my words did glow with the cooler
sunshine and my tunes were played on the
strong would you give my voice
[Music]
[Applause]
see would you hold it as your own it's a
hand-me-down
[Music]
broken perhaps
[Applause]
I don't know don't really get
[Music]
[Applause]
when there is no Botox to reach out your
if you turn up be empty if you come is
full
maybe
No
years of mouth
[Music]
was not me but handsome man
between
[Music]
you go
that is for your steps alone
[Music]
with
No
[Music]
you
should stand
[Music]
[Applause]