yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 178 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to create a new
grower if you're professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots bank letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew ladies and gentlemen
this isn't going to be a long episode
I'm just coming in for a quickie
you're gonna release this on a Thursday
you're very welcome for a Thursday bonus
episode before I get to the main topic I
want to do a little bit of bragging I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friends at organic organic is a medical
marijuana dispensary in the state of New
Mexico they are located in Albuquerque
if you are in Albuquerque or a New
Mexico medical marijuana patient be sure
to visit my friends at argh antica
because I bred a strain called a rise
arise is golden go to Daybreaker
these guys have argh antica got some
seeds and they grew the arise and the
arise has been testing consistently in
the high 20s to low 30s their most
recent tests tested at 32 percent THC
was thirty five point eight four percent
THC a and thirty two percent THC it was
tested by my friends at steep hill lab
congratulations and big shadow and much
thanks and much love to everybody at
organic ah shoutout to everybody
good job you guys that's [ __ ] amazing
because that means I've got a strain
currently I hold the highest THC a test
at steep hill labs with the arize I did
not grow it but I bred it means a lot to
me it means there's a lot of potential
in the arise and a lot of potential in
the strains I crossed with
via Rhys mail alright so big shots
everybody there also shout out to my
friends at handmade apparel that's right
if you need some t-shirts hoodies any
sort of clothing printed I highly
recommend our friends at handmade
apparel
that's right handmade apparel dot biz
they are members of the cannabis
community they are smokers they are
dabbers they were putting together a
really cool event right now it is the
borrowed Derby it will feature dinner
and auction and bar oh I cannot wait to
see how it goes I'm really proud of my
friends at handmade apparel if you need
something printed if you need stickers
made if you need hat pins made please
contact my friends at handmade apparel
dot biz if you were my facebook friend
they are on my facebook it's handmade or
Adam hand check those guys out truly
appreciate them they do great work for
the community they printed my girl from
your heart hoodies they look super sweet
they printed my I read genetics t-shirts
they look super sweet they have printed
they printed the secret stash t-shirts
they printed my hat pins you guys these
guys have put in a lot of work for us
and I will continue to use them because
I support and respect that much love to
our friends at handmade apparel all
right if I want to keep this episode
short I need to quit rambling I need to
quit bragging let's move into the main
topic of this podcast because this
podcast is about something called
seasonal affective disorder also known
as sad also known as winter depression I
want to talk about winter depression and
feeling sad and ways that some cannabis
may help us out with this um why do I
want to come up with a podcast about
SADS because lately I have felt this
funk in my head I blending it on this
whether I'm a California person I'm from
Southern California I grew up right near
the beach boy oh yeah that was [ __ ]
stupid right but it's okay because I
meant it I'm seriously from the beach I
grew up 20 minutes from the beach I used
to go to Bolsa Chica Beach I used to go
to Huntington Beach I used to go to Seal
Beach I used to be all over the beach
bro lifeguard stand 23 at Bolsa Chica
beach used to be the spot it's where the
waves are ripping it's where the kids
could go do whatever we want swear the I
was a young kid is where the older kids
can go smoke some dope
even older kids would drink beer nobody
gave a [ __ ] what we did I'm a beach kid
I miss that constant sunshine I miss
just that vibe I live in Colorado now in
about October November ish it gets
[ __ ] cold and they gets really dark
the days get really
sure it feels like I feel like the days
didn't get as short in California when
the winter comes the day's feel shorter
in Colorado that just could be maybe
being older or not being a kid but it's
[ __ ] with my head you guys these dark
cold winter months you can't go outside
and do what you'd normally do I it's a
little slower you got to get up early
for work you got a defrost the car joe
rogan put it best joe rogan said there
are states that are called he calls them
the [ __ ] states because when you get in
your car to go to work in the morning
you spend three or four minutes sitting
there going [ __ ] [ __ ] cuz you're so cold
your body can't do anything stomach
muscles tighten up your brain starts
twitching your neck gets all stiff and
you just gotta wait for the car to
defrost and so that you could drive to
work that [ __ ] sucks snow drives me
crazy I don't like the cold I don't like
the snow it feels to make me it seems to
feel like it makes me weak and slowed
down it makes my bones and muscles hurt
I'm dealing with it I'm not enjoying the
winter I've got a lot of good friends I
do a lot of cool [ __ ] so don't let it
slow me down but I do feel it in the
back of my head gone bro something sucks
and it's just this seasonal
effectiveness disorder I want to talk
about a couple things that winter
depression comes along with and then
we'll move into the cannabis part of
this I did a little research it says it
usually lasts from fall to spring ish so
if you're feeling a little funky from
fall to spring this is probably why
especially if you live in these winter
colder climates some symptoms of this
seasonal affective disorder include
depression just basic depression it's
not your classic depression if you are
feeling like hurting yourself or
somebody else or if you've got problems
like that if you're thinking about
starting to drink alcohol or take pills
or hurt yourself or cut yourself or
break something or be an [ __ ] to
people please get some help ah nobody's
gonna judge you
nobody's gonna hate you we're gonna love
you we're gonna treat you right if you
want to hurt yourself if you want to
kill yourself please call me if I can
send me a Facebook message
we'll talk call a suicide prevention
hotline call somebody I don't we
probably don't know each other too
personally if you're embarrassed to call
somebody hit me up I don't know you
I won't broadcast your business we'll
talk about why you won't hurt yourself
and we'll fix that [ __ ] that doesn't
need to happen so if you're really
depressed please get some help but if
you think you've got some winter
seasonal depression we can help you with
some cannabis suggestions another
symptom here would be some laziness just
low-energy
lethargy no desire to get out of
you just want to lay around put some
blankets over you maybe plan your phone
and not do a damn thing losing interest
in life that's sort of a a an effect of
the winter depression here a lot of
people have no desire to eat when this
winter depression comes on but oddly
enough the internet says that people
will seek foods like carbohydrates and
such during the winter which is odd for
me because I always like carbs I like
pizza and pasta and [ __ ] but it says
that you're gonna seek out carbohydrate
type salty foods if you were
experiencing seasonal effectiveness
disorder it says you're gonna be
agitated and irritable which I am there
that's partly how I'm noticing this I'm
partly I feel more tired I feel grouchy
I feel [ __ ] annoyed and I'm pretty
sure that it's mostly just this seasonal
affective disorder another thing that
the internet said that I totally relate
to and this is kind of what inspired me
to want to talk about this because it's
part of where we are in this new
generation this new part of life they
said that this seasonal effectiveness
disorder comes with panic attacks and I
think there's a reason for these panic
attacks that we're getting now as humans
we are too attached to our computers and
our devices and as humans we have become
completely lazy and complacent in the
winter I think that there's something
inside of me that gives me this trigger
to go hunt and gather food and build a
fire so that I can keep the family warm
through the winter but now we all have
jobs that don't require most of us have
jobs that don't require that sort of
stuff I work in a grow up but a grow at
6:00 in the morning I do grow stuff I
leave there at 6 p.m. I come home I play
on my computer I live in a house I Drive
a car my food all comes from a store I
think that as humans we were supposed to
we were designed and built to be out
there hunting our food we should be I
should be out there chasing down deer or
Buffalo and killing that [ __ ] and
dragging it in and then skinning it and
cleaning yes I am a vegetarian and I'm
saying this this is part of why I think
humans are [ __ ] up because we're not
doing this there's something primal in
us that makes us supposed to do that and
in the winter that primal instinct to
survive becomes even stronger be
it's harder to survive and in the
environment where I am it's even harder
because it snows I'm not saying that I'm
in the worst conditions but I mean we
get snow and it's [ __ ] cold and if
you don't have shelter and food and
warmth you will die out there
so our inside our instinct our natural
design is to be hunting and gathering
and you're supposed to be using energy
and adrenaline and that anger that you
feel you wouldn't feel that if you were
throwing a spear at another animal so
that you could survive you wouldn't have
time to be angry you wouldn't have time
to be depressed you'd be letting out all
that anger through adrenaline through
hiking through stalking an animal
through or maybe through gardening if
you were a vegetarian back in the
whatever times I'm talking about maybe
you had to spend all of that energy in
the garden and we're not doing that [ __ ]
anymore we're sitting on computers and
we're playing video games and we're
driving up to a window to get our food I
think a lot of that is kind of what's
causing the winter depression for a lot
of the males I'm not sure if this
affects women the same way I'm not
trying to be sexist I just know it's a
testosterone thing maybe women want to
be hunters and gatherers also maybe
women suffer the seasonal effectiveness
disorder for the same reasons but
differently I'm not sure this part is my
opinion the panic attacks and the
hunting rent is all my my own opinion
here but I think we should be using our
energy and I'm gonna start talking about
now about things that we can do to help
ourselves with this seasonal
effectiveness disorder I already talked
about being active ah exercise get out
there and do something I hypothetically
saying I feel like we should be hunting
we should be chasing down an elk or a
deer and then we got to kill it with
either spear or a bow and arrow a
recurve bow and you got to go drag that
[ __ ] back to camp and then you got to
skin it you got to get everything out
then fire I think being around a fire
makes me feel really good like a
campfire something inside of a campfire
really fixes me especially in this cold
weather so get out there and be active
build the campfire go camping go hunting
if you're that type of person be
physical something I can really
recommend to get you out of a seasonal
affective disorder kind of a funk is
join some sort of organized martial art
or fighting be physical use your body I
think a lot
what's causing this is pent up body
energy from the winter so get out there
and use your body go join a Brazilian
jiu-jitsu class go join a martial arts
class go be a wrestler if you're not
into that go do some yoga just use your
body use some energy I think it'll
really help you out so now let's start
talking about before I get to smoking
cannabis I wanna say go for a drive
should put on some music and go for a
drive that always fixes my head when I'm
a little bit funky ah put on your
favorite music some reggae whatever
you're into if you're into some metal
put on some metal turn it up a little
bit too lime just go for a drive that'll
fix your head but I wanted to say go for
a drive before I start talking about
consuming cannabis because Michael flip
out if I say smoke a joint go for a
drive it'll make you feel better so now
let's talk about other things
cannabis this is how cannabis can truly
help with the seasonal effectiveness
disorder
I think that's smoking sativa dominant
cannabis either flowers or dabs are
going to help fix your mood I've got a
short list of strains here that I have
experimented with personally that I have
found to help uplift my mood and not
make me too anxious or jittery and still
allow me to function and get my job done
and still be like a normal person would
still have a nice buzz and nobody could
tell how high I am so on this list
number one on this list is Jilly bean
Jilly bean has always put me in a good
mood it's uplifting it makes me walk
with a nice little pep in my step it
puts a grin on my face Jilly bean will
wipe out any anxiety depression it'll
calm me down and put you in a good mood
the next one on that list is tangi yes a
lot of people are gonna say Jilly bean
and tangi are the same thing they're
very similar strains they have very
similar qualities they taste very
similarly they grow similarly I think
they both put a smile on my face
the next strain on my list is tangerine
haze from soma this is actually sohma's
New York City Diesel but there is a
phenotype that tastes very tangerine and
orange II that tangerine haze is always
been I used to call it my morning
breakfast smoke I'd be like I need my
morning oranges and I would smoke some
Selma's tangerine haze or his New York
City Diesel known as tangerine haze so
there's a group back in the day known as
the devil's harvest crew and they grew a
bunch of stuff and they found a very
orangey phenotype
very orangey phenotype of the New York
City sour sohma's diesel and they pass
that around and call the tangerine haze
that's where it got the name and I found
the same phenotype out of a pack and I
grew it and I loved it and it always
used to put a smile on my face so I
think those top three that I listed are
very orangie very citrusy very sativa
yet very light strains when you smoke
them when I smoke them I don't get super
high I can't get high as [ __ ] off of
either of those three strains but I can
catch a really killer smiley buzz so
something in that orange chirp is really
helping you fix your mood the next green
on my list you guys is Cindy 99 shout
out to the Brothers Grimm seed company
Cindy 99 has always given me a nice
smiley cerebral uplifting buzz it's just
a mood changer it gives you a little
shift I like it it's easy to grow I
think it's available again in seed form
from our friends at Brothers Grimm you
can possibly pick that up at the dank
team.com I'm another one that's always
uplifting and puts me in a good mood but
is sometimes too much for some people
this one may give you a little panicky
if you get a little jittery in too much
sativa this may be a little too much but
the jack herer
has always been a good strain for me it
changes my mood it gives me energy
it keeps me upbeat and it makes me
social but it can drive your head a
little crazy
if you're somebody that gets too
talkative when you smoke too much
cannabis Jack may not be the cross for
you if you need to get social if you're
going somewhere and you're like I gotta
go talk to people maybe some Jack will
be the one for you another strain that
is always uplifting and puts people in a
good mood and you guys are gonna be
surprised that I say this because I've
made plenty of jokes about it but blue
dream blue dream is always a good strain
for putting you in a good mood for
changing your vibe it's not one of those
strains that makes you like want to curl
up into a ball when you get to high
because I've seen people want to do that
blue dream is you can't get too high
from blue dream and it's a nice mellow
buzz that's why I make fun of blue dream
I call it stripper weed because it's
that's how high strippers want to get
strippers don't get [ __ ] high as [ __ ]
like I do strippers just want to get a
little buzz you know spend on the pole
I'm just joking but that's why I call it
stripper weed so basically any kind of a
haze cross you guys most of what I've
mentioned has a haze in it also Jack the
Ripper Jack Herer and Jack the Ripper
have a lot of the same pair
Jack the Ripper is a cross of Jack Herer
I strongly recommend some Jack the
Ripper but like I said about the Herer
it could be a bit much for you you guys
it could make some people's head spin if
you're not an experienced smoker so if
you're trying to beat seasonal
effectiveness disorder and you are able
to take a strong heavy sativa dose and
you like to get kind of whirlwind high
grab yourself some Jack the Ripper it's
available at a lot of dispensaries it's
a great tasting cannabis it has a great
high to it and it's usually pretty easy
to find because sub cool is a very
popular breeder
since we're talking about sub cool I'm
gonna mention vortex I used to get some
vortex
it was wax but it was kind of there was
a different texture of wax from a
dispensary in Denver and I loved the
high from it it made me it gave me
tunnel vision high to where I couldn't
pay attention to anything except what
was right in front of me but it also put
this stupidest smile on my face I really
love the way that vortex made me feel
again vortex if you were not an
experienced vortex made my heart race it
made my heart was going but I loved it
there's something about being too high
like that that I really really enjoy um
another strain that is good for the
seasonal affective disorder is the lemon
Jeffrey that's a golden goat cross -
it's actually lemon skunk crossed a
golden goat I bred that one it is one of
my favorites to smoke it has been tested
in the 30% range for THC it is
definitely a head changer something
about the orange and lemon Terps the
limonene Terps really create like a good
mood a good vibe so I think things that
smell like oranges smell like fruit
smell like lemons are usually going to
be uplifting positive vibe kind of
strains I think most of the haze crosses
and the tangi and jellybean crosses are
usually going to be good to put you into
a good mood so those are strains that I
can recommend for smoking if they are
available where you are
if smoking isn't something for you and
if you're not getting the desired effect
from smoking edibles may be a better
route to go body chemistry is all
different so if you're trying to fight
depression or seasonal affective
depression maybe you need high THC maybe
you need CBD I would kind of stay a
away from the indicas what happens to me
and I have to go in history because now
I smoke so much and my tolerance is so
high and I'm older and I'm more used to
being high out of my mind when I was
younger and was new at cannabis when I
would smoke sativas I would get that
real psychedelic high and get talkative
sort of like I am now I'm just [ __ ]
rambling and talking about everything
but then when I would smoke indicas I
would go in my head and get quiet and
that's when you just sit in a chair and
you start thinking too much and I would
kind of sometimes you could drive
yourself crazy thinking too much and
when you're already in the seasonal
effectiveness disorder kind of head
state smoking an indica that's gonna put
you into your own head and make you
think may [ __ ] you up a little more than
you need it may cause more depression it
may cause self-doubt it may cause
confusion it may not be the thing that
you need so I would go for some sativa
edibles or CV CBD edibles but I would
definitely stay away from the indica
dominant stuff you guys I think the most
reliable cure for seasonal affective
disorder is to smoke a joint and go for
a hike find a nice safe hiking spot roll
yourself up a nice joint of your
favorite strain either the chili bean or
some lemon Jeffrey or whatever you can
find that fits in the list that I talked
about it's yourself a nice sativa joint
roll it up take one of your best friends
with you take your dog with you get a
bottle of water go for a walk
smoke a joint and fix your head and keep
in mind you guys it's okay to feel this
way everybody's gonna deal with some
[ __ ] in their life it's all right to
feel kind of funky once in a while just
don't be a dick try to deal with it
properly and pull yourself through it
hopefully when the spring comes he'll
start cheering up again hopefully by the
time 420 rolls around you'll be in a
good mood and then summer is coming back
and then it's time to get in a good mood
again hopefully you can figure it out
not go through it again next year are
you guys that was my quick talk on
seasonal effectiveness disorder I hope I
was helpful I hope I could guide you in
the right way to select cannabis to keep
you in a good mood hey even if you're
not suffering through some seasonal
depression all of these strains will
probably put a smile on your face keep
you social if you have to go to lunch
with somebody don't really care to go to
lunch with if you've got to do a chore
you don't really give a [ __ ] to do try
smoking one of these strains and just
might put you in a better mood for doing
it
alright you guys want to thank everybody
for listening to his short podcast this
was right at 20 minutes I appreciate you
for joining me
a thursday bonus episode ladies and
gentlemen if you have any topics you'd
like me to talk about on the show send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at a hotmail.com
i would love to hear from you I would
also appreciate it if you follow me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast I want to
send a huge shout out to my friend beau
Nellis and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
it's
[Applause]
[Music]