welcome back cannabis community is time
for episode number 179 of the girl from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated Dadar if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always need to send a huge
thank-you shoutouts when friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat the entire mystic
roots crew yeah hope you guys are
joining me on a smoke session right now
I just got done smoking some huge dabs
of cascade shatter the Cascade was grown
by me
the extraction was done by our friend
the barefoot grower and I am smoking
through my hitman hammerhead rig with a
brand new quartz banger from our friends
at elevate glass big shout out to our
friends at elevate I stopped by elevate
today I had to replace a few nails and
carb caps and such went in there
thinking I was gonna buy two things and
I walked out there with a whole bag of
goodies nice work you guys
took all my money today big shout outs
my friends at elevate glass at 517 South
day home go visit them if you need a new
rig if you need a carbon cap if you need
a male you need an e nail and all kinds
of great new [ __ ] in there today then an
email that you can operate with your
iPhone you can change the lighting
scheme it had a light of every color on
top of it and you can open up this app
on your phone and you can make that
thing look like a damn light show at a
Phish concert it's pretty awesome so
check us were friends at elevate go
check them out 517 South Bay home in
Colorado Springs also since we're doing
shout outs huge shoutouts my friends at
handmade apparel you guys I'm worrying
this girl from your heart podcast hoodie
and I am nice and warm it is super cold
here in Colorado but I am not shivering
at all these hoodies look great if you
need some artwork done if you need
shirts if you need hoodies if you need
stickers if you need hat pins
I highly recommend my friends at
handmade apparel that's right handmade
apparel dot biz for all your custom
printing needs check them
let them know that you listen to the
girl from your heart a podcast until
them Rasta Jeff sent you
they will take very good care of you
getting all of your printing work done
also since we're doing shoutouts holy
crap you guys I've been talking about
patreon for the past few weeks on the
podcast I've got a patreon account
let me explain patreon really quickly
patreon is a website where people can go
and they can sign up to financially
contribute to the podcast you sign up
you put in your credit card info and
once a month it will pay me the amount
that you have decided to give me or
donate to me or contribute to me
yesterday I got an email somebody has
decided that every month they are going
to contribute $10 to the girl from your
heart podcast one person is throwing
down $10 every month that is awesome
huge shout-out to that person I don't
know if you want your name said on the
show so I'm not gonna call you out if
you'd like your name said on the show
let me know I will certainly say it for
you because I appreciate that huge shout
out to everybody that has thrown down a
patreon contribution those are all
through on the 1st of the month I get
them around to the 3rd in to my PayPal
account
I truly appreciate that you guys I'm not
trying to get rich off the podcast like
I've said many times I'm using the
patreon contributions to cover the cost
of my website and it will also replace
some recording equipment my SD card for
my zoom h6 took a [ __ ] so I will use the
funds to replace that we can do more
podcasts on the road I buy these little
microphone covers I'm gonna rub it sort
of foam microphone cover here I buy a
lot of those because I try to give a
fresh foamy cover when the guests come
over I try to have a fresh foam cover on
there because people coffin to it and
people rub their faces on it on accident
cuz they forget the mics there and they
bump into it like that so I spend the
money on these little foam covers and
stuff like that eventually I'm gonna
need a new MacBook I feel this one's
starting to slow down and glitch out so
that's where that funding will go you
guys so huge thank you those people that
contributed to patreon I truly
appreciate it the person that is just
threw down $10 per month that is super
amazing thank you if you want more
information on patreon go to
patreon.com/crashcourse now there we go
let's get down to business you guys
today we are going to talk about proper
mixing and watering technique somebody
was asking
me questions about mixing their
nutrients and mixing their water and
then I got a tweet about mixing
nutrients in mixing water and I thought
this would be a great episode to do I
also have a friend starting a brand new
hydro setup and he needed some advice
since I was going to talk about it I
figured let's put a microphone in front
of my face and do it properly so today's
podcast is going to be about properly
mixing your nutrients and then we're
gonna talk a little bit about properly
watering your plants all right you guys
before I get too far into this I want to
say that this advice should work for
small gardens large Gardens this should
work for soil lists and soil gardens and
this also should work for hydro gardens
of course there will be some adjusting
to be done for different applications
but most of this will apply to most
Gardens if you're running a TLO or a
no-till or a living soil this probably
won't work for you for you know till and
TLO guys will get frosty organics back
we'll get bare foot back and we'll do
another show about that organic stuff
but for now we're gonna talk about
mixing with bottles and such so my first
point will be clean water good water is
very important reverse osmosis water RO
water is ideal I understand that not
everybody can get an RO machine and
install it in their bathroom or in their
kitchen for their home grow I do get it
if you can't do RO water tap water is
okay if you're using tap water I would
recommend that you go to either the pet
store like the fish tank store or either
the hydroponic store and get yourself an
aquarium air pump and what this is is a
pump that sits outside of the water it
does not go in the water don't put it in
the water it will kill it you might
electrocute yourself it'll be bad don't
do that so it's a pump that goes outside
of the water and it's got a wine that
runs to an airstone and you'll need to
buy some clear wine some flex hose or
some clear line they'll have the right
size line sitting right next to the pump
don't worry and then you'll need air
stones to put in the bottom of your
reservoir so you'll fill up your
container you put the aquarium air pump
next to it it's a good idea to have the
aquarium air pump higher than your water
because if the power does go out you
don't want water siphoning down the line
and coming out at the other end that has
happened before so keep the pump higher
than the water get a get it on a shelf
don't put it on the ground cuz it can
work as a siphon if the power goes out
so you've got your filled container
you've got your aquarium air pump
you've got your plastic line going to
some air stones those air stones go in
the bottom of that container that's
filled with water and you plug it in and
it simply bubbles I turn it up all the
way it might get kind of light I'll just
like just turn it up it'll bubble and
it'll bubble bubble bubble that chlorine
out of your water and hopefully within
24 to 48 hours you'll get rid of most of
that chlorine now there are some things
that can only be taken out by reverse
osmosis but honestly if you are running
a home grow and your grow is not large
enough to where you've got extra money
to invest in an RO machine you're
probably going to be ok using tap water
you guys it's not that major of a deal
one thing I should mention is if you're
using tap water you can use less cal-mag
than if you're using reverse osmosis
water the tap water already has plenty
of calcium in it so you can reduce that
if you're using RO you need to use the
recommended amount or pretty close to it
that's the major difference so you
should be okay if you can't use reverse
osmosis water is what I'm getting at all
right now let's talk about the
temperature of your water it's very
important that when you're mixing your
nutrients you have your water between 65
and 75 degrees that's best for your pH
and for your nutrients if you're going
hydro I can say that if you go anywhere
above 70 you do kind of encourage algae
growth so if you're going hydro try to
keep your water around 70 degrees if
you're going soil soilless mix 65 to 75
works seventy is about ideal 65 is a
little low I would never go lower than
65 if you water your plants with water
that's cooler than 65 they will start to
make this claw-like shape and the leaves
and they will stop growing they
basically freeze they chill out they
don't do [ __ ] you don't like sticking
your feet or your hands in cold water so
don't do that to your plants that's my
recommendation um if you need to get the
if the water is coming out of your
spigot or your spout wherever your water
is coming from if the source is too warm
or too cold for example right now in
Colorado it has been ridiculously cold
it was 17 degrees the other day when I
went to work at 7 in the morning we
filled the containers with water
the RO machine and that water was 62
degrees there was no chance I was gonna
feed that water to the plants so we use
bucket heaters to heat the water if it's
too cold you can use chillers if you're
not looking to invest money and items to
keep your water at the right temperature
you can use the lights in your grow room
if you are filling your reservoir and
putting your bubblers in there you can
move that to the grow room you may deal
with a little bit more humidity but the
grow lights and that grow room will get
your water to the correct temperature it
may take a little while but that will
get it to the right temperature this may
also have the opposite effect if you're
running a hydro grow and you've got the
hydro reservoir in the room perhaps
you're running a flood and drain table
and the reservoir is underneath the
table maybe the room is heating up the
water too much and that's when you're
gonna need a chiller I actually realized
that I said something wrong a couple of
minutes ago if your water is too cold
you need a bucket heater and if your
water is too warm that's when you need a
chiller I realized as I was saying it
that I said that backwards so we have
covered the basics of getting your water
to the appropriate temperature now it's
time to talk about measuring and mixing
your nutrients into your water so the
first thing you need for this is a clean
and accurate measuring device maybe you
have some measuring cups I like the shot
glass and the beer glass looking style
cups they're really easy to clean the
downfall with them is they're a glass if
you're clumsy like me it may be better
for you to get the plastic style there
are a lot of options get something with
milliliters with tablespoons and
teaspoons with ounces because each brand
of nutrients is going to ask for
different stuff I like brands that go by
milliliters milliliters per gallon is my
favorite but each brand does their own
thing so you'll need a measuring cup or
a measuring device if you're using dry
nutrients like veg bloom you may need a
scale I recommend that you have a pH
meter a ppm meter and possibly an EC
meter and a thermometer I can highly
recommend the blue lab combo meter it's
got all of the above on there it's got
the ppm the EC the pH and a thermometer
all in one unit I really love the device
it's a little expensive one thing that I
can recommend if you with any pH meter
keep the probe wet seal it up somehow
with some pH 7 solution in there and
keep that probe wet as long as you can
because that will keep it alive they say
about pH probes if it dries it dies so
keep that [ __ ] wet and also calibrate
your equipment frequently at least once
a month if you're working with it a lot
do it once a week but at least once a
month if the big grow if I'm working in
a big grow you guys you know I bounce
around from large grow to large grow if
it's up to me when I'm using those pH
meters about once every two weeks I
catch myself just going to some solution
you dump the pH solution into a
container there's one that's four and
then one that's probably seven or ten
and just check up and see and if they
don't come out perfectly accurate take a
minute and fix the pH meter it can't
take that long maybe five maybe 10
minutes at the absolute most if it's
frustrating give me a hard time
it'll get quicker so just adjust the
calibration on your pH meter that's
super important sorry I went off on a
rant there so you're going to need a
bucket or a reservoir with a clearly
marked measurement area either like a
reservoir from the hydro shop that is
already a predetermined volume or what I
like to use is the I think they're
thirty two and fifty five-gallon
Rubbermaid trash cans by the trashcan at
Lowe's and I also get the little wheels
that go underneath it so that you can
roll that sucker around then I will get
a five-gallon bucket or one of those
5-gallon like the deep rock water
bottles or whatever brand water bottle
the five-gallon kind that gets delivered
I'll go buy one of those and I will use
it to measure out five gallons and I'll
mark it on the inside and the outside of
my trash can and then I'll measure to
ten gallons and mark it on the inside
and outside of my trash can and then
I'll do 15 and I'll do it in increments
of five all the way up to 25 or 30 or 50
or however big my container is so that
way I can see 5 10 15 or however many
gallons I've got and I can be accurate
that's important to me so you need a
clean marked container that you could
put water in I may need to be movable
you may need to get it from your water
to your gross so think about wheels
think about
you're gonna carry it most of you guys
are probably just gonna be mixing in a
five-gallon bucket
I like the Lowe's bucket Home Depot
bucket keep it simple keep it affordable
if you want to buy one of those fancy
reservoirs from the gross store go for
it be my guest
it looks great looks weird in pictures
and it's already marked for the the
volume just keep in mind as soon as you
pull up to the house and carry that
thing in the house everybody knows you
grow weed now all right so you've got a
chosen reservoir a chosen container one
thing I should mention is that you need
to clean this occasionally I would clean
it probably every use if you can if it's
a big trash can I understand that's kind
of a pain in the ass if you don't have a
place to rinse it out and hose it out
try to get to it as frequently as you
can you'll see some biofilm buildup on
it it'll get funky that will start to
mess with your EC your ppm and your pH
clean your [ __ ] it only takes a few
extra minutes just clean stuff up take
it out it's a try if is a trash can you
could probably sneak it out to the
backyard and hose it out people won't
wander too much what's going on if
you've got that reservoir from the hydro
store everyone's like oh he's cleaning
his weed reservoir so that's when you
might want to think about what you're
gonna buy hosing out a five-gallon
bucket is really easy you can do that in
the bathtub you do that the shower so
just think about cleaning your container
do that frequently please clean
everything very frequently all right so
you've got a clean container now the
next step is to fill it up you're there
using your RO water or your tap water
fill your container fill it up - if you
need 15 gallons if you need 20 gallons
fill it to where you need it to that
gallon amount if you're using a five
gallon bucket fill it up to the five
gallon point in a five-gallon bucket
there will be some extra space you will
not fill it all the way to the top
there's probably like an inch or two of
extra space and there may be three
inches of extra space don't fill it all
the way to the top if you're making a
reservoir try to have a little extra
room in your reservoir as well we're
gonna talk about why here in just a
couple of seconds so you fill up your
container and you check the temperature
the first thing I would do is check the
temperature if the temperature is too
high or too low we're gonna use the
proper tool either the bucket heater or
maybe an aquarium heater or a chiller or
we're gonna use the heat from the grow
room or we're gonna use whatever however
you got to do it get that water to the
appropriate temperature
you're using tap water you may have
wanted to fill this up 24 to 48 hours in
advance so that you can start bubbling
it and then you can also get your
temperature correction device in there
at that time so that when it comes time
to mix the nutrients you're already at
the right temperature so if you're
running a commercial grow before you
leave tonight fill up your containers
with water put your chillers or your
bucket heaters in there and let them run
for a little while
set them on a timer maybe to click on
three hours before you come in in the
morning that [ __ ] might start getting
right it'll be correct by the time you
get there I think I had you guys
thinking ahead and growing is very
important so fill your container get the
temperature of that water correct now
it's time to mix up your nutrients now
it's when you need that clean mixing
container that clean measuring device so
when you're mixing be accurate you guys
if the bottle says okay this is a side
rant if the bottle says 50 mils per
gallon you can probably get away with 25
to 30 mils per gallon but whatever you
decide to mix be accurate if you wrote
down that your mix is 30 milliliters put
30 milliliters in that bucket don't do
29 don't do 32 be as accurate as you can
and your plants will love you you will
like it you'll be able to take better
notes you'll be able to correct things
in the future if you see problems so
when you're mixing your nutrients be as
accurate as you possibly can also never
mix your bottled nutrients together
without mixing them into a large
container of water those nutrients are
in separate bottles for a reason it's
not just because they want to sell you
two bottles there are elements in each
bottle that if they were sold together
would bind and it would deactivate
basically the ingredients that are in
each bottle so they keep them separate
and when you pour bottle a into this
much water it dilutes it strong enough
to where when you pour a bottle B into
that much water they will not create a
chemical bond and it will not disrupt
your solution so never mix your
nutrients together without plenty of
water in the container now let's move
into actually doing the mix the actual
mix of the nutrients making the soup
something I should talk about is wear
gloves put on some nitrile gloves some
rubber glue
of some hand protection some of the
things you're gonna be touching pH down
is bad for your skin my skin reacts
funky to cal-mag from some brands of cow
bag my skin will get splotchy if I touch
it a lot of the things that we play with
in the grow are not really good for our
skin so I recommend that when you walk
into the grow you're just wearing rubber
gloves all the time have some gloves the
Black Knight trials are my favorite they
fit the best of the shape the best shape
they don't make my hands smell super
funky that's what I would recommend so
wear gloves also when you're mixing
nutrients you guys wear eye protection
you might feel nerdy who cares you're
not in there to be stylish nobody's
looking at you wear some sort of
protective eyewear if it's those goggles
the science lab goggles that's probably
what I would recommend because I have
heard a story of a friend who actually
listens to this podcast he was mixing
nutrients in his private grow and he
splashed maybe one drop of pH down in
his eye and he had to pull his phone out
of his pocket and he had to use Siri to
call 911 for himself because he could
not see he went into full panic mode
because it hurts so bad and he had to
call the police and the paramedics to
come to his grow to rescue him because
he got products in his eye so you guys
wear eye protection
you only get one set of eyes you don't
want to [ __ ] him up be very careful in
the grow please with your eyes with your
fingers with your hands we're gonna talk
about grow room safety in another
episode that's a really good idea so put
on some nitrile gloves put on some eye
protection and then grab your clean and
trusty measuring device and we're gonna
talk about actually mixing nutrients now
I asked our Facebook friends and my
Instagram friends for guidance on this
and 9 out of 10 people said makes your
potassium silicates first so if you're
using some sort of potassium silicon
product if you're using botanic air it's
just called potassium silicon if you
were using Oh sand 90 is that oh so
ninety or twenty-eight whichever Ossa
products you're using if you're using
OSA for potassium silicates everybody
says to put that in first so potassium
silicates first stir that for a few
minutes get it emulsify that's the word
I'm looking for get it fully emulsified
into your water if you can see it in
there you need to stir longer after the
potassium silicates everybody recommends
that you add calmac and in the
recommended or appropriate amount of Cal
mag stir again and then after that if
you're using micro that's when you would
add in your micro if you're not using
micro you might want to read about it
maybe your nutrient line has something
else that is covering the micro check
and see what you're missing
after that everybody would recommend
that you use your base nutrients if
you're using a brand that only has one
bottle of Base nutrients add in your
base nutrients at the appropriate amount
if you're using something like advanced
nutrients that has an A and a B you
would definitely do a first give it a
little stir then put in B and give it a
little stir again this is all about
chemical bonds we're doing things in
this order so that things do not bond in
specific ways so mix in your potassium
silicon your cal-mag your micro your
base your a and B if you have a two part
and that was when you would add in any
other additives that you've got if
you're adding a bloom booster if you're
adding any sweeteners or Bud hardeners
those would all get mixed in last now
something that somebody recommended to
me and I checked on this and it makes
sense
stir counterclockwise again this is all
about bonding of certain molecules so I
know it sounds crazy you guys we do
research on that if you'd like to
stirring your solution counterclockwise
will have a difference in bonding of
molecules in your solution if you're
interested read about that it's very
interesting alright so we've got all of
our products stirred into our water it
has all been stirred counterclockwise
it's all at the appropriate temperature
it's hanging out for a couple of seconds
getting all mixed in together now it's
time to check the ppm s why do we want
to check the PPM s the particles per
million tells us how much stuff is in
our water and if you feed your plants
too much stuff they're gonna choke
they're gonna get nutrient lock out
they're gonna get burnt they're gonna
look funky so we want to make sure that
there's not too much stuff in there
not too many particles not too many
nutrients not too many elements so how
many PPM's do we want to get our water
to that kind of depends on what phase of
growth or bloom you are in so seedlings
in small
don't need a lot of nutrients they don't
need a lot of PPM's I try to start off
at a lower ppm for my smaller plants
somewhere around 600 to 900 PPM's for
the small stuff like the small veg
plants and cups and small pots as they
get bigger I do increase by week four
I'm usually up to about 1500 PPM's in
veg I don't really go too hard with the
nutrients I give them base nutrients
potassium silicates cal-mag I'll give
them some stuff to keep them moving
route wise but they really don't get a
whole lot of nutrients in the veg phase
I just want them to grow I want them to
get stout I want them to be healthy so
once we start flowering that's when I
kind of start boosting it up I week one
of flowering I'll probably start off
right about maybe a thousand or 1300 ppm
and then I will increase I until I hit
honestly I'll get close to 1900 PPM's
but honestly I would not recommend if
you're using bottled nutrients and
you're not a very experienced grower you
probably shouldn't get over 17 or 18
hundred particles per million in your
solution or you'll start burning your
plants if you think you know what you're
doing and you can mix and match
nutrients so you're not giving it too
much of one thing but you're
supplementing what's missing by adding
more PPM's then you may be able to get
away with it but be very careful because
once you've burnt the plants you can't
take that back you can give more but you
can't take anything out honestly most of
the feed charts that come with bottled
nutrients these days most of them are
pretty accurate if you follow that feed
chart maybe you reduce it maybe use
about 75% of what the bottle says most
of the companies will make a feed chart
you can find it online follow that and
it won't get you over seventeen or
eighteen hundred ppm and then see what
that chart does and adjust from there if
you want to go a little harder go for it
if you realize you need to go a little
wider go for it that's something that
you could do so you've got your solution
mixed up you're checking your ppm s if
you feel like it's right where you want
it now you need to adjust the pH if you
feel like the ppm s are too high if you
feel like it's too hot for your plants
you can simply add water if you've got
everything mixed up and the PPM's are
hitting more than you want for that week
and you feel like it's too hot for the
plants add a little bit of water if
you're using RO water put RO water in
there
if you're using tap water add more tap
water get your ppm meter and put it in
your solution that's mixed up and then
get your regular water and just slowly
add it and watch the numbers on your ppm
meter go down and then once you've get
it to the acceptable appropriate number
then you can stop and that's when it's
time to adjust your pH the last thing
you do is adjust your pH now you need
your pH meter you want to put it in the
water give it a little stir around give
it a couple seconds to adjust and see
where you are if it's up too high you
need to put some pH down in there if
you're too low you need to put some pH
up in there a good area for your plants
for most plants to be is six-two pH your
solution to 6.2 and you should be just
fine my smaller plants I go a little
lower my larger plants may get a little
higher but 6-2 is a good general range
of pH for most cannabis plants I did a
whole episode about the importance of pH
I recorded that episode on August 10th
of 2015 it's actually episode number 88
and it is called the importance of pH if
you want to check that out it is still
in the feed on iTunes and stitcher and
it's on the website I read genetics
Colorado calm there are a hundred
episodes available there so if you want
to go back in history check those out
again it's episode number 88 it's called
the importance of pH all right you guys
so we've got our reservoir filled we've
got our nutrients mixed in there we've
got our PPM's adjusted to the
appropriate ppm store it won't be too
strong of a solution for our plants we
have got our pH adjusted to
approximately 62 or whatever you're
finding appropriate for your garden at
this stage of its life now let's talk
about actually physically feeding the
plants if you're running an auto hydro
system or a soil or soil s or cocoa
system that's on a drip system make sure
that the plants get that the root zone
that the soil gets fully saturated when
you water those plants with your
automation system you have to figure out
how long it comes on and how frequently
that watering system comes on I am going
to do an entire episode about building a
watering system and getting that set up
so that will be probably 2 or 3 episodes
from now I may put out put that one out
as a Thursday bonus episode so if you're
running an automated system May
we focus on getting everything saturated
let it dry kind of and then saturate it
again you need a timer you'll have to
run the timer and see how long it takes
to saturate the plants and then you'll
have to pay attention to how long it
takes him to dry and then you'll have to
make that timer run again so its
duration and interval is what you're
gonna have to figure out it's not too
hard it just takes a day to do it that's
pretty much how you're gonna have to set
up any drip system with any sort of
hydro or cocoa or soilless mix just make
sure that if you're using cubes or
whatever you're using make sure that
they get fully saturated and that
they've got the appropriate dry time and
then just repeat that cycle over and
over as the plants get larger and
further into the flower phase you may
have to increase either the duration of
watering or the less interval between
waterings is something you'll have to
think about but you'll see that
happening as it grows and we're gonna
talk more about that and that auto
watering episode that's coming up so
let's talk about watering your soil or
cocoa or soilless mix plants that are in
pots um maybe you're watering with a
pitcher maybe you're going to the
reservoir just getting a pitcher like I
use and my personal grow I use like a
kool-aid pitcher I use a one gallon
plastic pitcher I use two of them so
that I could scoop water with both hands
my plants are in seven gallon pots so
they're not too too low I can reach them
just by kind of doing a short band I can
walk down the middle of the row and
water two plants at a time I scoop water
out of the rez turn a little bit water
to plants so I used the kool-aid pitcher
if the commercial girl I use a water
wand I put a pump in a trash can
which is the reservoir the trash cans on
wheels I put a pump there it's like a
sump pump that plugs into the wall that
runs to a hose which runs to a water
wand that water wand I basically squeeze
a trigger and the water comes out it's
got about a two foot attachment
extension on it so that I can get to the
plants that are at the end of the rows
that's why I like the water want for the
commercial grow so I either use the
pitcher or a water wand however you want
to do it is find the water wand you tend
to make a little bit of a mess with the
pitcher you can kind of put the water
where you want it I feel like the
pitcher is more time efficient because I
can grab water and pour it grab water
and pour it in it there's no time for it
to come out it just pours out of the
picture but the water wand
with the seven count with the five
gallon pot if the commercial grow I
count to 70 as I water I count one two
three four five and it takes me to 72
water a 5-gallon pot appropriately so
that takes it's probably 50 seconds of
me counting to 70 that's how fast I just
probably over a count time but that's a
lot of time so I prefer the pitcher
method anyway you do it soak the plant
when you are watering the plants make
sure you fully saturate that root zone
all that soil needs to get wet you want
to see some runoff you want at least a
little bit of runoff if you got catch
trees underneath your plants if you're
in the table you want to see runoff from
every single plant I like to know that
every inch of soil inside that pot got
saturated with nutrients and water so
that when those roots when it does start
to dry out and those roots go growing in
there they find those nutrients in that
soil and it's like hey there's some more
stuff for me to eat and it's really good
to saturate the whole thing I think so
make sure you saturate your entire root
ball get a little bit of runoff and then
let them start to dry out over the next
few days and I don't water until they
get kind of dry I like to pick them up
and see how light they are once they
start getting light that's when they
need water you'll know the difference
you'll start learning the difference I
also like to watch for when the leaves
start to droop just a little bit
normally the if you're doing it right
your leaves are facing up just a little
bit they're praying if you're doing a
good job
the leaves are horizontal well they
start getting thirsty they'll start to
curl down and hang and droop just a
little bit as soon as you see that droop
is when those plants want water that is
the most ideal time to water those
plants if you can figure out that timing
from when you water them to when that
droop barely starts and water them right
then every time your plants will be as
happy as they can be so try to find that
timing that sweet spot of right before
they droop and when they get super light
and then water them right then and it
will get easier the more you go the more
you grow the less these things will seem
like a challenge to you you'll get
you'll walk in the grove and you'll be
able to see you'll go home I can tell by
looking at the top of the soil that that
plant needs water you'll get good at it
don't worry just keep practicing so soak
the entire plan give it some time to dry
then re soak it then watch the leaves
for
indicators of issues you guys if your
leaves start doing funny [ __ ] that tells
you that there's something wrong with
the feeding your leaves are gonna tell
you if the plants were over watered if
the plants are over watered they're
going to start making a claw if that's
over watered or too cold it will look
very similar the leaves will still be
horizontal and they won't droop but they
will claw up they will start to look
like just hold your hand out straight
and then make a call like you're a
monster that claw shape that's what your
leaves will start doing if they are over
watered if they are under watered
they'll just start drooping they'll just
go limp and start hanging down if they
get severely under water the top to your
plants will just start drooping over and
they'll look dead you'll be able to see
it it's sad you'll be scared of [ __ ] if
your plants do get to that sort of a
dryness I recommend that you don't water
them with full strength nutrients right
away I would water them with light
nutrients just to get them alive and
back to life and woken up and then feed
them with nutrients later on because the
way I see it is I don't want to get
woken up to a big gigantic meal I don't
want to eat spaghetti and meatballs and
garlic bread first thing in the morning
I'd rather have maybe some oatmeal and
some OJ to get myself started maybe some
fruit and I feel plants are the same way
you don't know in there that droopy you
just want to hydrate them and get
a-movin you don't want to clog them up
with more food I don't know maybe some
of you guys want to wake up and eat a
steak right away but that is not how I'm
gonna roll okay so under water we talked
about that burn if the plants start
looking like they are getting crispy or
if they're getting funky on the edges or
if they have rust looking spots on them
you may be giving them too much
nutrients if the edges of your leaves
are starting to get crispy and over
sharp you may be using too much cal-mag
pay attention to the leaves if you need
to reduce your nutrients you can do that
but that burn is probably not going to
go away keep an eye on the new growth
and make sure that you're not burning
the new growth it is okay if leaves get
funky it is okay to go ahead and remove
a leaf don't be worried just cut it
right off or pull it off with your
fingers there are probably more leaves
coming to back that one up one thing
I've noticed is when you take off leaves
the plants will just replace it if it
needs it also the leaves are gonna tell
you if you have any sort of deficiency
if your leaves start getting pale yellow
if the plants are going slow and not
growing fast enough
probably are missing some nutrients and
you could probably increase your ppm s
also that could be a pH issue you could
have a lot of problems if you're showing
deficiencies quite often pH issues
disguise themselves as deficiencies I
talk a lot about that in episode 88 so
pay a lot of attention to the leaves you
guys paying attention to the leaves will
really help but also keep notes if you
keep notes of what you mixed into the
solution and what you fed try to write
down what you mixed turn it right down
the pH and try to write down the ppm s
of every feeding write down the date and
time and also take notes of anything you
saw in the grow room that day so that
you can look back and you can have a
chart and some history and you can say
oh look on this day my pH was a little
high and now this plant is acting funky
and now I know that I need to make the
pH lower and that's how I've learned
that like OG Kush plants the cushier the
plant the more calm agate wants just
stuff like golden go is always macro
deficient there's just stuff like that
that you learn and you can you can
really boost up the macronutrients with
golden good it's just stuff you learn
from growing specific plants over and
over again so learn from each watering
learn from your notes I think that will
be beneficial take a lot of notes you
guys I take a lot of notes that is
definitely a huge part of what makes me
a better grower all right I feel like I
have covered the basics and maybe a
little bit of more than the basics of
mixing your nutrients and properly
watering your plants to properly
saturate the soil and give them some
time to dry out
now I posted to Facebook that I was
seeking help and guidance for this
episode because I wanted to make sure
that I didn't miss anything and when I
posted to Instagram I got a couple of
replies that I felt I wanted to share
with you the first one comes from
dragonfly Earth Medicine the question
that I posted Instagram basically said
hey I'm writing a podcast about growing
with bottled nutrients does anybody have
any guidance the folks at dragonfly
Earth Medicine said more importantly
what bottled nutrients make sure you
read ingredients and make sure it is
healthy for mind body and soil let's
also remember there are only six
companies that sell synthetics and all
fertilizer companies are from those six
companies and then they also say that
brewing is only expanding your
microbiology so if you're brewing since
you're wasting your time it is
counter-intuitive to brew synthetics it
is like treating your body herbally and
doing a round of antibiotics at the end
so the important part here was that we
need to pay a little bit of attention to
where our products are coming from and
what we are putting into the products
that we are calling medicine so pay
attention make sure that what you're
using is healthy for your mind body and
your soil I also got another message on
Instagram this one says if you add a
form of high quality fulvic acid to your
guys water before anything else
it helps buffer ph of your solution and
provide a natural form of chelation
without adding any p + PK or ppm s to
your water it works and any type of
setup super cost-efficient and it helps
your plants to naturally and easily
uptake the nutrients and minerals you
give them especially the hard ones such
as iron so this guy recommends that we
add a form of high-quality fulvic acid
and he recommends full power or Shilla
JIT as the brand to use and he says it
will he says to add that before adding
anything else and it will help buffer
your pH and it will help your plants
uptake your nutrients better so that's
always helpful then here's the part that
really got my attention he said also we
should completely move away from harmful
and non regenerative farming practices
such as synthetic fertilizer programs
that aren't sustainable and do more harm
than good to our Gardens planet and its
limited natural life-sustaining
resources of life such as water land and
clean air he goes on to say there's
nothing wrong with using bottled
nutrients or other forms of farming but
we must still be aware of the effects we
have on our planet and fellow man
through our action or worse yet in
action he said I feared I'd touch on
that last part my shameless alternative
techniques promoting that came from a
guy who calls himself el OS gardens on
instagram l OS underscore Gardens hey I
appreciate it because we all need to be
reminded occasionally to pay attention
to where our products are coming from
and what we're putting into ourselves
and our Gardens
I appreciate the insight and I
appreciate the help and advice you guys
I understand that not everybody is able
to grow organically not everybody lives
in a farm area I understand that a lot
of us live in
city's a lot of us have our neighbors
right next door I can almost reach out
one of my windows and touch my
neighbor's house is how close we are
I completely understand that we don't
all have space to do organic farming
practices I understand that we can all
conceal the odors and the extra
ingredients in the extra steps I
understand that I'm not judging you if
you need to use bottled nutrients let's
do it I use bottled nutrients myself
let's just think a little bit while
we're doing it let's not try to support
companies that don't support us and
companies that don't support the
environment you get to choose where your
money goes so choose wisely I want to
thank everybody who commented and
replied on my Facebook and Instagram
post that helped me put this episode
together I truly do appreciate it I also
want to thank everybody they'll listen
to the bonus episode that I put out
Thursday you guys if you did not listen
to the episode that I put out Thursday
about seasonal affective disorder you
may want to go give that a listen
especially if you live in one of the
colder winter climates where we are
freezing our asses off for the past few
weeks it may be a good episode for you
to listen to also I have found two
solutions for the folks that have been
asking for old podcast episodes I have
got a short-term solution and a
long-term solution they are under way I
am NOT going to tell you what I'm going
to do because they are not there yet
once they are out I will tell you all
about it you guys will be able to give
it a listen
I truly appreciate how interested
everybody is and hearing the old
episodes that really lit a fire under my
ass I will get those episodes out to you
the first 22 are ready I'm working on
there are a hundred and seventy nine
episode you guys it's gonna take me a
minute to catch up but I will get every
episode listenable very soon 22 are
ready I'll make an announcement where
they are very soon if you're if you're
proactive you may be able to go find
them on your own so I want to thank
everybody for listening it's been 179
episodes they truly appreciate everybody
for following me this far because I need
to give you a huge shout out to my
friends at handmade apparel once again
if you need some shirts or hoodies or
stickers our hat pins made I fully
endorse and recommend my friends at
handmade apparel check them out handmade
apparel dot biz I would love it if you
guys follow me on the social media on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast on facebook
it's the girl from your heart podcast if
you want to say something and you're not
into the social media you can send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I talked at the start of the
show about pay
Triana I would love it if you could
support me on patreon if you cannot
contribute to patreon I still love you I
still want you to listen to the podcast
those of you that can help out I truly
do appreciate it if you can't contribute
to patreon and you want to help me up
it'd be great if you go to iTunes find
the iTunes Store search from the girl
from your heart podcast find the ratings
and review section type in a comment let
me know what you think about the show I
will read your review on a future
episode so far you guys everybody has
given me a 5 star rating type in punch
in as many starters as you feel I
deserve and I will appreciate it because
I'm going to wrap up this podcast I want
to thank you for joining me for a
hundred and seventy-nine episodes I want
to give you a huge shout out to my
friends at elevate glass and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
in the world
[Applause]
[Music]
that's the only way
searches strange places times and rival
like travel then you lose the battle and
get left behind when you strike your
left miss Ryan four-fifths got left
behind you'll buy yo yo yo
[Music]