welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 181 of the
growth from your heart podcasts your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roof and foot news
their music on my podcast big shot to
cap to the entire mystic roots crew
yeah I hope you guys are having a great
day great morning evening nighttime
whatever time it is wherever you are
hope you're having a great time okay
smoking something with me I'm smoking
some cascade shatter I grew the flowers
our friend the Fair Food grower did the
extraction for me I'm gonna give you a
huge shout out to our friends at elevate
glass for keeping me supplied with fresh
clean glass also I need to give a huge
shout out to my friend tater big shout
out to tater glass for the custom pencil
got a brand new Rasta colored pencil
dabber with a custom carb cap at the end
of it so I carved my banger big shot at
the tater glass also big shot at the
Jenny Beth for the amazing Valentine's
Day gift thank you I appreciate that
very much
I've been using the [ __ ] out of this
thing it is super sticky should probably
clean it make sure that's all the folks
to take good care of me yeah I'm doing
shoutouts to give a shout out to my
friends at handmade apparel that's right
if you need some hoodies printed if you
need t-shirts printed if you need
stickers made if you need hat hat pins
made I can't recommend anyone better
than my friends at handmade apparel it's
right hand made apparel they make my
growth from your heart podcast hoodies
they make B I region that extends they
have made my I read genetics hat pins
they make most of my friends t-shirts in
the cannabis industry they make a lot of
the Hat pins you see in the cannabis
industry you guys I fully recommend
handmade apparel check them out at
handmade apparel dot biz and let them
know Rasta Jeff sent you let them know
you're listening to the growth from your
heart podcast and they will take very
good care of you when your custom
printing means all right this episode is
going to be part 2 of preventing
identifying and eradicating your common
garden pests and issues well that's hard
to say that's a lot of words for a
podcast title but it's gonna be part two
of all that stuff before we get to
talking about new issues I need to
mention some stuff I forgot in the last
episode in the last episode we talked
about fungus gnats and we also talked
about spider mites when we talked when
we spoke about spider mites I forgot to
mention one helpful thing you guys if
you start seeing
spider my webbing developing in your
plants you can easily vacuum it up with
a shop vac hang on to the plant very
carefully get the shop vac and just suck
those spider mite webs right the [ __ ]
off of there honestly if you've got
spider mite webs you've got big problems
you need to get through that harvest you
need to clean that up and then you need
to figure out why there are spider mites
in your grow you need to correct that
issue you need to seal your gaps you
need to use some pesticides you need to
use some predator bugs you need to get
rid of the mites if you've got that big
of an issue but the shopvac will
certainly work to help you clean up
spider mite webbing should it be there
in your growth one more thing I should
talk about another way to really easily
find an issue in your garden is to be
there every day and just take a look you
guys pay attention look around in the
grow see what's going on look at the
plants everybody stares into the plants
all day stare with a purpose look at the
leaves see if you see any stippling see
if you see little bugs tap the soil see
if bugs fly up out of the soil
shake the plants see if bugs fly up out
of the foliage look around the room see
if anything looks out of place look and
see if you have some sort of leak or
drip coming from an air conditioner or a
dehumidifier just pay attention the best
way to find an issue early is to look
every day and pay attention and be there
all you got to do is go there and look
around alright just pay some attention
take some time in the grow I like to
walk in and just pull a leaf from a
random plant I try to pick a different
plant every day pick one leaf flip it
upside down make sure there are no bugs
no issues on the bottom side of that
leaf turn it look at the top side of the
leaf hardly ever problems on the top
sides you can see it from far away if
there are but grab some leaves pull off
the plants take a look and see if you
notice any issues ok another really easy
and simple way to prevent problems in
your garden is to simply clean up after
yourself don't leave leaves on the floor
don't leave dirt on the floor don't
leave your tools in the grow room and if
you bought some soil and you plan on
doing some transplanting don't bring
that soil into the grow room until you
can properly treat it and be sure that
there are not bugs and I should mention
that a lot of soil that you purchase
comes with free insects a lot of people
complain about specific brands having
insects in it honestly all of the soil
is eventually stored in the same place
if whatever brand you choose if it's Fox
farms if its roots organics if it's
whoever else there's just the first two
I thought of if its brand a brand B and
brand C they are all made by different
companies right but then they're all put
on a truck and they are all sent to
whatever King [ __ ] hydro supply in
whatever
and they're all stored in one warehouse
there until they're shipped out to
smaller warehouses to smaller warehouses
to retail stores so they're all shipped
to one place and in that one place I
imagine it's just a [ __ ] bug farm
every thrip and fungus net and spider
mite is just in there plotting to take
over your garden right now so when new
soil comes you have to pay attention to
what's in there that's a great way to
get bugs I forgot to mention that in the
last episode so be clean and pay the
[ __ ] attention one more thing we should
talk about a lot of people were like hey
what about ladybugs can't I use ladybugs
in my garden to help keep pests away
ladybugs are really cute but they are
not that aggressive I don't feel that
they eat enough enough problematic bugs
to be worth their money if you do get
some ladybugs release them in the grow
take a bunch of photography because
they're really cute and then in the next
morning get out the shopvac and vacuum
up all the dead goddamn ladybugs because
most of them are going to die within the
first 24 to 48 hours they're really not
that useful in my opinion and an indoor
grow when they die they stink you step
on them they're crunchy you find them in
your ducting you find them all over the
place also you guys I don't really think
a praying mantis is too beneficial in a
garden they mostly eat things like
aphids and soft bodied insects they
won't really go after too many spider
mites they aren't that aggressive what
I'm getting at is if you are going to
employ predator insects it is way more
worth your time your budget and your
energy to research and purchase the
correct predatory insect for your
problem for every insect that I
mentioned in these problem episodes I'm
going to try to include a predatory
insect that will control that pest
problem eventually I'll do a full
episode focused on beneficial insects
and predator bugs but for now I'll just
include one or two predators for each
problem that we face because if you are
looking to employ and use predator mites
and sort of an integrated pest
management system and go the organic
route I can fully endorse a company
called our Beco organics it's a RB ico
organics they are available online at RB
code - organics com they do not pay me I
am not sponsored by them but this
one simple catalog this is the early
spring 2017 catalog it includes
beneficial insects and mites to combat
almost any problem I could imagine in a
garden there are my predators there are
white fly parasites they're a fit
parasites you can buy anything from
ladybugs and preying mantises to my new
pirate bugs to assassin bugs which we
will talk about in the IPM episode which
I do have coming up for you later
gentleman my point here is that I do
completely endorse our Vico organics you
guys another way that you can pay
attention and notice bugs before they
become a problem is yellow and blue
sticky traps I said blue also yes most
people know about the yellow sticky
traps for your garden let me let me talk
about yellow sticky traps for a second
the reason yellow sticky traps are
yellow is because bugs are attracted to
the yellowing leaves the yellowing
leaves are a sign of weakness
imagine you were a bug you want to eat
through the leaf that thick green leaf
is crunchy and it has protection on it
it's gonna be it's gonna take a little
more work to get to the crunchy juicy or
that juicy taste the insides if the leaf
is already yellow it's a little bit weak
and you can get your little fangs right
through it and get in there and suck out
the juices and get what you need so
plants are Pro our bugs are programmed
to want to head for those yellow leaves
so hang those yellow sticky traps up I
like to put one kind of low near the
bottom of the canopy I like to put one
kinda in the middle of the canopy and
then I put them up high where flying
bugs are gonna go up near the lights so
I like to have those yellow sticky traps
around to let me know if bugs are there
and then if I see insects gathering on
those a couple is fine you're gonna see
a couple occasionally because [ __ ] flies
around you're just gonna have a normal
bug flying around but if you start
seeing them gather on there it's time to
treat for whatever bug you see gathering
on there it's probably gonna be a fungus
net if it's something flying the blue
ones put those lower the blue sticky
cards put those lower near your soil and
they will let you know if you are
getting thrips they are a good indicator
of leaf miners and thrips and other soil
bound insects so the sticky traps are
certainly a good way to let you know
that insects are coming also another
good way to know that you've got bugs
flying bugs will stick to your lights
the light reflectors they heat up if
you've got glass on there that'll heat
up somewhere there will be bugs stuck to
that pay attention to that if you see
little black bugs or little white bugs
that means you've got fungus
or white flies that you have got to
treat for so those are really simple
ways and indicators that you have got
problems and very simple ways to prevent
problems now it's time to work our way
into talking about preventing and
eradicating and identifying more garden
issues let's start today with white
flies white flies are more ugly than
anything but what white flies do is they
make your plants weak it will slow down
the growth of your plant they will make
your plants weak and tired they will
certainly diminish your yield they will
diminish the quality of your plants
white flies like to stick their little
teeth into your plants and suck the SAP
out of your plants and then they fly
around then they land back on your
plants and they [ __ ] all over your
plants and leave little honeydew streaks
on your plants so they make your plants
weak and then when you try to take
photos your photos are [ __ ] ugly
because you've got white flies in there
you've got white fly [ __ ] in there it's
really frustrating so let's talk about
white flies sounds really easy to
identify a white fly I did white fly
identification they are little white
bugs that fly around how do you know
they're there they're flying around if
you don't see them the best way to check
for him shake the plant when you shake
the planet shake the foliage white flies
will take off flying like I said earlier
look around the white shake the plants
and look toward the white because the
little bugs want to fly right at the
light when you shake them and then
they'll just fly around for a couple of
seconds and they'll land right back on
your plants they're really frustrating
so that's easy way to identify them a
good way to prevent white flies is a
clean dry sealed grow room and also low
temperatures you guys white flies thrive
and reproduce in temperatures over
eighty degrees so try to keep it closer
to 75 77 degrees in there that will slow
down the white fly production if they do
get in there also like I was talking
about earlier clear out all of the plant
debris that you have in your room don't
have that stuff in there dead leaves and
stuff get rid of that also in the last
episode I talked about using fine dust
filters and HEPA filters on all of your
ducting or on your intakes or on your
outs make sure you have some sort of
ducting on all your ins and outs and
make sure that all of your vents are
covered so that the white flies can't
travel through there so that's a great
way those are great ways to prevent
white flies so now you know how to spot
them and you know how to prevent them
now should you get them let's talk about
ways to get rid of white flies like I
talked about a little bit ago yellow
sticky traps are a great way to start
catching the white flies but you're only
gonna get a small portion of what's
there just the ones that fly to the
yellow sticky traps just the dumb ones
the dumb ones are gonna fly right to it
the smart ones are gonna stay there and
they're gonna keep breeding another way
that you can get rid of them is to shake
the plants and when they fly up simply
use your shop vac I've done this before
in gardens I've done this in personal
gardens I have done this also in
commercial Gardens just shake the [ __ ]
out of them shake the plant and just use
the wand on the shop vac and as they fly
out just suck them up they're gonna fly
right out of the plant and they're gonna
fly right up to the light so maybe keep
the shot back up toward the light just
shot back just just suck them right up
shake the plant keep sucking chase him
around suck him up until you're bored
until your arms go tired or until they
quit flying around do whichever one you
got to do so get off the shopvac and
shot back the [ __ ] out of those white
flies also things you can do you can
apply sprays you can use neem oil
woodwork to help you get rid of your
white flies pyrethrum sprays will help
you get rid of your white flies and spin
Oh sad sprays will help you get rid of
your white flies those are all things
that are up to you if you want to use
the Evergreen pyrethrin spray it seems
to be a very versatile product you could
spray the leaves you can do a soil
drench and that will get rid of most of
your insects I think two or three
applications of the Evergreen pyrethrins
will get rid of most insects to tell you
the truth but that is up to you if it's
something you want to do also if you're
if you've got a very small garden in a
very light case of white flies you can
use insecticidal soap there is safer
soap I think and Rosenthal makes his own
type of soap simple products like that
are great to use if you've got a light
infestation but also keep in mind like I
mentioned in every episode
everything you spray on your leaves is
going to end up in your concentrates so
if you're going to apply essential oils
or botanical extract oils those are
going to end up in your hash if you plan
on making hash if you're making BHO if
you're making water hash this stuff will
end up in your concentrates you're going
to end up smoking it you're going to end
up tasting it it may have a health
effect I do not know what product you're
using I don't know the long term
Effects of these just keep that stuff in
mind another thing that you can use to
get rid of your white flies is it
beneficial fungi and I think it is
pronounced Bavaria
bastiana it's a beneficial fungus it can
be applied in several different ways
it's sold as a powder it can be
sprinkled onto soil it can be mixed with
water however you get it please follow
the instructions wear a mask if you use
it wear gloves wearing goggles please
you guys this is a horticultural product
please be be very careful with this
stuff it is not a joke okay now is the
time when we talk about the beneficial
insects that you can use to get rid of
your white flies if you do not want to
apply pesticides if you do not want to
get out the shot back you guys get out
the shot back and just suck the [ __ ] off
it won't hurt anything beat the [ __ ] out
of your plants it's kind of good for if
you don't want to apply pesticides if
you don't want to use beneficial
funguses if you don't want to put
spinosad on your plants one thing you
really can do is get white fly parasites
there are 1 2 3 different types of white
fly parasites available in the arborcoat
magazine and they are all very
affordable the white fly parasite I
would recommend to you is called the
encar sia Formosa there are actually
little wasps that fly around your
greenhouse and eat the [ __ ] out of white
flies all right you guys that is my
quick talk on how to get rid of white
flies honestly the best way to get rid
of white flies is to prevent them keep
your clothes clean if you've been to
another grow keep your grow room sealed
up keep your low yellow sticky traps
hung up and hopefully the little [ __ ]
don't get in your grow you guys one
thing I should mention a common way that
I have discovered pests and Gardens is
through photography I am a huge cannabis
photography enthusiast a shameless plug
if you'd like to follow my Instagram I
am I real or genetics on Instagram I RIE
underscore GE and ET ICS I read genetics
on Instagram I post a ton of cannabis
photography some of my recent posts have
gotten nearly 500 likes so far I'm at
480 something likes on a couple of posts
so if you want to check that out go for
it but photography is how I discover a
lot of issues and problems I'll snap a
picture at a grow I'll zoom in real far
I'll snap a picture I'll come home I'll
throw the disc in the computer I'll open
it up on the computer screen and zoom in
thinking that I've got the most amazing
shot and then I'll notice that there are
some white flies or some fungus gnats or
some a photonic orner on one of these
buds that I did not even notice and it
ruined my photo but at least now I know
that there's a problem there's something
I need to treat for something I need to
take care of so if you've got a good
camera if you've got a decent camera you
could probably do this with your iPhone
or Android camera if you suspect you've
got a problem take some pictures zoom in
look at the pictures when you zoom in
and you may reveal some problems you
were unaware of all right you guys I've
been going for 17 minutes here it looks
like I'm going to press pause for a
second I'm gonna take a drink you know
I'm gonna take a couple of giant dabs
and then I will be right back and we're
going to talk about a Fitz
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back and I
am heavily medicated I hope you enjoyed
the music we're listening to during the
break the song I played was called fat
spliffs by a band called Slightly
Stoopid I'm sure a lot of my reggae
friends are familiar with Slightly
Stoopid but if you haven't heard of them
check them out I'm sure you will dig
them during the break you guys
I took some gigantic dabs of some
distillate and I am heavily medicated I
like to talk about how much I enjoy
shatter I do like shatter shatter is
probably the most cost effective way for
me to medicate the way I prefer I like
to smoke frequently I like to take large
dabs I feel like I get more medicinal
effect off of one giant dab than I would
3 little dabs if you took the same
amount of hash if you took let's just
say 1/2 gram I would smoke a half
granddad by itself instead of breaking
it into 3 small dabs and I feel like if
I smoke those 3 small dabs back-to-back
like inhale blow it out eat the rig up
again do it again blow out the dab heat
the rig up again smoke it in blow it out
dude again I think those three dabs back
to back would not get me as high as one
single half gram dab would do so if I
took the same half grab broke it down
into three pieces took them all or took
one giant dab I'd get way better
medication off of the half gram so I
like to take giant dabs and I like to do
it frequently I like to take 2 or 3 dabs
at a time when I take a dab break
sometimes I'll take 4 or 5 dabs at a
time so shatter is the most
cost-effective way for me to get the
medicine I need for the price I like to
take big dad's very frequently but when
I need a little extra when I just want
to do something extra to my head you
guys this distillate is the way to go
it's a little bit expensive so you can't
get down on it you can't spoil yourself
every day
but if you're trying to spend a little
extra money at the dispensary I highly
recommend a nice glass vial of
distillate and what I like to do I heat
up the banger I heat the banger a little
bit too hot or the nail whichever you're
using or the email the email is already
on get it to a little bit hot and then
let it cool and then I just take the
torch and just barely heat the tip of
the glass syringe which the distillate
comes in and then you just barely tap
the plunger and it'll just push I think
three drops of distillate is a good dab
for me sometimes like to go four or five
if I'm trying to go crazy if you want to
go big go like seven or eight or ten
drops of the distillate into the banger
and do it but I think one or two drops
two or three drops would get most people
choking and nice and high so big shout
out to distillate I'm really starting to
fall in love with distillate you guys
I'm gonna quit rambling about distal and
concentrates and we're gonna talk about
a fits a federa common in cannabis grows
they love warm environments in warm
conditions that's why you find them in a
lot of ganja grows that's why you find
them in a lot of greenhouses so let's
talk about identifying a fits a federa
bout the size of a piece of rice I think
may be a little bit smaller I've seen
aphids plenty of times they look like a
piece of rice maybe just a little bit
smaller they're pear-shaped Athens come
in many different colors you guys I have
seen a fits
I've seen white Athens I've seen orange
aphids I've seen green Athens I have
seen a Fitz that are a reddish-brown
color almost the color of blood Athens
come in many different colors Athens
like to hang out on the bottom sides of
your leaves you guys they like to
congregate at the bottom sides of the
leaves usually kind of where they've got
some protection where they can hide from
predators and white and you and the wind
I've also seen a fiddler the bud at the
top bud where it kind of where the
leaves come out of the bud and kind of
make like a bowl the leaves were coming
out of the bud and curling up because of
the bud was really happy and right in
that little chilling area where the
leaves and bud made contact there was a
nice little colony of aphids just
chillin and living right there I don't
know how long they'd been there but they
were there for a long time because there
were a bunch of them so aphids liked to
hang out in a lot of different places on
the plant so make sure you check often
and they also breed very quickly so make
sure you're paying attention for a
it's also a fits the problem with aphids
is they are leaf suckers they like to
bite into your leaf and suck out the
juices just like all the other damn
pests for your gardens so they get up
under the leaves they poke little holes
in there they start sucking out the leaf
juices and all the life out of your
plants your plants start looking like
[ __ ] now your plants are getting weak
and they are susceptible to other
problems they're also gonna yield less
they're gonna grow slowly they're gonna
look like [ __ ] a lot of times if an
aphid problem gets out of control you'll
start seeing the leaves start to curl
and will and look like they're dead
they're just given up those plants have
been beat to [ __ ] and they've been
chewed up by the aphids so bad that
they're not even gonna try to fight
anymore
they're just gonna curl up and die try
again next year all right let's talk
about how to prevent yourself from
getting aphids in your ganja garden like
most other pests we can avoid getting
them by having filtration dust filters
and HEPA filters on your intake and your
outgoing vents also you need a clean
grow room I keep talking about a clean
grow room but every leaf every piece of
debris is a place for a bug to hide so
also something you can really think
about for aphids you need clean clothes
and clean shoes if you go on a hike if
you were around plants outside if it is
warm please change your clothes before
you go into your garden I worked in a
commercial grow everything was clean one
of my co-workers talked about taking
their dog for a hike they posted
pictures on Instagram all about taking
their dog for a hike they stopped by the
Gro to say hello and see if we wanted
lunch on their way home
three days later that garden had a fits
you guys I don't want to blame that dog
for running through a bush getting in
the car putting aphids on my friend my
friend coming to the girl putting aphids
in my garden but honestly you can tell
in my heart that that's what I think
[ __ ] happened so please do not go to
agro after you've been out hiking do not
come to agro after you've been playing
with your dog I think that pets are huge
carriers of garden pests they're out
there running and around in everything
they're low to the ground where the bugs
are they're playing in the dirt they're
playing in the bushes that's where the
garden pests are they're rubbing up
against plants plants are where plant
pests live
they're not gonna bring home predatory
mites they're going to bring home spider
mites they're gonna bring home trips and
a fits so please be very careful with
your clothing your shoes and your pests
another good way to prevent Athens in
your garden is to check for them I mean
if they're already there you're gonna
see them a way to prevent an S
infestation is to check for them very
frequently that's the best way to check
and prevent any type of pest infestation
is to pay attention every day one sign
that you have got an aphid problem is
ants if you have got ants in your grow
room you have probably got a fits also
ants and a fits
I often come together in your garden so
if you've got one you've probably got
the other answer easy to get rid of
we'll talk about that in another episode
I'm actually gonna write it down right
now all right I even wrote it down so
that will happen okay let's talk about
ways to eradicate a fits up in your
garden of course we talked about this
quite frequently the first step that you
can do if you choose to is you can spray
products on your garden there are many
things you can spray for a Fidesz neem
oil neem oil will get rid of the aphids
they don't want to be there it's sticky
it smells like [ __ ] it tastes terrible
the aphids don't want to hang out on
that a couple of applications of neem
oil should get rid of your a fits
however if you're in flower you do not
want to spray neem oil on flowering
plants keep in mind I say it all the
time
everything you spray on your buds and
your leaves is going to end up in your
concentrate if you've got big fat
swollen buds they're going to act like a
sponge you're gonna spray neem oil on
there and it's going to absorb and hang
onto a bunch of neem you're gonna
concentrate it you'll actually see the
neem oil float on the top of your hash
so you may have to think about what
you're gonna do if you're going to make
a lot of concentrates these sprays may
not be for you if you do choose to use
sprays pyrethrum sprays work well to get
rid of aphids I of course have been
endorsing the Evergreen brand it's very
affordable there's another brand that's
quite expensive it's the same thing as
evergreen you can use cinnamon oil you
can use clove oil you can use a product
made by Ed Rosenthal called zero
tolerance all of these products will
help you to get rid of your a fits it's
up to you to choose how strongly you
want to attack these pests and also
how harsh of a chemical you want to
apply to the plants that you are loving
and that you are growing to use as
medicine for yourself or other people
that you care for
another method we can use to get rid of
our a fits is a beneficial fungus called
Bavaria bassiano which is actually sold
as a product called botanic garden it
spelled Bo T and I G ard and it's 22 WP
it's a little bit expensive but it will
certainly work this is the beneficial
fungus I keep speaking of that can be
applied to treat a plethora of garden
insects you guys you can find it of
course at our bee code - organics
dot-com I did not realize it would be
for sale on that website I was not
looking for it on that website I did a
quick google search to see where we
could purchase it so I could share it
with you and the first place they came
up was our pico organics you guys I'm
sure they will not sponsor me because
I'm a cannabis podcast but let them know
if you do shop with them let them know
that you heard about them through the
girl from your heart podcast through
Rasta Jeff now we've talked about how to
get rid of these aphids on your plants
if you don't have giant buds if you are
in flower and you've got giant buds I
would never recommend spraying products
on there you don't want to spray
something that's going to leave a flavor
or possibly cause some sort of
long-lasting health effect that we don't
even know about for years to come so if
you don't want to spray the plants
what's the next option it is time to
bring out the predator bugs you guys
this is where ladybugs are useful
ladybugs do love to eat the [ __ ] out of
a Fitz there's actually a really cool
picture and Rosenthal's book of a
ladybug just devouring an aphid so this
is where the ladybugs do come in
ladybugs are actually useful for getting
rid of your aphids also the praying
mantis i discredited in earlier he is
actually really good at getting rid of
aphids so the ladybugs the praying
mantis those would be the first steps to
getting rid of aphids in your cannabis
garden then you can bring out a food
paradise and aphid predators
there are several available the phidias
kool Imani is a well-known a fin
parasite there are several a fad
predators available some of them prefer
certain conditions so if you're going to
work with the Predators and the
parasites make sure that you've got the
proper and appropriate conditions for
these insects so that they can thrive
and destroy your a fed's another thing
you can do that is completely free and
completely organic it's safe and simple
you can simply remove leaves
or you can remove buds that are infested
with bugs it is not a big deal
chop it off put her in a trash bag seal
the trash bag put that in a sealed trash
can away from the grow and you will have
manually eliminated the problem from
your grow another thing I want to
mention that I forgot to write down but
I just thought of it as I was talking
oftentimes I have seen a fits on these
stems of cannabis plants moving up and
down just traveling around the plant a
product called stylet oil will coat the
stems of the plants and it will leave it
like an undesirable place for these
aphids to be so check out a product
called stylin oil diluted heavily apply
it to your plants and that will keep
away most of your garden pests
especially these aphids and also the
white flies
alright cannabis community I wanna thank
you for listening to part 2 of
preventing identifying a near addict
ating common garden pests and issues so
far we've only covered insects but once
we cover the majority of the cannabis
pest insects we are going to work our
way into identifying other problems in
the garden such as plants that are too
dry and too wet I'll teach you how to
identify overfed and under fed plants
will talk about calcium and magnesium
deficiencies I've got a lot of things
planned for you I hope you subscribe and
stick around for all of those episodes
ladies and gentlemen this is the part of
the podcast where I remind you about
patreon if you would like to make a
financial contribution to the podcast
please visit patreon.com slash grow from
your heart for all of the information
let me tell you what I'm going to do
with your contribution if you do choose
to contribute to patreon ladies and
gentlemen it does cost me a small
portion of money to host my website I
read genetics Colorado com which is
where I host this podcast I'm not trying
to get rich the people that contribute
to patreon their contributions will be
used to pay for my web hosting that's
all I'm trying to pay for so if you're
able to do that I appreciate it if you
cannot contribute please do not feel
like I am leaving you out like I'm
abandoning you I love you I want you to
listen I am simply creating the option
for people to contribute if they are
able to and choose to do so only give a
big shout out to the people who have
contributed to patreon somebody threw
down $10 the other day I'm not sure if
they want their name set on the show but
big shout out it's hugely appreciated
all right guys I need to give you a huge
shout out to my friends at handmade
apparel if you need some t-shirts made
if you need Hootie's printed if you need
hat pins made my friends at handmade
apparel can take great care of you make
sure you visit handmade apparel dot biz
and let them know Rasta Jeff from the
girl from a heart podcasts and Chiu
legend gentlemen I want to thank you for
listening to another episode that's all
I've got for you this week I want to
give a big shout out to skinny and your
mom Cindy until next time take a phat
dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you