it would have podcast world its Rasta
Jeff a lot of people have been asking
for all episodes of the podcast that are
no longer available in the iTunes and
stitcher feed I decided to put old
episodes together in large chunks and
throw them back into the feed so that
you can enjoy them without interrupting
the current podcast schedule before we
get into the old episodes that are a
couple of things I should tell you up
until episode 50 the show was called the
iGrow culture podcast I changed the name
to grow from your heart at episode 50
also I should make a disclaimer that I
have learned a lot in a hundred and
eighty episodes of podcasting so some of
my ideas and opinions at the start of
the show may be strongly different from
my opinions now and in the future so
don't hold anything against me all right
you guys episode 1 is probably quite
embarrassing I can't even listen to it
so I hope you do listen to it I hope you
enjoy it I cannot wait to hear your
comments on iTunes and I cannot wait to
hear your tweets make sure you tweet me
it's at g f YH podcast ladies and
gentlemen there's episodes 1 2 &amp; 3
[Music]
very first episode of the agriculture
podcast some reason my mic is pulling
out real bad but we'll fix that later
like to thank you guys for tuning in to
the very first episode we got the
chuckles over here is that a couple few
dabs some some what do we got Jack the
Ripper I grew it and my buddy over here
my buddy Kevin from elevated
concentrations blasted it we call the
milky trichomes my buddy white mic so uh
my name is Rasta Jeff I'm the girl I'm a
breeder I gotta fix my mic it's blowing
up hold on boom should be fixed hold on
there we go I'm back all right so they
call me Rasta Jeff I'm a medical
marijuana patient I've been smoking for
over 20 years I'm a grower I'm also a
caregiver I like to teach people how to
grow clean safe and effective medicine
and after being involved with the plant
for so long I thought I should become a
breeder so started doing some pollen
Chunkin and eventually I put together my
own little seed company and now I've got
higher genetics Colorado so check out I
read genetics Colorado calm all right
thanks a lot
so how about you keV what are you your
sneezing hold on I'll give you a second
we'll go to Mike what do you call
yourself bro what do you call yourself
or KJ what I want to know [ __ ] I
do I make concentrates for fun it's
awesome to me hopefully for a job pretty
soon and concentrations which stand your
microphone so we can hear you which will
be returning very soon I had some issues
and had removed the marketing so to
speak but other than that we're all gold
oh we're still doing what we do so
helping out bros like I reject nice
heard some good supplies kid makes me
some good hash he keeps me supplied with
my head
- and it's pretty epic so uh what do you
like to smoke bro when you're looking
flowers do you like smoke in the Khazar
sativas I like in because I'm a huge fan
of blueberry and some deadhead OG I know
a guy that girl some pretty killer
deadhead OG I know one myself
alright I usually ask people I want to
ask people if their medical or direct
patient but I know you I know you're a
medical patient yes sir do you find a
line between medicating and wreck
creating sometimes I do because it
doesn't it doesn't really take very much
to medicate and to make myself feel
better and to help my ailments to get
really stoned and I go beyond that and
write smoke more than I actually need
but it helps my head a lot would I do
that so like your vibe your attitude
yeah helps understandable aura and it
helps me to sleep a lot if I
overmedicate in the evenings so so it's
not over medicating it's perfectly my
idea yeah yeah right drug isn't light
it's just better dude over here to my
left that's my buddy Mike we're gonna
ask him how long have you been smoking
weed bro well somebody who's got to do
math for us how your are you do you
consider yourself a medical or
recreational smoker ah for a good chunk
of that it was completely recreational
it was just some fun I did occasionally
with friends and then I injured a couple
of years ago working I hurt my neck real
bad and messed up some of the discs in
my neck and had some nerve generated
pain is what the fancy doctor folks
would call it and cannabis works a lot
better than the pain pills they had me
on and that was really my personal entry
into the medical world and so now it's
it's both I would say but the regular
use of cannabis is definitely medical
rather than recognizing great that for
sure nice it was recreational I probably
had some joints on the weekend or
something but the definite consistent
use is medical for sure okay
like there's definitely a line between
when the pain stops and any sort of
enjoyment or energy
it begins and they go game time or
whatever yeah that lines easy to feel
it's you can tell when okay the my my
pain is gone I can get up I can do what
I've got to do for the day and then you
can kind of feel the pain slowly coming
back and go medicate a little bit more
the pain goes away and they'll the line
before you become intoxicated is really
easy to walk for me but when I get home
and wanna unwind definitely recreational
okay dabs from your recreation I go
right past medicated into happy okay
that's a good that's the opposite dabs
for me are very medical I have a lot of
respiratory issues and smoking the herb
really gets to be smoking a lot of weed
really gets to me
so doing the dabs and not having to
smoke so much and now that we've learned
about dewaxing and all that stuff and
getting a lot of that plant matter out
of it has really helped me to not be
congested or wheeze all the time and you
know that's if I'm doing quality dabs
but I notice if you dude some dirty
stuff that kind of hinders that a little
bit but my me and I sorry to interrupt
you just made me think it dirty stuff so
I met Mike basically he started coming
to the dispensary I worked at and
managed whatever I had a lot of roles
there and he got to see the evolution of
dirty stuff come to what it is now yeah
remember some of the junk we used to see
come to that dispensary people would try
to pass off his ear wax or judean each
oh they were calling it butter because
it was goopy and sir
the first time I was handed ear wax was
black tar in a coke vial and the guy
said this is earwax hash and handed it
to me and I looked him in the face and I
was new at the shop so my automatic
response to insult the product that I
was just handed had to be gut checked
and kind of held in reserve and I just
kind of nodded and put it back like on
the Shelf I didn't feel like I could say
anything there but good lord like the
quality of hash in the last six years is
lightyears ahead of where it was yeah
definitely the stuff little keV brings
back for me is freakin impressive yeah
yeah that's I mean you got to think a
lot of the whole community for doing
that for us everyone sharing knowledge
with each other and you know being being
fairly open with each other and people
being willing to to read and learn and
gain that knowledge has really you know
made that happen I heard you say
something interesting ago today and I
want you get closer to the mic just for
this one something if I want to get into
hash what's the first step gonna make a
sh sorry not getting into it if I want
to make make my own a BHO go to a school
or a library and grab a basic organic
chemistry book and sit down and read
that [ __ ] and then introduce the
Cannabis later once you understand what
you're dealing with and how to respect
it
see I think that's a good approach and
then after that read some forums and
don't watch a single video until you
have an understanding and you feel like
you could do it on your own and make a
batch or two if you feel confident and
you have done those steps and done the
reading and gained the knowledge and
then watch videos after you've already
tried it because there's so much stupid
[ __ ] that people do in those two minute
videos making a good batch of dabs
doesn't take two minutes I don't care
what your that's why I recommend doing
the reading and the research I've waited
two or three days for this do to bring
me back cabs it's like the longer I wait
the better they are yeah so it's well
worth it yep by all means people do your
homework the only reason people are
getting hurt trying to make dabs is
because they heard about it from a
friend and the friend didn't really know
what they were talking about and then
they ran to the parts store bought a
bunch of flannel flammable chemicals
took them into an enclosed space and set
all the feelings on fire I've talked to
be the dumbest [ __ ] ever if you do any
any research at all you learn how to not
blow yourself up in the first two
minutes it's about respecting what
you're dealing with don't blast in doors
my number one piece of advice that do
not blast indoors
it's ridiculous so what uh for you keV
what's uh what kind of mark do you want
to leave on the cannabis industry or the
society or cannabis world I'd like to
just keep continuing with the main the
main attitude that most of us have and
just continue that positive positive
outlook and that positive view from the
people as well you know just keep
gaining that doing everything as best I
can with the most knowledge and learning
everything as it comes to light as
everything's changing just always keep
up with that and share that with the
people around me because that's how we
get better yeah by sharing your
knowledge that we have for sure that's
how we prevent blowing up I know you're
doing a lot of work in the cannabis
industry you're not uh you're not a girl
you're not a hash maker but you're on
the other end you're uh you're the
computer nerd that we all need your do a
lot of stuff from what I know on the
HuffPost I see tweeting a lot of cool
stuff about cannabis you're an activist
in my mind that's part of why I wanted
to have you on my show do to speak for
us you're well-written well-spoken yeah
I like to think of the last five years
is working on a doctorate in cannabis
but other people might call it
unemployed or self-employed or weed
employed it kind of employed I'm kind of
employed so what kind of mark do you
want to leave like when when you're gone
when the earth blows up and somebody
reads a book about Mike what do you want
it to say honestly it would be amazing
if my name was in some of the history
books as part of this huge experiment
going on in Colorado right now about one
of the first big names to do it
incredibly right and if I could just put
you two in a warehouse and chained you
there for a year like that would be done
Mike Rowe in the front me on the grow
keV on the hat right if I could just
enslave you to and keep Jeff in the
garden and Kev in the hash room and I'd
have to chain myself to the front desk
to if they can't believe I can't believe
this is fair
but if that could happen my name would
fully be cemented in history is is the
[ __ ] golden Coors brewery of southern
Colorado I know that for a fact that
would be way cool there'd be way cool to
have my brothers accomplish that sort of
thing that would be a lot of fun yeah
definitely be so much fun to playing in
the mountain and just saw weed with you
to for the rest of his life we have some
better songs but yes I like the idea of
Loompas little people and that was a
free promo if you're a meat eater and
want a weed job I suppose you should
call me I'm one of those hippie types
y'all I don't need any animals got a
bunch of people that just met us or just
he doesn't mean grilled cheese but by
that folks that doesn't count I like
some falafel and hippy [ __ ] man all
right well we had a topic we want to
discuss put it back on a serious note
here a recent article that came out
written by Ricardo Baca in the Denver
Post an independent Denver Post study of
several marijuana infused product shows
wide variances in THC levels and edibles
versus labeling so what that means is uh
apparently they acquired some edibles
and they took them to a testing facility
they took them to Steve Hill Halen labs
and they tested them and the labels did
not match the test finding so on read a
little bit further for you guys before I
do I had a couple dabs before the show
sorry about the the wobbly voice trying
to read out loud on the on a microphone
so it says is one of the largest
producers marijuana infused edibles in
Colorado dr. J's hash infusion makes
chocolate
caramels and candies but many of the
company's products contain only a minut
fraction of the THC promised on dr. J's
labels according to independent tests
organized by the Denver Post 1 dr. J's
milk chocolate stars bar labeled for a
thousand milligrams of THC had and pay
attention here point three seven
milligrams of valued psychoactive
component according to three tests
conducted by steep hill Halon of
Colorado a state licensed marijuana
testing facility another dr. J's another
popular dr. J's chocolate bar the 100
milligram winter mint flavor the page is
refreshing that's cute let me scroll the
heck down there we go winter mint flavor
tested similarly in two experiments
showing 0.28 milligrams of THC so
basically these chocolate bars cost
about 10 bucks plus tax
and they promised to have a hundred
milligrams of THC in there and you
basically just bought a Hershey bar or I
can't I don't know shouldn't say a brand
name you bought a regular chocolate bar
off of the shelf is basically what you
got at least the regular dollar
chocolate bar up by the register at the
quick way is standardized and like
there's always gonna be kind of what you
ordered the stuff they're cooking in
their kitchens if they can't get the THC
that they're trying to put in it in it
does it even taste like food or taste
like blue leather dude it those numbers
you need a hundred of those things to
get one normal 25 milligram dose right
yeah at that point you've diabetes for
one dose so you're gonna have diabetes
and funky
that's ridiculous so I'm gonna continue
on it says they need to work on their
process as Joseph Evans laboratory
director it steep hill Halen who's a
really cool guy by the way shout out to
the guys at steep hill halen yeah
they've been attacked over this and
everything I've heard and known about
steep hill hamlet is all gold star type
information you ever heard anybody whine
about any chicken I know those guys
personally they don't pay me a penny
they're friends of mine they're business
partners of mine I have my products
tested with steep hill
Graeme Gatsby Joseph Evans and Addison
de Moura are the three guys that I'm
friends with they're straight-up dudes
they have no
reason to lie no reason to make anything
up they do good business they're making
our industry much better they're
improving every day so from me from
Kevin - thank you very much I didn't
appreciate check them out steep hill
Halen labs that's enough about that when
they say this says they need to work on
their process as Joseph Evans laboratory
director it's deep hill Halen I don't
know that it's irresponsible but it's
non-professional which is pretty much
how I feel yeah
the evolving marijuana industry is still
finding its way in Colorado and one of
the evolving aspects is the testing or
lack thereof products the state
marijuana Enforcement Division enacted
new regulations last week and more
changes are to come in May and in
October for people that aren't from
Colorado or aren't familiar with all
this there's some mumbo jumbo and here
the marijuana Enforcement Division that
is the division that oversees all of the
dispensary regulations rules and taxing
they're attached to the IRS they're able
to randomly show up at your dispensary
on any day that business is being
conducted they can open up all your
business records they can open up all
your saves saves safe so boxes where you
keep money they can open those parking
lot everything cars in the parking lot
they go through the bathrooms if they
feel like it if they find like a roach
or a pipe or something you can be in
trouble I don't know exactly what they
do about that but you can be screwed so
there are strict rules and everything in
these medical and recreational centers
are under camera from there everything
yeah you walk in the door to the minute
you pay your money
[Music]
they require these cameras and read it
perfectly so there yeah yeah they've got
their stuff under control and they're
just popping in and inspecting places so
that's that's the place that's involved
and responsible for this and they're
coming out with new regulations all the
time they're trying to get it under
control
so I'll continue the article but as the
marijuana industry looks ahead to the
potential of regular mandatory testing
dr. J's problems seemed deeper than a
bad batch or two the two bars that both
tested for less than 1/2 milligram of
THC were purchased two months and 40
miles apart from each other and they
were separated by 282 batches or roughly
70,000 units so this couldn't have been
just like a fluke batch or something
this was this was definitely like yeah
this is all that that's that's [ __ ] up
that's definitions their business model
being found out wide about it but it's
like if eleven of the twelve pop cans in
your 12-pack were empty or just full of
water like yeah it's insane it's it's if
they're 200 batches apart that's a
business practice it's or a huge flaw in
their business practice is it minimum if
you produce a hundred batches of
chocolate bars do it probably do it
playing with the toys in front of these
kids podcast the [ __ ] out shout out to
Fong who made the cool ice torch that
we're using things are awesome so uh I'm
gonna read a little bit I have something
to add to what you were saying but I
want to read a little bit more to get
this through this article before we
weren't too much you get distracted the
next he has a little header it says
enter enforcement agency hundreds of
customers have complained about dr. J's
products at least three recreational pot
shops dropped the brand entirely others
said they won't carry them and the
grousing has the attention of the
medical marijuana Enforcement Division I
gotta turn down your mics I think so and
be crazy loud but go for it I can learn
how to do it today
try to drop that torch out of there
sorry Oh an independent Post study of
several products showed the THC levels
and edibles are never exactly what the
package reads so that's never a good
sign
that's never a good sign so mile heights
candies watermelon drops you're labeled
labeled at 100 milligrams of THC but
they actually contained 17 that's a
failure in my mind that's a huge failure
Incredibles Mile High mint chocolate bar
advertises 100 milligrams of THC but
instead included 146 now keep that in
your mind for a minute so I want to read
the next one big shout out to the
growing kitchen the growing kitchens
Chocolate Chunk cookie tested at 100
milligram 101 milligrams on our products
labeled for 100 so you were one
milligram off which that's doing it
right my opinion good job guys big love
to the growing kitchen check those guys
out by their edibles the Chocolate Chunk
cookie
it's [ __ ] what it's at so something
I've said to keep in your head
146 milligrams and an edible that's
listed at a hundred for getting one and
a half times your dose I'm okay with
that but you and me are but the general
public that's I I'm a caregiver I am
registered caregiver for five patients
and I have two people that if I fed them
that they would probably get mad at me
it could definitely if I had stuff to do
that day and I was expecting say half of
a hundred milligram dose to start my day
off with that I really got 75 instead of
50 by half a night that could mess up a
good portion of my day this is medical
marijuana yeah tested product what if
this company gave me a vicodin and I
just thought I took it's a 750
milligrams just took what is that
thousand milligrams right that's
probably I'm gonna be [ __ ] up I can't
yeah right let's go to work now 1250
yeah whatever somebody were you guys get
the damn point please
[Laughter]
it's not a math Bowl I already forgot
the numbers I said no this is a product
of the industry being on the fringe
still it's we're only months removed
from this industry completely the people
that went to school and learn the skills
that it takes to put an exact number of
milligrams of THC in a little fun sized
candy bar haven't moved into this
industry and then numbers great enough
to really provide awesome product
standards across the board with edibles
clearly who came in one above one off a
growing kitchen the growing kitchen has
got somebody who really knows what
they're doing I understand that the the
folks in charge of making the capsules
and the oils of Charlotte's Web that
were given to the kids with seizures of
also taking great lengths the standard
I'd they're jealous exactly clearly
other people haven't bothered to do any
of that well they're trying but I mean a
lot of this stuff came from mom-and-pop
operations that had to grow and expand
quickly true but if you're shooting for
a hundred and you're getting 15 either
you're a [ __ ] or your math is seriously
flawed then I skip the paragraph where
the owner of there if that company
argued saying that they had to be better
I may have skipped a paragraph I
apologize if I did I'm skimming through
immediately making Storybrooke yeah oh
do you want to keep reading shut up no
keep going cuz you're gonna cover what I
miss when this story broke the first day
it was published on the Denver Post and
in the cannabis the industry responded
immediately with their lying or their
testing methods were off or some other
nonsense this quote he said I would be
in shock if those tests were accurate
said dr. J's CEO I'm not gonna butcher
your last name doctor his name's Tom
we're on top of the business in Colorado
I wouldn't be in business this long if
we weren't doing things right
ninety-nine percent of the time
I think 99 percent of people for the
last year just didn't know what they
were buying I'm speechless on your
answer sorry I paused and nodded and
nobody on a pond
can see me POP if it was any other I
mean I go back to if it was any other
product if somebody told you that you
know two out of four Ford's just burst
into flames on the road
would you ever even consider by what
again that's [ __ ] up I've been looking
at a Ford sorry
Ford if that's not true for it I love
you I've driven many Ford's for many
years thank you for like it's just silly
do you've if you can't produce a
standardized product you need to to
rethink what you're doing and and reset
your kitchen now clearly they're failing
miserably and now anyone in Colorado can
just walk into a testing facility inside
I think this chocolate bars Blanc I
saved two bites test it for me that's
strange I mean it's gonna cost him a few
bucks but if I got a hundred dollars I
think it you'll get more in a lawsuit
saying I've tried to buy my medicine
from dr. J and shafted me that's a good
point well I bet you a lot of
dispensaries are gonna drop dr. J before
too long and I was gonna say it I'd be
surprised if that company is operating
under that management and under that
name in six months six months ladies and
gentlemen today is the day after st.
Patrick's Day March 18 March 18th so
this won't go out for a little while I'm
gonna try to put a couple episodes
together before I throw them out there
get my [ __ ] together before I run so uh
Colorado medical or a marijuana is free
later I'm getting back into the article
by the way Colorado marijuana industry
leader Dixie elixirs tested at 60
milligrams of THC with its Dixie rolls
in the post study which are labeled at
100 milligrams that's sixty percent of
what you're paying for that's wrong it
is wrong so let's if I went to what's
worse if I want to what if you stopped
at a fast-food restaurant under way here
where would you have gone to get like a
drink or some sort of beverage I don't
do a lot of the fast food well I'm gonna
see Taco Bell we're gonna say Burger
Bell we're just gonna make up a spot
called burger Bell if you stopped at
[ __ ] burger Bell and you took off the
lid and your drink was only
three-quarters of 60% of the way full
you'd go back can you spit in this and
fill it the rest of the way up right now
if it was any other industry none of
these things
be acceptable at all none of these
things would be acceptable not ever you
got 60% of your dinner it are B's or 60%
of the gas I'm proud of somebody for
stepping up and doing this thanks to the
Denver Post for doing it and the steep
hill
so while continue while we were
disappointed to learn that the learn of
the post-test results we also know that
a testing can vary significantly from
one lab to the next disc C elixirs
that's hard to say when you're dabbed
out and reading quickly Dixie elixir CEO
Joe Hoda said regardless we will
continue to focus on our quality control
to be sure all of our products from
edibles tinctures and topicals reflect
agreed upon milligrams of THC so from
here on out they they're gonna do their
best they say maybe they can regain
their [ __ ]
I see a lot of freebies somewhere from
dr. J's you don't have to give a [ __ ]
ton of stuff away man I'm really hoping
this shakes through the whole industry
in Colorado from the edibles companies
that have clearly been doing some shady
business for the last several years down
to the shops that have been saying
they've got you know their Tora Bora
tests it I don't know what ten percent
THC 10 percent CBD like they've been
able to claim whatever without the
public having any real recourse to test
that right and like if your beer says it
was at three point three percent and it
could be at any percent like that causes
real problems in society like having
this radiance standard is a good thing
it's part of the awesomeness that comes
with legalization none of this was
possible five years ago you know yeah
revolution boys a lot of knowledge
that's coming out now is possible
because of legalization right we can
have these labs like Steve Howe that can
test that for us and give us good
results and standardized results I've
seen a tour of their facility and it's
impressive it's really awesome
independent testing labs one of the
first thing that sprang up alongside the
legal weed industry in Colorado it was
really cool to see that that became like
a foundational component to it it's just
sad that the edible companies have done
such a bad job standardizing so far well
they can't now
you know maybe now they know it my mic
sounds weird my headphones I apologize
if it sounds goofy to your ears we'll
fix that fix it in post
alright I'll continue it says but if the
10 edibles tested in the exclusive Post
report no edible had the THC level
problems of dr. J's Evan said you're
taking less than a milligram of THC and
our product that says 100 Evan said if
people have no confidence in the
industry then there could be a sort of
backlash against the whole legal
marijuana movement yep so I'm gonna
finish the articles one paragraph since
how can these numbers be so disparate
while there's been much discussion over
testing guidelines it's still a
voluntary action for growers and makers
of marijuana infused products or mi pees
so again I just want to give credit to
who's the homie that wrote it Ricardo
Baca from the Denver Post now what they
tested was bang fire chocolate bar I've
had that that's a tastiness right there
it listed 180 milligrams it actually had
a hundred and fifty six milligrams not
too bad it's a lot closer yet I'm gonna
give that one a 6 I'll give that one a
thumbs up that's cool that's you missed
it by a little bit but I mean compared
to the competition what the hell can I
say
so dr. J's bars the milk chocolate
listed 100 milligrams guess how many bro
point four point four that's ridiculous
redonkulous if that's acceptable yeah so
what if you bought that what dude people
are relying okay right dr. J star bars
winter mint chocolate 0.3 they claim to
have a hundred dr. J star bars white
chocolate claim to have a hundred look
they stepped it up they got five out of
a hundred five percent like a five
milligram that's there dr. J's highest
test score was five per se that's why I
was excited for five milligrams and five
mil it's 5% cos it's 100 so it's that
was that's accurate for that one dr. J's
jellystone's they list a hundred they
got point two point two dude if you owed
me a hundred dollars and I showed up was
that twenty cents if I showed up with
twenty cents and threw it on the table
would you punch me in the damn mouth
well maybe not for the mouth for twenty
of a point well-taken like this is like
it's it it's irresponsible business
prayer if any other industry did this
they would not if your new car showed up
with no seats no tires no engine no
brakes no brakes like come on I'm a
caregiver I'm in this I fell in love I
worked at it I was a grower I was in
love with wheat I've been smoking weed
for years before I should admit it I
fell in love with cannabis years ago I
became an employee manager I ran a
dispensary I fell in love with watching
people fall in love with cannabis and
watch it improve their lives I'm a
caregiver I am involved in cannabis I
breed cannabis I like watching people
feel better the people I'm responsible
for that I'm a caregiver have they have
[ __ ] up conditions that I see I see it
I'm their friends and I watch them get
better consuming the medicine that I
produced that's when I'm in it for when
you're producing an edible that's listed
to have a hundred milligrams and only
has five you're taking money from a sick
[ __ ] person first of all a person
that no matter who you are you work hard
for your money no matter what you do now
you work hard for your money well most
of us work hard for our than others yes
but some of us have mommy and daddy's
money but that's a whole other podcast
you're ripping people off you're taking
money out of hard-working people that
trusted you to take care of them and now
they aren't medicated what about people
like brave mykayla what about people
that needed medicine what about people
like cash hide that rely on that sort of
thing and sorry to bring up people that
have passed and people that are sick but
those people needed medicine and if you
give them okay this will help you don't
rely on you exactly what was it girls
name from Utah that was doing the
Charlotte's Web sorry to disrespect but
that's people a good example if we gave
them medicine that was not what we
promised to give them they're not gonna
get it medicated and they're gonna get
sick again they'll go into remission and
we just ripped them off and gave them
cancer all over again and that was
[ __ ] up in my mind you that's not love
that's not compassion that's dollar
signs dr. J's on to give you guys the
opportunity to redeem yourselves I can't
pass you a hundred percent I'm not a
scientist I don't work for your company
I want you guys to get it back together
like to see you come through
and redeem yourselves please well you
know the Denver Post isn't done with
this in six months they're gonna do the
same thing they're gonna send the
reporters to 15 or 20 shops they're
gonna buy up less election edibles from
different shops they're gonna take them
back to steep hill and one of the other
testing labs and this reports coming out
again every couple of months I hope so
until it comes back with 80 or 90% of
the products tested or scoring right
where they should I mean there's no
reason that I mean edibles have always
been hit or miss but when you're working
in a kitchen trying to make can of
butter or can of oil and then make them
into an edible product for you and a
couple of friends the process is
different and being unevenly dispersed
throughout the batch is less important
and that sort of always been true with
edibles you're gonna make make a tray of
brownies one brownie will wreck you for
30 hours another brownie won't do
anything but when you're selling it as a
medicine and as a standardized product
in the store it can't waiver your your
10 milligrams should always be a 10 your
hundred should always be an absolute
about this conversation so comfortable
though like Jeff and I had had a
conversation right after he came back
from meeting the guys at steep hill
about how your terpene molecules and
things like that can be dispersed
differently throughout your like slab of
hash that's why I depending on what part
of the slab of hash you get done
watching this sample so there you go I
think that could also be true with the
canna butters and the kind of oils and
it all gets dispersed differently so
when you make it it would it's it's it
is very difficult to to get that
completely spread across the board
Jeff's brought me Kevin's brought me
slabs a hash that and sometimes I get
you know 10 to 30 grams from him
sometimes when he does it he's making
the shape of a pie plate or a frisbee
with my hands so those of you who can't
see through the radio now I was trying
to measure how many grams that
so and sometimes I we can see the
puddles of different I don't know if
it's terpenoids or flavonoids or there's
another one that the name just left my
head right now Paley it's I think is
what they may be and I can't identify
them by the puddles but you could see
that there's any of you dad from
different sections they taste different
you can see the different layers of
stuff yeah like you're different
different layers of the pie and it's
different oils separating at different
textures so that's a good defense for
these edibles and I agree with you there
maybe maybe they cooked them
tipped up this way the horizontally no
that's vertically maybe they cook them
vertically and all the goodies ran down
to the bottom bite and they tested the
top bite but those edibles are not a
hundred 100 milligrams is too much of a
dose for the recent person I've been
treating that's too much for him he
needs half of that so if he it's hat he
expects to get half of it when he splits
it in half he doesn't think I'm gonna
get [ __ ] roller-coaster the first
time and just be bored the second time
if the fact we're talking about is
what's causing dr. J's test results that
means that there are dr. J's edibles out
there with several hundred milligrams of
THC per dose rather than the single
hundred they're advertising which is
just as and I don't think that's the
case with dr. J's it is probably the
case with some of the others that were
testing white chocolate star bars and
winter mint chocolate maybe that shit's
stirring up and it's getting a little
puddle on one side or maybe it's stuck
to the wrapper we got to give them a
little bit of those yeah maybe these
idiots are cooking it off in their ovens
a little too hot or something cooking it
at 400 degrees for 30 minutes that's a
good I'm just saying they had a rogue
employee rip them off if they're doing
dr. J's company like the good folks
there have no idea maybe there's one it
takes one bad apple and your whole
company to [ __ ] produce a whole seven
units seven thousand units of [ __ ] up
chocolate bars knowing this
of Dixie elixir and Sheba choose in some
of those other major companies
operations I can see how their numbers
kinda went all over the place these last
couple of months because their
distribution quadruple I mean they're
they weren't prepared for the demand
that set their companies even a little
bit it's hard to predict [ __ ] blew up
here yet no one knew what was coming at
what the demand would be like and on top
of that none of these people were
allowed to produce product for the new
recreational market they had to transfer
over up to fifteen percent of their
existing inventory and this caused all
sorts of product interruptions and
shortages and in an effort to scramble
to catch up how much of these test
results are due to that just trying to
rush it it's a good point just trying to
rush it nobody we saw it coming but we
didn't know it was gonna happen like
this
and when a rack hit it was so hyped up
and everybody got anxious and [ __ ] like
we got pumped up I want to say another
thing I don't wanna scare everybody away
don't be afraid of dispensaries and
edibles this is one company out of I'm
gonna read off more brands at a pure
lemon drops hard candies listed a
hundred percent they tested it 45 mile
high candies watermelon drops listed 100
they tested at 17 Dixie elixirs Dixie
rolls 100 listed 60 actual here's a good
one for us
blue kudou cookies and cream chocolate
bar listed 100 they came in at a hundred
and five I'll give them props just like
everything on the Shelf asked the
budtender which one people come back and
buy a budge from is right there are two
I don't even know if I want to say the
company name but there's to know if you
got something you like you can say dude
she would choose is awesome they're
gonna listen to them their number on
this test was disappointing me i it hurt
to know a company that I've supported
vocally good score you should do I mean
I'm not being a smartass to your answer
you should do the math you because the
number the recommended dose is smaller
than the rest so I'm gonna keep reading
we'll get to that growing kitchens
Chocolate Chunk cookie listed 100 we
talked about that came in at 101 much
love again mad respect for that
Incredibles mile-high mint chocolate
listed a hundred milligrams came in at
146 that's dangerous you guys I know I'm
a pothead you're a pothead we can handle
it but there are patients out there and
people from Texas that haven't had a lot
of they're not ready for what they're
gonna get hit with no I bought an
Incredibles I went to dispensary looking
for Chiba chooses actually what I wanted
they didn't have him and they had
Incredibles on sale and I bought the
mile-high mint and I bought a what's the
to monkey bar I love that [ __ ] monkey
bar bro and I ate I hate them both I was
wrecked I was really really high and I'm
a professional bro they both had to be
overdosed cuz I was so here's Mike's
favorite Chi but you quat dough soft
candies which is usually my go-to edible
if I gotta go somewhere to eat inedible
they say they have 70 milligrams they
came in at 53 right I am that's not
nearly as bad as some of the other
companies on there but still there
what's the percentage did you do it I
didn't do it Oh 70 53 divided by 70
right that's right it's still a shortage
of I mean if you're paying for seven do
you expect I did they came in better
than a lot of the companies in my
experience with them is it's a
consistent product it's a good product
like the flavors decent I love their red
Hornet candies or the Green Hornet candy
yeah it was sad to see that they weren't
right on the money
that was the first thing I look for when
I saw that article came out I scan for
she would choose results my favorites
Joey Diaz likes to call him the Cibo to
that she believes no freaking Tebow chew
on [ __ ] wreck top so the last one on
our list is sweet stone candy fruit
loops big love it's listed 50 50
milligrams came in at 45 so shout out to
plot the Candyman and Melissa yeah the
whole sweets don't seem cool freaking
people man not just the honorable makers
but they will see they're not a huge
operation they're not doing millions of
units out of a warehouse right I don't
know there are business I can't another
product is good and the Claude is a cool
[ __ ] dude and that Melissa smiles
every time you waver at her and smile
every time I see cloudy if you smile at
him and say what's up bro and high-five
him and he will give you a cloudy bear
to eat a cloudy day keeps the haters
away [ __ ] Claudia bears you just got a
big ol promo from me Claude much love
bro well guys we've gone 45 minutes you
want to wrap up the first episode here
and call it a success give some promos
to make sure you check out our genetics
Steve Hill hey check out my buddies at
top shelf extracts there you go
if you run into any old elevated
concentration stuff on the internet
might be fun to look at there you go and
next time the whole cannabis community
dude so cannabis can worry
hey you just got your ticket for the
cannabis cup didn't you I did did you
get a two day or one day today we'll be
there both days we're not going together
but we will definitely you'll see us
hanging out together this is hanging out
apart will be doing dad's we smoking
balls smoking fat joints saying hi to
people look for me will be cannabis
cupping Mike you got any cool [ __ ] to
say for the end of the show nope nope
stick to flowers and hash people clearly
edibles don't have a nailed down yet
[ __ ] words from the wise bro hey I
want to thank you guys for joining me on
my first show you guys my bros you've
been with me since I was [ __ ] grown we
eat in my mom's basement back in the day
that means a lot to me Mike's trimmed a
lot of my weed Kevin's [ __ ] smoked a
good portion of that [ __ ] thank you I
want to thank everybody they listen dude
that was our first episode I wanna call
it a success as the iGrow culture
podcast dude we have a Twitter it's a
tie grow culture if you want to hear
about something growing
smoking something about Colorado if you
want to say hi if you want to tell me to
[ __ ] off please do that's at at
agriculture I'm also at Rasta Jeff 420
but you know the talk goes everybody be
good to yourselves be good to underneath
one another I'm already [ __ ] slurred
and stumble and hey take a phat dad for
me give your mom a hug peace
[Music]
it's gonna be really loud it's too loud
we play we've got plenty of songs tasks
rock songs covered yeah hydro has plenty
of bad songs down it what's up ladies
and gentlemen happy hump day podcast
world welcome to episode number two the
iGrow culture podcast this podcast is
brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for info on Hydra genetics
mile high Sin City and Gabe green
genetics also use coupon code Ivy to 14
for 10% off and you'll always get free
shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com done dab the [ __ ] out I'm over
here try not to cough into the
microphone pre-show dab session over
here
oh we're hanging out on a Wednesday
night we got Kevin's back Kevin from
elevated concentrations and a little bit
we're gonna play a phone interview that
I did with Addison tomorrow from Steve
pillow labs we'll get into that but
what's up bro how you doing Kevin I'm
doing pretty good yourself I'm doing I
read awesome thanks for having me again
I appreciate it thanks for coming back
and figured out you'd be a good guest to
have yeah the topic tonight is gonna be
about hash and when we talk about hash
my favorite topic sometimes you sound
like you're full of [ __ ] but when
attached to you I believe I try to keep
up on my hash knowledge and most of my
cannabis knowledge you do well in our
group we have a nice we're a cannabis
encyclopedia in our group it's pretty
cool one of us has the answer sweet well
the reason we all the reason we're
gathered here today we I wanted to talk
about the secret cup the secret cup was
this past weekend in California should
tell you guys about the secret cup the
secret cup is a pretty exclusive hash
competition the competition part is
invite only you have to be invited by
Big D shout out to Big D for hosting a
super sweet exclusive hash event
definitely we've competed Kevin and I
have competed together I grew across
and Kevin extracted it and made pretty
tasty dads out of it I was satisfied
with our results as a first-time
competitor
yeah me too especially just a year into
it so that was really nice to see where
I fit in and we did well we we placed
respectfully doubly respectfully top ten
finish it was both yeah yeah once and
again we'll do it so the secret cup is
the competition part is invite only if
you want to go hang out you kind of just
gotta know how to get tickets they don't
really advertise a lot you got to know
who to know if you're in the loop you'll
end up at the secret cup yeah definitely
it's so the way they do it every
competitor brings his hash to the entry
table and they divide it into small
samples and every competitor gets to
actually be a judge so they all take
dabs of all the stuff that's out there
so I find it to be a pretty fair
competition because it's judged by the
competitors which keeps it fair that I
just repeated myself and I mean it's who
better to judge some hash than a bunch
of hash makers and hash connoisseurs you
judge it against your peers are you
gonna join again that are we gonna
participate again this year bro I'm game
I'll be entering big deal if you hear
this I read genetics and elevated
concentrations want to come participate
in the secret Cup again once again it
was a great time last year so much fun
with all the competitors and everything
and they're all such great people and
it's just fun to put our stuff together
and try everybody's dabs this whole dad
community is amazing from we've got
musicians they entertain us while we're
dabbing we've got people that come and
bring medicated and non-medicated food
that are part of the scene I don't just
see them I don't see them at any other
events other than cannabis related but I
see them at every cannabis related event
vending food we got people that make
pipes for us that are in our groups like
in our industry we got people that are
making our extracts we got clothing we
got pin companies we're all friends now
yeah it's kind of a neat little
community industry I guess that's what
you call it it's a family bro if you're
honest and real and not a dick you're
pretty much accepted and
and well and even if you are a dick
we'll let you into the crew because
every crew needs a couple of dicks yeah
that sounds really gross their dicks out
there but they know what they're talking
about when it comes down to serious [ __ ]
so so you have to respect him this is a
weird segue
speaking of deities a lot of people are
frustrated and hating on steep hill
halen labs but I find what they did to
be I think it was legit every sample
that runs through the secret cup is
tested through a lab and they used steep
hill Halen labs which is I know the
representatives grimy Gatsby that's John
Hunt and I also know Addison demora Earl
Ripper check him out and also I'm
friends with Joe he's one of the I don't
know your official position brother I'm
sorry but you're a good bro I know that
those guys are cool guys from the Cpl
Halen they tested every sample that went
through there and they found some pretty
interesting results almost every single
sample that was entered into the secret
Cup was it would not have passed
California Standards or Colorado
standards for what they call clean and
safe BHO it all contained a chemical
called pentane it's actually a gas
called pentane which is part of butane
so uh are you ready to play the clip bro
yeah we've got a clip from Addison de
Moura I guess are you ready to listen is
what I should have asked we're gonna uh
yeah we're gonna play the little clip
with Addison let me pull it up here and
my Kevin and I we're gonna turn off the
microphones take a couple of dabs and
we'll listen with you because Kevin
hasn't heard it yet so here goes this is
my interview with Addison de Moura from
steep hill halite Laboratories hey
Addison it's Rasta Jeff with IRA
genetics I'm calling you from the iGrow
culture podcast how you doing buddy
record you from the phone and myself at
the same time without blowing something
up hey thanks but I think I got it
figured out how are you doing bro
[Music]
well make sure you tell those dudes I
said hello so where was a good bromide
and you mean Adam Dunn is Adam Dunn the
Adam when you're hanging out with
awesome well make sure you tell both of
those guys that Rasta Jeff amira genetic
says hello
cool bro thanks a lot
hey what's your official title over
there at steep hill hey wow that's a
good place to start excuse my uh my my
voice here it's 4:20 in Colorado is just
participating in 4:20 all the time
especially when he got swerve and Adam
done in the house I bet you guys are
having a good time over there
nice the main reason I wanted to get you
on my show this is the second episode of
my podcast I really wanted to get you on
your a big member of our community what
my topic was the secret Cup was happened
last weekend and steep hill hail had the
honor of testing every sample that was
entered into the cup and from what I've
read you guys have discovered pentane or
other contaminants and nearly every
sample that was entered I'm hoping that
maybe you can educate myself and my
listeners about what you guys do and
[Music]
we
[Laughter]
[Music]
I think to do stuff is to cause a stir
in this command I really appreciate that
as but that was great
what to be dangerous and how dangerous
[Music]
well I'm a heavy dabber and I hang out a
lot of heavy dabbers and I'm a member of
the community and we all appreciate what
steep hills doing keeping us safe and
you guys are revolutionising medicine
you guys are keeping us all safe and
healthy and I appreciate it
[Music]
I'd rather some feelings speaking of
growth what's in the future for steep
hill is beautiful oh that lab is
beautiful I've been in that lab
[Music]
I'm proud of you guys I'm proud of you
guys and I appreciate it so well what's
in the future for adding it what's in
the future for Addison tomorrow what do
you want to do it's do it is do what
kind of mark do you want to leave on our
on our community my friend what kind of
mark when when the world is coming to an
end and we're reading history books and
they say that Addison demora
what kind of mark do you want to leave
on this world what do you want people to
say about you and your respectable
answer my friend I appreciate that
did you have any you have any plugs you
want to give shoutouts or anything
before we say goodbye to each other
I really appreciate you being my first
phone interview on my show it was kind
of awkward for me but I'm getting used
to it now I was really good having a
friend to do it for me so I really
appreciate that dude if you have
anything you want to add you've got my
phone number feel free to call me
anytime
keep in touch with me on Facebook dude I
love you guys I love what you're doing
give everybody out there a hug and a
high-five for me hey man go spend some
time with your kids you deserve it
[Music]
appreciate you Lauren bro I really
appreciate you and I hope we talk again
soon take care yourself brother peace
and love ladies and gentlemen that was
my first phone interview ever I was with
mr. Addison tomorrow from steep hill got
a lot of education to give us there feel
like I just got a hash education for
free yeah that was pretty cool actually
it was neat to hear some of the things
he said especially towards the end about
a lot of the specifics on the testing
that they're doing because I didn't
really know much about that end of it a
lot of the beginning stuff I was I was
pretty much privy to I guess you could
say and just kind of holding it in
myself so it's neat to kind of have some
of the things I've been thinking about
and some of my concerns also validated
through somebody who's so respected in
the industry me being you know beginner
doesn't that always feel good yeah it's
it's neat like it's it's just different
you're accidentally doing [ __ ] right
yeah exactly
all right so once again a big huge thank
you to Addison tomorrow thanks addy we
love you for that buddy check out our
old Ripper I'm not sure how he spells it
we'll find
before the end of the show that he's got
some cool pictures
get your stuff tested by steep hill I
always trust everything that they tell
me they've got a good clean lab I've
been there I don't they don't pay me to
say that I like it that's the only
reason I talk about him and also to the
secret I where did I come from a bad
southern thing that's a great couple you
guys were listening to all the secret
cup competitors whose concentrates were
tested were not uh we're not calling you
out we're not trying to dis you or
anything we just this was the example
that we had this is where the results
came from I know that you guys will get
together and fix your tech and you guys
will figure out how to do this yeah and
we'll see where everyone else is that
too because like like a DS Addison said
it's that's the first time they've done
that test for the secret cup so it'll
kind of we'll see when we go to the
other regions what what the rest of our
hash tests at and if it's similar or if
it's you know some more way different or
who does what you know he did also
mention that they'll even the butane is
the highest concentrate concentration
high most highly concentrated them that
was hard to find butane is the most
highly concentrated residual solvent
left in dads at their finding and he
said that that is not even at a
dangerous level if you consider other
applications that we're using butane for
so we don't need to quit dabbing just
because of a little pentane scare this
is just the new thing we figured out
Mystery Oil we've learned how to get rid
of Mystery Oil we're we're a smart bunch
we're gonna learn us together yeah the
more we work with it and the more we
develop and the more we learn about it
the better we can make everything and we
can make things you know just like we've
already keeps we already keep stepping
it up as a community keep making things
better and better and easier and more
safe and all that so you know that's
that's what it takes takes a community
and we all pitch in a little bit and
every time you bring me back about your
hash it's a little bit better every
single thank you I learned from every
batch ash I learned something from every
single batch if you pay attention to it
you will I mean it's just a natural
hollow sherry
a website with you I got a scroll down
to find it but once I get to this
website it's where a few of our highly
respected hash community members it's
where they find and share their
information so it'll be useful to
everybody get a pen to write that down
I gotta also remember to give you the
correct at Earl Ripper Instagram just
scroll through Instagram and look for at
er RL Ripper it's close to that you'll
find him there's pictures of this dude
named Madison he looks like that uh that
Mexican drug cartel that just got busted
I thought that was really funny yeah
kind of does look like that guy so one
cool thing that I heard in there that
caught my attention they don't reveal
this solvents they're testing for well
yeah kind of neat I thought that was
interesting kinda like that I think it's
I think it's much less biased and I
think it just makes it really fair for
everyone you know just try to make the
best hash you can make and we'll test it
and find out there you go you know and
then we'll share information to let you
know what's going on after we're done
testing and that's kind of nice you know
yeah well that's and now we know to get
rid of that to that kind of exactly so
what we learned the one I give you a big
thumbs down in the middle of that while
he was talking Terps terpenes terpenoids
their terpenoids if you don't know the
whole word you got to read the
definition of terpenoids and read what
those are once you know what terpenoids
are than you can say terms also if you
say try chromes or trichomes it's TR IC
H ome yes it's a trichome there's no
Chrome
we're not polishing it I just want to
help you people be educated I'm not
trying to be an [ __ ] even though I
feel like one sudden these terpenoids
I'm speaking of boil at the same
temperatures as pentane so when you're
trying to purge off your pentane
you're [ __ ] destroying Detroit's and
the Terps are but the second one of my
favorite second favorite part of the
hash for me and that was an interesting
part for me because when he started
mentioning you know using the closed
loop and the cold trap and how it's
getting us to these you know safe levels
and things we can do to further advance
our concentrates I've been
it's something I've been talking about
with a close group of friends of mine
that we should have been at this point
when we first started so do you know
know that and I think we should have
been using closed-loop systems and cold
traps and all that when concentrates
first when I first learned how to make
decent concentrates I was like dude we
should have been doing this way
differently for a long time now the
money there and the money that you
invested in the material that I invested
could have been better used towards but
we didn't know that yeah exactly
this thing's always evolving yeah and
then I can't complain about any of the
hash you've made in the past so I don't
how long you been how long have you been
killing it about a year friends place
yeah since then you've been crushing it
you learn things from Denver and Springs
that impressed me yeah so you know how
to compensate and are you gonna do you
know do you have an idea how to figure
out how to remove the pentane you got to
go to I took a couple of notes from
another spot I think it's a hundred and
six degrees is where pentane starts to
boil off and that's also where the
triple anoints burn off so how are you
gonna do you have an idea of how to
compensate for all that stuff you that's
what he was talking about with that cold
trap you're gonna be able to suck those
gases out in the cold traps there's like
three chambers and they have different
filters in them so they all trap
different things and one of them traps
terpenoids and so you you just
reintroduce that back into the hash
afterwards so you can you trap your
terpenes that you lose and you
reintroduce it back into the hash the
the pentane is not the same molecule
structure or the same size as the
terpenoids but it does boil off at a
similar temperature okay I understand
what you're saying yeah I catch you it's
it's a filtration system and a cold trap
system so between the you put the cold
trap between the vacuum pump and your
vacuum oven or chamber Wow so as you're
you're vacuuming that that gas through
it traps stuff and it
let's stuff through that sounds [ __ ]
brilliant I'm the breeder and the grower
they're expensive
that sounds to sciency for me they're
awesome and I would ruin that I feel I
feel so comfortable with the plants and
breeding and growing and here and see I
don't I feel very comfortable with
sciency stuff
tima for sure for sure so find us at the
secret cup this year in Denver
we'll be roaming around together I'm
tall I'm a white guy with dreadlocks I'm
sure we're wearing hoodies and
grassroots hats you know we'll have our
genetic shirts or elevated concentration
shirts or mixture of the two I'll have
red eyes so uh I look forward to it I
look forward the Cannabis Cup is coming
up but I'm I'm just going I'm not
promoting it I don't have a booth there
anything I've got a bunch of friends
with booths we're gonna have a good time
so I read a post from a well-respected
member of the hash community on Facebook
no let me on Facebook I read a post he's
well respected everywhere not just on
facing clear about that [ __ ] this guy
throws this secret cup he throws the
dabs of Denver he he did the dabs of
Denver event and gave all of the
proceeds to a care center I don't know
the official word a care center so that
they could buy themselves a van to get
their residents to and from their
doctor's appointments and this dude puts
his heart and soul into what he does and
bro you got my mad loved the guy I'm
talking about his Big B he posts on
Facebook and I'm kind of terrified
paraphrasing and chopped into pieces
here so that it makes a good show but it
says a rat in a lab can handle 6,800
PPM's of pentane with every single
breath it takes for 120 hours straight
and have no discernable effects he also
advised to make sure that before you eat
BHO you don't you decarboxylase it and
that will make sure you get rid of most
residual carbons gasses things you don't
want
he also says excuse me dabs are clogging
me up
this is if you choose to inhale BHO
please make sure that you heat your dab
up to 600 degrees at least until it
vaporizes and then filter it through
water and by through water he doesn't
mean filter it he means use a bong a
water pipe a bubbler yeah yeah some
don't do the dry hit dabs and while
we're at it don't use shitty Chinese
import glass made by some [ __ ] little
kid without protective gear yeah please
buy american-made if you know a glass
blower try to support them indeed indeed
especially if they're good yeah they'll
get better you'll have something from
the beginning when they're in the glass
galleries next to our heroes what I bet
the people that have a coil piece from
back in the day or ultra proud what if
your next glassblower friend becomes
coil condenser man so man we're all
using the email and I I don't think a
lot of us are heating it to 600 degrees
because there's that low low temp dab
sensation that's been going on the craze
with the emails and carb cap yes is that
gonna be a thing of the past or are are
we too stubborn Diesel's
so well I that's gonna go that's gonna
change with technique and as people
develop their technique to get rid of
this pentane thing because it's just
like they said it evaporates the same at
a similar temperature as the terpenes so
if you're doing a low tamp dab well it
tastes better because you're conserving
more of the Terps and if you do a higher
temp tab you're getting rid of more of
the gas like he's saying yeah it doesn't
taste as good so that would only you
know that's makes sense most of the
people that dad was you know that I kind
of knocked the low temp dab thing that's
not my style I like those beer in the
middle kind of feels like you're
drowning and disco dancing at the same
time I love those dads I mean once we
start getting rid of a lot of these
gasses again and developing our
technique to be even better we're going
to be able to do those low temp
ABB's and not inhale however thousands
of ppm pentane big up to steep hill for
helping me not further harm my lungs
with useless garbage yes so a couple a
couple episodes where am i this is
number two it had to be the last episode
I'm pretty sure I bet so I bet that in
episode number one you said something
about dewaxing
you mentioned dewaxing sure did you are
gonna become my hash expert on my on my
little podcaster I hope you're aware of
that
[Music]
can you define and then here's my
disclaimer for you kids not a scientist
you did not go to science school don't
try this [ __ ] at home we're not
responsible be a [ __ ] that don't read
a book go to school read a book in the
book read a [ __ ] book I did
need some books but so yet don't sue us
and Kem's a hash maker not a scientist
or a professor or something like well
dewaxing from my knowledge is when as
you're making the concentrate in the
process you use cold temperatures to
separate plant fats and lipids and waxes
from the the oils because your your
cannabinoids and your terpenoids are
pretty much all oil form so slightly
different polarities with each of the
molecules what have you but the you the
cold actually separates the wax to the
bottom allows you to after time you know
you let it sit for a little while the
layers separate and then you can pour
the oil through a filter just in case
any of that wax is loose you can filter
it out with lab filter paper so at one
point you're basically you've got your
dabs where they're liquid I've seen at
that point it's slushy and now you're
pouring it into something and that's
settling essentially you have okay
yeah and the chunky part is what we
don't want to suggest plant paraffins
yeah what else is it lipids black
is and battles are like the cellular
structure of the plant right yes I want
to do an experiment and this is off
topic I want to see if we run silicates
potassium silicates in a plant if it
makes a difference on the amount of wax
you take out so what do you do that
if anybody has a grow room and you can
do that if you have a hash guy that is
doing this I'd like to see our potassium
silicates affecting our wax and dewaxing
processes and [ __ ] up our hash so
keep going dude I'm sorry to interrupt I
make the picture clear you got like this
big can't in my mind you've got a big
container of butane hash mixture he
parts sinking to the bottom yeah okay it
looks it's the opposite of beer the
heads on the bottom yeah okay and then
essentially that goes through a
filtration and this they make
essentially closed sealed dewaxing
chambers with regulators and all that
it's essentially the same process it
still needs to be in a cold bath to get
the separation all of that so you
transfer that oil into the hot water
bath or hot water container chamber
depends on the system everything's going
to closed-loop now so it's all
technically the same you still do it the
same way it's just all in a closed
system now which makes it much easier
safer higher quality definitely okay and
that just removes all that harmful plant
matter from from the concentrates
because a lot of what what causes the
congestion and the heavy harshness when
when you smoke flour is a lot of that is
is a carcinogenic plant matter now I've
also really that makes people puke
headaches headed no no we don't want
that you know medicine counterproductive
yeah definitely all right so now you've
taken you run it through a filtration
you pour that [ __ ] through like a funnel
and it filters out mm-hm and then then
it goes to the back purge essentially
yeah
and I think most of the hash makers
understand that uh and if you don't
understand that's cool because it's not
you're gonna have to do research we may
leave [ __ ] out so that you have to yeah
we don't want to guide you into yeah
[ __ ] yourself or any of my friends or
any of your patients uh yeah you use you
know screen mesh things like that to
filter whatever size of whatever you're
trying to get out do different two
different strains require different size
screen meshes like when you're making
the oval from when I've noticed yes
different different strains have
different trichome sizes and that will
affect your yield in extraction if you
don't use different filters sizes makes
complete sense and it will affect your
purity levels to think if you if you
have smaller trichomes and you're using
a bigger filter you're gonna get a lot
more of that nasty whack stuff in there
oh yeah I can just at least solvent what
[ __ ] that makes so good good description
Brussels what more question I have about
that does that how does that affect your
yield is it worth you know I haven't
seen it affect my yield and enough of a
negative way to change what I'm doing it
since you started doing it for me the
hash hasn't come back like lighter yeah
yeah sweet yeah when you don't take out
the waxes I've noticed you get the heavy
lungs I dab with other people and I know
who is dewaxing and who's not usually
after a couple of times you can also
tell because if you don't do ax it'll
leave residual particles on your nail is
that why I got a replace and or scrape
my nail every once a while and I know I
shouldn't scrape it but I can't [ __ ]
replace it every day yeah dad like we do
over here you go through nails hey tasks
it's time for some new nails buddy I
need the the duality 14:18 please maybe
a couple of fluxes I know you can tell
me to go [ __ ] myself I'm just trying
buddy shout out the task Rock do that
first year with plenty of good titanium
keeps me uh keeps me davon I need to get
one of those Trinity nails soon for my
new rig that's coming there you go
give that guy shout out that glass oh I
don't know his frickin last name I don't
know his company I don't find out what
he wants to be called it's all happy
I'll be back he'll give this all figured
out all the information cuz he's a
badass got a pretty cool new rig going
it's good so so you're ready to go to
the closed-loop and cold packs aren't
you yeah dude I really yeah I just
recently became employed so it's gonna
be a second unless my job wants to start
hooking it up on concentrate equipment
so we can get something go in there but
I like to do what I do so you know the
more I can step up my game and the more
I can advance my process technique
equipment more I'll do so oh I kind of
hinted that I was gonna share a website
I've got to look up real quick I want to
scroll through this I've saved a couple
of yeah you did I know and I don't want
to why - our friends cuz we've got oil
listen there's it's two episodes and
they've paid attention this far skunk
farm research calm farm with the pH
research calm skunk farm research calm
shout-out to Big D he's the one that
told me they're posted on Facebook that
that was a good site to look for hash
information you know I need to tract
myself lower temps the boiling point of
pentane is 97 degrees I said 9606 yeah I
did see I'm [ __ ] lying
yes it's 97 which I just want to be
accurate yeah so yeah I just wanna track
some things now I'm gonna introduce a
new part of the show I'm gonna create a
segment here it's called gift Thanks
it's a segment where I want to give
thanks to somebody who has contributed
heavily to the cannabis world and
deserves some thanks so this this
episode we're gonna give thanks to mr.
mark Emery yeah yeah if you don't know
who mark Emery is he's in a bunch of
movies he's in what's it called super
high me with Doug Benson he's the guy
that talks forever forever Doug looks
like he took a nap while he was there
it's like a six-foot bong it's probably
five feet four or five feet maybe six
and just talks his ass off he's got
those droopy he looks like was it droopy
the dog the remember don't be droopy the
dog yeah he looks like that who's got
the droopy eyes because all the [ __ ]
weed he smoked he's a Canadian guy but
we won't hold that against him
Marc Emery I'm gonna read a little bit
about him Marc Emery is a Canadian
cannabis reform policy advocate who is
currently serving five years in American
federal prison for selling cannabis
seeds keep in mind I said American
federal prison that's gonna come into
play later Marc ship seeds from Canada
to the United States and he was charged
with conspiracy to manufacture marijuana
Marc was the publisher of culture album
sorry I'm stuttering here Marc was a
publisher of cannabis culture magazine
and once ran for the Mayor of the City
of Vancouver so the students not a
criminal I call Marcus soldier you know
that's cheesy as [ __ ] right thank you
mark started mark started mark Emery
direct marijuana seeds in 1995 which he
ran until it was rated by Vancouver
police acting on a request of the United
States Drug Enforcement Administration I
want to say that again more clearly
without stuttering
this dude was raided by the Vancouver
Police acting on the request of the
United States Drug Enforcement
Administration so America called Canada
and was like this guy is pissing us off
it's illegal you [ __ ] with him and they
did it dude that's it's kind of [ __ ]
he wasn't even there how do you she's in
another country and America is just
overstepping their boundaries in my
opinion and going and pulling this dude
if you went to if you went to James
highest elementary school and a Kevin
elementary school some [ __ ] went down
James high school isn't gonna come and
get you that the schools aren't gonna
trade your ass it's [ __ ] where you do
your where you do your crime is where
you do your crime where you did your
time and there was no crime in my
opinion so it's all [ __ ] all right
I'm on a train right here I'm gonna read
keeps me focused Marc Emery was taken
into custody on September 28th of 2009
and held at the North Fraser
pretrial center in the
see - oh wait sorry I cut and pasted
this and I missed something but I'll
keep going - wait he was held there -
wait extradition to the USA and on May
the 10th of 2010 Justice Minister Rob
Nicholson signed the order and ordered
Emery to surrender to authorities which
he did this same day [ __ ]
on May 10 2010 jester Menace justice
minister Nicholson ruled Emery be
extradited to the United States where
Mark faced five years in the US penal
system the possibility existed that
Emery may be allowed to serve all or
part of his sentence in Canada but US
authorities rejected this option
rejected no you got to come to America
so Henry was extradited to the United
States on May 24th he appeared in a
Seattle courtroom and pleaded guilty to
one count of conspiracy to manufacture
marijuana he had to plead guilty because
I mean imagine the [ __ ] court
pressure all the lawyers all the
[ __ ] up against him take all your
money and that's part of what this they
think this was about politics mark was
heavily involved in politics and stuff
and they think marks people think that
they were trying to take take all of his
money because he made a lot of money
selling seeds and they were trying to
take his money and get him out of
politics so on September 10th 2010 in a
Seattle courtroom mark Emery was
sentenced to five years in prison US
District Court Judge Ricardo Martinez
sentence Emery stating there was no
question his actions were criminal and
that Emery ensured others broke the law
by selling them seeds there's so many
things that go through my head right now
cannabis seeds they're a little bit's to
preserve their souvenirs their
preservation their gifts I mean probably
thirty percent of those were ever
actually grown and I'm sure he made
people promised they wouldn't germinate
them that's what you do on it what's
what they do on a seed site apparently
allegedly alright so the court noted
that Emery claimed on his website to
have made some three million dollars a
year from selling seeds from his
Vancouver headquarters hate to call you
out mark that was a [ __ ] mistake
don't ever say you made three million
dollars selling seeds don't ever [ __ ]
talk about how much money you made
that's my personal advice in the hair so
amarty donated almost all of the money
generated from his seed sales to
marijuana policy reform efforts
he just redeemed your fuck-ups for
bragging about your money in my mind
summaries claims at all that his Emery
claims that his arrest was political
this was these claims were disputed by
the prosecution sorry I'm tapped out I'm
trying to read someone November 19th
2010 mark Emery was transferred to the D
raid James Correctional Facility in
Folkston Georgia his since then been
transferred to a Federal Correctional
Institution it's called Yozo City low to
serve the rest of his sentence
mark Emery is a victim of the drug war
and we owe him a cannabis medal of honor
so we salute you and we give you thanks
mark Emery seriously from the bottom of
our hearts from the whole cannabis world
mark Emery thank you we're sorry you're
in prison we wish we could all split
that up amongst us and serve an hour a
day or whatever we had to do just to
take a little bit of that yeah he's got
a wife she needs him in home he needs to
be at home it's in federal prison I've
seen some of the [ __ ] they make him do
there too they so dude seriously much
love and respect for Montgomery in the
prison that he's in they make him tuck
the beds down like military-style and
they give you a checklist of what you're
allowed and you get so many like one
toothbrush three ounces of toothpaste
this shit's ridiculous dude nobody
should have to live like that feel sorry
for the poor dude and feel sorry for
everybody in prison maybe now that we've
changed the marijuana laws here we'll
start releasing all the people there was
a case that uh it was kind of a
ridiculous try but they got one lady's
cannabis case overthrown but there was
also there were also other ridiculous
charges in that case so she's still
incarcerated on those charges but the
cannabis is erased from the chart
there's no good but I mean it's still
kind of so that in court that [ __ ]
counts that says precedent stands
forever
damn I think we had a good podcast
brother feels like time to stop you got
any plugs anybody you want to say what's
up - um I don't know man
I guess just thanks for having me on
again I'll do thank you known to be in
my hash guy Irie Irie genetics is always
killing it on the seed reading so thank
you so are many
the other guys here in Colorado we got
some good breeders coming out of the
Woodworks here and they're gonna start
setting some some new standards on some
new your stuff so that's exciting to see
especially coming from the end process
the concentrate end it's nice to see
some new tastiness coming out and some
very oily stuff so excited for all that
and I look forward to competing with all
the the extract artists in the in the
secret cup coming up in August I'll see
everybody at the Cannabis Cup and let's
do some dabs don't be surprised if you
see some collaborations and breeding
companies yeah from the cannabis cup
their talks of trades and thanks again
to Addison tomorrow for all the other
good knowledge and always always making
this community step up that's really the
whole true Big D thanks Big D I ordered
a lot of your Facebook posts I'm sure
you posting as always the whole
community just just for killing it and
moving up and coming together there you
go moving up and coming together it's
what it's all about guys quit being uh
well I'm not accusing anybody don't be
selfish and stingy with your information
try to uh try to share and help each
other to learn and if you see somebody
doing something wrong don't try to call
them out on their [ __ ] gently
correct them let's help each other I
know some people don't want to [ __ ]
learn I get it totally get it try to
help people sometimes and they just
don't want to hear your [ __ ] but the
people that want to learn help them
learn don't try to shoot him down
because it's the only way we're gonna
get anywhere hey thanks for listening it
was episode number two promise I got
more great episodes coming
check out nature's green remedies comm
check out hydrogen etics colorado comm
check me out I'm at Rasta Jeff 420 on
Twitter we are at I grow culture on
Twitter I just made a Twitter and look
at I region antics on Instagram for some
ridiculous cannabis photography I'm
saving a whole bunch I had a photo shoot
the other day that was very well done
I'm not gonna take photo credits the
plants are all mine but the the photos
were from another friend we'll bring him
on the show and let him talk about it
but you guys are gonna see some great
new photography coming up for me pretty
soon yep alright so I'm gonna select an
outro song here and we'll catch you guys
next time
peace and love take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
what's up podcast world welcome to
episode number three of the high-growth
culture podcast it's warm today in here
yeah it was warm at work too
man it's kind of nice I think I like it
cuz it's been cold so I think I like it
but it's just different before we get
started out this podcast is brought to
you by nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies dot-com for info
on ira genetics mile-high la plata labs
Sin City and gage green genetics use
coupon code youtube for teen for 10% off
and you'll always get free shipping at
nature's drain remedies dot-com I've
been playing some pretty cool intro and
outro music that some of my favorite
stuff I got to give credit to that
before we go any further episode number
one my intro song was tasked Rock a task
and lioness big shout out to task I
respect you so much bro thanks for all
the stuff you do anyway the song was
d-day the outro song on episode 1 was
mystic roots with DJ and a dance
shout-out coot and Katherine and mystic
roots crew friends of mine great music
episode number 2 I opened with Marlin
Asher ganja farmer because they call me
the ganja farmer
why wouldn't I play that song what the
hell episode number 2 the outro song was
Anthony B Erb people love some dancehall
reggae oh you just heard nyura
with positive herb and I got a cool
outro song coming up that I will give
credit on the next episode got a stay
proper and give credit to the people
that helped us out I got to give a big
shout out to my buddy Wade Ridley he
made me a really stylish logo for the
podcast that uh microphone with the bud
growing out of it there yeah that
stuff's looking good
that's Wade Ridley's designs thanks
brother I appreciate it
another big big ridiculous shout-out to
my buddy Tony without Tony this wouldn't
even happen Tony does my web stuff and
you're a boss at that [ __ ] brother you
really helped me got a feed going got me
up on iTunes really quickly
you're a pro bro thank you he makes my
website look good I read genetics
Colorado calm take a look there and then
most importantly thanks to the people
that are following us you've gotten
three episodes in you must like
something I must be doing something
right and I do appreciate you for
following and thanks for hitting the
subscribe button that makes us feel good
I want to give a huge thanks again to
Addison to Maura for his in-depth
description take a note in my head try
to remember that so Big Shot Addison he
did gave us a check out episode 2 if you
missed it gave us a nice long
description and education on testing of
cannabis and edibles
so yeah shout out to everyone that's
gotten this far with us we appreciate
the support now we're hanging out again
we got Kevon from elevated
concentrations to my front what's up
over to my left we got milky track calms
everybody's white Mike hey I just
learned that Colorado Springs has a Mme
D facility so if you're trying to get
badges yes definitely it'll slow down
the the overflow because video is
getting crowded yeah somebody at work
was talking about that a couple days ago
so that is really cool
I learned something if you try to open a
sweet stone candy the package with your
teeth
get scissors get some teeth got my jaw
the other day with that one in your
freaking car my car after the comedy
show yeah trying to get it open the next
day my jaw was so sore those things are
super childproof that's your child can
get scissors they can get into that but
you shouldn't have your child getting
the scissors either yeah I just cut my
teeth trying to open it up so I'm gonna
eat this while we're live eating or not
we're not live we're live here but the
show is not live while we are on the
show I'm gonna eat a uh we're alive yet
we're mostly live
if you're gonna do it do it closer to
the microphone say Fool's Day we did not
kill anybody I'm eating sweets don't
candy cotton candy gemstone I'm gonna
throw out my mouth whoops
it looks like I'm opening a condom to
tell you the truth I open one of these
in a comedy show and I'm pretty sure
that at least one or two people had to
think for I reached in and pulled out a
candy they had to think I was busting
open a condom dude I'm pretty sure
you're right that's the size it looks
just like I've done nothing but talk
[ __ ] I said the wrapper [ __ ] up my
teeth and looks like a condom I just put
this candy in my mouth all of the [ __ ]
talking is done this is delicious
haven't had the cotton candy flavor is
it kinda good that dr. P was freaking
awesome dude I could smell that I was
Jesus we were in the car and he busted
open doctors like what the f-- I was
eating some chips these chips have some
weird chemical that are making me crave
possibly
this thing's tasty shoutout to Claude
you guys don't pay me to say shoutout to
you you just make great edibles and so
that gets me to say good work you're
super nice people so we're so lucky here
hope to see you guys at the Cannabis Cup
I'm sure we will well let's get down to
business
hey somebody was responsible for keeping
a pipe loaded I don't know who I don't I
didn't know it's not loaded it isn't
from the wheat is in front of me oh I
forget you like empty well we're
connoisseurs at this table my friend
it's still connoisseur level if there's
still green weed that's okay we're all
we're smoking on some Sour Diesel Kevin
made some wax for me this time usually I
get shattered but he wanted to
experiment make some wax I have it for a
while so I wanted to make sure that it
was like riding a bike and I could still
accomplish fantastic tasks accomplished
do you uh you did well done job I like
it because I could pick it up and just
drop a big fat glob on yeah sorry that
was my Mike's Wheatstone your gun
it's not good or less versed in wax dabs
etc the difference sirs oh wow the
shatter you you can drop it but it's
harder to handle the shatter is a little
stickier it's due if your fingers are
warm it'll melt and get sticky and stick
to your fingers the wax is it doesn't
stick as much Kevin since this is a
topic it's a little bit about the
difference between shatter and wax
they're essentially the same product or
they're simply the same product just
different consistencies and towards the
end of the process you do a slightly
different technique with each one it
involves timing temperatures agitation
things like that and you can you can
achieve the different consistencies
which is essentially all shatter and wax
are they're just different consistencies
of the same same thing and a lot of
people hate on wax I'm I tell everybody
just stay on the mic i'm over here
bobbing back then Stevie Wonder I'm high
dude dab the [ __ ] out eating a sweet
stone it's a good night it's a wonderful
night hanging out to my favorite Bros
even a lot of people hate on chatter -
there's some people that are just really
into the wax and that's why I like a lot
of the conversations that go on with us
in the 7/10 community with the extract
artists especially is we're not sharing
so much information with the public
anymore we're sharing it a lot with
ourselves and we're learning a lot more
about you know what
what's better and what is actually going
on with the product so that's really
nice to see how it continues to evolve
and the knowledge continues to grow so
there's a lot of personal opinion on
indeed whether wax or shatter is
preferred there's a lot of opinion and
some some verification of one being
cleaner than the other so I'll leave
that up to everybody to go ahead and do
some research and read it deep because
I'm gonna kind of spill your beans from
what I have read from trusted sources I
have and I have not studied this I've
read this on Facebook from people that I
respect the the wax is usually cleaner
and comes back with less residual
solvents in there
yes that's what I bring with me that's
what I have read as well people that are
hating the butters or the waxes the
butter I'm gonna say butter
I would can I would consider butter
goofier and stuff that we wouldn't dab
we wouldn't dab butter if it's runny and
dripping off your [ __ ] I probably won't
have that exactly snap yeah I'll hit
that all day long
some good crumble if I want to I want to
put a little bit of it I'm gonna heat
the nail up and before I inhale you're
not gonna notice if you give me the dab
but I'm gonna give it a little sizzle
test before I inhale I'm a hippie I know
how to blow a didgeridoo so I know how
to make it look like I'm inhaling and
I'm not and that smokes I can get rid of
that smoke if it sizzles or tastes like
doodoo I won't take your dab but if it
looks good I'll hit some wax or yeah the
reason I like the difference is the
shatter I got to use the dab right a
little dab tool takes a little more work
a little more effort task Rock says the
tip the dagger tends to chip to shatter
in my eye
ow if you ever knows that the first time
you buy shatter from the dispensary
you're gonna take it home and you're
gonna get your little dad tool and
you're gonna stick it in that [ __ ]
shatter and you're gonna break off a
piece and it's gonna fly across the room
and you're never gonna be pissed
that's one dad for your dead home you
just have to get used to that yeah
that's if you haven't experienced that
yet use your thumb and just rub your
thumb on there and eat that [ __ ] up a
little bit till it comes pliable you're
gonna have a big thumbprint Polly deal
talk [ __ ] quit putting your fingerprints
all over my damn shanna but there's just
you turn and they heat it up a little
bit but but I like the wax because I can
grab however big of a piece I want and
squish it together and make a nice
little ball and then heat up my nail and
just slam dunk it like a Michael Jordan
on that [ __ ] and get it nice and
the wax the consistency makes it punch
me harder on the hit it makes it seems
like it does really does this shatter
I'll admit it shatter is slightly
smoother SAP is really smooth but the
[ __ ] I like that heavy and it's not
heavy like when you're smoking co2 oil I
do not like that's my personal
preference it always makes me feel like
it's bubbly in my lungs it's heavy I'm
drowning in myself to labor but the the
wax gives me a pleasant punch like it's
so like remember when you're in high
school and you take a big [ __ ] bong
and you
oh really it gives me that yeah maybe I
need lose my dabbing since it's taking
me a quarter gram dab of some good wax
for the body yeah I'm going to I didn't
want to talk about this until I had it
more planned out but a friend of ours a
collective friend I think we all three
know he's a doctor and I'm going to have
him send me to a local drug testing
facility I'm gonna wake up in the
morning I'm gonna go to the doctor he's
gonna write me the recommendation to go
and somebody else is going to drive me
and on the way there I'm gonna take dabs
and I'm gonna drive to a drug testing
facility and dab the [ __ ] out like a
normally water to dab session six or
seven fat dad and walk in there and let
them take my blood and then measure my
THC content and then I'm going to go the
whole day and not dab like after that
session I'll live the rest of the day
without any dabs and then I want to go
in in the morning and go in and have
them take my THC and then I'm gonna go
another day and then try two or maybe a
couple days later or something just I'm
gonna have to challenge myself and not
take dabs it would be [ __ ] cool but I
want to manage myself at two or three
different points urine and blood and
find out where I am right after I dab
where I am when I wake up in the morning
and maybe I should but I should include
one more there's so many that I'd like
to do but I have to pay for each test
pocket that's gonna get a little crazy
and he's gonna try to help me out he's
gonna try to like make it not as
expensive as it should be because he
knows the people in the lab and such but
it's gonna be a fun conversation at the
drug testing lab huh I'm gonna tell em
what I'm doing right so listen it's
podcast yeah but I want to see my goal
is to find out where we wake up good you
don't have as much as I do but for your
body weight dude you keep up closely
little keV oh yeah yeah and I went home
from work and it like 15 straight and
went to bed in a day just medical
patient you don't have [ __ ] that hurts
and you valid reason and you like to
take some naps so I want to find out
where our nanograms be Tulsi is in our
blood to find out if we're legal to
drive because when we're gonna do an
episode about duis in cannabis in
Colorado
did you just kind of headphones mic it's
doing something we've uh I think your
channel has issues we apologize for the
technical tease that requires okay so
the sweet stones dissolving and it's
giving me a little wha
my throat my throat was all clogged up
so excuse me I had some wonderful sweet
stone flavor in there okay the first
piece of the cotton candy is dissolved
where I need another one that [ __ ] is
delish different colors every flavor
I've had are amazing I think I'm gonna
wait till this piece is completely gone
and try the blue and see if it varies in
flavor or if they just did them
different colors to be cute we're so
spoiled here right doctor people in
other states and like I heard you can
give brownies it's just like yeah we've
had store shelf brownies since what 2004
why can I work dispensary huge remember
when we worked at madame our and our
friend the baker would come in and we
were bud tenders I was a manager Mike
was my backup bud tender I was a head
blunt tender I guess you'd call me and
the boss would come in and this was
before all the weird regulations they
was just make edible x' at home that's
definitely what it was they'd make these
edibles at home and they would bring him
in by the tray and they would have one
set aside for Mike and I have everything
that they made that they brought in for
inventory that day and sometimes it
would be a good six or seven pieces they
had fudge that white fudge bro I will
fight you for the last piece of that
fudge every day that [ __ ] is so good and
it got me high as giraffe [ __ ] thank
you Joe Rogan banana bread not only was
it delicious it was like a kick to the
face I saw the rest of the day was just
a beautiful bliss so a 200-pound man
roll down two flights of stairs not one
not like a straight line he had to turn
these stairs went straight down and
turned to 180 and came back at you as
they went down the second flight she
rolled down two flights of those stairs
and giggled like a [ __ ] cartoon
character because of too much of that
banana bread there would be times when
I'd look at one of the bosses would be
like can somebody just do this for a
minute and they would laugh at me they
didn't care that I was too high to
function they would laugh she walk in
and set the tray down and you know
traffic would stop for a minute she go
eat one of these tell me if it's any
good you go alright it's like 11:05 we
just opened but yes boss and 15 minutes
later she walked by and go how'd it
taste and you'd say it was delicious and
she'd say cool try the fudge yes boss
[Music]
people anymore the banana bread the
fudge those were my favorites definitely
they made some sugar cookies that were
shaped like weed leaves that I could be
like a million of those in a shift just
so I didn't like caramel but I heard the
caramels that were amazing just got
ridiculously frequently we had a really
good chef back in the met amar days
random question hey Kevin if you could
hear any song right now what would it be
any song right now yeah you're high I
asked you on the spot questionnaires
[ __ ] sure does Jesus bro that sounds
like a ween song I failed in my test
[Music]
through one of them the mollusc
okay welcome to the group what else you
got work hard play hard
some Wiz Khalifa right there that's
completely different into the scale oh
you gotta love that I went to the Wiz
Khalifa snoop show dude I wish and $30
for a concert ticket partially I love
Red Rocks don't get me wrong but it's
April 20th I went last year on 4/20 you
went with me bro it was cold it was it's
gonna be cold I've read that it's go by
the weather reports but that's it's
Morrison if you didn't know it cold
you're not from here yeah I've been
there I've seen widespread panic that
are 9 or 12 times
and it's never been as frickin Clippers
I've never seen either of those artists
and those are two of my favorite rap
artists for him you probably paid 60 or
70 don't see either ones that light to
her for 20 they both do it our I be cool
I'd love to go to I want to see him on a
more or indoor venue so I finished the
pink piece of this Wheatstone I'm
letting that flavor get out I'm about to
throw in the blue piece and see if it
tastes any differently it was [ __ ]
disgusting it tastes the same as far as
my taste buds can tell it may have a
thicker more it may have more flavor but
my tongue is going numb from all the
meta sucking on him real slowly I
noticed last time I eat these I ate the
whole pack is slowly as I could sucking
on them in a comedy show to not have
cotton mouth and not have to piss every
10 minutes they they weren't greatly for
that by the way if you need to go
somewhere to suck on some candy these
are the way to do it my tongue wit know
I'm doing my lips would all know I was
trying to talk to people and I was like
hey well what the [ __ ] this little girl
was tiny she got up on a barstool and
measured my dreadlocks to her body
height I bet your dreadlocks or as tall
as me and she got on a barstool and
measured who's cute all right I've got a
topic I try to have a topic for the show
not just a bunch of dudes sitting here
getting stoned although it's been
[ __ ] good at that today that will
happen I was ordered to do this before
we even started the leader of this
podcast I didn't word you I apologize
[Music]
can you are if somebody looks at you and
throws a bag of weed in the patient's
like keep the smell complaining you got
to kind of just man up and keep all
right so we just had a conversation
about shatter and wax shadows or wax
Kevin let's do shatter all right Mike
I'll go with wax all right we got one of
each here we got a shatter dad for Kevin
bro
the coughing you hear for me is no
comment on the product we got away my
kid mic is I'm surprised I'm not
coughing from looking at the hash I can
feel the cough building now just
thinking about the dab to come and that
is entirely tobacco use related I'm
really curious if our listeners enjoy us
just chilling out smoking some dabs and
bullshitting or if they like you better
when I'm reading and getting to news so
how many people let us know tweet it
it's because I'd like to do a show that
is for the people it's not just for us
to sit here and get yeah I'd like to
serve the purpose the first two were
very news related and this one so far
I've gotten very sit around to the point
we do have points and things we are
gonna talk about I made a new friend
[Laughter]
I'm just packed up Depp's for both of
these guys on the two divers I've got
available and did not save a DAB for
myself you want the beer read bro yeah
purple beer rig purple drippy beer rig I
sure do
I'm going to hand you the doll glass
that's Jack the Ripper from oh cool yeah
from my Gardens it's actually bred by TJ
sub cool shout out to Jason Cole gin
gee-gee a genetics yeah this candy in my
mouth I feel like a rude [ __ ] so good
I don't give a [ __ ]
podcast I'm gonna give them a shot I do
a podcast called seven one nine the
blocks with my friend Wade Ridley
shameless plug better listen to it it's
uh it's much more that's not as dabby as
this one it is entertaining it's a good
show but wait I handed him the dabber
ready to go we're live doing a show and
he put his mic on the microphone or his
mouth on the microphone and drop the
batter like he held the rig in front of
him he didn't burn anything but he
dropped the dab on the nail and inhaled
into the mic
it was priceless I called him out on the
show so if you guys catch that episode
it'll be funny chugging that sucker no I
enjoy every every episode of that starts
out with a [ __ ] you Mike so [ __ ] you
wait that's because you said that the
intro is monotone oh I know and the
intro is monotone but my therapist
everyone on the block's podcast is what
we're ranting about it's a tasty dab a
Jack the Ripper the last batch did not
come out that good the last Jack the
Ripper batch that we did I think that's
that batch bros then the very end of it
no the yeah I know the the batch we did
before this Wow
okay the Ripper yeah the past one ice I
had a phenotype that I was trying to get
something out of that phenotype and it
wasn't what I was looking for and I
tried to be stubborn I should have
gotten rid of it nothing against that
fee no that strain I'll grow Jack again
but uh that fee no wasn't a keeper for
me so it's gone will get I've got a five
pack of that we'll run that again and
find that lemon fee no you need the
dough Mike is gonna cough like a champ
cuz yeah it's not a little baby dad that
I gave him could just be the difference
in technique from a couple months ago to
no yeah you're learning a lawsuit I
learned a lot from you this makes
perfect you know I'm often impressed by
the really do much knowledge that I see
you gain cuz we're hanging out we're not
you're not going anywhere so yeah [ __ ]
did you learn that question I texted you
about can I do you want to discuss that
on the air is that something you'd
rather keep on the down-low let's do it
we talked about cold traps and pulling
Mike just goes wander off he's not gonna
cough into the mic he's too respectful
for that if we don't if we don't hear
from him in ten minutes we gotta go find
him I don't know what
okay this episode will be trainwreck
number three so we're using cold traps
and we're pulling out the gases and the
leftover contaminants and we're also
separating terpenoids and then you said
something that caught my attention
reintroduce the terpenoids back into the
finished product so that it's tasty and
contains terpenoids which also affect
your high in your medicinal qualities
could i hypothetically save that cold
trap set those terpenoids aside to run
another batch gather those terpenoids
set them aside run another batch and
introduce all three batches of
terpenoids into one batch of smaller
hash you could do that there is there is
a point of overdoing that takes a little
bit of a explanation but oh there's a
point of overdone everything's yes yes
so I think it would take some
experimentation to figure out what what
would be overdoing and what would be
where you wanted it to be and I think
also a better use would necessarily get
more flavor but to save different
terpenes that you trap from different
cannabis so because there's different
concentrations of different terpene
molecules okay so take those different
terpene molecules combine those in a
ratio for certain ailments because the
terpenoids have been have been known to
help with certain conditions and help
with how we receive the cannabinoids so
I think that would be a better and more
practical use for it is the combination
of certain terpene profiles does the
future bring us isolating the
cannabinoids specifically are we gonna
lie think it I think we're gonna be able
to in the future
definitely isolate several cannabinoids
if not all of them and several
terpenoids as well readily identify them
and separate them probably through a
couple it would it would take a couple
different processes like almost like a
condensation reaction along with your
normal solvent reaction
to get specific my follow you yeah yes
if ik molecules out of each one you know
I get we'd have to purify it like they
do gases and things your you know like
Addison was I think Addison mentioned or
I'm a met mentioned on one of the past
shows the butane and pentane SF all
comes from petroleum that's you know
refined into those gases based on their
boiling points so it's gonna take
several reactions like that to be able
to refine terpenoids cannabinoids I
think we're gonna start to discover the
differences in them and each molecule ur
structures specific melting points
boiling points and things and we'll be
able to separate that and reintroduce
them with each other eventually so we
can separate the whole pie exact heat
the pieces we need didn't cook off the
order I don't know if it's cooking off
bailing off dissipate may be the word
I'm looking for dissipate the gases and
other products who don't want filter out
contaminants and waxes will that bring
us to I see a cylinder a graduated
cylinder I think that's the word with
different layers of sediments in it
that'll show waxes eventually what I'm
headed for what I want to know the end
are we gonna be able to pull apart
pesticides like are we gonna say here's
all the pesticide that was found in your
plant is are we gonna get as the
research continues I bet we can I don't
see why not the guys it's you know
exactly has a site in a plant that was
treated while in early veg yeah I can
identify it in a dry DC and we're
already at that stage and also you got
to think about what some you're saying a
second ago there are any breeding plants
to be 15 to one CBD THC ratios are
already on that stage of separating
stuff in the plant stage and now the
dabbing concentrates in relative time
aspect is much newer than growing weed
right so we're very early in our
research in our study with what can be
done and how it can be
and it's already moved very very very
quickly so I think as more people and
with the legalization more people like
PhDs in chemistry and things like that
that know a lot about the subjects come
into it that'll start to teach the whole
community about about all of it steep
hills a perfect example of that perfect
example
those guys are crushing it one thing
that I mentioned on Facebook today on
somebody's post they were talking about
people don't forget about the other
weekend while I was off identify 60 of
them right now there have got to be a
lot more because we're discovering new
[ __ ] every day
so don't go ahead I'll let you know
while I was off coffin I was thinking
that what you were talking about Sanjay
Gupta was just talking about and his
last weed too special that he just
excuse me while I cough a little bit
more dabs are gonna do that to you Oh
dad's just ruined me for a minute
but what you two have been talking about
is the very forefront of something he
mentioned in his show called the
entourage effect or at least that's what
they're calling him now in medical
circles and what that is is the
different cannabinoids the 60 of them
that you were just talking about working
together to produce amazing medical
effects yes part of the hard sell in
medical marijuana is it so useful
treating so many different things so
when someone doesn't believe you from
the get-go when you tell them that it
helps cancer epilepsy aids you know the
list goes on and on they think you're
lying and it turns out that it's just
different combinations of these
different cannabinoids having amazing
effects all over the body right and you
two are on the forefront of that with
some of the work you're doing and it's
crazy that it's happening it places like
it's happening instead of research labs
and research laboratories across the
u.s. because of the law it's just silly
and I got to point out that I'm really
thankful and grateful I don't know I
don't want to point out whatever I've
been thankful to but whatever you
believe in I'm [ __ ] thankful to that
because I've got such a really cool
position where I get to grow a medical
cannabis product and both of these guys
sitting at my table I'm their caregiver
I'm their medical marijuana supplier and
caregiver I get to talk with my bro keV
and see what hurts what doesn't feel
good and he says dude I really like this
strain that you grow it makes my X not X
and my smile go smile and for me and you
just smile like a [ __ ] Lee said that
but that face when you smoke the lid
that I grow to make you not feel like
[ __ ] that's golden to me bro yeah same
thing for you Mike I know you love my
grateful dog like its I was hurting when
I got here today it's been a rough week
at work
been hauling a lot of heavy things up a
lot of stairs and within half-an-hour
getting here I was pain free and that's
all due to the medicine you produce and
it just angers me when people say it's
not medicine I read that a dozen times
today or when I read about CBD only
legislation finally somebody's listening
but they're clearly not paying enough
attention to what's being said if
they're taking away CBD only legislation
is actually going to help anyone yeah
you respect the whole plant not just one
part they need the full profile of
everything that's what I try to explain
to any patients or customers I get in
the dispensary I work at now they that's
one thing I really try to push is that
this entire profile of this plant is
very important and that's why
concentrates really helps so much
because I can concentrate that profile
of that plant and it's about the whole
not just teeny pieces yeah definitely
definitely
all right well that kind of brings me to
another topic that I want to discuss I
did have something lined up for the show
the Colorado Department of Public Health
and Environment is actually attempting
to pass a bill to limit caregivers to
six plants per patient and a limit of
five patients per caregiver
which is gonna be a cap that I say that
right you give me a funny face no it's
my Mountain Dew bottle sounds crazy loud
no it does but no matter where I move it
so they're trying to make it to where a
caregiver with six patients or with five
patients and including yourself if
you're if you want to grow medicine for
yourself but they don't even allow a
number for that you're they want to make
it to where a private caregiver is
capped out at 30 plants total right now
right now you're able to go if you go to
the Medical Marijuana doctor and you pay
your regular fee the doctor should see
you examine you and write you your
recommendation and that comes with a
standardized count of six plants and you
can have three of those plants in flower
and three of those plants in the veg
stage which means some are budding and
some are not if that you gotta read your
own book to get that far with me right -
even get to what we're talking about now
there's a whole lot of history well I'm
gonna try to catch up acting it like
there are a lot of people who made crazy
decisions to get us here but this is
what legislators decided right and I
have a nice little article written by a
friend of mine who's very well written
and I'll read I'm gonna read through it
and try to do the best I can but what
I'm I want to give people an update on
what's going on right now they write
your card if you are I'm gonna use your
old man isn't as an example he requires
a little more medicine than some people
cuz he's got a condition that we need to
supply him with yeah and he the doctor
knows that because he's met with the
doctor and the doctor said holy [ __ ]
you've got a condition we got to get you
treated who's your caregiver how does he
grow how much medicine do you need how
is your grow gonna make that much
medicine
okay here's that many plants they send
it into the registry he's legit his
caregiver has set up a grow to supply
that much medicine for him and he's also
got that caregiver also has more
patients that he's responsible for so
he's got a certain amount of people he's
responsible for taking care of he's
gonna grow this many plants produce this
many once's a weed for this many people
we've got a thought of people are taking
care of now they want to chop that down
to only 30 plants and now people are
gonna run out of medicine early because
if I'm not able you guys I've got I've
got five patients that I'm responsible
for plus myself and I I know how to grow
I know how to pull weight off of a plant
and these guys can smoke some weed it
was
mildly between the raw flowers that we
smoked flowers is the buds for the
people that aren't in the industry or
aren't caught up on terms when we say
flower we just mean buds driving to your
manicured buds
that's flowers concentrates I'm usually
talking about some pho some dabs between
the flowers and the dabs and the edibles
that these guys require I need to grow
more than what I'm actually I'm not
doing it but I could use more plants I
could definitely use an increase in your
guyses numbers because you guys like to
medicate heavily well in this you have
to get into to some of the requirements
for actually growing quality medical
marijuana here like six marijuana plants
sounds like a lot of marijuana plants 30
marijuana plants sounds like a whole lot
of marijuana plants earlier you guys
were talking about phenotypes
everybody's talking about different
strains when you're capped at 30 and
you're trying to supply five different
people all of a sudden you're incredibly
limited into what you can do what you
can work with and we wouldn't have CBD
only sprains or Charlotte's Web or any
of that without a dispensary system that
was allowed to grow thousands of plants
right and trying to care give you almost
have to do I mean hundreds of plants
over a couple of years to really get
your patients figured out there's a
there's something else I wanted to get
in 30 at a time is just crazy I like to
grow big plants I like a seven gallon
pot fold with the soilless mix a lot of
perlite in there a lot of I'm not even
gonna tell you so much of it but I like
a nice seven gallon pot I like to veg
them until they're about three feet tall
three and a half feet tall and I like to
flower them at that point I'll top them
one store they're nice Bush and by the
time they're done they're about six feet
tall I like to draw a big plant but if I
grow my super silver means that I've got
in a pot that size oh excuse me I'm
burping if I grow a super Silver Haze
strain that I have in a pot that size
it'll grow through the frickin ceiling
in the eleven weeks that it takes to
finish so I run more of those plants in
smaller pots because it's more as a
grower that's experienced I know that's
the most economical and efficient way to
run with that strain so I have to
not run I have to time it because if I
have to count I have so many numbers I
can play with and if I want to do super
Silver Haze for my guy that wants a
straight up head race and sativa I've
got a plan nine of those instead of four
and that just messes up my plant count
already just for strain adjustment so
that's changing our numbers is kind of
it's gonna mess with us and they're
trying to stop us from being a lucrative
enterprise and right now being a
caregiver it nearly cost me money
to be a medical marijuana care guy I
don't make any money doing it certainly
there are light bills I work I spend a
lot of time putting your guys's medicine
together right it's it's not easy if I
would say I was to order something that
was I don't know fifty percent THC 50%
CBD or whatever the profile is how long
from me going I want this to you being
able to produce it do I have the strain
that you want or do I need to create
that flow I just showed up and I'm a
journal I've never mentioned it before
and I want it now breeding a strain is
gonna take me at least well to breed it
the first time I gotta get the mail I
gotta get the female if I've got the
male and female that you're helping I
you know I have to have the male and
female and I have to get them both veg
big enough I have to flour them out veg
stage is probably two months flower
stage is definitely two months maybe two
and a half to three depending because
you've got five months already I'm gonna
kick out seeds plants got a dry it'll
pull the seeds out you're looking
another couple few weeks there we're
happy you're just making the first batch
of seeds now we have to run those and
share those with other providers that
can take a clone of that so that if they
find the champion that you're looking
for then I can get a clone of that and
then I need to breed that one to either
the male or the female again but the
male again to stabilize it and then so
we're like you're two now right yeah
it's gonna take us a little while we'll
have what you need at first but if I
want to get it in seed form that's solid
for it to be out and available we're
looking at two maybe three years right
it'll be available to sample here and
there but before it can be something
that you could keep available study form
and we're looking at three years yeah
yeah that's what the rules though they
are now if if all of a sudden every
caregiver in Colorado is limited to 30
but are 30 or 36 plants are limited
people period if you're working in
Denver city and county you're limited to
12 pant
plants per household period no
exceptions
how many mother plants do some genetic
companies have right hundreds
Wow I know the archive I can't quote but
I'm pretty sure archive has about
eighteen to twenty five mother plants
archive seed bank I would be way off
then yeah I think sub cool probably has
got 40 I was thinkin strains know mother
mother plays like one seed company like
one seed guy in the and the big guys
like swerves probably got I'm just
dropping names now swears probably got
thirty five mother plants that he works
with yeah and two males and he reverses
[ __ ] and so that's you'd have to keep
thirty five females just to have those
four genetic supply like with that it's
gonna off the that's stretching it
though a little bit this is where all
those crazy names come from is all the
work a hard work that these people are
that we're describing right now I'm
gonna read the summary of a caregiver
bill that's written by my friend Kevin
hey Kevin I apologize it's not the Kevin
at the table it's another Kevin I don't
know how to pronounce your last name and
I feel it'd be more polite just to
straight up say I don't know how to
pronounce that I'd like to meet you in
person shake your hand and have you tell
me how to say this Kevin is the
political director for pink house blooms
he's a very educated and well-written
well-spoken young man here's what he has
to say I'm reading from my iphone so
excuse me when I have to refine my spot
several times the current debate focused
around Colorado's marijuana caregivers
is a result of recent of a recent audit
of the caregiver program by the Colorado
Department of Public Health and
Environment and the Department of
Revenue he had the Department of Revenue
is attached to our marijuana system in
Colorado they do keep very good notes
throughout the process there were
several shortcomings in regard to the
enforceability of the program and the
overall implementation auditors
discovered regulars were not
sufficiently overseeing doctors who
issue recommendations to patients
caregivers were not given proper
oversight fer from the Health Department
officials failed to issue red cards
within the constitutionally required
35-day timeline which has been a problem
day one right there they'd never had
that right how's that the caregivers
fault
this is what sparked it all they honored
it because of this and then they
realized all the stuff that's going on
and I agree with part of it and we'll
get on to I understand why but so
they're not getting the cards in the
required time and also accused the
Health Department of charging too much
in patient application fees which they
have reduced to fifteen dollars it
started off at ninety and down to thirty
five they did something for indigent
people and now it's fifteen bucks
they've gotten an overage in their
account of like 10 or 13 million or
something like that in state law forbids
things like that so they've had to drop
that fee over and over and over again
because they can't take in any more
money legally huh until they spend all
the money they've already shaved out of
the medical marijuana program it's kind
of Handy it's a nice little provision if
you're a taxpayer for sure or car red
card holder I like that the fee got
cheap oh yeah at the fee got cheaper I
definitely appreciate that the
Department of Public Health and these
guys are plotting why in the studio the
Department of Public Health and
Environment generally agreed with the
recommendations from the auditor's
report and are already taking steps to
rectify the issues they're considering
redefining who is an authorized CD Phe
employee which could mean increased
access to private medical record medical
marijuana records by independent
contractors limiting the number of
patients that private medical marijuana
caregivers can serve as well as putting
a cap on the number of plants an
individual may grow did that make sense
do you guys I felt like I might have
skipped something yeah so they wanted
theirs the sentence they should have
caught limiting the number of patients
that private medical marijuana
caregivers can have as well as putting a
cap on the number of plants an
individual may grow
reiterating what I was saying it's gonna
[ __ ] things up so I'm gonna continue
doctor Larry won't walk WOL Kay of the
Colorado Department Public Health I'm
gonna see CD Phe from now on to save us
all a headache so let me walk with the
CD Phe along with the state legislators
working to craft new laws clarifying
their stance on caregivers and home
growers but House Speaker mark F who
does not good with these names that are
not English completely so mark I'm not
gonna [ __ ] up your name I have respect
for that mark who decides which bills
can be considered said he won't allow a
vote on the issue until medical
marijuana caregivers and patients are
consulted maybe they're gonna kind of
try to listen to us and we've already
raised a stink one public hearing
already and I know that a number of
caregivers stood up and spoke I know
that a couple failed to put their best
foot forward which was unfortunate but
for the most part they they went and
they said our piece and try to explain
to the legislature why limiting people
in this way is a terrible idea
any time government is between a patient
and a doctor bad things tend to happen
and that's totally what's going on here
they want to tell you what your
prescription should be and because in
Colorado we're not allowed to have
prescriptions for medical marijuana we
have to have a recommendation and all
sorts of other things the legislature
just realized that doctors haven't been
giving out the minimum per for everybody
that they're for the hundred and ten
thousand people in the program doctors
have actually been talking to the
patients asking them how much they
consume how often in writing them a
recommendation that's appropriate to
that and they freaked out now there are
one or two examples that they cite that
are pretty egregious I'd admit the dude
with a hundred what 501 plan count
that's yes since federal limits up but
they're fed any federal plants is
illegal federally but they but they say
they don't care if it's 99 right do if
it's a hundred and one dude with a five
hundred plan account card that's a lot
of plants yeah well that's cool because
that's like the guy when you're on the
highway and there's that one guy in the
yellow Camaro that goes haulin ass past
you then you go enjoy that ticket and
you know you could just drive right by
the cop cuz he's getting he's [ __ ]
with that other guy already we'll just
let that guy with the 500 plants per
race right by us there's only 24
caregivers in the whole state I think it
said that have more than five patients
so they're they're making a huge stink
out of a pretty small problem for the
this part um you know I mean yeah well
they're here to change the rules for
everybody and screw up 12 years of good
practice we'll get in we're gonna talk
about that in a minute here because
that's I'm jumping ahead well no that's
just the the part I want to rant about
that's the result and we're gonna save
the result after we read you know you
got to do all the math and the moles
summarize the results so I'm gonna read
a little more there's one good paragraph
the caregiver issue has the men the
marijuana community split down the
middle the industry mm IG and CB air
both supporting the CDP a cheese efforts
while patients and patient advocacy
groups the patient advocacy groups
patients out of time Colorado Springs
Medical Marijuana Council Coloradans for
cannabis patients rights and green faith
ministries make up the opposition many
believe that groups such as mmm IG and
CBA are only supportive of tighter
regulations because and this is what I'm
thinking it will force patients into the
regulated market and in return increase
profits those that are opposing efforts
cited doctor-patient relationships
privacy and compassion as areas of
concern so what I think is gonna happen
here if they will limit my number of
plants all caregivers not just myself
they'll cut us down and it's gonna make
a short supply because there's already a
short supply supply in Colorado is bent
it was tight before Weimer is mine do
you ever go anywhere else to get your
medical marijuana other than your
caregiver mmm only one I'm stuck in a
town right how about you can't eat well
sometimes but I work at a medical
marijuana dispensary yes I love when you
bring over some train wreck like you did
today to smoke me out what that was
pretty tasty that's always you've got a
no yeah I wouldn't not outside a market
research right outside of my work
I don't listen like in Denver as you
guys don't need to go anywhere else cuz
I do my best to even does his job very
well I I sometimes I won't make dabs out
of my personal supplies so that I've got
that extra little bit because I know you
guys are gonna I've got
timed he grows strains for us that we
like that he doesn't did I say on the
errors was this a private talk I grow
the Tora Bora like a boss and I do not
like growing the plant personally as a
grower as a cannabis photographer I
don't like growing Tora Bora it doesn't
grow well for my growing style my
environment doesn't get along with the
rest of my plants it doesn't play the
same but these guys love the majority of
his patients love it half as much as all
of my heavy hitters
which is really awesome
he really gets our opinion takes it to
heart and runs with it you know it's
like like I've said before that my joy
is watching people feel better I've got
a friend who he's got a bad back he's
got some sciatica his legs are [ __ ] up
he walks with a cane he showed up here
in pain and we all hung out and I got
him nice and heavily medicated and he
stood up to leave and the old bastard
forgot his cane that's how I felt that's
how good the man felt that statement in
itself is huge forgot his cane I got two
I made that happen like I'm not trying
to say but I mean the feeling inside me
was like wow he's walking upright he
forgot he hurts yet a little bit of
spiritual therapy from hanging out with
all of us for an hour or whatever that
kind of stuff is priceless so when they
limit might grow or other caregivers
because mine they're not really gonna
this isn't gonna hurt me too much
honestly my problem is that I've got
mother plants and I'm gonna have to like
minimize mother plants to make this work
or something else but I can adjust I can
roll with punches I'm that's what a
grower does that's what a breeder does
you [ __ ] adapt to just [ __ ] move on
but they're gonna be people that cannot
do that are not as skilled they're not
as educated they aren't as experienced
they're not gonna be able to keep up
their supply for their patients what's
gonna happen is these people are gonna
have to go to a dispensary but here's
another [ __ ] up issue the medical
marijuana dispensaries are running out
of medical cannabis while the
recreational dispensaries are well
stocked
I find that [ __ ] up but hugely so Mike
you're gonna have to go I'm out of weed
because they limited my numbers I can't
grow I don't have your outs for this
whatever time
we hypothetically but I'm not gonna go
to the weights in number but thank you
for not disclosing medical information
right your guests your monthly
subscription
sorry it's half short because of these
new regulations I haven't adjusted my
grow to that yet you're gonna have to go
to the dispensary did you lots of that
on my world are huge
yeah financially you're gonna cost
increases I don't want to say because
you could kind of look it up if you
really do your home [ __ ] what do your
homework people this will give you a an
example of how jealousy should be I
would pay at least twice as much if I
had to fill my prescription at a retail
at a medical we paid twice as much at a
medical medical shop because of the
taxes almost three times three times a
traditional shop and you're gonna and
what I'm getting at is the medical shops
are at a weed and that's where the the
medical the most of the stuff that's
there is tested they're a little ahead
of that everything's gonna have to be
tested you're real soon like no there's
there's for sure right provide you a
strain specific product that you have
gotten to look at you've gotten to trim
with me you've experienced that plant I
think part of you touching your medicine
like you guys have been involved with us
see it all the way through it makes it
better you are connected to that as you
consume it and as a I'm a Rastafarian
and I feel that that touch that
connection makes the medicine work
better for you involved with uncertain
that's one of the reasons that when I
make concentrates from your material
it's the most fun and I get the best
concentrates out of it it's and the
whole process is just really awesome to
me
not that it isn't always but with your
material there's like an extra level to
that for me and I think that's part of
it just being able to watch these plants
grow and being so close to you and the
plants and stuff it makes it like yeah
you guys ask me how is the lemon Jeffrey
doing yeah week seven come look wash
your hands can take a look yeah I came
over what half a dozen times watching
the last batch of grateful doc come on
just I know you don't have any can I
just come stare at it for like you
sure come on over I'm seen I have
learned to eliminate a lot of the sprays
and talk things that I don't think I
would want to consume in my hash if I
wouldn't mist it into the air and let it
land on my hash I'm trying to get it out
of my grill room right and I am seeing
more and more companies more grows I am
privileged I get to go in to grow rooms
and I get to see things that [ __ ]
civilians would [ __ ] their pants over
dude right but I see four lights on so
many levels flora might in a court or a
paint container in professional grow
rooms and that dude though if uniform
light is terrible you're if you spray
flora might I guess any time is what I'm
learning even in veg now it's gonna
still remain in your flowers at harvest
after flush it'll be there and you're
gonna be dabbing it most likely if
you're a future kid and you're dabbing
neurotoxins on a daily basis yummy stuff
we're talking about there's no I'm not
to animal without legalization these
guys know I'm not flora my dabbing them
you know no I've been watching you
learning why not since pretty much the
beginning right Mike remember the time
that I saw
I [ __ ] up one time really badly it was
the middle of winter and my gear it was
it switched from the in Colorado we get
a heavy switch from fall or summer fall
winter it just goes boom it's about a
week right you'll be wearing shorts and
a t-shirt and then you're in [ __ ]
eskimo boots and a snow hat freezing a
dick off and at that time period I got
powdery mildew from not adjusting and
adapting to the rooms because I wasn't
experienced in Colorado to grow yet I
got a four to five ounce white rhino
plant that had powdery mildew up to one
side that was facing the wall because
the wall radiated cold and it made it
I'm sure that right I was an amateur
mistake but I heard an answer to like I
totally remember this night is it's one
of the reasons that I stopped really
shopping anywhere else because I knew
that whatever was coming from your
garden
had this step in it and I watched him
take a set of shears cut the plant out
of its pot and stuff stuff it right into
B black trash bag and haul it out of the
house immediately
yeah our five ounce plant we had we had
just trimmed two identical to it that
were perfectly healthy and that third
one right to the trash just no
questioning no thought to loss or any of
that and I have watched other growers
cut mold and things out of plants and
sell the rest yeah yeah I'm a medical
marijuana caregiver and I love the guys
that I'm helping out I really do I got a
big heart I like to thank for being such
a big dude I got a big heart if I would
have given the old man I talked about
earlier that has a cane or my friend
Doug that you guys know or even you guys
if I would have given you Baldy weed
with powdery mildew in it and in your
future any of you get some sort of lung
infection I will think that was my fault
and I'll feel like [ __ ] forever for it
that's not my job my job is to keep you
better yeah keep all that [ __ ] out of
your plants please cuz for us extract
artists it can be nightmare on equipment
it can be nightmare in the extracts
first and foremost no no no sprays no
[ __ ] mildew no molds none of that
I've heard a lot of people recently say
no that's okay just use it and just
please don't throw it away
tell me that the only thing you can do
with moldy pot is blast yeah yeah I just
I throw up a little in my mouth when
people say stuff like that heard someone
say I'm a peaceful person there's just
one scream I heard someone say the other
day well it kills it it's like dude it
concentrates it that's what I'm making
exactly any of the pesticides just don't
even do it no don't
that's lab testing lab testing has
provided us so much all of the worst
parts of
the only real dangers really of buying
part or buying pot and sorry in the 90s
was it might be moldy or it might have
powdery mildew in it or god only knows
what they sprayed on it to get their
crop to harvest you know it's labeled I
know it's tested never tasted spider
mites or spider mite eggs or think that
your money
yep everybody had their little there old
wives tale old hippie tales about if it
pops or if it sparkles or if it crackles
or if it burns black or much respect all
the pioneers and the revolutionaries if
you guys are here my homie task crock
said if you're here it's likely you're a
pioneer this is stage 2 of that you guys
are jumping into phase 2
yeah phase 1 was well I'm gonna say
we're phase 2 tasks and hellstone crew
was phase 1 we came in at phase 2 now
you guys phase 3 the sheriff and look
back on this day and say I was here
shout out a scrappy little bird I feel
like we've been talking about me growing
a lot that's kind of weird I want to say
that well I mean this stuff they're
talking about in the legislature right
now screws with us on a personal level
yeah it really does yeah
think about the medications you take on
a daily basis or your diet I know we've
got a bunch of mountain dew sitting on
the table shoutouts I do not I want to
mention that I have really quit drinking
Mountain Dew and I'm effing proud of
myself I had a bad addiction I'm fairly
impressed as well is this serious
Mountain Dew addict but like think about
some idiot in Congress toying with your
drug regimen every day on a personal
medication level what if your xanax
prescription was about to go from three
pills a day to one because somebody in
Congress just realized that doctors
weren't giving out the bare minimum
regardless of what the patient feedback
was I told you you can only take your
birth control pill on Wednesday Thursday
and Friday good luck right like how many
different medications I'm sorry your
prozac's just two a day now because you
know the legislature really doesn't
think you should be taking for a day
regardless of how much your body
or what your doctor is your doctor are
you crazy
yeah and I actually use marijuana for
medical purposes I was injured I have
nerve generated pain you can google this
we don't have a pill that works great on
nerve generated pain no I can swallow a
vicodin and I did for a number of weeks
after I got hurt in my arm still felt
like it was stuck in a car door I'm
gonna do it Jack the Ripper dab with one
of these sweet stone candies in my mouth
and I can imagine it's gonna be [ __ ]
delicious keep talking for a minute what
do you guys along with a whole bunch of
people in Colorado tried marijuana as a
medicine for a medical effect I just
pictured a bunch of you and a bunch of
people sitting down like at the face of
buttermilk Mountain just lined up we all
got together and we're like alright
everybody don't take your pain
medication today we're all gonna go do
dabs
then try that for a day but that's
essentially what we did we stopped I
stopped taking pills for a day and just
smoked a little bit of pot in the
morning and went about my day off smoked
a lot of pot in the afternoon and as the
day went on and I started to hurt more
I'd smoked a little more and the pain
would fade right away right now I'm pain
free and I was hurting when I got here a
few hours ago I'll be a little sore
again when I leave so that I can drive
safely home back to the blood test
slightly afraid of needles but I've got
tattoos and I've donated plasma so I
think I can handle and make them write
you a note for the track marks right so
one thing I want to mention before we
caught ranting about me and growing and
I want to get on to the next subject
here I think a lot of the places that
people get problems from their plants
their bugs
often come from clones you're bringing
in bugs when you bring in clones from
other people I know it's awesome to
trade clones but be careful dude be
careful inspect that [ __ ] the best that
you can and have some sort of organic
regimen to get rid of those spider mites
quarantine that plant spider much of the
most common and also one of the most
[ __ ] pesky it
that's why seed is so awesome and why
plant count limits of three and six and
thirty are so restrictive is because you
got to order ten seeds so I got up all
ten of them and there's a third of what
you're allowed to have yeah and then you
got to find the few cupcake clones of
them right from those ten seeds you
might get one or two that you keep but
until you figure that out you've got ten
and you've got to check off your count
sorry I did not just stick on this one
topic but it's one I've been watching
all week and it just it strikes a nerve
we can tell we can tell it's good excuse
my cough I'm looking for an article I've
got saved here what are you reaching for
bro do this thing with my headphone jack
again tap him make him get live again
perfect slowly rotating sound bounces
from right to left in my headphones and
it's disorienting like it's hard to
explain exactly how this has been our
longest episode so far I'm kind of proud
of us Wow yeah lots of talking it feels
good so every episode I tried to do a
segment that I call gif thanks this is
our second installment of give thanks
that's cool I pulled the word
installment right out of my face if
somebody saw that flew out like a big
purple unicorn big purple unicorn coming
at the horn got me good so I'm gonna get
seriously you know in pay respects and
give thanks to everybody's favorite Jack
Herer
I think it's hammer hill it's Harry
I better not say Herrera we gotta say
herro everybody pronounces it
differently I don't even attempt it uh
well I know that I used to think that it
was like short for Herrera like it was
from the same shoe cuz where we're from
that's a popular name it's not that
so it's Herer and not Herer so we're
gonna try and say it right I got to
retrain my brain I apologize first take
a DAB that's my excuse so Jack Herrera I
want to give you thanks
you're crucial to the cannabis movement
I'm gonna read a little bit about him
this is mostly from Wikipedia
Jack Herer is born in June 18th of 1939
sometimes called the emperor of hemp
Jack Herer was an American cannabis
activists and the author of the Emperor
wears no clothes a book still worth
buying and reading ladies and gentlemen
when it works nice in this book why is
it worth buying to read you guys want to
elaborate on that for me for a minute
[Music]
it's a fantastic history of hemp in the
US and across the world and you should
read it
short version and it's used to back up
like the legalize cannabis talks it's
got a lot of yeah reasons like useful
stuff it's kind of things in the front
that's I don't remember that it's been
15 years since I've read this book now I
feel bad for not being prepared but it's
essentially a challenge for an insane
amount of money that if you can disprove
anything in this book I will give you a
huge amount of money and no one ever
attempted to claim it nice because you
can't disprove anything he says and it's
really the Pioneer book about cannabis
and all of the medical and industrial
uses in a time when knowing a bunch
about marijuana was a criminal offense
essentially sounds good I like your you
know some [ __ ] bro really Jaime I saw
your eyes roll back in your head and you
started going to books you bro of course
the emperor wears nose closed which
we've been ranting about and also a book
called grass
there's also documentary about him
called the emperor of hemp Jack believed
Jack Herer believed that can the
cannabis plant should be criminalized
because sorry I got the sweets no no my
mouth had to move it out of the way see
the cat is plan D there's like five or
six little ones in this package and I'm
just savoring every [ __ ] lick of that
thing he felt the cannabis can't plant
should be decriminalized because it has
been shown to be a renewable source of
fuel food and medicine that can be grown
in ritual any part of the world
he further asserts that the US
government deliberately hides his proof
there is a strain of Jack Herer
Wikipedia mentions that error I did it
again but I should mention that that
strain was absolutely not his favorite
he wasn't even very fond of it
kind of ironic in my opinion like most
strains named after people the people
they're named after never interact with
the person attempting to honor them in
any way so you get that a lot loud seeds
and ganja farmer OG big up give them a
shout-out they actually collaborated
they got the gun your farmer oh gee
that's kind of waiting for that
precedence I'm impressed
does not surprise me that you know the
the example that breaks the rules yeah
well that's - that loud is a great
reading company and they were all over
the Cannabis Cup last year everywhere
you looked as loud loud loud yeah and
Marlon Asher is a reggae artist that
sings janja farmer so of course I'm
gonna know that nice of course did you
guys know that her ran for the United
States president twice in 1998 and 1992
as a grassroots party candidate I did
not know that I could not have told you
the years but I knew that that was one
of the stunts that he pulled
unfortunately in July of 2000 he
suffered a minor heart attack and a
major stroke resulting in difficulty
speaking and moving the right side of
his body he mostly recovered but on
September 12th 2009 he suffered another
heart attack while backstage at the heme
stock Festival in Portland Oregon I
spent a month in critical condition in a
Portland Hospital in a medically induced
coma he was discharged to another
facility Paul Stanford of the hemp and
cannabis Foundation said that he's
waking up in gazing appropriately when
someone is talking but he's not really
communicating in any way and
unfortunately he passed away at the age
of 70 on April 15th of 2010 in Eugene
Oregon from complications related to the
September 2009 heart attack it was
buried in Mission Hills California one
more little piece of info on August 12th
of 2012 a video was released uploaded to
YouTube of a man named Rick Simpson
claiming that Jack passed the torch of
legislation the sweet stones got my
mouth all delicious [ __ ] by him Rick
Simpson claims that Jack passed the
torch of legislation to him so big up we
thank you for your life's work jack
herer
thank you sir respect first
respect but I want to mention one funny
thing there's a guy named Jeff McElroy
he is running for the mayor of Toronto
Canada not an endorsement that's just
how this story starts his campaign sign
he's got these big there's six feet wide
and I think there's six feet tall but
they're like a plywood sheet so it's
only like it's got posts so it's only
half of the way it fit it is wide it's a
pretty burly campaign son yeah he's not
the little plastic one on the wires no
no it's this sign the sign reads Jeff
McIlroy he promises to just smoke pot as
mayor not crack any one's better than
Rob Ford right if you get that you get
that that's [ __ ] funny I love that
Rob Ford's approval ratings have gone up
or remained steady since the scandal
broke it turns out in Canada no one
really cares what you smoke as long as
you don't screw with them too much from
a government standpoint one more one
more piece of information that I feel
like we should share with the world
we're coming to you from Colorado we
talked about that a lot I love Colorado
got medical land right now here's what I
want to hear ever well we got to go some
places sometimes you can't make me
pretty pretty serious so I had this
conversation yesterday with the wife and
I really don't want to leave without
some serious serious tempting I think
it's got to be a pretty happy order
anyway go on with what you're saying if
you're dried this man several people
apparently have reported that they were
in Idaho driving with Colorado license
plates and they are harassed by the
police pulled over and the cops harassed
them about marijuana like they're
driving cool but they and this is
allegedly I am NOT in anybody's shoes
here I'm reading a story from the
cannabis tis actually where I found this
because if you want cannabis news and
you don't feel like hearing me rattle it
off and stutter it the cannabis has a
lot of great stuff
my friend Kevin that works with pink
house also sends me a lot of great info
and I scour the web for this stuff to
find it if you've got something you want
to hear feel free to tweet it to me at I
grow culture and I'll talk about it I
love to do that would love to do it so
what's going on
and idaho these cops are pulling you
over and [ __ ] with you cuz you got
Colorado plates one guy they detained
him and they took his car to the police
station and had six cops search his car
for six hours and they didn't find
anything but the cop treated him like a
prick the entire time it was real
accusatory that the man was carrying
cannabis turns out the guy wasn't
affluent businessman and has a little
bit of money so now he's sparking up a
lawsuit against the police force that
harassed him so I can't wait to see how
that turns out
the this story is making the rounds this
week but it's it's really just the
latest example of this happening in all
the states around Colorado it's been
getting worse since we first passed our
medical marijuana laws back in 1999 or
at least after the dispensary explosion
in 2008 is when it got real bad is
Colorado license plate so like a big
target on your back if you're out of
state you're gonna get pulled over at
some point or people have been alleging
this for years there's a video of it
that you can poll of people trying to
record these encounters there's a number
of testimonies I suppose you'd call them
that have been put up on the web of
people being pulled over and harassed
for hours searched extensively for
marijuana beer or other drugs because
they've got Colorado plates mentioned
what happened in Texas and this will be
our little cinema in other states along
the southern border especially there's
been a number of cases in the last six
months or a year so of troopers pulling
over people not necessarily with
Colorado plates plates from anywhere and
saying I think you have drugs and when
the person says I'm sorry officer I
don't have any drugs or contraband the
cop essentially keeps insisting you have
drugs and then in a number of examples
an example recorded on a dashcam
an officer performs vaginal and anal
cavity searches on an aunt and a niece
at the same time on the side of the road
without changing their glove I mean just
take a minute and throw up and I
apologize I make this nice and clear but
this is the size of a public highway in
Texas
a cop car your car these ladies car you
know side of the highway lights of
flashing yep aunt and niece on the side
of the highway yep like it's 40 year old
and a 20 year old female probably
handcuffed feeling humiliated scared yep
terrifies I don't think they were
handcuffed but they definitely were
humiliated and terrified
so this officer I don't know if there's
a trooper or a State Patrol or what they
work this dick
member of law enforcement this leo is
what we call them took a rubber glove
put it on one hand one glove one glove
on man suspect number ones vagina yep
proceeded to spin suspect number one and
then dig in person's anus yep so front
to back action here at the same glove
Sam glove here's the best part that I
want to clear up went to the next
suspect which is know I'm calling a
victim because you're being raped yep
fingers in the butt to see if you got
drugs yep fingers in the vagina to see
if you got drugs I believe it was the
reverse order but yes either way that
gloves been in your friends bought that
same glove four orifices two people all
of this I feel how many bacteria can you
count the bacteria they got around in
that truck I don't even want to know if
one of us did it will be charged with
forcible rape on to victims and some
sort of the fact that it happened on the
highway just because the cop felt like
pulling them over and going I think
you've got drugs is appalling gun sucks
this is America land of the free home of
the brave are you kidding me we're
clearly terrified if we're raping women
on the side of the highway with the same
glove looking for a little weed like how
much drugs could you have in a vagina
like does it does that warrant any of
this and this isn't an isolated example
when when the stories break a number of
people come forward and say that
happened to me last October and you can
look all this stuff online please google
anything I've said tonight you said
please so I truly do it to do it so that
was a little bit of a disgusting note to
end I really hate to take it there yeah
we're spoiled in Colorado we have access
to legal regulated well done marijuana
that's produced and sold just about like
every other product
on the market and we enjoy safety in
oversight that you don't get in the
majority the other 49 states and we also
enjoy freedom from persecution because
of our use of this beautiful plant
beautiful plant alright where's what I
want everybody to do if you don't want
the new caregiver law to pass I want you
to call the state reps and I'm an idiot
and I don't have that phone number
available I would have to look through
my phone and I feel like I got a podcast
and google the rep for your area real
easy what I'm gonna do I will tweet it I
draw a culture on Twitter and I'll get
that number out for you guys to call I'm
writing a note to do that cuz I'm a
pothead and I'm forgetful but do your
best to contact your Colorado your local
Colorado rep and tell them not to change
the caregiver account and let us do what
we're doing because we're not [ __ ]
around we're trying to help sick people
every rep in Colorado has a web page
with a button on it to make it easy to
email them please do so do it that's
it's our responsibility to have to fight
for what we want it's our responsibility
to stand up and speak if nobody if
nobody speaks up nobody speaks up and if
when one of us speaks up and you see
your buddy speaking up it's that much
easier to speak up so go first what
traditional versus the people who are
terrified of marijuana write five emails
and the people who have done their
homework and know what it's capable of
doing in to helping with and all the
positive that can come from it are too
busy working to send an email and it
said send more emails contact your
legislators legislators what yeah I was
gonna I've got cottonmouth real bad and
my tongues not cooperating that means
I'm doing a good job you've succeeded
sir success victory is mine
trying to pull up the outro song but I'm
gonna just have to I'm reaching I'm
reaching everybody by Colorado breeders
seeds every genetics is pretty badass
there's a few others
earlier support Colorado it's awesome
place to be there was a question on the
cannabis yeah we know the answer to that
hey anybody got any real shoutouts that
you want to say specifically anybody
okay how do you thanks for coming you
guys are my sure we will have other
people on I've got a lot of other stuff
planned out I want to get comfortable
and get good at that
podcasting thing before I go and try to
get people on that are gonna feel like
yeah yeah I want to think you guys were
in during the first three right an hour
and 17 minutes it's ridiculous so please
check out keep going
I read genetics Colorado comedy camp
check out nature's green revenues comm
follow me agriculture on Twitter go to
add hydrogen etics on instagram for tons
of excellent combusting for a lot of
cannabis photography that I feel is high
quality yep yep all right dude keep
listening I promise to bring a great
content will improve every episode so
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen episodes one two
and three of the girl from our podcast
formerly the iGrow culture podcast I
hope you enjoyed that was quite
embarrassing for me I cannot wait to
hear your opinions please send me some
tweets
it's @gf wih podcast I would love to
hear from you you guys please ignore all
of the old social media stuff on all the
old episodes most of that is inaccurate
please go with the @g fyh podcast
twitter they grow from your heart at
hotmail.com email all of that would be
the best way to get in touch with me
ladies and gentlemen this episode has
been long enough so I'm getting out of
here thanks for listening until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
you