it's up Podcast world it's time for
another throwback episode this time I'm
gonna put out episode 7 8 &amp; 9 let me do
a couple of disclaimers before I get
into the episodes all of the social
media has changed now it is @g fyh
podcast on Twitter and the girl from
your heart a podcast on Facebook and the
email is at know it's a girl from your
heart at hotmail.com that's what I'm
trying to say also a lot of my ideas and
opinions may have changed in 104 85
episodes so if I said some [ __ ] that was
stupid
please forgive me alright I don't wanna
make this file too long so here is
episode 7 8 &amp; 9 of the girl from your
heart podcast
[Music]
raise with the toy it's the paper the
paper
my room my name is with the bumping
track let me get another path going on
the butter so you know the mother who is
gifted and we've lifted like a
hovercraft Lumberjacks coming for your
trees and we wanna back all my friends
creating called from a bunch of scraps
we set the trends break the mold then we
run the bad people thanking me for
showing them the way to go like way to
go eh on the radio
give me a diver in a silly the net or a
mic cuz I'm a rapper you can kill it
it's wet entreprenuer man building a
well lit up so cool I only chew it
myself
[ __ ] so if you wallow in our back it's
probably cuz you wanna be if you're a
fan then it's likely the company for the
second time today we have a little
computer issue I think I've got it
figured out what helps it suppress
record that's not really what happened
but I think we got computer going so
we're here strong ready to dab out bring
you our cannabis cup review show [ __ ]
amazing 4:20 this weekend
[Music]
today we're gonna be taking off a 14
millimeter flux nail and a duality nail
we also use in a carb cap if you want to
get some of these products visit Aqualab
technologies and type in highly-educated
much respect task rock was a pleasure to
meet and see you this weekend I've met
you before a bit less pleasure to see
you again bro meet up with you so how
would you how many 4/20 weekend Kent it
was awesome you were there I was there
bro I wanted you to have some input bro
come on we did partying it up dude a lot
of people liked our dads very honoring I
don't know if honoring is actually I
don't know if that's a word see it was
true sure most people are here for gaps
not English class which is cool because
we get a little weed a little ridiculous
on that yeah we went to the cannabis cup
the US cannabis cut I think it's the
High Times us cannabis cup in Denver
where anybody 21 and over was able to
hang out freely smoke cannabis with us
dabs where available cannabis was
available we were having a grand old
time
so the first day I guess we'll get kind
of into that the first day we got there
we stood in line for two hours which
sounds like it would suck but studied
through the men that was kind of it
started the party just right we get to
hang out yeah hang out in line with a
bunch of cool people just hang out we're
dabbing in the parking lot it's sort of
a kind of reminded me a lot of my old
school fish to our widespread panic to
our days that's where we just hang out
in the water all day and make friends
and get down kind of do with what you
had there we met people from seven or
eight different states just while we
were hanging in line for two hours hey
Sean that's my buddy Sammy for a little
bit of help there we needed some help
for a minute and Sam helped us that was
really cool too bro really appreciate
that all day that's a cool guy the shout
out Sammy show it to the weed nerd crew
and there was no drama at the Cannabis
Cup I didn't see any ridiculous like
crazy drama I saw one girl look like
she's having a she might be passing out
kind of a moment they had to kind of put
her in a chair like but that was the
scariest sure and I saw all weekend for
the most part people seem to behave
themselves and take good care of
themselves
yeah I think they really really improved
the Cannabis Cup this year last year it
was crowded it almost gave heard a lot
of people saying they're having panic
attacks because it was just too damn
crowded this year you were able to move
around you were able to get to the
booths they gave out a pretty nice map
they told you where where who was where
who was on first if you will we're not
even gonna go down that rabbit hole so
it was a big shout out to those guys
they did a really cool really cool
improvement everything was nice and
smooth it was easy to get through there
wasn't a vegetarian food option that I
could find but I guess that's my own
dumb ass I don't need to complain about
that if I can find some vegetarian food
there would have been an oasis I had ice
cream for lunch which kind of made me
feel like [ __ ] by the end of the day
that's my only gripe I guess with the
whole thing it was worth it because I
got to see all of my friends old and new
sure if I wanted to list all the people
that I saw there and say hi to everybody
this show would be four hours long
because Kevin and I we spent more time
just stopping and saying hey what's up
man good to see a good to meet you like
it was a great time we got through the
first day and it was hot we roamed
around we uh we were only there for a
couple of minutes before we started
bumping into people but then it rained
so everybody kind of sought shelter we
ran into this little building and that
kind of cleared out a lot of the large
chaotic crowd for the first day so Kevin
and I felt like we had a lot of the
place to ourselves I felt like it was
mostly the true you know like people
that had a booth and like that yeah so
we ended up we're walking through and
this guy named swerve swerving he's a
owner of the callee connection he kind
of calls us over it is booth and we
thought he wanted to chat he actually
wanted to hang out with us he invited us
to the back of his booth we did a few
dabs
ended up hanging out with Addison demora
John hunt was there Graeme Gatsby and
then this dude named Darby Holmes showed
up at the case of glass and Kevin and I
had to hide my stoner boner I was
getting a little out of control there
that glass was some of the most
beautiful glass I've ever seen in person
yeah so we got the dam out with Darby
home we dad with the steep hill true and
the callee connection crew and Adam mill
which was kind of an honor Begins don't
know who animal is he kind of inspired
part of this podcast he had a podcast a
long time ago it wasn't a long time ago
in stone her time it was a long time ago
but he had a podcast it kind of got shut
down he started his own thing and he
just recently got re added to iTunes so
check out getting high with that Emil
that's my buddy
I just don't promote other podcasts it's
kind of weird but that's my bro I like
him listened to his show he inspired me
to do part of it he's part of what
inspired us to do what we're doing here
so yeah shock to everybody that I saw
this weekend that's where I was headed
man I can't start to list off the people
because I feel so bad so I'll leave
everybody out we dimensioned the callee
connection crew all the seed companies I
got to hang out gates green alpha tronic
your Lopilato
I'm gonna miss a bunch of people Sin
City was there
oil slick almost like noise it's always
great to see the oil slick crew those
guys are some of the funnest kids in the
business selecting nicotine I gave I
gave nicotine pack of seeds and in
return he gave me some cannabis capsules
yeah those are much appreciated there's
a family member there's a family members
need down absolutely bro absolutely yeah
pops need some help we're gonna we're
gonna do everything we can to get pops
back on its feet and super healthy again
sure that's what we do here yeah all
right so we saw a bunch of cool people
who want to say what's up to all those
people if we saw you and should candy
we're saying what's up to you right now
because we don't want to leave anybody
out I was gonna wait a little longer to
get into this part but you know who was
there that we never saw jiggy Kush bro
oh yeah Decker was all over the place
she was the most popular girl at the
party and she wasn't even there bro she
was not even there much loved the genie
cush we're gonna talk a little more
about that love of the lady later so bro
what was your uh what was your favorite
booth it's cannabis cup yeah we did
spend a little bit of time there we had
a lot of fun I'm gonna throw a stick in
the background
oh [ __ ] I'm gonna turn it down yeah
Kevin got some really sick glass um that
[ __ ] was awesome no those guys were so
cool my favorite glass at the place
there was some amazing glass there this
yeah so do you have a moment that you'll
never forget from this cannabis cup the
moment was there anything I think it was
that lemon mix and he had a big huge
baby was like yeah
so the Grammy gets who likes that a
hatch that kept mail and that's that
that is an honor because those guys get
to smoke a lot of hash yeah they get to
definitely Addison hit it right
afterward and did a very similar
reaction he's the one one actually
pointed me out to Darby's glass
he doesn't like showing me this rig is
like come here yeah so that was a huge
honor just to be invited to hang out in
the back of the Cal connection booth I
don't know how we managed that
and then Saturday was chaos it wasn't it
was controlled chaos but Saturday about
three 350 I realized four twenties
creeping up we should find a nice spot
to hang out take some dad's and it was
it was a hectic place it's like a State
Fair based around weed and I don't mean
to downplay it but you know you got your
booths you got all your vendors lined up
and there's a grid of people just
rushing left and right everyone's trying
to get from place to place we wanted to
find a nice cool spot to take some gaps
or 4/20 and something my mind said that
Cali connection booth had two really
cool couches so we uh we wandered
towards enter we could see from one
angle that those couches were completely
empty and there happen to be well that
was Sunday sorry sorry yeah it was
actually 420 yeah so we wanted a nice
spot for 4/20 dude you're playing with
that piece of shatter why don't you yeah
yes no I mean like picking up and make
like a nice couple of dads for us with
that [ __ ] yeah we left I left that
chatter on the table for the weekend and
I think it it cured itself up a little
bit better that's cool so Sunday by the
way we're uh it was Sunday have them
high and saying the wrong day Sunday
we're cruising we end up over at the
Kennedy connection booth and there's
this big dude blocking the way is a big
biker guy and he must have recognized us
from being there earlier because he goes
you guys need to get back in there and I
go yeah man I need to get right into
that booth and he moved out of my way
and kind of led us he pushed the crowd
on let me in keV right into the back of
the callee connection booth and one of
the guys who works at County connection
I don't know your name bro he's kind of
a tall dude he's got long hair he's got
kind of dark skin he was one of boots
and jeans and a hat and that guy is a
cool ass dude shadows of that guy
dude whose name is not known yeah we'll
see you next time
definitely because that guy saw his
sauce coming and he's like oh man get
back in here exists crowds get dick and
he let us grab two spots on the couch
and we dabbed out the callee connection
true for 4:20 at a mill was working his
ass off giving shirts and merchandise to
the crowd tighten up the crowd they were
hustling and that's why I was trying to
keep him dabbed out those are I Oh
swerve and a demille those guys have
done me a couple of favors
they're just crew so I was like let's go
dabbed em out and they give us a spot to
chill so that was a true honor like a
lot of people hate on those I know that
but it sticks out if you play a sport
imagine the biggest star if you play
basketball imagine Michael Jordan
inviting you into his house and play
basketball that's kind of what it was
like yeah yeah business like it's donor
boner moment the whole entire weekend I
do like you know you've arrived when you
walk into the cannabis cup and all your
fellow readers are ignoring customers to
come run over to you and talk to you for
a moment that's kind of neat to see yeah
I really enjoyed getting all the ceramic
products they're really impressed with
the ceramic brothers I wasn't sure if I
would be but I have been very impressed
so we don't get your hands on some
ceramics or know somebody nice I'll give
it a shot give it a try and see what
it's like next week on the next episode
whatever it is will probably be the
start of next week we're gonna actually
all have you bring over your ceramic and
we'll do a little review on the show and
we'll see how you think a week later
yeah I'm gonna I'm curious about it it
did taste good it seemed kind of clean
only took dad's off it but I'm a little
partial to the titanium I'm afraid I'm
gonna break that ceramic that's my
biggest fear but I don't want to take
there you go your personal alright yeah
on my pendant I take it around there you
go yeah
I'm looking for someone music here I
know what I want to find it's easier to
play it off in this way than doing it
the other way you're gonna play a little
bit of task this episode and fun seeing
him got a little a great vibe for buck
the background I hate it that uh YouTube
plays commercials now it's obnoxious so
my favorite part of the cannabis cup
collectively I think would be just the
unity that I felt the welcome miss and
the unity and it felt like we're
actually uh we're getting somewhere
you know we've been going all these
events we've been one we've been working
our asses off people don't see what the
hash companies doing with the seed
breeders do as much but and we're
finally getting some respect from our
peers and it's nice thank you guys we
appreciate that worst a couple of
pumpkins from quite well it's good to be
accepted yeah I felt like I always kept
thinking everyone's Astro Colorado I
kept forgetting there's tons of people
from other place there was somebody
there from every state at I would say
every state I kept forgetting though
just because the same place big love to
miss Nadia dabs if you listen and
sweetie thanks for the hug thanks for
sharing sand dabs with us I'm glad you
liked it sure we're sure our friend said
that Colorado hadn't flown wow we just
had a little technical glitch on the
computer so I hope everything's legit it
looks fine here we're gonna keep
recording but uh miss Nadia dabs
Facebook saying that she wasn't having a
good time in Colorado and that there
weren't any good dabs so Kevin and I
stopped by her booth and we corrected
that issue quite promptly she looked
very happy when we last
Instagram she might have said that those
are the best and she had in Colorado so
you posted your rig and your Chewbacca
which was cool if you guys want to
follow some gorgeous women on Facebook
or Instagram she's missed nah she's
Nadia dad's and she's missed Nadia noir
on Instagram I think so find her she's
gorgeous she used to be the tiny rebel
she yeah she changes it up so it's hard
to yeah if you go to Facebook and look
for Nadia dabs you'll find her that way
yeah for sure you just got a fat plug
from us miss Nadia dabs
so I'm gonna uh I'm gonna grab my my
wrench here I've been watching this dad
for a second I'm gonna hit this it's a
14 millimeter highly-educated flux now
shameless plug there yeah it's a brand
new duality bro seasoned to perfection I
think I season that sucker
just right think I got it perfect my boy
task rock taught me really nicely how to
season a nail all right you talked for a
minute about something while they ticket
to have this
I'm gonna nail if you guys put the
cannabis companies on you've got
pictures or even tagged me I didn't
think for me personally any time I walk
into a spot see Rev Jeremy Charles
chillin
I usually just pop the chair up next to
him it's usually a pretty bouquet so
much money generally fail there much
look to Adam done in the hood lab yeah I
was a cool little after party you guys
through there they always throw fun
chill little cannabis parties you think
they're always fun and chill and
complete I'll see you in my headphones
but I don't know you're not showing up
on the computer here there you are well
that's me
but because I apologize if there's some
[ __ ] technical issues in this
episode the computer might behind we're
Davin will just give it some excuses
computer might have had a floor 22 I'm
pretty sure the computer enjoyed for 20
as well so Kevin Wright went to the
civil restaurant in Denver Siri took us
there I thought it was was called the
the cherry tomato
it was delicious I had no key and I
would recommend it to anybody it was so
good the price was reasonable it was
just delicious the waiter was super cool
whatever whatever the waiters name was
that was super cool
it was awesome indeed there are some
cute waitresses there so go check that
place out if you're ever so there are
some updates available for my computer
it's telling me so if this episode is a
little bit sketchy blame it on Mac
trying to [ __ ] for some updates on me
right now you know I thought it was
funny in that restaurant because uh
everybody not everybody most of the
folks in there looked like they were on
dates of his guys and collared shirts
with their hair really nice and some get
ladies in that place man but uh
everybody looked like they were on a
nice fancy date and then there was us
our two hi asses in black hoodies
baseball caps Kevin's got like 20 pins
on his hat and I'm sure
we just reaped update we just came from
the cannabis cup like and nobody even
acted funny nobody said a word to us
about anything they all treated us
really cool we've got to grub and it was
delicious
dude my hotel I got to my hotel the
first night and before I walked in it
smelled like a [ __ ] dispensary in
there it just wreaked up sticking game
you get as I walked my hook down the
hall to my hotel room Agnes hear people
Chokin and coughin all the way down it
was very cool malarious there's no sorry
I'm coughing there's a big sign saying
that you can't sell cannabis in the
hotel it's illegal to display or
purchase cannabis in the hotel they're
talking about all kinds of Colorado
state laws every one corner I went to
had another poster that was worded
differently I thought it was funny but
nobody cared we'd dad [ __ ] out of that
place
all right I'm dad down here dad dad
worked I bet my voice sounds funny in my
headphones all right I'm gonna press
pause we're gonna play a commercial
because I'm not sure that this recording
properly so hang out for a second we'll
do an ad this portion of the hydro
culture podcast is brought to you by oil
slick oil slick tools to help you
concentrate
check out oil slick addcom for more
information ladies gentlemen we're back
I think we fixed all of our technical
difficulties we take a little break take
a couple dabs of commercials going for
you guys hope you like that all right
I think everything's working I'm
satisfied sorry about that guys
hate to break up show like that so uh I
guess it's time to read the winners of
the High Times Cannabis Cup we haven't
gotten to that part yet we talked a lot
about the county Scott will rambled on
and on and on so the High Times Cannabis
kept this is actually a High Times 40th
birthday so happy birthday hi times
getting a lot of free ads for me today
congratulations
to all the winners and people who place
by the way I think I need to turn down
some tasks Rach just a tiny bit and then
BOOM we'll announce some winners all
right so they did a lot of awards they
did edibles they did concentrates they
did booth we're just gonna read you the
flowers and they did two separate
categories there was the medical and the
u.s. competition the medical competition
was only available to of course Medical
dispensaries the US competition was
available to anyone 18 and over that can
afford to enter and felt like doing so
so the best medical hybrid hybrid is a
not indica not sativa but a nice blend
it can't be more than 70% leaning me
either way
so third place best hybrid best medical
hybrid golden goat from the green
solution second place can crush from
Lacan teas first place pure power plant
from good meds networks that's your best
hybrid pure power plant for the US
competition the best u.s. hybrid third
place Cinderella
99 times white from natural remedies
second place best us hybrid was Colorado
Kim from cannibals and first place us
hybrid was cookies and cream from exotic
genetics not a big surprise to see the
word cookies in their cookies like to
win awards yeah you know side note I'm
surprised we did not see Kyle kushman
this year I didn't see him I was even
more surprised that I did not see him on
stage he didn't win I didn't see him
there but I was even more surprised that
he didn't win anything that was usually
we see Kyle kushman on stage a lot a lot
of the winners were a lot of the winners
had some TGA stuff in it though yeah all
right so now we'll move on to the sativa
category the best medical sativa third
place
cherry pie from the clinic I don't smoke
a lot of flowers that cherry pie is the
bomb I'm shopping a lot of dispensaries
but if I had to go to a dispensary the
clinic would be one of the very few
places that I would go to
so shout out to the clinic third place
cherry pie best medical sativa second
place Durbin poison from Denver relief
once again another impressive facility
and another impressive strain there are
very few places that I really like to
shop that because I mean I've got my own
you know I've got my hookups I don't
need to go shopping but Denver relief
they they've always been a great spot
from the beginning they've been around
for a long long time yeah we're sure
we used to go get that biodiesel oh yeah
the [ __ ] was the fire so first place
best medical sativa in the u.s. High
Times Cannabis Cup was Jillybean number
one from standing akimbo so shout out
Jillybean TGA subculture nedick's best
sativa in the medical cup let me find
more music I'm just gonna play more
tasks there'll be something on the
screen here we go it's plan I promise
it's going to see alright okay
best us sativas second place was Twista
from the green solution
second place super Silver Haze from life
is good healing I've always liked some
super Silver Haze if it's done properly
and then first place was go strain haze
from green man cannabis which is really
cool because that's our friends at rare
dankness which is a colorado brand i
always like to see fellow Coloradans
doing good things they were they were
suffering what they were calling the
colorado curse rendered agnes wins cups
everywhere they go except colorado in
the past couple years we've seen scott
from rare dankness
have a look of frustration at the end of
the event and they finally broke free
from the colorado curse
so congratulations rare dankness and
green man cannabis with your ghost train
hayes and victory
so best medical indica is where we are
now
third place best medical indica denver
maple from ballpark holistic dispensary
i don't know anything about the
dispensary or the strain but we should
check it out second place rascal OG from
colorado alternative medicine rascal g
has always been a tasty [ __ ] dank dank
strange
cam has always been one of the few
dispensaries I would shop at it would be
probably the clinic [ __ ] Denver
relief cam and sometimes kind love are
like four or five four places that shop
at there's another one there are several
branches of the clinic so I'd go to one
or two of those if I had to
some rascal og from kam and then first
place best medical in the cuts would be
Larry og from MMJ America that was a
collab with Kelly connection and MMJ
America it's good to see Larry og taking
more Awards it's a dank ass stream grow
that [ __ ] that's good stuff all right
best us indica excuse me a malt dabbed
outta my throat is reflecting such so
third-placed best us indica MK ULTRA
from the green solution that's a great
stream I don't know that dispensary but
I'm Kayla is definitely a great strain
that's OG Kush and a haze if I'm Karachi
13 it's what it is oh gee cushioned g13
so it's got a nice little little little
mix there second place
granddaddy purple from cannibals people
are gonna hate on me I've never liked
purple weed I'm not the color purple but
strains that are from the Purple Line
just it always tastes it tastes like CBD
to me I guess it is what I've learned
and I've never been a huge fan of that
CBD flavor
to each his own you can hate on me if
you'd like that's at hydro culture on
Twitter there's first place best u.s.
indica South Central LA from Colorado
alternative medicine and root cellar
seeds South Central LA from cam and root
cellar seeds so root cellar seeds gave
camp some seeds cam to the shoot out of
it it's called South Central LA and then
won best us indica so that's pretty
chill all right it's got a couple more
people's choice Cup this is for hash the
third-place People's Choice Cup which is
the people voted on this apparently
third place king one shatter from New
Age medical second place Jillybean
shatter from 7-10 labs bud med health
center anything with that jelly bean
flavor tangi flavor grapefruit flavor i
will take another dab yes please that
[ __ ] is always so tasty in fact let me
read first place and there was a lovely
lady I don't know your name we bumped
into you close to the end of Sunday
night and you gave me a little parchment
with this grapefruit dab in there and
there were probably three or four dabs
of my size holy crap honey thank you
this is some delicious dabs
I was gifted a lot of cool things and so
far this is the one I've enjoyed the
most
yeah these dams are delicious I'll try
to split this in half with you see I'm
pretty sure you got some of it I'll give
you a demo what's what's here it was
tasty though alright so first place
people's cup hash it's a golden ghost
shatter gotta love that golden goat
shatter
by infusions powered by the green
solutions so shout out to the green
solution with their golden goat shatter
I freaking love some golden goat shatter
yeah golden goats a great stream yeah
it's good for migraines good for
seizures different ID it's not good for
naps if you need to take a nap
do not smoke some gold and go that's one
of the strains that uh if you need to
get the dishes done and you're not
motivated puff a little gold and go
ahead you might get wired up enough to
go and do the dishes what do you got in
that gabirol me oh that's some tasty
Ness everybody have to cut this we loved
it you guys better look out for us when
the secret cup comes we're gonna crush
you should knock that dab off there or
do it and then I'll give you this this
grapefruit dab it's super tasty there's
that one I'm gonna uh yeah I'll take
that cat card cat so I got three more
words to read while
yeah I know baby I'm keeping a I got a
mouse on the computer and I just scroll
the mouse to where I am and that that's
my secret for finding where I need to be
so yeah we're gonna crush it the secret
that's there so there we'll talk about
it after the show up here so the
people's cup flowers
this is flowers for the people that I
gonna explain to things Clark app and
flowers and I write myself into a circle
so flowers for the people that aren't
from Colorado and aren't hip to all of
our cool lingo flowers are pre run I
just [ __ ] you again my buddy had a
mill calls a pre run because flowers are
but flowers and concentrates flowers and
hash flowers are just buds we call it
flowers it's the flower of the plant we
just call it back here in Colorado were
a little a lot of the guys call it
pretty Ron I'm not sure how I feel about
it
I know it feels disrespectful to my
plant that I just spent three or four
months trend and nurture and then you
guys pre run but that's just my baby
okay alright so people's cup for flowers
third place Sour Diesel from the walking
Raven retail marijuana center who does
not love some good Sour Diesel if I
smoke sour D it makes my head spin it's
like I'm a [ __ ] [ __ ] I go full
[ __ ] no I go even worse than full
[ __ ] I go like a DD I forget what I'm
doing I start nine projects at turn on
the Xbox don't even play it that makes
it food and don't even eat it and just
go nuts
second place Death Star from New Age
medical deaths friends a good strain the
cut that was going around Denver it's
got this really and in a good way it
smells like burnt rubber and cush and it
tastes like dirty cush in your mouth and
I love it it's a good thing if you're
into that good cushy dirty earthy smell
that death start that goes around
Colorado of the Denver area that's a
good cut if you can find that one all
right
first place people's choice cut for
flowers first place was president
cush from the green solution a couple
breeders that work with cuts they call
presidential cooks I can't shout out any
breeders they don't know which one that
came from presidential coach green
solution was the people's choice that
means people liked it people voted go
smokes of that [ __ ] see what you think
didn't know that was the the high times
winners list there I want to find the
one that Joni one so I can read it
properly
our friends from naturalistic caregivers
took home an award and I'm looking for
they took home two awards here it is
best medical edible yes mystic CBD
capsules from natural mystic cannabis
caregivers big up to Joey from natural
mystic caregivers he hooked me up with a
few of those and they were the last ones
he had some more but they're the last
one they had so I could give to my pops
is so big give them back to the industry
another person so it's good to see him
win some stuff to when that chili from
that shop actually is a cancer survivor
so you can see the love that they put
into that cannabis saved her life and
she she gives that back every day I
think being involved in what she does so
much definitely so much love and respect
to natural mystic cannabis caregivers in
Colorado Springs they also won best
medical non-solid hash for first place
with the blueberry waltz awesome
non-solvent hash that's your my hash guy
bro even let's uh we're both back down
here a little bit but explain non
seulement hash is just they don't use
any solvents nothing is dissolved the
plant matter they essentially use cold
temperatures and ice to freeze keep
plant matter frozen not good track bones
off of the plant and to be able to
separate using filters to attract
Coneheads from the trichome tails and
then they make pure forms at high slacks
by swags and reduce
did they lay it out them and flatten on
parchment and dry it for several days so
there's no chemicals there are no
chemicals used in it only water is water
so the the other option is solve
attached which would usually be BHO or
butane honey oil which is made with or
co2 the BHO is made with butane and the
co2 is made with compressed co2 of
course and there's ISO that's made with
isopropyl alcohol so this is non solvent
which means it's made with essentially
ice and water and some people I'm gonna
cut you off don't even go there you're
gonna say but water is a solvent yes we
do understand that but in this case
water is not being used as a solvent I'm
kind of quoting Nick a tea I'm giving
credit to this statement writer to make
a tea this is not my teachings nicotine
has taught me that water is not being
used as a solvent in water hash or ice
hash it is simply being used as a
separator and a carrier because what
we're trying to do work 3do we're
freezing the trichomes basically and you
knock them off of the plant matter like
how do you get gum out of your hair
remember back in the day you just freeze
the gum and it comes out of your hair
kinda it does the same thing the
trichomes and oils will fall off of the
plant so you're not using it as a
solvent it's a carrier and it's not
dissolving it's just better to freeze
its what is it then you're extracting it
from the plant material so I did that
all I probably said that all wrong but
it's not a solvent in this case because
it's not being used to dissolve we're
washing something essentially right yeah
shout out to nicotine he kind of he
taught me better than that I just can't
remember exactly what I said I should go
google it so that I could get it right
for him but make it to use nicotine is
awesome at that right here on the screen
it says second place sour lemon OG
solvent list from essential extracts and
trill alternatives and then right here
best US non seulement hash white OG
solvent less wax from essential extracts
and down with Derby Hashanah - down with
dirt he's a breeder and he's a cool
little dude he's always humble he's
always kind he's always polite he's
always friendly whatever he sees me he's
always got a pack of seeds and a
high-five for me that's a cool little
dude right there
lookout for down with receipts they're
gonna be doing some big things in the
future
I predict
I predict that so uh 4/20 weekend
happened right did anybody hear about
that no not only was there the cannabis
cup but there was also a big event at
Civic Center Park in Denver there were a
few bands set up there's actually an
area where they were selling alcohol
which we ranted about that on the first
on the last podcast we did we don't
approve of that and I hope nobody drank
Kevin had a couple of friends that went
to the event at Civic Center Park and
how did you say that they felt about it
yeah the people I've talked to everyone
said very much it was really boring and
they felt very uncomfortable unlike past
years with all the fencing and security
and all that stuff they like they
commented that it made them feel like
they were in it in like a prison yard
and they were extremely uncomfortable so
I saw a tweet that said with all of
these barricades and things if somebody
shoots this year all we're going to do
is trample each other yeah yeah that's
pretty ridiculous
that I wasn't there I can't judge it but
I think you guys are getting the wrong
idea of how we need to have our cannabis
events need to come look at a cannabis
cup and see how that was done I think
there were 40,000 people there there had
to be 50 I'm gonna guess there were
40,000 people there but this was a
cannabis event and everybody's
everybody's friend did a cannabis event
if I would have been patient enough we
both would have gotten in what's a
wristband you know what I mean we just
didn't want to hunt around and find the
right people we wanted to get in there
so everybody's bringing in a homey like
every vendor got so I'm sure there were
50,000 people in that place I'm gonna
guess 40 to 50,000 people and I didn't
see any problems there was no need for a
major security and I can agree that too
much security to be intimidating you're
just trying to get stoned and chill out
participate yeah they come dressed for
war we come dressed for a party right
all right well by late afternoon at the
4/20 rally in Denver Denver police had
issued 47 citations for public marijuana
consumption at the downtown rally as
well as 16 other arrests or citations
for other reasons Denver Health Medical
Center paramedics had treated 14 people
including three who were taken to
jocks were those people drunker are they
high the people taking the detox what
the [ __ ] is we detox like yeah you just
sit in the corner unless you had some
cartoons to watch yeah I hope those were
being too drunk
yeah the hospital's emergency room had
treated about half a dozen people most
of whom had passed out through a
combination of Sun and substance abuse
those people that don't use the
elevation water yeah if you don't drink
water in that elevation and you're
dabbing and it was hot yeah there was a
nice hot day I've got a wicked sunburn I
joy it you know it's like I feel like a
kid again I haven't been sunburned like
this in years but so yeah I would I
would assume that a lot of those people
are I pick on Texas a lot so let's say
some people from Nebraska it weren't
used to being up so high and they wanted
to get dad down they just ended up
dropping like flies
by the way what I'm reading comes from
the Denver Post I just want to give them
some credit so uh I don't want to read
about this girl that got a ticket I'm
not gonna say her name she lit up her
Chilam on the outskirts of the rally
just before police officers on bicycles
rode by they handed her a hundred and
fifty dollar ticket for public marijuana
consumption but they said go into a
crowd where we can't pick you out so
they were trying to be cool about it the
shooters just right on the out spirits
portion they were like he done ass we
got to give you a ticket you know so
maybe that was not smart on her part
doesn't seem like there were many uh
events because of cannabis this year I
bet they were predicting a lot worse oh
that's well with all the police they had
set up dude like this is ridiculous you
can see the pictures of it there are
guard towers yeah mm-hmm that's no way
to celebrate 4/20 this year's rally had
fences around Civic Center designated
entry points with pat downs and bag
check street closures dozens of
Booth's from hemp energy drinks to
festival favorites like the turkey leg
guy and two stages for musical
performance after a shooting marred last
year's rally armed security guards this
year walked through the crowd at
mid-afternoon the air even smelled
slightly less perfumed with pop than
last year's are the nears best mm-hmm
that's kind of funny so they were
smoking less down there is actually
easier to smoke outside before it was
legal a person said the police are
watching much more now so maybe we kind
of hosed ourselves by doing this you
guys maybe and then we can do about it
now but we gotta be careful gotta be
responsible right all right so uh I
think we should take a quick dab and
then we should do the part of the show
that we call give thanks really special
all right guys we're gonna find a cool
song take a dad with you what are you in
the mood to hear Kevin music you're such
a smart ass bro so I'm just smart and I
say if you guys have musical suggestions
for us go ahead and send them because
Kevin doesn't have any ideas and some
steel poles I've got some Steel Pulse
go get some steel poles helps if you
sell those our torches that you hear
that's a torch that you hear
because of Steel Pulse was not a
commercial you can skip this ad in one
second there's a little bit of Steel
Pulse while I take a DAB dan cab you're
going in bro that's a DAB my students
dropping probably Porter Graham onto the
[ __ ] domeless got the carb cap on
there
Oh his eyes are crossing but he just
keeps smoking yeah nice bro you just
plotted out the whole spot no wonder my
computer won't work it's stoned I don't
I'm gonna take a little dab here you can
cough into the microphone let people
know we're still here I'm gonna hit the
flux nail represent next week because
we're gonna do a ceramic
bring your favorite rig with it like the
one that it works best with you know
what I mean like Stu yeah how you would
set it up I'm gonna take it down here we
go enjoy some steel poles and Kevin on
his own shout out the net lovely young
lady they gave it to me I was delicious
savor mine savor my last grapefruit dab
on the show to you guys
Oh tastiness my mouth is like in there
let's give thanks to somebody dude how
would you just how would you describe
the flavor of that on your tongue it's
like an orange jolly man Jolly Ranchers
came in orange that's what it would be
like so chickens like Kevin's
descriptions kinda like that okay I'm
done coughing every episode we try to do
a part of the show called give thanks
I'm gonna apologize in advance because
the two of us may tear up a little bit
for this yeah this is the most most
special episode of our version of give
thanks we've ever done we want to give
thanks to the young lady by the name of
Jenny Kush I've been looking for the
right words to say about Jenny Kush and
I honestly did not know Jenny a whole
bunch but I do see the effect that she
had on my community our community and I
feel that she deserves to be awarded and
honored and so I was at the Cannabis tub
I know cannabis tub up above but I saw a
magazine with miss Jenny Kernan on the
cover and the magazine is cm report and
it's October 13
it's Volume one issue three it's a free
magazine it's got a beautiful painting
of Jenny on the cover she's got a red
building green hair purple in the
background
and the author of this and him and I
kind of we're in the same boat about
with our level of how much we knew Jenny
so I'm gonna read another person's
article because it's perfect here we go
Jennifer to let Mon said more commonly
known as Jenny Kush and often self
referred to as Ginny [ __ ] cush
it's so awesome hi I'm Jenny [ __ ]
cush anyway Jenny [ __ ] cush a mother
an activist mmm and we'll make her a
friend and a lover of many things
ironically taken from us by the very
things she fought so hard against I want
to make sure I'm recording this because
we've had issues with the computer all
right while traveling home from a
concert Jenny and her life partner
Jeremy were struck head-on by a drunk
driver travelling the wrong way on the
high occupancy vehicle lane early in the
morning of August 31st Jimi hosted sex
pot radio where they would discuss some
of our favorite things sex pop and
all-around mental physical and spiritual
well-being
Jenny off the tinted local Jenny often
attended local rallies and protests and
with her background in Nursing Jenny was
always ready to help someone in need and
this isn't my article but I completely
missus we're in the same boat here so
says I only had the pleasure of
interacting with Jenny a few on a few
occasions so I feel somewhat under
qualified to write this article although
my personal experience with Jenny was
limited by experience what those are
life touch is plentiful
I don't know slowly because if I go too
fast I'll cheer up I'm all hidin making
me read this all right this woman
brought a community together in a way I
have never before witnessed within hours
of hearing the horrible news her friends
quickly organized donation pages to
collect money for Jenny's four surviving
children Shelby
Christopher Jordan and Tyler the
memorial party was organized at the hood
lab on Larimer and the first and in the
first 48 hours the fundraiser site had
collected seven thousand three hundred
and eighty one dollars
I was proud to be a bull I now add that
to the if $5,700 collected at the hood
lab and another three thousand dollars
for moms of marijuana donation page put
the total over fifteen thousand dollars
in less than two days that was our
community that did that well I can't say
our community but that was mostly you
know the cannabis community so that
shows that we're not a bunch of wheat
heads that we ignite for a cause and
when we love somebody man we can show so
this was the response from Jenny's
mother Laurie on the donations for
Laurie Monson I don't know any of you
but Jenny was our daughter some of the
names sound familiar as jenny was always
talking about her friends from Colorado
I just want to tell all of you how much
it means to me and the rest of my family
what you were doing for our daughter's
children many blessings and things go
out to each and every one of you
that's the print that makes me cry a
little bit yeah that was someone's
daughter that's rough it's our friend
but I'm gonna turn to read on the hood
lab was packed
sorry that was a lot but I was back to
I'm passionate trying to keep it
together for you bro it was the hood
that was packed and there was a line of
about 30 people formed around the front
door a friend's waiting to sign the
guestbook and make donations this was
most definitely the largest crowd 250
plus people in attendance the venue the
large crowd the venue hadn't seen since
it opened in 2012 the reason a
celebration this is so well written
right here
hold on tears are for [ __ ] quote the
reason a celebration a celebration of
the life of Jim that were balloons in
unicorns rainbows and two tubes
dude we saw big 300-pound dudes in tutus
and [ __ ] with rainbow socks bows in
their hair whose aureus alright that
makes me smile purple hair awkwardly
long hugs our industry is known for
awkwardly long coats yeah it's like a
[ __ ] Phish concert alright laughing
and of course there were tears I'm
crying right now and I'll admit I missed
this girl I don't even know her all
right I was overwhelming to say the
least
I want a stranger's hug the woman
dressed as unicorn cry
we all enjoyed some laughs at stories of
Jimmy's good deeds fantastic edibles
acts of peace and her unique laughs
we're told it was only fitting that
following this thunderstorm the next day
Jimmy blessed us with an extremely vivid
rainbow across the entire Denver sky
there's everything generally Ginny loved
and exactly how she would have wanted it
to be - the tears is tears so just being
in the room with her being in the room
with her at the secret cup yeah you
could just feel she was everybody their
shoes their mama like she gave everybody
like yeah yeah that was the first time
in whole new time when I got to meet her
I had a little conversation with Jeremy
and they were they were like my heroes
and I had only heard about it before
they were just they acted like I was
just you know their best friend in the
whole world still the last 20 years
that's how they treated me
and that's how she seemed very happy my
dog and just acted like she's known me
forever and I was the best thing the
world in that was for you know five
minutes but it was I'll never forget it
nobody has ever treated me like that the
moment pretty lasting impression of what
a human being can be and what we can do
like as as a person if we if we want to
just takes a second
just a second to say what's up to
somebody yep so we want to give super
big thanks to Jenny cush yeah we love
you Jenny so also Jenny had four
children and what any community should
do is help take care of some kids yeah
you can go to a website it's called
fundraiser I will tweet a link to it so
that you don't have to search to it go
to Twitter go to I grew culture podcast
and there will be a link click on that
link and I promise it's a real website I
promise you're actually donating money
for Jenny's children there's a beautiful
picture of Jenny she's won a hemp
necklace and uh I don't know I'm not a
I'm straight so I don't know what to
call this top she's running she's got
her arm up on her head that's a real
website go contribute right now there
are twenty one thousand nine hundred
dollars raised yes that's a lot of money
yeah so what I can do I grabbed a couple
of pins from the rare Danis Jenny
khushboo that the cannabis cup I've got
three pens one is it's a sex pot radio
pan one is an eye dab pen and the other
one is the zombie unicorn pin which is
kind of rare and limited I bought those
and I want to make those a prize the
first person that contributes $100 to
Jenny's fund on Rickon fundraiser and
sends me some sort of a picture or a
screenshot on Twitter at hydro culture
I'll send you these three pins as a
thank-you
that's the least I could do so go to
this website I'll tweet it you donate
$100 and I will send you these pins
that's all it takes
actually if you uh if you go throw down
money on this site you can it looks like
you can Facebook or something and it
shows people who have given money shows
Mitch guys gave $100 Bobby black from
high times gave $200 he says this
donation is on behalf of myself and my
wife April as well as a gentleman named
Eric Carle who was the winning bidder
and the auction from my porn collection
so Bobby got married a little while ago
any auctioned off his porn collection
and all the proceeds went to Jenny tush
yes yeah
so it shows uh Joel Halen gave dude big
[ __ ] love Joel Halen I don't want to
say how much he gave there are three
posts in a row that are my rent yeah
yeah shout out Joel hey landlord yeah
uh-huh
so I can see it if you post here I think
but if you just want to take a
screenshot with your phone and tweet it
to me I'll send you these three pins I
would be proud of you it'd be great feel
like we can all work together that way
so we're gonna get our [ __ ] together a
quick crime we love you Jeanie Kush
support the Rebbe
support her children support each other
any one of us could get hit I guess to
wrap up that story the person that
killed Jenny Tosh has pleaded guilty
yeah to manslaughter particular
manslaughters whatever no charges there
were no please offered so she just
stepped up no she did many people do
that
she thinks it's 36 years in prison 36
years issue she we would I would run
fast yeah she comes somebody friend of
mine she's gonna live with that inside
forever and I hope she I hope she can
learn and grow and I hope she can
recover all I can really say is leading
to making them go through another year
of court just keep dragging it on you
know prosecution that's you don't see
that to to so very true already true
well I think they may have caught on to
who they could the lady was that they
killed and yeah big kill the celebrity
with the way cannabis is going around
here with the support from the community
we've got they killed the celebrity
everything she did all the way
she was a champion karna yes one in a
billion person right there so I don't
want to harp on it but as a community
what we need to do we all excuse me I'm
not requiring a one hundred dollar
donation but that's what I'm gonna do to
send you a pin if you guys can throw
down ten twenty dollars these are for
little kids that don't have a mama that
needs some care I mean they have family
to help out but who expected mama to
disappear if my if I disappeared I hope
somebody would throw it out ten twenty
bucks to help my daughter did you just
make those numbers up you look [ __ ]
confident good job we were a little
somber after the Jeannie cush Jenny
coach me love you thank you sweetheart
we're gonna continue because this is
emotional so on our next episode we're
gonna answer Twitter questions if you've
got questions send them to us at
agriculture we related stuff if you want
to know about growing if you don't know
about waz if you want to know what's up
in Colorado if you've got questions feel
free to ask them we'll I'll read them
like I like interacting with the people
that are listening that's part of what
I'm here for
yeah so please send me or 200 questions
at hydro culture we've got a friend
coming on the show pretty soon who is
not a pot smoker he's a comedian well
we'll see about that when he's on the
show but he has a lot of questions about
growing cannabis he says that we we talk
over people's heads sometimes he said he
has no idea what we're saying a lot of
the time so he's gonna ask us a bunch of
beginner questions and we're gonna bring
it kind of help our listeners I'm not
gonna say his name yet I'm not gonna say
his name yet I don't know I don't know
what you need I don't know if he wants
me to say his name or if he's got a
moniker he will use you know you've sat
at this table with him I think he's a
comedian we've seen him naked in his
comedy act
- sure I think I just blew his whole bit
- and also I plan to start doing the
gross cool I want to get comfortable
with the microphone I want to get
comfortable at the show I want to figure
out the computer today it took a dump on
us while we were recording the first
episode or the first round of this
episode so I wanna get that figured out
then we're gonna do gross cool we're
gonna go from germinating seeds all the
way up to drying and curing we're gonna
talk about a lot of stuff in that you
got anything else to say Kevin bro not
really nothing about son-goku cannabis
cup episode I think yeah it does for you
we ended it while with Jenny Kosh all
right we'll check us out on Instagram
that's a hydro culture check us out on
Facebook at agriculture check us out on
Twitter once again at agriculture you
can listen to the show on iTunes
stitcher and in less than a week the
show will be available on a site called
swell it's a ww-well a.m. they claim to
be kind of like the Pandora of the
podcast world if you click like on a
couple things they'll try to find what
you like and if you click [ __ ] hate
this they'll try to not play that stuff
for you so that's their shtick I've been
in email contacts with them over the
past couple days and they claim that
they'll have my feet up in less than a
week so check that out I don't know that
you like the show keep listening keep
listening the song the opening song I
don't know if I ever said it that was
first place by task rock the closer is
gonna be blazed up by midnight so I'm
gonna go ahead and find that hey thanks
for sticking around thanks for listening
to me cry while we talked about Jenny
cush she got to see my sense it was sad
thanks to Kim thanks dude thanks for
hanging out with me at the Cannabis Cup
I mean up thank you this sounds weird
good uh thanks for noticing yeah this
may sound weird but it was fun going to
dinner with you weird but we've never
gone and just sat down at a snazzy
restaurant just broke down
or throws it in restaurant like that sir
two dudes thinking like weeding the
classy joint that was pretty fun with
you bro he's every fun we don't get to
do that a lot thanks for coming on the
show we're gonna play
[Music]
yeah welcome ladies and gentlemen
episode I grow culture podcast and we
host Rasta Jeff thanks for joining me
for another show this podcast is brought
to you by nature's green remedies calm
check out nature's green remedies calm
for gage pain genetics applaud elapsed
since city rare dankness mile high can
adventure I read kinetics and many more
trusted brands if you purchase too fast
as I region s you will receive a free
five pack of Bounty Killer while
supplies last
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our podcast listeners type
in coupon code Irie 2014 for 10% off any
order and always get free shipping in
nature state remedies calm this podcast
is also sponsored by highly educated
titanium if you're consuming high-grade
extracts you deserve a high grade
titanium nail don't trust the nail made
in China by people who don't care about
your health
company's been part of the movement
since the beginning highly-educated
titanium more information or to purchase
highly-educated titanium visit Aqualab
technologies calm this podcast is also
brought to you by oil slick oil slick
tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick pad comm for more
information now let's get down to
business there's the agricultural
podcast
[Music]
yeah
now that's how you know you're recording
is when Jeff starts hacking Apple yeah
you know that's how the show gets
started every time all right I'm gonna
fade this out we'll start talking
awesome fade-out we come into Kevin with
the torch say what's up keV what's up
you should have said what's up Kevin
that have been a lot smoother yeah all
right ladies and gentlemen thanks for
listening to that cool intro
we're hanging out here with uh we got
Jesse that we got spins we got keV
we got Clint yeah Clint's got a great
look on his face yeah scared of these
dabs it's gonna get in me oh that's a
good place to start so we got our buddy
client he's a comedian he's not a dabber
have you ever smoked in your life I've
smoked I've never done anything much
much no just you know hitting the ball
back 10 years ago 10 years ago yeah so
weed has changed completely since back
then yeah that was high school weed oh
god I'm sorry
yeah all right you'll be in for some
lessons today yeah Clint's gonna get an
education he wants us to teach you guys
some of the amateur stuff that we seem
to have forgotten musics too loud my
headphones Sorry Sorry also sitting over
there on the table we got her buddy
Jesse I almost said your last name dude
I'm sorry I won't be that so Jesse and
our buddy Spence were in a contest or a
competition called the Pueblo super bud
bowl over the 4/20 weekend and they both
got some awards what kind of what did
you win up there Jesse I took over all
in private entry overall crowd favorite
for my great boji congratulations you
got a really good review one of the
people that hosted the contest said this
was such a favorite of myself and the
judges until there was none left to
display a landslide winner in this
category nice yeah I said you drew that
[ __ ] to perfection yeah why is it you're
across did you make the grape oh gee I
hope Paul and Chuck polish like that I
was provided the pollen and just hit it
with a plan I had and I wasn't expecting
what came out from it it's really floral
really gravy
great stuff now it's really good it has
has like it has pretty much everything
the bag appeal it smokes great it has
pretty good benefits to it as well so
there's some positives behind it
do you know would you tell us what the
cross is or do you want to keep that a
secret um the the mom is a reversed
Tahoe og or no I bad SF vog okay from
Cali connection I believe the female or
the the other female yeah I'll just kind
of keep that one female that uses male I
know that's a good [ __ ] so yeah right on
Clint's lost over here yeah what's so he
made a scream he took a female plant and
used I'm not even gonna ask about the
method because I'm a breeder - I don't
know we don't talk about how we do our
reversing and such that's kind of our
own but you take a female plant you
reverse it make it into a male by
certain techniques and then it'll spit
out pollen that only has female traits
and so you'll make female seeds out of
that elaborate on that a little more if
you want to nice solo the grape oh gee
what's it taste like you bring me any
little shaky bit they were able to
return to me you got some back I'm
amazed it's dances [ __ ] it's bright
green it's got a nice orange to it I'm
gonna smell it I know why it's called
grape I approve dude nicely grown yeah
thank you
I didn't attend the super bud ball house
up the cannabis gut next time I'll have
to grow something and have one of you
guys wrap it for me or something I
didn't realize we could do that actually
saw I can't remember the gentleman's
name but I saw really great a heart of
gold sample there Wow yeah he said he
was also growing your
grateful dog to Jeff tomorrow so I wish
we knew who that was
yeah man was it good yeah it was one of
the more golden go free nose yeah yeah
article the heart of liens a lot to be
called the SS yes
this was one of the real heavy ones but
it yeah I smoke to join with whom is
great yes
shout out to whoever did a good job with
that hit me up on Twitter or email
because I'd like to see your work I'd
like to taste it and maybe I'll give you
some more beans you can put some good
stuff for me Spence would you win buddy
um oh I entered in private side of hash
and at the end they ended up joining the
medical and the private side together so
I took second um second place in best
wax is what they called it did you enter
shatter or wax
oh my inner chatter okay oh you have any
of it you have some of it do you I have
some of those the talisman yeah good
stuff I've been dabbing that all weekend
is it's definitely good at some gauge
products shout-out to gauge gauge being
good family sure I got to meet key play
and mk4 or m4k whichever one yeah good
cats really good cats good family keep
going sorry I totally interrupted um I
took second behind uh my job
conveniently so it was not too bad but
um it was a talisman OG or I don't even
know if they're calling or no G but
talisman um in my mix was actually three
different fee knows of the talisman
altogether so I figured it'd give a
better you know taste for what it was
made of um
I dubbed it chemtrails because it was
made out of one of the parents of
talisman is Kim dog og so it's very very
keen me so that's why we named it the
chemtrails sweet so some somebody hit me
up and said I like Kim but I don't like
Kim trails and I was like well you'll
like it anyway so it was cool dankness
has a strain called chemtrails so be
careful yeah I wondered about that
sometimes I'm gonna bust your balls a
little bit and we're bro so it's cool
when the hash makers make hash sometimes
it's confusing to patients when you
label it as Kim
because now they think it's chemtrails
dabs yeah or if you made up a name I see
I know one guy on the online on the damn
Internet that makes up names oh he took
off his headphones we're gonna fight
no the headphones cut out so oh man I
can tap them here but when people mix up
the the flavors it's confusing to the
patient so just to bust your balls a
little no worries let's cool the hose
for a competition it wasn't for a
dispensary or anything we can get your
headphones gone bro yeah I was gonna hit
a Kevin next so here I'll keep talking
does it sound anything see I just got a
TAC polygon again see it's right here
right there how's that mmm that feels
good oh you like that but does it make
the headphones work right there okay
yeah that's kind of gross yeah you
should have seen the look he gave me
that's kind of gross are you doing over
there keV you're quiet today bro
hi I'm hi Spence won two awards bro
proud of him we promised the viewer or
the listeners the viewers you can't even
see us we promised the listeners last
time that we're gonna talk about your
hive nail oh yeah you want to take some
tabs off of that sure all right we're
gonna do a little bit of a review
we gotta get if you're using a hive nail
something I should tell you don't use
titanium tools don't use metal tools
don't use a paperclip coated a plastic
like of our friends tried to do you
listenin bro you've done a lot of
smarter [ __ ] than that in your life
let's not uh yeah don't don't use weird
tools on the hive used some glass or
some they need to make a nice ceramic
diver they do okay all right fair enough
so you're supposed to heat it in a
circle right yep for how long I can
count do you know do you have like a
count on your head I always know how
long I haven't counted I have not took
the time to count it's about 15 to 20
seconds if you have encountered how do
you know that how do I know what
estimating time okay estimation what a
ball busting on this show estimation
time so heat in a circle
[Music]
five
Tan
fifteen I think that's good and I feel
it now feel it okay don't touch it don't
grab don't just grab it I think it needs
a little more I know how to tell when
it's hot enough it needs a little more
high that's what I kind of feel warm by
your fingers about an inch above twenty
to twenty five is where I think we need
to go you don't want it to be hot but
you don't want it to take a second to
feel warm yeah do one of you hash guys
want to explain about low temp dads and
all the people overheating their dads
either one of you guys both you together
Spence nada to you bro go alright I'll
chime in thor's yeah the low temp jobs
like really help conserve the
cannabinoids and the terpenes throughout
the hash when you do higher tabs you end
up boiling away and it destroys some of
that molecular structure if it's too hot
but also you don't want to do them too
cold either because sometimes you know
you want to melt all the hash obviously
you want to get everything consumed from
the dab and God forbid if there is
residuals it does help burn off the
residual so you don't consume those
pentane burns at 600 zeros yeah you
don't want it to be too cold so no I'm
wrong with that help so I don't remember
yeah 600 like 605 will burn off pentane
and butane yeah a lot of people don't
understand it but it's you know you
don't want to be diving off of a
scolding red nail that's not very good
for your body
Yeah right here I mean obviously you can
tell like when you're yakking up after a
dive it's most likely from your dad's or
a red-hot nail or you take too big of
dads like I do or you do that I kind of
do them too large so I like that that
was nice and smooth honestly it wasn't
my first date off there but it's my
first one on the show it's smooth it
tastes good I overheated it just to
touch but it tastes good it's nice and
smooth what I liked is somebody told me
that you could take several dabs off of
it if you kind of overheat it the first
yeah holds temperature really well if
you're I even say this if you're in the
car and dabbing and all three of you in
the car need to get a DAB and you don't
wanna be with the torch in the car a lot
and he can pull two or three dabs I'm
not sure that if I just promoted dabbing
in the car but people do a guy in Denver
a couple weeks ago dabbing in the car
he's scared the [ __ ] out of me I thought
he was gonna drive into some [ __ ] he
doesn't he was not pro like us oh I
thought you were talking about a parked
car yeah
dab in the car if you're parked go for
it [ __ ] it so if I'm driving keV should
take dad no problem he should take more
dabs you should take one for me right
yeah exactly for your homies mm have
slowed your face what do you think of
that nail dress yeah it's really smooth
cool cool it scares me though I've seen
a couple of minutes yeah go ahead you're
gonna I'm a big guy a fragile thing
scare me means well yeah that's partly
why I'm afraid of it until we break it I
approve that's a cool thing I'll try my
best not to break your nail bro it's
ceramic and in my world we're heating it
and cooling it I just make sense to me
that it's gonna bust I've seen one my
friend's house and they broke it pretty
quickly now the nail is the the piece
that's that's connected to the ball yeah
Clinton noob yeah yeah I'm gonna ask the
questions that some people I know it's
awesome I like it we need you here for
more episodes yes I'm in just like that
exactly what I need you for I believe
that would be referred to as the rig's
sorry the thing that looks like a bong
called the rig there is the
the heated parts it's a baby bonk it's
the heated the part that you're heating
up is called a Mickey yeah from what
I've gathered so far yes ceramic or
titanium or quartz or glass if they're
really cheap [ __ ] I've seen I've seen
Jeff Davin off of titanium as well as
now I've seen the ceramic now between
those two what do you guys prefer is
there a preference in between those two
or is it still nude is a ceramic still
new and you don't know yet um I haven't
spent enough time with the ceramic to
see how long it'll last the titanium
does burn out from heating and cooling
and absorbing all that Earl and all that
it does kind of burn out I haven't had
this rat McClung enough haven't seen one
around I I'm not the ceramic doesn't
come in a domed version and in my
backpack when I'm cruising I need a dome
because I get [ __ ] stuck to my domeless
nail the next time I go to use it it
tastes like [ __ ] it's funky so I need a
dome going like with the dome here oh
it's almost a cap that goes over your
nail and these are domeless there's a
hole right down the center of it so you
don't need the dome so it's a little
more convenient for here at the table
but in my backpack I need this style
seems like go for it I just did I didn't
even heat it with the torch it was still
hot enough for me to do my dab it was
like the perfect temperature actually
that's kind of a throw dab that's gonna
need yeah this actually also represents
progression and nails - yeah starting
with the domed ones and then the dome
lists no the ceramics is so the domed
ones were the first ones yeah right yeah
actually what was kind of first was the
swingarm skillet yeah they made a piece
that came out of here and it hung upside
down and they wrapped like a piece of
wire around it and hung a little
titanium plate underneath there okay and
you drop your dab on the plate and it
would go when you inhale it go up and
those things hit like so we're very
happy that we moved away from that yes
yes shout out the task for improving and
innovating the nails every day for sure
oh yeah I had a question on the gray
posy or oh gee sorry great bounce
nobody idea on the gray poaching is
that's something that that somebody can
pick up is there a place they can pick
that up or is that just your personal
stuff that's my personal okay and then
on the shatter we were talking about
earlier I already forgot the name of it
is that something that do they sell that
kind of stuff in dispensaries and
recreational places we like I work for a
shop so like the demand for it is so
high that it's never around okay
I mean it is but once it's there it's
going I guess I kind of half-assed
trying to plug your stuff so people can
buy it it's your stuff then yeah yeah a
lot of dads are hard to come by where
those of us that are blessed enough to
have a nice little slab like this we
kind of hoard it yeah I take my material
from Lima seed maker I'm a seed breeder
and I have my own little caregiver girl
and I take my leftover material the trim
and whatnot and let these two guys blast
it for me and that's how they make a lot
of their cut for their personal hash I
don't want to get into their business
but then I get my cut back and I barely
get enough I dab a lot yeah and I've got
patients that I have to distribute it to
share it with medically so it disappears
very quickly all right yes see you know
in the room not like I'm sitting there
going oh cuz I've only hung out with you
when somebody's dabbing it's only been
you and I always see like there's a good
amount of I guess chatter yeah so we're
gonna call yeah yeah wax wax is the same
you take this probably for doing it
right you take this product and at the
end you heat it again and apply like a
whipping motion to it to put air into it
and it just fluff it up a little bit
okay and some people skip a couple of
steps and they do that too early and
that [ __ ] everything up if you do it
right and do it at the end wax can be
great now what I like about it this we
have to use the little dab tools it's
kind of shatter it's hard to work with
wax you can pick it up and play with it
make a little ball and a slam dunk it
without a dabber okay a little easier to
work with and it hits harder yeah some
of the best-tasting
have ever smokes has been worse okay
sure yeah for sure some tangi wax as
long as your day the guy down there at
the end of the table actually has made
the best tasting wax oh sure I think it
was something you grew it a couple years
ago that was actually if you you know a
while ago too so it's probably the dog
or the I want to say it was the lemon
skunk wax yeah cool thank you I think
that lemon Geoffrey is some of the best
a lot of people always ask what's your
best for dabs if you're making shatter
order up a pack of lemon Geoffrey but
guess what everything sold out for a
minute
they're coming to I'm working on it it
takes a long time to breed some seeds
see that you're sold out I think you can
refill it tomorrow or like it takes a
minute bro how long does it take to
breed seats and what exactly is that oh
wow the quick part is you got to get
plants that you have to make selections
you have to have a male and no which
females you want to breed with you have
to get them large enough to put into the
flower stage which will take you two or
three months okay the way that I like to
grow usually about two months three if
you're just from clone then you got to
get those flowering you have to one
needs a head start on the other will not
get specific in two times so you're
looking about twelve weeks of flowering
time after the two months so you're
looking like five or six months just to
produce the seeds and then you need to
test them like if I were gonna put him
out I would give them to all these guys
to grow to see what they do before I
would even consider putting them out to
anybody of course yeah yeah and then if
I find that they're kind of [ __ ] up
but they're close I'll find one that's
really close to what I'm looking for
because it'll be variations that's there
be variations in phenotype it's like if
like your brothers and sisters all don't
look the same well stations yeah yeah
yeah I'd find the brother and sister
that looks just perfect that I want to
make babies with
to breed it back with the daddy again
okay and so that'll bring the traits
that I want maybe or or sometimes
crosses sometimes when you [ __ ]
everything up huh
but if you do it right if you fly if you
got that magic cut it's all genetic
combinations if they match up right
you'll come out with by the third or
fourth generation every seed will be
very similar to each other by the time
they're done okay yeah so breeding could
take if you're making F ones from fans
and you're cool with that five months
six months after making F ones that are
rags five or six months but if you want
to make f2s which are going back and re
breeding or make F threes
you're looking at years and years I
thought I was doing I've been that
crossing for four or five years now so
Wow and I'm only on the third leg of the
back cross so goodness yeah so there's
there's there's a lot more to you know
growing a weed then then many people
give you guys credit for you know
because I look at it I'm like alright
well there's plants in the ground or
plants and pots and they're growing them
and then harvest them and I don't look
at you know all the back work that goes
into that and I know that like like the
last time I smoked weed was ten years
ago and so of course things are gonna
get better but I I did see that huge
progression when when Medical started
being okay oh yeah
that's yeah they're really what is what
helped us be able to breed we could set
up not we but they could set up thousand
light wire houses and just throw out as
many seeds as they could and grow all of
them and then you find that magic keeper
and then yeah if you've got that if you
can grow in that many numbers that's why
Holland is big haulin lets you kind of
get away with a lot of playa numbers you
shout out to Holland the best comes from
Northern California or came in Colorado
Colorado Colorado breeders are killing
it not even from here but we have a lot
of we have a lot of advantages were the
same altitude and climate and conditions
as Afghanistan which is where a lot of
our favorite genetics are from oh it's
really advantageous yeah 300 days of
sunlight a year yeah that's you don't
get that in a lot of places yeah besides
like Iraq I grew up all right
do you yeah so the plants get huge here
gigantic yields trunks this big around
they for the listener that was like a
twelve inch circumference yeah easily
one of those Gatorade bottles or yeah
gonna arm two water bottles
I've seen I've seen branches that grow
man can actually stand on to like reach
the top of their plan yeah I've seen you
guys have to get ladders to trim the top
yeah there's I know spots where I've
been on three hundred and fifty plant
outdoor farms where the four of us grown
men sitting here sorry Kevin Dineen to
disclude you from the grown men but it
wouldn't take you also it just needs us
for the four of us could reach around
these plants and barely touch hands but
the four of us would take to get around
these plants Wow yeah we're looking five
pounds on some of those not on Jesse's
but these are like in a mountain town
where nobody you'll find him five pounds
out of one plant five pounds out of one
and then rocking probably 300 of a month
some of these plantations but that's I
mean there's putting a lot of money into
like the like you were saying yeah
there's there's a crew like us weren't
like us boys there's a crew of us
working there all day long from morning
to night all day and then at night they
just hang out like they pass out yes
it's hard manual labor it is people
don't give us credit for yeah for being
uh I've got an indoor facility and
you've got trash to deal with like the
city doesn't want your weed trash you
gotta know that you got to get that to
the dump and the dump doesn't want it
either well yeah but that's a fire
ordinance you know I don't want to come
into your grow facility it smells it
stinks
it smells got to deal with you got water
to deal with there's a lot to think
about
it's yeah electricity the fire hazards
licensing there's a lot too yeah see and
that's something I think everybody got
mad because like the dispensaries were
oh it's gonna be so expensive I can get
it from this guy and it's like well yeah
but look how professional they are being
with these in these dispensaries yeah
they have to go through such regulations
right and the weed there mostly is
usually pretty clean usually they're
going through a lot of regulation now so
the weeds tested they're all going
through steep hill Halen labs or a
similar laboratory
and they're getting all their stuff
tested for mold parasites pesticides
little bugs so if there's spider mites
or fungus gnats or white flies in your
weed they're gonna find it they're able
to test Addison said that they can test
for things like flora mite and has a max
and as oh my in your plants in Eagle 20
in your bud
if you use that [ __ ] in the cloner yeah
yeah that's one of those is a mite aside
one of them is actually a fungicide and
the other one is just like an all-around
bug treatment but what that means is in
the cloner is basically the start of
life you cut a plant and it's got a
clone to make roots and then you got a
veget most people go 3 or 4 weeks I go
30 to 45 days I like them a little
bigger and then you flower for usually 9
weeks is average
so from these little tiny babies all the
way to they grow and you flower it you
dry it you trim it out this lab can find
pesticides in there they can be like oh
yeah use this [ __ ] here it is we found
it in there
oh you dry it out of these like this
kind of but these are like neurotoxins
and proven carcinogenic sand now you
don't want a dad nervous because where
most of us are dabbers they're they're
meant for ornamental flowers that aren't
going to be consumed okay yeah but
doesn't care medical caregivers we don't
like his pops is quite sick he's got a
condition that if we gave him some
cannabis that had neurotoxins in it it's
only gonna make him worse we're trying
to heal him you know so that's the kind
of stuff that we all have to be aware of
and we have to be conscious of and like
that's our goal that's what separates
the medical growers and the real growers
from just the guys out there trying to
make a buck I'd rather cut down a moldy
plant throw it away and sell it to one
of my own most of my patients honestly
are older cats and I don't want to see
them I don't want to feel like I just
killed them I don't want that I do this
to feel better it feels good to watch
people his old man came over one time
felt like he walks with a cane
yeah hunched over walks with a cane
smoked the perfect strain with him that
dude stood up and walked up the stairs
and turned around and said hey we bring
me my cane I forgot it nice yeah that's
the kind of [ __ ] that makes you feel
like Jesse smiling over there
is not in his head that's like yeah it's
awesome
oh yeah that's that's some weed that
people hate I drew that and it made this
guy stand up and he forgot her know if
he forgot that he heard or if the pain
went away it doesn't matter the
interaction the smoke session and the
cannabis healed him long enough for him
to forget his cane and walk up some
stairs so that's that's where is even
going I guess no topic but as the at the
bud Bowl this weekend one of the judges
did it uh don't worry Oh judges that
smoked the grape OG was epileptic and
she told me she didn't have any seizures
for three days why she was smokin that
oh and I mean that's awesome
she had already smoked pot and you know
had good results from it but it still
had the occasional seizure but with the
grape OG she I guess three days with
that one so now is that a like a THC
content or a CBD content hasn't been
tested it's the perfect combination
whatever it is I don't think it's one
I'm not a scientist but as my experience
with the plant and administering plants
and strains do people think it's a
combination of terpenoids and THC CBD
all of the different cannabinoids I
think it's a combination perfectly
matching her condition in her body
profile there may be another person
sitting right next to her that has the
same condition that it may not help yeah
exactly but I may have a plant in my
arsenal that may be perfect for that
person well there's thousands of strains
now yeah yeah and there's millions
because Jesse's appalled and chucker
Spence is on his way to be an apology
I'm a pollen chucker
by the time calf gets good at drawing
weed he'll fall in chucker because he's
watching all of us yeah it only takes a
little once if you're reaching for
quality you want a pollen jock it's the
way that the progression goes I had to
explain to a customer one time he he
actually was like I don't see why
there's all these different strains they
can't be different and I had to explain
him like actually they are like we found
over 200 different molecules that are in
different levels in every single plant
so you can teach us about genome mapping
I can't wait I'll call him and see what
he knows maybe he can put us in touch
with the right people
shadow absent amorous steve hill labs
yeah something else i just like to
mention kinda on the subject a CBD only
legislation that is happening estates
that like maybe just a strain named
after a book they only want to grow that
well that's [ __ ] because because of
what we were just talking about yeah
it's the full profile not just CBD some
conditions do require a higher level of
certain things than than other
conditions yeah you need to find the
right one that has the right levels of
the right molecules for you you know one
thing that one thing that somebody
discovered i did this was not my
discovery I think it was Mitch to know
so they made this realization plants
that are high in CBD and low and THC
qualifies him and it's legal to grow
hemp all the [ __ ] over mm-hm so grow
that [ __ ] grow a large fields of CBD
plants if that's you're sick yeah and
then make RSO out of it so actually
we're not supposed to call it artists Oh
Rick I was referring to Rick Simpson oil
but we're not gonna call it Rick Simpson
oil anymore because there's some
controversy with that people claim that
he stole the idea and there's a lot of
weird stuff being said in the cannabis
community and I don't want any part of
the backlash so it's full cannabis plant
extract essentially you take a whole
plant and I don't know how to do it I'm
kind of ignorant to it that's not my I'm
not an extract guy I'm a grower you take
the whole plant and you take a whole
bunch of it and you make a little bit of
it looks like tar and it's edible or you
can rub it on and it's uh it's basically
all the cannabinoids and all the good
parts squished into a little tiny vial
and you take just a pea-sized bite of it
and it's been known to I can't see cure
cancer but stop cancer and it Tommy
Chong claims if that's what got rid of
his prostate cancer Wow yeah real life
snake oil yeah but the real [ __ ] yeah
yes so he calls it snake oil is like oh
so it's fake but it's it's miracle [ __ ]
but no none of the medical
establishments want to recognize that
it's actually your curing and helping
well of course not because if it's
curing things and they have no job
exactly exactly but they're a little
girls not having seizures and Tommy
Chong doesn't have prostate cancer and
pretty soon our Kev's my buddy chemist
is not gonna have his condition if we
can find somebody that's willing to help
us out with some I don't know how to do
it and I don't know how much product it
takes but we need somebody to help us
out with some RS oh definitely so
Colorado and you've got a little bit to
help us out with trade you seeds or
something we're willing we've got a guy
in need he's a two of them yeah we got
two really really smart extract artists
yeah and two good rowers yeah we don't
read the perfect strain we could make it
you guys do it I think I have an idea
how do you how to make it I just don't
hurt ourselves
don't hurt yourself it looks [ __ ]
scary dude it looks scarier than making
BHO to me one of those ingredients to
our s oh yeah it's a little tiny bit of
it it's supposed to get rid of cancer
and it comes from like a whole whole
plan no the whole plan full plant
extract I've heard it called full
extract cannabis oils any other names
for there's a movie called run from the
Cure or Run for the Cure Race for the
Cure
yeah Race for the Cure Race for the Cure
at the rate Simpson story if you guys
want to know more about it check that
one out it's worth it's worth the watch
that YouTube YouTube will have it yeah I
have the DVD of it here somewhere if you
guys headed 20 if I can find it yeah
cool I got a very basic question good
like indigo versus sativa anybody wanna
laugh um a Mike Adams cool and that one
too yeah he meant the first one yeah he
wants to know about what's what's blue
versus sativa indica is more of a strain
from Iraq Afghanistan rocky mountainous
regions that is more that make you
lazier or couch locky
that's the strains where you will find
the CBD stuff so sativa is more of a
tropical region kind of stuff it'll grow
so the indicas grow short and bushy
gonna have bigger fatter leaves they
finish earlier because where they're
from the cult comes and they got to be
done sooner and they don't get as tall
because they're in Rocky your area so
the land
the roots actually branch out further
this way instead of going down yeah
because they're in rocky regions they
can't dig so they stay it may get bushy
because they can dig up bigger feet so
they can balance out wider sativas on
the other hand err from tropical area so
they get real tall and they kind of get
Airy so they don't get moldy because
there's humidity there so they've got to
get some like this is the grossest
[ __ ] description you know and it's
hot here ball swing yeah sativas kind of
spread out a little a little bit trying
to get some space yeah so the sativa is
kind of do that and if you guys are
getting larvae buds in your grow room
just cuz you're overheating and that's
the exact reason why if you're not
growing a good sativa in your shits air
it out it's cuz it's too hot try to get
some space make sure yeah
so a sativas are more from like what a
vietnam like a lot of stuff is from
vietnam like like asian countries and
stuff like that the way laughing
spinster now somebody hey Shona Fung
made my torch I've said that a couple
times on the show if you want a really
cool custom torch fun fun he'll do your
nails do yeah yeah I'm gonna take a
picture of it right now
Instagram and I'll tag Jeff in it so we
can check it out too but uh so that I
can check it out I've never seen it
before yeah what's it look like pretty
cool I was saying see your listeners can
check it out indicas we'll finish
earlier and because I've seen some
they've finished in 55 56 days I like to
let most plants go at least 60 I think
they're done then but uh indicas will be
done around 9 weeks the longest I've got
sativas that take 77 days which is 11
weeks in flower that's just the the
flowering cycle and they'll grow tall
and skinny and I think they pack on way
more THC like the sativa plants they get
you way I prefer that buzz so that's an
ex parte the high indicas are the ones
when you smoke at the end up laying on
the couch
that's indica if you need to calm down
if you need to sleep if you need to eat
that's in because the way to go if you
need to get the dishes done if you want
to paint if you want to play music and
get create if you want to ramble on a
podcast smoke some sativas okay yeah
that's that's kind of the opposite there
no no for like a layman like me somebody
that doesn't do this and I do feel like
you know this could be advantageous to
writing and stuff like that
where would I start you know who find it
you have two three or four Deb is half a
gram dab is the way to go for the start
this might need to win screen I felt
myself blowing [ __ ] up sorry gonna do
mic guys are kind of like it so you
would want to pipe like this and I'm not
encouraging I'm just showing you pipe
like this with the fresh bowl of
something man if anybody at this table
drew it it's gonna [ __ ] you up one hit
and you're gonna be high from it so just
take one good hit be hanging out with
somebody like us that knows what's up
they'll be don't call your mom I'm so
high don't do that [ __ ] hang out with us
we'll feed you but get you some water
you're gonna wanna watch some cartoons
yeah sounds normal
some spaghetti or a peanut butter and
jelly sandwich can't cure nice that's
all you need to do is eat and take a nap
and if you're too high or whatever
you'll be fine but our good friend Wade
Ridley there's a good comedian buddy of
yours what's up bro he'll have an idea
you know he'll come up with the bit and
Karlin said the same thing he'll write a
bit and then they'll write it sober and
then smoke a little and go back and
season it that's like putting the
dressing on it you know back and that's
when you kind of go and sprinkle some
detail and get a little funk into it all
right that's kind of how I did it as a
musician - we'd go to like writing
sessions totally sober but then you show
up for Brett practice or recording and
you smoke a little puff and that's when
you start Oh Oh check it out oh yeah
then you get a little funkier when you
get stoned you just loosen up a little
yeah and I feel like the right strain
some strains don't do this but the right
strain like when you put blinders on a
horse when the horse is at the fair so
it can't see the [ __ ] on the outside the
left and right eye just focuses on
what's in front of it good weed the
right strain does that to me and it puts
me just boom in the focus if I'm playing
music or growing weed watching a movie
playing a video game I'm in that [ __ ]
like just that it's like goggles for me
humming trimming oh yeah dude give me
one of those indica chiba chews and sent
me down
and time flies and I trim the whole crop
it's awesome but but for a nonsmoker
where they're gonna get started is
probably just trying to start with a
pipe
yeah maybe a joint or a pipe and just
one or two good puffs is all you need
well if somebody here drew one puff if
you got it from the dispenser you take
two and just put it down and see what
happens if you don't feel high enough
you'll know we're gonna take your time
yeah I mean really well some people
don't you know some people like the
edible people that have just been
scarfing the whole snack thinking that
there's Superman and getting hurt and
[ __ ] see that's something that I had
kind of thought like I was like man the
edibles are probably like where you want
to start but that's way wrong
yeah the edibles will sneak up on you
spence's Naughton one night Spence's
lady
they made some dads in a pyrex dish like
you're supposed to do and we had plenty
so they didn't want to scrape it all out
you know there's some residuals in there
she put the dish in the oven to heat it
up and all the dabs soak to the bottom
or sunk like in a puddle
she bought a brownie mix on top of that
[ __ ] and I think there were four or six
grown men in that room that ate that
[ __ ] and all of us were comatose it
wrecked us and I can't get that high
from smoking like it would take all day
to smoke that much so that's that's pro
level staff that would do that was super
mario versus the dragon in the [ __ ]
tunnel trying to fight Metroid on level
three like it was it was insane dude
that's scene that's just kind of
something where I don't know where the
where my thoughts came from on that like
I I guess I just thought you know you
would you would just start with brownies
or something just have a piece of a
brownie and that's where you'll start Oh
to last four or five times longer if you
need a brownie - yeah edibles lasts a
long time I get I feel drunk I've had
nights ready eating too many edibles
where I've woken up and been like holy
[ __ ] what did I do
like and you feel weight hangover yeah
big time I don't complain from it I
don't mind it huh like I like it had a
hangover in a while so yeah no thanks
I'm too hyper so I got to smoke the
indicas to kind of keep me mellow when
I'm smoking flowers but when I smoke
dabs I prefer a sativa hmm yeah for that
head spin yeah sure you agree yeah word
I like edibles to sleep like if I can't
sleep yeah yeah we'll put you down yeah
that's what I use it for I like to eat
edibles before a comedy show I'm going
to see some comedy this week
I'll definitely stop at a dispensary and
pick up too many edibles and overdose
myself for the show right on yeah good
300 milligrams I'll be Kiki Kiki Oh Bart
exactly a TKO stirring some Claudie
bears yeah Claudia bear [ __ ] yeah that's
the perfect combo for me but for those
guys coming from out of state that
haven't had the experience that we do
here in Colorado and they go to a place
they go to just go buy something
start with weed and a pipe yeah smart
with weed and a pipe joint don't buy a
pre-roll from a dispensary never buy a
pre-roll from a dispensary they're
giving you all the [ __ ] that fell on the
floor while they're trimming you're
gonna have a bad time you're gonna have
a bad time I like that see there you go
Texas we love you Texas we're trying to
make peace with you by offering good
weed please be careful with edibles yes
yes start off with like a pipe or a
joint and then if you're gonna eat an
edible get something if you get a
hundred milligram edible seriously eat a
quarter of it and wait 45 minutes 25
milligrams doesn't sound like much of
THC but for a skinny dude like Kevin
sighs that's never eaten edibles that's
plenty dude a lot of people that come
into the shop that's too much for them
like they need like 1/8 of it or a
10-minute walk to Mildred yeah they
seriously need like 10 15 milligrams and
they're perfect a lot of like never
tried weed in their entire life yeah and
they're scared of that thing yeah it's a
pipe smoking you know they don't smoke
at all there were people at the Cannabis
Cup this weekend that we were in line
for two hours dude so batter now we're
into it Kevin and I pulled out our dab
ribs Oh somes cutting out here is me I'm
too loud sorry my fault so we start
dabbing in some people Chicago people
we're like what the [ __ ] what is that
it's dad's bro you want one and they're
like Oh
[Music]
you have a guy his first dab at a party
and his eyes were better than your shirt
bros Vince is wearing a red Nike shirt
and it is blood red for sure and his
eyes were that richer yours are I can
feel yeah we got some good dads at the
table I've got this fat dab sitting here
I'm gonna take it out of this little
Rasta rig off of a highly-educated 14
millimeter flux now cuz that's what I
flux with is there a strange for a
non-user that you would recommend that
is setting on user a medical patient or
just a recreational smoker this is gonna
be Rick or you know what I think that's
I don't know what do you think your
listeners they're gonna want to hear
honestly I think they'll want to hear
both yeah for a medical patient I'm
gonna see how it elaborate like you're
going for I always ask above the head or
below the head or like spine or brain
like there's no there's a couple
questions there Tora Bora is an
all-around good strain for new smokers
it's high in CBD it's low in THC you'll
get a nice tingly body buzz if you're a
new smoker your body will feel good and
high but you won't freak out you won't
get paranoid
it's not so high in THC and th TV and
THC aid that your head is gonna spin and
you're gonna get paranoid cuz that's
what ruins the high for a lot of people
they reverse sign they're so high
they're scared and paranoid and freaking
out you won't get that from the Tora
Bora also for a medical smoker Tora Bora
wreckin medical I guess if you want to
get head wrecked go for a strong sativa
get some Sour Diesel I'm not sure if
that's really sativa but when I smoke it
I can't pay any attention like I'm a pro
and Sour Diesel messes me up I can't sit
down on decently yeah Sour Diesel yeah
it's the one that makes you want to do
the dishes and all kinds of stuff like
that you just brought up something
really funny I'm gonna give a plug to
another podcast just as they clear up a
lot of myths the Adam Dunn show for sure
had ken-dog and a J and P but I think
his name was on the show and they talked
about a lot of cool stuff so you guys
check that out if you're a fan of my
show you like that Adam Dunn show if you
have questions about
Sour Diesel gabber there you go nice
catch
if you got questions about Sour Diesel
if you got questions about the chem dog
the people that made that [ __ ] and a
stat well they didn't make it the people
that mainly found this yeah they they do
a show and you want to hear it like
that's that's a plug for another podcast
I listen to it so it's good it's good
yeah I think everything so yeah we all
heard it listen to that [ __ ] Adam Dunn
Mitch Inasa all those guys great show
bike good show guys if you ever heard an
[ __ ] that's funny
somebody talk Willie take a dab the the
public up that you guys just did how
prestigious is that how many entries and
stuff like that are there how many their
first debate okay so everybody's first
event is kind of you know it's the first
one so nobody knows exactly what to do
yeah but I mean there was entries from
Penrose local pueblo dispensary pueblo a
couple other local growers so it was I
mean it wasn't a large event but I mean
because it was the first you are they
gonna do it or is it gonna be I think
it'll be annually oh yeah I think this
plant and and is there a reason they did
it in April 420 that one I got it's like
our Super Bowl yeah and actually with
the cannabis scope it's rapidly becoming
that I heard literally yeah I was
thinking um that maybe there was
something to do with the growth cycle or
something like a good harvesting time
that that would have been that's why but
maybe I don't know when if you are doing
it outdoors you're not gonna have like
indoor conditions like that you can
control your outdoors so when is the
harvest when you're outdoors oh yeah
right around Halloween course depending
it depends on strange conditions yes
right before the first snowfall yeah no
you go cut that [ __ ] Colorado you got to
let him go right
then sometimes or you pull out the hoop
houses and the heaters people get
elaborate but basically right around
Halloween is usually about harvest time
okay yeah so so why isn't and then how
long after say you harvest and it takes
you a couple weeks to trim everything
depending on the size of the harvest um
didn't dried and cured up to three weeks
and then and then after you've done
trimming how long until that weed is
able to be smoked
depending on your thirst for the money
right then or gear it for a couple of
weeks or your trim style too I suppose
yeah yeah yeah okay and then and then in
good conditions how long can that we'd
stay good six months ish I've seen we
last a year but six months is before
it'll start degrading and [ __ ] in a jar
sealed alright so maybe the end of May
would be the end of excuse me may be the
end of May would be like the trying to
get rid of everything so I guess April
20th would be like a good that's the
time people flush out all their that's
why you see the dispensaries with all
their sales they're getting rid of last
year's outdoor stuff oh for 20 yeah I
also think what's a holiday that it's
becoming a lot of growers playing a
shoot for that they plant and there's
like there's cups there's contests you
know I'm saying and there are actually
uh harvest ball cannabis competitions
but we're so busy if you got a big
outdoor girl you're just too busy at
that season even do anything you've got
a big harvest you're trying to trim it
curious you got to flip it you gotta pay
your trimmers you got to get back
cleaned up you got to get [ __ ] going
like it's a busy time of year so make
sense no that's that's all good
information that you know if somebody
was wanting to attend one of those
there's a good reason that it's in April
like that you're not super busy at that
part when when are you starting like
when you start plants and stuff when
you're outside now yeah June 1st is a
good day I mean set somewhere towards
the end of July beginning of September
to say that right
August August yeah with my brain that's
what most strange will start flowering
okay outdoors I've seen plants you know
go a little faster than what they did
indoors
I've seen the exact opposite but you
know that's when you go from the it
stops growing and and starts well not
necessarily stops growing but that's
what it starts produced seeing a flower
a fruit and that's the that's the cone
the bug yeah and that's what we're
little white pixels yeah for sure first
part you're smoking yeah that part takes
about nine weeks to develop yeah ish
depending on the strain yeah snap [ __ ]
me up I'm having a good time I didn't
even ask you how your 4/20 was other
than other than your victory yeah yeah
went to Canada Cup on Saturday and
worked sold t-shirts for the greener
side yeah how was that I smoked a lot of
weed
we stopped by the booth it was chaotic
yeah it was chaos it was nice checked it
out a little so Danna head up the bug
Bowl on Sunday
you mean anybody cool with the top I'm
Dani Danko giddy up I think that's it
probably I I saw some cats but you know
working was she so yeah I'm sure you
were busy dude I stopped by that booth
and it was crazy
I was right there on the other side at
the gauge booth a lot of the time yeah
that's my buddy how about you Spence how
was your 4/20 um it was fun the the cup
was crazy it was there's a lot of people
I'm not the people person I mean I like
people but there's just like thousands
of people around you so the house I like
to smoke to shark you can't really just
smoke walking around with 10,000 people
around you but it was fun I got to see a
bunch of people that I wanted to meet
also pick up genetics
yeah that was a lot of people's goal
they did a lot of genetics hey uh when
you say pick up a genetics or I mean get
come on his face buying seeds all the
breeders go and they have booths all the
seed makers yeah so you could buy seeds
of almost all the hottest strains most
of the hottest strains on the market you
could pick those up at the cup for
discount prices and if you know the guys
and he make buddies they'll throw you
freebies and [ __ ] if you buy intro from
them a lot cheaper and you get some
hookups no are those like feminized when
they come some Sam and reg yeah what
what would um what constitutes it being
feminized like it will 99.9% of those
plants will be females will grow from
those seeds Yeah right
and then you get G papa yeah there's
some strains that have failed and this
is breeding techniques some genes don't
match up properly so they don't make
good seeds and you have to throw those
away but that has come from a specific
plant that are going to produce female
plants female seeds feminized seeds so
why take a female plant and I treat it a
specific way and that makes it turn into
a male mm-hmm but it doesn't actually
have any male genetics in it I just kind
of stressed it to do that hmm and so
when it produces that pollen there's no
male chromosomes in there Wow so when it
hits the female it's only female
genetics that are combining once women
figure it out or all folks
yeah females I hope you weren't
listening to that [ __ ] [ __ ] I explained
it to my girlfriend once and that was
kind of my replay replay we just end the
show with a suction sound and we're all
done right there once women figure it
out we're [ __ ] us again the hate tweets
we're gonna get
our listeners loved us they're all stone
alright so you're at the cup did you go
to some concert I saw some pictures bro
um yeah I went to a dizzy concert he's
somewhat of a new hip-hop artist out of
Las Vegas he's got a good movement you
know he's all about like he makes a song
called world peace you know and he
smokes a lot of herbs so I was fortunate
enough to be able to give him to lead
because who knows where he's getting his
weed from so I figured hey I'll give you
some weed Instagram because he was
giving you shoutouts he liked your weed
bro
there's a picture of him holding the
garden of Weeden jar and he looks faded
I think he's actually next to you
standing next to you in that picture
yeah [ __ ] it's cool though because you
go into like and honestly it wasn't like
a big venues at Cervantes and did yeah
yeah so it was just the backstage is
like who saw that so it was cool we just
blaze down got to give us some stickers
so who knows where those maybe those
stickers will make you somewhere yeah
well I saw where some of them made it
yeah yeah it's a bracket booty some
ratchet where would we what's your
what's your Instagram do you want people
know on that yeah that's cool it's a
garden of Weeden garden weed he grow
some really really nice stuff he works
with some of my strains some of the
hydrogen etic seed line he's one of my
testers I work with Jesse's as well two
and two a bush uh growing for hit not
for him but I'll grow some same strains
that he grows just to kind of have him
around since we're on plug Darrell where
do we find you
Jesse grows all one-word Instagram he's
got some lovely cannabis pics that's
what I got my ghost of Bubba
that's a fire strain a lot of good stuff
from them I got my white widow cut from
Spence over here for sure yeah how about
you Clint where do we find you at tall
Clint
Twitter Instagram then uh wild cousins
on Facebook at Todd client hey I was
awesome on our other show he he's he's
got some Tourette's and every once in a
while the conversation will be going and
you'll just you're at Oakland
it's Carl it's fun bro do you have
anything you want to check out online no
don't look at your stuff don't don't
look at me online
yeah I'm not interesting at all that's
interesting guys you want to stretch out
one more question we are like about 10
more minutes
sure more good question I I know that
like hemp is important for for just
becoming a better society honestly like
there's so much we can do with it I know
that we can only grow it or can we grow
it now is that like is that legal
now can we grow it like in a field
untested oh well in a field never end us
that's another question I thought you
meant in a garden like well I think so
because until now dr. Bronner's had to
buy all of their hemp in Canada and have
it shipped here and I'm pretty sure that
the first hemp crop that was produced in
America was purchased here in Colorado
it was purchased by dr. Bronner's so
there's some legal way that we can grow
him crops here now I'm ignorant to that
okay yeah I unfortunately don't know all
the specifics you guys are growing for
different purposes completely yeah but
that's a good question that we should
understand because that's a part of our
industry and hemp is really reliable
that's something I can show you oh okay
the government did just do something to
make it there was a hint bill I'm gonna
sound really ignorant but I'll give you
this much yeah there was a hint building
got approved and then in Colorado I
believe they just issued the first
licenses this year the actual license
that last year's crop was just kind of
crazy own testing the boundaries getting
the guys feet wet but uh yeah in in a
nutshell that's so like the first
industrial license industrial hemp crop
I saw pictures of crop yeah it was down
in our Springfield yeah hemp drop on the
on the notes here that'll be somebody
I'll try to talk about on one of the
next upcoming shows that's a good topic
um Adam Dunn would be
pretty good answer this close well yeah
I'll see him up at hood lab pretty soon
here shoutout to the hood lab here those
guys threw an awesome party here though
if I didn't ask you about your 4/20 bro
we talked about that in the last show so
yeah yeah so yeah
shadow to Adam doing he threw a hell of
a party we all hit the hive nail the
ceramic anybody got into reviews or
opinions you want to throw down and out
of it towards the end of the show I'm hi
I'm stuttering it's awesome very high
good I don't mind it um I like the
flavor the flavors a little bit better
than titanium I would say I guess
depending on what you're dabbing good
smooth it's smooth only reason I don't
like it is because I broke mine so it's
cool it wasn't like it wasn't as
expensive as titanium so it's it's if
you break it you can probably buy
another one um but I don't know if where
the directions in yours yeah okay see I
didn't read directions that's probably
why I broke a so I guess I am a fan of
it yeah I've been using pretty much
non-stop since I got it props for the
nice little rig - yeah sneaky the dudes
that I got it from hooked me up pretty
nice on it so got a little pendant ring
from them too so that was [ __ ]
awesome I don't even remember their
[ __ ] name I asked him like four times
yeah their sign was hard to read it was
something Street New Jersey maybe Jersey
Jersey Boys that's a mr. Dubois clue
some great Chris Christie if you're
listening which I'm sure you are did you
have any opinions on it I'm like I said
I'm a big guy
it scares me yeah that's cool just the
mic it was smooth it's it's hard to tell
how hot it is like that was mine like
you say I'm a big
I'm kind of afraid to break it yeah I
think I'm not a highly educated see I
didn't pay him to say that he doesn't
even know that the show is sponsored by
highly educated titanium products he
didn't know that so the show spot I'm
sure he's probably just mute - I know
yeah it doesn't even yeah it's just like
when you're a girl give me some seeds no
those don't exist any one about clones
so it's my turn I like the hive did it
taste good you're right it's hard itself
it's hard enough I agree with that I'm a
big guy I'm afraid I'm gonna break it I
agree with that I can't use my
pre-existing card cap and dagger that
I'm in love with and so I'm gonna buy
all new [ __ ] for that which I mean for
me that's not a big deal I do okay but
some people are not privileged in doing
well and they can only buy a few dad
things so I guess here's my my sum up if
you can only buy one nail get titanium
because you're gonna break the hive
eventually for sure but if you're
spoiled and you want to try something
cool if you're a spoiled hash bag for
your connoisseur so if you're from
Colorado I personally don't recommend it
for like your travel rigs like towards
bounce it around and [ __ ] like just
chill it on the table put it on your
coil home if you know what I mean by
coil then you got a coil condenser
there's no way to hook it up to it so
far that I know of I could be totally
wrong I've never seen a way to hook it
up to an email uh yeah once they get
that going I think that constant he
would probably bust it that would be you
should be using a honey hole anyway if
you're doing that shout out Joel Halen I
definitely do like highly-educated
titanium for sure if you can only afford
one nail definitely educated either the
whatever size you got go for the duality
that's probably my favorite nail of all
of there's the duality you know the flux
the turbine flux that's the so that the
flux is the one here it's got
and then the turbine flux has like a
cone shape on the inside so kind of
swirls around the turbine flux is my
favorite my second if you have a dome
the turbine flux if you're going
domeless go for the duality yeah that's
and then a carb cap of course and I use
my carb cap on my domed rig to go that
was a fat plug right there man yeah that
was nice cool
one more question broke because that was
a quick question and it ended up more of
us rambling about him um like what laws
are coming out right now that we need to
be aware of like I know that like on the
iGrow culture twitter you had posted a
few things like
look at look at these guys look at these
guys there are two of them that we
should pay attention to
SB 77 and 78 is the drug endangered
Child Act they're gonna make it to our
what's hum and that's a weird sound it
sounds like a drag car Wow Wow dude what
do you guys got some gas over there some
Taco Bell so uh SB 77 and 78 the drug
endangered child act it basically has
accidentally aimed at cannabis users if
you have marijuana and utensils in your
home and you have children you're
endangering your child maybe not
accidentally yeah that was another part
of my rant on that too is giving kids
cannabis now because it helps so that's
something we need to fight against
because that accidentally like if I had
this in another room and my daughter was
on the couch that's a drug endangered
child in their eyes with the new axe so
we need to fight that down and on the
Instagram for agriculture or on the
Twitter there's plenty of info of people
to email and talk [ __ ] to about that the
other one I can't remember the numbers
of it it's a caregiver act that's trying
to limit Colorado caregivers to 30
plants maximum no matter what your
location or status okay that's gonna
[ __ ] a lot of reasons for several
reasons we went over it on a whole
episode but if you're if you have a
perpetual grow and you've got five
patients that require the amount of dabs
that my patients require 30 plants won't
cut it yeah
yeah and a lot of people grow small
hydroponic plants and there's a reason
why their doctors recommended them a
certain amount of plants and now there's
gonna be a new law it's like we're
playing football we're playing football
right you caught this pass you got super
close to the endzone
you got tackled you're cool right you're
doing good but then suddenly the breath
comes out and goes oh wait new rule new
rule you can't wear purple how you want
a purple back the [ __ ] up twenty yards
and you're like wait wait I didn't know
about that rule you just made and that's
what they're doing to us caregivers have
been around for 14 years you know as
long as a minimum 20 has been no issues
up until now and it's all about the
patients and the caregivers without that
relationship it wouldn't exist the whole
model would fall apart and they're
trying to make more people have to shop
in dispensaries and the dispensaries are
already out of medical weed but they
have plenty of recreational weed which i
think is a whole other rant that's
[ __ ] so that's it's about money in
the long run is what I think taking the
money away from and it's not they don't
realize we don't make any money being a
caregiver there's no money in it because
we don't take a lot of money from our
patients because they're sick people
there most of them don't work like the
people I work with don't have a real job
that are actually sick so I don't take
money from them and growing weed cost
time money and energy so I lose money
honestly being a grower like a caregiver
they're on fixed budgets yeah so we're
trying to they think that they're gonna
funnel money into their system from it
which they kind of will but in the long
run my patients are gonna go in pain or
sick or what if what if you were working
with cash hi cash I had had a tumor the
size of a golf-ball the only thing that
was keeping them alive was some cannabis
oil and if they limit his growers
production his tumor is gonna grow back
and he's passed already now
unfortunately bless him but he's a good
example and he died because they took
away his cannabis and that's kind of
what they're gonna do to people and
people are moving here because of the
availability and now they're like oh
rules and I don't find it fair so that's
something we need to shoot down yeah I
think that was a good question thank you
yeah dude no no I'm happy to be the
ignorant guy honestly we'll have you bet
because you do ask great questions hey
guys if you're listening tweet us at
agriculture and send us your questions
cuz that's I'd like to educate and help
you guys if you have some of those I
heard this and you don't know if it's
true
send it to me you consider to me
privately even if you want I won't say
your name that way you can not be
embarrassed if you feel like that I
invite all of your questions there's a
facebook there's an Instagram there's a
Twitter I've been posting up some cool
pictures on my eye region etics
Instagram check those out I don't plug
that very much so usually we do a
portion of the show right towards the
end called give thanks where we give
thanks to a person who is heavily
contributed to the cannabis industry
last week we cried it was awesome bless
each any cush we still miss you we still
love you this time got a really easy one
didn't take a lot of research I saw it
all weekend long I want to give thanks
to everybody everybody everybody in the
cannabis for 2710 the ganja movement
from Clint with questions to the growers
to the breeders to the smokers to the
dabbers to Danny Danko to frickin the
guys learnin to write to everybody
you've heard of gage green tea GA sub
cool Cali connection John hunts deep
he'll everybody that you've ever not
heard of all of them thank you that's
what makes it a community it's what
makes it a movement all of you guys
without all of us doing our little parts
there wouldn't be this without the
Colorado people doing what we did we
couldn't sit here and dab out at a table
I had a guest on that told me dad's in
Texas were a felony and you could do
life in prison look at my table look at
my table Kevin he's got a lot of
boyfriend's suddenly that was a long
rant but it was heartfelt really without
all the giant the without all the little
pieces the giant machine wouldn't
function I saw a lot of unity at the
Cannabis Cup this year I was kind of
proud because this industry has gotten
cliquey and I didn't see any of that
[ __ ] at the cup people that people
that hate each other saw each other and
gave each other hugs and made amends and
it was kind of cool so that's my gift
thanks this episode all of you guys
everybody for listening if you're not
listening if you've ever smoked weed if
you've thought about weed if you've
fought for weed
if you flicked a Roach somewhere if you
found a roach someone thank you we give
you thanks thanks for being part of our
family anybody got anything to say at
the end the show is I think we should
try that great
gee real quick and give a little well a
little review on that before we got it
he doesn't want to tell us the genetics
of it though he's keeping one parents
secret it's a cool if I plug a couple of
shows do it dude do I got a may 2nd will
be at Phil's radiator here in Pueblo
we're gonna be that's a local standouts
for the first part first Friday after
party be up in Manitou May 17th all you
Manitou hippies go see some comedy he's
funny
thank you I appreciate that thank you
and then we're bringing some big names
through Pueblo on May 27th we got a
couple of people coming from LA David
Ross and Amber Tozer and then we got one
of my favorite comedians Sam talent
coming down from Denver nice Tozer well
[Music]
yeah so much better looking I am yeah so
no fortunately I've seen a lot more of
your skin yeah things go but each of
these shows is only five dollars you'd
be hoping that's not a lot just to come
and laugh and we got open mikes and
stuff like that I mean find us on wild
cousins on Facebook Wow's cousins it's
we're trying to we're trying to make one
better and southern Colorado like just
give us something to do because I don't
smoke and I don't drink you know I quit
smoking cigarettes like an e-cig now
like I any puffs on that thing they're
like a pacifier yeah that [ __ ] yeah no
it's it's really bad so tell us who's
all in the wild cousins since we're on
that topic
oh it's myself Paul Rosales [ __ ] him I'm
just kidding yeah whoever you were gonna
say [ __ ] John Wayne oh [ __ ] him -
yeah it's a little tiny hands
brevet marques I love that guys so much
I can't even joke about him yeah he's
great yeah and then Matt Chapman oh he's
awesome - yeah and then we got some
Denver guys that are I love all you wild
cousins boys I'm just giving any [ __ ]
Andy bueno and Patrick Scott they're
good guys everybody's we're just having
fun you know everybody's getting so much
better we've only been doing it you know
eight months or so like most of us down
here but I think we're getting better so
get on it that's all it is that stuff
tastes really good thank you I'm hitting
it it was nice and smooth very very uh
surprising outcome towards the
microphone like I could share it with
the listeners like they would get a
taste of like here who have some okay I
taste a grape that's very smooth yeah
it's linger it's like I had some great
bubble gum in my mouth before I pass it
- very well done bro I see why you can
win some stuff all right thank you thank
you for sharing that Congrats on your
winnings guys we're gonna in the show
with some music I don't know we're gonna
play a piece in it at the end piece it
in at the end language is hard after a
lot of dab so excuse us any last words
last chance yeah if anybody likes or
dislikes this let Jeff know because well
you know we'll try to format so what
people like will take a DAB and laugh
about it yeah but what if you don't like
me being on here and asking stupid
questions and let him know if you do if
you think it's add value let us know
he's coming back so I like his his
element you bring a lot yet we forget
we're pot snobs and elitists we forget
that people aren't all up to speed so
it's great having you here honestly I'm
not just rubbing your ass no that's not
this time not this time not this time
all right ladies and gentlemen take a
phat dab give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
find yourself in writer bono I go by the
name coppice - now you're know it - two
choices start
[Music]
yeah sup ladies and gentlemen welcome to
episode number nine of the high-growth
culture podcast thanks for joining us
again I'm your host Rasta Jeff it's good
to be here with you this podcast is
brought to you by nature's green
remedies dot-com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gauge green genetics
apply to labs since city-bred dankness
mile-high Ken adventure area genetics
and many more trusted brands right now
if you purchase two packs of either
genetics you will receive a free five
pack of Bounty Killer seeds while
supplies last also nature's green
remedies is running a special for the
podcast listeners I'm gonna turn that
down just a little bit there you go
all right we're running special for the
podcast listeners type in Kuta coupon
code I read 2014 for 10% off any order
and of course you always get free
shipping at nature's green remedies calm
we're also brought to you by highly
educated titanium if you're consuming
high-grade extracts you deserve a high
grade titanium nail don't trust the nail
made in China by people who don't care
about your health trust the company
who's been a part of the movement since
the beginning highly educated titanium
more information or to purchase highly
educated titanium products of idjit
visit Aqualab technologies dot-com also
a huge fist bump and a shout out to the
grimy Gatsby big shout out to hunt the
grimy Gatsby the lifestyle to rich in
the Gatsby music fashion parties
sustainable living action sports and all
the grime you can handle WWE Grammy
Gatsby comm check in daily on news from
around the world much respect also a big
shout out to select the nicotine you're
listening to Joseph Starr sound presents
Kush and coconut water before we go any
further a big shout out we defeated
Senate bill 177 and 178 victory yeah
word also coming up in this episode
we're gonna talk about a local hookah
bar got scrutinized for their private
dad parties we're gonna mention
something about a weed symphony
and we're gonna read a little bit about
a review of a Denver Post article that
has a bunch of frequently asked
questions and they respond with some
weird and sometimes accurate answers so
we're gonna read a little bit about that
if we have time turn this music down
introduce our buddy hanging out with
this we got Kevin back what's up bro
what's up dude how you been been good
man hanging out hanging out nice
everything's been real busy since 420
everyone thought it was gonna calm down
not in this industry man it never comes
down it just keeps building and building
and building I think we drunk up more
business and now it's made us even
busier I'm not complaining I love it
yeah oh my gosh I've been busy it's fun
it's fun a good industry to be busy in a
lot of cool things coming up some
collaborations and such I did I did get
my email sent to the secret cup for my
company name and all my contact info so
I haven't received anything back yet but
it has been sent and Big D sent me a
private message on what to send and
we're so so I better get going because
it's gonna yeah soon we have to focus we
have to do it at the end of July I think
because the competition is the first
week of August I believe all right cool
so it has to be dried ready to go we'll
talk about that it is time to think
about that you told me right after 4/20
if we hadn't talked about to let you
know so I just put in my grower get some
[ __ ] together I think we've got it I
think we're well on the right path so
well yeah that was not planned at all a
shout out to the whole secret cup
community Big D is it Jeremy that helps
put it together after Jeremy Nouri yeah
shout out to that guy
he's the rig rags dude that's an
excellent event oh he was also also he
was on another podcast that listened to
recently so cool yeah he's a really nice
guy you know he's a cool dude he seems
to be knowledgeable yeah and Big D of
course yeah first one of the leaders in
the hash industry
yeah so I'm gonna turn this music down
just a little bit more just cuz it feels
too loud to talk over it won't go down
much more without muting it out but
there we go alright so how are you bro
I'm good man busy like just like you
I've been working the hell out of the
shop and getting stopped and asked all
kinds of questions all the time so it's
been are you calming down are you
picking up uh we've been picking up and
we've been doing summer is bringing in
busier days yeah so are you getting more
locals are you getting more like
out-of-towners it seems to still be
about the same ratio a lot of our
customers are out-of-towners it's kind
of amazing
well most of the local people that come
in and buy weed they already have their
cards and chips so that's most of our
medical side is our local people and
then the REC gets a lot of state
shirred some Jillybean with me from the
other day that's how things go before
it's gone yeah shout out to tur pax
Jordan from Turpin hangout with Jordan
and also me Gatsby but I got to hang out
Jordan the other day and he threw me
down some og dad's just a couple of dabs
of it it didn't last long dude those
dads were great if you listen to show
tur pecks at trip X - 15 Jordans cool
dude they're these got other dudes but
Jordans guy I met that's good hash derp
X good guys yeah chirp X is one of my
favorite companies for sure
and of course hi dude thanks for letting
me kick it on your couch that was pretty
fun yeah we won't even elaborate there
yeah it took dad with your dad bro not
really it was kind of a joke I showed up
in hunt was dressed in business attire
he looked like a substitute teacher
because I had my dreadlocks I was happy
in the sunshine mode and he looked like
he was babble on there to give me a drug
test or something
shut out bro shoutout he changed clothes
and we got down to some dabs yeah he's a
cool guy
cool we got a bunch of news I kind of
wanted to bring to the table I've got a
lot of topics Kevin and I used to I
don't want to say too much we used to
hang out kind of contribute a little bit
sponsor I guess a dab party at a local
hookah bar at the cloud9 hookah bar
on 4th and Santa Fe I think the address
is actually 420 South Santa Fe 419 419
okay it was close okay but that's not
the point is and I'm gonna read a
Facebook post that they post and we'll
just get right to the point I regret to
inform our club members that all
cannabis events in the city of Puebla
have been canceled by the Pueblo Police
Department under threat of revoking
business licenses consumption of
cannabis in a private setting is legal
according to the amendment 64 task force
regulation of MMJ and recreational
cannabis
however we apologize for this injustice
and our administrative ly working to
bring you a safe place to consume
cannabis however as of today April 26th
2014 all cannabis events canceled by
Pueblo Police Department others under
threat to shut down the club permanently
for additional information there's a
phone number and then they say we shall
overcome if you want to support this or
something it's a cloud 9 hookah H oo ka
H check that out they're the one in
Pueblo Colorado that's where Kevin and I
rep were from Pueblo Colorado much love
if you want something if you want to
help out if you have some legal advice
or some guidance or if you just want to
chime in on their page and show some
support go to cloud 9 who could let them
know that you support them because it's
kind of crap yeah I definitely had a lot
of customers that came into our shop
because we were helping promote the last
event that unfortunately got cancelled
but we had a lot of people come in that
night for the event we're really bummed
that they couldn't go and partake
because there most of the people were
from out of state that recently have
moved to the area and so they're trying
to meet new people and meet like-minded
people and it was people of all
different types and ages and everything
just like every other cannabis event
yeah we had everybody it was packed on
that Saturday with these lawyers coming
in to get their herb before going down
there and then they were just bummed to
hear that all day it was really
unfortunate so there they're back in it
100% as well we got a lot of customers
that are trying to help out with the
movement too so if any of you guys are
listening to it that's the the Facebook
page that you can go and show some
support and you can write city council
send them a well written thought out
response and letter
don'tjust yeah right chicken scratch
they type it yeah there's a printer he's
spellcheck spell check grammar check all
that and man show support I've met
several of our friends they're people
that we hang out with yeah yeah exactly
and I have actually met a couple of
people that I knew already on Facebook
that I wanted to hang out with I told
them come down to this place and meet me
because it's a chill spot bring new
people to my house I don't have to go to
your house and that place is cool so uh
we met and just Manny Anna and Gary all
three I met at that spot on different
occasions and now that was such huge
networking we're just friends now I got
my job through that place see like the
manager of the place went down there for
one of our events and invited me to come
meet the owner and you know start
working I hadn't had a job for almost
eight years we used to be able to do
here just give you some background I
guess I should rewind a little there was
a there's this hookah bar they're still
open you can still go in there you can
get your hookah I think they have a pool
table and they watch movies in there you
can still go get your hookah
on you just can't consume cannabis at
all in there now so what we would do
they would post private parties and you
had to pay a cover charge to get in you
had to show your ID and once you did
that they would offer hash like in the
form of dabs which would be either wax
or shatter and then I would always be
there with some flowers and Shatter and
I would just be rolling up fat joints
and packing bong loads and then giving
people dabs and the club provided rigs
and torches and we brought our own rigs
and torches so it was kind of cool we'd
all go hang out I just dab out they
serve they sold like bottled beverages
like Mountain Dew and coke and whatnot
and they would order pizza sometimes if
there were enough people and sell the
pizza at a fair price and so there was
nothing wrong going on the cops came in
one night and walked through and I was
the first person like as you walk in the
door I'm the first person you see in
that dude and they looked at me and they
kind of grinned
like stupid hippie take your ABS they
weren't offended they weren't afraid no
they were they went and talked to the
owner for a quick second and then
laughed and that was it and that was
just their normal like walk through like
they do at a bar or anything else they
just walked they didn't check anybody's
ID they didn't harass anybody they
didn't
to anybody other than the owners and
they were fine there was nothing wrong
going on and I said all and so and
that's what I'm getting at is there were
never any fights the most dramatic [ __ ]
that happened in there was our friend
Wade's a comedian and he was Wade it's
like the most dramatic scene in that
place
we've got obnoxiously loud but it wasn't
like violently loud yeah it's like dude
we're high turn down your volume loud it
was like the worst thing that's ever
happened sorry Wade I'm just picking on
ya but like really nothing ever went
wrong in there there were actually
people as I walked in one night that
tried to ask me to sell them weed and I
told them to get the [ __ ] out because
they were gonna ruin a good time I told
him come on in I'll get you a hi a [ __ ]
but you can't stand out here and buy
weed let me get the [ __ ] out of here or
come on in because that will ruin our
yeah definitely nothing went wrong here
nothing's going wrong well at the same
time there's a seven bars within a
walking distance of this hookah bar that
there are fights at on a regular basis
there's drunk people driving home which
of course we were probably gonna be dead
than attempting to drive home but it
just seems weird that we can't hang out
and smoke a little cannabis in a private
hookah bar setting and it's the same
[ __ ] that we ran into are running into
in Denver this is why the secret cup the
hash event is damn moved yeah like we're
not even gonna say a word but it has
been moved to a secluded location it'll
be much smaller makes it better it makes
it worse it's now we have to limit the
vending we have to limit attendance and
that makes it less inviting to people
but it makes it more prestigious so it's
kind of cool too I think it's just
[ __ ] that uh we can't have a nice
little smoking spot here in Pueblo or
anywhere anywhere in Colorado where it's
legal there are places that I know they
do puff and I don't want to call them
out now since they're shutting down
places but yeah if they're doing that be
careful you guys keep them going strong
support those places and also tweet me
where they are and we'll Kevin and I
will get in the car and we'll go do a
little tour of these spots whenever we
have a little bit of time
hit me up it at I drug culture or at
Ross to Jeff for Tony on Twitter I'm
serious and we'll come check out your
little smoke spots I owe that
all of them Kevin will come with me down
we'll bring some killer chatter yeah the
fire shot to the fire yeah move on
moving on
sound echo we do I know it's cuz we got
the reggae in the background it's moving
on I'm all dubbed Out Boy
shout out once again to nicotine thanks
for giving me full permission to play
this CD it's cushioned coconut water
it's a little bit old but man it's still
relevant still gets going right music is
always relevant right well good music is
always relevant some of that stuff that
the the MTV tries to feed you is
irrelevant like immediately all right
here's something I thought was cool
somewhere where they do invite cannabis
in a statement Tuesday and this comes
from it just says the Associated Press
doesn't really have a a good author
listed so in a statement Tuesday
Symphony CEO Jerome Kern says they're
part of efforts to reach a broader
audience the state so I'm gonna read
that again in a statement Tuesday
Symphony CEO Jerome Kern says they're a
part of efforts okay that's where I
[ __ ] up they are part of efforts to
reach a broader audience the state's
only full-time professional orchestra
like others has struggled with doing
billing audiences and budget problems so
solution listeners are encouraged to
bring their own marijuana to smoke or
eat to the symphony smoking will be
allowed at the private venues where the
first 221 of 21 and up concerts will be
held organizers say they will follow the
rules at the final show and the publicly
owned Red Rocks Amphitheatre where
smoking is officially banned I got a
couple things to say there but the last
sentence where smoking is officially
banned at Red Rocks and we just have
snoop and Wiz Kalifa there dude you
could smoke the [ __ ] out at Red Rocks
they have stopped giving a [ __ ] I
remember a few years ago I walked in and
I had a bubbler tucked into my waistband
like it was a gun said nowhere else to
put it
and I figured I could distract him with
my hands and all my movement my wookie
type skills and so I was cool you let me
through but then the wind blew and it
highlighted like it rapped my shirt up
on my body real quick and
my bubbler and he goes what is that and
I go that's my bubbler and he goes here
what and I go my bubbler and he looked
at me and he felt embarrassed that he
missed it and he goes just get out of my
line and let me go through yeah he
didn't wanna like cuz he had already let
me through his boss would have saw him
pull that [ __ ] out after I already
passed security so who'd have been in
trouble but so in an attempt to get more
people to come to the symphony these
guys are inviting you to bring some
ganja to come spark up at the symphony
I like symphonies bro yeah are you a
symphony kind of guy dude
the one I went to was so awesome what'd
you go see Beethoven's fifth up in
Denver that sounds Prado Symphony
Orchestra okay it was freaking intense I
was like the only hippie looking kid in
there like there's all these like rich
people in tuxes and furs and [ __ ]
super blinged out jewelry like all these
old ladies and [ __ ] and [ __ ] dude it's
ridiculous I was it they're all stone
dish it's the only person not dressed up
yeah so they need to they need to make
more events like this why can yeah can
we go smoke at the symphony but not at
the bar has couches snacks and plays
reggae if I ask them to understand the
point but I do like that I can [ __ ]
blaze out as some symphonies yeah those
things are gonna sell the [ __ ] out right
they should just let us smoke at every
concert and not worry because that's
part of the musical experience we've
wanted people have been enhancing man I
remember when I used to go see fish one
night and I it was the date was 8:00 596
and fish opened up set to with Space
Odyssey 2001 into Halley's Comet ended
down with disease into its ice I'm
pretty sure that's the order during that
little section of music there at some
point Red Rocks lift it up and spun
around and did a bunch of circles and
changed colors and then it landed
perfectly back in place
and that would not have happened without
a little bit of concert enhancement yeah
so that's the kind of [ __ ] that's like
part of what you go for
that's part of yeah it's part of the
experience all right so let us smoke
your concerts that's all we're saying
let us smoke everywhere I'm gonna take a
sip real quick I got some truck mouths
happening those waters brought there you
go bro it's actually what it was
therefore I just wasn't paying attention
I like to set it right out of reach of
the guest so you get ready and you have
that like I can [ __ ] see the water
they're like don't buy the headphones
I don't like it does that me is that
mine or is that cuz it's just yeah that
was on purpose not really how about that
reggae airhorn right at the drink break
seriously thanks Nico for letting me
play your stuff please listen to one
podcast make it make sure it's this
episode I'm gonna skip this part we're
gonna move on to another news section
here we've got a couple more I want to
make sure I get them all in cuz I got a
lot of stuff going on you have a lot of
news there's a lot of news sometimes I
have a hard time selecting news stories
I can't find enough news and then
sometimes since I did new much news on
the last show with all the boys I had a
water news saved up so I put my pins I
bet they're down here I don't have any
pens in my reach all right May first was
the day that mandatory testing for
edibles begins in Colorado and the
story's coming from the cannabis it was
originally written by Erik Gorski from
the Denver Post sorry clear my throat
ready so for the first time makers of
marijuana infused cookies cupcakes and
candies were required to submit samples
to newly licensed independent labs for
testing starting Thursday which was May
first if an individual individually
packaged product exceeds the legal limit
of 100 milligrams of THC
marijuana's major psychoactive
ingredient it is supposed to be blocked
from reaching recreational store shelves
manufacturers can fix the problem or
destroy the badge or you can donate them
to the agriculture podcast that will
make sure that they are disposed of
properly
that is definitely an acceptable option
feel free to send all of your overly
medicated edibles right this way I will
I'll dispose of them yes yes yes very
well safely I'm a professional I know
how to dispose the proper way
oh don't refresh please so my uh this I
may be [ __ ] right now the we're at the
Internet's down here in my neighborhood
and the page just refreshed but we've
got good news that came back by the way
uh [ __ ] you Comcast please get my cable
and internet fixed because it's going to
be a long night without any internet
trying to do podcasts and post podcast
and all that good [ __ ] way off task here
ok so send me all of your edibles that
are overdosed
now the debut of mandatory potency
testing for edibles did not come without
problems only two labs were cleared to
start testing Thursday and even those
haven't yet been fully certified the
state postponed another test that was
supposed to begin and edible
manufactures are concerned about a lack
of standardization and results are all
over the map
state officials acknowledged testing
will not be perfect at the start so the
labs that are testing aren't tested yet
so how can any of the testing be valid
but anyway for us it goes back to public
safety said Louis Cod caused key sorry
dude I just [ __ ] up your name said
Louis Koski director of the marijuana
Enforcement Division part of the
Department of Revenue we'll talk about
that in a second I'm gonna hold my head
up in the air do remember to review that
it's a necessary step for us to ensure
that the product is what it says it is
on the label the marijuana Enforcement
Division I've talked about those guys
before that is basically what it sounds
like the marijuana Enforcement Division
they go to your to the dispensaries and
they have access to everything they also
go to like private homes and [ __ ] too of
people who have badges if they suspect
you're doing something wrong oh wow yeah
I didn't know I also show up with like
local cops and [ __ ] that's pretty
mean-looking if you're doing anything
illegal
we might want to tell a couple of our
friends that so just so you know yeah so
check out what Kevin is says if you're
in Colorado and if you have if you are a
badged medical marijuana in for an mme d
badged employee the mme d can bring the
local police to your house and come to
your house and investigate to see if you
are conducting any sort of illegal
activity it think about that you guys
that a lot of you guys that's yeah give
us a lot of you guys some [ __ ] to think
about because a lot of us are private
caregivers and a lot of those guys are
also gonna have a home grow yeah you
know so but were legit right they can
have their home grow just as long as
they're not if they're within there on
the side or beating their wife on the
side or having a bunch of guns or some
[ __ ] they're not getting a crime illegal
guns right all right that's weird I
guess that's one of the things you sign
up for yeah I wonder if a lot of people
paid attention to that that's a whole
nother show that we should hear your
rights get pretty effed in the a when
you apply for badges through them yeah
so they can come too apparently if your
a badge a badge employee means that you
have to apply for a medical marijuana
Enforcement Division employee badge
there are certain levels of badging that
are required for different parts of the
store or job you need those to do
anything dispensary related grow related
in a shop that is going to go
recreational or medical infused products
and yeah it's all of it so the Mme D or
the meed the marijuana and for it used
to be the medical marijuana Enforcement
Division not just the marijuana
Enforcement Division they can go to any
dispensary and they can also search the
employees vehicles that are in the
parking lots they can search the
employees pockets if they feel the need
they're there the weed Nazis they're the
ones in charge of all of it so it's not
just the wild wild west out here a few
years ago here under we're under strict
regulation between ten and eight years
ago it was the wild wild west around
2007 liked 2010 ish I think it was nuts
around here you there was no Enforcement
Division you would open up a dispensary
and home growers or caregivers would
bring their products to the shop and
offer you you want to buy this pound of
weed and you buy that pound of
put it on your shelf like it was no
thing all you needed was a red card we
didn't give a [ __ ] back in those days I
missed that time over-regulation is
making things weird so I'm gonna
continue the article a new the new
testing comes amid growing scrutiny of
the edible marijuana products with two
recent deaths linked to edibles hospital
emergency rooms reporting more patients
reacting badly to edibles and state
legislators and regulators nine I never
mentioned the two deaths on my show
because I don't want to support that
propaganda is honestly why I never
talked about it very much in depth I
think we mentioned the one kid jumping
one time I don't want to support that I
don't want to be attached to it I don't
want to touch it I don't know enough
about it I don't know what that kid was
on so I avoided it sorry if you felt
like I should've talked about it
enforcement division officials say even
testing labs have been licensed and four
are being certified an additional step
carried out with State Department of
Public Health and Environment to be
certified labs must meet standards that
include lab director qualifications
quality control security and sample
tracking as of Thursday however none had
completed the process state officials
said two labs receive provisional
certifications meaning they're in
material compliance but not through the
process there's a little fly buzzing
around me I'm trying to smack it I'm
hitting everything but the fly that's
[ __ ] funny where did I go okay state
officials I indefinitely postponed
mandatory mandatory testing that was to
begin Thursday for homogeneity basically
making sure THC is spread throughout a
product and not concentrated in any area
a spokeswoman said the division wants to
take one step at a time to ensure a
controlled rollout process for testing
so they're not just gonna slap everybody
with huge problems if they do come out
kind of wrong because I understand the
lab could be [ __ ] up too they
understand that we have to do this
slowly just like the cannabis industry
worked a lot better when it grew slowly
I believe and now we're in this big
giant cannabis bubble and it's gonna pop
somehow because there are a million fete
pin company yeah there are million
edible companies and so I like her idea
of a controlled rollout process like
that's what we do in the cannabis
industry that's how we do it you know
large scale right away because it cost a
lot of money and we're all grassroots
companies crap but you know what I mean
yeah now that grassroots use that name
they [ __ ] get a lot of promotion and
also that's something we talked about on
another episode the THC being spread
through a product and not concentrated
in any area like if your chocolate bar
melts and this is relative to another
topic I've got coming up if your
chocolate bar melts and it's tipped one
way and then it's reharden you may have
just restored all of the [ __ ]
cannabinoids to one area so I understand
what they're trying to do and that's
good because I've got a patient that if
I gave him 100 milligram edible that
would be four doses for him if it all
got moved to one end he'd be really
[ __ ] up one time like he'd be bad so
I'll continue Koski said earlier this
week he was confident Labs can handle
potency testing for the roughly forty
forty Colorado businesses making edible
products for recreational use so the
company has to make him/her test him her
the company has to front the testing not
the dispensaries which is kind of cool I
think if the dispensary were required to
do it the cost would land on the
patients a little more yeah since the
company is doing it they're gonna take
they can take the hit a little better
but among labs and edible companies
there was uncertainty there always is
that's how our industry thrives as an
uncertainty I think everybody is
probably in the same situation as me
hanging back waiting to pull the trigger
on adding instrumentation or personnel
said Joseph Evans laboratory director of
steep hill Halen which says it got the
green light to begin the mandatory
testing shout out to the guys at steep
hill Halen labs Earl Ripper at Graeme
Gatsby
that's Addison de Moura John Hunt much
love you guys that's those are some cool
guys I really and Joseph Evans also I
had to pull myself away from a
conversation with Joseph ER I would have
been there for like why would a camped
just to talk to that guy would had just
sat down on the table bring a lunch I
could talk to him all day one day I'll
get the opportunity you know when we
talked to Addison he sounds like he
knows everything about dabs he learned
it all from Joe yeah I feel oh not just
Joe by like Joe knows twenty times that
and our buddy that sits at the table and
teaches us about chemistry Joe would
school
yeah and no offense to either those guys
but Joe is [ __ ] brilliant Joe
entertains my mind I like it
so shut up big guy had to talk to that
dude - we go up there at the table
willing to talk all we have to do is
show up at the labs if you call steep
hill labs and tell them you need some
information they will they'll do some
consulting for you if I may charge you a
little bit but you can go up there and
get some consulting done instead it's
really cool yeah I paid my upfront
consulting fee for a minute so got that
account going so some edible companies
fear a backlog can the labs handle the
volume in a timely fashion said Joe
hotus spokesman for Dixie elixirs and
edibles of Denver Dixie elixirs hard to
say under dab the [ __ ] out by the way so
if it was a 24 or 48-hour turnaround for
voluntary testing becomes two-week
turnaround that significantly impacts
our production I [ __ ] up that sentence
but you got the point Hoda said because
of inconsistent results in Colorado's
lab testing industry Dixie has is moving
to lower the dosage in its hundred
milligram products to reduce the risk of
failing a test so instead of trying to
get the test right you're just gonna
[ __ ] lowball yourself and we'll make
sure see samples from each batch get
widely different results from different
labs meg Collins executive director of
the cannabis Business Alliance said the
consistency problem can be addressed
with data the state collects from
mandatory testing it's important for the
state to begin the program and not delay
it she said if there are wrinkles they
can be worked out go slow that's what I
recommend so Dan Eldridge and Glen den
and Glen Evette appear which infuses
food products with THC disagrees he
supports a delay in mandatory testing if
a company relies on a test result that
underestimates the true level of THC
companies could end up putting too much
he said very good point then we're right
back where we are over at Oh some people
this is a result of trying to rush
something to appease public opinion and
what it's actually doing is putting
harmful public policy in place he said
the state said is working to contract
with the reference lab a sort of
independent check on the process that
would be used to verify the results and
practices of labs conducting the tests
so they want to hire a lab to test the
labs that are testing the product
so we're gonna have to hire a lab to
test that lab too right
I would assume which makes sense but man
this is what happens when you freakin
over-regulate [ __ ] yeah cuz guess who's
paying for it the patient's customer
they definitely yeah
so there's another dollar on every
product that you buy one more dollar for
all these tests maybe maybe the dollar
25 that doesn't sound like a lot but if
you're an MMJ patient and you're already
struggling because your wife is rough in
Colorado where in the world you're gonna
be [ __ ] broke so dr. Michael wimp
director of medical chemistry core
facility at the University of Colorado
School of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical
Sciences I'm so glad that it's not my
[ __ ] title would you imagine having
to write that or introduce yourself that
hi I'm dr. Michael went director of the
medical chemistry core facility at the
University of Colorado School of
Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical sciences
that dude that should have come first
except it's extremely important he said
how can you release a product to people
and not know whether the label is
correct this is the only industry that
would get away with that also yeah is
doing that so senior enforcement
director of the marijuana Enforcement
Division acknowledged that a system
without a reference lab is not perfect
but mandatory testing and regimented
testing of the product is better than no
testing at all he said other testing of
recreational marijuana will be
introduced in coming months including
screening for contaminants that's the
part I look forward to so basically
they're trying to roll out this thing on
the first of the year everybody's got to
get compliant and everybody but the labs
and the system that they put in place so
that's how the Mme D works sometimes
hurry up and wait hurry up and wait what
I liked is they said that stuff's coming
up that all of the cannabis will be
tested in the future all of the hash
will be tested in the future it will be
tested for potency and will also be
tested for contaminants like
contaminants will be bugs mold and I'm
hoping that they implement the new stuff
that steep hill is using and they are
looking for pesticides the guys at steep
hill told me that they're able to find
pesticides so if you spray your plants
when their baby clones little tiny
clones and cups
you let them grow for two or three weeks
for weeks you flour them for nine weeks
you let them dry you trim them you
harvest them even if they're flush
properly and taken care of the kids it's
the professors the scientists the
chemists at steep hill labs can find
those pesticides that you sprayed in
your buds and your flowers they can
definitely find it in hash they said
it's way more prevalent in hash because
you're concentrating everything if we're
gonna be finding a lot of great and a
lot of terrible [ __ ] here in the very
near future looking to see how much of
music we have on the CD we might run out
of nicotine music oh [ __ ] we got like 40
songs on this disc we ain't got no
trouble
shout out nikka thanks for let me play
your CD bro alright so another story
connected to our edible report tens of
thousands in product thrown away after
pot shop health inspections this is by
Boris Sanchez from Fox 31 Denver
hopefully we don't get a pop up all
right
soy boo I think that's how you say it
the guy's name is toy boo a public bin
for health inspector at Denver a public
health inspector is changing the edible
marijuana business in Denver not only
does she go oops I said he huh not only
does she go I think I called that person
a guy earlier not only does she go into
local restaurants to make sure their
food is up to par she now also inspects
the edibles and recreational marijuana
dispensaries and the kitchens where they
are made we don't really look at it as
an infused product we look at it as food
said boo who along with her team of
health inspectors has been making
unannounced visits to metro area
marijuana businesses since January first
the focus is to look closely at edibles
manufacturing process from stem to snack
how they are cultivating the plants
asking them about different fertilizers
fertilizers pesticides and what they're
using set vu at most dispensaries our
goal is to look at whether or not
edibles are being stored properly her
team has had to establish new
regulations for how edible products
should be kept base off based off
federal rules that already apply to non
similar cannabis infused products yeah
have you ever gotten an edible at a
dispensary dude that you could tell it
is full-on been melted and like they
threw in the freezer to fix it like
yeah yeah so they're gonna try to stop
that because that's messing with your
health that could be dangerous I'm gonna
read right after this drink give me a
sip time here we go
sift so I could time out drink time out
lots of dads and talking man you need
some water all right according to
records obtained from the Department of
Health new rules have forced dispensary
owners oh I said that huh dispensary
owners dump out a lot of product
including hundreds of boxes of edibles
costing manufacturers and dispensaries
tens of thousands of dollars
man so these guys had to dump out tens
of thousands of dollars
the most prominent prominent example
hache infused oils boo says that not
being refrigerated when they should be
adding that to keep adding that to keep
products from growing bacteria we'd like
them to ensure that it's being held at
41 degrees Fahrenheit or below so while
you guys are making edibles and having
edibles why don't you do this for us to
keep it at 41 degrees Fahrenheit or
below when you're storing it and that'll
prevent any bacteria from growing
that'll do us all a favor and then you
won't get any trouble for making anybody
sick so one metro-area hash oil
manufacturer who did not want to be
identified is not too thrilled about the
new rules does it make sense said the
manufacturer who had to recall several
of her products and dispose of more than
$5,000 worth of edibles though she says
no one had ever become sick using her
products I personally never seen a
bottle of olive oil sitting in a
refrigerator so to me it doesn't make
any sense at all she said in response
toy joy says that most other oils sold
in grocery stores undergo a rigorous
inspection process by the FDA which even
the oil manufacturer admits would not
happen with their products when its
infused product there's no laboratories
that would touch anything of that sort
she said adding that while the recalls
are frustrating she believes though and
her team are doing the best they can
surprisingly with this industry they are
extremely compliant they want to ensure
that whatever product they are producing
is safe so they are kind of making sure
that there's quality control now it's
not the wild wild west like we talked
about a minute ago don't do that to me
we might have lost one story
think I had it was the next one that one
article disappeared so we're not gonna
get to read too much about that maybe I
can get back to it which one was it
so the Denver Post is receiving a lot of
questions about it's gonna reload we may
have internet service back here again
the Denver Post posted an article about
a common a Colorado Marijuana guide 64
answers to commonly asked questions yeah
some of them sometimes I think I've seen
did you read some of the answers some of
them are kind of hokey some of them are
but some of them are actually
educational got a few minutes here so
we'll read a couple of them before we
get toe toe then I just say before we
get to-- before we get to our gift
thanks portion before we read a couple
of political rants so here are some like
I said the Denver Post post it I'm
trying to find the author John Ingold
from The Denver Post this was posted
this was possible Oh updated January 3rd
so this is kind of old news and I'm just
now reading it so there are a lot of
crazy questions here I'm gonna skim
through them I'll read the opening
article on January 1st Colorado became
the first place anywhere in the world to
allow legal marijuana sales to anybody
over 21 for any purpose you have you
have questions about how it works here
are 64 answers to commonly asked
questions alright so the first question
which I've been talking about for a long
time did marijuana become legal in
Colorado on January 1st 2014 and we all
know that marijuana was actually legal
in Colorado prior to 2014 since the
voter approved amendment 64 went into
effect on December 10th 2012 it has been
legal for anyone 21 and over to use
marijuana or possess up to an ounce of
marijuana for any purpose even if it's
just as Rolling Stone magazine has put
it for getting high purposes marijuana
possession and used by people under 21
who aren't medical marijuana patients
remains against the law so the follow up
question what happened on January 1st
then New Year's Day was the first day
that marijuana could be sold to anyone
over 21 at specialty license stores
don't marijuana use possession and sale
remain illegal under federal law
nowhere else in the world has pot sales
this legal not even Amsterdam so that
was kind of their accurate there I give
him props the next question is where can
i buy weed more than two dozen shops
open January 1st for recreational sales
we here at the Denver Post have compiled
a list of stores that opened and if you
go to this article in the Denver Post
they have a they actually have a
marijuana section so go to that section
find this article and there's a link
there of dispensaries in Colorado that
are open for recreational use my buddy
here kevro he works at a place called
the spot in Pueblo West they don't pay
for any plugs or anything if you want to
talk to the kid that I know Kevin knows
a lot of [ __ ] about weed cuz I'd like to
toot my own horn and say he probably
learned a good portion of it from me a
lot of it and I just know a lot of the
links and where to find out information
through you too yeah so I trust that he
knows what he's talking about 90% of the
way because he learned it from me and
our crew and we try to teach each other
the best and he makes hella good hash so
he must be learning all right so if you
guys want to buy weed the next question
is how does it work the greatest answer
you basically walk into your store show
them your ID and make a purchase it's a
lot like a liquor store there's a lot of
normal questions are there limits on how
much I can buy people with the Colorado
ID can buy up to an ounce of marijuana
at a time people with an out-of-state ID
can buy up to a quarter ounce at a time
the next question is there enough pot to
go around yes I'm not even gonna read
their answer yes we got some weed don't
worry can I make multiple purchases on
the same day yes
the only cap how much you can buy it's
the legal possession limit the only cap
on how much you can buy is the legal
possession limit no one who's a non
medical marijuana patient can possess
more than one ounce at a time but that's
up to the customer to abide by there's
nothing in the state's rules for
recreational marijuana stores there
requires them to track the purchase so
the next obvious question is can I go
store to store buying weed yes you can
if you have more than an ounce of weed
on you you've broken the law at that
point so you can go get four good
quarters and then go home
smoked seven grams to go buy seven more
but if you're a rebel you can do that is
there a list of marijuana customers that
will be given no I already know the
answer but I'll read it to you know I'm
in mid 64 which is a constitutional
measure specifically forbids it
the measure states that the department
shall not require a consumer to provide
a retail marijuana store with personal
information other than government-issued
identification to concern to determine
the consumers age and a retail marijuana
store shall not be required to acquire
and record personal information about
consumers other than information
typically acquired in a financial
transaction conducted at a retail liquor
store so that means you will not be
tracked you wanna you will be on camera
though the next question is there
anything that will show that I bought
weed at one of the shops and it says yes
you'll be on camera there's a lot of
stuff about the camera yes you'll be on
camera can i smoke in the store no where
can I go to consume that's a little
fuzzy they you can't really smoke
anywhere in here can I in Colorado
unless you find like a private bar or
something I'm not gonna read the stuff
that they said here but there is a
Colorado's Clean Air Act so pot smoking
isn't allowed anywhere that cigarette
smoking is also banned so if you can't
smoke cigarettes can't smoke weed there
there have been exceptions made I'm not
gonna mention them can i puff at a park
somewhere absolutely not
ski slope Colorado's winter resorts are
not all stoked at the possibility of
stone skiers and what's more most of
actual ski slopes are on federal land
where marijuana use and possession
remains strictly for boating so don't
smoke at the ski slopes so that means
taking marijuana on a summer camping
trip is probably out to yes national
parks national forests national
monuments all off-limits well I didn't
even think of that what about apartments
landlords can say no yeah but there are
some places it'll be time we're gonna
smoke weed there they'll let you what
about my back patio front porch or
balcony different cities a lot of
different stuff is kind of the answer
there
so there's a lot of stuff going on I
don't want to read all those can I send
weed in the mail keV can I send weed in
the mail no no you can't [ __ ] send
weed in the [ __ ] mail I won't send
you any we don't send you any dabs I
want some Gini slabs send you some dick
pics that's all you get
don't send weed in the mail Colorado's
working hard to get you ladies
Colorado's working hard and all that
[ __ ] that leaves here is [ __ ] it up
every time it gets caught it's [ __ ]
it up so I'm not gonna I've ranted about
that if you want yeah don't do that is
it okay to drive with marijuana in my
car the answer is yes as long as you're
transporting it and not consuming if
driving stoned is absolutely against the
law ah Colorado this year made it easier
to win convictions against own drivers
the state set a standard of how much THC
the psychoactive chemical in marijuana
that drivers can have in their system
the driver tests above that the
prosecutor can tell the jury is okay to
assume the driver was stoned there's a
lot more questions
well my employer be okay with it I'm not
gonna read their part that's up to the
employer probably not can I legally
possess an ounce of marijuana how much
is that in practical terms it's a lot
Reacher's of Sookie
so in Alta marijuana 28 grams of a good
dank herb it'll fill up like one of
those sandwich baggies just about
perfectly like that cuz it's fluffy it's
not good but a sandwich bag full how
much will it cost is the next question
in the medical marijuana market ounces
cost from 150 to close to $300 but
nobody buys full ounces the more common
purchase amount is 1/8 think of it like
a 12-pack it's right around 25 to 45 for
medical marijuana we'll have to wait and
see what stores set the recreational
prices does that include taxes no right
now I see prices being advertised for
rec shops right about 200 to 250 an
ounce for good stuff what do you charge
of your shop for rec shops
that's about medical sorry that's
totally what I meant yeah med shops yeah
I don't even walk into a rec shop the
only reason I go to a shop is to get
some edibles all right I got a monkey
bar I ate a monkey bar dude I should
from Incredibles shout out Incredibles
[ __ ] monkey Mars you think so yeah as
well medicated 1upon says favorite is
the blueberry bliss oh yeah yeah I don't
do blueberry but it yeah it's as good as
the monkey bar he loves it yeah I think
they're really good to cookies-and-cream
thing is delicious oh my god so on your
wreck site at your shop what do you guys
sell an ounce for uh we're at 460 before
tax and how much is it on the medical
side 230 for non-members okay 180 for
members half price if you're a medical
but we're not really doing Elsa's right
now on medical because we're trying to
make sure every patient has so meds cool
like we're cool you know good recreation
good half though like getting sick and a
half but we're trying to make sure we
keep product on our shelves for
everybody and we're not like some of
these other dispensaries that don't have
anything so there are a lot of other
stuff questions on there one that I want
to go over that I just discovered seed
to sale tracking how does it work this
could be long in December the state
rolled out its 1.2 million
excuse me 1.2 million dollar marijuana
tracking system called MIT s for unn
creatively marijuana inventory tracking
solution it works a little like this
every plant that a commercial growers
start sticks in dirt gets a
radiofrequency tag an RF tag that moves
with the plant through its lifecycle
once the marijuana is harvested
everything is weighed then its weight
again after drying out and at other
points during processing until it's all
packaged up to leave the grow so
basically uh when if you work there in
your trimming you make three piles you
have buds you have trim and then you
have trash and you get a plant you cut
it down you do your harvest and all of
your stuff has to weigh what it weighed
when you originally cut it down you have
to have enough buds enough trim and
enough sticks to equal the weight of the
original plant or they think you just
stole some [ __ ] or it's missing and it
needs to be accounted for so it's it's
weighed several times then the packages
shipped to stores the stores can't weigh
more than a pound
and they get their own RFID tags at the
shop store owners are required to weigh
their inventory every day all of the
data is entered into the MIT s the mints
stores are also required to have some
type of point-of-sale tracking system to
charge sales in theory every purchase at
point-of-sale system should have a
corresponding drop in inventory in the
marijuana tracking system it's up to the
state's pot auditors to actually scour
the books and make sure it all matches
up I need to drink hold on let's make my
height which I need her to drink so bad
that's bad that's uh that's dry that's a
little too dry need some clear throat
all right clear eyes it's clear throat
all right so the tracking system does
not have limits though which is why
officials say is it just an it's just an
enforcement tool not a whole regime and
embarrassingly for the state holiday
shipping delays mean not all plants in
the commercial system were entered into
the mitts by January 1st that was kind
of funny January 1st they're like this
is all required this is all required
I was watching dispensary owners sit
there going well unless UPS comes today
that [ __ ] ain't happening it's kind of
funny so there's a lot of stuff I don't
want to read I want to open my own
marijuana store where do I start
I'm not even gonna get into that one
dude that's wrong all right I got a TD
on this article so I'm glad I got to
share that one a little bit with you I'm
gonna move on to the next topic here I
mentioned at the start of the show that
we defeated a Senate bill 177 in 178 I
tweeted a lot I didn't know I didn't do
as much as I could but a lot of people
sent emails a lot of people rallied we
had a lot of support that's really cool
proud of us for that we needed to knock
that down so now there's a new one we
are looking for volunteers to send a few
emails urging members of the Senate to
vote YES vote YES on Senate bill 218 218
with its passage Colorado can visite
begin the process of lifting up those
that have been so adversely affected by
the collateral punishment associated
with criminal criminal convictions of
marijuana I have a template and a
contact list but I'm happy to share with
you so what this will do this will
possibly start to
free marijuana prisoners fielder in jail
for weed crimes you know yeah
and take some convictions off of some
people's records who have already served
their time that's there you go that's
awesome yes or yeah if you were or if
you have a weed crime and that'll go
away now in Colorado if you do the right
take the right steps so I will post I
will get those email addresses by the
time this episode posts and I will post
those up and we can vote YES on SB 218
big shout out to my buddy Kevin
mammalogy who helps me find all these
Senate bills and keeps me up to date
with what's going on that's really cool
would be able to do that section without
him so I'm gonna get into the give
thanks section it's almost an hour into
the show you should time this out just
about right for an hour before we get
there bro ah you got anything you want
to add to the show just put you like
let's get some dads it's been a pretty
fun episode we've talked about some
really interesting things which I always
like those better at podcasting I feel
like to hear getting comfortable some of
the news so I don't always get a chance
to read it this is kind of my news
update yeah it's really nice I hope
someone's hanging out in the grow room
or driving in the car or stuck at work
or commuting and I hoped I'm educating
them and you actually dude if you get
the topics ahead of time they want to
text them to me or something I can start
researching some of it and maybe find
something else so there you go some
branches on the same topic yeah well
sometimes uh sometimes I find him out as
you're showing up yeah exactly that's
what I mean if they if you do think
about them early shoot me a text that's
one thing about my show I've realized is
I've got my episodes out quickly because
it becomes from irrelevant quite yeah
yeah we we're a pretty topical show so
all right before I take a dab on to
thank everybody for listening there's a
torch for you brother here's a torch
just throw across the room it's awesome
why it's the thing for the water oh
alright you can throw that I guess
you guys should take a guess is what
we're gonna give thanks to this time
while we take a DAB it's gonna be it's
gonna be a good one I don't even know
yeah thank you I've met him he's signed
a book of mine if that gives you any
hints it does give me some hints you
hints you were not there when it
happened no I didn't think I was I don't
think I have been any of your book
signings I hear you need a DAB - sure
signings like I like I have book
signings that I go to like I sign books
that sounds pretty dope see I know it
sounds like that but that is not the
case
one day I'll write a book one day so I
think we're dabbing some I think this is
the Grateful Dog mix that you made or
the sativa mix I'm not sure I put some
in the to-go container containers and I
is it the harder one or the softer one
you know it's a softer one okay Seto no
that's not okay it's a grateful dog and
Tora Bora Tahoe gee go Scout cookies I'm
gonna take a phat dab of it right now
you guys take a dab with me if you're in
a place where you're able to I noticed
the citrusy sativa plants tend to
shatter up a lot more than the
than the like like indica plants but
something wants to talk about on a show
it's a good topic we're gonna start the
grouse school and we'll have our buddy
Clint back in a couple episodes the guy
that asked all the good questions yeah
we need to get back here all right here
we go dad time take a dab with us it's
perfect the music ended right as we
decided to take dad's and quit talking
you know nicotine I really appreciate
you letting me play cushion coconut
water shout out nicotine
check out his hash company check out his
bags select the nikah teach out his
music he's awesome Jeff over there
coughing change of colors you knew what
this bro I was a good death it's tasty
yeah well it's purple licious
we gotta quit saying the word turns by
the way that's getting overused it was
that a lip smacking dab it's tasty nice
alright so we're at that point dude the
music was really making the show that
tasted like grateful dog that would ya
accurate I taste the dog in there so we
give thanks section every episode we try
to give thanks to somebody who's been
beneficial influential supportive to our
community somewhere we couldn't have
gotten to this point that we are without
them somebody I know I could not have
gotten to this point without them
oh man it's my left lung no I'm just
kidding the person we want to give
thanks to in this episode is none other
than mr. Jorge Cervantes boom big love
big thanks much respect too yeah for
sure Cervantes Jorge Cervantes is a
pseudonym for George Van Patten who was
born in 1954 in Ontario Oregon he's been
he lived in Spain for a little while he
lived in California for a little while
he's a horticulturist horticulturalist
so hard to say right after a fat dab and
a writer specializing in indoor/outdoor
and green house cannabis cultivation his
books articles photographs and
instructional DVDs have been sold
worldwide worldwide as guide books to
horticultural techniques to high-yield
closet basement backyard and gorilla
gardens
if you are learning how to grow weed you
need the grow Bible the indoor marijuana
horticulture grow Bible by Jorge
Cervantes that's the book if you're
trying to grow weed put that one by your
get one for by your toilet and get one
for in the grow room and just read them
both constantly when I was starting to
grow that's the book dude that's the one
that introduced me how to grow cannabis
properly how to when I had a bug problem
or his book identified my bugs when I
had a grow problem Jorge's book
identified my problems
Jorge's books didn't he's God I think
he's got I probably have seven of his
books downstairs that I can think of
yeah so I could go on and on about Jorge
Jorge wrote a monthly
question-and-answer column or his rx
from 2000 to 2010 in the High Times
Magazine he provides his solutions to
grower problems
he also pens a regular column and soft
secrets magazine I wrote a few things
about him it's published several books
oh he also published a three DVD set and
he also has a YouTube channel the
YouTube channel sometimes it's updated I
haven't seen a recent update but there's
plenty of stuff on there so I want to
give big huge thanks to Jorge Cervantes
I got to meet Jorge one time oh no I
caught him off guard there was a big
line of people and he was answering
questions he would answer one question
for you personally and everybody's
questions were like my clones are doing
this or my plants doing this or how do I
do this and I've read his book dude and
I've been growing for a little bit so I
walked up to him and I said hey Jorge
what kind of music do you like to listen
to when you're in the garden and you
know he was on autopilot he was signing
books and just spouting out add nitrogen
add nitrogen or whatever you know what I
mean and I said what kind of music do
you listen to and he closed my book and
he put his pen down I said well that's a
really good question and he had to think
about it for a minute and so I felt like
I kind of had all those other people had
a moment with Jorge but Jorge had a
moment with me shared that he was like
oh man you read the book you don't have
to ask me a weed question you want to
know about Jorge Cervantes so I said
what kind of music do you listen to in
your garden
and his answer was the Beatles Led
Zeppelin and Shakira and he said
Shekinah he didn't say Shakira he said
she get her so that's what Jorge listens
to big shout out to Jorge Cervantes if
you're a new grower if you're an
educated grower go back and read that
Jorge book it will teach you some [ __ ]
that you forgot and a lot of guys are
gonna say that's outdated [ __ ] that's
where you got to start you can't go all
advanced you can't be high-tech until
you learn how to be edgy Jorge thanks
bro
so that's pretty much the end of the
show I gotta do some plugs the grimy
Gatsby highly-educated if you want
highly-educated stuff check out aqua lab
technologies of course nature's green
remedies calm much love to our friends
from oil slick oil select tools to help
you concentrate check out oil slick pad
comm for more information about those
guys check me out at agriculture at
Rasta Jeff 420 check out my instagram @
hn Attucks that's where i put a lot of
cool pics
any plugs for you keV no no you already
did
I already did them all nice ladies and
gentlemen thanks for joining us it's a
perfect hour take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for me all right podcast Road
I want to thank you guys again for
listening to Episode seven eight and
nine of the girl from your heart podcast
I'll be back Monday with the brand-new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
Oh
she knows I'm dancing yeah all the pumps
are
Oh
puffing elbow like a Japanese doll lots
more freebies rolling with njz
see you try sweet on the cabinet I wanna
hit
with the marijuana spray wholly from
chocolata and the hydro [ __ ] swing
shipping [ __ ] your father