what's a podcast world a lot of people
seem to be appreciating that I'm putting
out these old episodes so to keep with
the trend
here's episode 10 11 and 12 of the girl
from your heart a podcast before we
start the episodes I need to make some
disclaimers all of the social media and
emails and contacts have changed all the
sponsorships have been finished and
completed there are no sponsors there
are no special offers and if you want to
follow us on social media you can follow
me at G fyh podcast on Twitter you can
find me on Facebook under the girl from
your heart a podcast and if you want to
email me you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at a
hotmail.com I would love to hear what
you have to say about these old episodes
alright no further ado ladies and
gentlemen I present to you episodes 10
11 and 12 of the iGrow culture podcast
no I said resist Irish marijuana is more
lovable now are we on the almighty up
I'll pick up a cell phone or essential
extracts I don't know the cast of avatar
[Music]
yeah happy Mother's Day podcast world
welcome to episode number 10 of the
agriculture podcast I'm your host Rasta
Jeff thanks for joining me for another
episode podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gage
green genetics well quite a labs since
city rare dankness mile high can
adventure IRA genetics and many more
trusted brands if you purchase two packs
of IRA genetics you receive a free five
pack of Bounty Killer while supplies
last
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our podcast listeners type
in coupon code re 2014 for 10% off any
order and you always get free shipping
in nature is green remedies calm the
show is also sponsored by a highly
educated titanium if you're consuming
high-grade extracts you deserve a high
grade titanium nail don't trust a nail
made in China by people who don't care
about your health trust a company who
has been part of the movement since the
beginning for more information or to
purchase highly educated titanium visit
Aqualab technology's calm big shout out
to our friends over at oil slick oil
slick tools to help you concentrate
check out well slick pad comm and also a
huge shout out to tree thugger calm this
episode is brought to you in part by
tree hugger comm it's live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
calm for concert and festival news and
reviews WWE sucker comm much respect big
shout out to make a tea listen to Nick
to T's soundcloud page right now look
for him at DJ nicotine on soundcloud in
this episode we got my good friends
Clinton Way joining us so let's get into
the show here we go ladies and gentlemen
I have officially pressed record we're
hanging out with two of my good friends
were hanging out with a tall Clint Clint
Stewart he's been here on the show
before hey guys he was the the cannabis
amateur ya the kanima is the non
cannabis not even an amateur yeah the
other guy on the other side of the table
is my good buddy Wade Ridley say what's
up bro word alright I don't know that
Wade's an amateur I would call him a
professional wait yeah Wade can smoke
he's not
she's not a level 10 black no I am that
both of these guys are local aspiring
comedians they're also my bros we
brought tall Clint back because I really
liked having him ask cannabis 101
questions it was kind of the crowd
demanded you back bro I appreciate it
guys thanks for calling me back
[Music]
so my buddy Wade we're talking about how
is level I'd probably put them in like a
blue belt okay I don't know that is in
the level of belts then cool I would
take myself at a 5 to a 6
what's it white out of a new brand black
white yellow orange blue purple Austin
Jiu Jitsu oh man didn't that one with
the dude I did have to actually we did
get stripes they put yellow stripes on
your white belt so that you think like
T's you like the pre-test ready to test
and now at the test time you could
actually pay the money to take the real
test to buy the real was realizing where
I went to karate class was kind of twos
the Ponzi scheme karate is what it was
you gotta bring in two friends before
you can get to the yellow belt but don't
worry we'll pay ya with the black belt
to be in right here's my my card
can't be the splits dude nobody cares
what's up I grow culture yeah so we got
two comedians in the place already we've
been taking dabs well Clint has not been
- I've got a Clint does not smoke and
I've tried to pass him a pipe always
tried to pass him a pipe uh everybody
everybody sure you have the guy that was
here earlier hanging out this tried to
pass him a pipe in the when he said I
don't smoke he looked at him like why
are you here to his defense he is
slightly [ __ ] that Clint what the
dude that was here
[Music]
you guys are both comedians you perform
on stage garage you got you do bits that
are prepared and also a little bit of
improv yep we were talking earlier about
the use of cannabis wait I'm gonna bust
your balls you do smoke weed be there
you perform and you're pretty cool about
people knowing that I hope right so wait
does participate in cannabis use I see
your weed use is more medicinal than
recreational it is 100% with this yeah
yeah I know you it keeps my [ __ ]
straight man yeah you're a high-strung
dude yes and you're high right now and
you're still high-strung as [ __ ] I
walked about eight miles a day yeah the
students fired up and so we're talking
about the differences between Clint not
smoking because he doesn't drink or
smoke at all
well no there's no disrespect to you big
[ __ ] but mentioning it so do you think
that smoking before you perform your
show helps you out
or does it hinder your show so do you
remember when you first looked yeah do
it it takes tolerance I guess to build
up to where you could to get past all of
the in the beginning like the paranoia
okay to get past the the this is
actually stoned and feels good so in the
beginning when I was get too high I
would sit there and lose track and lose
thought or maybe I wasn't in enough
situation and focus but I would learn
with marijuana how to do it essentially
okay
and now now I have a great little
medicinal level to where I sit at in
that I don't have to go overboard I
don't have to do anything like brash and
overmedicate because that's what you
want to tend to do at the beginning your
anxiety is like jacked yeah through the
roof and you're like I need I used to
suck a bowl no [ __ ] right before my set
I would I would leave the comic who
would perform for me for five minutes
and I would shock on a bowl so goddamn
fast go inside get up on stage I would
crowd work for the first minute of my
set to get over the the like the COFF
and the high the initial initial and
then I would go into my material and if
I remembered it all the way through I
would kill but then if I didn't yeah
then it sucked so how long did it take
to find your threshold for more because
I'm a musician yeah I know that same
threshold okay
I can't keep time if I get too high and
I know that and you get panicky of
course start doing dumb [ __ ] on stage to
try to cover how long did it take you to
find your little threshold zone to where
you knew how high you could be I'm gonna
say a good eight months like were you
smoking the first time you performed
comedy were you high yes okay yeah
extremely okay so you didn't have to
learn how to do comedy and be high at
separate times you just you were already
high doing it your first time I have a
little bit of a lucky background of
being sort of a public speaker I was in
management for a little while and I also
did acting so the acting thing like I
just started smoking weed two years ago
like on the rig we took away - the way
was kind of an amateur until he went to
the secret a lot of but he was a huge
amateur I would he would come over and
hang out I would give him dabs a1 one
day it would [ __ ] him up for the
afternoon he told me that he took a nap
for eight hours and stuff so we took him
to the secret cup and he sat next to me
at the secret cup where we were
down and I looked at him and I told him
pretty much you're in the big leagues
buddy and I started giving him man dabs
yes and from then on I quit giving him
the little amateur dad's I decided he
got his purple about that day yeah and
so two years from till now Doody really
stepped up the game well it's uh I love
and I feel like I gave it an unfair shot
for only 34 years of my life so I'm
giving it all fair shots if I can and it
improves everything that I've done so
far because I know a lot of people say
that it it makes you go all over the
place
but for someone like me that is wired
I'm already all over all over the place
so what marijuana does for me is focus
more than anything I tell me more about
that first 34 years that you said you
were biased on marijuana I [ __ ] hated
all of you all of us potheads yes why I
would specifically blame it on my on my
brother going back to high school my
brother was scouted by like major
Division one universities for football
when he was in seventh grade started
smoking weed around ninth grade and he
gradually declined to where he quit
playing football by his junior senior
year and I blamed marijuana a lot for
this because I watched his life and I
watched my life and then I watched a lot
of my friends around me that smoked weed
and everything like that and I was I was
very judgmental of all of them and I
found out it wasn't just it wasn't weed
they were just losers and I was a
douchebag
now that's a personality trait and
that's all it was it really was so and
that was just us as young kids and that
was me in my 20s and then and then I
went to Vegas and in Las Vegas I was a
four years to get away from my ex-fiance
which I decided to keep around in my
life for several years afterwards which
led to me doing about three
antipsychotics a couple antidepressants
and a couple of sleeping medications a
day to calm down these major hives that
would break out all over my body
all prescribed all prescribed
good question absolutely yes they this
was all given to me to initially get rid
of these hives that were breaking out
all over my body at random times in
situation that were just from anxiety
correctly okay but but no one knew
dermatologist and no regular doctors
finally someone said go see a shrink I
was like great I'm gonna go see a shrink
and they're like you [ __ ] up I was
like finally I knew it so they put me on
all this [ __ ] and I would find myself at
a stoplight and I'm driving my truck
right and I've got this smile on my face
but inside my head I'm like why I
there's no I'm not I'm not happy for any
reason sad pretty reason either there's
just there's no that I I'm not I'm not
this I'm not this and then like Oh turn
on the shower and just forget that it
was on and not in the weed way but just
it was on and then I found myself
needing like klonopin what was one the
specific one that I knew that worked
like they could immediately get rid of
the hives both gone later what is what
is the klonopin is an anti anti anxiety
okay and antipsychotic I believe is what
they used before so like it immediately
can calm down some anxiety man and it
worked for me but it didn't work for me
you know so I moved from Vegas went to
New Orleans when I got to New Orleans I
no longer had the insurance but no
longer the will to actually like take
these pills
I hate being slaves to things in my life
so I quit and a year or so went by and I
knew that I still needed something so I
finally decided being in New Orleans
marijuana is prevalent down there
although it is very expensive because it
can be rare no you can't really grow it
down there if they don't [ __ ] your [ __ ]
up dude bet I said I'm gonna try weed
and I'm gonna I'm gonna give it
a control point you know I'm gonna try
this many times and if I hate it I'm
gonna get past it that's called the old
college try well and I just wanted to be
educated about it you know I was like I
don't want to be stupid I'm 30 at the
time I'm 34 and I'm going to be smart
about this
it took three two-and-a-half tries and I
was like I don't need I don't need any
more to know that this is good for me
and and I haven't stopped good for you
how good for me in the know anxiety like
the anxiety that I have now is justified
like I'm about ready to go on stage in
front of like maybe a hundred people
with words that like even the tested
stuff I don't know if it's gonna ever
eat I'm in a different town in a
different town that doesn't know
references that maybe I've grown up with
well not even not even that just the
audience and that's why like the Pueblo
seems so different is because we we only
have a couple of spots so it's always
it's kind of always the same audience
yeah so you want to write new stuff yeah
but but when you're moving out and the
stuff that does work down here you're
thinking oh good I get to go use it up
there they've never heard the stuff yeah
100% and I and I completely but it's
never a hundred percent by taking a
knife to a gunfight up their body you
could be I mean you just even on a good
room you know well here's how it's
justified anxiety yeah well in here's
how it helps me now throughout the day
and outside of company I wake up at 5:00
a.m. every morning I go to bed around
11:00 to midnight I don't have children
I'm single I sleep for like five hours
asleep and it's because like the
corporate world teaches you how to be
this machine it's perfect if you were in
the military also correct so the two of
them have got you kind of robot mode but
but they don't teach you how to not be a
machine so they don't teach you how to
shut it off because they wants you
thinking about work all the time and I
would be and I still do now so like I
consumed myself with all these not only
my comedy but all my [ __ ] up thoughts
like everybody else has and they keep me
awake and I wake up at 5:00 a.m. and if
I don't smoke weed let like I
immediately wake up and walk five miles
and that's no lie and I'm heavily
sedated so would you be an advocate that
cannabis does help PTSD because yeah so
there are states that are not allowing
that as a reason a valid reason for
medical marijuana so anybody that's
listening you just heard wait
mostly describe to PTSD and depression
depression 100% is what his cannabis
uses is helping do you I know you're new
and you're you hang out with me and a
couple other guys that are kind of we
know what's going on do you have a
strain that works best for you or a
strain that doesn't work for you and I
know you you're not as well-versed the
best the last best thing that I've tried
out of from from the samples that I've
tried the veganic lemon Jeffrey no lie
broke some [ __ ] off nice like that some
[ __ ] it really is that's mostly sativa
it's almost a pure sativa
dab wise you're not beating your
grateful dog or your Girl Scout cookies
hands down okay and weed why's that GSC
show me something show me something
that's going up against that [ __ ] that
Girl Scout cookies is a hell of a strain
I wish I would have read that I didn't
know that [ __ ] dude so I wanted to talk
a little bit more I'm gonna whisper
something to you because I want to know
if I have permission to talk about
something yeah yeah yeah okay I want to
talk about some lab testing right quick
as you said that lemon Jeffrey ideas
samples to steep hill Halen labs in
Denver and the lemon Jeffrey I was doing
Paganica Lee it was bred by me grown by
me I we hit twenty four point three four
percent THC a total cannabinoid content
on that was twenty six point oh let me
make sure I'm not lying
it's twenty five point three sorry it's
really small prayer phone 25.3%
cannabinoids on the lemon Jeffrey
searching my phone I'm looking for the
Grateful dog we've got several tests in
here here's the Grateful dog when the
four point eight I think it was
something similar to that
yeah really close twenty-three point
three two thca and then for a total of
twenty four point three yeah that's the
Grateful dog so the strains were
breathing that you guys are getting a
smoke around here you're getting spoiled
there dude alright so for us amateurs
and let's go over a couple of basics
here I like you know yeah cuz um I'm
gonna ask when you say THC I know I know
a lot of us know what THC is but just to
start out with some guys may be from
wherever that don't know
THC being the thing that gets you high
correct yes
there are several active cannabinoids
I'm actually trying to get to the steep
hill web site while I'm doing this so
that we can maybe they have a chart of
cannabinoids on there to give me a
little bit of a guide okay it'd be
really cool to see yeah and then and
then cannabinoids was my other question
was so the cannabinoids are the part
that they work in conjunction with
terpenoids flavonoids and a few other
molecules but it's mostly cannabinoids
that we're looking for and these are
molecules yes essentially essentially
and so they call them compounds as what
I think they actually call them okay I'm
not a scientist but I buy stay more in
the grow room but what I play one on TV
that's right I stated a holiday in these
guys to do the test hotel for 24 they
test for CBG a CBG THC THCA
THC v THC by itself
dat HC th cv cbn a CBN CBD a CBD CBC
c.b.c oh there's a negative sign I don't
know what that negative sign means but
for the most part that we were looking
for honestly was the THC the THC a those
are all cannabinoid the the CBD yeah
those are the basic cannabinoids the THC
is the one that gives you the head high
that makes you kind of it's like more
psychedelic the CBD is the one that's
more body oriented more analgesic more
relaxing and the CBD is what's helping
wait the the opposite is the one that's
all correct
yeah THC oh really because I think it
lifts your brain up out of the
depression it's uplifting it just bends
you up out of it the CBD however is the
one that they're giving to kids for
seizures and epilepsy problems and
autism and tumors and such and that is
getting rid or stopping cancer and a lot
of people as CBD CBD rich medicine so
I'm gonna brag here I've got a cut that
was given to me from my friend Joey at
natural mystic cannabis caregivers he
got it from our good friends at DNA
genetics
I drew this tora bora came in the THC
not impressive four point nine seven but
the CBD content on this bad dog was
eight point five six percent it's the
phone it's a two to one CBD to THC ratio
which means this is perfect for those
sick folks that don't want to get high
one person need some medicine okay this
is the one we've got a patient a friend
of mine good brother who's going through
some turmoil right now with his health
but he came over and we've talked about
it he didn't feel good he was on a cane
he felt like [ __ ] mentally physically
and we had some dabs of that tora bora
and stood up and forgot his cane and got
all the way up the stairs and turned
around and shouted we bring me my cane
visualize myself
yeah when so so it sounds like 25 is
huge as a THC content that's a that's a
good good reference point to ask for uh
high anything over the guy told me
anything over thirteen percent is
considered high whoa but the growers and
breeders and dispensary guys we look for
anything eighteen to twenty
one is satisfactory some of the highest
s-- there's reports of 29s and 30s but
that's questionable 26 and 27 are
remarkable my good buddy Spencer I'm
gonna give Spencer a shout-out what's up
Spence what is up Spencer bro he grew
[Music]
goes black people here black folks black
people here he's so cool the Capleton
hit twenty nine or twenty point five
nine the one that's impressive I'm
looking for it
Spence grew rianne's Rhino from another
breeder and that hit twenty five point
nine percent THC the total was twenty
seven point two with three point one
percent terpenoids in it and i didn't
even pay him to test her the terpenoids
they were just so blown away that they
wanted to do no [ __ ] so if somebody had
won would we direct them to that website
or something if they wanted to get their
stuff tested since they're being pretty
cool about testing your stuff you know
I'm affiliated with labs and things or
with dispensaries and things and they
just kind of changed the rules like two
days ago so we're now you have to be a
licensed facility to get anything
through the testing facilities the [ __ ]
yeah [ __ ] you we'll talk about that on
the over-regulation is costing
legalization so I want to give Spencer
shout out one more time excuse me sorry
to interrupt no no dude this is we'd
show interrupts all day Girl Scout
cookies grown by spent at the garden of
Weeden twenty six point eight nine
percent THC [ __ ] you goddamn stoners
total cannabinoid content dude twenty
nine point two get the [ __ ] on nine
point two from Spence in the garden of
Weeden follow that dude at that garden
of Weeden I think there might be in the
but it pretty sure it's at garden of
Weeden on Instagram yeah that's
impressive I'm gonna go to High Times
real quick and look at their High Times
strongest strains because I don't want
to misquote myself and say what I think
the og ghost train haze came in at if I
could smell strong just to be hopefully
yes tea sorry
I'm saying I said what I was typing I do
the garden of Weeden yeah dude and
honestly no dis dispense he's not the
first person I've heard you use that oh
no no I'm just saying the the
originality of marijuana names for
things never ceases to amaze me just the
names that you guys choose to take and
then like form into the weed culture is
amazing there's probably something for
like garbage truck that is just like oh
we can name everything something cooler
than it is yeah in 2013 this highest
strain listed that I find on this little
thing on High Times it's twenty four
point seven nine I'm gonna do another
Google search because I am confident
there needs to be something higher
because I don't want to go chit in our
pants that we did higher than those
alright I'm not seeing garden of Weeden
on Instagram so it might be oh this will
be a video there will be sound I need to
mute and it's a w ee DN sorry I'm
should've I just thought that that might
matter I just realized that w ad en no
he just in weed and mmhmm yeah actually
meant the listeners but Bruce Banner
number three twenty eight point three
five percent was their winner for one of
these years Bruce Banner some good yes
and I are keeping up with those guys
yeah yeah we're keeping up that's pretty
impressive
yeah garden of weed and yeah I got it
now good good
Clint's following him cool cool so uh
only get back to wade for one second I
asked for permission can I mention your
dad dude you know 100 percent Wade's dad
is an elderly gentleman I've honestly
never met him but I've been heavily
involved with 78 78 years old I've been
kind of helping these guys figure out
and guide his a short stint with medical
marijuana use mm-hmm I heard that the
old guy was having problems and I kind
of jokingly said give him some pot
cookies or something and Wade was like
no I want to but my mom disagrees with
it
mm-hmm so after some persuasion I took
about three months three months of
persuasion on mom
research and then tell them what
actually I think will actually sent them
over the convincing edge to let him do
it and I'm referring to the Facebook oh
yeah but I did or remember he was the
brave I asked well I made them so
[Music]
basically attacking my dad are not
attacking but the plan of attack for my
dad was having as much information as I
could and having as much information I
could it is hard for someone who a is
not familiar I guess you could say
what's the type of contacts to get such
information I mean you could look it all
up and everything like that but when it
comes down to it there's a lot of people
that are gonna be coming in from out of
the state that will look at the products
and be like I love it but I really don't
know what I'm getting so I didn't want
that to happen
anyone did not have that information and
I wasn't sure was going down Jeff took
it upon himself he got a hold of cheaper
choose himself on Facebook he's like yo
this is an area this is what hurts where
can I get this or what is the best
method of use Shiva choose is like you
can't get that where you're at but this
is what you can get and they they
answered in less than an hour 100% and
they're a huge company and for them to
just got at me within an hour like that
was pretty cool so when I took all of
this information to my dad I was like
listen dad you my dad my dad has a 12
pound hernia that sits in his front it
looks like a volleyball just always
sticking out okay I asked a hunch over
he worked at the steel mill for 450
years and he can hardly walk he can
hardly sit and he has to take
painkillers and it [ __ ] him not bad man
it messes him up emotionally you know it
messes your body up and I was like dad
listen these pills are given to you by
by a doctor that really doesn't give a
[ __ ] about you and and he's given them
to you because
the the people that are telling him to
give them to you make money off of your
Medicaid I'm asking you to take the TV
to because I love you and I don't want
your pain to to affect your daily life
anymore
and he took a man he took him for about
two and a half to three months he was
doing edibles strong and then I think my
mom got involved yeah he was showing
signs of having too much fun at Walmart
is one of the conversation wonder 100%
100% you know what though if somebody's
having fun at Walmart there's something
wrong well well no I agree right no my
mom was like me my mom wasn't used to
the adjustment period of getting high so
my dad is is learning how to get high
and he's 78 years old and these
receptors have never been you huh
so he's taken an edible and he's high
and here's like I don't think I'm high
could you pass me some water you know
and you're like you're [ __ ] high well
at least it's water and not more yeah
right because as we discussed on the
last pot this is this is don't take two
it did happen this is what did happen so
he was like he's gonna feel like the
pills make me feel I was like whole
[ __ ] let's go you know I was like you
could just bite off as much as that [ __ ]
if you want dad it's not gonna kill you
yeah you may freak out a little I was a
that's I said yeah I was like be careful
you know it's like you if you like it go
for it if you don't then take a nap bro
cuz that's probably what you want to do
anyway
you're old we went from getting him the
pure CBD well I was Wade kind of tasked
me for being in charge I knew that was
my job you know yeah in this circle
that's my job your old man sick you're
thinking about we'd come to me I'll talk
to you about it as a caregiver yeah
you're a good guy and so I went to I
obtained the proper CBD dosage I thought
he would want and the old guys like I
want to get [ __ ] up a little bit I'm
old I missing that head spin from the
pigs exactly we've got a little bit of
THC and he's like bring it he kept up
he's like more THC and then till finally
mama cut him off apparently in it's
because she doesn't know she was the
only one not in the party basically yeah
because my dad would walk you know and
he'd just kind of stand there and he's
just kind of chilling and he's just not
really you know he's not being a
crab-ass so my mom thinks something's
wrong just quit [ __ ] that box of
macaroni and cheese like it's heaven
because man you know not only did it
help because he was a well he didn't my
father has to take a nap every day has
to it's got to be about a three-hour two
four four hour and a half every day so
he can get through the whole day when he
was on the edibles didn't have to take a
nap you know active his mood was better
uh he was acting like he was like a
human not to say that he suffered
without we did the time you guys spent
while you were high together improve oh
excuse me I'm burping improve your
relationship at all
wait a minute I'm sorry TMZ if that's
too much I could tell you this much 100%
I have about zero conversation serious
conversations with my father especially
about a his health I've never really
given it is cannabis topic is mostly all
I've heard about your father utilities
yeah I agree
yeah I don't it's not it's not a subject
that I approach he is the let's just say
there's a reason why comics are comics
he's got a lot to do with okay so when
he's high did he quit you said he wasn't
a crab-ass no he was you could tell the
do you could tell how pills affect the
attitude yeah right so when you take
oxycontin all day long and your brain is
just tired of it those receptors in your
brain when you wake up the next morning
they're burnt but but your body wants it
you hurt another one well not only do
you hurt but your addiction hurts too so
your receptors are like I need this but
then I need more of it
but you're draining the melatonin in
your body the entire time and this is
like and at that time that affects your
your entire attitude man and you can see
it you can see it in old people they're
[ __ ] mean all the time because
they're up on oxycotin so it's trying to
find a happy medium between a couple of
pills and half a tube at you forum or
something to where mama thinks oh here's
here's what was going down he would go
to Walmart and when he would take the
pills you know he's zipping around but
he doesn't know he's hurt when he's on
the pills when he'd take the weed he's
on the weed but he's aware of his pain
you know what I'm saying yeah so when
he's aware of his pain he's acting in a
different way and my mother did not does
not know how to handle that the
transition for her for someone that is a
nonsmoker to see someone of 40 years her
husband that is now trying to be
introduced into this culture that she
had to be conned into oh yeah they grew
up in the time or marriage itself she
admits that freely she's like listen I
don't like it because reefer madness the
exact quote yeah that's programmed into
her head dude and she hates it because
her best friend's a hippie and she's
like [ __ ] yeah give him that [ __ ] shout
out hippie friend right hey hey alright
so I said I was gonna find a cannabinoid
chart found this little cool pie chart
if you've got an Apple computer it looks
like that [ __ ] thing that spins
around every time you use iTunes that's
a pie chart kids they graduate from East
High School you don't know
but we know so CBD takes over more than
half of the pizza pie here and the
symptoms that CBD can benefit I can't
even print out some of them so
antipsychotic anti epileptic
neuroprotective anti-spasmodics anti-ice
semuc anti-cancer anti a medic
antibacterial anti-diabetic anti anti
sporadic analgesic Bone stimulant anti
inflammatory t-cell increase oh that's
huge immunosuppressive adeno sign up
take and there are other words that I
honestly I'm not even gonna say good job
we only CBD CBD v specifically points to
bone stimulant Delta 9 THC a anti
proliferative antispasmodic there's one
that unfortunately the text is the same
color as the piece of the pie chart so
we'll never know what which mark which
article or molecule that is I think if I
highlighted with my mice yeah maybe I
know it's not that type of page okay
nice try though now I gotta [ __ ]
figure out how to zoom out right here
it's got the - alright CBG I've never
known what CBG was antimicrobial bone
stimulant analgesic and
anti-inflammatory so I'm thinking
antimicrobial if you've got some mold
infection in your lungs
start smoking some CBG heavy medicine
the anti-inflammatory is if you turn
that if the if you believe in the
analgesic like they said like you could
run on out but you could rub like if you
believe in the rubs I guess do you
believe in the ropes that's not what I'm
aiming for I'm a pothead and a dabber
got a fear I believe that if you believe
they work they do okay I'm not sure I'm
not I don't know I don't get anything
from it because I smoke too much
[Music]
CBG is a bone stimulant antibacterial
anti-poll if it is okay
and then there's a line coming off of
Delta 9 THC V and C B G that I think is
anti epileptic that is both of them o
Bone stimulant for the Delta 9 THC V
anorectic what does that that's what you
can't get an erection those are just a
few from one little pie chart of from
the different cannabinoids of what they
benefit and how they can yeah and this
came from trends in pharmaceutical
Pharma it's really tall small print
pharmacological sciences there's more
apparent that I can't even read but
that's where this little chart comes
from we tweet that out on the girl
culture maybe a link to that I've got a
better one in my phone that I'll tweet
but I didn't want to dig for that one in
my phone it looks really shitty to be on
the phone well it encourages you
[ __ ] to get on the phone it's mainly
what happens I'm not good I'm trying to
get more people to your Twitter nice
come Twitter my Twitter page at
agriculture thanks for following me
thanks for listening
dude that was that was really awesome
from late sorry to pry too much good to
say oh no I don't know if I have
anything good to say I was gonna say I
go up without that anxiety and I know
that if I did have that I wouldn't be
doing it so I'm glad that that's working
for you yeah dude
are you nice and calm before you perform
umm I get really nervous up until I hit
the stage okay and then once I'm there
it's just yeah what I'm already here
you're already up in front of people it
doesn't matter and I have a background
in acting as well I'm not good acting a
little bit of theatre keep your clothes
on okay no no I can't seem to do that no
but I have like just short films and
then a little bit of stage time on
theater stuff and you know being a
frontman for a metal band so I never had
a problem getting up in front of people
the hardest part is getting started like
almost anything in life yeah seeing that
first joke in front of somebody has got
to be a friend do it last night man that
he was pacing I think he listens to this
show yes he does
usually he went for his very first time
last night and watching him do it he did
not want to smoke weed before and he
didn't drink before what's good
immediately after he finished
give me that [ __ ] J he crushed
all right no he did great he did
absolutely great but it is something
where I if I was having those symptoms
that would be something that I'm glad
that this helps you you know it's not
something that I feel like I need but I
wonder how how it would affect me I'm
not gonna find out because it's not
something I need to do I've already been
addicted to far too many things Prozac
wellbutrin alcohol I was [ __ ] drunk
wellbutrin is one I'm not I know a
little bit what it's like Prozac it's an
antidepressant okay um but I but like
you were saying earlier I don't like
anything controlling me right you know I
don't like anything changing me I want
to be a Clint Stewart and if I'm a
[ __ ] [ __ ] that's how it is
yes you know I need to be able to change
me not a pill changing me caress I mean
so alcohol cigarettes to to
antidepressants you know and all at the
same time unfortunately I've given all
those up except for the nicotine out of
a vaporizer that thing's the size of a
small baseball bat it's John bueno put
it best it's a it's a little robot dick
so we're a second podcast of the night
I'm on another podcast with my friend
Wade that's sitting over there it's
called seven one nine the block so
listen tonight if you would like to
please do shameless plug but through the
course of two podcasts Wade has killed a
pen and completely turned to paper blue
and white and it's beautiful thank you
are going at it over there that's is the
concentration thing man like it really
tearing it up it helps that paper is
gonna be all your whole hand is gonna be
blue on the bottom side right there by
the diner
this man nice all right I want to put
the show back on track we got time for a
couple of questions dude we bring Clint
on to do a little bit of cannabis 101
yeah quickly scramble through your phone
and find a question all right so class
is in session shoot me a question bro
we'll try to answer it for the noobs
well I'm glad we went over THC levels
cuz that was one of the questions I had
you know that's something that that I
don't think a lot of people know and but
with weight I don't know if I asked it
last time but with THC levels for a
newcomer you know what what levels would
they be looking at you know is that
something that even they is that
something they do it dispensaries okay
Clint's never even walked into a
dispensary yeah do they have THC levels
on the some of the shops will have the
THC level printed the higher class
places will but it's expensive to get
the test done okay some of them
unfortunately will put a higher level to
mislead you decide a side question do
you believe that there will be a future
regulation of marijuana good question
they're already trying to outlaw in
Amsterdam you can't have cannabis over
15 or 17 percent on the shelves in the
coffee shop so they're doing it like we
work I don't think it'll come to that
here in the states they are trying to
ban dabs in California from what I just
wrote everything true that's true which
uh-oh all that does we know that's you
know what happens when you [ __ ]
outlaw [ __ ] I don't even need to go and
draw abyssion prohibition sort of
speeches so when you go into the shops a
lot of times they do have the THC
content listed on the strain
unfortunately they'll grow one strain
for a year and they get one batch tested
and they claim that it's that THC
percent the whole time correct there's
nobody in the future we will be required
to test everything that's on every shelf
that goes out of every door and every
dispense it's pretty dude that's pretty
much how it should be a little bit so
sure now yeah I mean like everything but
cigarettes here right yeah yeah right I
mean and we don't want to be classified
as cigarettes honestly and if you I say
we very loosely cuz I know I'm not a man
you're part of the community well I am
supporting it you are you're here but I
don't want anything to people to think
oh it's like cigarettes because they
don't have to like they don't have this
regulation and I would rather we had the
regulation on it I don't like the way
that they said
treat it like alcohol and the
regulations because that made it feel
skeezy to me but you did work it did
work unfortunate well you know what and
I was a proponent of saying you know if
you're gonna treat it like anything
treated like alcohol but then after
after like 16 months of smoke and it's a
the complete wrong mentality to take
towards it right and I'm gonna write
myself a note cuz I want to talk more
about this but you guys kind of put me
off on something I wanted to kind of
sidebar on yeah so if you go into the
dispensary anything is gonna be if it's
well grown you're gonna hit fifteen
seventeen percent THC hopefully like the
dispensaries if you're lucky you're
gonna find a twenty two and that's
that's not super far apart honestly I've
seen both I've smoked both and it's very
my new and it's also the lab that tested
it some labs you can kind of if you
buddy up and build a relationship your
numbers seem to go higher and there's
some labs I know will not do that
because they have high integrity [ __ ]
yeah yes so thank goodness if you're a
noob like two or three good hits off of
a bowl like if you're a smoke if it's
your first time one or two good hits off
of a bowl of twenty percent THC weed
will get you stoned
you'll get red-eyed and cottonmouth two
or three good hits and you'll be like
sucked to the couch forever yeah so just
start with one yes anything just start
with one yeah don't be the people that
buy an entire [ __ ] TKO bar and an
eighth and then go smoke a bowl and then
eat the [ __ ] TKO bar and do something
dumb and make us I'm gonna try one of
those the tiki bars or I haven't tried
to many of the the brand-name edibles I
guess you can say just because I would
rather spend my money on the flower yeah
she was the TKO one I know you talked
about this on a previous podcast maybe
two or three I wasn't it was not tested
I have tested those and I would have
[ __ ] testify that that [ __ ] works
I will also testify that it works on
Jeff how about the before I even mention
the name brand I bought us a coop we
went wait and I win cyan thinny Jeselnik
a Comedy Works and I bought us each a
cookie at a dispensary at a recreational
shop
how did you feel about that hundred
milligram cookie I think it kicked in
after the show and I fell asleep we're
sleeping a little twitchy yeah that was
the growing kitchen that cookie was on
point it tasted good oh yeah oh there
was no no I edibles a lot by the over
over marijuana taste so if you're gonna
be a pro at it and you're gonna like
sell marijuana and packages and
everything like that you should be able
to get that big weedy taste in your
edibles it's like weed correct yeah so
great product great great little product
not overly we taste
uh-huh and it end powers high throughout
the show but then when when we read Abdo
I was [ __ ] done so you know I get so
wrecked right edibles and then take dabs
there's something about just you feel
like you're floating already on an
edible and then you take a dab in its
sky right yeah I've no I don't I don't I
haven't really done that yet I haven't
really put I know it it's hilarious when
you do though really bit when you took
that TKO bar you took you went up to
Denver to handle some business you take
a TKO bar coming back down we recorded a
podcast that night and your eyes were
open like man you were like [ __ ]
preaching some fire and it was hilarious
it might have been lit up you were a few
real quick before um so what you're
saying is that it you don't feel like
the the the cookie kicked in during the
show or you said you were high
throughout the show what what do you
mean like you were high throughout the
show on the cookie and then once you hit
the dab it was like I'm done is that
what you're saying or were you guys
smoking I guess my real question is is
how long did it take for the cookie to
kick in or do you not over an hour
easily for me it's like about an hour
and a half and see and that's something
I'm trying to get out as don't if it's
not gonna work immediately don't just
take more and expect it to work
agreed that's that's that's one of my
main focuses people to not overdo
something
here for me it's like is so this is
where like when dabs come in for me it's
just like whenever I take a dab the very
like a big damp right when Jeff puts a
man dab up in front of me the only thing
I think in my head which I know is
impossible and I would just like to
preface this by saying that but the only
way it goes on my head is like is this I
just don't want to be the first person
to die that's all let's I don't want to
be that dude that's like well wait
Ridley died from marijuana and now
everyone is [ __ ] because I couldn't
handle my [ __ ] you won't be the
match.com killer anymore yeah I'll be
the weed killer even better the one who
killed everybody's high earlier earlier
a nice-sized dab off of a new rig hey
shout out to Mike Ron Mike I don't know
if I said that but it took a dab off my
new rig and I heard the ice cream dude I
was a fat kid trying to chase that
[ __ ] down I knew he just sped up and
looked at you and laughed at me until he
got to the corner yeah my friend Joey
went to a dispensary today my friend
Joey is a medical marijuana patient they
didn't have any medical marijuana in the
dispensary however they had plenty of
recreational marijuana which is about 25
percent more in regular price just off
the shelf plus another 25 percent tax
yeah right that's some [ __ ] if I
haven't had time to research you that I
got this text message as we were sitting
down to record our first podcast today
and I haven't had a time any time to
look at that okay if you guys anybody
listening has experienced this if you're
a medical patient and your medical
marijuana center doesn't have cannabis
for you as a medical patient but they do
have reck weed let's talk about it tell
me how you feel
tweet me at I grow culture I will speak
your voice on the air I won't say your
name if you don't want you can send me a
private message let's get it on I want
to [ __ ] talk about that that's [ __ ]
up we didn't legalize cannabis to
abandon the people that
well your honor footing here's what
they'll say is it's free market you know
what I'm saying is it's free market it
is but it's [ __ ] up it is
disrespectful
hey if if you keep punching me an eye
and I don't say dude quit [ __ ]
punching me and I you'll keep doing it
all day yeah
so I somebody's got to say quit [ __ ]
punching the patient's in the eye
because they're the ones that got this
going they're the ones that need this
where somebody's got to be responsible
and I can do what I could do I have a
big mouth and I've got a podcast feed
and people listen and we can try to
figure out what we can do to prevent it
or something it sucks I think the
patients are the ones that got us going
dude but definitely well know that
that's a more than accurate statement I
would say like it medical marijuana was
so when I lived in New Orleans
medical marijuana was active here when I
moved back it's really it's recreational
and legal for everyone it's not like it
was recreational first and then
marijuana second yep a lot of people had
to put in a lot of work to get it where
it is and we're kind of [ __ ] those
people now and it sucks I didn't even
think about that
yep that sucks yeah it's happening to
people yeah you know what you guys
should do
Sunday's Mother's Day mom some weed I
don't know I saw a post today it's
graduation time in Boulder and I saw a
post that said the dispensaries are
busier today than they were during 4/20
because all the moms and pops need to
get some weed for going into that
[ __ ] store okay you're getting me an
eighth of the stickiest of the ickiest
and you're driving home don't pinch my
sack don't you [ __ ] touch that thing
all right I'll give you one more
question if you got a good one on the
phone screen there
um I know like like electricity bills
for four growers like I know that not
everybody is an outdoor grower we talked
to some guys that last time we talked to
a guy that was an outdoor grower I'm
wondering you know per plant you know
how many lights are you using or is it
one light for foreplay
you know I don't what's common I'm not
trying to get into you got business
example there's a huge it's kind of a
personal preference how many lights per
plant
so most most larger grows will be a
thousand watt light usually if you got a
bedroom I've seen guys doing two in a
bedroom some guys got four in a bedroom
that's usually like your average
residential grow no more than four
lights or so in a house if you're doing
an industrial thing then you need what's
called phase three electrical you're an
industrial guy you know what I'm talking
about it's I do we don't a little more
power availability uh it's just going
from like a hundred and twenty volts to
two forty two forty two warning yeah
because and it's instead of just being a
single phase line power going in it's
it's like three phases I it's a lot of
jargon yeah yeah but it's able to
harness a lot more power without being a
fire hazard
also that is that's the most
intelligence since I've ever heard you
know I was like man he is fluent in
speech when it comes to some power you
know what's it cuz I went to school for
for electrical I was gonna do solar
powered stuff I thought uh yeah well
back when it was not ridiculously
expensive before Vestas came in like
this is a while ago before all the solar
power stuff was going on I thought this
is the field I want to get into so I
went to school for like electronics and
stuff so I actually have like a minor
like understanding of what's going on
with that stuff I'm not saying I know a
whole lot but but as soon as
unfortunately like the the prices of
like solar panels and like wind turbines
and stuff like that just skyrocketed
windmills and stuff it's it's far too
expensive to get in and and have a
profit or save any money within the next
10 years so I'm sure it sucks but that's
that's something that you know I wish
that there was a cheaper alternative to
those things that would be like I carry
around a book solar energy for dummies
oh no [ __ ] oh yeah it's in my backpack
like it's it's always on me because III
think that's an amazing industry oh yeah
I wish that it was more prevalent
because [ __ ] you Black Hills yes
we had a dispensary downtown no we were
the only dispensary downtown for a while
and they shut us down but we were
running quite a few lights in there
there were easily 20 grow lights in
there and that I'm gonna get back to
what your question was there's easily
there were easily 20 grow lights in
there plus a more veg light area and
then another downstairs area and then
plus the dispensary business area we had
so much solar on the building on the
roof that we were our bill was negative
we're getting money back from the
company but you got to be a dispensary
to have that type of funding you know it
was that building was actually a health
food store before our dispensary took it
over so they had a lot to they started
it and we finished funding it but if
you're running a residential grow what I
have seen from like a caregiver girl
you're gonna average about $100 per
thousand watt light per month on your
electric bill because you need the light
is gonna run you so much you need a
couple of fans you need a blower you're
gonna have a couple more accessories
that go with that that I'll need to plug
in a timer for this and that you're
gonna be running some about a hundred
dollars per light through a veg cycle
hundred dollars a month per month per
light yeah well but from one light if
you do it right you're gonna get a pound
of weed if you do it correctly there's
one pound of weed and depending where
you are I don't even want to talk it's
me about three thousand thirty two and
you're actually you're you're talking
[ __ ] about just about the right numbers
nice yeah anywhere from 25 to 35
depending on who you are what you grew
what you've got that's about what a
pound is gonna get you so that hundred
dollars of electricity if you do it
right hopefully you spent about a
hundred dollars in nutrients like
another hundred on supplies maybe one
hundred on dirt I just maybe two hundred
under I'm just guessing off the top of
my head now yeah but you're hopefully
you can are able to make that an
investment hopefully you're able to give
a portion to your patients that your
caregiver for and take a portion for
yourself to make some hash out of and
then maybe move enough of it to your
patients when they run out of their
initial gift they got to pay for the
rest and that covers the light bill yeah
hopefully you can work it out that way
once you go protein grow pound a half
two pounds per light but you just got to
get good and have the right genetics it
takes a while that takes a minute the
right nutrients
that's why we're talking on the genetics
guy yeah yeah no heart of gold harvests
heavy lemon Jeffrey harvest like a champ
if you're looking for heavy harvesting
heavy weight crops yeah we're almost in
an hour I'm gonna kind of in the
questions and we're gonna do a couple
more little quick things I remembered
dude thanks for asking those good
questions we're gonna bring Clint back
to all the listeners because we didn't
get enough questions and he's got a
whole list of questions in the phone
yeah and if you guys got questions
please I grow culture on Twitter see
he's good at advertising and everything
Wow so I'm just gonna read something
that this is I've got a forum I'm also I
read genetics Colorado we've got I read
genetics Colorado calm if you go I read
genetics Colorado calm slash forum I
wrote this ten months and two weeks ago
is what I believe it said I got a scroll
up ten months and two days ago and my
point is that it's still relevant here's
a little bit of advice that I decided to
rant a while back that says I'm asked
tons of questions about grande ganja my
first piece of advice is to buy yourself
a good cannabis grow guide I recommend
something from ed Rosenthal Jorge
Cervantes or Greg Greene the good grow
grow guide will answer most of your
questions before they arise and you will
if you take the time to read the book
before you start growing you can't just
buy the book and set it by the [ __ ]
you got to open it up and read it that's
I didn't type that but that's how I feel
yeah you gotta open it and read that
thing from cover to cover before you
even get your seeds all right now on to
the reading one of my other biggest
pieces of advice I can ever share would
be to think twice before you do anything
new in your garden
if you have a bright idea to try
something new that you heard from a
friend or read online take the time to
think it through before you attempt it
anyone can post on the internet and
claim to have heavy or have stellar
results some of those results will not
only will only work in specific
situations and will often lead to
additional problems down the line in
your garden
I'm not discouraging you from
experimenting in your garden I strongly
encourage experimentation and expanding
your skills I'm encouraging responsible
experimentation you won't learn anything
new unless you try new things don't be
afraid to kill a plant or two but don't
get reckless and kill an entire crop
trying an idea you heard at the hydro
shop the next time you get an idea in
your garden you should think about a few
things what is your goal what's the
point of what your attempt
seriously and clearly think about what
you're trying to make happen
cannabis grows stop making it more
difficult than it needs to be that's
like something I always tell my friends
that are grown weed may have problems
stop making it more difficult than it
grows in Afghanistan on the side of a
cliff he asked mountain in the wind and
the rain and the Sun and it's getting
beat to [ __ ] animals piss in it let it
grow dude it's gonna be you should be
cool it's a weed
it is good weed if you do it right so
now on to my reading where did you get
this idea is the idea from a reputable
source or is it a troll online who's
never grown a plant but thinks he knows
everything keep in mind that most of the
things you do won't show results for two
to five days you can spray or feed some
ridiculous [ __ ] today and think
everything is cool and then in a few
days boom everything is brown and pissed
off scissoring and pruning are not
fixable if you chop off something
important be mindful of what you're
making happen every action has an equal
and opposite reaction plants seem to
remind this remind us of this when we
try to get silly in the garden if you
decide to try something new
don't try it out on your whole crop test
an idea on a plant you have grown a few
times and you know exactly what to
expect under your normal conditions I
just got all nasally in my headphones if
you like what you see you can do your
new trick to the entire crop next time
if you do things correctly you'll be
running another crop in a few weeks and
you can try new stuff again don't try
everything new all at once you can make
five changes and something works how
will you know what made the buds grow
like that try to make changes slowly
right if I if I tune all five things how
do I know which one made that bud get
really huge yeah exactly so once you've
thought about your idea twice and
considered the long-term effects go
smoke a fat joint and reconsider your
idea
read a cannabis grow guide from a
reputable author and see what they say
about your idea if you post your idea
online expect varied replies and please
don't take anyone too seriously
after you've thought about the methods
and results of your idea twice read a
Grove read a grow guide smoke the joint
and reconsider it every detail take very
good notes of what you do and follow
your heart to reach your goals take good
notes good notes because that's how we
know what we did what worked what didn't
work take good notes mmm so my point
here this is still I wrote this months
ago and this is still valid just think
about what you're doing because you're
gonna go in there you're gonna be like I
want to try this
rhasta Jeff said to do this online maybe
I'm growing a heavy indica and your
plants this ateva and you're gonna try
that and it's just gonna put the kibosh
right on your whole crop and now you and
your patients are gonna be out of weed
but I want you to get in there to try
some [ __ ] so do that to one branch do it
to one small plant don't don't get
reckless but yeah that's when we're
talking about learning new stuff that
was my favorite piece of advice that I
could come up with a long time ago
wanted to share that that was good man
thanks dude
I like to write a little bit I do have a
creative side to me I did mention I get
some books this is gonna be a like an
ultimate segue here I'm gonna go from
this to some books I mentioned some
books from Jorge Cervantes or head
Rosenthal I'm holding in my hand now I'm
reaching I'm lying I'm reaching for
marijuana horticulture the indoor
outdoor medical growers Bible from Jorge
Cervantes it's been updated since I got
this but I'll never let this one go he
signed the inside for me this book
honestly has gotten you can tell by
looking I think this book has been
through hell and has gotten me this is
probably good 50% of my grow education
right next the intro book right here if
you're gonna grow some weed so we did
Jorge Cervantes as our give thanks
section last episode this time we're
gonna do the author of this book this is
the marijuana growers handbook it's the
official course book for Oaksterdam
University
between this book and the marijuana
horticultural Bible there dude you can't
go wrong all of the answers are in here
if you've got a new problem that's not
in this book we're [ __ ] those are the
two books I recommend everybody grab you
want to put a picture of those upon your
eyes definitely plan on doing that I'm
just gonna steal the pictures off of
websites and just use those high quality
shots instead of taking a photo but
that's gonna lead me into a section
every episode we do here it's called
give thanks where we like to give thanks
to somebody who has contributed heavily
to the cannabis movement of course I'm
talking about mr. ed Rosenthal the
author of the marijuana growers handbook
ed Rosenthal was born in the Bronx New
York in 1944 this dude's an old cat he's
got to see he got to see the revolution
of cannabis he was there when having a
joint
was a serious crime and now he's here
where he comes to Colorado and comes to
all the parties and takes dabs wahid I'm
thinking dabs he smokes joints with us
come he gets down now
so he's a California whole
horticulturalist I can say that word
when I'm not reading it that's weird for
the cultural list yeah I still [ __ ] it
up anyway he's one of those guys an
author publisher and a cannabis grower
known for his advocacy in the
legalization of marijuana use he served
as a columnist for High Times magazine
during the 80s and 90s he was arrested
in 2002 for cultivate cultivation of
cannabis by federal authorities who do
not recognize authority of states to
regulate the use of medical marijuana he
was convicted in federal court but the
conviction was overturned on appeal yay
Rosenthal was subsequently convicted
again but was not be sentenced since his
original sentence had been completed
Rosenthal briefly attended Youngstown
State University in Youngstown Ohio
yeah yeah Rosenthal has been active in
promoting and developing policies in
civil regulation for medical marijuana
with the passage of California's
pioneering proposition 215 in 1996 which
authorizes medicinal use of marijuana he
worked with the state and local
governments to implement the delivery of
pharmaceutical grade cannabis to
patients with the doctor's
recommendation to use marijuana he's
also the author of numerous books about
the cultivation of marijuana he wrote
like I said one of the most essential
books that I've got in my book
collection will do another guide to this
series I'm gonna make a note to do the
next guy writing his name down this is
who's gonna be next in our gift thanks
portion but I got another author that
you got to read who will be next
ed wrote some important books he's also
comes to Colorado he goes all over the
country all over the world and does
seminars and Expos and teaches people
about growing weed and the benefits of
cannabis so we got to give big thanks to
mr. ed Rosenthal much respect much love
keep doing it bro thanks a lot you've
taught me a lot you continue to teach
people a lot he's at Oaksterdam all the
time I think he's still involved with
them so you can learn a lot from that
dude read his books read his books go
buy his book yeah read a book wait
they're gonna be like I'm gonna sing the
whole read a book song if you guys know
the reader books I don't know there is
we're gonna have to google that no it's
not it's just funny it's funny wants
it's funny once all right guys we're
right about an hour now I think it's a
good time to wrap it up you guys want to
do some plugs where do we find mr. at
tall Clint on the social media I that's
that's my twitter handle there and tall
Clint on Twitter you can find me there
I'm on Twitter a bit wild cousins is our
comedy crew we will be in Manitou wait
and I will both be in Manitou May 17th
it's gonna be a great show at the Red
Room I'm excited about that one great
room it's I'm just trying to be a
comedian
you know I it's fun it's the it's the
most fun thing I ever did if you're
having fun you're doing it right yeah
and I love it
yeah if I can make some money at it
that'd be better but as it is right now
just put money into it so um but yeah
find me on their Instagram it's all the
same it's all the same how about you mr.
Wade Ridley how do we find you and I'll
advertise the show after after yeah it's
no problem at weight in the toilet on
Twitter and the blocks plug low comedy
scene on Facebook sweet Wade and I share
a podcast he's uh mostly the host I'm
kind of the co-host engineer guy i chime
in once in a while
it's called seven one nine the blocks
we've got Instagram and a Twitter at
seven one nine the blocks check those
out please give us a listen of course
you can find me send a lot of questions
harass me I like the social media
interaction it makes me feel special
makes me tingle inside you can find me
at agriculture at rasta Jeff 420 of
course check out I read genetics
Colorado calm look at the forum if you
have questions there put them there and
I'll read those on the show that's where
I'm gonna go to for fodder when I need
more questions thanks for joining me
dude take your fat dab and give your mom
a hug for me all right now that the
show's over do me a little favor
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store find
I grow culture podcast give us a five
star review and then type in a little
comment about how you feel
[Music]
juwes if star saw myself in Oh M
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah oh yeah Susan
Tassone we got it right
smoking marijuana and we just don't hear
we got it right there sweetie guns are
your here we got it right here we got it
right
yeah sup listeners welcome to episode
number 11 of the agriculture podcast
I'm your host Rasta Jeff thanks for
joining me for another episode this
podcast is brought to you by nature's
green remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gage green genetics
plata labs Sin City rare dankness mile
high can adventure
I read genetics and many more trusted
brands if you purchase two packs of
ivory genetics you will receive a free
five pack of Bounty Killer while
supplies last
nature's green remedies is running a
special just for the podcast listeners
type in coupon code outdoor for thirteen
percent off any order and you always get
free priority shipping and nature's
green remedies dot-com big shout-out to
her friends at oil slick oil slick tools
to help you concentrate make sure you
check out oil slick pad comm for more
info and also Big Love to tree hugger
comm this episode is brought to you in
part by tree hugger comm live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
comm for concert and festival news and
reviews WWE thugger calm but respect to
nicotine
check out DJ nicotine on soundcloud
we're playing his music in the
background of the show right now hope
you guys like that also check out some
essential extracts big shout out alright
so coming up in this episode we got a
little girl lesson from my buddy Jesse
and we're also hanging out with my hash
buddy Kevin how are you doing today bro
doing pretty good man you doing good
doing good no you got this recording
figured out yeah it's been a it's been a
little difficult this evening but
technology does that sometimes I guess
I'm not sure it's the technology's fault
it might be the tabs the dabs and the
phase-two rig and the torch combination
I'm gonna blame it on technology because
everyone has a lot of problems with
technology all the time so it's common
but the good things are not so rare
we're notable dabbers so I don't really
want to admit like so much retardedness
for Debbie right now I might be I like
to call myself a professional how was
your exam bro
it's fit it's been eventful so events
you'd like to share with us no not at
the moment
okay so well I won't spill any believes
got some really cool [ __ ] coming up in
there the last couple days have been
exciting and I'm I'm excited to to have
it happen all right so we got we'll
announce that stuff when the time hard
work hard work pays off hard work and
dedication just get it done get it done
pretty eventful week myself I get to
hang out with this guy he does comedy
his name's Doug Benson oh he was he was
in Denver twice he was there Sunday and
he was also there Monday and no it was
Sunday and Tuesday so where did he go
Monday he went to Omaha Nebraska Wow
yeah so he he went and came back well
they booked the show for Sunday night he
does he I don't want to loop he does a
tradition of Mother's Day at comedy
works every mother is Sunday every year
and so he does that sunday a 20
that's exciting well it kind of sucks
it's Mother's Day we should be at home
with our moms and I got a good burn see
Doug Benson it's worth it I go up there
and I see I took my good buddy wait on
Mother's Day we went up there and we saw
Doug Benson and actually he came after
the show and smoked out with waiting
myself and a couple other people that
happened to be diehards of that exciting
dude that guy's a really cool normal
down-to-earth guy nice so then he said
that the reason he had to go do he did
Monday or he did Sunday sorry he did
Monday in another stay at Tuesday's cuz
he booked the show and then Comedy Works
saw how well it sold and asked him to do
something else so then Tuesday night was
actually the taping of Doug loves movies
which is probably my favorite podcast
that's a toss-up there are a couple that
could qualify but yeah so I got to go
see the taping of one of my favorite
podcast and then once again uh a lot of
people really uh they didn't think he
was gonna come out they were really I
can't think of the word they didn't
believe they were not believers that he
was gonna show up and come out and smoke
with us they were skeptics and he came
out and he puffed a big fat joint it was
just him and I dude and hanging out
behind Comedy Works
that's no I gave him an IRA genetics
t-shirt so if anybody sees Doug Pinson
wearing that I read genetics t-shirt
please take a picture take a picture tag
tag send it to me I will move up I'll
send you a sticker
than for yourself if you the first
person to send me a picture of Doug
Benson in my shirt
don't go photoshopping that [ __ ] please
no we can tell we have experience keV
worked in a print shop for many years so
he'll be able to spot your photoshopping
this if that happens boom boom yeah
that's enough ranting and bragging I
hang out with Doug Benson that was
pretty damn awesome so we both had a
pretty pretty nice week pretty positive
week donuts awesome yep yeah
bringing the IRA vibes I read something
weird in the news today Minnesota passes
concentrate only medical marijuana bill
that I tell you about this concentrate
only yeah Wow I'll read the article and
then we'll talk about it for a second
here okay though qualifying Minnesota
medical marijuana patients will only
have the option of vaporizing and eating
concentrated forms of marijuana illness
they'll have access less than two months
ago Medical Marijuana seemed dead at
least as far as legislative session was
concerned but during a press conference
this afternoon Scott Dibble and Carly
melon announced that Senate and House
have come together on a medical
marijuana compromise Dibble said the
compromise bill is based on the more
restrictive house model there will be
eight so-called alternative care centers
around the state qualifying conditions
for a medical cannabis prescription
include cancer terminal illness glaucoma
hiv/aids and Crohn's disease PTSD isn't
included in the qualifying condition
Dibble indicated he isn't happy about
that but said it's a compromise it's not
a perfect process patients won't be able
to smoke or vaporize loose-leaf
marijuana but will have access to whole
plant extracts as Dibble put it rap Dan
Shoen characterized the bill as the
strictest and most regulated in the
country as far as medical marijuana goes
Governor Mark Dayton announced he'll
sign the bill into law even before this
afternoon's press conference even began
he announced that he would before the
conference began there's a lot of I
should have stopped on a lot of things
here
loose leaf cannabis made me chuckle we
call that flowers that's weed that's
cannabis buds
yeah that's notable cannabis that's what
it is marijuana they're gonna be
alternative care centers around the
state and I think what you
gonna be able to do is medicate their I
don't think they're because they're not
gonna give me any flowers it doesn't
sound like does it concentrate so I
think they'll probably sell concentrates
but does that mean because isn't dabbing
vaporizing kinda is so that's how you
smoke oils is you vaporize them and
another stupid thing PTSD isn't included
as a qualifying yeah that's that's
freaking [ __ ] yeah because the first
of all there's evidence I guess it you
can't prove if it's helping your PTSD
really you can't maybe you can if you're
a psychologist I but I have paid I have
patients that come into my shop that are
former military veterans and stuff and
they man does it help them in their
quality of life yeah and their families
quality of life because of what the PTSD
does and the other option is what they
do if they don't have cannabis as they
drink alcohol yeah I've actually had one
patient that I cured with cannabis from
an alcohol addiction for many many years
and he hasn't he keeps coming back and
hasn't used alcohol since he came in the
first time the first time he came in he
didn't know anything about marijuana B
so yeah definitely so something that
really is weird here there whoever who
pushed this bill who set this up to get
past this way this is a failure in my
opinion he says it's a compromise it's
not a perfect process dude you just
signed up for [ __ ] that kind of
cock-blocked any of the stuff that would
have been useful I'm not saying that
edibles and capsules and concentrates
are not the way to go but the main the
way we discover the effectiveness of
cannabis the best way to consume the
natural way the real way is to just
smoke raw all right that's what's been
done for thousands of years yeah and and
we need that to make anything else yeah
we need that quality flour and that
research and that that's everything
still being done on on the plant because
we need that
to its full potential to be able to make
the concentrated medicine right so I
wonder how I wondered who's gonna be
making the concentrates for these guys
mmm
the strictest regulations in the medical
marijuana game that's yeah we'll see um
we'll see what comes out of there yeah
what if you guys are in states that are
proposing medical marijuana regulations
don't settle for stuff like that you can
you can language your bills your
proposed bills can be language din the
way that worked for you yeah be smart
about it and make sure that you are able
to consume raw loose-leaf material and
flour definitely that's available make
sure you enable yourself to grow make
sure that each person is allowed to grow
cannabis when you're if you're the
persons that are involved in writing
these bills and proposing this if that's
your responsibility make sure you're
able to grow
make sure there's access and please stop
the CBD only treatment yes please I've
ranted about that for food if you're one
of the people that's helped I keep
telling all kinds of people that come in
from other states that they're talking
about the CBD only stuff that's going on
wherever they're from or whatever I'd
let them know that that's not not the
way to go we need this whole plant it's
not one specific chemical that does this
thing it's the combination of of what's
in the plan and sometimes CBD is the way
to go for some folks but men I believe
higher CBD not just see yeah yeah it's
the entourage
it needs the mix of everything else to
work correctly Sanjay Gupta I think is
who were coined the phrase the entourage
effect I'm not sure if that was him but
that's all the cannabinoids working
together yes so yeah I'm gonna move on
cuz we could go about that one all day
if this is kind of an old piece of news
here oh it's actually from today state
approved marijuana testing labs in
Colorado can't accept private pot
samples yep luckily I am part of a
facility where I'm able to get my stuff
tested so it helps me search for
phenotypes
it helps me decide what I need for each
patient unfortunately the average
citizen cannot go and get his stuff
tested I'll read it to you
Colorado medical and retail marijuana
testing labs license by the marijuana
Enforcement Division can no longer
accept and test private samples dropped
off by patients and caregivers legally
they're only allowed to test marijuana
from state licensed marijuana facilities
for new listeners the marijuana
Enforcement Division is the group we
talk about all the time they are in
charge of they're exactly what they
sound like the Enforcement Division
they're able to show up at your
dispensary and inspect everything they
are attached to the IRS they are
seriously involved with all of the
medical marijuana the recreational
marijuana business they are heavily
regulating all of it so officials say
the move keeps the state out of the
federal government's crosshairs by
maintaining a tight lock on marijuana
inventory but it also punishes home
growing patients who want to know what
they are putting in their bodies and
prevents objective third-party tests
from being conducted on products
currently for sale so what they're
saying is I'm a caregiver and Kevin's my
patient I've got another patient that
would really like some super high CBD
medicine and I have one strain that I
work with it's really super high I've
got another one coming up and just
finding the keeper if Kevin if I weren't
growing with the dispensary or involved
with dispensaries and had those shops
growing my products growing my seed
packs I wouldn't be able to get these
things tested ah
if Kevin were his own caregiver he
wouldn't be able to take his medicine to
the to these places and have it tested
to find the high CBD strain that he
needs or the high THC strain that he
needs and that's who it should be all
about is the patient so they're kind of
screwing the caregiver over on this one
essentially you just got to grow a bunch
of weed and smoke it and find what works
for you and that's what works instead of
being able to just you know take a nut
off of each of your plant and take a
gram and go have each one tested and
know what's going to work for you and
another thing that we can't do we can't
test for molds or pesticides or
pathogens or any type of heavy metals or
contaminants I I have faith in my
growing but wouldn't you like to know
once in a while I mean that's how you
know if you're even right just take a
sample to the lab and luckily I can do
it I just got a bunch of stuff tested
and I hate to brag but I hit pretty
freakin awesome numbers and zero
contaminate
pathogens problems pesticides it was all
clean
luckily I'm hooked up like that
according to the meed the rule hasn't
been in effect since October 15th of
2013 but it wasn't being followed at
least not so strictly that the Denver
Post wasn't able to get independent test
done on edibles as recently as March
through steep hill Halen and Hemi
devised ins lab do our officials that's
Department of Revenue officials haven't
admitted that those tests which showed
an embarrassing lack of oversight on
behalf of the meed
spurred the sudden enforcement of the
rule and announcement of the change but
the timing is curious and brings up
another point westward and the post as
well as many other as any other media
outlet will no longer be able to do our
own independent tests at state verified
marijuana labs so I'm gonna recap a
couple of episodes ago we talked about
the westward bought edibles from
dispensaries and took them to labs to be
tested and we found out that there's
some [ __ ] going on there and now
with these new rules
maybe those tests reminded the
regulators that this rule is in place
and we shouldn't they forgot nobody's
enforcing its we think we kind of got
their attention by maybe putting it in
the paper but then also now we can't do
that anymore a normal guy like you and I
if we get an edible and we're like this
one's crap and we save half of it we
can't take it down to the testing lab
and say test this for me so we've kind
of been blocked out which I don't think
is cool I don't think it's cool so
that's another thing if you uh if you're
setting up legalization in your state
make sure that the testing is available
for anybody not just state licensed
facilities because not everybody can
afford the state licensing not everybody
needs to be state licensed as long as
you're a caregiver I think you should
have the right to get your stuff tested
agree I agree with myself I'm gonna see
if I got another news topic in here read
one more news topic and then we'll get
into my good buddy Jesse came over a
little earlier and we recorded some
stuff about outdoor growing so this may
be a little bit old to some of you I
wanted to talk about it on the show but
we've been so busy that had a lot of
news going on and this week there ain't
[ __ ] in the weed news I'm sorry for that
kind of good things that let us get the
grow episode anyway
House bill 1361 which limits hash hash
sales and House bill 1366 which further
regulate edible sales were approved by
the state Senate on third on the third
reading yesterday and now I head to the
governor's desk for signing and then
there is an update oh that's the update
the original post
I read that kind of backwards I'll tell
you what they're what they're signing a
bill limiting how much marijuana
concentrate can be sold in state and out
to in-state and out-of-state residents
who are age 21 and older as well as
legislation placing new rules on
marijuana edibles appear on track to
become state law as lawmakers try to
wrap up a 2014 session loaded with weed
bills by Wednesday afternoon damn that
was a mouthful of words I'm gonna take a
drink of some coconut water here give me
one second quick second taking a drink
here we go shout out to coconut water by
the way you know if you buy the coconut
water do not get one with lemon in it
there are a lot of tasty flavors mango
there's pineapple
there's citrusy ones don't get the one
with the lemon I had to try it once okay
oh dude
I don't really know what that's about
but that's good for you dude it's good
for you Oh tastiness that water from the
coconut its water from the coconut it's
pretty much the package says it's like
sticking a straw in a coconut and I
think it's accurate okay yeah get the
ones with some fruit juice in it if
you're new the it'll it'll kind of be
different the first time you try it you
won't be ready for that alright that's a
big plug for coconut water for the word
alright House bill 1361 would charged
the Department of Revenue with
establishing how much hash or
concentrates equal to an ounce of
marijuana the measure has already been
Greenland by the State House and it
passed on a second reading in the state
Senate yesterday without any amendments
as a result the bill could have its
third reading as early as today as we
pointed out last month the bill's
wording doesn't seem to make it clear
whether the DOR is meant to measure the
total THC in an ounce or the total
amount of hash or concentrate that can
be produced from an ounce neither does
the legislation address the potency of
the flowers to be tested whatever the
final interpretation the net effect adds
up to the same thing
consumers will no longer be able to walk
out of a shop with
28 grams of hash far fewer than that
probably out-of-state consumers who are
already limited to a quarter ounce of
herb at a time will be limited to a
quarter ounce of herbs equivalent in
hash how are they gonna regulate that
bro because um about a gram
they'll probably limit it to a gram you
think that'll be it for out-of-state
they'll probably say a gram for
out-of-state and they'll probably do an
eight for in-state maybe up to a quarter
maybe not depends on what you know yeah
because I may do five grams and this is
it doesn't say they haven't decided they
don't even know how to dissapoint yeah
how is a bill being passed when they
don't have when they don't have it
written or the or the law it's likely
it's not the next line says it's likely
that the DOR will create a working group
later this year to iron out details as
the Department has done with marijuana
centric legislation in the past so
they're gonna go about it backwards
again yeah they're gonna play back so
like every [ __ ] three months there's
gonna be new regulation and new
regulation and everyone's gonna get
audited and [ __ ] with just because
they can't figure out what dude you can
get four good nugs you can get [ __ ]
25% like average it to 20 off of a nug
run put it on ten as a trim run [ __ ] you
got seven grams that's about 0.7 if you
got nug rin that's about 1.4 so you
average it out 1 1 gram have you ever
have you ever seen anyone laters think
like that no some of us in the community
they try to listen to forget that try to
listen to some people that for sure I
agree blue yeah if you want to limit it
to the same thing as buying an ounce
whatever that makes it concentrate but
can pick an average number and that's it
pick one that's in the middle of the low
end and the high end and go with that
that's nice round number yeah I like it
they should just take they should make a
tube it holds perfectly an ounce and
just blast that in to contain
and there you go that's your one out for
the country it's for sale little to go
portion yeah so in a related measure
House bill 1366 which would ban edible
manufacturers manufacturers from making
pot infused foods that and in quotes a
reasonable consumer would confuse with
the trademarked food product yeah so
that means that the reefers and the kif
cat those are now banned in Colorado it
also looks like it will become law in
addition the bill prohibits edible
makers from making pot foods that are
primarily marketed to children and I'm
sorry that I shouted out reefers and
kiff cat but those were the obvious ones
that I thought of I don't mean to point
you but keep keep your recipe the same
and shape everything like a weed leaf
yep then it can't be confused require
more stringent packaging and labeling
from the marijuana industry the bills
authors say the moves are needed to
protect children while advocates have
said the language is so vague that it
might even prevent them from making
marijuana cookies the state marijuana
Enforcement Division is also working on
limiting the potency of edibles and is
also discussing a labeling system it's
still having a [ __ ] labeling can you
change it again exactly yeah well
because they're due to change policy
guidelines again well yeah but that's do
you change the number on the [ __ ]
potency that kind of relates to
something we talked about how are we
gonna measure the potency of these these
edibles if the labs can't get their [ __ ]
together and kind of agree on a standard
of how they're gonna test they all do
different tests if we took one lab or
one candy bar to another lab and one to
another it'll be different well that's
why not very many labs are licensed to
do that right now very true very very
true why it's very limited and that's
why there's back orders on [ __ ]
products because there's like a couple
of [ __ ] places to get tested at all
these companies have to send all of
their stuff to get tested there
and wait for the results and wait that's
hundreds of companies in color I don't
have to do that yeah yeah Wow I didn't
even think about many companies all
right well I posted something on
Facebook just out of curiosity I said
how much does a bag of herb cost where
you live what do you pay for 1/8 the
quarter or an ounce what's the quality
what country do you live in I should
have put state I put what country that's
curious what state or country do you
live in is cannabis legal in your area
and then I said that I'm gathering info
for a podcast so I'm scrolling down
Santa Cruz California he says one
hundred and fifty dollars a zip all day
for bomb Endor which I believe you if
that's Santa Cruz you must know somebody
another guy says 25 1/8 fifty a quarter
175 an ounce quality is 78 out of a 10
organic flushed cured very nice genetics
western Colorado
he says it's legal but dispensaries are
banned in my County so caregivers only
good caregiver they're hooking up twenty
five and eight 175 an ounce nice work of
Internet County 140 an ounce for legal
medical use some endure some good endure
tons of great quality outdoor there's
some answers that I think might be
[ __ ] people just trying to brag like
sheep Paso my guy said standard Street
prices do what what is that where are
you what our standard tree exactly bro
wherever you are I'll really pass
medical what's going to take some time
before many people can even get their
license multiple doctor visits at cost
and there are no dispensaries in the
state as of yet so even if you do have
your medical marijuana you can't get any
weed anywhere in Illinois it looks like
this guy says $10 grams $30 $850 ounces
in Bakersfield
we're the only County in Cali were they
voted to ban dispensaries and there's
about thirty now that's funny Flint
Michigan wholesale $200 ounces retail
325 and outs this guy wrote retail and
wholesale prices so it looks like retail
for a quarter is 50 he kind of didn't do
it all in the same order so I gotta
figure out which twenty minute but 30 an
eighth for top shelf in Flint Michigan
is what it looks like Oregon
you're looking at
40 and 890 a quarter for a grade triple
a weed I believe you there the Detroit
area 250 an ounce
this guy says he's in Stanwood
Washington we're looking at flowers 10
to 15 a gram here concentrates 20 to 60
a gram
gives a shout out to a place where he
works and then says Thank You Kim
so if you're this guy is freaking
collective employer Thank You Kim that's
cool of you keeping this guy's supplied
with medicine the Philly area fifty to
sixty and eight 100 to 120 a quarter 300
to 375 fer now it's never much of a
selection but not bad either so uh looks
like prices are varying a little bit
from 200 to 350 I South Carolina 350 to
500 ounce quality is so warm not legal
J's yeah I'm out to Colorado you say
that gets Bangka t dank and [ __ ] be
legal at a medical shop erection yeah
you can come into a shop and get [ __ ]
badassness for that price somebody just
chimed in around 2:30 an ounce for
b-grade buds near Missoula Montana Oh
somebody had messaged me - they didn't
want to post it on there so we'll read
we got two private messages Jacksonville
Florida ounces of accurate strain Callie
and Colorado ship full how it goes for
50 100 200 350 1,100 you say ship flower
yeah so don't ship the rest of your
stuff cuz your ship and stuff we talk
about [ __ ] it was [ __ ] weed don't ship
any [ __ ] weed products goddamn it
we've talked about it several times
obviously you don't listen to podcast
that's right
let's see zips are 200 from the garden
250 from a friend 10 Plus from the
dispensary I don't know what 10 means 10
Plus from the dispensary the lower the
price the better the quality in that
order bless oh it must mean like a grade
10 plus
people just have a hard time typing I
think sometimes so I just wanted to
share with you what prices art of
cannabis across the nation right now in
Colorado there are eighths of top-notch
superdate crystal e-tank homegrown nugs
by homegrown I mean by a care giver
which loved his plants they were all
organic nothing funky put in them you're
looking about 25 and 8 if you know the
guy if you're out of the loop maybe up
to 35 ounces there are 200 bucks all day
long in Colorado you can find them for
150 I've seen them for 250 if you go to
the shops you may he may feel a little
dirty it's a little more expensive there
he want to tell us what rec and medical
prices are bro since you're more
informed well it depends on the shop but
medical prices will go from 150 to 260
I've seen it for an ounce just depends
on the shop and the weed and the weed
but sometimes you can get good deals you
just never know but average is about 180
200 okay for an ounce and then rec I
haven't really haven't been any other
wreck shop but mine so I couldn't say
really do want to tell us what you
charge for now to recreationally to your
shop regular shelf is 395 I think in the
before tax and then top shelf for the
badass [ __ ] is 460 before tax you're
looking at about 460 after tax and 540
after tax man banging on the quality a
weed you want eighty bucks worth of tax
on an ounce of weed and 17.4% so much
ouch ouch ouch $65 eight the cost you 76
and change can I divide my ounce into
four separate quarters it's gonna cost
you quarter prices oh my god you're not
even gonna hook a brother up and give me
we can't oh my god dude the way the tax
is we got a [ __ ]
okay for the tactile it [ __ ] alright I
need to go change my pants after this
we're gonna fade out here real quick and
we're gonna bring in the outdoor grow
lesson from our good friend Jessie and
then we'll also be back with a very
special gift thanks portion stay tuned
this portion of the podcast is brought
to you by our good friends at oil slick
check out oil slick Pat comm more
information oils to help you concentrate
ladies and gentlemen that's alright
we're hanging out here with my good
buddy Jesse anyway I was talking to
Jesse the other day he sent me a text
message
he was like hey bro the outdoor seasons
coming and I want to teach people how to
grow outdoor and he's like if we're
gonna do it we got to do it soon because
it's getting warms getting nice and I
said how about tonight so the dude is
here we got Jesse over there on the mic
say what's up bro hey thanks for coming
on dude thanks for coming to share some
knowledge with us for sure
I guess I should start how long have you
been growing outdoors this will be my
seventh or eighth season so my earliest
memories I forgot I run around in a dope
patch so nice yeah it's seven or eight
years but on my own though so that's
I've been around that's respectable yeah
sounds like you know what you're doing
yeah sounds like your parents are a
bunch of damn hippies from the way you
talk so your fondest earliest memories
are running around in a dope patch yeah
super fond memories the images that come
through my head or just joyous yeah I
wore overalls a lot as a child barefoot
yeah [ __ ]
yeah funny story used to think my dad
was a skunk farmer
so a lot of people knew him yeah man and
then you know always in the fall he he
went hunting for skunks and that's why
the freezer stunk
yeah out there for a couple days
chopping down all the skunk's yeah
awesome bastards
yeah dude if you wanna if I wanted to
start growing outdoors in Colorado or
even in California or most of the warmer
parts of the country now is the time
right oh yes holes dug and started
getting clones out there yep if you're
lucky you're well if you're not in
Colorado you've started earlier so guys
in Cali are already in the ground ice
yeah we took some dad's earlier it'll
take us a minute to get rolling get it
started don't worry you can you put the
mic just a little closer yes yeah yeah
so ideally you know if you're growing
from seed you've wanted to start a long
time ago especially if your girl from
regular seed so that you can all sex
them yes sex them even possibly you're
growing a clone of the original seed
plant outdoors that's kind of
complicated so trying to stay more basic
feminized seeds are great for that
absolutely hence I read genetics I
haven't done it yet but I suspect some
heart of gold would kill outdoors here
so yeah thanks for that yeah I would
agree with that too someone's grown last
year in Maryland I think oh well it was
awesome yeah well done so clones you can
start a little little later you know
ideally by this point you got about a 12
to 18 foot little bush yeah no no no 18
foot no so you get a 12 hopefully we've
got a 12 inch to 18 inch little bush
yeah it's been topped Lots The Times
okay guys well I'll make a note to talk
about topping in the future because
that's a whole another topic that I'll
get into quickly that just it kind of
divides the growth and makes
one growing oh man I just got
complicated basically you take the top
shoot out of the plant the main top part
that you're gonna tell is gonna grow a
big top cola and you cut that branch out
and hopefully you just left a nice
y-shaped intersection with two tops now
and instead of one one giant cola you're
gonna get two nice fat colas that are
gonna hopefully weigh more than that one
would have yeah that's the theory and if
you learn to do it in the right spots at
the right time you can create a [ __ ]
dragon with 55 heads on it I know Joe
and if you start early enough and that's
when uh that's when the outdoor stuff
gets good several times big big bushes
bush Christmas trees the the stuff that
everyone imagines yeah did you dream
about it you see little you think a
little elves should be at least as big
around as your finger by now your middle
finger may be a little thicker yeah and
you know actually we kind of had a cold
snap here locally that might have kind
of rained on a few people's parade but
norm you know this is a little early but
it's a safe time to go out from here too
you know June 15th is completely safe
time today is May 15th we're recording
just so that people have a reference one
thing to speak on on that is if you have
your plants indoor say under 24-hour
light cycle and they're rootbound
and you put them outside right now
they're gonna bloom we only have about
15 hours of light right now and a lot of
sativa plants that's plenty enough to
trigger blooming coming from a
stressed-out 24 hour light cycle or 18
hour die cycle he's totally right yeah
I'm sternly LaBrie but he's also taking
a chunk from a dad yeah but uh he's only
right if you're putting your plants that
have been outdoors since jani are inside
since January they're in pots they're
starting to get Ruben bound cuz you're
putting it off you're just waiting to
put him outside here
once you reduce that flowering time and
they're already stressed enough they
will start to flower which is actually
probably a good thing here in Colorado
yeah you're gonna because unfortunately
in July it's gonna come out of flower
and let's go go back into veg and then
it won't go back into flour till August
so that could really mess some stuff up
this is the time of year for windowsill
plants normally growers have advised
against window plants but this is the
time of year to you know it's safe to
have that plant in the window getting
used to the natural light cycle and
everything okay I'm kind of Milcah on
and off maybe have a little t5 above it
what if I mean house be ideal about now
yeah yeah I mean as long as it's not
stressed um you know nice fresh clone
would be pretty safe in there and it's
gonna go ahead and start veg in so a
little bit of high nitrogen feeding slow
down the bloom process to help prevent
that yes yes yes if you guys don't
overdo it but just uh when you put them
out there feed a little extra nitrogen
if you're doing it right now
yeah and a lot of rude inoculations you
know go wrong with a lot of inoculants
yeah and then you know larger containers
is the best way to fix a root bound
plant so you were we were talking before
the show you said that the best way to
do it is always to throw that plant into
the dirt get it into the earth that's
the best way to go firm believer in
attaching you know when it's man I gotta
think of a good way to explain this I
just I believe plants do better when
they're attached to the earth and and
they container full of peat moss not
that that's a bad way to do it I just
think they're better in the earth well
that makes good sense
our organics are really hard to mess up
you know that's that's the easiest way
to do organics and have stellar results
in my opinion could you say and this may
be some you said the word hippie dippie
[ __ ] earlier so maybe that's what this
is yes is it the vibration of the earth
is it that connected yes okay I believe
a lot in that sort of stuff in there
growing I believe that that's part of
why our gross stand out because we agree
that the plant is in the earth and us
symbiotic relationship and I learned a
lot of that I had adopted this style
before but then I learned a lot more of
it from soma yeah if you guys are
familiar with the old breed or soma if
you're not do some reading on soma yes
sir alright so we've gotten ourselves up
to we're vegging outdoors we should
rewind and talk about maybe having a
secure garden and being having a legal
garden that's up to you if you want to
be legal in Colorado we advise you to be
legal you can have six plants as a
medical patient now you can have six
plants as a civilian over the age of 21
I do believe that half of those need to
be in flower and half of those need to
be in veg so you can put three large
plants outside as long as they are not
accessible or visible to the general
public and okay amendment 20 says it
made mid-20s real open that's the
medical bill it needs to be a secured
area basically as I've you know I can't
recall per badum but whatever that is
but amendment 64 does mention some stuff
and it says a locked enclosed secured
facility okay so depending on you know
to me that says dog kennel yeah
something just like this zone I was
thinking - yeah or green house would be
perfect anything should if you've got
locks on your gate I take them coupe
yeah or just backyard in general I think
that should be enough yeah you did your
you tried your best
so yeah three per adult at residence you
know that's three plants is plenty
enough to grow person an ounce a week
here in southern Colorado you could
produce 52 ounces off of three large
plants and that gives you an ounce a
week which would save I'm gonna do some
fake math here I'm gonna go low I'm
gonna guess that an ounce is about 300
bucks inter-disciplinary sure yeah
medical medical medical so okay well
that's time racket to you anymore
reckless a400m Wow so we're looking at
400 bucks times 52 I don't need a
calculator to know that I'm gonna save a
[ __ ] ton of money yes yes it's like
switching to Geico just by growing
outdoors guy code there we go I fixed
the sound issue God okay yeah this piece
right here needs to go we're gonna smash
it with a hammer after the show the
ballast the ballast um that's awesome I
think that may have been why it took us
a while to realize it growers I when I
drew it home all the time I would wake
up and not hear the hum and that's when
you know something's wrong
look in the flower it's off okay yeah so
you know don't grow it in front everyone
don't rub it in anyone's face you know
keep it in your backyard fence secured
if you live in Pueblo just grow a bunch
of weed yeah what you have to worry
about I've got security written down
yeah
thieves are your biggest problem here in
Pueblo other than let the cops aren't
even that big of a deal no it's not
around here cops are cool whoa
I've had a few run-ins with them this is
cool this is a weird Avenue for me to
even go down but think about what you're
bringing when you're setting up an
outdoor garden if you do run into a
thief if you do catch somebody out there
think about what you're going to do
before the time comes because everybody
has a they've got big balls when they're
thinking and talking but you're gonna
have to deal with some [ __ ] if that does
happen so think about what you're
bringing I know that's a shitty Avenue
to go down set up some security cameras
have a dog yeah
dumb dogs do wonders and getting your
stuff ripped off is a very humbling
experience yeah and it also there's
there's a few stages of it it's gone
yeah could it be everyone was everyone
yeah and then it wasn't anyone and then
you find it on the somebody selling you
an eighth of it on the street and then
you're just glad you tried so yeah
that's a weird Avenue to even mention
but be prepared what you're gonna do
because somebody may attempt to steal
your [ __ ] and please don't shoot them
over marijuana grow more next year yeah
human lives are worth way more than 10
marijuana yeah don't shoot anybody over
your pot that's a crime that becomes a
crime you're uh you're protecting your
criminal enterprise at that point yeah
yeah just let them have it if they're
gonna come steal it like that if you are
if you're a fighter and they don't have
a weapon you're brave like that do that
but don't pull out a firearm Chris not
in the name of weed good good dog good
little little Barker's yep two little
chihuahuas that'll let you know who's
there so we should back up once more
into soil prep we've got nice big 12
inch tall plants they've got 18 inch
tall plants they've got stalks bigger
than my middle finger
they've been topped now they need to go
into the dirt we should prep the soil
you got a dig of nice size hole we
should prep some soil to put in there
right yeah all right what are you what
do you like to add to your outdoor mix
um I organic Jesse's all about the
organic so he's a hippie in disguise I
make my own compost slash worm casting
kind of combined thing and lots of bone
meal lots of blood mill a fish bone meal
as my lime kelp mill rock phosphate worm
castings it said that guano sliced
iguanas pop some flowers I don't know to
me that's all basic stuff but that
sounds like a lot of stuff that's all in
very small dosages of each piece right
for beginners you equiano's you'll kind
of beef up on yeah the fish meal blood
meal bone meal you can go heavy on yeah
yeah the other stuff just you can tread
lightly and you'll still have a good
product for sure okay do not use
anything from like Home Depot don't get
anything with Scotts or Miracle Grow on
it don't do that no no it'll taste like
[ __ ] it'll burn your plants and don't
support that [ __ ] anyway
yeah don't don't put that in our earth
right if you're growing your own
cannabis you want better products going
into your what you're putting in you're
going to smoke so try to stay as close
to natural and as friendly with the
earth as you can think about the impact
you're leaving on
I know it's your backyard it's your a
patch of dirt but hopefully you're gonna
grow there next year and next year and
next year and then one day maybe your
kids are gonna grow there or somebody's
kids are gonna grow there so be
conscious of what you're doing to our
hearths please yeah that's cool we gotta
remind him yeah and and like he said
that's your patchy Earth so you know
that means those words mean a lot to me
yeah kids Earth one day so ideally you
would uh makes your soil earlier you
know nice warm day in March or something
like that or in April put it in the
ground water good cover it with plastic
turn it a couple times that just helps
kind of activate everything it's called
a lots of different slang words for it
janna you know cooking your soil brewing
your soil whatever if you see a white
webbing stuff on there excellent that's
a good thing don't freak out don't don't
panic that's awesome that is life
happening in your soil and that life is
gonna transfer right into your plants
and your plants are gonna have a big
life orgasm in there
yes but if you didn't do that don't
freak out you know that doesn't ruin
anything if you're you know just here in
this it's you know you're still fine too
you know makes your soil you know pretty
much follow the directions on the back
of the boxes you know bugs should we
have done anything by now for bugs or
animals or pests or anything outdoors
see on the door guys so Allah I'm
learning with you on this or I'm
learning with the listeners on this
outdoor lesson it's my opinion here in
the Colorado there are more good bugs
outside than our bad bugs pesticides
outside I've never used them okay so in
my in my ideal world whatever is eating
my plant today tomorrow something is
going to come to eat that critter
tomorrow somebody will eat that and
hopefully mother nature and the eco will
balance me out yeah okay and that's why
organics are so important outdoors you
know when you dump salts and stuff like
that into the earth it kills it and it
kills the beetles and it kills the bugs
and which kills the birds which kills
the bees when he says salts he's talking
about bottled nutrients almost
everything we're buying in a bottle yeah
be it veganic or organic it's a salt
based nutrient yeah yeah related yes
which mostly just kills all your mykos
anyway so now we've got healthy fats oil
rich soil we got some tall plants in
there they're top they're starting to
grow those are gonna get out of hand bro
because we just topped him like 50 times
they got a bunch of heads how do we keep
that under control well you can take
like some 4x4 metal fencing hog fencing
I think it's commonly referred to make
up 36 48 inch wide
a super tomato cage basically okay
fasten it to the ground and you're able
to pull the plant down and redirect the
growth so you want to spread it out just
like you would endorse to kind of get
the light down the Sun down in there
yeah yeah you're able to make the plant
bigger it's also a good security device
oh there you go to turn it yes very much
maybe tie a belt or two to that cage oh
yeah
yeah you see that Lincoln that wakes up
your little chihuahua
so what's he run out there and rescue
the crop hopefully you're just scaring
away some punks
nobody tough yeah all right so I'm
picturing like this big cylinder of
tomato caging essentially it looks like
maybe like my plants in a cage and I'm
gonna put that on early enough to where
my plant has I don't have to struggle to
get my plant into that right yeah so 36
to 48 inches you guys that's three to
four feet around that's what we're
planning on this little tiny 18 inch
plant turning into how tall do I need
that my cage um five six foot okay you
know alright most privacy foot six foot
so unfortunately I've always grown
behind privacy fence make it six inches
shorter than the fence you know so your
your nodes the arms of the plant are
gonna grow up basically and you're gonna
want to grab one of those and weave it
through that tomato cage where the
outside looks like it's got just a bunch
of arms poking out okay yeah yeah okay
and then those will be strong enough to
hold themselves up because they've been
outdoors I'm not gonna need to stake
them after that hopefully yeah another
thing is a good thing to hook this cage
to is like a wooden frame made out like
four by fours that also helps hold the
water in for the plant so you can water
it proper amounts and everything okay so
like a slightly raised bed yes like
basically a little micro bed
you know and a depression in the ground
there these these plants will use up to
five gallons of water a day easily Wow
even more so keep that in mind you guys
for these plants that we're planting if
you're doing three of them to stay legal
you need 15 gallons of water a day so
you're gonna have to think about how
you're gonna get that water there if
you're doing it somewhere that's that's
by the time they're blooming easily
that's that's the biggest thing outdoors
this keeps those guys pondered yes yeah
I don't want water water lots of water
it's really really hard to overwater in
southern Colorado soil really hard for
marijuana especially that outdoor Sun we
get here do you think the this is random
do you think the difference we get in
the heat during the day in the cold at
night plays a big difference in the
flavor and potency of our cannabis yes I
agree we get a lot of tasty fruit the
cantaloupes and the peaches are
delicious and I think it has something
to do with that cold sour dealer loves
it really don't tell everybody that do
two things got a good sour decal let's
help them out if they're growing that
sour do you send a notice don't send
anything when you see me share me yeah
if that if you have one those
hard-to-find ones they really there's a
guy around here with a cut that's just
fire yeah all right so we've got him out
we're gonna have to do any more pruning
do you wanna indoors I cut off all that
bottom [ __ ] we do lolli popping do you
want to do that as much on an outdoor
Crocker sure I like to hollow the plants
out basically like I do the fruit trees
over in palisade say your plants four
foot in circumference everything you
know this is totally situational but you
know just approximately you know 12 to
18 inches of plant length every I think
I see what you're saying yeah you're
probably gonna have to okay so you know
from the
from the outside in you know every you
know about 18 inches you just want
pretty much strip everything off the
main branches Oh God you know if there
isn't a branch itself keep them nice and
hollow that helps air flow in there lots
of air flow we're talking about molds
earlier bug deterrent bug deterrence you
don't want moldy we we do who do have
caterpillar caterpillar issues here so
what are those are things we get here
there are these little orange worms I've
only only happens around here um I've
seen them brown and yellow I've never
seen again
orange ones but yeah yeah they totally
they're from Moss okay boost Moss that
makes good sense to me and that's their
larvae and they're their parents were
way hippie and decided to lay their kids
a bunch pop plans and it actually
happens early in the bud development and
you don't really notice it till the
harvest time yeah that's what songs you
don't find it to harvest and please if
you do find [ __ ] like that don't make
hash Adam yeah so just just cut it out
of that bud I've never you know you know
discard that bud it's it doesn't affect
the entire plant it just affects the
area around the bug itself so that's one
of the few pests that is and does it
ruin the entire plant that's another
good question what are some of my
pitfalls are gonna be growing outdoors
in Colorado um if you don't have good
air circulation in the fall you're gonna
get out of em old make sure you don't
over plant your area and you have plenty
of air circulation around your plant you
should be fine you know if you plant it
in the forefoot area between your shed
and your back fence and your side fins
and there's a bush growing on the side
and you threw a tarp over the top so the
neighbors in the second story building
couldn't see you you're probably gonna
get mold just just like growing indoors
with that aspect but you know plenty of
that mother nature do your thing
spider mites I have seen outdoors here
it's really hard to get that's mostly
from sloppy indoor grows so just
carrying them out there yeah should be
taking care of that inside anyway yeah
and those will ruin your plant a powdery
mold and you want to talk about sad
people
it's one thing to throw away an indoor
plant because it had one of those things
throw away an entire outdoor plant is
yeah we're hoping to grow 52 ounces here
with these three outdoor plants so I've
only got a couple more questions for you
know we're gonna turn it we're gonna try
to do segments we're gonna have him back
in a couple of weeks and well I'm Jesse
back in a couple weeks and then walk
back a couple weeks after that and
hopefully it'll be harvest time and
he'll bring some of his outdoor harvest
with him to show us and talk about and
you guys can yeah well I'll talk shop on
the show what day around when am I gonna
go into flower outdoors here in Colorado
this year July 15th around then okay the
hours will start going negative that the
hours in the day will start getting
shorter okay up until then they're gonna
start getting longer so cannabis only
needs about fourteen hours of daylight
to make it start flowering outdoors when
the Sun sets this is some trip [ __ ] yeah
and I may get this wrong when the Sun
sets it starts putting off a red
spectrum and that red spectrum triggers
the hormones in the plant to sleep so it
kind of tucks it in a lot of people talk
about well it's not 1212 outside why am
i flower it's that red spectrum in the
Sun it's kind of messing that's not
messing it's exactly what it should do
it's telling your plants in the night in
the morning it's blue and that wakes
them up I've heard I read no old DJ
short burger no anyway I know GJ short
is where I heard this it's only about an
hour hour and a half that makes these
plants flower outside versus indoors
it's anywhere from twelve to six hours
difference of light to make some flower
no it's the equatorial stuff they're
very coming from Thailand and places
like that or more jungle regions and and
outdoors
different strains a little different
times so your sativas go first
I've noticed your landrace plants will
go first to hybrids typically go last so
okay yeah
when is my when should I really be
focused on getting these things down by
as far as harvesting yeah what's my
harvest date what's my deadline do I
just sit outside and watch for that
first frost if it comes then three hours
before it freezes the first no that's
really hard to say you know when they're
done right yeah but by the end of
September it's not gonna freeze and most
plants are acceptable to harvest so safe
safe to take down okay you were talking
about strain selection without giving me
any shameless plugs I mean I do know
that a couple of my strains work quite
well outside yeah what kind of stuff
would work well for the Colorado region
around us and if you know any of the
popular cuts that people have got I know
golden goat is a good outdoor feel it
takes a minute to finish with that girl
what else would you throw outside like I
suspect heart of gold would kill
anything with kim de groot does
excellent okay so put some grateful dog
heart of the old Bounty Killer outside
would probably amazing float is really
good flow and blueberry honestly are two
of the best performing outdoor plants
I've I've never done my own outdoor but
I have helped a couple of guys and the
flow and the blueberry always blew my
mind when he did him outdoor uh ghost
Bubba does really good outside okay
that's a good strain too
Oh doesn't yield good but she tastes
amazing else
Golden Girls good Sour Diesel actually
does pretty good around here some guys
in a little town yeah outside of here
that make sure that outdoor salad be
shown guys I'm not gonna bust your spot
but [ __ ] out lemon tea short us P pasa
Colorado green bud no those are all
local strains I'm gonna pack a short bus
that somebody handed me at the first
cannabis cup that's from that same
little town neat yeah they just walked
by and planted them on me Kenneth going
well yeah if you've got some room
locally bred strains always do better if
they were bred here I don't know why but
they do that's their environment that
makes sense to me so um yeah I had one
more question but I can't think of it
off the top of my head so we'll save it
for next time okay those right in 30
minutes bro so if you got any couple
ending things to end on we can save the
rest for next time or um pest
pesticides if you do use them please use
like neem oil organic ones don't don't
kill the bees feed with teas but yeah
we'll get to that next time there we go
I'll make a note to talk about teas and
security don't tell anyone that doesn't
need to know that even if it is even if
you're in a legal state don't tell
anyone it doesn't need to know that'll
be your first suspect when it gets
stolen and then that's gonna [ __ ] up
friendships yeah and they're unlikely
that person didn't do it but it's really
hard not to think they did
that's great [ __ ]
one thing I was gonna mention if you're
gonna get some stuff tested well you
can't get stuff tested they just changed
the rules here in Colorado if you were
able to get stuff tested do you think
the outdoor stuff is gonna test
considerably higher than the indoor
stuff I would like to see a indoor I
suspect is probably gonna have higher
THC simply because it doesn't have the
dust in the wind in the rain
I think the Sun outnumbers all of that
in my opinion so we should we should
grow the same strain indoors and out and
see will be for sure what I do think
will happen outdoors is you're gonna
have a lot of these other cannabinoids
are gonna be off the charts okay so
that's my theory
so are grow lights we're only bringing
out specific yeah is that why we're
getting so much Lebanon and things oh
yeah yeah here's something I've never
shared if you want more lemon flavor
I've never I don't think I've told
anybody this I read it and something I
think it was steep hill or something
like that long time ago if you want more
lemon flavor lemon can be increased it's
almost a stress reaction by making too
much light and too much heat on the tops
of your plants that will increase your
lemony and lemony limey kind of flavor
mmm safety reaction I think so yeah
alright there's just over 30 minutes
I'll put a couple of ads and some more
stuff onto the here
you gotta clubs or anything yeah sure
Jesse grows on Instagram all one word
and garden of Weeden on Instagram I
don't know if spilled weird al' tag on
Instagram page so they can find us so
yeah cool
Jesse we'll be back in a couple of weeks
and hey thanks for joining us right now
guys all adds more to this piece all
right ladies and gentleman thanks for
joining us for our first grow lesson
that was a very special feature for my
buddy Jesse I wanna give him a big
thanks for coming and spending some time
with me Jesse got a little nervous on
the microphone but by the third or
fourth time we have him on the show I'm
sure he'll be nice and relaxed alright
this is the portion of the show where I
take a minute to give thanks to somebody
I feel has been beneficial or crucial to
the cannabis movement the past two
episodes I've given thanks to Jorge
Cervantes and Ed Rosenthal because they
were very important in my my development
and my education as a cannabis grower so
I want to continue that uh that series
and give thanks to Robert Connell Clark
Robert Connell Clark is a native-born
Californian here Owen illustrated the
body and ecology of cannabis as his
undergraduate thesis at University of
California at Santa Cruz where he
graduated with honors
he later self-published his thesis and
started pods pressed in Ben Lomond
California
Clark has published articles in High
Times magazine and other journals on his
favorite subject as a well-known
cannabis photographer his photos and
illustrations have appeared in numerous
magazines books posters and calendars
Clark continues to travel throughout the
West interviewing cultivators and fellow
researchers Clark carries an active
correspondence with the major cannabis
researchers throughout the world and
this is reflected in the in-depth and
accuracy of his writings on cannabis
Robert Connell Clark is responsible for
a lot of my breeding knowledge he wrote
he wrote a book called marijuana botany
he also wrote cannabis evolution and
ethnobotany
and he also wrote the book called
hashish which also has a updated version
the book marijuana botany every grower
that's trying to reach the next level
should read this book and if you're
thinking about breeding this is the book
to get this is basically an instruction
book on how to breed high-grade cannabis
and to hit the goals you're looking for
so I just want to take a moment and say
thank you Robert Connell Clark you've
been very crucial and instrumental in my
cannabis education and I wouldn't be the
breeder that I am without you so big
thanks Robert Connell Clark big thanks
to you guys for listening hey stay tuned
because next week we have our special
dabbe episode coming up and I hope you
guys join us for that I want to give a
big thanks to Jesse and Kevin for
joining us so hope to see you next time
until then take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
okay now that the show is over
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store find
the iGrow culture podcast give us a five
star review and type in the comment and
let us know how you feel about the show
also find us on Twitter or Instagram
anti-drug culture
[Music]
welcome to episode number 12 of the
iGrow culture podcast I'm your host
Rasta Jeff thanks for joining me for
another episode company live over
Memorial Day weekend I want to take a
quick second to say thank you to
everyone who lost their lives keeping us
safe
I never support a war but I always
support our troops this episode is
brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit matrice Green
remedies comm from a lot of labs Sin
City alpha chronic rare dankness
mile-high cat adventure pirate genetics
and many more trusted brands if you
purchased two 10 packs of ivory genetics
you will receive a free five pack of
Bounty Killer while supplies last matrix
green remedies is also running a special
for our podcast listeners type in coupon
code podcast and all capital letters for
15% off any order you'll always get free
shipping and nature's green remedies
calm that coupon code does expire on the
31st so place your order today the show
is also brought to you by our good
friends over oil slick oil slick tools
to help you concentrate make sure you
check out oil slick Pat comm for more
info and also big love to tree hugger
comm this episode is brought to you in
part by tree hugger comm live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
comm for concert and festival news and
reviews tree hugger comm Big Love
all right so I'm hanging out on a rainy
Sunday night here in Colorado coming to
you guys with the promised DAB episode
but before we do that I want to read a
little bit of news a few episodes ago I
told you guys about the Colorado
Symphony inviting folks to bring
cannabis to their concerts
well the concerts have since happened
and I've got a little article here from
the Denver Post written by John Wenzel
it's the headline is symphonies first
cannabis concert wus and raises funds
the Colorado Symphony Orchestra's first
classically cannabis event began Friday
night like any other fine arts
fundraiser with suit and dress wearing
attendees politely mingling at a high
ceiling art gallery sipping drinks and
shaking hands no clouds of pot smoke no
tie-dyed t-shirts not at first anyway a
closer look revealed the distinctly
cannabis-related nature of the event the
first of three fundraisers in which
invite only attendees were encouraged to
bring their own marijuana Fridays
classically cannabis event also featured
a patio on which attendees casually
smoke pot from joints vaporizers pens
and glass pipes under umbrellas as a
light rain fell the back of the Space
Gallery on Santa Fe Drive which was
covered with an l-shaped lofted area
that supported a half-dozen
more small tables also featured vendors
from dispensaries and pot shops that
sponsored the event such as wellspring
Gaia and boulders the farm as the night
wore on the sticky sweet smell of
marijuana wafted and regularly from the
wide garage door that opened into the
patio which led to another small outdoor
area with food trucks and a pair of ice
cream and popsicle vendors where
attendees also openly smoked cannabis
we're bridging the gap between classical
music and marijuana in both directions
at Morgan Carr co-owner co-owner of
wellspring as he showed off the
complimentary vaporizer pins preloaded
with hash oil and wellspring branded
glass jars and disposable lighters the
event which was switched from public to
private after the city of Denver warned
the CSO about the illegalities of public
marijuana consumption has garnered
international attention and speculation
since it was announced the 250 or so
attendees shelled out at least $75 per
person to support the CSO s experiment
in culture bridging but it's kind of
take a second right here that's
these guys had to change their their
idea from a public [ __ ] smoke marijuana
with us to make it a private event these
little gray areas are [ __ ] we need
to learn how to get it together so we
can all consume cannabis safely together
anyway look around this is not stoner
town said Evan Lasky executive vice
president of the CSO who characterized
the series as just another design to tap
into new donors we have we have to build
new audiences because the older people
are dying off we have to fight this
perception of elitism the CSO brass
quintet dressed in all black suits with
pale green ties began its 45-minute
performance with Richard Strauss ominous
also sprach zarathustra fanfare followed
by short speeches from the CSO and
sponsors acoustics in the unadorned
space were sharp and bright as the
quintet continued with recognizable
classic favorites the chatter of side
conversations from attendees who stood
are milled about due to the casual non
seated set up nearly rivaled the content
of volume at times compared to the
average Red Rock Show it was a state
affair but is unlikely any sponsored
official classic music event with the
city organization has ever attracted so
so much open marijuana consumption or
contended with so much weed smoke
hanging in the humid air co-organizer
jane west of cannabis company edible
events said thirty thousand dollars had
already been secured in sponsorship for
the night and CSO officials confirmed
another twenty thousand dollars was
garnered from attendees the CSO is
hoping to raise $200,000 from the
3-space gallery shows and another non
pot sanctioned classically cannabis
event at Red Rocks this summer
there didn't used to be any events I
felt welcomed that said West but after a
legalization happened we wanted to start
putting on events to it we would
actually go to for their part the CSO
musicians treated it just like another
gig even as the smell of we began
wafting to the opposite side of the
gallery where they warmed up in a
private room we loved playing chamber
music wherever said Trump trombone
player Gregg Harper it is what it is
we're just going to play the pieces we
know and hopefully people will
appreciate it well it sounds like a lot
of people appreciated it there are
plenty of people in attendance and a lot
of money was made so why can't this be
an example there were no negative events
there were no fight
there were no crimes committed here
there's a great great event why can't we
do this at Red Rocks why can't they say
symphony at Red Rocks why can't they say
reggae show at Red Rocks why can't they
say any concert at Red Rocks bring a
joint have a good time we don't care
that you're smoking cannabis all its
gonna do is make you hungrier and
thirstier and make you enjoy the show
more that's gonna benefit everybody at
Red Rocks they're gonna sell more food
they're gonna sell more drinks the
people they're gonna enjoy the concert
more I don't see a problem with smoking
a little bit of cannabis it's legal and
it creates commerce stoner Commerce
Munchie Commerce if you will all right
I'm gonna find the next news article
here we go I just want to read a little
bit of news so we can hurry up and get
into the dab section all right our next
article comes out of Canyon City and the
headline is pot heads against potholes
hits streets for March in Canyon City
the article is by Carrie Canterbury from
the Canyon City Daily Record about 50
citizens took part in a march down Main
Street just before Monday's regular City
Council meeting to voice support for
retail marijuana in Canyon City if you
guys don't know where Canyon City is
that's a little bit west of Pueblo a
little bit west of Pueblo West actually
probably 40 30 40 minutes outside of
Pueblo the gorgeous little town there's
a lot of great stuff out there I've got
a lot of great friends out there that
are in the rafting business so what's up
guys giving you a shout out go visit
Canyon City see what's out there anyway
Fremont cannabis owner and event
organizer Dana su said the group pot
heads against pot holes also hosted a
cookout complete with volleyball and
other entertainment at the formal Canyon
floral building at 111 Main Street
before the March she said about a
hundred people attended the cookout
ranging in age from early 20s to the 80s
they weren't from the 80s they're in
their eighties the response was more
positive than negatives who said we were
kind of surprised we weren't sure how
people were going to feel about it we
got a lot of honks and people screaming
and waving the group ended the march at
City Hall where participants sat in on
the city council meeting sue said they
wanted to show the council that there
are supporters for retail marijuana in
the community the last meeting was in
the middle of the day and it's kind of
hard for people who work to get there
she said City Council members Kevin dip
Maura Colby catch Miranda
why'd walked with the group for part of
the March I'm glad to see that there's
some Pro retail marijuana people
starting to show up for some of our
events wide said we've made no secret
about it that I certainly am in favor of
it I think it's ridiculous for us to
turn over control of retail marijuana to
our neighboring cities Pueblo West and
Salida I think we should be the ones who
control what goes on here the general
government Committee on May 7th by
majority agreement elected to extend the
moratorium beyond the November election
to allow a vote on the matter and set
the question to be asked on the November
4th ballot the current moratorium
expires July 1st the ordinances are
expected to be presented to Council for
first reading during the June 2nd
meeting and if approved second reading
and adoption would be during the June
16th meeting city administrator Doug
Dotson said the first ordinance would
extend the moratorium and would set
question on the ballot for public vote
the second ordinance would ask if the
first one approved if there should be
additional sales or excise tax on the
sale of retail marijuana so I want to
highly advise them to vote against that
because when we legalize recreational
cannabis here in Pueblo I in the county
when the shops opened up they are
required to charge 25 percent tax on
anything so if you buy a hundred dollar
bag it's now a 125 dollar bag so vote
that down if you get the option let's
get back into the article during
Monday's meeting Mayor Tony Greer said
there's a rumor circulating that there
is a conspiracy for catch mar to recuse
himself from voting on the retail
marijuana issue specifically so that
Grier can vote in favor where said that
is not true I have not made up my mind
on that Grier said that is why we have
public hearing when clarifying the May 7
meeting minutes catch Maher said during
that meeting he thought it looks like a
good idea to send the issue to voters
but at this point he does need to
abstain I don't know if it's going to be
kicked back he said I'm really not sure
where we are going with it at this point
all right so there's no certainty in the
future of recreational marijuana in
Canyon City if you guys are in Canyon
City do what you got to do to get out
there and vote get out there and wave
signs encourage your your Congress
people we got to get some recreational
cannabis for you guys out there in
Canyon City
I got another news article up here and
then we're gonna get into the hash
section of the show as promised
do a little hash 101 and speaking of
hash that brings me into our next news
article this article is written by mr.
William breeds the headline is new
Colorado hash laws signed by governor
the what do they actually do the article
says yesterday Governor John
Hickenlooper signed a baker's dozen
worth of bills on various topics but
arguably the two most high-profile
measures had to do with marijuana
legislation to establish a one ounce of
cannabis equivalent for concentrates and
a proposal to make marijuana edibles
more identifiable a prominent marijuana
advocate praises these measures as
examples of responsible legislation even
though it's quite unclear at this point
what the new laws will actually do the
summary notes that the bill directs the
Department of Revenue to promulgate
rules establishing the equivalent of one
ounce of retail marijuana flower in
various retail marijuana products the
bill authorizes the department to
contract for a scientific study of the
equivalency of marijuana flower in
marijuana products but there's no
telling what that means in practical
terms as the westward outlines in the
following excerpt
the legislation is vague on the
specifics of determining just how much
hash is in an ounce of herb which
depends on how strong the ounce of herb
is to begin with we kind of talked about
that on this show once a couple episodes
ago what they base it on a thirty
percent THC og Fino or a low THC batch
of something like blueberries even then
it's unclear whether legislators want
producers to measure total THC in an
ounce or simply estimate how much hash
can can be produced from an ounce all of
this would widely impact the amount of
concentrates that are legally approved
for sale say for the sake of discussion
that the DOR determines that there are 5
grams of pure THC in an out to verb that
could mean it's in state residents 21
and up would be able to purchase about 6
grams worth of ninety percent THC hash
oil since out-of-state residents are
transient currently limited to
purchasing a quarter ounce of cannabis
they'd hypothetically only be able to
buy one or two grams at a time that's I
think that's what Kevin and I agreed to
the last time we talked about this but
if the lab the state chooses bases its
findings on how much hash can be
produced from an ounce of herb the
amounts can be much lower we've spoken
with several hash makers who tell us
that 15 that a 15 percent average
returned from bud to concentrate is
reasonable for vho extraction which
means they get about 4 grams of hash for
every ounce of herb ice water can be
even lower only 8 to 10% resulting in
top grade smokeable hash and the rest
suitable mostly for cooking I've seen
people get 20 or 22 percent returns from
some BHO and actually I saw a guy get
thirty four percent return on some live
resin the other day but that's not the
point here the point is they're trying
to figure out how much hash that they
can sell us and how much hash is equal
to the limit of we were actually able to
buy now because people are coming from
other states I know I pick on Texas a
lot but they're coming from Texas and
Oklahoma and they're buying seven grams
of hash and it seems sketchy to some
people I don't think it's sketchy
because when the dispensaries had a lot
of hash available that was good and I
was new at the hash game I would go by
if they had the Durbin poison hash I
would say can I have all of that please
and I didn't think that was sketchy
all right that's enough for the news I'm
gonna take a quick dab and a drink of
something here
and I am going to get into dab 101 while
I take a DAB you guys should go check
out oil slick Pat calm you're dabbing
with me you're gonna need something from
oil slick stop getting your mom's table
all sticky
check out oil slick Pat calm
[Music]
all right stoner dudes and stoner chicks
gather round
it's time for dab 101 all right we're
here for dabs 101 let's start with this
one what is a DAB a DAB is basically a
hint of the cannabis concentrate which
is usually Pho in my world some solvent
list is dabble but for now we're just
gonna focus on pho pho is short for
butane honey oil pho is hash made with
butane and the butane is then purged off
and the results are BHO of different
consistencies now I did say it's made
with butane but after that the hash is
put into a vacuum chamber and heated and
the butane is removed that way so you're
not dabbing any butane if it's done
properly I'm not gonna teach you guys
how to make BHL because I don't want to
be responsible for you guys hurting
ourselves no matter how many times we
say it no matter how many news reports
we see a people getting hurt people
still insist on blasting hash indoors so
please stop making pho inside it's not
safe alright so I'm saying we get
different consistencies of pho some of
those different consistencies get
different names like they're shatter wax
crumble Earl Sapp other snap and Peele
and then also there's the new thing
which is called live resin so I'll
describe them to you and I'm gonna start
with shatter shatter is usually amber in
color it's usually it should shatter
well if you try to break it but if you
heat it up with your fingers it will get
sticky and it'll be bendable but when
you first pick it up it should be snappy
it should break like maybe like a thin
Jolly Rancher candy or something like
that
most of what you're picking up now what
we're finding now is shatter from the
dispensaries and stuff like that it's
really close to shatter
really close to shatter there's another
type that's called sap or snap and peel
it's really the same color of shatter
it's that ambery gold color it can be
anywhere from like a dark amber it's
almost a bright yellow I've got some
right now that's really dark it was done
with some flow and it's got some tangen
there
it's fluent and we've been calling it
the flange or the flange erine or the
tangelo we kind of [ __ ] around with the
names a lot but that one comes out a
little bit darker for some reason and
then there's some freedom thai lemon
baby dabs it have been being made
recently that are coming out really
white light golden yellow so it's all
about the product and all about the
starting material it'll make different
colors so the sap and the snap and field
looked very similar in color and texture
to the shatter but they of course SAP is
kind of sappy its stickier when he
folded up in parchment paper it sticks
to the parchment paper sticks to your
fingers it's kind of goopy err there's
something that's right between shatter
and SAP I call it snap and peel it
doesn't shatter like shatter does and it
doesn't stick but it kind of breaks off
it's sort of like a Laffy Taffy kind of
like the Laffy Taffy of hash so you can
pull off enough to get a good dab you
can mess with it long enough to get it
on the dabber and handle it but it
doesn't break off and it doesn't stick
so it's kind of nice that's one of your
better ones
it's the snap in feel and I also think
that it's higher quality most of the
time when it's the snap in peel that
style usually seems to have a lot of
flavor to it in my opinion
so there's also wax wax is real popular
in the dispensaries and it's kind of
easy to make a lot of the wax people are
skipping a step and they're doing the
whip part too soon but that's the main
difference between shatter and wax right
towards the end there you basically whip
it like it's a cake battery stir it up
real good and that adds air to the hash
which makes it fluff up and it gives it
a waxy texture I like wax a lot because
it's easy to handle and it also it seems
to give a big fat hit like when you take
a fat chunk of wax and you hit that you
really feel that in your lungs like a
kick it's not for some reason shatter
feel smoother to me and the wax hits
harder which sometimes I like you know
sometimes you like a shotgun to the head
you're in the mood for it there's some
wax that doesn't stick together and
that's just because of the texture of
the plant material or there are a lot of
things that can contribute to that but
the Trumbull is basically wax that won't
stay together it crumble apart there's
nothing wrong with it it just won't
stick together for some reason it could
be moisture it could be a lot of oil in
the in the hash itself so bets shatter
wax crumble Earl we just call a lot of
the stuff that we smoked Earl
my name is Earl you know everything is
Earl nowadays there are a lot of other
cool names for it I also talked about
live resin so when you're making BHO you
can either use nugs or trim and i
believe that the better you put in the
better quality you put in the better
quality you get out but some people now
they're taking a plant that is ready for
harvest you cut it down you let it dry
for three or four hours then at that
point they put it in the freezer and you
let it get nice and frozen once the
whole plants frozen they put it into a
closed-loop system and we'll talk about
that again later they put the whole
plant into a closed-loop system and they
blast it with the butane that way so
after it comes out of the closed-loop
they put it into a vacuum oven and they
purge off all the residual butane that
could be left in there and the hash that
comes out of that is called live resin
and it tastes delicious some of the
best-tasting hash I've ever had it also
gives me an amazing high and it seems to
last longer in my opinion live resin
would retain more of the beneficial
compounds then hash made from dried
material like dried trim or dried buds
but it does require a closed loop and
it's pretty advanced tag so live resin
is like next-level [ __ ] I feel like
now's the time when I should mention
that you should not ever use
contaminated material don't ever use
moldy buds or moldy trim like if you had
powdery mildew or bud rot
don't use that [ __ ] in your BHO if you
had bugs I mean if you wanted if you're
the only one dabbing it if you don't
care
for it but if you're gonna give that to
somebody sell that to somebody if you're
gonna give that to a medical patient if
you're gonna give that to a sick person
don't ever make dabs with your buggy ass
material that's not good for anybody all
right please don't do that try to think
about your patients think think that
every piece of hash you ever make or
have or even your buds think of all of
that stuff imagine what would happen if
you gave that stuff to a sick person you
don't know where it's going so try to be
conscious of that that's our
responsibility as growers is hash makers
as part of a cannabis community all
right that's what makes us the
difference between the people that care
and the people that are just in it to
make a buck and also be very aware of
everything that you're spraying on your
plants because that's going to end up in
your dad if you're spraying sighs
stomach neurotoxins onto your plants you
will be dabbing systemic neurotoxins in
the future you're planning on using that
as medicine that's what dads are
intended for is medicine so don't use
your medicine as something that's gonna
make you sick because that's why we're
using cannabis in the first place is
because we don't want to take the
medicine that they're forcing upon us
that is making us sick so fight the
power
help yourself fight the power all right
so before we can do dabs we're gonna
have to talk about a gear list this is
where it gets fun so let's say that you
have acquired some dad's you went to the
dispensary you called your guy whatever
happened however it happened you got
some high-grade dabs you're gonna notice
that you need some special packaging for
those dabs probably came hopefully came
wrapped in parchment paper maybe it came
in a little silicone package if you're
using those silicone packages I only
recommend oil slick oil slick is
platinum cured silicone I recommend you
go to oil slick pad comm and read about
the process of platinum curing their
products because it's very important so
once you get home get those dabs get it
out of that parchment paper get it out
of whatever they they sold it to you in
and go on oil slick pad comm and get
yourself a little slick stack or a slick
ball or a slick ball mini get a couple
of them then fill all those up with
different types of dabs so now you got a
little dab collection and a safe
container to keep it in the cool thing
about those slick stacks is up your
hatch won't stick to those you won't get
ripped off you always feel like if you
put it in plastic or glass you're gonna
get ripped off and don't go trying to
scrape those last
dad's off the plastic because you're
gonna end up dabbing plastic it's gonna
taste like [ __ ] you're gonna choke and
that's gonna suck you're not gonna have
a good time all right so you got
yourself a slick stack you got your hash
stored up nice and safely now you were
probably gonna notice that that hash is
real sticky kind of hard to handle
you're gonna need to get some dad tools
or maybe a highly-educated dabber or
maybe a highly-educated dabber with a
carb cap on it it'll stand upright for
you but you need something to stick in
there to handle those dabs for you
because it's gonna stick to your fingers
if your fingers are warm you got to get
those dabs onto the under the tip of a
dabber somehow and then that dabber is
actually gonna be gonna be the key to
your success here pretty soon and also
be careful the first time you go dab it
into a container of shatter you're gonna
stick your dabber right into that
container and I've said it before uh
soon as you push down into that
container a shatter a little piece of
that shatter is gonna go flying off into
nowhere and you're never gonna find it
you're gonna be pissed
so don't lose your first dab be gentle
maybe stick your thumb in there warm it
up with your thumb rub it with your
thumb a little bit that'll make the hash
a little softer it'll be more pliable
then you'll be able to get a dab off of
it without wasting your first dab if you
do a launch one off into the middle of
nowhere we always say that's one for the
dead homies like I used to pour out of
40 no you just flick a dab off into the
middle of nowhere I'd be thankful that
it didn't go into your eye because when
it does it [ __ ] burns trust me all
right so now you've got your uh dabs you
got yourself some shatter or some SAP
you know how to get it out of container
without wasting it it's time to I figure
out a little bit more of this gear the
most important thing you're gonna need
is a rig and a nail a rig is basically
everybody tries to call it a bong if
you're smoking
Earl threw it that's your rig it's an
oil rig so needle rig I prefer a small
rig we'll talk about that later one of
the Twitter questions is why do I use
such a small rig I'll explain that to
you in the future you also need a nail
nails are either made of well they're
made of titanium or my favorite there's
also ceramic there's glass and there's
quartz I'm not a fan of the glass they
never seem to taste right to me the
quartz is awesome however I break [ __ ]
which is also why I don't use the
ceramic
I prefer the titanium if I'm gonna buy a
nail I only buy a highly-educated nail
to tell you the truth tonight I've been
dabbing off of a highly-educated duality
nail shadow two tasks thanks a lot bro
so I know I say this a lot but really
invest in your nail if you have a budget
spend the smaller portion on your rig
and the higher portion on your nail
because you're gonna be heating that
sucker up to a really high temperature
between four and six hundred degrees
maybe hot or depending on how crazy you
are with torch but you're gonna be
heating that up and then you're dropping
your medicine on to that and you're
smoking it off of that you're basically
inhaling whatever is in or on that nail
if you've got some funky [ __ ] from China
they don't care about you our friends
here at America that are making good
products I'll recommend hive and I'll
also recommend highly educated they make
good stuff the Halen honey hole awesome
that's good [ __ ] right there those are
three products you got a quartz you got
a titanium and you got your ceramic so
the hive Halen honey hole and the
anything from highly educated highly
educated titanium product has got my
endorsement all day long so get yourself
a good nail get a rig I like a little
tiny break I said that before now you're
gonna need a dabber and a torch those
are the first few things you need be
careful with the torch everybody gets
scared of you when you pull out a
blowtorch be careful where you do that I
need a little dab torch
I like the vector torch they're a little
more expensive but they do have a
lifetime guarantee
I like to wrap them up in stickers I've
got a custom torch with the Chewbacca on
it it was actually a creme brulee torch
they came from Bed Bath &amp; Beyond that my
buddy customized for me so if you're not
a big spender go to Bed Bath &amp; Beyond he
can get the $30 creme brulee torch it
works just as well as the vector but it
doesn't have a lifetime guarantee so now
you got your rig you got your nail you
got a torch you needed a bird a dabber
is basically it's a poker that you use
to drop your dad you just put a little
dab on the end of it just a little tiny
dab will talk about dab size in the
future also so you just take a little
dab you put it on the end of your dabber
you heat up your nail with your torch
and you don't have to go [ __ ]
destroying this thing with heat you just
need it
enough if you put your hand over it you
just barely want to feel your skin
tighten up and get a little hot you
don't want to burn you don't want to
touch it but you want to like hold your
hand over and feel the heat you're just
trying to melt this hash so if you're
using a rig that has a dome on it you
put the dome over the nail now and then
you put the hash inside of there
directly onto the nail if you've got a
domeless nail
don't drop it right down the hole put it
in the area around the hole and if
you've got a carb cap put the carb cap
over it and just inhale as soon as you
touched that and your gonna get a nice
fat dab if you did it right all right so
now we're familiar with the rig the nail
and the torch and the dabber I talked
about a carb cap I'll explain that a
little bit later you're also probably
gonna need like an oil slick pad or
possibly a rig rag or some sort of dab
pad you're gonna have some residual
leftover tabs on your tab or after a lot
of dabbing dad pad a 7/10 dab pad is a
good place to wipe that on an oil slick
slick pad or a slab pad is also an
excellent place for that a slide pads
also a good idea keeps your keep your
rigs safe from the table is also handy
but it's not as classy as the other two
just something to wipe that excess
damage off of also you may be you may
see the evening all coming out somewhere
the emails the electric nail let's talk
about that there are a bunch of
different brands available lately but
most of them do the same thing the email
is basically the electric nail eye plugs
into the wall it's got a little box and
most of them look like a small like a
piece of musical gear a small amplifier
or something you know like it looks just
like my little focus right audio
interface here is about what most of
them look like little box with a couple
switches on it and then a cord coming
out of it and the cord attaches to a
nail most people are using the
highly-educated infinity nail so you put
this heat element onto your nail and
that sits on the rig and it always stays
hot at the perfect temperature so you
could drop that down to a nice low temp
you can set your dab on there then you
throw the carpet the carb cap up on top
of that and you let it sit for just half
a second and then you start dabbing it
and you really get a nice flavored
perfect heat dad
I think it's great it does make me over
dab a little bit honestly when I have it
sitting on the table I tend to take
extra dabs because I don't have to sit
there and heat the nail but when you're
having a social gathering and there are
a lot of dabs going around it's really
helpful because I find the torch to be
slightly abrasive when there's
conversation going on that's just my
opinion so when you're balling get
yourself an email it's worth the cost in
butane alone you'll save so much butane
from heating up the rig a lot of people
talk about hitting a vape pen I'm gonna
piss a lot of people off here a pen hit
is not a dab
that's not dabbing that's cool for if
you're at the movie theater or maybe
it's cool for your girlfriend but just
get a break and take a DAB all right so
we should have a basic understanding of
what dabs are we should know what the
gear is should know how to handle your
dabs by now seems like there's only one
thing left to do let's take a fat dab
together but put a nice sticky dab of
some shatter under this highly-educated
carb cap with the dabber on it I like
the flat tip the best I've learned and
I'm gonna grab my torch here nail this
nail I usually have to give it about a
10 or 12 count I'm gonna hold it away
from the microphone I usually go one two
three four I'm sure you guys can count
to 12 right so it should be getting
pretty close all right
I think it's me about there I can tell
that it's hot enough by looking at it I
can see that it's slightly getting
orange let it cool for just a brief
moment here now there's where I take a
nap take a dab with me guys please do
all right now I'm gonna call for a
couple of seconds then we'll come back
and answer a couple of quick Twitter
questions hey don't be afraid to cough
and turn red and sweat and [ __ ] after
your first couple of dabs we expect that
of you if you're not choking and
coughing you're not taking big enough
dabs give me a minute to get my [ __ ]
together
welcome back and work on these Twitter
questions I hope everybody survived
their dabs all right so let's get to
these Twitter questions I said earlier
that I was gonna answer the question why
do I use such a small rig somebody saw
me post an Instagram little clip and I
was using a little tiny mad rob rig I
like a little tiny rig the purpose of a
large bong is so that you could fill it
up with smoke and then pull the carb and
then you get all that smoke it wants
with the dab you're just taking a little
tiny dab and you don't really want to
fill it with smoke you just want to get
that smoke to your head so a little rake
takes less sucking and less air if I had
a great big rig a great big bong I'd
have to suck all that air through to try
to get that dad through it it just feels
like I'm sucking a lot of air because
you can't fill it up with smoke you can
only get so much dad I mean you're not
gonna carve it cuz you got the it's hot
it's hot as [ __ ] the nail is really hot
so that's why I use a small rig cuz I
don't want to smoke air I want to smoke
a phat dab right to my face I want just
enough water to cool it down I don't
need a whole lot of special percolation
just a basic perk is cool with me cuz I
just need that to cool it I'm not trying
to get really filtered like you do with
your cannabis I don't want to over
filter it I want to cool it down punch
it right to my head so that's why I use
a small rig the other question was about
dab size and how much hash my smoking
not me myself how much hash are people
smoking in a dab how much is what's a
serving size or a dose I'd start off
with like about a sesame seed size dab
maybe it's a piece of a relic a piece of
rice I think a piece of rice it's
probably about point zero two of a gram
so the average medical patient or the
average dab consumer is gonna take about
a point zero to two maybe like a point
one would be kind of a larger dab but
some people take up to 0.2 or 0.25 you
know just depends on what you're getting
into and how big you like to do I did a
little bit of math there are 28 grams in
an ounce and if you get a 20% return
that turns into 5.6 grams of hash
basically smoking a point to dab is the
equivalent of smoking one gram of herb
in one hit by yourself so you can go
anywhere from point two point zero 2 all
the way up to point two with your dad's
I've done a grand before but I wouldn't
recommend it don't do that my lungs are
still [ __ ] up from it they never will
be the same I don't think from taking
too large of a dab several times not
just once but I didn't over and over
again I think I hurt myself another
thing to think about is it takes a lot
more heat to heat up a big fat dab than
it does to heat up a little dab so just
take a bunch of little dabs and it
requires a little bit less heat and your
lungs don't get all that heat in there
yeah I say that but then I look over at
my dabber and I've got a big gigantic
dad sitting there waiting for me I'm
gonna take a big dab I'll answer one
more Twitter question they were gonna
give thanks and start wrapping up the
show all right I hope you guys enjoyed
that dab I sure did my last question
from Twitter is what is with this 7 10
what a 710 mean well 710 is nice and
simple if you turn the number 710 upside
down spells the word oil if you've been
listening oil is all about the dabs in
one of my earlier episodes I mentioned
that if somebody sent me a tweet with
who coined the phrase 710 that I would
send them some stickers as a prize
somebody actually tweeted me the correct
answer maybe it was on Instagram but you
sent the correct answer you just need to
give me your mailing address so that I
can send you those stickers the correct
answer was tasks Rock and the guys from
health stone
so now we're gonna give thanks and then
we're gonna wrap up the show here we go
this episode we're gonna give thanks to
my friend Big D Daniel Desai I don't
think the hash movement and the 7:10
community could be where it is today
without the help of Big D Big D was the
founder of top shelf extracts he's a
cannabis Cup winner
Big D actually gave me my very first
real dab at the Cannabis Cup at the
Broadway wellness booth when we had the
first cup here in Denver at the expo so
I wouldn't be the dabber I am today I
wouldn't be able to give you this info
today without the inspiration and the
help from Big B Big D is the host of the
secret cup the secret cup is a secret so
I'm not gonna tell you too much about it
but it is a dab competition they host
regional competitions they have a Finals
and then they also have the national
championships as a hash competition bush
it's a secret that's going on right now
Big D's in California working his ass
off I hope you get to hear this big
thanks much love one year four seven ten
Big D hosted an event called the dads of
Denver he had a bunch of raffle items to
give away and he sold raffle tickets
they threw a big fat show at the
oriental theater where we were able to
dab out and have a real community event
there were a bunch of people there that
night and there was also a huge raffle
and Big D donated all the proceeds to a
local care center so that they could buy
a van to get all of the disabled folks
to their doctor's appointments to let
make their lives a little bit easier
that's just one example of the awesome
things that Big B does for people he's a
big guy he's got a big heart so we want
to give him a big thanks we love you Big
D much thanks from the iGrow culture
show and the entire 710 community big
thanks to Big D thank you everybody for
joining me for the dab episode it's kind
of a short episode this time but it's
just me so it makes it easier you guys
don't want to listen to me for a full
hour
now that the show's over please go to
iTunes search for iGrow culture and
leave a little comment in the box let us
know what you think of the show and also
give us a five star review I'd really
appreciate it also you can find the show
now on iTunes stitcher or on swell a.m.
and you can also listen to the show on
the IRA genetics Colorado website
there's a little tab right there to
listen you can find every episode on
there make sure you go check out
Treehugger com make sure you check out
slick pad calm and don't forget codeword
podcast at nature's drain remedies for
15% off and they just got a refill on I
read genetics product so make sure you
go check them out they got that black
cherry chem in stock right now so go
take a look also make sure you follow
agriculture on Facebook Instagram and
Twitter thanks for listening guys take a
phat dad give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you