welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 189 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're the
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross
the jeboa thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots bank letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic
root crew
I know if everybody's smoking on
something delicious with me I hope
you're rolling up a fat joint hope you
got a blunt Twisted Fate you're smoking
some shatter
today tonight I am smoking some
apothecary extracts lemon Jeffrey live
batter I picked this up at a dispensary
in Colorado Springs called elevations
big shout out to everybody at elevations
today was my first time there it was an
amazing visit everybody was super kind
to me some familiar faces and some new
friends I highly recommend them
elevations in Colorado Springs fair
pricing good products and a super
friendly staff somebody let them know I
said that let them know they got a huge
compliment please big shout out to
everybody there's treated very well by
everybody people I knew and people I
just met all treated me like a rockstar
is [ __ ] great
so big shout out to apothecary extracts
they ran this lemon jeffrey live batter
this stuff was delicious you guys I was
at the dispensary around four o'clock
this afternoon and this gram that I'm
holding in my hand this package is
completely empty that's how delicious
this hash was I just kept taking dabs
because it tastes amazing it tastes just
like the lemon Jeffrey flowers they had
lemon Jeffrey flowers on the shelf you
guys the flowers were beautiful they
were perfectly trimmed they were nice
and frosty they were bright green just
like lemon Jeffrey should be done big
shout out to our friends at elevations
in Colorado Springs also huge shout out
to apothecary extracts good great work
guys everybody did great work the grou
had to be amazing because the material
is amazing and this hash is delicious by
the time this episode comes out I assure
you this product will be sold out over
elevations but check them out they've
always got amazing products on the shelf
also check out wherever you can find a
drop of apothecary extracts live resin
live butter live batter I highly
recommend it nice work woody good work
bro you're doing a great job also shout
out to Brandon for take good care of me
today so let me explain something here I
said bad or right I said live batter
people are probably going what's he
smoking live batter so this is hash this
was a live resin I got to keep backing
up steps because the more stuff I say
the more stuff I realize I need to
explain so these plants the plants that
made this material were cut down and the
big leaves were taken off anything with
trichomes were left on there those buds
were frozen that frozen bud was
delivered to an extraction company that
extraction company ran it while it was
still frozen through a closed loop
butane system i says here solvents
butane so this was ran with and butane
is what it was made with so they ran it
through probably a
Motech machine or something similar in
obidos ran it through there with
n-butane while it was frozen then it
came out very all of the terpenes were
still intact that's what I'm trying to
say it came out very turfy all of the
Terps were still there all of the flavor
was still there why are they calling it
live resin live resin is when the plants
are cut down and frozen and we run them
frozen that's what live resin is why are
they calling it live batter is what I
should get to it looks like cake batter
you guys it's got the consistency of
cake batter it's not quite as runny as
cake batter but it's thick and battery
it's got a really interesting and unique
consistency to it
a long time ago we might not have
approved of this a long time ago we
might have said this look too bad but
the new tech makes it look delicious so
big shout out to everybody I've just
kissed their ass for a good solid
minute-and-a-half but I completely
approve of this I bred the lemon Jeffrey
so when I saw that apothecary had ran it
and turned it into batter I had to go
get it
so big shout out everybody did a great
job I did a great job of smoking this
gram it was delicious
I'm glad I picked up several shout out
much love I'm gonna move forward ladies
and gentlemen I've been putting out old
episodes of the podcast in chunks of
three that's right I've got some OCD my
OCD comes in groups of three so you're
getting podcasts in groups of three also
they're about an hour long so that
3-hour chunk is kind of what my
recording software and where I post my
podcast they don't really handle longer
than a 3-hour episode so you're getting
three hour chunks of three episodes I
hope you're enjoying those I put them
out every Thursday if you haven't caught
on go listen uh episodes one through
nine are available now in three
different chunks so I've been doing a
new episode on Monday an old episode on
Thursday a new episode on Monday old
episode on Thursday I'm going to try to
do that as long as my schedule will
allow like I announced done a few
episodes back I am now the lead
cultivator through for Three Rivers
organics in Pueblo West that keeps me
completely busy I also have the podcast
I have got my own garden I'm a father
I'm a person I've got a social life of
course I need to eat and sleep and take
care of myself I got to take care of my
health I take care of my mind so I do
stay busy I will try to get all the
episodes out to you I have promised you
YouTube videos I'm working on the
YouTube videos it takes a lot of work to
make a damn youtube video with iMovie
I'm getting them done they will be up
there I'm gonna put those up in chunks
because like I said you people are
savage
and when I put out new content you
consume it immediately and then you beg
for more I want to have more for you
lined up I don't want to put out stuff
and then not have anything ready for the
people that are savages so be patient
with me I will get that stuff out there
next on the agenda I want to talk about
t-shirts and hoodies that's right I
still have a few girl from your heart
podcast hoodies available I've only got
bigger sizes I've got large extra-large
and possibly extra extra-large and maybe
even triple X it depends on when you
email me if you're interested in one of
those send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I'd love to put a
hoody on you they are affordable
shipping on them is kind of expensive
because I shipped them in one of those
priority mail boxes that is a little bit
pricey but it's well worth it I will get
you one also coming very soon ladies and
gentlemen grow from your heart podcast
t-shirts the hoodies let me describe the
hoodies the hoodies have the girl from
your heart podcast logo on the left
breast and it is smaller it does not
have my face it just has the EQ bar and
it says grow from your heart podcast on
the back however it's got the logo quite
large with my cheesy face on there just
like the logo you see on itunes that is
on the hoodies on the t-shirts
it says grow from your heart on the
front without my face it's got the logo
that does not have my face I don't like
wearing a shirt with my face on it I
want to be able to wear a girl from your
heart podcast t-shirts so on the front
it's got the logo does not have my face
nice and bright it's got the EQ bars
that are red gold and green so I can
keep the Rasta colors in there all the
girl from the heart podcast logo is
Rasta colored it's red yellow and green
then on the back you guys on the back
centered on the back across the
shoulders it says take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me so those
t-shirts will be here hopefully this by
the time this episode comes out
hopefully those t-shirts will arrive
shadow to our friends at handmade
apparel for making me more t-shirts
they're very affordable if you're
interested in a t-shirt or a hoodie
please send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com big shout out
to my friend Kelvin Medina as soon as I
told him I had t-shirts available he
placed an order for two for himself and
one for his son much love much respect I
appreciate that I love the support
allright t-shirts are come in hoodies
are here if you want one email me grow
from my heart at hotmail.com next on my
agenda before we get to the main topic
let me tease the main topic before I
keep up boring you let me get your
attention to make sure you keep
listening that's how you're supposed to
do it right this is going to be episode
number 3
of the common garden pests and issues
part three this episode we're going to
talk about thrips
that's what we're gonna talk about is
the garden issue thrips come seems like
if you buy soil you get thrips for free
and most soil these days so we're gonna
talk about how to take care of that let
me keep moving on with the pre-show
stuff that I like to cover and then we
will get into the handling thrips talk
where was I patreon that's right patreon
I talked about patreon quite often
ignored patreon for a couple episodes so
that people didn't get sick of it let me
tell you what patreon is patreon is a
service that allows you as a listener to
contribute to the podcast financially if
you feel like this podcast was worth a
dollar of your time you can go to
patreon.com/scishow from your heart and
you can sign up to contribute to the
girl from your heart podcast I'm not
trying to get rich off podcasting you
guys i podcast because i love it
my podcast cuz i can't shut up i podcast
because I love cannabis and I can't shut
up about cannabis I was sitting at the
table with Maddy and Spence and a bunch
of the crew a long time ago and people
would ask me questions about growing and
I caught myself repeating myself saying
the same [ __ ] over and over to people I
thought I should just record this and
when somebody asked me this question I
can tell them hey go listen to number
seventy four of my podcast and you can
learn this and I just love talking about
cannabis and I love podcasting I love
communicating with people I want
everyone to grow good weed so that's why
I do the podcast the reason I'm asking
for financial support is because it does
cost me money you guys the equipment
cost money to upkeep I'm always having
an equipment failure or something always
[ __ ] breaks technology always breaks
down on you it's kind of a [ __ ] also my
website I region etics Colorado comm is
where I host the podcast it does cost a
little bit of money since I'm putting up
one episode on Monday and another three
up three hour episode on Thursday I'm
using up a lot of bandwidth so I'm
paying for a large service package it
cost me a little bit of money to keep
that website up every year so I'm just
asking for help to offset the cost of
that I will pay for it out of my pocket
if I need to this is one of my favorite
things to do I love doing it but if you
guys would like to help I would
appreciate it I'm not begging
I'm just saying hey I could use a hand
I'm doing you a favor it'd be cool if
you did me a favor and if you can't help
me out I still love you I love you just
for listening to the podcast and being
there thank you I love you for
supporting
I love you for wanting to know more
about cannabis don't feel like you need
to give me something for me to like you
I like you just for being there so
thanks some folks can contribute some
folks contacted me and they're like hey
man you helped me out a lot what can I
do for you folks like that patreon is
there for them if you want to I'm not
begging alright so now I want to move on
to reading a couple of iTunes comments I
haven't read iTunes comments in a couple
of episodes and I've got two great new
comments I'm gonna take a big deep
breath and slow down I feel like I'm
talking really fast so here we go
alright sometimes you've got to calm the
[ __ ] down right and get Zen not even get
ahead at that moment out so this first
comment that I want to read comes from a
person who calls themselves will grow
freely they left the comment on February
27th their comment was titled touch of
green of course they gave me five stars
and it goes like this this is an awesome
show I look forward to new episodes
coming out every Monday jeff puts a lot
of time and energy into making every
episode and it shows as someone from a
prohibition state it's great to hear
about growing and cannabis culture so
that i can keep tabs on what's happening
in the free world
white Mike rules as well you hear that
Mike you just got a shout out bro white
Mike rules as well best cannabis podcast
out there by far it will grow freely I
appreciate that several people have told
me I'm the best cannabis podcast out
there I'm not in any competition but I
completely appreciate hearing that
because some of my heroes have podcast
about cannabis so knowing that my heroes
you're telling me that you like me more
than the people that have inspired me
that means a lot to me although I don't
find competition in their support all
the cannabis podcast who learned
something different from everybody
that's why I list I listen to their
podcast I try not to listen to too much
of the other podcast I can listen to
bone Ellis because she doesn't uh
contaminate my thought process but if I
listen to the dude grows and Adam Dunn
show too much I feel like they kind of
contaminate my podcast I end up doing
their show it's like if I if a musician
if I'm a drummer I feel like if I listen
to Led Zeppelin all day and then I play
my drums I sound like Led Zeppelin so I
don't listen to the dude grows too
frequently I do listen of course I
listen to the dude grow show but I can't
listen religiously because I start
talking like Scotty and I start talking
like the dude so I can't listen to too
many of the cannabis podcasts but I do
listen to him and if I listen to Adam
Dunn podcast I get to
sucked into the topic that they're
talking about I want to research it then
I want to do it on my show and I feel
like I'm just ripping them off and
that's not fair so I do listen I just
can't because I don't I feel like if I
listen to the same comedians all the
time I start telling their jokes I don't
want to do that to the podcast I want to
keep it mind
how the hell did I get way out there I
was talking about being the best podcast
yeah I listen to them all I don't I
don't want the competition but thank you
that's really cool we'll go freely thank
you for the five-star comment I
completely appreciate that I'm glad that
you are appreciating the culture part it
feels like you're here with me is what
I'm trying to do I want you to know that
we're dabbing I want you to know what
we're doing I want you to know about the
events we're going to only don't know
about the equipment we're using so what
I'm trying to do is keep you in the
loops of thanks for noticing and super
thanks for the comment the next comic
comes from somebody who calls themselves
KC CB 68 the title other comment was
sets the standard they left the comment
on February 27th and of course they gave
me another five-star rating the comment
is short and simple and it goes like
this
Jeff has an elite knowledge of cannabis
horticulture and doesn't push brands I'm
glad that you noticed that um there was
another podcast that kind of inspired me
to do a show every time somebody would
say hey I've got a problem they would
say go buy this product and spray it all
over your plants problem solved and I
feel like that was not a real solution
yeah your that's a band-aid
you've got spider mites spray floor
might you don't have spider mites
anymore
for about 45 days but in 45 days you're
gonna get spider mites again because you
did not correct the issue
I don't push brands I push solutions I
push logic I push passion so thank you
for noticing Matt an elite knowledge of
cannabis horticulture I can I use that
in my resume that sounds [ __ ] good
dude thank you
dude dude at KCC b68 is very uh that's
uh that's open that can be open gender
so I appreciate that comic dude and or
dudette you could be both nowadays I
guess right I'll I didn't just embarrass
you saying that that's awkward but
anyway thank you for the great comment
I'm gonna use that in my resume and
elite knowledge of cannabis horticulture
and I do not push brands I try not to
I've been approached by brands that want
me to advertise on the show and I I try
not to do it because I don't want it to
affect my advice so you guys thank you
for the comments if anybody wants to
leave in iTunes comment I would truly
appreciate it all you have to do is go
to I
toons go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast scroll
down to the bottom click on the girl
from your heart a podcast logo then
there's a little section it says ratings
and reviews you'll find where to write a
review you'll also find a word it put in
some stars so far everybody has given me
a 5-star rating I encourage you to click
on the amount of stars you feel I truly
deserve I would appreciate it and I will
also read your comment on a future
episode I'm sure you guys can hear the
dryness in my voice so I'm gonna press
pause for a second take a quick drink
and I'll be right back we will get to
the point of this podcast
all right podcast world I took a couple
more dabs and I took a couple of drinks
and I am ready to talk about our next
garden issue let's talk about thrips and
how to identify eradicate and prevent
getting thrips in your cannabis garden
let's talk a little bit about thrips
before we talk about getting rid of them
thrips are ugly [ __ ] you guys
thrips are barely visible to the naked
eye they're super tiny you need a
microscope to see them you need a
magnifying glass to see them you will
probably never see them but you will see
the damage that they leave in your
garden you'll see their honeydew you'll
see their poop you'll see their effects
so let's talk about the adults adults
have wings but they don't fly what kind
of [ __ ] bug is that it's got wings
that doesn't fly so if you see a bug
with wings it doesn't fly and your
magnifying glass it is probably possibly
a thrip sometimes they jump I've read
that thrips jump I've never seen this
personally because they're so small I've
never seen it happen thrips have yellow
or brown heads and bodies ah
they are yellowish brown they look uh
there's ugly there's ugly little nasty
little bugs they attack the leaves and
they're often found on the surface of
your leaves honestly you guys the number
one way that I think I have gotten
thrips is by purchasing soil I can't
blame any specific brand of soil because
it's happened with more than one brand
what happens with soil is it's made by a
certain vendor you're buying soil brand
a soil brand B they're made by a vendor
and a certain warehouse in a certain
location maybe one's made in Colorado
one's made in Michigan one's made in
California but eventually they all end
up in a shipping warehouse together they
all get stacked together one of those
packages had bugs and just like any
other community the bugs spread
throughout all the dirt and now those
packs of dirt get put on a pallet they
get
to your local hydros shop and you buy
them and now you've got free thrips with
your dirt so it's a good idea to treat
for thrips right away I like to when I
transplant I like to soak a root root
drench all of my new transplants with
evergreen pyrethrum spray or a pyrethrum
drench I use 15 milliliters per gallon
of evergreen that's evergreen pie Ganic
mix that in with your water you can put
it in with your nutrients it can ph it
and then just soak your plants with it
soak the water soak that or soak the
soils what I'm trying to say and that
won't get rid of most of your soil bound
pests I would almost recommend doing
that again in about five days and
that'll if you they laid eggs in there
that will kill their eggs also that will
really help you out if you're gonna go
organics use some neem cakes some
karanji meal some neem meal in the soil
that will really help get rid of them in
the soil but I feel like a lot of the
thrips you buy them free with your dirt
they're like a bonus they're like a
prize in your cereal a lot of bugs come
that way so it's a good idea to treat
before you even see problems with drips
in a lot of soil especially now in the
springtime and in the summertime when it
gets warmer you will get a lot more bugs
when it's cold they die off there in the
dirt they're being hauled across the
country in the soil they're in the back
of a hydro shop in the cold there
they're gonna get cold they're not gonna
live through that but the eggs may so
you need to treat all right so you will
find them attacking the leaves in the
leaf surfaces they get up there and they
chew on the leaf surface they penetrate
the leaf surface and they suck out the
SAP and juices you guys that's what most
of these plant insects do they get in
there and suck out the life juice from
your plant they dehydrate your plant
they suck out all the nutrients they
suck out all the nourishment this slows
down the growth of most of your plants
this slows down the vigor this will
certainly slow down and decrease the
yield of your plants this will mess with
the amount of resin and your plants this
will mess with the flavor how does it
mess with flavor the plants will trigger
different terpenoids
and different cannabinoids because
they're under a stress response things
will be different you will see problems
that you didn't see before because
they're dealing with stress is so thrips
will leave like a white silver mark or
patches on your leaves we call this
honeydew it's their [ __ ]
they're biting into your leaves they're
sucking out the juice and then they're
leaving these little snail trails this
little glistening glittery they call it
a honeydew tray
it that's their [ __ ] that's their
secretions they're pooping all over your
plants and I find it to be completely
disgusting so you don't want thrips in
there they'll make your leaves look kind
of scab they'll make like you look
leaves just got beat up they'll make
everything ugly it looks like
something's been in there chewing on the
garden because it has it is thrips
sometimes you will see green or black
specks on the bottom sides of the leaves
quite often near the veins of the leaves
you got the main vein that runs down the
center of the leave then you got the
little veins that branch out you will
find a specks of green chunk or brown
chunk or black chunks underneath there
guess what that is you guys that is
thrip [ __ ] on your leaves you're gonna
make hash out of that and you're gonna
smoke thrip [ __ ] and it's gonna be
disgusting get rid of the thrips you
guys there's several ways to get rid of
them we're gonna talk about that here in
just a couple of seconds nobody wants to
smoke
thrips or thrip [ __ ] or thrip honeydew
that is gross let's get rid of these
bugs sometimes the damage looks a lot
like spider mites
but it gets a lot worse a lot more
quickly thrips can do a lot more damage
than a spider mite Russert mites are
probably more dangerous than through
trips but thrips can really destroy
things quickly thrips can kill gardens
commercial gardens have been shut down
and started over because of thrips so if
you see thrips if you suspect thrips you
need to get in there and you need to
take care of it very quickly how can you
prevent thrips just like most of the
other issues i've talked about you can
prevent thrips by having a clean sealed
environment you need a clean grow room
do not let your pets into the grow room
if you bring in new plants from another
grower if you bring in plants from a
dispensary treat those plants before
they are introduced to your main grow
have a quarantine area if I give you a
clone do not trust me I am a good grower
I am reputable you don't know where I
got clones from you don't know who I've
been cloning with you don't know whose
garden I've played in you don't know
whose dispensary grow I've been to you
don't know what grow store I went to and
who I brushed up against if I give you a
clone act like it's got bugs act like it
has powdery mildew treated accordingly
and don't introduce it to general
population until you are sure that it is
bug free so don't bring
clones in don't bring plants in without
treating them don't bring your pets into
the garden I've talked about how your
pets carry bugs don't bring them in
there treat your soil when you buy a new
soil when you put plants into it treat
it right away if those plants are
vigorous enough treat it with the
Evergreen peg annex and that will help
you get rid of soil bound pests also
don't travel from garden a garden if
you're in another garden take a shower
change your clothes don't drag the pests
around change your shoes don't were the
same shoes from one Garden to another if
you were recycling soil if you've got
soil in a compost area or if you've got
soil outside or if you've got soil in
your garage treat that soil as if it are
contaminated with bugs so get rid of the
bugs make sure you don't bring the
thrips in they're a pain in the ass all
right a prevention another way to
prevent thrips are the yellow and blue
sticky cards put the yellow ones up kind
of higher and the blue ones a little bit
lower they will certainly help you out
those are mostly going to let you know
that thrips are there and that you need
to treat harder or start stepping up
your pesticide or your beneficial insect
program your IPM program needs to be
stepped up so use the cards they will
let you know if you've got insects
showing up they are not going to catch
the large amount of the population
they're going to catch the few that fly
to the cards that travel to the cards
when you see those that lets you know
there are a lot more there that you need
to treat all right so the cards are a
great start
another thing you can do if you see the
bugs or you can do it as a preventative
you can use diatomaceous earth on the
top of your soil this only works of
course if you were using soil plants if
you're growing in hydro this is not an
option for you if you're using soil or
cocoa or soilless mix take the top of
the pot let it dry this is something
that Shawn taught us well Shawn at the
Shawn king Cola what's up dude also shot
it to Kelly I saw Kelly the other day I
was working I didn't have time to stop
and say what's up she saw me she was
working for to have time to stop and say
what's up but we waved what's up Kelly
hope you're doing well
shout out to killer Kelly and King Kola
Ross Kola you guys are doing well keep
it organic you guys so diatomaceous
earth when the soil dries sprinkle of
layer like just a thin layer of
diatomaceous earth across the entire top
of the soil surface you want to cover it
all now diatomaceous earth is really
coarse it's kind of sharp if you are a
soft bodied insect you don't want to
climb through that [ __ ] because it's
gonna call you up it's like trying to
watch a human climb through a bunch of
lava rocks while naked you're just gonna
get cut to [ __ ] it's not gonna be any
fun so the bugs don't want to climb
through the diatomaceous earth they
don't want to get in there the thrips
don't want to climb down in there they
don't want to go into the soil they
don't want to climb out they will die
diatomaceous earth is very effective on
a lot of insects that travel through
your soil that want to go from the
leaves to the soil they try to make like
a little Y like a little area like a
what does a traveler trade route is what
I want to call it
dad tenacious earth is great for those
types of bugs let the soil dry sprinkle
it on there once your plants need water
yes you can water them but it's most
effective to put it on there while the
plants are dry try to let it go for a
little while another great way to get
rid of thrips are beneficial nematodes
I've talked about beneficial nematodes a
lot of course I recommend a place called
RB Co organics to get your beneficial
nematodes if you want their website it
is RB CO ARB IC o----
- organics dot-com they do not sponsor
me I do not pitch them because they pay
me I advertise for them because they
send me a very helpful magazine in the
mail every three months and it tells me
which insects I should be using right
now for the weather for the environment
and it's very helpful I trust them and I
appreciate this company and they're very
affordable and reliable one thing I want
to mention and mentioned some beneficial
insects for other predator for other
problems
and I should tell you to pay attention
to which predators you're purchasing
because if you don't have the right
environment for them they will either
die or leave they will just scamper off
and go somewhere where the environments
right so when you were looking for
perhaps an aphid predator a food
predators that I'm the ones on this page
that I just happened to see it says here
they prefer 64 to 77 degrees with a
moderate to 70s percent humidity if you
don't have that environment you may need
a different beneficial insect because
those guys aren't gonna want to hang out
they're gonna take off and go where it's
better even if you've got food there
they don't like it if you've got all of
the good food if you've got all the
pizza and dr. pepper on the planet but
it's a hundred and two degrees I still
don't care about that pizza and dr.
pepper I'm gonna get the [ __ ] out and go
where it's about 75 degrees and I'll
find some dr. pepper and pizza there so
you may need the right environment for
your beneficial insects another thing
that you can do if you see these thrips
coming neem oil helps get rid of the
thrips but like I've talked about before
neem oil will to make your concentrates
taste like [ __ ] the other day I smoked
some concentrate from a dispensary and I
could taste the pesticides in it it was
not a pesticide it was an essential oil
I hid it and I went ooh
peppermint I didn't say anything out
loud but I passed it to somebody else
and they took a DAB and I go what do you
think of that and they said it tastes
like [ __ ] peppermint and I was like
all right it's not in my head you can
taste the essential oils on plants you
guys only use neem in veg if you're
going to use it at all another thing you
can use to get rid of the thrips is
spinosad spinosad is a fungus that
happens if they bottom of whiskey
barrels it is a product and off product
of fermentation you can spray it onto
the plants and it will destroy most of
the insects that are on there it'll take
down white flies and it'll certainly
take down full thrips
I called them flips in my head another
thing I like is evergreen pyrethrum or
evergreen pie Ganic it works as a spray
you can spray your plants with it and
you can drench the soil with it I feel
like if you do the combo if you put up
some yellow and blue sticky traps you
spray the plants with evergreen and you
root drench with evergreen everything
except the plant will die and that is
organic and it is not too harmful and if
you do it early in veg and one time
before flower you should not have a
problem with funky [ __ ] on your buds
when it comes time to harvest there
should be a full nine weeks between
spraying and harvest time hopefully
that's long enough hopefully you're not
[ __ ] up and spraying too heavily
concentrated of anything on there the
only thing I would really spray in
flower is like a compost tea maybe some
push I don't like hitting them a lot in
flower one one reason you don't want to
spray them when they're in flowers cuz
the buds start bulking up and the
moisture gets inside the bud you do run
the risk of promoting bud rot that's a
big reason why I talk about not spraying
in flower also you're gonna mess up the
flavor you're gonna mess up the taste of
those buds that you're growing for nine
weeks
why spray some [ __ ] on them [ __ ] up the
flavor when you can leave them the way
they are and it tastes super delicious
if you do it right
so what thing I just thought of that I
didn't say let the soil dry throw down
some dye Oh tenacious earth soaked with
the Evergreen spray with the Evergreen
put up the yellow and blue sticky cards
you should be golden you shouldn't have
any bugs that should get rid of most of
your bug problems
I hope unless you've got a serious
infest to infestation that should really
solve like 75% of your bug problems all
right guys of course another thing you
can do to get rid of your thrips are
pirate bugs there's a bug called theme
my new pirate bug the aureus insidious
the suckers ugly he eats
thrips white fly spider mites a fatale
kinds of other stuff you guys he loves
to get him in and eat stuff in your
garden he's a very versatile insect he
will thrive in an indoor and a
greenhouse he's something I highly
recommended also predatory mites the
sworsky mites that I recommended for
your spider mites will also work very
well on thrips all right you guys now I
hope you are able to identify thrips it
looks like a little [ __ ] been
crawling on your plants and [ __ ]
this shiny stuff and just chewing holes
in it kind of looks like there's glitter
on your plants maybe the leaves are
starting to curl up and wilt a little
bit they're starting to look dry in
certain patches maybe they're getting a
little bit crispy you've probably got
thrips in there it's time to give out a
magnifying glass it's time to identify
exactly what you've got it's time to
treat for probably thrips ladies and
gentleman I hope you learned a lot from
me on this episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friends at the dude
gross show the dude gross podcast gave
the girl from your heart podcast
Rasta Jeff specifically white Mike
specifically we all got personal huge
shout outs from the
dude grows show we were also given
personal invitations to the dude grows
evant ah myself white Mike the dab in
granny Lindsay the traveling stoner and
Chris also known as Bobo blaster Co
we're all given open invitations to come
to the dude grows event which is kind of
a private party that he is hosting I in
April dude if you were listening to this
dude and Scottie both much respect much
thanks I will be there I look forward to
it I'm going to bring my zoom h6 and I'm
going to try to record a podcast my goal
is just a record part of the event and
then I will send you the file and we
will both hopefully post it up as a
podcast together that's what I have in
mind so I'm gonna try to do that you
guys big shout out to my friends at the
dude gross show also since I'm spreading
love to podcasters I wanna give a huge
shout out to bone Ellis bone Ellis has
been giving me a lot of respect and I
want her to know that the respect is
completely returned much live to
everybody in the cannabis podcasting
community
I love seeing us come together I love
seeing us share information I feel no
intimidation I feel no there's no
competition I want it all to be a
community much love much respect
everybody spreading the word and
fighting the good fight for cannabis we
were all on one team and I appreciate it
I'd love to do a podcast with everybody
out there that's got a cannabis podcast
we can all get together and do shows and
expose each other's audience to each
other's audiences I think it'd be a
great thing to happen all right you guys
I would love to hear what you feel about
the podcast you can go to iTunes you can
leave me a comment on iTunes if you
don't want to do that you can find me on
the social media on Facebook search for
the girl from your our podcast on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast on
Instagram I use my company name it's
Irie underscore genetics I RIE
underscore genetics IRA is a Jamaican
word I pretty much means to be as
blessed as you could be or to feel as
good as you could feel I describe it as
a kind of that feeling when you're
sitting in the grass under a tree you
got your dog or your best friend sitting
next to you you got a fat joint in your
hand nothing's wrong the wind is blowing
just right in your hair the Sun is
setting it's nice and cool and
everything feels good
you got that inner peace feeling you
feel Irie just chilling not worried
about a damn thing everything Irie so
that's what I remains you guys Irie
underscore genetics is my Instagram I'd
love it if you followed me there if
you'd like to reach out to me and you're
not into the social media stuff
you can email me it's a girl from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you I would love to hear what
you have to say alright guys I'm gonna
wrap up this podcast oh when you give a
huge shout out to my friends Tim and
Charlie in New Mexico shout it to
everybody at org antica and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
the king
you
[Music]