yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 190 of the
growth from your heart podcast you're a
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Ross - Jeff wanna thank you guys again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you shout outs my friends
in the mystic roots man flood muse their
music on my podcast
big shout to cat coop and the entire
mystic reefs crew
Wow my timing was way off on that intro
I'm high as giraffe [ __ ] tonight damn I
hope nobody noticed until I pointed it
out jeez about halfway through I caught
on what was going on I smiled big
because I know there are people with
mouth and the intro word-for-word when
it happens it I was like today that [ __ ]
yeah I'm sorry Mike and I are hanging
out welcome to the show Mike
[Music]
it's a Sunday we're hanging out on a
Sunday evening it's hot as [ __ ] in
Colorado today already what's going on
it got super warm today and I took a lot
of dabs
I've been smoking this Apothecary
extract lemon Jeffrey live batter and
I'm [ __ ]
can we say [ __ ] yes I am [ __ ]
because my my my mental growth has been
slowed
[ __ ] right now that is true I can
use the word appropriately at this point
in time it was delicious you said lemon
candy and that was it exactly it was
like the yellow I just brain fart at the
type of candy any lemon candy lemon
heads bro lemon heads but not like super
strong it was just that nice it's almost
got a lemon head okay that's what
because it doesn't have that harsh yeah
it's also got kind of a lemon sorbet
like a ice cream sort of a thing
happened into it a sherbet sort of the
thing goes just a nice sweet lemon candy
and not maybe want to do stuff it made
me want to [ __ ] sit in a chair
[Music]
certain products effects certain people
differently based on our biology it's
such a neat thing it's one of my
favorite parts about cannabis is that we
are able to medicate ourselves
appropriately goodbye the products we
want my least favorite thing about that
though is the opposite this lemon
Jeffrey is not going to be available
forever there was only so much of this
kazoos and I was only able to buy so
much at this time and I'm sure that the
next time I go to this dispensary this
[ __ ] will be gone because I've been
hyping it up on Facebook everybody I've
smoked with smoked it with is driven to
the dispensary to buy some it's gonna be
gone that's frustrating it's uh you see
it in other industries a little bit like
they'll do a limited run shoe or a limit
album where it's special for whatever
reason but in the cannabis world man
beautiful stuff get one off this that's
just regular business how it goes you
show up at the dispensary and you're
like Oh lemon Jeffrey batter let me get
three grams of that and you go home and
you smoke it's [ __ ] delicious I'm
gonna stop by there Tuesday after work
and you go Tuesday there's another spot
fill that spot where the lemon Jeffrey
is filled with another product you're
like oh where did it go when I was
working the counter if someone said I
really like that I'd always make a point
to be like well we have 12 left just do
you know you're buying one which means
when you leave the store that will be 11
sitting here and you're welcome to come
back and buy as many of those as you'd
like but when they're gone they're gone
and when you come back after they're
gone there's a lot of times it's the
damn employees buying up all the good
[ __ ] - oh when it comes in you've got to
put it on the shelf so you're the first
one that sees what's amazing and what's
okay yep and then you get you sell it
and then the people come back and buy it
from you again they're like dude I
bought two grams of that I need like
seven more grams or give me my limit
that's always my favorite let me get my
limit and that yeah back in the day
there was a dispensary Mike and I would
travel up to they had vortex wax uh and
this take extra people with us like
here's your 250 yeah you get the limit
in this just say what I say they thought
I was dead Durbin poison and vortex like
all the time they consistently had those
two strains and I loved him they were
delicious and I'm sure they thought I
was flipping it but I was buying it and
smoking every bit of it myself no we
were just the first group of people they
ran into that was consuming at that
level I was driving it was in Denver and
I was driving 125 miles and sometimes
it'd be winter time and it would take me
two and a half hours to get to that
dispensary and you can't do that more
than once or twice a month when you're
working and have a life you know I'm
back and forth to Denver all the time if
I can cut a trip out or try to double up
what I'm doing in Denver for a trip I do
yes I used to go in there try to buy my
limit and then eventually they're like
seven grams only
so then I took Mike and Kevin then went
and got my mom a medical marijuana card
and took her to all the dispensaries
with me it's like come on mom you gotta
go help me buy a bunch of hash before
that we were this was before dabs were
so readily available now hash is just
abundant you can go everywhere and get
hash we and how long you think it takes
to get out to Three Rivers it's about 15
minutes out that way right rivers is out
in the county it's east of town yeah if
you're living a long ride 25 you're not
more than 20 minutes from it
there are ten dispensaries in Pueblo
West the spot I didn't want to choose it
one there's probably the most popular
out there 22 in 1200 count E and we're
about to get five more in the city Wow
five more in the city we've got one in
town now well there's we're gonna get a
trek shops in the city but three of them
are existing Med shops so I don't count
those as new yeah but still eight more
shops in the city where you can buy a
rack here in a couple months it's funny
that it has taken place so long to come
along to the shops in town yep since
Mike and I actually had we were partners
with another guy there was a guy who
didn't really want to be known too much
who had a dispensary he hired me as a
manager one day I he said what do I need
to do to make this place better and I
looked him straight in the face and I
said the best thing you could do would
just be to go the [ __ ] away he was a
great guy you guys don't get me wrong I
love Tom and he's a good dude he is not
somebody you need running a business you
need Tom outside of the business growing
weed but that it that there were so many
moving parts to that because like he
wanted to go live his dream on the
mountaintop and what he did that it
became perfection he's just a good old
southern boy and when they got hot in
the building he would prop the back door
open of the dispensary we've got two
security guards up front with guns
checking IDs we've got security between
myself in the front door but the back
doors propped wide open with a brick and
I'm like Tom this this defeats all of
our purpose here or walks over the walk
through the bedroom pull it turn it on
overhead fans
he goes through it turns on three fans
we got to tell the lobby all right you
guys gotta hold up for seven minutes
while these fans slow down
work our scales again but we had that
shop that was about ten years ago now if
you think about it it wasn't quite that
far back but nine eight or nine I think
we're it's seven now okay damn it feels
like a lot longer because we've got kids
well it's only been seven years but
that's like 35,000 pots
how many harvests is that so much Mike
and I had that building running like a
fine-tuned machine that was a super
machine we were making a lot of money in
that dispensary and they came to shut us
down and now they finally have figured
out how to do the rules they showed us
no because they weren't properly zoned
and hadn't made rules for us yet it was
the only reason they could give us they
that shop got shut down officially
because we were violating zoning rules
that they would officially pass like two
months later you guys we're super super
rambley let me give you this is gonna be
a bonus episode this is not a normal
Monday episode I'm still gonna put out
the long episode also I need to put that
together when we're done doing this but
good week for the fans gonna be a good
week for podcast listeners thank you
guys for listening I appreciate it
Mike's here to talk about some laws that
are coming up some proposed laws and
we're gonna talk about the rules here in
Pueblo County a few people recently have
asked me like how many plants can i grow
what are the rules how do I do it so I
wanted to go over some rules and of
course Mike is the guy that call for
that one yeah before we get that far we
got to do a couple things Mike tell
people how people can follow you stalk
you track you
find you hide me on the interweb on the
interweb yes tell about your tweeter and
tell them about your Facebook you can
check me out on twitter at at Nemo Punk
15 and he mo PU and k15 and then on
Facebook it's pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws make sure you check Mike
out support him on Facebook he posts a
lot of great stuff it's the easy way to
keep up on the news it is and it's the
truth micah is very good at searching
out the truth and filtering out [ __ ]
he won't share the [ __ ] with you
dude I was at a gas station yesterday in
kind of a small town and I was wearing
my hydrogen etics Colorado cannabis
t-shirt shado Tahiry genetics Colorado
whoever does that is a bad [ __ ]
but this girl at the counter she was a
young gullible young girl and she goes
hey you're winning a cannabis shirt and
there's like a line of people in the
store and I'm like oh [ __ ] here we go
and she goes have you seen the things in
Denver and McDonald's but the bubble
comes down you and you can get high in
the bubble and I was like that's why I
didn't I didn't want something like
that's not real like that's the Internet
sorry that's the onion sweetie yeah but
she she was pretty sure that that was
real she's like I want to go to Denver
and move to Denver just to see that it
was like holy [ __ ] people in little
towns that they'll believe anything dude
the level of misinformation is is
greater than ever and it seems like
people's willingness to double-check
[ __ ] is lower than ever yes we have so
many opportunities to check [ __ ] we
can call [ __ ] on so many things I've
got I've got a MacBook Pro in front of
me I've got an iPhone and to the right
of me I've got an old iPhone that's full
of pictures and still has Internet
access to the left of me there and there
I've got YouTube on my phone over there
I've got Explorer on my TV over there we
can do all kinds of [ __ ] nobody wants to
fact-checked nobody wants to double
check I mean even the president is
getting away with [ __ ] likes man oh my
cousin told me
it's what my advisers told me anyway
it's true big like true huge it's it's
what I heard it's what people are
talking about it it's what I
it's absolutely nuts just take two
seconds in and google it I got now an
argument one day over does America have
a national language
now I don't want to rehash any of that
mess and or but I mean it's a Google
thing like this is just something that
you can check there doesn't need to be a
debate you just check it just people
just don't like taking that extra Siri
will tell you you don't even have to
know how to type now you can hold down a
button and say all of your questions
into a device and either a lesson or
Siri will tell you yeah you don't even
have to think anymore um but for some
reason people just hate doing that even
there when they're real passionate about
stuff
basically the reason pueblos for
sensible cannabis laws exists is because
there's a group down here that's anti
cannabis everything and they were
getting a lot of press and
kind of making a little name for
themselves a couple years ago and I was
like well why don't I start a troll page
and so they're plepler for positive
impact so I started pueblos for sensible
cannabis laws it just started debunking
there they would put up a post and I
would just go through it line by line
and explain why that was total [ __ ] and
then take the two minutes it takes to
Google and pull the actual information
down my favorite part is the way that
they reply to you
they block Mike that's all the [ __ ]
can do they just block him every time
and if anybody supports Mike that person
gets blocked too and right when I
started doing this somebody told them
that if they share my post more people
like my page will be seen by more people
and so they screenshot instead it's
somewhere there's an anti pot kook with
like thousands of screenshots of
everything that I posted this page good
but that's kind of where that Facebook
page started in one of the things that
you'll notice if you try to check out
any anti cannabis stuff online is their
total inability to give
they'll cite a study they'll say so you
know a new study said this but they
won't tell you which new study or who
conducted it or where it was published
because even when they're citing an
actual number
it typically doesn't mean what they're
saying it means I mean even nationally
it's I can't it was did they get in
trouble for a campaign that they
couldn't support their facts that they
were posting they did get they didn't
necessarily get in trouble but they they
created a lot of really I
mean I honestly think it helped more
than it hurt they blanketed this city in
big mailers leading up to the election
every day you would get a new anti pot
nonsense mailer with your junk mail and
the closer we got to the election the
more insane the the argument became and
so even people that were like wow did
you read this honey this is you know
maybe we should be thanked this
ninety-nine attend pot growers eat
babies for breakfast yeah but by the
time the election showed up people were
even when they were started out on the
anti pot side they were sick of getting
these in their mail every day and the
people that were reading them were
finding just I mean even a quick glance
at him by the end it was like this is
clearly ludicrous like nine out of ten
doctors aren't out advocating against
legalization like we would have noticed
that there's a lot of doctors like that
seems like a parade amount worth of yeah
there was a women's March and it was on
TV we saw it right yeah that [ __ ] didn't
happen when a whole bunch of people are
pissed about something
people tend to notice we've kind of
given them too much publicity so [ __ ]
that group check out Mike's group yep
and so that's what I mean that page is
all about and just double check your
stuff people this it's more important
now than ever that the cannabis
community get on the ball and not I mean
I get it most people don't have an extra
20 minutes a day to be like oh okay I'm
gonna double check that figure out what
what exactly is going on here and then
post the actual information online so I
do all that work for you you just have
to come read it and share it there you
go and share it that's all you gonna do
when you get information from Mike share
it click share clicking share is the way
you counter bad information is by
spreading good information yeah like
that's the truth what we do the show is
just good grow information so that more
people grow better weed some people just
don't want to know the truth they don't
want to be walk wrong they've said
something and they don't want to change
their opinion even after they're
educated some people you just can't fix
but that's just some people so my big
laugh of the week did you catch the
story about the federal study marijuana
how shitty it is oh it's got mold in it
and [ __ ] I glanced over that one
basically what they're doing is taking
the plant growing it out and there's
stuff and the whole [ __ ] thing at a
woodchip or freeze drying it and calling
it study product it's just what the [ __ ]
it's just
what so what do you think the government
would pay a master grower to come read
and I didn't mean to just call myself a
master I know the title in the industry
that's why this was the laughs of the
week cuz cuz when I saw that article I
chuckling I was like they need to be
listening to the show yeah come on down
listen I want to go apply for the job
I'd go work at that [ __ ] farm in
Mississippi and grow the dankest buds
ever and then show them what's really
going on you know get him up to speed
going into a 6-month console-like just
show him how to try yeah yeah 420 bees I
want the amount of property they've got
out there's intense and if you watch
some of the Sanjay Gupta footage from
his weed special where they go out and
film at the farm
they've got all the parts yeah they just
don't have a pot grower there's just
yeah they don't have a pot growers
they've got a researcher and who knows
what kind of genetics they've got - oh
they got some Mexican bang seed that is
just a herm and they don't know what the
[ __ ] they're doing at all no they don't
know they know phenotype selection no
fee no hunting nope man they really
don't know what's going on and it it
honest-to-god looks like they're taking
the plant they might be drying it before
it goes into the wood chipper but it's
going through a wood chipper shredded
stock seed materials honest material no
joke honest at the end of every two or
three days I run a wood chipper at the
big grow to get rid of all the sticks
and stalks and dead leaves and it just
turns it into [ __ ] there's nothing there
that could be tested or useful at the
end of all that what the hell there you
had the freeze drying it and then drying
it
yeah
we make live resin I'm not sure exactly
what happens when you freeze dry it
yeah I don't do that to my cannabis
please no but the stuff coming out of
the University of Mississippi Farm is oh
good if you didn't see that story this
week folks go check it out have a good
laugh shout it to the farmers that
respect cannabis from beginning to the
end of the grow yeah so anybody who's
trying to do overriden trying to do
better since I'm doing shoutouts mmm
let's get to this part the dude gross
show big shout out to the dude and
Scottie Mike and I received personal
shoutouts on the dude grows podcast Mike
hasn't been here since then this the
first time he's joined me I get a lot of
shoutouts everyone's like shot - Ross -
Jeff bone Ellis gives me some shoutouts
the dude goes give me a shot he gives me
shoutouts I [ __ ] loved hearing
shoutouts to my crew on other podcast
that's really cool bo gives you shot
outs big shout out to bone Ellis at the
spliff podcast and also huge super huge
shout out to everybody at the dude grow
show the dude grow show has some loyal
fans I don't know what the fans are
called but they as soon as they said
shout out to Ross - Jeff my phone
started going
like bro listen to the new drugs listen
to the dude gross you got it I've got an
email it says you should listen to the
dude gross hey they just invited you to
a party listen to this check this out I
was like something just happened because
my phone just started blowing up when I
was working in the girl I was like who
died he's like I got so many messages
all at once but they've got a great fan
great following a great fan club man
thanks for all of the love from the dude
bro show because they reached out and
invited us they're a little private
party I will be there I'm going to do my
best to be there I'm gonna go dab out
with those guys I'm gonna take the zoom
h6 and two microphones and I'm gonna try
to get those guys on a microphone I know
they're throwing a party and they're not
gonna be focused on doing a podcast I'm
showing up I'll just bring a little
small recording device and a couple mics
and I'll just catch them when they're
walking by hey what's up guys I talked
him to the mic for a couple of seconds
and then I'll try to catch a bunch of
stuff from there and piece it into a
show and then maybe they'll run it in
their feet also that's kind of what I'm
thinking hoping for yeah I haven't
wanted to go to a canvas event in a
minute like I've just been too busy to
even consider it and when I heard that
piece on the show I was like I need to
find out more and go yeah you're not
like the the social butterfly you don't
go to a lot of the dab events I wasn't
super social before I had a kid and I'm
just - yeah
my kids getting fun she's old enough to
be social and we can hang out and kick
it and wait till you get there I met the
like it's it's he's getting so much more
mobile and so like that I always called
it like babies or suicidal yeah that I
can't climb off the side of this and
survive the fall thing it hasn't been
learned yet and he's getting to the
point where like now it's really
dangerous like he can make it from one
side of the house to the other in a
heartbeat yeah I was tired as ever now
there's like 15 fatal [ __ ] options
between you and that 15 feet that he
just made a friend of ours just had a
kid and I saw a post like the fourth or
fifth day the kid was in the world it
was like wow I'm tired and I just
started cackling hysterically like I
lost it for a couple of minutes and just
had a laugh so Mike's gonna get a
babysitter yeah and he's gonna come -
dude gross party with me and then
Lindsay and Chris have a project they
were invited the traveling stoner Abobo
blastic oh they have something that's
happening that day I'm not sure if they
can make it if the party wait they'll
come but they have something else going
on in the day it's their business to
announce I'll let them drop bad news on
the show and the time comes
it's really cool talking about it's a
[ __ ] really cool project they're
working on davon granny granny I've
reached out to you a little bit but I've
been so busy and so have you
Gale you've been invited to this party
what the dude grows I would like you to
come I know you listen to the podcast
this is the easiest way to reach
yes yes the dude grows want you to come
to the dude grows party it's a private
party if you can go let me know and I
will set everything up we've been our
crew has been invited to be judges for
their cannabis event so we get a judge's
pack we're invited to the event I'm sure
we'll be treated like [ __ ] rockstars
they were pretty excited to invite us
there thank you guys for the event if
you're if you guys listen to the show I
heard them say that they do listen and
that they've built soil with me and
they're here before so that's that's
good to know that I love that my other
podcasts are listening to each other I
love that there's no sense of
competition or anything like that
there's enough podcasting and enough
listeners for everybody
my favorite part is that I hear a lot of
people say as soon as I run out of Rogen
episodes I listen to you and I'm like
that's [ __ ] cool I have no qualms
with being second to Joe [ __ ] Rogan
because it's if you look at my podcast
list in my phone
then put seriously nine hours of content
a week minimum sometimes twelve or
fifteen hours of content thanks Larry
there's a couple of guys that do that
that I'm like how do you how can you
possibly find the time you've got to
spend I mean half a week in front of a
microphone he's Joe Rogan and he's he
just says on it on it on it and then
they just paid his money and he says
stamps calm stamps calm and then they
pay his rent and then he goes Dollar
Shave Club and then they send him a
Porsche so that's how Joe Rogan [ __ ]
does it honestly it's a whole different
world
yeah yeah and I'm cool with dude I grow
from my heart so I'm all about seeing
pictures of the plants that people grew
with the advice I gave them that's the
Porsche that I get out of this honestly
it's lemon Jeffrey like something
special happened like in the middle I
love seeing stuff I watched you breed
and I was sitting around this table
while we were smoking Levin Jeffrey when
it was still I don't remember what it's
cereal was but it was a
basically a judge's pack here's your
sample pack from this you know phenom
huh yeah which which three or the top I
remember when lemon Jeffrey was in a
hunt and here we are a couple years
later seeing it grown by someone else
totally unrelated to the crew in any way
processed by people totally unrelated to
the crew in any way and it's just
phenomenal product yeah apothecary did a
great job with this the grow at elevated
was beautiful the product they showed me
it was amazing it is neat to see it come
the lemon Jeffrey is in a lot of
commercial facilities nowadays I'm
impressed with that words out on that
one in the arrives for sure arise yes
arise in New Mexico like arises the
number one strain in New Mexico right
now I never wanted to go back to New
Mexico and then I saw a lab test and was
like well [ __ ] it oh
yeah so if you were in Albuquerque New
Mexico and you shop at organic ax there
will be more arise seeds very soon I
apologize for the delay that was
partially it was all my fault wasn't
partially my fault was all my fault I
needed more packaging printed and my
printer that I was working with failed
me so I had to go into the route and
it's been done shout out to the people
that came through yes yes [ __ ] Kinkos
dude like I tried to support a small
business all day long but
sometimes it's hard to have your friends
do work for you because when they [ __ ]
it up you can't like not pay them cuz
they're your friends and you don't want
to [ __ ] up your friendship so I I've
chosen to just go to large businesses
and let them do it right the first time
it's better unless it's something that's
already in their wheelhouse look I know
when I get ready for an email I'm going
to someone that's in the circle yeah
yeah I'll guide you through that there's
there's a couple of different things
like that where we know somebody who's
just does it out of this world
just go to the shop that's known for
doing it our friends that elevate at
5:17 South Tejon will take very good
care of you if you need a new email if
you needed a break they don't even pay
me anymore they did yes they did sponsor
the show in the past they hooked me up
with glass they gave me good discounts
at the store we did some advertising for
each other I was there yesterday I did
not pay them to be nice to me they were
[ __ ] super kind to me they gave me
really good deals they sold us quality
products I like shopping there they play
good music they have the elevat-- dolls
and turtle turtles there he's a turtle's
cool [ __ ] dude
he's an elevated all uh and they've
they've hired a couple of dudes he used
to be all ladies there but they've hired
a couple of dudes now the two dudes that
were there yesterday super kind funk
Becca the owner super cool lady 517
South a home that's where I would
recommend you go buy an email if you're
in Colorado Springs the Colorado Springs
area go there tell him Rasta Jeff sent
you tell me listen to the girl from the
heart podcast I give turtle a fist bump
check out all the cool panties you know
that penny with the two elephants on it
you could buy that [ __ ] send it to me
yeah
I'll calm that thing's [ __ ] dope dude
and I was like gonna buy that but I just
that's why
I've got other stuff I need to spend
money on
4/20 is gonna be awesome in my world
because so many things are wrapping up
at the beginning April like for me it's
not like a celebration thing it's like a
freedom thing so many things will be
checked off the do list and the save up
for list and that I shouldn't do that
because of this list by these like the
first week April when that's cashed in
oh I'm it's gonna be fun I'm gonna drop
a bunch more myself nice
I'm almost there also yep two items two
toys for myself it's always fun we could
buy expensive toys I want to buy them at
the same time so they kind of go
together I'm like yeah I'm just gonna
buy them just upgrade my life a little
bit yeah buy these two new toys gonna be
dope we kind of I kind of drifted from
telling granny that she should come to
the dude gross party a granny you've
been invited let's be judges we get a
judge's pack it'll be [ __ ] cool Mike
came over because we wanted to talk
about some rules and some laws that are
happening in Colorado there are new
proposed laws its SB 1220 that is the
trying to limit the planet count to 16
plants per household unless you were in
an agricultural area
zone a glance special so if you're at
anything that's zoned residential which
is the majority of housing in Colorado
period
so if you're a medical marijuana patient
and you've got a plant count for 24
count for 24 plants doesn't matter 18
plants doesn't matter 18 that's it
that's all you can have sorry 16 is
denied it's 16 is the new proposed
statewide limit in this bill already
made it through that the House of
Representatives in Colorado it started
out as a 12 plant limit I'm after like
nine and a half hours of testimony they
upped it to 16 and dropped the penalties
for breaking these rules from felony to
misdemeanor
and then the bill made it through
another committee it is now sitting in
front of the Colorado Senate so it could
get changed some more in the Senate
before it heads to the governor and the
governor is excited he wants this little
bit bad right Wow he's a beer guy right
that's not the only reason
extended plant counts became the
scapegoat
for marijuana regulation about I'm gonna
interrupt you just a little bit here but
I apologize for it I just want to
explain everybody what an extended plant
count is okay in the state of Colorado
we are allowed to grow six plants as an
adult as an adult 21 or over you're
allowed to grow six plants of
recreational cannabis if you get a
medical marijuana card the original rule
was that you were allowed to grow six
plants this was the default limit is six
plants right if you have a debilitating
condition that the doctor feels you
require more cannabis or your delivery
system requires more cannabis to treat
the conditions you were treating for
they can write you what's called an
extended plant count which would it
allow you to grow more plants to produce
the amount of medicine that you need to
take care of yourself that's an extended
plant count these extended plant counts
are now being scrutinized and they're
being kind of vetoed by other well
there's a whole lot of history and other
rules and stuff going on that kind of
led to the practice but in Colorado
extended plant counts basically 99 was
that the biggest card that that
anybody's written in the last several
years before that there were a couple of
doctors that were doing five hundred
holy [ __ ]
and
for the most I mean the the numbers of
people with cards that are over twenty
four was I mean it was like twenty five
people across the state tiny amount of
people my number has dwindled down and
I've got a good relationship with my
doctor back in the day I could walk in
and get a good number and now my number
is not as impressive as it used to be
the two two years before this last visit
my my to visit or so the last visit and
then the one before that the one before
that their earliest - when I walked in
he was like you want your normal count
yep gave me the extended plant count I
had before didn't bat an eyelash right
not an issue his dogs farted in the
office a couple times yep but anybody
that's gone to that doctor knows who I'm
talking about - oh my god half the
people in Pueblo and Springs have been
to this doctor he brings his [ __ ]
dogs and they fart in the office and it
smells like death yes most definitely
but I mean it wasn't a news just like
here's your extended plant count how
does a nice life I'm I'll see you in a
year unless you have an issue before you
know your cards are right when I went in
this last time it was I do six card six
count cards period yeah and of
conversation they're they're paranoid
now I want to lose their licenses like
the reason they're doing this is like I
was starting to say extended plant
counts and caregivers became the
scapegoat a couple years back when cops
started showing up to
grows where it was just like a an
outside horse fenced area with 50 plants
in the backyard and
from time to time they would show up to
one that was real egregious with
paperwork that had paperwork saying that
the the overall plant count is legal and
the cops started going to the press
saying you know we're running into car
ELLs who are using the extended plant
count and caregiver rules in Colorado is
cover to produce huge amounts of illegal
marijuana and then they would point to
busts of cartel home grows where they
had two thousand three thousand five
thousand plants
it's the one has nothing to do with the
other right the illegal growers are
illegal growers they've always been
illegal growers that's how like forty to
sixty percent of a sixty billion dollar
national market gets produced in
basements and
they were attempting to blame all of
that on our caregivers and because of
the Chris Berkowitz story
several years ago caregivers do not do
interviews I
not so much the last six months or so
but for the last several years I would
get a couple of calls a month from
reporters every time the new caregiver
bill would go through the legislature
trying to give me to set him up with a
caregiver who's your caregiver we know
you've got a caregiver we know you know
caregivers please put us into contact
with these people and the answer was no
like I'd reach out to care everybody I
know that's a caregiver that reporter
asked we developed a relationship with
that reporter and she would call me
first and say hey will you be on camera
and I would say nope and then she would
call you and be like have your caregiver
come and I'd be like
thanks my good cover buddy thank you
good work
caregivers don't do interviews because
when caregivers do interviews the the
local law enforcement wherever they live
shows up and gives them how because the
interviewer only wants to know about how
much you can produce and how you're able
to survive and make a living if you
clearly spending 50 hours a week doing
that
and the cops take one look at that know
like we should rate him he's clearly
illegal and they show up they make your
life how they trash the place and even
if you're lucky and you've got all your
paperwork
your whole situation still destroyed
right yeah in minimum you've got a huge
legal hassle a couple of days
some clean [ __ ] and then several days
cleaning up the mess they made turn your
[ __ ] apart and they shot your dog right
and your dog's been shot so
caregivers just don't do interviews and
part part of that has led to
very few people stand up
and say I'm a caregiver if you pass this
new rule you're proposing
three of my patients are going to die
right and for a lot of caregivers that's
the situation they're treating someone
with cancer or epilepsy
and if they're no longer able to do what
they've been doing legally for years
their patients are screwed
the the rules that they're proposing
will end caregiving period in Colorado
with 16 plants only half in bloom at one
time is it enough to provide for more
than one or two people period barely
enough to provide for one person if
you're talking about oils and things of
that nature right like Doug wouldn't
survive on these numbers no I would have
to it would be I'll have to decide whose
caregiver I would want to be if I even
chose to continue you could you could
probably take care of Doug if you
dropped everyone else including yourself
yeah yeah I would be able to I would be
able to grow for myself and Doug would
be about it I don't think you'd be able
to cover ball see you I know I know I
could because I know how to produce
weight with small numbers in small
spaces but the average person is gonna
struggle doing it well see and that's
where that's part of the art the the
argument that gets lost in a lot of the
testimony is
when you hear okay there's a caregiver
living in a residential house with a 99
plant count and that's their six
patients combined add up to 99 or their
five patients of themselves sorry
combined add up to 99 people picture 99
Volkswagen bus size price right in full
harvest and what they don't realize is
that immediately off the top you cut
that 99 in half and so now you've got 44
in bloom 45 in veg or 45 and one and 44
in the other and
I'm sorry 55 yeah I was gonna let you
guys take a drink so I just let it slide
so you keep a light did something weird
on the panel like I'm not crazy you
think it went usually it lights up two
dots when I'm talking and it went up to
like five and so my brain did the stoner
thing that was like did you do something
weird I kind of lost my train of thought
while I was trying to do math plus
little Jeffery jabs you cut your plant
count in half is all you're allowed to
flower out and then if you're a
caregiver caring for five people and
yourself those five people's conditions
are gonna require different strains
right which require different mother
plants and all of a sudden you're in a
situation where you're harvesting nine
plants at a time seven plants at a time
maybe twelve well think about this one
way that medical users produce quick
amounts of medicine is to put a four by
four tray with 64 rockwool cubes and a
tiny tiny plant and veg it for like two
weeks and flip it flower for 60 days and
then each one of those produces five to
ten grams that's not a lot that's
approximately a pound of weed as your
goal there
as far as Bryan but you've got to do 64
plants to make that even a viable option
and you're not gonna pull as much weight
as an experienced grower is gonna do
like I could pull two pounds with four
plants under one line if I do it my
method it's just all about how your
timing works out and it just sucks if
people that are doing this like a small
hydro center we're gonna have to change
everything because of but a bunch of
stupid [ __ ] rules when when you
listen to the testimony of the people
that are really in support of this bill
they say things like every plant equals
a pound of marijuana
I wish or two or three I wish and it's
like well
maybe outdoors like if you did some
stuff and had some talent and a couple
other things but like five of those are
illegal if so you're looking at a couple
ounces for like a really nice big plant
indoors not a couple pounds right and so
the whole conversation that's taking
place at the state level here is twisted
you can hop online and people like it's
this is legislation that's taking place
it's broadcast it's recorded it's posted
you can listen to the testimony
I mean it's disturbing there's during
this bill when it was in its first
hearing a little girl girl and her
father testify it's kind of cute before
when the committee's like whoever wants
to go first the dad's like please let my
daughter go first and then judge her
independently from me because like I'm
military and I'm can be harsh and I
don't want you to misjudge my daughter
because I'm a douche
but the the wrap-up of the doctor's
testimony is this rule forces my family
to choose between who lives me or my
debt and like I'm a dad and so that hit
me like right in the gut like oh and
then like two minutes later while the
dads testifying one of the committee
members is like wait a second you guys
live on AG land and he's like yeah you
know we're we're here to testify that
there are a lot of people in Colorado
like us that this is gonna harm and the
committee member goes but it won't harm
you too so we don't really have to
choose which one of you dies like that's
not really a choice you guys are gonna
have to make like other families sure
but not you too personally and when the
dads like no you know we live on
agricultural land where homesteaders we
do our own meat veggies we grow and
produce everything ourselves I just
didn't give a [ __ ] about him at that
point it was like now we can ignore
everything you two have said oh you know
different zip code than me [ __ ] you yep
because yeah because that's it exactly
you'd the land you happen to reside on
is zoned agricultural and so these rules
won't necessarily affect you until you
try to move so since we are allowed to
grow six plants as a recreational smoker
and how much is a recreational smoker
allowed to possess cannabis wise I do
not know that room we'll see that's the
thing there's this weird open-ended
loophole where
recreational wise you're allowed to keep
your whole harvest one of the questions
we left with Maui yeah okay is what you
can do with the eggs if I get pulled
over how much can I have in my car a
mouse okay just if you're right honest
and not to even taunt anybody you guys
if you get caught with weed in Colorado
and you don't have like a [ __ ] pound
exposed you can have your weed like
whatever you've got they don't they
don't care like you just don't be a
[ __ ] about you have to be doing the
like crack your window to DUI checkpoint
constitutional I'm gonna ruin this cops
45 minutes kind of thing or like the
eyes are glazed have you been eating
doughnuts like you have to be really
[ __ ] stupid for the cop to care about
your two and a half bags of weed I had a
cop walk up to my car and I I am good at
getting pulled over we've done an
episode about how to get pulled over
properly I brawl down my window all the
way before that copper anywhere near my
car and had both hands up on the
steering wheel and he was probably 15
feet away from me and he goes so do you
have any marijuana in there
yes probably I didn't know for sure but
I was like yeah probably cuz I probably
I had my personal bag of weed in there
you know I work at it grow like that's
right right into your states there's
enough marijuana ground into the carpet
in my floor the
answer was what smells pretty strong in
there and and then I just grabbed my
badge had my marijuana Enforcement
Division badge attached to my shirt and
I just go uh sir I work in a grow and I
smell strong every day and that's he
relaxed he goes oh my daughter works in
a grow and he became friendly and did
not I was going ninety two he clocked me
at ninety two and a 75 and didn't give
me a ticket because I told him I had
weed in the car no when you start off
friendly and honest that the interaction
goes a different way completely and in
Colorado like that oh my god I've got
weed on me now that none of that needs
to happens for a couple of seconds it's
I'm from that school when I have more
weed than I care to admit that was in
the car and I shouldn't have and I've
been pulled over and gotten away with
that I used to see the red and blues hit
the turn signal to let him know that I
was gonna stop as soon as it was safe
and then do the inventory yeah
okay here's a quick time to do a PSA
don't put illegal [ __ ] in your glove box
so it's [ __ ] stupid I see a lot of
people do that I hear a lot about people
doing that don't do that every time I
see you on TV or in the movies I chuckle
yeah you're gonna get pulled over think
about this cops behind you right you
start [ __ ] your pants you're doing
what Mike does [ __ ] what's in the car
what's in the car who do I have be cool
be cool when that cop gets there he's
gonna say license registration proof of
insurance license is in your pocket in
your wallet probably guess where your
registration and proof of insurance are
in the [ __ ] glove box where you've
got the gun in the dope hidden I'm doing
that stupid [ __ ] you guys
and you got to reach in there and fish
out that you're gonna be all shaky
reaching out your license an insurance
card that Geico card you're gonna fish
that out without letting that baggie
fall out [ __ ] somewhere else you guys
part of the beauty of car like when we
get pulled over here we just yes officer
there's weed in the car no I'm not it's
oxidated we got pulled over at lunch one
day there were four of us in the car and
it was what are you guys doing and it
was we're on our way back and I did the
same thing you did I kind of held up my
badge and we're on our way back from
lunch and the cop scans for the car and
was like oh go to work yeah yeah like I
thought you were four idiots out here
cause in trouble you're four employees
eating in a parking lot real quick
before you hurry back to your job have a
nice rest your shift fellas you know
like didn't bat an eyelash yeah there's
weed in the car all four of us we're
gonna dispensary my buddy James is from
Georgia and he got pulled over the other
morning cuz he had a brake light out on
the I passed him
James gonna be late but uh I was like
man how was that he was cops here's fun
cool you gonna be [ __ ] up to get
pulled over in Colorado like yes you do
they didn't care they just pulled him
over down here and Pueblo it's a little
like
Patrol him no they just pulled him over
because one of his brake lights was out
and they just it was 6:00 in the morning
we're on our way to work early in the
morning and they just pulled him over to
him hey you got a brake light out you
know I used to get hassled a bunch when
I was a teenager further north but not
since I moved here yeah oh you could
kind of do whatever you want this town
yep a lot of what you want a lot of it
yeah
let's talk a little bit about 45-minutes
let's talk a little bit about the city
of Chania Pueblo there's one tiny little
caveat to these state rules they don't
want to add I mean let's hear it they
built in a loophole to kind of make it's
mildly more palatable
it's [ __ ] not going to win a second
but the little loophole they built in is
several cities and counties have already
passed homegrown limits and so if a home
if an area has already passed a limit I
can't remember if the state bill says it
automatically supersedes or that area is
allowed to decide if it wants to have
their previous rules supersede the state
rule
and so your area if it wants to can pass
a much higher plant count limit
or which is much more likely like Denver
and several other places have already
done they've already passed a 12 plant
limit and they want to keep it even
though the state limits gonna be 18 and
so there's that one little kind of
loophole spot but there's I guarantee no
area in Colorado is gonna go after that
it would make you to I mean it's just to
be the only county in Colorado that
allows 40 right everybody everybody will
move their slop you'll pack up the day
they say that immediate right now if you
if I five if I owned a Glenn in Colorado
I'd be all over Craigslist right now so
I think that everybody lives in Colorado
that is over 21 if you have got 5 by 5
square extra feet in your house and your
life in your backyard wherever grow six
plants of cannabis do the best you can
grow six plants get six loans from
somebody from a dispensary get some
seeds grow that [ __ ] everybody even if
you do not consume cannabis even if you
don't care about Animus there is a
medical marijuana patient out there that
is about to get [ __ ] out of their
caregiver it's not gonna have plants to
grow they're grown for them a caregivers
job is to provide safe quality cannabis
to their patient that their and their
patient relies on them and trust them I
know that when Mike gets cannabis from
his caregiver he knows it wasn't sprayed
with anything funky it wasn't fed
anything funky it was trimmed properly
it's not moldy anything that may have
had a problem got destroyed and thrown
away it was not passed off as usable
product those people are going to not be
allowed to help the people that need the
cannabis so we need everybody to grow
grow grow use your rights grow and then
find sick people that actually need
medicine and give them the weed that you
grow growing weed will feel good to you
it will make you make you pay attention
it'll make you slow the [ __ ] down it's a
super reactive plant it's not like
having a pet hamster like
it's giving you something fun and new
every day and then you get to take this
medical marijuana product to a sick
person and make them so happy and when
they smoke it you get to watch
I've got a friend who has he's not well
in his head and sometimes he has bad
days and he'd be like dude bring me
something different and I'll show up and
you can see it on his face he's got rate
he's got road rage he looks like he just
he doesn't drive it he looks like he
just was in traffic for seven hours
trying to [ __ ] fight Denver traffic
going north in the southbound lane and
then I'll [ __ ] take a couple of dabs
with him and he relaxes and he goes man
thanks thank you I'm gonna go do stuff
now come back later and if we weren't
able to do that for people
but when you get to see that happen you
understand why and how important this is
if you listen to the reasons rules like
this or getting proposed and pushed
they I mean during the testimony for
this one in particular
one of the legislature members actually
that's a torch by the way listeners yeah
shine it's my dad torch one of the
legislators actually stops the guy
testifying this like wait any plants
because the guys like if you have more
than one or two house plants in your
home you're probably generating talks
mold and dirt because that's basically
when they they go after caregivers
in-home grows they list every problem
that you typically see with the most
egregious black-market production
house is gutted power stolen
fertilizers and pesticides dumped on the
back lawn I'm diesel fuel spew spilled
on the neighborhood children just a
traveller Trap House grow that is not a
medical marijuana caregiver grow that's
a Trap House grow
there's no mold in my caregivers grow
there's no stolen power feeding my
caregivers grow all of this is a legal
behavior symptom and they're trying to
attribute it to anyone attempting to
grow any kind of house plan even if it
wasn't cannabis that you were trying to
grow in your house and so one of the
Legislature's legislators is like wait a
second I've got like two dozen house
plants and you can kind of see her we're
doing the trying to count him in her
head like well I fill up the picture and
I do this room in that room it's just
like I've got a bunch of houseplants do
you mean my house is full of mold and he
was like well that really depends how
you take care of them and you could kind
of see the mood change when it was like
Oh bro you dropped the [ __ ] for just
a second and you let reality slip out
for just a second
it's all about how you're doing if
you're willing to do it right you don't
have stolen power you don't have mold
you don't have poison spray on your
plants you don't have neighbors
complaining about the smell you don't
have teenagers and thugs from Florida
breaking in either's no traffic coming
and going there's nobody parked in front
of the house with the music plan no
we've never had to threaten your
neighbor did not say anything about
something they saw that shouldn't be
right because it's not a black market
production facility
that's that's trap house behavior and
they think they're gonna solve all this
by bypass in a plant count and it's like
alright so you can't catch them stealing
power you can't catch them destroying
rental houses you can't catch them
selling the product on the Internet you
can't catch them driving it across state
lines you can't catch them depositing
the money in the bank they're not
following the rules for any of that
behavior and think you're gonna solve
all this with the planet count rule the
only people this will affect are the
people who are desperately doing
everything they can to follow yep yep
and those are the people these rules
were passed for everybody else is it
even worth having a medical card now
totally okay I've had the medical card
for two reasons the entire time I've
been allowed to have one one because I'm
injured and I use cannabis to treat my
pain and two because it provides me
significant additional legal protections
all right I like it because I can shop
and I mean that's a huge benefit to but
I don't shop that much but anytime
anywhere I can stop and shop yeah I saw
that this apothecary lemon Jeff was on
sale and I was able to get that without
the card I would have been [ __ ] yep
I've been stranded in springs before I
had a fight car break down at Springs on
two different occasions in both times I
was like a card in the wallet yeah yeah
Colorado Springs does not have any
recreational cannabis stores no medical
only and when I go visit my mom with in
Denver at the place half a block from
her house is meds not only okay and so
when I pull up to her in her house and
I'm like man today was stressful didn't
bring anything
not a problem yep just walk shop yeah
sure shops are so much cheaper to it so
those extra legal protections that I
really like I actually like some of the
things that do in rack over what some of
the things they're doing medical the
testing the testing is exactly what I
was kind of hinting it I would bring
that back into there bringing those
rules in in the line with each other I'd
love to see a lab test on this lemon
Jeffrey but there is not one not just a
disclaimer that when it shows up it'll
be very by 15 percent of [ __ ] is
that yeah you guys in Colorado they are
allowed to be 15 percent plus or minus
on the THC content that is whack that is
completely wack yeah there's a new rule
that passed recently everything says
plus or minus 15 so you're not sure if
you just bought a 10 or a 25 and
cannabis usually ranges from about 20
and right now it's somewhere between 17
and 25 30 is really high so a 15 percent
variance you could get zero if you know
what I mean you could have 2%
cannabinoids in there if you read 15% on
a label that could be a zero or that
could be a 30 and that kind of swings a
problem because roll up a joint and I'm
a noob and I can't judge potency by
characteristics that the art on the
label right you know
yeah when you light that up who knows
where you're going if it's zero you're
gonna get to the end of it and be
confused if it's thirty I love smoking
joints at concerts I can smoke all of
your weed at a concert and not get high
cuz I'm a dabber and people just look at
me like what is wrong with the
Terminator over there he smoked all the
weed it's really funny I need dad to get
where I need to be I like shows where
there's a lot of joints moving because
you never know what's coming through
the last time I was in line at Red Rocks
the kid next to me
there was a guy running up and down the
the entrance selling loose joints out of
an Altoids tin and the second time he
shouldered between me and the guy next
to me the guy next to me chuckle it was
like skinny little [ __ ] and I thought
he was talking about the guy and I kind
of chuckled because it was this really
skinny white kid in a polo shirt
in khaki shorts and I was like accurate
description and then he pulls out a
joint that's thick around is my thumb
and like half as long as my forearm and
he was like this is a real joint but I'd
charged more than $5 and I just start
chuckling he lights it up amazing weed
yeah as soon as that goes out maybe 15
minutes later someone else that was
right in our vicinity that got a hit a
couple of times was like I got next
pulls out an okay size joint it looks
like it's well ruled lights it up and
before I can get to me I'm like oh I'm
good bro
like I'm gonna pretend like I'm too high
for a minute and just passed this
quietly to my left and let someone else
hit this mess I can smell it from here
it smells like it's all dog hair I was
uh it was at Red Rocks in 96 seeing fish
and uh I don't know how you remember
things like that was it the point of
seeing fish that you'll never be able to
remember you know see that's that's
what's weird is I used to I've seen more
fish shows not on drugs that I have on
drugs I think the I do I like to do
drugs when there's nothing else to do I
like to remember Phish concerts my some
of my favorite things that make sense
it's like being when you're would you
take out when you're super drunk at the
bar out and drink a new marble and
you're super drunk at the bar and you
get that super hot girl come home with
you and you wake up next to her and
you're like I wonder if that was any fun
that's like you know what I mean like
god am i that was probably a good time I
don't even know what happened like so
that's that's why I kind of I don't do a
lot of drugs at fish shows I have don't
get me wrong the story I'm about to tell
tributes to this um so we pulled out
some joints me and my buddy Greg we
pulled out some J was for 20 and we're
in line at the fish shun we pulled out
some joints to smoke and the guy next to
me goes trade you some acid for a joint
and we're like well [ __ ] yeah we'll do
that me and Greg each gave this guy a
joint and he gave us one hit he goes one
should be cool for you guys we split it
was one of the best trips of my wife red
rocks
during so they do a song called Space
Odyssey 2001 during that song red rocks
lift it up
and then it pivoted around the drummer
and myself it was like spinning around
the drummer was the axis but somehow I
was also and it was spinning and we
lifted off for a little while and then
you know how red rocks when you're
looking at the stage it's orange there's
just orange with lights and there's the
big speaker stacks on each side they
just turned into a big orange blur with
nine squares on either side I couldn't
tell what anything was and my buddy Greg
tapped me on the shoulder news you
should drink some of this water you're
[ __ ] tripping and that's like you are
so correct right now buddy and I drink
some of that water and ate a rice
krispies treat and sat down for a few
minutes and everything kind of came back
together because they went into it side
down with disease and it's ice and
that's some of my favorite music and it
brought me back but they pulled out a
joint and this dude's I got read you
asked him for that and we had no idea
what we [ __ ] cut ourselves in due to
that acid we trip for like 15 hours off
a half a hit each I one of my friends in
college when not whenever Red Rocks
would come up here and member mumble
don't eat the brownies
I'm not sure if she still goes but there
used to be a chocolate-covered mushroom
lady in every now and then they were in
brownies and I guess someone else handed
him one and he had a really fun
afternoon two Red Rocks tomorrow yeah
yeah when you go to book shows be
careful you guys so really quickly we
said we were gonna talk about Pueblo and
we've totally skipped Pueblo
we bore the [ __ ] out of people when we
talk about Pueblo so I try not to do too
localized stuff we were basically all
Colorado this episode but we're gonna
talk about Pueblo we live in the city of
Pueblo Pueblo County is just on the
outskirts of where we are so it affects
us heavily let's talk about Pueblo
County and their plant counts okay so
separate rules for the city and county
the county passed a plant count limit of
18 a while ago okay 18 plants in Pueblo
County yep so and that's any that's I
think that's period piece of property if
you're not a licensed marijuana business
okay I'm relatively sure that includes
AG land and then in the city they
actually fought tooth and nail for this
when it was going through they wanted a
limit of nine
and I was able to convince the people
that were writing these rules that
passing a plant cap limit would cause
problems and headaches because it's the
city getting in between patients and
doctors but there were several other
clever ways of limiting the size and
scope of a grow and I got them to do a
square foot limit um I wanted a lot more
than a hundred feet hundred square feet
cuz it's really not that much space it's
a ten inside the city you're limited to
a hundred square feet of gross space in
any one home I mean you can apply
if you've got like in a garage that's
got a foundation for walls and a roof
you can go to the city and apply for a
variance allowing you to do like 150
feet I think it is in that outbuilding
okay but you have to jump through an
extra little hoop or two to do that now
what if you've got what if your room
that you're trying to grow you get 100
square feet what if your room you're
trying to grow in is 10 feet by 11 feet
do I need to
tape off that one you you don't have to
modify
existing
structures to make it work but that's
all the space you're allowed to use okay
honestly I haven't heard of a single
person in the city that's gotten busted
we're a small like you were you know you
were using 110 square feet right nothing
like that the people that have had
trouble with law enforcement here and in
the City and County right now it's
zoning rules that you're violating if so
you get a municipal court ticket like
you painted in a wildly inappropriate
slogan across the front of your house
or something
it's not like a felony or a misdemeanor
or anything it's just a civil infraction
okay and that's part of the reason a lot
of local government people that have
passed rules like this are pushing for a
statewide rule because the stay arrived
rule they were pushing for felony um and
ended up so far it's gonna be a
misdemeanor if you break these rules now
so a bit heavier stick to threaten
people with if they break the plant cap
rules but in the city the only people
that have been busted were way above
what their limits were
so the city you can have as many plants
as you like you just have to keep them
in that ten-by-ten area
how you go about that like I'm sure
there's some people that have gotten
real creative
right yeah yeah or how many plants you
can cram into that or how many lights
you can cram into that yep and I'm sure
there's some dude who's built a cube of
kavita's
thinking layers you got to do shelves
shelving like small plants on a little
six-inch shelf taller on it that's a
hundred square foot period if you're
talking about having a veg space in a
bloom space yeah now you've got a 4 by 4
and a 6 by 6 or 2 5 by 5's right things
get ugly quick you know a 10 by 5 and 2
5 by 5's this way to go yep yep mom's
veg flower boom blow it out
if this state rule passes Pueblo City &amp;
County would have the option of keeping
those limits or adopting the statewide
just vague limit of 18
and so that would be up to each little
local jurisdiction when all is said and
done if this passes the good news is is
basically every year for the last seven
years
the legislature has had at least one
effort going after caregivers I mean
every single one of them has failed
every single one
they've attacked this problem a couple
different ways over the last two years
the like we mentioned they're going
after the doctors and so there's not
gonna be anyone in the state that has a
99 plant count card here come
[ __ ] probably September yes
caregivers are
the registry is now main statewide
caregiver registry is now mandatory
you gotta hop online and register
right now if you're a caregiver and
you're following your plant limit your
only rules you've got to follow our
basic building code your electrical has
to be up to code
you know you can't be stealing power you
can't feed dump and stuff in the law and
that kind of thing but
if they pass these rules a lot of the
people who are currently legally allowed
to grow larger amounts and and for the
most part these are the people that are
giving away
huge amounts of CBD oil the right to
poor families with kids with the face
syndrome one of the things a lot of the
kids with that are being treated with
cannabis their illnesses bankrupt
families quickly
things like epilepsy devaís syndrome
cancer leukemia
autism these are not cheap to treat
these are not the appointments needed to
diagnose an arch right moving to
Colorado isn't cheap leave finding a new
job relocating all of the things these
families go through to get here are all
incredibly expensive and when they get
here
several of them have been really lucky
to find caregivers who are willing to
produce
grow large numbers of plants which is
risky just because it's a valuable
commodity I'm depending when you're
standing with it
grow large numbers of plants refine it
down into a consistent noticeable
product that like an oil or a pill and
then they give it to these families at
little to no cost oftentimes the people
with the really big counts because
there's like five of them in the state
they're bulletproof as far as law is any
sort of jury of their peers is concerned
because of how they operate in a care
for but with these new rules they're
legal right to operate like they have
been for years is gone which means it
doesn't matter where they're treating it
doesn't matter right if 12 12 of their
peers agrees that they should be able to
do this to save that kid's life it
doesn't matter they're breaking the
rules they're falling now there's these
kids that have to have seizures you got
a watch watch them twitch it's terrible
yep all right Mike we've been going for
an hour this is supposed to be a bonus
episode we're spoiling we're spoiling
the people let's turn off the mics to
take some dabs and chill out for us we
love you guys thanks for listening we do
we love it when you ramble I got that
before I had it here somebody sent me a
tweet I like it
nice do you remember who it was
shout out to that Twitter follower you
guys make sure you follow the podcast on
twitter at g f YH podcast also you can
follow me on twitter it's at Rasta Jeff
420 of course don't forget to follow
Mike on Twitter it's at Nemo punk 15
also check him out it's pueblo for a
sensible cannabis laws on Facebook it's
getting warmer folks it's time for
Crow questions
you can email them to grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I know you guys got
questions and those I've got three
questions about how to get my crop to be
better this year emails make some really
good shows yes email me all of your
questions if it's an outdoor question I
will get it to Jesse if it's a question
that I cannot field I will find the
proper channels we'll get those people
on the show we will talk about it I love
listener generated content it's the best
because that way I know I'm hitting my
target I'm getting the listeners get the
info that they need I love doing that
and those tend to be the
where we really really get informative
yes it inspires me it gives me something
to dig for it's something to kind of
strive for and learn about well I mean
it's kind of like the wouldn't you get
pulled over with weed in Colorado things
like it's hard for us to remember what
we wanted to know when we were at that
stage of the game right right I forget
that sometimes we forget that not
everybody works in a grow or a
dispensary and has 22 grams of shatter
in their pocket I got an email the other
day that was like they said CBD I don't
know what that is and I had to give him
the whole like here's your cannabis 101
breakdown over Facebook messenger that
was fun oh man jeez good an email
address right all right you guys Mike
thank you for joining me dude thanks for
coming and hanging out you've been here
for quite a while I appreciate it big
shout out to Mike's wife for letting him
come and play for a little while I
appreciate that baby for going to bed
final I hope
man hopefully the wife's taking good
care
I know she is I have no doubt in my mind
that she is ladies and gentlemen thanks
again for listening to another podcast I
would appreciate it if you go to iTunes
I'm sure you know the spill right now go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store find
the girl from your heart podcast find
the ratings and review section I would
love it if you give me a review I will
read your comment your review on a
future episodes so far everybody has
given me a five star rating clicking the
amount of stars that you feel I deserve
I would [ __ ] love it also don't
forget about patreon patreon.com slash
girl from your heart if you are
interested in contributing financially
to the podcast I would appreciate it
patreon is the way to do it check that
out if you can't contribute I still love
the shoot out of you don't feel bad at
all I thank you for listening ladies and
gentleman I'm gonna wrap up this episode
once again thanks to Mike for coming big
thanks to everybody for listening I'm
gonna give a huge shout out to my
friends at elevate and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Applause]
[Music]
are they
my choice
I'm tired
[Music]
friction
behind
[Music]
[Applause]
you