it was a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
I'm back and I'm doing that thing where
I've drop in a big chunk of old episodes
this time I'm doing episodes 13 14 15
and 16 of what used to be the Hydra
culture podcast which is now the girl
from your Hara podcast before we start
the old episodes let me make a couple of
disclaimers first off if there are any
advertisements any offers any promos and
in these episodes that shit's all
expired don't get too excited that
passed a long time ago also all of the
social media and contact information has
changed if you want to send me an email
you can reach me at grow from your heart
a hot meal calm if you'd like to follow
us on Twitter the show is at G f YH
podcast my Twitter account is raw at
Ross to Jeff for 20 also you can search
for us on Facebook just look for the
girl from your heart podcast all right
you guys here is episode 13 14 15 and 16
of what used to be the agriculture
podcast I hope you guys enjoy it tweet
me let me know what you think yeah good
evening good morning good afternoon good
night whatever time it is for you
wherever you are
hope you got a fat bowl of something
tasty in your hand it's time for another
episode of the hydro culture podcast
thanks for joining me this is episode
number 13 I'm glad to be here with you
guys again
this podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies com 4-gauge
green genetics lopata labs Sin City red
dankness mile-high chan adventure Huayra
genetics and many more trusted brands if
you purchase two packs of ira genetics
you will receive a free five pack of
Bounty Killer while supplies last
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code dab life for 15% off any
order and you always get free shipping
at nature's green remedies com I just
got a text message from the guys at
nature's green remedies today they're
gonna do a special for customer
appreciation day and pull it up the text
message here it actually says June 20th
21st and 22nd will be customer
appreciation day if you spend 50 bucks
you get the promo package the promo
package is still actually being built
but I can tell you there are some
hydrogen etics products in there there's
something from gage green in there and
possibly something from a company called
dynasty in there
so you'll get that if you spend $50 or
more Plus you also get the buy two packs
of to ten packs of IRA genetics you get
the free five pack that counts and the
15% discount also counts so make sure
you go check out nature's green remedies
calm and use that coupon code add life
let's give a huge shout-out to our
friends over oil slick oil slick tools
to help you concentrate check out oil
slick Pat comm for more information make
sure you follow oil slick on Twitter
find him under at oil slick pad send him
a tweet
tell me listen into the hydro culture
podcast big love to tree hugger calm
this episode is brought to you in part
by tree hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews
WWE tree hugger calm much respect to all
of our sponsors for making this show
possible all right before we go any
further I want to say thanks to a couple
of people I owe a huge thank you to mr.
Omni Oh from Twitter and also rich mila
han from facebook thanks guys I'm really
proud to have your support I was looking
for something on a facebook feet and I
couldn't find it spent about an hour
searching through Facebook looking for
it I posted that I needed help and a
rich found it in about 30 seconds so
thanks a lot dude and mr. Romney oh you
contribute to the show via Twitter
whether you know it or not I also want
to say a huge thank you to everyone
who's left comments on iTunes I'm
actually gonna go read the iTunes
comments to you right now the first one
says nice find by Todd to dip into death
that's Tod DDD Todd with the bunch of DS
Todd says I really like the tone of the
show it's never too serious and never
boring
I laugh and learn and laugh again well
awesome dude that's kind of what I'm
aiming for
I like to make people learn and making
me laugh is just a bonus I'm kind of a
goofy dude so like that comes across
thanks bro the next one is awesome buy
llama box llama box that's the coolest
name dude
he says loving the show telling about
the culture from the front lines that's
it that's that's our jobs what we got to
do
the next comment is from our friend
logistics he says great listen great
podcast always fun listening to Jeff's
stories on cannabis wish I learned about
this podcast sooner and met the man
himself during my short trip to Colorado
I don't worry bro you'll be back to
Colorado you get to meet me look at the
hangout I got all the cannabis events
I got a dad for you don't worry so shout
outs all the people that left comments
on iTunes thanks guys
if you leave comments on iTunes I'll try
to read it on the show also find the
comments on stitcher and read those on a
future episode stitcher is kind of weird
they don't put the comments all in one
spot they spread them around they stay
on each episode so unless I go search
back through the episodes I won't find
them if you don't want to leave a
comment on iTunes or stitcher you can't
send me a tweet at I grow culture or of
course you can find me on Facebook and
I'll respond to you there if you want to
say something anonymously you can always
send me a personal message and I will
keep your name private I won't bust you
out on the air say your name if you ask
me not to alright that was Sinbad love
to everyone at the garden of Weeden
what's up guys you guys are my home away
from home my family away from family the
fraud be part of your circle I'm honored
to call you my friends much respect
unfortunately the garden of Weeden lost
a brother recently he was taken from us
tragically so I'd like to take a minute
and say goodbye to Danny I love you bro
miss you I'm gonna read a beautiful post
that was written by our friend Maddie
all right this post says and I may tear
up cuz he was a cool bro it says we've
lost a great brother and part of our
crew living an experience in Colorado
with you and your family has been a
blessing to all of us Danny always had
so much positive energy and brought so
much fun to our lives it's gonna be so
strange and I haven't you walk in the
front door with the yellow vitamin water
and Dad bag in hand arts go out to you
and your family we all love you and miss
you we will all grind that much harder
for you bro hashtag country bearded
dabbers country bearded dabbers was
something that Danny and a few friends
came up with
yeah there's a North Carolina boys Danny
was always a cool dude he was kind of a
friend of a friend if you know what I
mean like I was introduced to him by the
garden of Weeden crew but from the first
time I met him he treated me just like I
was one of the bros so you know always a
cool dude big shout out much respect I'm
gonna take a phat dab for Danny who will
be back with the rest of the show all
right now back with the news we've got
some good news to report this week this
article comes from voxcom Vox explains
everything you need to know in two
minutes
so I got two minutes this article is
written by German Lopez and it was
written on may 30th the article says the
US House of Representatives
late Thursday passed a measure that
would prohibit the federal government
from interfering with States medical
marijuana laws this bill is the first
time in history that any Chamber of
Commerce has acted to protect medical
marijuana businesses and users it also
got bipartisan support a hundred and
seventy Democrats and 49 Republicans
voted in favor of the bill the measure
was attached to a funding bill for
several federal agencies and it blocks
the part of the Department of Justice
and Drug Enforcement Administration from
using funds to prevent States from
implementing their own medical marijuana
laws the measure however will require
approval from the Senate and President
Barack Obama as soon as a Senate is
expected to pass its own funding bill so
the Medical Marijuana amendment will
need to survive through both chambers
reconciliation process and then obtain
Obama's signature to become law so are
two steps away from getting these
[ __ ] to quit [ __ ] with us and
letting us do business and grow our herb
and take care of our patients and do
what we need to do
I don't want to rattle the cage too much
so the article says still marijuana
legalization advocates praised the
houses decision Congress is officially
pulling out of the war on medical
marijuana patients and providers federal
tax dollars will no longer be wasted
arresting seriously ill medical
marijuana patients and those who provide
to them dan riffle director of federal
policies at the Marijuana Policy Project
says a statement this is a historic vote
and it's yet another sign that our
federal government is shifting toward a
more sensible Marijuana Policy the vote
while historic and a bit surprising even
advocates as part of the federal
government's ongoing shift toward more
liberal marijuana policies just a few
weeks ago the feds increased how much
marijuana can be grown for medical
research President Barack Obama and his
administration have taken steps to
mitigate prosecutions against marijuana
businesses that operate illegally under
state laws marijuana advocates in
previous interviews have said that this
is the logical progression for Marijuana
Policy as popular opinion shifts in
favor of legalizing the drug and more
states begin to seriously consider fully
legalizing marijuana as more
congressional leaders gain more
constituents that complete that legally
used marijuana for recreational and
medical purposes they will face
increasing pressure to relax their
stance on the drug still legalization
advocates have their work cut out for
them marijuana is still illegal under
federal law and considered a more
dangerous drug than cocaine and men
under the DEA scheduling system as a
result banks don't have enough faith in
marijuana businesses to let them open
bank accounts which horses pot shops and
cultivators to run is risky cash-only
enterprises we've talked about that a
little bit on the show so as it stands
we are only two steps away from the
federal government
stopping raiding patients providers and
dispensaries for marijuana production
and possession maybe once we get to that
point the banks will start accepting our
funds and the dispensaries will start
being taken seriously like businesses
we can only hope right here's another
article involving the feds and some of
their silliness I looked all over for
this article for information of who
wrote it there's no no authors given
here I can't give you credit for your
homework if you don't write your name on
your paper it does come from The
Huffington Post politics section it
actually says feds block water for state
legal marijuana grows I'm gonna repeat
that feds block water for state legal
marijuana grows the article says an
agency within the US Department of the
Interior announced Tuesday that state
legal marijuana growers are banned from
using federal water on their crops as a
federal agency reclamation is obligated
to adhere to federal law on the conduct
of its responsibilities to the American
people set dam Debray public affairs up
the public affairs chief for the US
Bureau of Reclamation which oversees
management of federal water resources
reclamation will operate its facilities
and administer its water related
contracts at a manner that is consistent
with the Controlled Substances Act of
1970 as amended debris went on this
includes locations where state law has
decriminalized or authorized the
cultivation of marijuana reclamation war
for any inconsistent uses of federal
resources of which it becomes aware to
the Department of Justice and
coordinating with the proper enforcement
authorities reclamation will continue to
work with partner water districts and
providers to ensure their important
obligations continue to be met now that
federal water is banned for marijuana
growing should a reclamation employee be
aware that bureau resources are being
used to facilitate the cultivation of
cannabis that employee will be expected
to bring it to the attention of his or
her regional director who will report
such use to the Department of Justice
and document the reporting actions
according to the temporary policy most
about the u.s. be our website
so if an employee of the reclamation
reclamation department finds that you're
using water to grow some weed they're
supposed to report to the Department of
Justice man whatever so currently 21
states in the District of Columbia have
legalized marijuana for medical purposes
recreational marijuana is now legal in
Colorado and Washington State and about
a dozen other states are considering a
legalization in the coming years
still the federal government continues
to ban the plant classifying in a
Schedule one substance alongside heroin
and LSD we get our way pretty soon here
we got two more steps and we may see
some change maybe they'll give us our
water back but Obama tells them to stop
rating off illegal growers and grow
facilities there's actually a dispensary
in Pueblo West that's suffering right
now because their waters been turned off
and I called them and tried to get in
touch with them but they did not respond
all right let's read another article our
next article actually comes from Pueblo
Colorado
it's in the Pueblo chieftain the article
was written by Peter Roper that's a
[ __ ] poor name if I ever heard one
okay the article is headlined webelo
City Council nota making hash no
agreement on where pot should be smoked
making hash oil will be illegal in
Pueblo that's one decision City Council
didn't have trouble with Tuesday night
as it wrangled over some simple and some
complicated questions about allowing the
use of recreational marijuana in the
city hash oil by the way is a potent
cannabis concentrate that is made with
butane a flammable gas that has caused
the exploding houses in Colorado Springs
and elsewhere Council collectively shook
their heads no Tuesday night after
assistant city attorney
Carlos Sykes explained some of the
hazards of hash oil during the weekly
work session but the tougher question
should city residents be able to smoke
pot on their front porches or in their
yards did not get resolved although the
city doesn't allow the sale of
recreational pot council is trying to
give city residents guidance on how they
can legally use in the city I want to
mention that there are dispensaries like
five miles outside of the city limits in
Pueblo West and twelve County and just
south at stamp Beach so for five or ten
minutes away we don't have access to it
they just don't allow it right inside
city limits which we have talked about
which we find silly so we'll continue
councilman Steve Morocco councilman
Steve Nawrocki and Ed Brown as well as
Councilwoman Aimee Nawrocki all spoke up
for letting people use legally use
marijuana anywhere on their property
just like smoking cigarettes or drinking
beer
we just have to trust people to use
their best judgment Steve Baraka
contended Council President sandy daffy
responded by underlining her opposition
letting people use pot their front yard
my community deserves better than this
she said sikes explained how other
Colorado cities such as Arvada and
Boulder restrict the use of recreational
pot to backyards and enclosed yards I'm
kind of offended by the statement that
she said my community deserves better
than this what's wrong with me sitting
on my porch on a nice summer day sit
with my damn phone in the sunshine I
know that's ridiculous but I watch the
traffic and I cool off and just let my
thoughts wander for a minute sometimes I
put the phone away just I'd like to be
able to just smoke a joint without
anybody [ __ ] there yeah I don't do it
cuz I don't want to bring any attention
to myself but I wish I could do it
without anybody just bitching and I know
like why can't dread locks I'd be the
perfect target for them to go [ __ ] with
so I just don't do that but we deserve
better than this we we voted this in we
voted to be able to use cannabis we
voted for it to be recreational we
should feel free as adults to smoke
where we feel like we can smoke all
right I got a quick drink I'm all choked
up from the jab dad hold on for one
second all right
front yards and walks are essentially
public she said an amendment 64 does not
allow the public use of marijuana
Denver does allow open use in yards and
Steve Nawrocki said he wants the city
staff to bring forward an ordinance that
starts with the Denver language if there
are votes to change it they can amend it
he said he was referring to death
councilman Chris Coffman Councilwoman
IVA Montoya and councilman Chris nickel
who have all challenged recreational pot
in one way or another there are some
decisions about whether to allow
marijuana clubs if bought is legal for
recreational purposes why shouldn't
there be clubs allowed where people can
use it together but the general
consensus on council leaned against that
a major reason was the challenge of
having city police or firefighters
respond to incidents at such a club
where they might be to have prolonged
contact with marijuana smoke that could
affect their job performance I know I
laugh to do that because I read it it
got [ __ ] silly to me but I tried to
read through that [ __ ] again without
laughing at you guys the major reason
was the challenge of having city police
or firefighters respond to incidents at
such a club where they might have
prolonged contact with marijuana smoke
that could affect their job performance
so one of the reasons they're trying to
stop us from having a recreational smoke
lounge chair at Pueblo Colorado is
because they're afraid if the cops are
the firefighters have to go there they
will have prolonged contact with
marijuana smoke that could affect their
job performance that's some [ __ ]
that's that's over worrying how long do
you think they're gonna be in there how
smoky do you think it's gonna be chill
the [ __ ] out
I was actually asked recently to be on
the council that's going to write the
rules the proposed rules to get a
recreational shop open here in my
neighborhood actually people that are
opening you don't even realize I live
right by that they came to me they said
that the council is gonna stop it from
being possible if we don't proactively
try to write rules and propose it to
make it happen I think this is the
announcement right here where I said I
am gonna do that because it was up in
the air still I think I'm gonna
participate help them out they need my
help they need somebody that knows
what's going on and in this area that
seems alright I think that's enough news
for the day I am going to take a DAB and
grab another sip of something and we'll
come up with the the first Gro lesson
after that and we're gonna driven ate
some seeds and we'll talk about that
here we go give me a second well I'm
taking a quick dab you guys should check
out tree hugger comm WWV tree hugger
comm alright guys we are back it's time
to give you a quick lesson on
germinating seeds but I want to read a
little post that I made on Facebook long
ago and it's still relevant says I'm
asked dozens of grow questions every day
let me give everyone my first piece of
advice to anyone who wants to start
growing cannabis on any scale if you
want to grow enough medicine for
yourself or if you want to supply North
America with your buds this is my first
piece of advice before you ever order a
seed or purchase a clone before you even
walk into the hydro shop before you open
a catalog to see what kind of nutrients
you want to use arabic i recommend
buying yourself a good grow book from a
reputable grower author i recommend and
Rosenthal's marijuana growers handbook
or Jorge Cervantes marijuana
horticulture at the medical growers
Bible of course I've recommended both of
those in the show before if you need a
simple step-by-step guide pick up let's
grow a pound of I see more bud
and once you have a nice knowledge once
you have a nice knowledge base take a
look at dr. Robert Cullen Clarke's
marijuana botany or Greg greens cannabis
breeders Bible there's a plethora of
knowledge in each of these books if you
read and study before you start a garden
you will have a better understanding of
how to build your grow space what to
plan for during the grow which types of
jet genetics you want to grow and a good
plan for preventing problems problems
will arise during your grow if you read
about the possibilities you'll have the
better eye for spotting problems before
they get out of control you'll also save
a ton of money by not buying unnecessary
equipment or products and making growers
this is just me and rejecting because
you when you go to the grocery put all
kinds of cool [ __ ] at the front of the
store it's just like when you go to any
store those are impulse buys it's [ __ ]
that you don't really need they just
want you to pick that up and spend a few
extra bucks sorry to bust out the grow
shops like that's that's their job you
need to take your buck so make sure you
need something before you buy it just
because it's shiny or flashy or has a
new bite on it don't don't buy that just
Google so save your money a good book
will be the best 20 bucks you could
spend on your garden but it will only be
usable if you take your time to read it
don't be afraid to make notes in your
books you should see some of my favorite
girl books they look like they're beat
to [ __ ] they've been through battles
their book markers in them there's
that's my best advice for any grower
there are people on the internet who
love to give new growers advice but how
do you know that they have any real
education or experience I've seen tons
of bad advice online don't let a
stranger ruin your crop
the first step is to learn about your
plants and patients before you build the
grow room once you understand what
you're getting into some type of let's
see once you understand what you're
getting into set some type of goals for
your grow how many people are you supply
how much do you smoke every three months
how do you produce enough herb to supply
those people and cover your costs and
how can you do this all discreetly and a
safe you have to buy everything
somewhere and you have to get it all
into your house without neighbors
singing your new lights in your new soup
co2 set up have fun sneaking that hydro
table into your house after your crop is
complete you'll have a bunch of soil and
or sticks to get rid of if you're
running hydrate you don't have as much
soil to get rid of but if you're running
soil crops or soilless medium there's a
lot of [ __ ] to get rid of where's all
that stuff gonna go are you gonna put it
out your trash by the curb will you have
enough you'll have enough to think about
while your grows happen a little reading
of preparation before you start will
make your grow much more enjoyable and
much more relaxing experience grow from
your heart and the plants will reflect
so get prepared if you're gonna grow
some weed my first piece of advice to
everybody get prepared understand what
you're getting into because a lot of
people think they're gonna start this
little closet grow they got their seeds
going and they're living week to week
with their grow which is almost
disrespectful and embarrassing to your
plants you're not gonna grow good weed
like that you gotta be I try to be good
for weeks ahead of myself which
sometimes I do get ahead of myself
literally but I tried I trying to have a
plan I know when this clone is being cut
I know when it's gonna flowers generally
I have a good idea so have a good idea
of what you're trying to do have the
equipment in advance have the nutrients
in advance because things sneak up on
you and they're drawn weed you get
distracted by life you have to be kind
of secretive about your grow in some
cases so you can't always do things at
the ideal times it's easier to try to
get to things a little sooner than later
so your crop is at stake here I love
your plants you're gonna love those
plants you wouldn't
the new whatever you're into the New
Jordans you're gonna go buy those today
why don't you take care of your points
today awesome get prepared sorry I have
to clear my throat there's so many dad
so before you're drilling it your seeds
have a good plan what you're gonna do
with them at a few days and a few weeks
and all the way through flower and cure
don't skip any steps don't think about
harvesting and selling that crop don't
even think about that yet cuz you gotta
think about getting it going before you
dream innate your seeds I totally
recommend you have cups or pots for baby
plants to live in for about two weeks to
a month or maybe even to finish it
you're gonna need some soil today I
actually went bought some light warrior
soil I like light warrior and happy
frogs my babies you'll need basic
nutrients and some maybe some rude
inoculants in about a week or two
another good piece of advice is to try
to use good seeds if you can back seat
is fine I mean chem dog was bagged seed
you know but it's less reliable and less
predictable so try to use seeds from a
reliable breeder if possible I know and
what you're growing with will make your
job much easier in the long run if you
need seeds check out nature's green
remedies calm they're actually in the
States so you don't have to worry about
customs taking your seeds or are you
getting a yellow package with green tape
across the front of it and matrix green
remedies also uses Priority Mail so your
package will arrive in just a few short
days to driven eight you're gonna need
some paper towels a marker a plate some
water plain tap water is cool the
bottled water is better in my opinion
you'll be just fine with either do you
want the water room temp so
grab all the things you need and will
germinate some seats together I'm
actually gonna trim innate some seeds
while we're on the show right now I'm
gonna start three seeds with you guys
right now I'm actually gonna start these
are something I just bred I haven't
germinated any of these nobody's seen
these before these are actually called
its grateful DAW it's blue dream a blue
dream here's a quick tip when you're
listening genetics put the female first
like ladies first try to remember that
so if you're crossing strains the girl
strain goes first the male stream comes
after that so ladies first all the time
when you listen etics that just calm to
practice standard so this is blue dream
prostitute the grateful dog it's a
feminized seed I reversed the grateful
dog who's that reversed pollen do that
on the blue tree and I've created a
strain that I would like to call blue
heeler if it proves successful so I'm
gonna germinate some of these right now
we're gonna do two to three of them I
don't have room for a lot of extra
clients right now this is kind of an
experiment I just want to see how these
go so my first step I say do you need a
paper towel right I'm gonna fold the
paper towel into a small square I'm
gonna fold it one two three four times
I've got like a little a couple inch by
couple inch here [ __ ] the square now
it's nice and compact it's nice and
thick so it's in a whole bunch of water
label it blue heeler
[Music]
blue heeler all right now I'm gonna
throw that on a plate
[Music]
fold it up labels I'm gonna go ahead and
soak put the paper on the plate and just
soak the [ __ ] out of it you want it's
[Music]
actually got some seeds on the plate
that I did earlier some paper towels
folded up there labeled that I did a
little bit ago so I'm starting some new
stuff gonna kind of recreate something
that I did a long time ago and got known
for quit making it cause it was not
exciting to me anymore but it's time to
bring it back anyway
ah now this plate has too much water on
it I can tell that there's standing
water on this plate I could see it
sitting here I don't want that there so
I'm actually gonna tip it off so hang on
for one second while I run to the sink
hold on here I go and aback wasn't that
fast
I love that it ain't cool after two
paper towels nice and soggy and excess
water is gone unfold it two times I know
that sounds weird we just folded it up
right but I want to get these seeds down
in there in the middle so I just
unfolded it now I'm gonna drop the seeds
in got one get - we got this is exciting
for me because I get to see what happens
with some [ __ ] that I just created fold
it back up
yeah just fold it back up so you got
it's all soaked you just put them in the
middle there
now you want the paper towel to stay wet
make sure it's damp and cold your hand
at all times if that paper towels dries
out your seeds will perish and you'll be
shopping for seats soon so keep them
damp but not soggy from here out I set a
timer to remind myself to check on on
every like four to six hours pour a
splash of water on him whatever the
paper towel seems to be getting dry the
time between watering is gonna depend on
your environment I actually traded I
moved them from one room to the other
today to have them sitting next to me
during the podcast and recording and the
ones I started earlier they dried up
because I have a swamp cooler right
above where I'm sitting and I kind of
dried them out quite quickly when they
were in another room
they stayed wet for most of the day so
that'll make a huge difference depending
on where you are make sure you check
them often if you need to be gone for an
extended amount of time something that I
recommend you can do is put the paper
towel that you've got into a ziplock
baggie and seal it to keep the moisture
in I don't do this because I like to let
my seedlings get a little more air but
it helps if you're forgetful if you're a
pocket-like a lot of us are so I'm like
24 to 48 hours hopefully you've got some
seedlings that have little sprouted
tails the tail is called the tap roof
that's super sensitive that's that's
really important to your plant right now
keep that thing in tact be careful with
the tap root while you're handling it
while you're planting your seedlings
that tap root is gonna be the source of
life that suckers gonna dig all the way
down to the bottom of your pot it's
gonna start spiraling out that's what's
gonna make your client flourish
hopefully if you do things right so
you've got a little tiny seedling that's
sitting in a paper towel after a couple
days right now you got to get it into
some soil hopefully you've got some cups
or whatever kind of pots you're gonna
put it in on it's ready so get your soil
pack it into the container that you're
gonna use the cup or whatever did it
lightly pack do you want it in there
kind of firm but not like hard you want
those roots to be able to grow but you
also want them do a little bit of work
you don't want them to just be able to
push through kind of make your plants
tough at this point and also if you're
using cups make sure you have plenty of
drainage holes in there and make sure
that the pots are using or
these clay pots use use plastic pots or
earth pots or air pots or root pots
something cool like that there are
couple of reasons for that so you've got
these seedlings they got your cup full
of dirt
or your container full of dirt I
recommend to water the containers with
pH balanced water and if you're gonna
don't use nutrients at this time wait
wait T wait till a little bit later to
use nutrients so get your pot filled
with soil and water it you're gonna see
the pot kind of the dirt is gonna kind
of cave in cuz you've left air spots in
there that's just out dirt works when
you water it the first time maybe have
to go back and sprinkle a couple more
handfuls of dirt in there if it's a
larger pot if it's a cup you just need a
little bit more ice cream cone
butt-fuckin so make sure the dirts right
before you put the seed in there what I
do is I just push my finger in up to
about the first knuckle into the dirt or
down I guess into the end of the dirt to
my first knuckle and just make a little
addition with my finger and then I just
set the seed right inside there and I
don't even bury really I just kind of
backfill the dirt real gently just kind
of push it on top of there just where
it's covered up from the light and give
it a little bit of a challenge to push
through to the top and it grows more
quickly down than it does up so it'll
push its way through really quickly when
it does hopefully it's got a nice rooted
bottom to it so now you've got your
little see links they've sprouted and
about 24 to 48 little while long if they
don't if they take a little longer don't
worry just let them go keep them Wyatt
let them keep going I've seen seeds take
up to four or five days to pop sometimes
older seeds need more love or whatever
but give them time so you've got your
seedlings they've got a little sprout
you sold your couplets or your container
with water pearl with the dirt sorry
filled your container with dirt you
pressed it down a little bit you watered
it made an addition with your finger or
drop your seed in there and you covered
it up now set that sucker under your
grow light t5 light works perfect right
now fluorescent at t5 you don't need a
big 400 water a thousand watt light
right now a little t5 or some of you
guys like the
LEDs that'll work fine for you right now
that'll work fine until you get close to
the bloom phase so we'll stop right now
that was the end of the first girl
lesson that I want to do thanks for
joining me for that it was really cool
I'm gonna take a quick break again a lot
of breaks in this show it's actually
just easy segues to tell you the truth
lots of spots to take bad to drinks so
I'm gonna do a dab do a drink I'll be
right back we're going to talk about
what's coming up in the next show and
we're gonna give thanks to somebody
super special hangout guys I'll be right
back all right there's a lot of stuff to
learn in that episode make sure you join
me next week so I'll have Jesse back
he's gonna talk a little bit more about
outdoor growing and I'm gonna teach you
how to cut a clone and take care of your
baby clones
once those clones and the ceilings catch
up they get about the same size we will
start talking a little bit more about
veg the vegetative phase and healthy
veggie ding and we'll talk about a
little bit of training how to train your
plants to grow the way you want them
we'll talk about talk about all the
basics of veg veg drove don't forget
about nature's green remedies use that
coupon code dab life capital da B
capital L IFE dab life that'll get you
15% off any company's products not just
IRA genetics but everybody in the store
so now it's time when we give thanks to
somebody who has been beneficial or
crucial to a cap to the cannabis
movement the person that I have chosen
to give thanks to this week is of course
and I know that you guys been waiting
for this one it is dr. Lester Grinspoon
awesome you guys might not know who
Lester Grinspoon is dr. Grinspoon was
born June 24th 1928 in Newton
Massachusetts
he graduated from Tufts University and
Harvard medicine medical school as a
doctor Grinspoon was the first American
physician to prescribe lithium carbonate
for bipolar disorder I know that sounds
crazy right but anyway here's the good
part dr. dr. Grinspoon became interested
in marijuana in the 1960s when its use
in the United States increased
dramatically
he had no
out it was a very harmful drug that was
unfortunately being used by more foolish
young people who would not listen to or
could not believe or understand the
warnings about its dangers
when Grinspoon began studying marijuana
in 1967 his intention was to define
scientifically the nature and degree of
those dangers but as he reviewed the
existing literature on the subject
Grinspoon reached the conclusion he and
the general public had been misinformed
and misled so originally when Grinspoon
started out studying cannabis he wanted
to prove that it was making people crazy
and it was all a problem but the more
research dr. Grinspoon did the more he
realized that we were being lied to and
misled dr. Grinspoon once said there was
little empirical evidence to support my
beliefs about the dangers of marijuana
and he was convinced cannabis was much
less harmful than he had believed the
title marijuana reconsidered reflected
change in that view Grinspoon is widely
known as the author or co-author of
several cannabis psychedelic related
books including marijuana reconsidered
psychedelic drugs reconsidered marijuana
the forbidden medicine and psychedelic
reflections the first who were published
during the 1970s when it appeared
cannabis was well on its way to
nationwide decriminalization in the
United States marijuana the forbidden
medicine was published in 1993 it
describes a variety of ailments for
which cannabis ingestion may be
indicated dr. Grinspoon appeared in an
episode of the Showtime series Penn &amp;
Teller's [ __ ] episode which
addressed America's war on drugs aired
in the show's second season grins Woods
discussed the way marijuana helped his
young son while he was dying from
leukemia leukemia in the 1970s
completely eliminating horrible nausea
and vomiting he experienced after each
of his chemotherapy treatments and
thereby making the final year and a half
of the boy's life far more comfortable
for his son and for Grinspoon and his
wife by not having to endure the pain of
witnessing their son suffer
drinks Grinspoon was also in a movie
called
it's a documentary called the Union the
business of getting high these guys was
talking about the pharmaceutical
characteristics of marinol as well as
his writing experience and also getting
high with Carl Sagan dr. Grinspoon even
has a street named after him hi so
influential he has influenced a lot of
people the people that taught us how to
grow learned a lot from dr. Lester
Grinspoon so we owe a lot to that guy
big thanks dr. Lester Grinspoon you're
an activist you're an author you're a
cannabis supporter in your and your day
you were brainwashed to think that this
plant was dangerous and you did your own
research and you had enough balls to
come out and say you know what I was
wrong and this plant is actually
beneficial so for that I have to say
thank you so thank you dr. Grinspoon we
really appreciate it
so that just about wraps up this episode
of the hydro culture podcast I
appreciate you guys hanging in while
it's just me Kevin was really sick this
week and have Jesse back we'll have a
couple other people joining us in the
future we'll keep it more entertaining
than just me ranting on once again I
want to encourage you guys to go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
iGrow culture find the review section
give us a five star rating and type in a
comment let me know what you think about
the show and I'll probably end up
reading your comment on the show in a
future episode don't forget that the
show is now available on iTunes stitcher
swell'd on Am and the ivory genetics
colorado dot-com website thanks for
joining us you guys take a fat dab give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 14 of the
agriculture podcast
this episode is brought to you by oil
slick oil slick tools to help you
concentrate
check out oil slick Pat comm floor
information it makes you follow oil
slick on Twitter tweet tell them you're
listening to the iGrow culture podcast
this podcast is also brought to you by
nature's green remedies comm visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics the plot of labs Sin City
rare dankness
can a feature may be more trusted brands
if you purchase two packs of ira
genetics and will receive a free five
pack of bounty killer while supplies
last feature screen remedies is running
a special for our podcast listeners for
15% off any order and you always get
free shipping at nature's green remedies
calm to 20th 21st and 22nd if you spend
$50 at nature's remedies on the 21st at
the 20th 21st and 22nd you will receive
a customer appreciation gift pack that
includes a gauge dream three pack a
dynasty three pack and a limited edition
I read genetics the coupon code dab life
is valid until July 1st and it's valid
during the sale so you can't get the
gift pack a free five pack 15% off and
free shipping if you shop smart and
nature's green remedies
also big luck to our friends a tree
hugger calm is brought to you in part by
tree hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out a tree hugger calm
for concert festival news and reviews
WWWF under comm I want to take a second
say hi to MIT from Pueblo West thanks
for the comment on stitcher pretty soon
we should have a dad lounge of a long
area and I advise you to come down and
take some dabs with me what do we do
can't wait to meet you
so if you guys want to leave a comment
on iTunes I'll try to read it on the
show I also find the comments and
stitcher debate those on the show the
comments on stitcher harder to find
iTunes puts them all in one place
stitcher has them spread out they gone
whichever episode you comment on that's
worsted true we'll leave it so I have to
go back and look at each individual
episode to find the comments we'll
figure out a way to beat that system
we'll get smart pretty soon I've always
just leave all the comments on episode
13 just go to comment on 13 it's already
up so if you're gonna leave comments do
a lotta so 13 or I'll find them all up
there makes it easier for me so leave a
comment there if you don't want to leave
a comment on iTunes or stitcher you can
send me a tweet at Highgrove culture or
you can find me on facebook at hydro
culture and i'll respond to you there if
you want to see something anonymously
send me a personal message and I will
keep your name private I won't put you
on blast on the show we took a few dabs
we took a lot of dabs take a couple of
dabs and do some editing and we'll be
right back with
I guess we are here hanging out with
Jesse he's back again to talk about some
more outdoor growing to catch up from
where we were last time and we also got
our buddy Spitz from the garden of
Weeden what's up bro it's good to have
you here bro thanks for coming thanks
guys both of you back on the show
awesome Spence the second time on the
show Jeb will be back I invited him but
he was sick he hasn't been feeling well
so uh shout out to kind of hope you get
well bro
take care of pops for us also so Jesse's
here we'll get right down to it last
time jesse was here we talked about
pretty much prepping for outdoor season
talked about security we talked about
soil prep we talked about caging and
pruning we touched on strange selections
we got our plants in the ground
we had them top several times so by now
we should have some happy little bushes
that are adjusted to being outside right
cool one thing we skipped though is
hardening off the plants well you should
have done you should put your plan out
for a couple hours one day it brought it
inside and then maybe a few more hours
the next day and brought it inside you
didn't want to throw that poor bastard
he'll look cool they just [ __ ] tell
it to live and wish it good luck
hopefully you caught on and hopefully if
it's out there already and it's just
stuck hopefully it's strong
[Music]
if it lifts through the hill that we got
tonight in Pueblo you've got a good plan
be prepared for that well it's a good
way to prevent that plant from getting
beat to [ __ ] by some hail so you mean
like maybe a trashcan or something oh
[Music]
yeah I just throw a tarp right over oh
well it's kind of built like some kind
of framing okay maybe some PVC hoops
you know fence defense or something like
that some tent stakes you know get
creative most owners are yeah we're
creating a creative fun all right
however those babies oh yeah that's
stuff that you guys gonna have to think
about so if you got it covered if you
want to put a heater in there later on
in the season is that gonna be wise I
personally utilize the system like that
so I can wrap my area and plastic and
keep my plants going I've had a minute
of November that's crazy
I don't usually a Halloween is your
cutoff time for what most people said
yeah humidity build up so you gotta have
a vent you know some fans some fans to
the humidity view not being stagnant one
spot oh yeah all right it'll create all
kinds of problems
normally how do we run any risk what if
we did not have that ten thing going on
the cover would we run any risk of
humidity problems of mold or anything
like that outdoors
[Music]
you know they've been a little bit
longer to switch from the vegetative
phase into flower I know the indoors I
see signs in like 10 days maybe 14 days
on a longer switching strain yeah you're
gonna have you know what I refer to as a
stress period and just a little
different period that you don't have
indoors and they're not gonna barely be
developing flowers they're just still
bolt all of a sudden it kind of and
you're like wow what's going on and yeah
it's quite different in indoors so
inside your plants usually kind of
double in size outside I think in the
triple do you think yeah maybe even more
maybe even more this
I say you get those you know if you
didn't top the plant the things gonna
get gigantic it's like if it's like a
seed plant that used to call you stop
yeah so if I've got my plants outside my
fence is like six or eight feet tall I
better just keep them short before
flower time comes right for sure all
right all right so that's where we got
to learn about trellising and [ __ ] so
gonna some outside plants they're happy
they're having a good time
how are we gonna keep them from getting
too tall we talked about a little bit
last time those buds are gonna get big
and floppy pretty soon they're gonna
start taking are not the buds but the
branches are gonna get big and floppy
yeah we want to use sticks just like I
do inside stakes elastics tomato cages I
think we touched on a tomato or a cage
built out okay my for fencing all right
netting like the end or netting even
like a screen of green idea yeah or even
just throw it over the plant stake into
the ground and you know pull the
branches down into the different little
squares okay yeah
that's pretty smart I would not have
thought of that and then you know one
bud talk per square you're a beautiful
little Christmas tree yeah people don't
think about trying to maximize their
space and they forget about that they
want a big giant Cola yeah you want more
more but for space alright so they're
looking happy we've figured out how to
keep them safe what are we gonna feed
while we're outside if were you a lot of
people are gonna just mix up some
bottled crap and pour that rush the
doors which sucks I would recommend
don't do that to our earth don't do that
to your plants if you could avoid your
going outside
let's go natural let's stick with
Jesse's ideas as close as we can with
organics is easiest outside but you know
the plan
feeding off the soil that you build up
to supplement and help keep the soil
healthy teeth with different cuantos I
kind of to my qua nose to what that's
what I would probably go for I've
noticed a lot of the sea bird stuff is
really beneficial any kind of see
products perfect all right so uh compost
tea do you how do you make your compost
tea you got some molasses you said
you've got the worm castings you got
your guano whatever else we're gonna add
in there just for fun that's when you
guys gotta get creative on your own how
do you need air stones a little aquarium
air pump four gallons or dechlorinated
water or reverse osmosis water let's
talk about the later shoe write that
down
borrow water yeah something I'll cover
for the guys later
so fall asleep bro you're right
[Music]
you can mix them up in a pantyhose all
you different ingredients like your dry
ingredients you could just put them
right in the bucket I've seen both ways
it works either way okay so something
like a tea bag out of the pantyhose
pretty much or just drop it right in
there just let it stir around I
personally just drop it right in there
let it mingle my book it's normally I
have a lot of hair full of stuff stirs
around pretty good you get it nice and
frothy yes - are you gonna dilute that
five-gallon bucket into a larger portion
or just use that that kind of depends on
your recipe okay I I use it diluted
actually I use like 25 30 gallons and do
the 10 different sized operation right
yeah yeah I know where you guys work the
boss over there what up hanky so you got
your tea how often do you feed the teas
[Music]
like I said tie to tune the ingredients
to the growth period the things that
always remain constant is a product
called great white worm castings
molasses and I make my own compost - so
are we still got that in there - Colts
are using food and stuff for your
compost or yeah their scraps awesome way
to recycle everybody should start a
compost pile you can do it in a very
little space it's very beneficial for
your plants it's beneficial for the
earth you'll learn a lot
you'll start to change better care of
your body once you start seeing okay
cycle of the plan everything I think so
I did so do you use your chickens yeah
yeah I have chicken stew
I just they're escaping say get settle a
non-gmo food and some stuff growing on
my family farm vegetable scraps some
types as well as when I clean your
little yard all that stuff goes into the
bottle their eggshells to their feathers
defenders does that mean God does it the
chicken stuff make the soil real hot yes
yeah chicken compost I cook it twice as
long it's just regular vegetable compost
okay all right that makes good sense
that's gonna advance stuff you guys
don't don't don't worry if you're not
caught up on that will talk about
composting way later way later in more
episodes it's easy though once we've got
you growing wolf we'll talk you through
that we mentioned some of the dry
fertilizers that they offer and top
feeding top feeding I personally use
like your ingredients bone meal but now
the different cuantos again compost all
kind of repetitive fish meal there's
another thing I chopped for you - this
fish bone meal actually yeah what isn't
flowering
and just various amounts I tend to so
you mixing that up in water almost like
your tea or you pow sprinkling that
right onto the top um I suppose you
could do it both ways but I dig it into
the top first a little bit yeah just use
my fingers and sometimes like the ref
talks about doing spikes I was gonna
recommend his buddy be into all this yes
shout out to the referee true living
organics but you have to be you know
doing the spikes where you dig a little
hole next to the plant basically and you
can drop the stuff down there and order
your ingredients down in there fill it
back up with dirt the theory is is that
I guess the bigger fruits get it okay
yes the Nexus and then you water that in
and they all kind of becomes part yeah
okay it's all natural like there are
doubts instead of for speeding it you're
actually letting it okay now if that's
you know a little scared of but you
still feel like you're playing need some
extra the dry fertilizer packs from a
cage old nothing wrong with using those
took us not my first choice but still
better than bottle matrix as long as
it's not anything from Scotts or a
Miracle Grow for anything made by
Monsanto you don't want really high high
ratios of nitrogen in your stuff you
don't want that long-lasting slow
dispersal [ __ ] you want natural stuff
just go to a hydroponics store not the
hardware store not the garden center
it's at the hydro shop or Mama's pops
yeah we'll have it be careful have
respect when you go in those places they
know you're growing but you don't
already tell up don't just go in they
already know don't feel the need to go
in there and tell them they'll kick you
I hope they kick you out
be discreet view Pro go in there buy
stuff for your tomato plants you don't
even have to talk about what you're
growing you just need to talk about what
you need to buy a square that is where
this is how much is this especially if
[Music]
you live in North Carolina or South
Dakota or Missouri Missouri just
business order online don't go to the
store because trouble all right that's
good advice even in Colorado I don't I
try not to be parked outside of there
too often because it's not just the not
just the law enforcement but people are
gonna see you there yeah we all know how
people are
so our plants are happy and fed by now
we're just in veg right if this is the
shows today we're in fact right we're
just veg and chilling out yeah what do
we need to worry about next what's
coming up in the next couple of weeks
[Music]
really hectic life lately
to take off be careful okay flour until
[Music]
all right a plant growing out back and I
was like what there's a little seed it's
either I don't know random s1 or testing
I would guess [ __ ] with your plants too
much but 14 to 10 days before a flower
maybe outside you maybe we'll be able to
go about seven days you'll be able to
see you coming when they go into that
stretch face
they don't understand what I'm talking
about now but what's a finis yield oh
yeah that's your last chance so you know
pretty much you're done top and go ahead
and get the super crop in there being
space we're just talking super strapping
yeah that's something I learned from
soba well not directly I rent from soma
I wish came to taught me that [ __ ]
super dropping you basically find a
branch you can tell it's gonna grow up
to high and just grab it and [ __ ]
break it bend it over to the left and
it's gonna snap and it's gonna scare you
but if it's a strong hardy plant within
six hours that will start drawing right
back up squeeze the area around just
Bertie I'll break it off first of those
walls if it's strong and healthy little
crunches like like good celery
yeah just like good celery that's a
description and it is safe too you know
yeah I mean you can just crank them over
too but right before a flower when
they're flowering I walk through and
just brush the whole tops on my endure
over just [ __ ] six and a half feet
tall Vince is pretty tall we got these
12 feet arm spans do you think you need
to come back and get us caught up with
some more [ __ ] cuz bears gonna grow for
a couple weeks right we're not gonna
flower oh yeah he'll be grown for over a
month
it's uh I don't know three four weeks
that's all right yeah we'll get it in
here right before that stretch face
kicks and cool and if anyone's got any
questions get them to to mr. Irish yeah
please do tweet me all your questions or
email me it's all at sea it's a grow
culture on Twitter it's what is it I
grow culture at hotmail.com I think will
work for you there's a Facebook page
there's plenty of ways to get in touch
with us I'll read all your stuff on the
air will answer all your questions a lot
of fun
if anybody's doing it - I'd like to see
pictures - yeah if you'd like us to
share your pictures send them to me on
Facebook and all Cheryl there's an
Instagram also drag us in there we find
you on Instagram bro jesse grows at
jesse grows and we find garden garden of
Weeden they post some really cool pics
some great wheat pictures so our burrow
Spence is from Colorado he burns not
from colorized in North Carolina
sorry he's new to Colorado he's been
here for just over a year right about a
year and a half about a year and a half
how do you like it so far bro I love it
I honestly don't I probably wouldn't go
back unless you know things are
different you know Chanakya it's so all
rights free you know saying this was one
of the words I was gonna say it's free
like I've come from somewhere where you
get caught with like a joy or like you
know I've even seen cops put I find like
crumbs like literally crumbs of weed in
people's car and take them to jail
damn so it's just it's you know you come
out here and it's you know it's so much
more free and then especially the people
you know that are moving here for you
know real reasons like their children
need the medicine so they have to go to
the source and Colorado is right now so
we are at the source so I'm definitely
thankful for you know all the roles and
stuff that are out here and it's just
more liberal free I know you're pretty
decently and I know you don't do
anything stupid you're not a criminal
boki cannabis was the only thing that
made you a criminal in North Carolina
yeah do you feel completely liberated
now like you're just living large now oh
yeah I have you know there was always
that worry you know I'm saying cuz we if
any any state you live in people are
going to smoke it's just yeah this
culture yeah
so you know when you're around people
that are smoking illegal states you know
it can be sketchy because it's not a
safe place it's you know in trouble but
you can get in trouble for do you still
forget sometimes that you're in Colorado
like when you're rolling if the cops get
behind yeah we don't like cops anyways I
definitely feel like I don't have
worries anymore about being high in
places and stuff like that because you
know it's all right to do so
okay when you go home you know you went
to visit recently do you catch yourself
slipping almost or yeah I myself there
about talking because here we can just
all my friends grow pot all my friends
smoke you know smoke pot so I just saved
Brandon pot stuff out loud so when you
go home you kind of got a bite you're
telling a little bit ya know what you're
saying around certain people I mean a
lot of people you know they know what
the word weed and pot and dope is which
I don't like white people in this house
think we just don't but definitely you
know bite your tongue a little bit here
there yeah oh man I bet you freaked
people out when you went home took dad's
with everybody crazy they get automatic
look like what are you doing and but
then when you give them a DAB and they
get done coughing it's like holy [ __ ]
I'm high
you forever yeah that was actually paid
oh yeah everything in the fridge and
sleep eight hours that wake up and want
to do it again even if they did have
rejection Yuri took off a long time way
oh yeah for sure how about you just now
that everything's all legal do you catch
yourself I like still because you were
doing this before we were supposed to I
mean maybe say that but you might have
been a grower before being a grows
appropriate do you get paranoid
sometimes still do you forget I don't
really like cops actually like
challenging them so no no I don't just
the best thing is you know we all have
paperwork and stuff that can disprove a
cop you have your card you know your
paperwork there's nothing he can really
do as long as you're not you know hi in
the wrong place like driving my friend
got kicked off the bus he was on the
greyhound uh-huh
they said he smelled like weed he's like
yeah damn right I'm a medical marijuana
patient and they're like no you can't be
high on the bus he's trying to throw a
fit but I mean look we don't know what
they can do this discrimination right I
agree that's what you flip on the bird
you still gotta walk to wherever yeah
that sucks well see this you know get
every insulting my buddies willing and
able he's a cool body guy but what if
somebody really sick was just [ __ ] you
know going across the country yeah
[Music]
always even when I don't have stuff on
me it just comes from my work and my
hobbies but uh I always smell like it
and I don't think I wouldn't like to you
know not like it yeah nice about like
weed me yeah that would really suck if I
was needing to get somewhere can so we
did like twice 24 minutes here any cool
things to shout out we're taking dad's
before the show we've got a bunch of
titanium and we're like we should shout
out tasks on the show so what I have
tasks shout out from the three of us
here for sure he's a machinist is a
rapper he's an innovator
she does a little bit everything when
you meet him and he hang out them at the
cup they just like normal dude he's like
what's up man he remembers us he knows
who you are he doesn't forget your face
the highly-educated hoverboard
that's pretty awesome alright that does
it have add a break attached to it so
yeah that's test
all right check out my friends ad Jesse
grows on Twitter or Instagram I don't
know if he has a Twitter Facebook Tumblr
[Music]
a little everybody in the Curtin
who's doing the what's that one called
massroots there's anybody on massroots
I've got one I posted one picture I'm so
overwhelmed with social media and
Facebook just stop sending me games if
you follow me on Facebook just obscene
games cuz I don't play it I'll take
those wants you to play the candy crush
saga my to my wife gets death threats
over also there's a new Hydra store yeah
I say hello if you're in the area yeah
stuff in cheapest prices south of Denver
really they honestly best prices sounds
of Denver did Pueblo Colorado on 4th
Street it's on East 4th
[Music]
okay yeah
big extra thanks to those guys for
stopping by and doing a podcast with me
they came here right after work that
[ __ ] to do they took a moment out of
their day to come and record with me
really appreciate it shout out to Jesse
shout out to Spence
be sure to follow both of those guys on
Instagram alright so this is the part of
the show where we give thanks to
somebody who I believe has been crucial
to the cannabis movement in the past we
have given thanks to people such as marc
emery jack herer
ginny cush or head servantes on this
episode i want to give a big cannabis
thank you - Keith Stroud mr. Keith
Straub is a Washington DC Public
Interest attorney who found it normal in
1970 strop obtained his undergraduate
degree in political science from the
University of Illinois in 1965 and in
1968 he graduated from Georgetown Law
School in Washington DC following two
years as staff counsel for the National
Commission on product safety mr. Straub
founded normal and ran the organization
through 1979 during which 11 states
decriminalized minor marijuana offenses
I should take a second and explain to
you what normal is normal stands for the
National Organization for the Reform of
Marijuana Laws that's right mister strop
was the founder of this organization
which actually was the first group I
ever heard of as an activist group for
cannabis back in High Times Magazine
many many years ago and I actually think
I saw Tommy Chong or somebody really
famous warning a normal shirt and I was
really proud to see that so Keith strop
is the founder one of the guys that got
this huge movement sort of public and
political so strop has also practice
criminal law lobbying on Capitol Hill
for family farmers and artists and for
several years so his executive director
for the National Association of criminal
defense lawyers which is the NACDL which
I would have just wish I would have read
just that anyway in 1992 strop was the
recipient of the Richard J Dennis drug
peace award for outstanding achievement
in the field of drug policy reform
presented by the drug Policy Foundation
in Washington DC
in 1994 straw presented resumed his work
with normal rejoining the Board of
Directors and serving again as executive
director through 2004 is currently
serving as legal counsel with normal mr.
Straub has appeared on numerous
television shows such as The O'Reilly
Factor crossfire Buchanan and press and
Hannity and Colmes I've actually been in
the same room with this guy at a couple
of parties and events he was at the High
Times Cannabis Cup where he received an
award he's just such a chill dude
he beams with energy he seems really
smart he's always got people around him
so he's he speaks really well he seems
super intelligent but he doesn't he
doesn't talk to the to the non
suit-wearing guys like they aren't just
as smart as the guys in the suits which
I find to be really cool he paved the
way for stoners he is paving the way he
still helps normal fight the fight
they're heavily involved in the
legalization movement so I wanna give a
big huge shout to mr. Keith Straub thank
you thank you for what you've done with
normal thank you for what you've done
for the movement I'm not sure that this
podcast would be possible without you
much respect so that was a portion where
I give thanks I want to give thanks to
you guys for listening to the show we've
made it through 14 episodes now I'll be
back in just a couple of days with an
episode about cloning and I'll have a
little bit of news for you
I know that the show is over please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store some
tried row culture by the review section
give us a five star rating and type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I'll read your comments
on the show don't forget the shows
available on iTunes stitcher swell that
I am and also that's well dot am excuse
me I might have had a few tabs today
swell dot am and also all of the
episodes are available on I read
genetics Colorado dot-com make sure you
check out I read genetics Colorado comm
check out the photo gallery check out
the genetics page check out the store
just do a little browsing we'd
appreciate that once again I want to
thank Jesse and Spence for coming and
hanging out with
me so until next time take the fat dad
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome to episode number 15 of the
agriculture podcast thanks for joining
me for another episode need to give a
big shout out to DJ nicotine for letting
me play music off his SoundCloud page
thanks a lot I appreciate that you're
listening to DJ Nick at T big shout out
to our friends at oil slick this podcast
is brought to you by oil slick oil slick
tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick pad comm for more
information - make sure you follow oil
slick on twitter find them under an oil
slick pad cinema tweet and let them know
you're listening to the iGrow culture
podcast this podcast is also brought to
you by nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauged
green genetics apply to labs since city
rare dankness mile-high chan adventure I
read genetics and many more trusted
brands if you purchase - 10 packs of ira
genetics you will receive a free five
pack of Bounty Killer while supplies
last and nature's green remedies is
running a special for our podcast
listeners type in coupon code dab live
for 15% off any order and you always get
free priority shipping at nature's green
remedies dot-com also check out nature's
green remedies for more information
about the customer appreciation day sale
they'll be having June 20th 21st and
22nd
get your chance to get a limited-edition
3 pack of hydrogen etics and don't
forget you always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com also
need to give a big shout-out to our
friends at tree hugger com the show is
brought to you in part by tree hugger
com tree hugger com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews
www.rediff.com once again big shout out
to Nick at E play music off his
SoundCloud page
today we're gonna get into a cloning
lesson so I'm gonna take a fat dad and
we'll be right back
[Music]
okay I'm back I found a funny story I
wanted to share with you guys in the
news before we get down to the cloning
lesson I found this in the cannabis tits
written by Ricardo Baca I'm sure a lot
of you guys have heard about this but I
found it highly entertaining and wanted
to talk wanted to talk about it on the
show it says New York Times columnist
Maureen Dowd reported direct from
Colorado's bustling marijuana scene
again on June 3rd where as one of the
popular columnist last pieces talked
with nudist 420 friendly B&amp;B owners in
Denver this one takes readers through
doubts scary trip on edibles
so yeah this lady bought herself some
edibles here in Colorado and she ate him
and she freaked the [ __ ] out so the
article says in don't harsh
our mellow dude dad plans a night inside
her hotel room with a marijuana infused
edible
she got no guidance from the bud tender
on dosage and she wasn't familiar with
the state recommended 10 milligram dose
regarding edibles she definitely didn't
read our useful edibles 101 8 tips for
getting the right dose piece guys
plugging his own stuff so instead she
asked what could go wrong with the bite
or two and then her trip turned into it
dark downward spiral god have you ever
eaten too many edibles I have it's been
a really long time since I've eaten too
many edibles but when I was younger once
I made some cookies
I actually made them and I threw two
ounces of schwag weed in there and a
brownie cookie mix for 24 cookies and I
baked it
I made butter out of it and then I baked
it the butter was green and [ __ ] but I
ate some of it my girlfriend ate some of
it and uncle ate some of it and a friend
ate some of it and nobody went back for
seconds those cookies [ __ ] us up I was
high for two days that was supposed to
go to dinner that night with somebody
with some family so I went over there to
dinner and I just sat with my head
and when people would talk to me I've
just looked at him like would you please
shut up cuz their voices it was annoying
trying to keep up with them talking
I felt [ __ ] and couldn't do it I
would just quit cuz I can't even nothing
they were saying was making any sense to
me I felt like I was trapped in time or
something because they would talk and
then by the time I'd figure out what
they said they were about eight
sentences ahead of themselves I was in a
bad bad bad way
my girlfriend refused to come to dinner
with me that night because she was too
high she ate one of those cookies I ate
two of them she ate one we came home and
we found her well first of all she
called me to ask if she could swallow
the lining of her mouth which I think
she meant her mouth I thought maybe her
tongue I don't know what she meant but
she was super high and we came home and
found her crawling up the stairs and my
uncle he uh he was a 325 pound guy he
had a couple of those cookies in his
eyes or bread like brick-red for two
days straight he said he'd never wanted
to be that high again those cookies I
don't know if it was the schwag weed I
don't know if there was something else
in there we were wrecked but it was it
was no fun to be that high this poor
ladies never consumed cannabis as far as
I know and she is laying in a hotel room
having eaten way too much of a weed
edible and she just flip it out so let's
read a little bit more about what she
says remember her last statement was
what could go wrong with a bite or two
and then her trip turned into a dark
downward spiral but then I thought a
scary shudder go through my body and
brain I barely made it from the desk to
the bed where I lay curled up in a
hallucinatory state for the next eight
hours I was thirsty but couldn't move to
get water or even turn off the lights
I was panting at paranoid sure that when
root when the room service waiter
knocked and I didn't answer he'd call
the police and have me arrested for
being unable to handle my candy so this
lady's flipping out she's so thirsty she
can't reach for water
she can't even turn off the lights she's
laying there panting at paranoid I've
been in a room with a girl who was this
high
and God it was hard to calm her down and
she just wanted to do all the wrong [ __ ]
she wanted to go out in public she
wanted to call people and I was like no
you just gotta be high right here just
keep this high and you're in a little
bubble don't [ __ ] up the rest of your
life just keep it contained sometimes
it's a struggle to keep those kind of
folks in the right state of mind so if
the lady says I strained to remember
where I was or even what I was wearing
touching my green corduroy jeans and
staring at the exposed brick wall is my
paranoia deepened I became convinced
that I had died and no one was telling
me so she said she was straining to
remember where she wasn't what she was
wearing but she vividly seems to
remember touching green corduroy jeans
and a brick wall see she never would
have noticed that stuff if she hadn't
gotten all [ __ ] up she was introduced
to some new things in life poor lady she
is paranoid and freaking out she thought
she was convinced that she had died and
nobody was telling her just imagine
sitting there in a hotel room by herself
thinking you're dead just thinking that
you're dead and what do you do he's
gonna wait for housekeeping to come find
you dead and lay there it had to be the
worst [ __ ] eight hours of her life so
it says this is hardly the first
newspaper columnist to eat too many
edibles and land in a dark place at
least dad didn't up in the didn't end up
in the hospital after a weird trip like
Pittsburgh post-gazette columnist
McKenzie carpenter I might read that
article next we'll open that up in
another tab we'll see what happened to
her let's get through it and see if it's
worth reading I'll keep going on this
one dad goes on and her piece referenced
the two deaths Denver police are linking
two edible marijuana a college student
who jumped to his death and the
observatory park man who hallucinate it
an allegedly shot and killed his wife
and you're gonna say why didn't you talk
about those I didn't want to give more
height to the people that they're trying
to link these deaths to cannabis I
didn't want to push that story even more
I thought it was getting enough press I
chose to ignore that I apologize if you
feel left out that was my responsibility
uh I thought it was my responsibility to
keep my mouth shut on that one but it's
related so we're talking to it or about
it
so she addresses issues of edible
packaging presentation and potency and
she asks Incredibles co-owner bob is
paranoid the Downs most pressing
observation is the column in the column
was a plea for more regulations and
warnings to the casual user I reckoned
that the fact I was not a regular
marijuana smoker made me more vulnerable
and then I should have known better but
it turns out five months in some kinks
need to be ironed out with the
intoxicating open bar at the mile-high
club so there's a lot of stuff going on
people are coming here and doing stuff
like this they're gonna start kind of
making the rules a little tighter for
the guys like us that know what we're
doing so check it out if you come to
Colorado please if you get an edible
that's got 100 milligrams I'm serious
eat a tenth of it one tenth if you're
new at editing oak weed everyday' cool
you don't smoke Colorado weed every day
and you don't eat Colorado edibles every
day these things are made for people
with cancer leukemia glaucoma Crohn's
disease AIDS so people are really trying
to medicate with these these aren't
candies to be [ __ ] with if you take
them seriously respect them eat a tenth
of it you don't feel anything feel
anything you can eat more if you end up
curled up in the [ __ ] corner in your
hotel room you're gonna be like damn I
should've listened to Rasta Jeff on that
podcast and a little bit of that thing
have some respect for the edibles have
some respect for Colorado have some
respect for yourself be safe so I said I
was gonna click on that other article
we'll see what happens
sorry I'm getting a little cold it's a
rainy night in Colorado I left the
window open it got shimmery here or I'm
recording the skin this article the
headline is Saturday diary Dumb and
Dumber getting a mile high in Colorado
all right I read that article just as I
suspected some lady came from another
state her two friends split a candy bar
has a mile-high candy bar actually was
100 milligrams they didn't realize such
she was at the pot shop to be novel she
bought a joint to be cute for friend
bought her an edible they split the
edible they both went to dinner
her friend fainted because she was so
damn high her friend got all freaked out
they ended up at the hospital and the
guy at the doctor at the hospital said
this happens every single day because of
edibles and the lady kind of made a big
deal about it so that's the basic part
of that story she got too [ __ ] up just
another case of exactly what we are
talking about alright guys I'm gonna go
find a hoodie I'm getting a little bit
of cold that's what I'm gonna do I take
a DAB all I'm finding that hoodie and
then we're gonna come back and we're
gonna learn how to cut some clones hang
in there for me oh my god I just hit my
funny bone why do they call that thing
the [ __ ] funny bone that's not
[ __ ] funny at all my fingers are numb
oh god ah alright it's gonna take a
little longer than I thought
I'll be back hold on
[Music]
alright guys I am back got a hoodie took
a couple of dabs and feeling better now
couple episodes ago we did a crash
course in germinating seeds and getting
seeds into the soil to get started if
you guys started seeds you should have
little sprouts pop it up out of the dirt
and everything should be growing off to
a good start looking happy one thing I
didn't talk enough about was the light
scheduled for your new seedlings a t5
light is perfect I use a 24 hour light
cycle when my plants are small I don't
let him sleep until they get a little
bit bigger like I said T fives are
perfect for that metal halide lamp is
perfect for that you don't need anything
big like a 400 watt is almost overkill
to start your seeds you can't start them
under a thousand but it's not necessary
at all t5 lights are perfect for that
little fluorescence so the guys you
people that started ceilings you can
kick back and let your babies grow while
we teach everyone how to take a clone
but pay attention because you're gonna
be taking clones from that plant that
grows from that seed here in about two
months alright so I feel like if we cut
clones this week and we let them get
rooted over the next couple weeks we
should have clones and seedlings caught
up about the same size and ready for veg
here in just a couple of more episodes
so now let's talk about taking a clone
from a mother or a donor plant a mother
plant is a plant that's kept in veg
indefinitely so that we can take
cuttings from it at any time if you keep
that plant under 24 hours of light or 18
hours of light it won't flower if you
treat it well if you prevent it from
getting root bound and you top it and
take clones from that every so often
that plant will stay in veg so you'll
always have it available because it's
great to have a reliable dependable
strain around that's how you hear about
all the strains that are your favorites
those are kept around as a mother plant
by somebody who has given them out in
clone form so a bunch of people don't
have those clones the tangi the Gorilla
Glue
somebody somewhere discovered the
gorilla glue or even Girl Scout cookies
somebody discovered the Girl Scout
cookies and some seeds they had they
gave out a clone of that
somebody gave they let it grow into a
mother plant they took a clone of that
and gave it out now those strains are
all over the Girl Scout cookies is
available from California to New York
now because of clones and cuttings and
mother plants so if you keep that mother
plant in veg forever then this strain
will exist forever you can always go to
that mother plant
cut enough clones off of it to fill up
your flower room and then you can keep
growing more crops and more crops of
Girl Scout cookies or gorilla glue or
grateful dog or whatever it is that
you've grown from seed or gotten a clone
up you can keep it going forever that
way some people are gonna ask why they
shouldn't grow from seed every time they
start a new grow well the reason for
that is because seeds do show genetic
variation there will be different
phenotypes which is something we'll talk
about in a later episode but not all
seeds are gonna look the same imagine
your brothers and sisters don't all look
the same but they came from the same
parents you're the same seed stock but
you look just a little bit different
than each other because that's the way
that genetics work so it's good to have
a clone of something that you've ran and
trusted and you know is reliable because
medical patients are limited to a
certain amount of plants and if you're
running plants that are not going to be
what you need in the end he kind of
might be wasting space i heavily
encourage seed running because i do like
finding those genetic differences but
I've got space I'm an experienced grower
so once you're comfortable with it I
definitely encourage you to do some
seeds but let's get back to talking
about mother plants the easiest way to
find a mother plant is to get a clone
that's been tested and proven you want
to know that it's a female you want to
know that it's dank good medicine you
want to know that it grows without any
trouble so usually if you get it from a
shop or a fellow grower or breeder your
clones are gonna be solid one thing I
should mention that it's your
responsibility to take a new clone that
you got from somebody and make sure
there are no bugs on it you can't get a
clone from somebody and then blame them
for having given you bugs later on if
you get mites or whiteflies from a clone
that's like not having safe sex you
can't blame it on the person that gave
that [ __ ] to you you should have been
taking care of that [ __ ] in advance so
be careful with the clone that comes in
there are plenty of ways to treat for
spider mites for white flies for
anything you should come up with a good
regimen maybe that
something we'll talk about on a future
episode is a way to get rid of and
prevent bugs on incoming clones one way
to do it is to grow from seed but let's
get back to clones again now once you've
got your clone and it's healthy and bug
free transplant your little clone into a
large pot I wouldn't use any smaller
than a 5 gallon pot for a mother plant
so get into a 5 gallon pot keep it under
24 hours or 18 hours of lights and
people do 18 somebody 24 I like to keep
my mothers under 24 hours of light
that's my personal preference I feel
like they grow way fast and they like to
give me lots of cuttings and they look
really healthy so take that little baby
that somebody gave you put it in a let
it get good and rooted put it in a
five-gallon pot let it grow you know let
it get quite a few nodes on it let it
get growing and then you're gonna want
to take the top right out of it boom
that's your first cutting that you're
gonna want to take you're gonna kind of
want to even out the height of that
plant so that every node starts growing
up to be the same size training a mother
plant how to grow by pruning it properly
is an art that will take you a few
plants of making them look super ugly
before you catch on but that's alright
something I do about once every year
irie mom all of my mother's so I'll take
my mother plant and I'll take six or
seven cuttings off of it and then I'll
take the best one of that and I'll root
it or I'll get it in a cup I'll get it
growing I'll get it into a pot and that
becomes my new mother plant for the next
year so that I have a nice healthy plant
because they I feel like they start
getting their Viggen true bound they get
old they get tired these plants were
only meant to live for a year so if you
try to keep it around for too long it
will kind of lose its vigor so I reclone
it and put some youth back into it so
that's how you could pretty much take a
clone that you're given or bought from a
shop and turn it into your very first
mother plant a lot of people don't have
access to that so they're gonna have to
run seeds and I was talking about that
genetic variation from seed so you're
not guaranteed of what you're gonna get
unless somebody's taken it to the f4 or
f5 stage which that is a whole other
podcast we'll talk about later so if you
don't have access to good clones you're
gonna need to get some seeds and run
some seeds to find your mother plant
what I usually do is I run a pack of
seeds usually between 10 and 50 seeds
depending on the strain of what I'm
looking for
I grow those seeds out and I pay very
close attention to the feds growth
because veg growth is really important
to me I need it to be a good grower I
would like to pay attention to the way
each phenotype branches out I like to
pay attention to the rate it grows I
like to pay attention to how many nodes
and how many little little flower sites
are not flower sites but they will be
flower sites how many of those develop
in a little cluster area along the
branches I like to pay attention so I'm
super careful to feed each plant and
tree each plant the same so that I can
see what each pot has to offer without
messing it up by doing something
different if it's nutrients or training
or trimming or topping or whatever I
treat each one the same so I mix up
enough nutrients in one bucket to feed
all of them are in one res to feed all
of these little seedlings and I feed
them all the exact same [ __ ] I try to
rotate them under the light so that
nobody gets like one spot of the light
has maybe has better lumens there I make
sure that doesn't happen I make sure
they get moved around so that
everybody's kind of treated the same and
I'll show any favoritism once you're big
enough to give me a few cuttings I take
your cutting or a clone from each plant
and I carefully label the plants and I
label the cuttings so I'll take I'm
super careful
I take plant a and clone a and make sure
to label those so you got your big
mother plant is plant a you got a little
clone is cloning then you got plant B
clone B all the way down to however many
you got you can do it my number you can
name them I've got a friend who names
them after old ladies for some reason
I've got friends that name them after
cartoon characters I always seem to name
my stuff after Grateful Dead songs just
something something that means something
to you letters and numbers work but once
I see what my my clothes are gonna root
and I'm safe to flower out that original
seedling plant I flowered out and see
what I get from them now a lot of people
will keep that original plant around as
a mother plan that seedling plant that
you planted a lot of people I believe so
as well it's got more vigor it's a
stronger plant
so they want to keep that one around as
a mother and na flower that one out
they'll wait for those other clones that
they took to root and then they'll
flower those but I think I saved time by
blooming out the original plants it's
already grown and ready to go and I do a
technique called lolli popping anyway I
take the bottoms off of the plants where
the light's not gonna penetrate those
little bottom branches I cut those off
because I feel like if the light's not
gonna penetrate down there there's no
reason to really have that on there it's
just gonna take energy from the tops
where I could build big fat heady
nuggets and there's I've learned how to
grow plants with no law or no little
tiny bud anymore all my stuff is big and
chunky just by doing a little a little
bit of pruning like that so me I'll take
a couple clones from that area and I
think those make great clones and flower
that original sealing plant some people
are against that but that's just I have
great experience doing it it's already
grown it's already grown you've already
put a couple months into it you've got
clones of it you're cool but during the
flowering process sometimes I'll even
pull out plants early if they show signs
of weakness I've seen plants that just
grow really wispy really weak maybe ice
thrown away the wrong [ __ ] but I need
stuff that breathes heavily and that
grows solid so I don't want to be
playing with those little weak [ __ ]
just the way we do it we practice
eugenics in the breeding room definitely
definitely isolate males or
hermaphrodites go immediately if it
shows signs of hermaphrodite
I throw that sucker away really quickly
we'll talk more about hermaphrodites in
another show I guess isolate the males
and if I'm not looking for a male to
breed I throw the male's away as soon as
I identify them if I'm looking for a
breeding male I already had that in mind
when I planted those seeds I've got some
seeds down right now that I'm hoping for
a male I'm hoping for three to five
males out of one of those packs I'm
hoping for three to choose from
selecting a male is a fun process in my
opinion so anyway you guys should throw
away your males if you're new you don't
want to have the males around those are
gonna create pollen those are gonna put
season on your crop which is probably
not what you want at this point so at
this point if I throw away a male or a
shitty plant I also toss all the clones
and that way you just took
you made space you just took your
numbers down one thing I should mention
about is uh I should talk about you
should plan if you can plant as many
seeds as you think you're able to handle
you need a vegging plant a clone and a
flowering plant so think about whatever
you're doing that seedling you're gonna
need three versions of those so if
you're able to have 15 plants plant five
if you're ready to have six I guess only
plant two a lot of guys forget that
they're gonna take clones they're gonna
have a mother plant they need plants and
veg they're gonna have plants in flower
so just try to keep in mind how many
plants you're gonna end up with because
you're gonna it's gonna be like anything
else you fall in love with you're gonna
be like I need a plant and then you're
gonna pretty soon you're gonna be like I
need a room and then you're gonna be
like I need a facility and then we've
seen how it goes you're on the internet
too so I would say plant as many seeds
as you think you can safely and legally
handle but plat one extra because some
shits gonna die something's gonna fail
this plant one extra you're gonna have
to think about space and stuff plan
ahead that's something that I like to
stress when we're growing here
so we'll let the best-looking plants
finish now don't be shy don't be afraid
like if you don't like the way something
grows if a plant is really pissing you
off cut that thing down we're gonna grow
more weed in the future it's not the end
some people are gonna cringe because
maybe you just cut down the greatest
plant ever but as a new grower don't
worry you'll move on I've cut down I've
lost strains that I miss and you know
what I bred more I've grown more
forgotten all about him until now that
I'm talking about it so uh I usually
harvest trim and cure the plants smoke
all of them myself not all of it but I
smoke a little bit of each plant myself
I also take a couple samples of each
phenotype and I give them to friends
help me decide which is best farm I'm a
medical marijuana provider so I have a
great team of testers for me that will
smoke and take good notes I've given
them a little a little chart to fill out
for me to tell me what they think of
each strain and I don't tell them what
it is I just label it a B C B or
whatever and they tell me what they
think of each one and then usually I
agree I usually know what they're gonna
want me to keep so I let those guys
smoke it once I've narrowed it down to a
few my favorites I take them to a lab
for testing
I should take all of them but honestly
the
a little bit expensive and it's two
hours away and I think it's better for
me to let the smokers narrow it down
because they know more than the numbers
do they know more than the machines and
that's what I'm growing it for is the
people that are smoking I'm not trying
you just grow for height numbers
sometimes I the plant that has sometimes
I like the plant that actually has lower
numbers those guys like the flavor or
something of a plant with lower numbers
and I think I can usually predict the
high testers I've said this plant is
gonna test higher and I'm usually right
to give you guys an idea of what some of
the stuff has been testing at I'm gonna
pull up a PDF guy you have here on my
macbook I just have to find it right
quick I've put a lot of stuff going on
here this is these tests were done just
a couple of maybe a month ago it's
opening the PDF right now it's taking a
sweet time so I grew I brought a strain
called lemon Jeffrey it's that's
actually the lemons gone across the
Golden go and she tested at twenty four
point three for THC that's kind of a
high test let me find another one for
you here the Capleton
that's the white widow times grateful
dog got to blow it up it's real small
here on the screen ballot is twenty
point five eight percent THC so that's
kind of what we're testing in the 20s
got the Grateful dog here also grateful
dog she tested at twenty three point
three two percent THC a so those are
that's kind of what some things are
coming out at they said at the lab
anything over seventeen percent THC is
actually impressive so that means we're
doing some stuff right over here I
should probably give you huge shout out
to the guys over at steep hill Halen
labs they guided me through getting my
stuff tested they gave me a sweet tour
of their lab in their facility and they
got the results to me in like three days
so big shout out steep hill Halen
definitely recommend those guys if
you're not able to get your stuff tested
don't worry that's not it's up to more
up to the people that are smoking and
then up to the lab like I said anyway
but either way once you've got your
keeper and you've got a clone of it
that should become your new mother plan
what like if you grew out a seed pack
and you and all your friends whoever's
gonna be partaking and participating
smoking enjoying you your girlfriend
your best friend whoever you know make
sure that you guys all kind of agree on
the same one and you keep that one it's
usually it's usually a no-brainer
that's your new mother you're gonna have
that around forever or until you find
something better to grow but I would
definitely recommend sticking with that
strain for a couple of runs so that you
can build a relationship and kind of
learn the plant and see some consistency
and see your improvement either way now
you've got your keeper you've got a
clone of it you keep that plant around
forever so that you always have clones
of it and you've always got that strain
to grow I keep my mother plants in large
pots to keep them from becoming
rootbound I'm going to switch to air
pots
they're not cloth pots they're plastic
pots but they've got holes in them and
they're designed to keep the dirt in
while they still have holes in them I
think that those will be great for my
roots I'll be able to keep a mother
plant happier for a little bit longer
keep them under at least 18 hours of
light I do 24 hours of my lights never
go off in my mother room my mom's are
under commercial t fives and they love
it make sure you love on those plants
often love on them once a week go take
some cuttings off of them keep them the
right size trim them up give them a lot
of airflow give them space keep them
Lively take cuttings even if you don't
need them because that makes your plant
keep growing and stay active feeding a
nice healthy veg nutrient regimen lots a
night not lots of nitrogen but enough
nitrogen you don't want to overfeed the
nitrogen take good care of them don't
let any bugs get to these plants treat
them with neem oil once a week if you
can if you're around other gardens or if
you're around places where people have
bugs maybe you need to step up your
treatment game maybe you need to find a
more integrated pest management system
which we will talk about in more
episodes I've got a friend who's really
good at such things he'll come and help
us out with that in the future
all right so now we understand the
mother plants right I hope we've got a
good understanding we put some time into
that one let's actually take some
clothes from the mother plant or any
plant that's actually in the vegetative
state you can clone from flowering
plants but I definitely don't recommend
it the hormones and those plants have
changed you've got to kind of revert the
whole plant back to the vegetative state
while it roots so unless you're
experienced and that strain is super
amazing I wouldn't even attempt it I
would just grow some more seeds or get
some on the clones so I need to grab a
drink and I need to take a fat dab and
then I will be right back and we will
cut some clothes together all right guys
I am back and it's time to cut some
clones the first thing I should say is
that the most important part of cutting
clones is cleanliness be clean I wear
rubber gloves while I cut clones I also
clean all my tools with rubbing alcohol
before I get started and I try to make
sure take have my cloning my working and
my clone room really clean everything I
use is it's cleaned right before I cut
my clones so you're also gonna need a
few items you'll need a pair of good
scissors or a razor blade you want
something that makes a nice clean cut on
the first try you don't want to go
sawing off little pieces of your planner
you just want to whack it one time and
be done you need some good rooting
hormone or cloning gel you're also gonna
need a cup of water and you should have
some pH down to lower the pH of your
water what comes out of your tap is
probably pH around 8 or 7 we want to get
for cutting clones we want to get about
6.0 would be ideal all right so there
are two ways of cloning that I want to
discuss today one is the old rock wool
cube and tray and dough method and the
other is the EZ cloner style method I
prefer the EZ cloner because they are
fast and simple but they're also kind of
expensive a good easy cloners gonna run
you probably 250 to 300 bucks plus
shipping plus you got to get a couple of
nutrients for it so for the cost of that
shipping you could probably get the
entire set up for the dome and rock wool
cube and tres style
so if you're using the dome and tray
method you'll need a cloning tray a dome
to put over your babies well what the
dome does is it traps humidity in and
gives your clones a happy environment
you'll need rock wool cubes or something
similar to that I've used rapid rooters
and I've used route riots there pretty
much all the same thing for this type of
cloning I use dip and grow for my root
hormone I basically just dip it in there
and it's ready to go if you're doing the
tray and dough method I also recommend
that you use a heat mat and a thermostat
to keep the clones warm that'll help
increase humidity and also increase your
survival rate for your new clones so if
you're doing the easy color method all
you need is the cloner
some nutrients and your neoprene discs
to put the clones into for the easy
cloner I use clone X for the gel and I
also like to add some stuff called clear
res I'm able to take some pretty big
clones a route fairly quickly and I can
usually put them into dirt in 7 to 10
days
use an EZ corner so first I'll describe
using the EZ cloner method make sure
hands are clean and hopefully where are
some rubber gloves make sure your
scissors are clean make sure your mother
plant is healthy I like to water the
plant with plain water the day that I'm
going to cut clones from it I'll just
put a plain pH balanced water right
through it in the morning and then I'll
cut clones that night is usually the way
I like to do it so then I get my clone
or all set up I've got the EZ cloner
I've got to fill it with water it's
running it's got nutrients in it its pH
dat 6.0 for my ez cloner I use advanced
nutrients jungle juice grow and micro
for my ez cloner
I mix my solution in 5-gallon buckets in
each 5-gallon bucket I use 25
milliliters of grow and 15 milliliters
of micro okay
each 5-gallon bucket gets that I feel
each cloner just below the sprayers make
sure not to overfill your clone ER with
water because it will shoot the water
all over the place now once you've got
it filled up then you adjust the pH to
6.0 and make sure you have the neoprene
discs in there before you plug it in and
turn it on or the water will go spraying
all over the place again so now we need
a healthy mother plant and a few healthy
shoots to cut off so the lower branches
are easier to clone because they're soft
and the fresh roots will grow out of
that more easily but I like to take the
tops of my plants for a fat clone so
from the top of your plant find a node
that looks healthy has a nice set of fan
leaves at the top something that sticks
up and looks like it'll become a nice
healthy plant on its own at the top if
you've got a new plant that hasn't ever
been cut before it's already got one fat
top sticking off of it follow that down
to an intersection tour when you cut it
you're gonna leave a little the little
tiny flowers that have just are the
little leaves have grown out of there
leave that leave that behind and maybe
it'll grow into two spots if you cut it
right you'll learn how to do it after a
little while so you got a spot that
looks like it's gonna become its own
nice happy plant cut that section off
try to give yourself about a six inch
section I like to clean off most of the
extra leaves on the clone I only keep
the top one or two pair of leaves for my
clone so cut this piece quickly I keep a
cup of water next to me and I drop my
cuttings directly into the cut of water
or into the cup of water to prevent
what's called an embolism from
developing in the fresh cut so I've got
my scissors in one hand I'll take a
couple of cuts
snip snip I've got two fat looking
6-inch cuts with nice leaves at the top
I just drop those into a cup of water
and I gather gather up cuts like I'll
take however many I need if I need 10 or
15 I'll just take them off and have them
in that cup and then walk to the easy
cloner so that I'm not cutting clothes
that sit there and have a chance to dry
up all right so I take enough cuts and
I've got a cup full and then I started
dipping my cups out of my cuts into a
one at a time into the clone acts like
to get a lot of clone X on my cuttings
so I pour a small amount onto I use a
plate because it's glass and the stuff I
won't I feel like that absorbs and I
don't waste it so I pour some out onto a
plate and I roll the bottom inch inch
and a half of my cutting into the gel
and I get it good and covered and then I
take the neoprene disc out of the cloner
don't try to shove the clone into the
neoprene wallets in the cloner that's
caveman style you're gonna fail you're
gonna kill the clone so take that little
neoprene disc out of the cloner open it
up like a pacman and put your disc put
your clone in there
and set your clone back into the cloner
so basically you cut it you store it in
that cup for just a second until you
have enough cuttings you cut it you put
it in the cup you get your cup and over
to your cloning area you dip it you put
it inside that neoprene disc and then
you set that neoprene disc right inside
of your cloner
and you leave it along you just cut your
first clone then you repeat that until
your cloners full just dip it and stick
it dip it and stick it over and over
again I don't even have to check my
cloners for like 4 or 5 days after I
start I just check to make sure that the
water isn't splashing out out of any of
the inputs where they are they and put
our output slots where you plug it in
and where the air hose goes and stuff
like that just make sure the water
hasn't evaporated or gotten too low and
you can mostly set it and forget about
it until the clones are ready to
transplant if you're taking clones of
multiple strains make sure you figured
out a way to mark everything and
identify which clones you've taken
sometimes I'll just use a sticky label
and put a name on it and stick that in
the row or on the front to identify
which row those clones are sometimes I
use a cup and I cut it into small like a
Solo Cup and I cut it into strips like
the size of a plant label and I write
the name on there and I just stick that
in a little pac-man slot of the neoprene
you'll know what I mean when you play
with the neoprene by the pac-man slot
right in the mouth just put it in the
mouth there and then each clones label
be sure to to label your clones if
you're working with more than one strain
there's nothing like having a clone that
you're not sure what it is
you grow it out and you get to wait till
about day 30 or 40 to figure out what
you're working with sometimes alright
that should get you guys through the
basics of using the ez cloner I feel
like I need to take a DAB and get a
beverage right quick again I hope you
guys join me and take a quick dab and
then I'll be back with a the lesson on
how to use the tray and doe method hang
in there I'll be right back yeah through
the magic of editing I am back already
so the Train dough method that we were
talking about will require a little more
attention you'll have to pay more
attention you'll have to check on it
you'll have to keep the humidity high in
there you will need to set up your heat
mat and a timer or thermostat
don't let the clones get too hot just
about 75 degrees is right aim for 70%
humidity set the tray on top of your
heat mat
I've used everything from Rockwell cubes
to rapid Reuters to every brand of root
cubes there are most of them work the
same get what you like or whatever is
available to you Rockwell is simple and
it's inert so that's a good way to start
there are no nutrients and they're not
like the ones that don't have nutrients
in them I now take whatever you selected
and soak it in water that's been pH day
at six point oh like you use Rockwell
cubes so be sure to soak those things
thoroughly they like to float and they
don't absorb the water they just float
sometimes so I fill a five-gallon bucket
with water and I drop all my cubes in
there and I let them soak I pull them
out one at a time and set them in the
tray you're gonna select your cutting
the same way as you did before you'll
take the cuttings the same way you'll
need to cut a nice angle at the tip make
a nice long angle because that area that
exposed areas where the root tips will
start to develop so have a cup of
cuttings and a nice with nice angled
cuts on the tips one at a time get those
into the dip and growing different girl
you just have to dip it right into there
you don't have to leave it in there so
just dip it in there and then gently
slide your cutting right into that
rockwool cube do not go directly into
the bottle of dip and grow pour some of
the different grow out into a shot glass
or something similar you don't want to
contaminate that whole bottle if one of
your plants has a problem and you put it
into that dip and grow now you just
infected the whole bottle whatever kind
of dip cloning solution you're gonna use
that may work in a dipping Road I think
it's got a little bit of alcohol in
there but still we don't want to risk it
all right I'd be careful not to bend or
break your cutting if you feel it snap
you can cut the broken part off if it's
still long enough and try to redo Pitre
stick it but I would just take another
cutting if you have it around
don't waste space with one you're not
certain is gonna work try to get your
cutting about a half inch or more down
into the rockwool cube if you can once
you've finished cutting and dipping and
sticking the cuttings you can put the
dome over the tray I leave the events
mostly closed I leave them just a little
tiny bit open to let some air flow on
the sides if you have side vents but I
leave all those top events closed
I'll even close for a day or two and let
that humidity build up in there put them
under the light that's always on and let
them take root t5 lights are perfect for
this LEDs are good also be sure to check
the humidity in the tamper every few
hours and make sure the cubes are moist
and never dry
if those rockwool cubes or whatever kind
of rooters you're using if those become
too dry
the clothes will die so make sure you
pay attention I had about two weeks
hopefully you'll have happy clones that
are ready for transplanting I feel like
I've gone over the basics of using the
dome and tray method I honestly haven't
done that for quite a while since I've
gotten the EZ cloners I haven't looked
back that's the only way to go when I do
it right and I pay attention and I keep
everything clean I get about a 99 to
100% success rate using my any easy
cloners they come out with big fat roots
and they're nice and healthy and ready
to go so that's the way I do it if I
skipped anything or if I said anything
that you felt was off please feel free
to email me I feel like I've given the
contact information out quite a few
times just to be clear it's I grow
culture at hotmail.com
you can tweet me at I grow culture can
find me on Facebook and I grow culture
we are not hard to find I was looking
for images to post on Instagram and I
found a forum post with tons of
information and pics I will post a link
to that on the Facebook page and I'll
try to tweet it between that post in my
rant you should have sexy clones in
about two weeks I think that wraps up my
Grove lesson for the week I hope you
guys have good looking clones I hope you
have good happy mother plants in future
episodes we're gonna talk about the
vegetative growth stage talking about
keeping your plants healthy we'll talk
about keeping your plants bug free we're
gonna cover a lot of things on this show
I hope you guys stick around for a lot
of the stuff that I have planned for you
alright now there's a part of the show
where we take a moment to give thanks to
somebody who I feel has been crucial or
beneficial or instrumental to our
cannabis movement and/or industry this
week we would like to give thanks to a
nice lady named brownie Mary Jane
Rathbun this article comes from paper
mag comm they actually wrote an article
called ten historic heroes of marijuana
legalization by Abdullah t-kid Saeed I
hope I pronounced that correctly it's a
great article we're going to give thanks
to Mary Jane Rathbun I made her buzzword
in state medical marijuana efforts as
compassion seeing the relief that
cannabis can bring to severely ill
patients makes the laws restricting them
seem cruel and unjust the highly
publicized story of brownie Mary was one
of the first to inspire this sentiment
as a hospital volunteer she distributed
weed brownies to AIDS patients
on the sly when she got busted for it
the public was on her side who can get
mad at a sweet old lady giving brownies
to sick people
brownie Mary Jane's Fame spent most of
her life dedicated to Cherry charity
work and was instrumental in the passage
of California's Proposition P and
proposition 215 now this was a time
before marijuana acceptance before
medical marijuana so this lady had huge
balls for being an old lady we give you
a huge thanks we I personally appreciate
and hugely respect what that lady did
what you did for sick people for sick
people in need for people in the
hospital on their death beds trying to
survive trying to be happy we need more
people like you fighting the good fight
for us so we give you huge thanks thank
you Mary Jane Rathbun all right guys I'm
gonna wrap this show up I went over time
a little bit I wanted to be closer to 40
minutes I'm already getting close for
the 45 minute mark before I go and
remind everybody to leave some comments
now that the show is over to go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
iGrow culture find the review section
give us a five star rating type in a
comment let me know what you think about
the show and I will read your comments
on the show don't forget - the show is
available on iTunes stitcher swell that
I ain't dot am I have a hard time with
that one and you can always find the
show on I read genetics Colorado com
there are limited episodes available on
most of the services like iTunes and
stitcher
but over I read genetics Colorado calm
we have every episode posted from one
all the way to whatever we are up to
number 15 will always be there keep them
all up there all the time on the next
episode we're gonna talk a little bit
about some change in some Jamaican laws
and we'll get a little bit more into
grow class and we will have Jesse back
soon for more outdoor grow lessons
stay tuned keep listening I'll be back
in about a week with another show for
you till then take a phat dab give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 16 of the
iGrow culture podcast I'm your host
they call me Rasta Jeff thanks again for
joining me for another episode proud to
announce that this podcast is brought to
you by high Gro indoor growing supplies
hi girll indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the brand new Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great way grew
Denver calm for current store hours and
special sales I also want to give a big
shout out to our friends at oil slick
oil slick tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick pad comm for more
information make sure you follow oil
slick on twitter find them under an oil
slick pad sit them between and tell them
you're listening to the iGrow culture
podcast podcast is also brought to you
by nature's green remedies dot-com visit
nature's dream remedies com for gage
green genetics apply to labs since city
rare dankness mile high can adventure
IRA genetics and many more trusted
brands if you purchase 210 packs of ira
genetics you will receive a free five
pack while supplies last
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code dab life for 15% off any
order and you always get free shipping
at nature's green remedies dot-com that
coupon code does expire June 30th so you
better get on that pretty quickly I do
need to give a big shout out to
everybody who participated and supported
the nature's green remedies customer
appreciation day sale everything should
be in the mail and on its way to you you
probably have it in your hands already
thanks for your support
we also want to give a big thank you to
our friends at Treehugger comm this
episode is brought to you in part by
tree hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger comm for
concert and festival news and reviews
WWE a girl calm but respect all of our
sponsors for making the show possible
I'd like to take a second and read the
comments that actually found on stitcher
there there they do exist I found it
tada I don't even know how I stumbled
across this but anyway her first comment
comes from our friend mr. omni o shadow
mr. Omni oh he follows us on Twitter now
I find a comment on here thanks for all
the support dude he says educational and
amusing I look forward to this weekly
positive to this weekly podcast as it's
both informative and then in parentheses
he says even for the seasoned pros they
says it's informative educational and I
enjoy its relaxed easygoing style
weather presenter only or with guests I
can pretty much be sure of a laugh along
at some point some point too as there's
often a laugh or two moments included
thanks dude I'm glad you appreciate that
that's kind of what I try to do I look
goofy dude if you know me personally
anybody that knows me you know I'm a
goofy son-of-a-bitch so I try to keep
myself together it keep it composed
while I do the podcast but sometimes we
just gotta bust out on the show so
thanks for having fun with me thanks for
learning with me are you a seasoned pro
dude I'd like to know more about you
tell me what your grow level is are you
a white belt grower are you a black belt
send me a tweet well we'll read more of
your stuff thanks a lot for the support
the next comment comes from Henry 710 he
says exactly what I'm looking for this
podcast answers the questions I've been
too afraid to ask
Colorado is lucky to have these guys
well thanks a lot man that means a lot
to me that's what I'm here for is to
answer the questions of the people in
other places can't ask a lot of us are
growing we're hiding still there are
only a few states that are well almost
half the states are illegal now but
they're that means there's half that you
can't have weed you can't grow weed so
you got to be on the undercover so you
can listen to this podcast while you're
working in your garden while you're
driving to work while you're doing
whatever you can learn some [ __ ] so I'm
glad I'm helping you guys out and uh
Colorado is lucky to have us I guess I
just feel like it's my duty I guess the
world is lucky to have me feeling like I
mean
to do this but I feel really blessed and
really lucky I blessed is the word
there's no luck involved I blessed it
worked hard and I was given what I
worked for to be this educated and this
just good with the plant so I feel like
I got to return it to you cuz I I love
it I just love it so I got to give that
love back so I send it out to you guys
with the show my return it's my Karma
the next comment is from our friend
overgrow the Gov what's up bro Ana who
you are he says the info show dude you
rocked it with the info on this one Jeff
great show I know who you are bro thanks
a lot man I appreciate you listening I
should appreciate the support he did
some help help me out with the favor the
other day when put some fliers out I
appreciate the help and support bro so
big shout out to overgrow the Gov man I
appreciate the comments you guys left
it's good to know people are listening
and appreciating the show and learning
something I put a little bit of work
into this and it all pays off reading
those kinds of comments I truly do
appreciate that
so uh if you guys leave your comments on
stitcher and iTunes I will read those in
a future episode you don't want to leave
a comment on iTunes or stitcher you can
tweet me at agriculture or you can find
me on Facebook and I'll respond to you
there I keep saying it if you want to
say something anonymously send me a
personal message and I will keep it
private and I'll respond to you and help
you out if you have a question or
something like that
you can always email me at agriculture
at hotmail.com coming up in this episode
we're gonna talk about putting those
clones we cut last week into some dirt
but first we're gonna read some news let
me take a DAB real quick and we will be
right back with a few cool news reports
hang tight
[Music]
all right before we get into the news I
want to do our first product review on
the show our good friends at Mary Jane's
glass haberdasher in Pueblo Colorado
we're kind enough to give me the cloud
poor cloud tank m2 to review on the show
it's a handy little dab pen I've been
smoking some lemon Jeffry out of it for
about a week and a half now
it hasn't burned out on me yet which is
actually pretty impressive for most dab
pins it gave me the Viking battery to
attach to it they said any battery of
this voltage will work the next part is
actually the cloupor tank it fits into
the is actually the cloud poor body it
fits right under the battery it just
screws in the next part is the heating
element so if that part dies you can
just unscrew the heating element and
replace it the next part is the tank
where the your extracts your
concentrates will go in I've got lemon
Jeffrey in here now it tastes delicious
out of this thing so you put your
concentrate in you screw on the cap and
then it's got this it's like a dome but
it's just a straight cylinder so it's
got a cylinder dome that fits on top of
that piece over the tank and then it's
got a mouthpiece now what I really do
like is they claim that this is all
titanium and that the heating element is
ceramic which is really cool because
what I don't like about a lot of these
dab pins is the plastic II taste that
they get and I'm sure because they do
have that feature where if you hit the
button for 15 seconds or 10 seconds
whatever it turns off right but we've
learned that trick so you just hold it
down for one second last let it go and
then start over again so that you can
keep heating that [ __ ] right but I've
tasted those dab pins melting while I'm
dabbing or while my buddy dabbed it too
long or whichever one of us overheated
it I could taste the plastic this one
I've been heating the [ __ ] out of it I
haven't tasted any plastic yet it did
get clogged up one time but it was
really easy for me to get it clean I've
had two other vape pens that I've
clogged up and once they got clogged
they worked done it does have a dry herb
attachment available but I did not ask
for that I told her I wouldn't use it I
don't like to smoke herb out of a little
pen that seems silly to me I would have
to smoke that have to fill that thing 25
times to get the effect I need but I'm
gonna go and give it four stars or four
leaves out of five because it's a
reliable product it's lasted me two
weeks now it stays charged and charges
quickly it holds
enough extract for me to do what I need
to do I haven't broken it yet it doesn't
taste bad the only thing is it could hit
a little harder like I feel like if they
made these little holes larger or if
they gave me a little bit more heat I'd
get more of a dab it takes you get a
certain amount of time of heat on this
thing and then it cuts off and I feel
like if I preheat it if I hold it down
for half of the time like I'm holding it
now and then I let go and then I
actually go back and hit it that's the
way to get a fat head out of it but I've
learned it I like it so I'm gonna give
it four pot leaves out of five I want to
give a shout out again to our friends
Mary Jane's glass haberdasher what's up
guys thanks for helping us out thanks
for hooking us up with this device I've
been loving it when I'm in a place where
I can't take a DAB and I'd really like
to but I check them out they've got two
locations in Pueblo they are on 1626
highway 50 and they are also on 1019
South Pueblo Boulevard that was our
first product review it's hard to say
when you're dabbed out we'll be right
back with the news here we go
all right it's time for the iGrow
culture news this time we've actually
got some good news to report there's
been plenty of bad [ __ ] going on in the
world but for the world news Jamaica to
decriminalize personal marijuana
possession big up to Jamaica this
article is actually by a Horace helps
from the Chicago Tribune that's a cool
name Horace helps the Jamaican
government has decided to decriminalize
the possession of small amounts of
marijuana joining the trickle of
countries moving to soften laws on the
drug known on the Caribbean island as
ganja Minister of Justice Mark Golding
made the announcement at the afternoon
news conference on Thursday saying that
Jamaica's dangerous drug acts would
formerly be amended this summer so it
looks like Jamaica is gonna you know let
you have some ganja Creedmoor the
cabinet of Prime Minister Portillo
Simpson Miller is at Porsha or for TIA
somebody tweet me and tell me a Tygra
culture the cabinet of Prime Minister
Portilla Simpson Miller made the
decision on June 2nd he said cabinet
approved certain changes to the law
relating to ganja these relate to
possession of small quantities of ganja
for personal use the smoking of ganja in
private places and the use of ganja for
medical medicinal purposes he said
approval has been given also to a
proposal for the decriminalization of
the use of ganja for religious purposes
he said so they're doing their laws even
better than Colorado did because in
Jamaica you don't have to get cancer or
get in a car wreck or claim that
something hurts or walk funny you can
just go in and say that it's for
religious purposes and you just grow
some dreadlocks and get your weed Oh
Jamaica alright Uruguay recently became
the latest country to legalize marijuana
use joining several countries in Europe
as well as the United States of God okay
they just worded this one funny the US
states of Colorado and Washington I
thought they were gonna call Colorado in
Washington our own states but they just
weren't that oddly so possession of
small quantities of the drug would
become a non arrest able tickle
infraction in Jamaica resulting in a
fine Golding said
and here's why they did it which i think
is kind of great they say too many of
our young people have ended up with
criminal convictions after being caught
with the spliff something that has
affected their ability to do things like
get jobs and get visas to travel
overseas bolding said he added that the
government would propose a bill in the
Jamaican Parliament soon that will
expose the criminal records of people
convicted for possession of small
amounts of the drug which has grown
widely across Jamaica the change change
means that a person cannot be arrested
if he has in his possession of to fill
up to fifty seven grams of ganja in
public space anyone ticketed will be
given 30 days to pay the fine failure of
which will result in becoming a minor
offence resulting in the offender doing
court-ordered community service
according to Golding possession of ganja
for religious or therapeutic purposes as
prescribed by a registered medical
practitioner or for scientific research
by an accredited institution will also
be decriminalized so big up to Jamaica
shout out much love much respect they're
doing the right thing it looks like
there's nothing in there that I wanted
to argue with they're gonna let you have
medicine medicinal marijuana they're
gonna let you have religious marijuana
which is damn cool non arrests able to
katha Belov ence infraction not even an
offence an infraction in Jamaica so you
just get a ticket now and they're doing
it for the right reasons that they don't
want if they keep [ __ ] up the youth
for small things like cannabis and then
they can't get jobs and they're screwed
forever do their this is gonna help out
a lot of people so this is a really cool
thing big up to Jamaica we are making
progress we're gonna legalize it the
world before too long here let's get
back to the united states welcome to new
york the 23rd state to legalize medical
marijuana i already know some of you
guys are gonna have some things to say
about this one this one is by joseph of
alaska is from The Associated Press I
found it on the cannabis new york is set
to become the 23rd state to legalize
medical marijuana under an agreement
announced by legislative leaders the
democratic-led Assembly passed the
legislation 113 to 13 early Friday after
an hour of debate
after midnight Senate Majority Leader
Dean Skelos I don't know if that's how
you say that but it looks cool said the
bill would be voted on later in the day
when Republican lawmakers had reviewed
the legislation ski lows of Long Island
said he had planned to vote for the
measure and believed there were enough
votes to pass the bill in the upper
chamber
anyway the so-called Compassionate Care
Act would legalize certain forms of
marijuana freezer for severely ill
patients the legislation does not allow
the drug to be sold in the platform or
smoked but it can be administered
through a vapor or an oil base wait did
you guys catch that because I read this
previously and I knew what I was getting
myself into cannot be sold in plant form
or smoked but it can be administered
through a vaporizer or an oil base
that's not medical marijuana you just
[ __ ] yourselves don't don't pass this
what do you do in New York all right I'm
gonna keep reading earlier in the
negotiations Governor Andrew Cuomo
sought to ban smoking the drug saying it
was wrong for the state to promote
smoking and then you have to balance the
needs of many of the patients and the
truth is we're coming to a point where
less and less people smoke anyway said
bill sponsor senator Diane Savino is
Staten Island Democrat on Thursday
marijuana could be scribed for at least
ten diseases including epilepsy AIDS ALS
and neuropathy under the direction of
the state's Health Department the health
commissioner would be able to add more
illnesses if approved by the legislature
the bill would allow the program to
start as soon as 18 months Oh in as soon
as 18 months and would allow a governor
to terminated under advice from the
Health Department or law enforcement
what the [ __ ] is that if it's approved
it could start in 18 months but if a
governor or the health department or law
enforcement decide that they want to
shut it down they can so you guys are
[ __ ] up over there in New York
Medical Marijuana has the capacity to do
a lot of good for a lot of people who
are in pain who are suffering and are in
desperate need of treatment that can
provide relief Cuomo said during a news
conference with lawmakers
sounds like somebody wrote that [ __ ] out
for her really well doctors that have to
undergo training to be eligible to
prescribe the drug and could face a
felony charge punishable by up to four
years of prison if they write fraudulent
prescriptions the bill does not require
insurance companies to cover the cost of
the drug of course not
patients who sell their prescribed
marijuana could face misdemeanor charge
patients will be required to carry a
registration card showing they're
authorized to possess the drug can be
subscribe' a maximum 30-day supply so
who's gonna decide what a 30-day supply
is New York you've done [ __ ] up dude
this is not right the more I read this
stupid or you sound five registered
growing organizations will be allowed up
to four dispensaries each throughout the
state wait five organizations get four
shops inch
I like monopolizing already with the
counties with the counties where the
marijuana is grown and sold receiving
revenue from an excise tax under the
stipulation cultivators must grow the
drug indoors in a secure facility Cuomo
was initially opposed to medical
marijuana earlier and his term but
proposed a pilot program in January to
allow up to 20 hospitals statewide to
administer the drug initially wanted a
five-year sunset period to evaluate the
new program but negotiations extended
that to 7 so Jamaica got it right New
York [ __ ] it all up what do you do I
do that's really that's that is stupid
medical marijuana in New York we I'm not
even gonna count them as the new state
for medical marijuana they're through
the new poser state they're like if you
didn't see six or seven red flags in
that whole article you're not paying
attention alright let's get back to more
local news we've gone worldwide we did
national now let's get back to the
hometown of Pueblo Colorado this article
is from the pueblo chieftain i'm looking
for an author it is written by chris
would cut it is titled bored eyes water
for marijuana
to policies to provide water for growing
marijuana within city limits and in
Pueblo County will be considered today
by the Pueblo Board of Water Works the
Water Board meets at 2 p.m. at the Allen
C Hamel Administration Building 319 West
4th Street two resolutions have been
drafted for consideration by the board
one for supplying treated water within
pueblo city limits and the other to
leasing raw water within Pueblo County
both types of water sales would be
subject to changes in federal law the
resolutions are an attempt to work with
the Bureau of Reclamation's temporary
policy which prohibits using federal
facilities such as lake pueblo to
provide water to grow marijuana it
excludes water not under federal
contract that is commingled with
contract water the policy issued in May
also requires lekha Maine reclamation to
notify the Department of Justice if its
employees learn water from a federal
facility as being used to grow marijuana
we talked about this in a previous
episode although medical marijuana was
approved by Colorado voters in 2000 and
recreational marijuana passed in 2012
drowing marijuana remains a federal
crime under the proposed resolutions the
bubble aboard the Pueblo water board
would not sell any water with the
federal Lincoln in the supply chain to
marijuana growers but it would sell
water from its direct flow rights below
pueblo dam to the pot industry the
resolution to the city use water would
revise the water board's policy to
change the use of water based on federal
policy it also clarifies that sentence
is what that says it didn't make sense
when I read it but I stopped and read it
again and it made sense the resolution
to use city water would revise the
board's policy to change the use of
water based on federal policy
they just like to write a bunch of
[ __ ] to make it sound like the
writing stuff it also clarifies that
some of the water rights owned by the
water board are not subject to federal
policy however the policy leaves open
the possibility of terminating water use
for marijuana if federal policy changes
it's all about policy check your policy
under the second resolution the water
board would make up to 800 acre feet two
hundred and sixty million gallons of raw
water available to marijuana growers in
Pueblo County annually through leases
that potentially can provide up to five
hundred thousand dollars in revenue each
year using the current rate of six
hundred and thirty dollars per acre-foot
it also contains a provision to cancel
contracts based on federal policy
changes and stipulates that the water
board is not required to negotiate or
approve any water lease the city of
Pueblo has regulations for medical
marijuana and for growing manufacturing
and testing recreational marijuana
webelo County has regulations that allow
medical marijuana as well as growing and
selling recreational marijuana so
there's one part here that got my
attention it also prevent contains a
provision to cancel contracts based on a
federal policy based on federal policy
changes and stipulates here's the [ __ ]
up part that the waterboard is not
required to negotiate or approve any
water lease so if one day they decide
water is now $900 per acre-foot guess
what they are not required to negotiate
or approve any water lease you guys
wonder people will often complain that
marijuana is too expensive that
high-grade cannabis is too expensive
that the shops are charging too much
this is the reason why [ __ ] like this
they every time and I'm experienced in
this I have seen this I was a part of
this every time i dispensary I was part
of the wild wild west I had I was a big
part of the very first dispensary in
city limits in Pueblo there were no
dispensaries in the city limits of this
town when I had a shop with some friends
they had a shop started I helped him get
it going one day they got tired of it
handed me the keys then one day the
police came in and closed us down but
every time we would get our [ __ ]
together they'd say here's your next
turtle we would jump through that hurdle
and then they'd go oh these guys can
jump high let's give them a really high
so they put us up another hurdle
eventually we're playing hi Joe once we
got good at high jump then they wanted
to do more [ __ ] they wanted us to
javelin you know what I'm saying
it I've seen it happen the dispensaries
went from a few rules to ridiculous
rules to everything being under camera
everything being on lockdown and every
one of those steps cost more money and
more money and more money and I think
that's a lot of what they're doing it
for is for more money but that's the
stuff that's making the price of
cannabis stay where it is instead of
going down with the mass supply that we
have provided we have to come up with
more money for water now we didn't think
about that
all right that's another rant that I
just went off on glad you guys were a
part of it
feel like that was enough news for the
day you guys want to get into a grow
lesson right quick in the last episode
we took a bunch of clones
I probably rooted so we better learn how
to get him into dirt I'm gonna take a
couple of dabs you guys hang out and
I'll be right back all right in the last
episode we talked about mother plants
and cutting clones those clones should
be rooted and ready to go into dirt now
or within the next few days potting
clones from the easy cloner and the rock
cool cubes will be pretty much the same
you'll need to be a little bit more
careful with the clones from the easy
cloner because they don't have anything
holding the roots in place so just be a
little more careful they're kind of more
delicate before I go too far I should
mention something noted to me by my
buddy cut proof cut proof does not use
mother plants cut proof uses his vegging
plants as his mother plants and takes
cutting us off of them two or three
weeks before he flowers his big plants
so that saves him some space if you're
only growing a few streams that's a
great idea some cool use that uses that
strategy I'm kind of thinking about
switching to it myself to make more room
available so instead of having a mother
plant that you take cuttings from and
then you grow those cuttings you just
have this plant that's been in veg for a
few weeks now and you just take 2 or 3 3
or 4 cuttings off of it now you've got
your new mother plant and then you've
also got your next round of plants to
veg from there
so as long as you're confident in your
clone cutting wait a couple of weeks for
those clones to root or whatever and
then throw that plant into the flower
room and then you've got your next
mother as long as you take healthy cuts
I don't think there is any genetic loss
they call it genetic drift I don't think
it happens if you were proper with your
plants we could probably talk a whole
nother episode about that one so back to
getting our clones into dirt make sure
your area is clean and try to wear
rubber gloves that's really important
because you're gonna have the roots out
the roots are the most gentle part
anything they touch they will absorb
keep that in mind don't go setting them
on some dirty [ __ ]
it's important to use good soil for your
plants I like happy frog or a light
warrior for my babies something that
allows a lot of oxygen into the root
zone is ideal I like to use a small
amount of nutrients when I put these
babies into dirt I make sure to add some
kind of root inoculant you want
something with lots of mica Raisa I use
a great use great white or OGT you can
get OGT at hydro pueblo we talked about
them earlier Michels are beneficial
fungi that promote root growth you'll
definitely notice a difference in your
plants performance if you use them if
you use them in one plant don't use them
in another you'll be able to tell by the
root acceleration once the roots gets
bigger get bigger they can take more
nutrients just makes your plants grow
bigger better happier faster healthier
so I definitely recommend using some
mykos in your mix I also use a small
dose of veg nutrients for my transplants
right now I mix up a five-gallon bucket
of water with my great white and my bed
nutrients that I'm using for small
plants I do use bottled nutrients I like
organic care for my babies so what makes
up some night treks and great white and
then just adjust it to 65 with my pH I
toss an airstone in the bucket and I let
that water get oxygenated while I start
getting my containers ready so for these
small plants they're just little babies
we're gonna use Solo cups like a beer
cup don't use clear cups you don't want
your roots exposed to light I take a
solo cup and I cut plenty of drainage
holes at the bottom to let excess water
escape you want water to drip right out
but you need the bottom of the cup to
stay intact
so once my cups are prepared I film
about halfway with soil put them in a
tray and water each cup with my nutrient
solution before I put the cloud into it
so you basically just want to water the
dirt the main difference between the
rockwool cubes and the EZ cloners that
the EZ cloner is a little more
vulnerable and needs a little more help
for this next step so with the EZ cloner
clones I make a little mound of my cup
it should kind of kind of look like a
traffic cone so I should remind you to
wear rubber gloves for this whole
process by the way so I have a little
mound of dirt like a traffic cone inside
my cup I try to spread the roots apart
around that mound kind of evenly and
then that really promotes root root
growth and balance plants so once the
roots are carefully spread out in the
clonus centered add more soil into the
cup until you have about a half inch
space on top left and then water the
clone throughly with the nutrient
solution and put it under a t5 light it
stays on for a minimum of 18 hours per
day I keep my t5 lights very close to my
plants and get them as close to the tops
as I can get without exceeding about 77
degrees definitely don't get above 80 or
85 in there you'll be in trouble 80 is
kind of high 85 you're in trouble for
the clones and rockwool the rapid
rooters they do the same thing but I'm
not as concerned about spreading the
roots out because the Rueter are at the
rapid Rooter the rock wall has them
spread out enough already and it's kind
of holding them intact to the base of
the clone which is where the real tender
so to set that rock wall into the wet
soil and fill the cup until there's
about a half inch of space left and then
water the rockwool clones the same as
you do the EZ clone or clones and get
those under 18 hours or more of life t5
s are good and again don't get them up
real high in temperature try to stay
about 77 degrees that's really important
people don't pay enough attention to
their temperatures when they're in veg
and that it doesn't allow you to grow
strong healthy plants so that when
you're in flower the plants don't live
up to their full potential
alright now here's where the humidity
dolmen Trey and Rockwell cute method go
wrong for a lot of the new growers your
clones have been in 70% humidity for
most of their lives so once those clones
get upset about the lack of humidity
it's hard to bring them back
unless you've been taken off the dome
daily and letting these clones acclimate
slowly they're gonna freak out when you
expose them to the drier atmosphere so I
would recommend putting those cuffed
clones that came out of the dome back
into the dome if you have room I think
you can fit about 12 of those cups in
one of the domes and tray setups if you
can't use the dome you can put a clear
cup on top of it get another bag of
those Solo cups and get clear ones this
time and put those on top of your red
cups or if you accidentally bought clear
cups in the first place thinking you
were gonna put clones into those now you
have a use for them cuz they aren't any
good for rooting your plants put that on
top and it worked like a dump for each
individual plant once they get rooted
into the soil they'll be more forgiving
to that humidity drop they'll have
another life source they won't be so so
dependent on the moisture in the air to
live because they'll be able to get
moisture and sustenance from the roots
for survival so give them more and more
time without the domes each day until
they're stable and then in just a few
days they'll be well adjusted so once
your clones are in two cups and fed be
sure to label your clones we talk about
this all the time it sucks having a
clone that you don't know what it is
because you got stoned mislabeled it or
forgot to label it then you have to make
up a name and that just creates more
problems so please label your clones so
these clones we just put into cups are
gonna need a few days to adjust and dig
their roots into the new soil they
should be cooling the cups for about 10
to 14 days you can go a little longer if
you really need to I just like to leave
them in there until I you can take off
the cup off the dirt and just see the
roots kind of trying to bust out that's
when I want to put them into bigger pots
I know some guys are gonna ask why we
don't go to larger pots now and save
time well here's the answer larger pots
do require more soil which means more
nutrients which means more water larger
pots also take up more space with these
cups we can plant plants and enough dirt
to let the roots grow while keeping the
water you slow which means you don't
have to add a lot of nutrients which
kind of save you some time and saves you
money saves you dirt saves you space
I don't want to feed nutrients to a
three gallon pot full of dirt while I'm
only aiming at a cup worth of roots is
kind of what I'm trying to say so try to
be more efficient more cost-effective
once these clones take root and they
show us they're gonna survive and
survive that transplant process will
begin the vegetative growth phase will
have grown the cups for a couple of
weeks before we repot them into
finishing pots or the veg for a few
weeks or a month and then they'll begin
flowering so we have a long journey
ahead of us I hope we can grow a nice
crop together feel like I've been going
on and on and on and on so I'm gonna
take a dad and we'll wrap up the show
real quick here like I've said before if
you have any Corrections questions
concerns or any kind of input please
contact me I was given a great tip from
cut proof and I'm glad he chimed in I
wouldn't have thought of that if he
didn't say it so don't be shy I know I
tried to cram a lot of info into one
episode or into one show so correct me
or ask me to elaborate on anything you
want to hear more of don't be shy like
the interactions you can find me at I
grow culture on Twitter I grow culture
at hotmail.com
or of course there's always a Facebook
page all right I'm gonna take a quick
dab and I'll be back to wrap up the show
all right I'm back to wrap up the show
I'm gonna try to get Jesse on for the
next episode and then on July 2nd I'm
going to be recording the podcast live
from the Brickyard in Pueblo Colorado it
will be closing down the hookah bar for
me it'll be a private party I'm going to
see if I can't invite some of the
podcast listeners to come down and hang
out with us I have to figure out what
they're going to allow I may give you
guys a password on the next episode and
then you'll have to use that password or
something to get in and then only the
people that know that are allowed in but
we have to keep it private to be able to
do the things we want to do there so
this is the portion of the show where I
give thanks to somebody who I feel has
been beneficial in the evolution of the
cannabis movement I was hanging out with
a friend of mine a few years ago several
years ago man this was a long time ago
we were talking about growing wheat he's
an old-school grower and an old-school
breeder from back in the overgrow days
and we're talking and he's like hey do
you know who soma is and I was like I
don't know who soma is and he said dude
you remind me so much of soma you need
to check him out so I did what any
responsible pothead would do I got
online and I checked out this guy soma
yeah soma and I have some related blood
line somewhere along the line because
this dude's got dreadlocks down to his
ass and dresses like an old hippie this
is the original wookie right here is
soma soma was born in 1949 he's probably
been growing wheat longer than you've
been alive he's the author of the book
organic marijuana soma style he was
accidentally became known as the ganja
guru after developing award-winning
cannabis strains he's best known for New
York City diesel amnesia haze lavender
and so Gouda home was a great dude he's
taught me a lot of not personally but
through his readings and his YouTube
stuff it's not me a lot of things about
mimetics and the vibe of the plant which
are things that I understood and
believed in anyway but it's good to see
soma out there doing the organics and
teaching this vibe for the plant not
just how to draw fat buds but how to
love the plan how to connect with it and
that's part of what I try to do a few
summers Awards this train winning awards
were $19.99 reclining budda won the
indica category in the High Times
Cannabis Cup in 2001 New York City
diesel won the sativa cup and the High
Times Cannabis Cup in 2002 Buddha's
sister won the indica category and New
York City diesel won the sativa category
in the Cannabis Cup 2003 amnesia haze
won the sativa breeder category and the
420 IC growers cup their list goes on
and on and on and on and all the
students bred grown and won many many
things so I wanted to say thanks to soma
if you don't know who soma is check him
out you're probably smoking some of his
strains I spoke to g13 haze from soma
one time it blew my freakin mind I would
have done all kinds of crazy [ __ ] for a
clone or seeds of that but it was not
available at the time so I had to live
without it I'll never forget it
all right so shout out to soma we thank
you so much
then a lot for my development as a
grower as a breeder I'm sure you're
doing it for a lot of people in
Amsterdam so is it Amsterdam he's not in
America he doesn't come to the States as
far as I know he hasn't been here in
years
so shout-out I hope you hear the show
somehow Big Love so much respect all
right that pretty much wraps up the show
check me out on Instagram at I read
genetics I also follow the show on
Instagram at agriculture there's a
Twitter for both of those as well
there's Facebook's for both of those
have given out the email for both of
those a couple of times so and that
shows over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for I grow culture
find the review section give me a five
star rating type in that comment telling
me how awesome the show is but even if
the show sucks please give me a comment
I want to know I want to know what's
going on with the listeners although I
think that if the show sucks you
probably wouldn't have listened to 35
minutes of it but still type in some
comments let me know what you think of
the show I'll probably read your comment
on the air I hope you're cool with that
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher and swell dot am and
also every episode is available on IRA
genetics Colorado com shout out to my
ninja Spence thanks again for listening
take a phat dab give your mom a hug for
me
see
[Music]
Josie starts on the never prepare make
me tell you dear love when I smile with
people kiss take up the courage we don't
care
Joseph's tarsier disappear
[Music]
all right podcast world that was episode
13 14 15 and 16 of what used to be the
agriculture podcast now currently known
as the grow from your heart podcast I
hope you enjoyed it make sure you check
back Monday for a new episode also I
would love it if you guys follow me on
social media and let me know what you
thought of these old episodes you can
find me on twitter @ GF YH podcast you
can also find me on Twitter at Rasta
Jeff 4:20 you can also email me it's a
girl from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you I thank
everybody once again for listening I'm
gonna give a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me