hey what's up podcast world I'm here to
drop another chunk of old episodes this
time I'm gonna republish episode 17 18
19 and 20 of what used to be called the
agriculture podcast which is now the
girl from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
couple of disclaimers a lot of my ideas
opinions methods and techniques may have
changed so please don't hold anything
against me if I said something that may
sound off also all of the social media
is different if you want to contact me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast you can search
for us on facebook i grow from your
heart podcast and of course you can
always email me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com i would love to
hear your opinions of these old episodes
ladies and gentlemen this is going to be
a 3-hour file so I'm gonna quit rambling
and we will get to the old episodes
ladies and gentlemen here is episode 17
18 19 and 20 of what used to be the
Hydra culture podcast now the girl from
your heart podcast please enjoy
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen welcome to episode
number 17 of the iGrow culture podcast
we are come to you live from Colorado
where it is a hundred degrees today I
hope everybody's staying cool and
keeping hydrated this podcast is brought
to you by nature's green remedies com
visit nature's green remedies dot-com
for gage green genetics apply to labs
sin city red dankness mile high can
adventure I read genetics and many more
trusted brands if you purchase two packs
of ira genetics you will receive a free
five pack of dub wise while supplies
last
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our podcast listeners type
in coupon code podcast for 15% off any
order and you always get free priority
shipping at nature's green remedies calm
I also need to give a big shout out to
our friends at oil slick oil slick tools
to help you concentrate check out oil
slick pad comm for more information make
sure you follow oil slick on twitter
find them under at oil slick pad send
them a tweet and tell them you're
listening to the agriculture podcast i
also want to give a big shout out to
tree hugger calm this episode is brought
to you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews WWE
dot-com I hope you guys really do check
out our sponsors they make the show
possible Oh a super huge shout out to
task rock the opening song in this
episode was do it again from tnl the
movements a big shout out to tasks much
respect task is a huge part of our
movement a part of our community you
don't know where the task rock task and
- make sure you check those guys out got
a great episode lined up for you jesse
is back to give us another outdoor grow
lesson I also want to read a little bit
of news before we get to that so let's
get down to it
all right this story comes from the
cannabis was actually written by John
Ingold of the Denver Post the headline
is police stings no pot shops found
selling marijuana to minors meed says
police have so far sanctioned no
recreational marijuana stores for
selling to minors during underage
compliance stings across the state
according to colorado department of
revenue authorities in Denver and Pueblo
working with regulators from the state
marijuana Enforcement Division have
conducted 20 undercover stings in which
they see whether a store will sell pot
to someone under 21 16 of the compliance
checks have occurred in Denver home to
most of the state's recreational
marijuana stores so far no store has
sold to someone under 21 in the checks
so they sent Undercovers around to
dispensaries to go try to buy weed and
they sent people that warrant 21 and
those people were turned away by every
shot that they went to so good job
Colorado that is proof right there that
we can follow the rules
the people that own these businesses do
not want to risk their businesses by
selling to somebody under 21 there are
plenty of people 21 and older coming
from out of state to buy herb so they
don't even need to risk it I don't yeah
so good job you guys good job for
following the rules so the article
continues in it says it is imperative
that we keep marijuana out of the hands
of kids Barbara brawled the executive
director of the Department of Revenue
which includes the marijuana Enforcement
Division said in a statement these
results show that strong efforts are
being made by the meb and the marijuana
business license to do just that
a licensees sorry marijuana business
licensees to do just that while medical
marijuana stores can sell to registered
patients under 21 a recreational stores
can only sell to those over 21 and must
check identification stores that are
found selling to someone underage could
have their license suspended or revoked
or face a fine up to $100,000
it says here medical marijuana stores
can sell to registered patients under 21
if you are a Colorado resident near a
medical marijuana patient that's under
21 by then you can go to the medical
marijuana stores as long as you have
your card you go to the
shops if you're under 18 to get medical
marijuana you have to be seen by two
doctors I believe it could be under 21
as well I think it's under 18 if you're
under 18 you have to be seen by two
doctors at the same time and they both
have to approve your medical marijuana
evaluation so that's that's one of the
little why they mentioned that people
under 21 can get into some shops only
the medical shops so it continues it
wraps up with we are pleased with the
results and we'll continue to monitor
the businesses to ensure the compliance
efforts are maintained well good job
Colorado I'm proud of you guys I'm glad
that you're not selling to the people
that you're not supposed to I'm glad
you're doing your job and checking your
IDs they mentioned Pueblo directly so
shout-out to all my friends in Pueblo
that have shops that are following the
rules thank you for doing it right I
don't know if you guys realize it you
are the example all eyes in the world of
weed are on Colorado right now so do it
right don't [ __ ] it up for everybody do
it right you're doing a good job so I'll
give you praise good job guys
all right I've got one more piece of
news that I found really interesting and
then we're gonna go ahead and get into
the grow lesson with Jesse this one is
from the Denver Post written by David
Magoo yeah it says Colorado's 40 casinos
and hundreds of others including the
gaming Mecca in Las Vegas are bound by
the same money reporting rules that have
made banks reluctant to let legal
marijuana businesses open bank accounts
federal authorities now say that means
casinos can keep anyone associated with
legal weed enterprise from dispensary to
grow operations away from gambling
tables anywhere in the country and if
they do allow them to play casinos must
file the same suspicious activity
reports banks must file whatever they
handle money derived from pop profits
according to the Financial Crimes
enforcement network a division of the US
Department of the Treasury FinCEN's
guidance applies to all financial
institutions covered under the fence and
regulations including casinos Vincennes
public affairs director Steven Hudak
told the Denver Post so this is going
out all my friends I'd like to go party
in Vegas and have a good time we need to
quit wearing our brand shirts and we
can't talk about what we do if we are in
the cannabis industry
[Music]
goes on to say because the government
says casinos are financial institutions
like banks they must have stringent anti
Mundi money laundering programs in place
filing suspicious activity reports RSA
RS to crack down on money laundering by
criminal and terrorist organizations is
not new for casinos what is new is that
it now extends to the legal marijuana
trade while fin sent in February
announced how banks could work with
legal marijuana businesses the
government only now realized that
extends to casinos that's in any casino
in the country whether in Colorado
Atlantic City or Las Vegas on land on
water or on sovereign American Indian
soil so casino and the Las Vegas Strip
would by law have to pay attention to
the owner of a marijuana dispensary in
Colorado who heads there to gamble is it
that trippy isn't that weird so if
you're from Colorado you go there and
you're kind of looking like you got some
loot because you own a dispensary and
you're trying to treat your employees
you are now suspicious and your money
will be reported so currently 22 states
have legalized the sale of medical
marijuana and to Colorado and Washington
have legalized recreational sales
Colorado and 41 other states have some
form of legal casino gambling the news
revealed June 12th at a Las Vegas
conference directed at curtailing money
laundering has stopped state regulators
and the casino industry in its tracks
the Colorado Division of Gaming was
unaware of the FinCEN guidance
spokeswoman Cameron Lewis told the
post-event division management will be
taking this matter under discussion
similarly the Colorado Gaming
Association the trade group that
represents the state's casinos was
unaware of the requirement to my
knowledge we have not been contacted by
fencin regarding any issues dealing with
marijuana suppliers executive director
Louis Rice said Mike banks casinos must
know their customer and have some
knowledge of their source of funds oh
I've been to casinos and nobody in there
gave a [ __ ] what my source of funds was
they had no idea how to tell as far as
they could tell I worked at a shoe store
like they had no idea so unless you're
going in there with your brand shirt on
unless your shirt says I make
or the big green dispensary then you
should be cool but be careful if your
money if your money stinks like weed if
you happen to keep your money and your
weed and a safe together or somewhere
near there your money before you go to
Vegas or just stop at your local bank in
Colorado make a deposit then for more
money out later so that you just traded
money for that stinky money for it on
stinky ass money I just don't want to
take your stinky weed smelling money to
Las Vegas or any casino we've got plenty
of casinos in Colorado we got [ __ ]
creek and [ __ ] so be careful going there
here we go I'll read more know their
customers where was I the casino
industry keeps close to track of
gamblers through a variety of methods
including high roller clubs frequent
player programs and other in-house
incentives casinos must comply with the
government's guidance on filing
suspicious activity reports said Jim
Dowling an anti Monday money laundering
consultant their alternative is not to
conduct a financial transaction with
these individuals who were involved
directly or indirectly in the mj--
business at Dowling a former IRS agent
who is also an adviser on money
laundering issues to the White House
because marijuana is illegal under
federal law Vincennes requirements for
doing business with the marijuana
industry modified how financial
institutions are to file si RS SARS
suspicious activity reports is what that
means the reports must now reflect that
clients are in states where marijuana
sales for allowed so if you win a big
jackpot and you are gonna show your ID
and your ID because you've shown it
you're 21 if you collect a big a
surprise the idea is gonna show Colorado
is your home state on there and they're
gonna make note of that they're gonna
fill out a suspicious activity report on
your ass the marijuana specific reports
would either identify the cannabis
related business or employee as legally
operating under appropriate guidelines
identify them as one conducting some
suspicious activity or as one where the
casino has ended its banking
relationship in order to maintain an
effective anti money laundering
compliance program the 7 page guidance
also notes a number of red flag
scenarios that would require a bank or
casino to file an SAR including for a
customer depositing cash
that smells like marijuana who might be
trying to conceal involvement in
marijuana related business activity so I
mentioned that earlier and I honestly
hadn't read that paragraph they're
paying attention if your weed smells if
your money smells like weed
they are flagging it something for all
of us to think about maybe you just have
your herb and your money in the same
pocket you know and then you end up
going to the bank and you make a deposit
and that money reeks like herb if you
got the dank so be careful be careful if
you're in Vegas be careful if you're at
the bank just be careful they're looking
for more and more ways to build the case
on people now all right I think that's
enough news for the day I'm gonna take a
couple of fat dabs and I will be right
back with a grow lesson with our buddy
Jesse hang tight while I smoke down
[Music]
this outdoor grill lesson is brought to
you by hydro indoor growing supplies
hydro indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the brand new Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out www.engvid.com for
current store hours and special sales go
check out the new location in Pueblo and
tell them Rasta Jeff sent you so I got a
friend who sent me a text one time you
were here for the show and your quote
was you know the show has started when
Jeff's coughing his lungs she knows who
she is what's up girl thanks for
listening to the show all the way in
California it was supposed to be
California but I just took some dabs and
my lips and lungs and throat or not
cooperating what's up guys we're back
with Jesse we got him here to teach us
some gross stuff I almost said your last
name again we're gonna get right down to
it we're doing some outdoor growing and
Jesse's here to teach us how to do it
this is his third visit I hope you've
been paying attention in the last
episode or not the last episode the last
time jessie was here sorry weird AB the
[ __ ] out it seems like we just hired to
come on to like Oh extra hi alright the
last ever listening they can hear me
so we're talking about security soil
strain selection T's will talk about T's
a little more today top feeding we're
gonna talk about topping and training a
little bit more so what's going on you
said we've got about 25 days until we
flower right at this point right yeah 25
30 hopefully 30 days before that this
stretch period is like really noticeable
and stuff you know that for lack of
scientific terms how many excuse me how
many days until you think we see that
stretch period so then we won't see
little bud sites forming for probably 40
days ish that's outside so yeah that
really depends on strange and even
location on a certain property can you
know change flowering types of stuff if
there's like a structure or true your
stuff like that I've you know seen a
plant start flowering a little bit
earlier in one spot as opposed to you
know same piece of property countered
feet away Wow just from one tree or yeah
this what this was a garage okay
what about what do we do about a street
light I know I just kind of went off
topic here but there how much your
streetlights gonna [ __ ] up our flowering
streetlights so I I don't know I've
heard the street lights messed them up
you know we have really full moon
sometimes I've always really deeply
wondered this myself but I don't know
okay I would assume it's trained
specific myself yeah some strains are
much more resistant to firming from
light leaks or whatever you want to call
it for sure the harder in because are
probably gonna go a little be a little
more resistant to [ __ ] up cases now I
have seen a back porch light the plant
interrupts the light cycle this was a
plant sitting in a container just like
on the dudes back porch and it totally
heard out but the light was a lot more
direct you know it wasn't you know 30
feet away and across you know the street
or something like that so yeah so I'd
love to hear some of some input from
some you know listeners on that topic
yeah so it's like you almost have to do
a light depth if you have an outside
light some wire like a street light near
your backyard or whatever II was
actually talking about his street lights
are probably gonna [ __ ] up his flowering
cycle for sure I told him jokingly this
is not real advice don't do this I told
him to get a pellet gun that is a
solution to it yes for sure I don't know
if that's the one I would advise
replacing that bulb the city's gonna
wonder what
yes 25 days we'll start seeing it seeing
a stretch phase a little bit after that
we'll start seeing our buds when should
we start changing to a flowering feed I
switch over each plant individually I
always when I do switch to a flowery
feet and make a ritual out of Dino given
like their first high peak a top
dressing and everything a little you
know I still be able nitrogen at that
point the outdoor plants just seem to
use more nitrogen okay I am helping with
a light depth and we're using bottled
nutrients because they're container
plants with the concrete floor in in in
the greenhouse and I really feel like
this cycle we're about to harvest it was
nitrogen deficient or just screaming for
more nitrogen the whole time
and like I couldn't really quit quite
figure out what it was because it wasn't
just yellow about for anything but I
feel the Sun makes them want to grow
taller stalling I don't know if they're
like I have any scientific evidence
behind this and you know that's what
they're supposed to get a medium
nitrogen to grow tall so once you get
nitrogen deficient at that phase you're
pretty much Sol you're gonna be chasing
it the whole time that's what we call it
chasing it you said when you first feed
them those flowering nutrients you want
to give them P and K phosphorus and
potassium you guys those are the things
you want to switch to just to for the
new guys lots of calcium to play if
you're using dry supplements go you know
go pretty heavy on that moisture show
for Easter meal
[Music]
just seems to help produce bigger
flowers outside big big flowers needs
lots of calcium so lots of nitrogen I've
got a friend who's growing some plants
that are I I'm not like being shady I
really do have a friend what's up Adam
he's got some doors I haven't seen him
he keeps saying that the bottom leaves
are all yellowing up but the tops of his
plants look fine they are in containers
he keeps them outdoors he feeds and
bottled nutrients do you think he's just
nitrogen deficient since he's outside
yeah your nitrogen lets you grow you
know also both sides of containers he's
in little containers and there's no
sauce you know that's the when the plant
starts just now you know it just started
well I guess I could start wherever but
small pots are are hard to do outside of
Star Trek's I like to keep them watered
adequately that's a problem he's having
yeah and keeping the the root zone cool
the temperature on those black pots can
get quite a bit higher than put them in
front door maybe 2 feet tall from the
last pictures I saw there about 18
inches 2 feet tall
I seriously probably go for like some 40
gallon spot smart pots that's 25 to 40
go and those little pots the bigger pots
cuz you're gonna have to feed a lot of
water cuz it's gonna get hot out there
it's already getting hot my buddies go
to water it was a hundred degrees here
today I'm sure by the time he woke up
that plant was thirsty as [ __ ] then I
bet he had to water it again at some
point another thing you could do is
mostly on the plant
some kind of organic mulch don't get
that stuff that's really heavily tied it
yeah that's the dye washes off and it
might get into your container and pot
doesn't like dice another thing you can
do this trip systems and then another an
easy fix is white panda plastic wrapped
around the pot white side out the color
of it yeah all right you talked about
light deprivation earlier and I kind of
skipped right over that some people
might not know what a light dep is so
light depth can be a real pain in the
ass it's honestly my opinion it's a lot
of work it's a lot of work so what
you're doing is you're taking a plant
that's outside and you basically have to
trick it every night to make you think
that it's nighttime by putting it a lot
of people will build a greenhouse an
arch shaped greenhouse hoop house type
of thing and then you basically pull a
tarp over it or some sort of cover over
it at the same exact time every night
just like you would turn off your lights
in your indoor grow the lights will go
and then every morning at the same
morning you uncover that [ __ ] so that
it's just like it's in the grow room
getting the lights turned off and turned
on and it thinks it's the season for it
to flower so that's basically light if
there's several ways to do it you can
bring the plants in but basically it's
covering it that way as a light
deprivation it's forced flowering your
outdoor plants manipulating that
physically manipulate
it's a lot of work it's a lot of
commitment so outdoor grilling is not as
easy as people would think not at all so
we covered we cover the light depth we
talked about that we're talking about
feeding a little bit getting my buddy's
leaves greener so we're talking about
chasing the nitrogen go heavy on the
nitrogen guys I reck I always recommend
be careful with it but it sounds like
you found if you're outdoors that plants
good how likely are we gonna burn it
outdoors do you think that the sunshine
and the natural everything is gonna help
us prevent [ __ ] up you know it
depends on your container this is one
good thing about being in the ground
it's a little more forgiving I feel like
[Music]
you know if you have a lot of water you
know there's a lot of sunlight and a lot
of photosynthesis is going on so you
know let's be careful clue you know
don't just you know alright three times
as much because the the stone guy in the
theory guy you know please don't do that
but you know work into it but you had
enough for this outdoor plants use a lot
of nitrogen instead of just flooding at
one time flood it decently and then let
it dry and then flood it again and then
really pay attention to it don't just
try to go and super soak that [ __ ] cuz
you'll drown it she'll die for sure
that's there's I think there's a
difference between watering and feeding
even though a lot of people consider
that the same act as far as just dumping
water on a plan
when I feed a plant I still water at
first and then I apply the feed to it
you know same outdoors with the t's and
anything like that that's something that
a lot of the new growers probably
haven't ever even considered instead of
just you can do this this is indoor and
outdoor I feed my plants with nutrients
every Monday all of my plants my mother
plants my veg plants just Monday it's
you know it's the easy data pick you
don't forget got it all figured out and
get the Monday ritual how you feed
everything I will
I feel the - Reza's I walk through and
water each plant in the flowering room
with a little bit of fresh water just
just enough to get it you know Wakely
give it a drink and then I go hit the
other rooms and then I come back and
then I mix up the nutrients for you true
them and go back and get them the first
watering is just enough to kind of kind
of moisten the topsoil like it doesn't
go very deep I don't think but it kind
of gives the plant a chance to wake up
helps the nutrient flow through better
you know but my theory was I don't
always want to wake up and have a meal I
don't want to put yeah I don't want to
start with a steak I want to have some
water in my throat up and get moving to
wake up and then have some food and some
oatmeal or some whatever yeah so wake up
let him enjoy the day so I guess we
should talk about feeding stuff what are
you putting in your tea right now um I'm
going a heavy with kelp meal alfalfa
meal and that the Mexican bat guano the
tea I'm gonna make tomorrow actually
I'll make it tomorrow I'll play it on
Tuesday
I'm gonna put seabird guano in it for
the first time okay start
I don't really have been eating a lot of
sunshine been swimming in the ocean yeah
if you're lucky might catch me there
maybe sometimes Jesse's down there you
know some people ya know GT heavy
moisture meal I don't put that in a
t-top dress I apply that to the soil
okay clogged up you guys gonna want to
know what I said azomite is what it was
that's something I've never really uh
messed around with clients just easier
anything like that or top dressing or
anything like that okay I put I put it
in initially in the soil yeah okay
that's I've usually seen it mixed in the
super soil but yeah if I didn't get it
in there maybe I could try now is what
I'm hoping for
deeper worm castings in your tea
[Music]
basically larger for yourself if I
wanted to just try some teas I could do
a five-gallon bucket if I'm a new
listener I could just do the five-gallon
bucket put some water in there about 3/4
of the way dechlorinated water now our
water if you can if you're making tea
you know you got a little aquarium pump
so our air pumps okay so we got a do but
about two days before you use this water
fill up your reservoir and put your air
pump in there not your pump put the
[Music]
yeah put your air stones in there keep
the pump on a shelf safe and dry that's
electric put their stones in there and
just bubble the [ __ ] out of that water
for as long as you can and you want to
get you want to stir it a lot of times
is what's happening essentially because
you're trying to bring all the chlorine
and anything else there's all kinds of
[ __ ] the pueblos water you want all that
to evaporate out so bubble it up a lot
before you use it and then use that same
water just leave Dara Snowden there
right let it keep it above one or in
your molasses 15 mils per gallon 50 or
50 15 tbsp okay about two shot glasses
worth for a five gallon bucket we've got
our tea we've got our molasses in there
yeah I don't do exact measurements on
that five gallon bucket I do like nice
little double-handed handful okay okay
so like two cups is what I think we're
looking at three or four cups means the
most there depends on how big your hands
are if you have homemade compost or you
got a cool neighbor or something like
that that that'll work and Lou the worm
castings or together together warm poop
oh man you're golden
put that warm tea in there yeah what
else are we putting we get the kelp the
kelp meal yeah um I've been I've been
kind of starting slow on that
I've used it before but I've never used
it in teas and stuff so read some stuff
this binary now I'm going nuts with it
right now let's see for five gallons to
say if how they do like a quarter cup
I'm sure you could probably go more I've
never seen a good healthy tea
Virna plan so if you guys want to read a
lot of these ideas there's a book called
we talked about it in a few shows ago
the folks that call it's called true
living organics by the Rev check that
out I recommend that shout out to the
Rev they don't pay me to say that or
anything he just writes a book that's
exactly what we're talking about so if
if you want a lot of their step-by-step
teas their directions how to make them
there are certain teas for certain
phases he's got teased for seedlings veg
plants late fetch plants early flowers
he's got a tea for every day of the week
in there they're pretty elaborate some
of them they're very effective those
teas are the way to go it looks like a
lot the Rev gross and gorgeous weed I
don't know that I've ever smoked any TLO
weed that's not what I do
Jesse shake it like you're in Colorado
some of my dad's or whatever
I saw a meme of myself a Rasta Jeff mean
yeah says droves began Akoni smokes bhl
sure some dabs or if I happen to have a
fresh crop of some lemon Jeff or
whatever will hol get down on that I
just want to taste your TLO weed I want
to see if what the heights are about you
know I'd like to come to your plants
yeah yeah I'm just knows he's like that
you can come see mine yeah thanks for
putting that out there for us alright
earlier you set a drip line yeah that's
a brilliant idea
for outdoors you're gonna want a water
often if you could set up a little
miniature drip line it's not that hard
you need a large res to hold your water
a resin
or that is not gonna get algae funked
it's gonna be something designed to hold
water don't be a cheapskate on this part
yeah sometime clean in lines often yeah
I need a pump like I don't even remember
how many gallons per hour pump but
depends on how many plants in how many
lines but then you just need a splitter
and then like octopus hose coming out of
that and one thing to each plant and a
spike and you just put that spike right
in the dirt near the center of the plant
and set a timer on the pump and every
however often you have it come on water
will magically flow from your reservoir
to your plants so all you got to do is
turn on that pump one time hit a timer
see how long it takes for those plants
to get an adequate amount of water and
then hit stop when they're well they're
good and then set your timer for that
much time on every morning so right
whatever time you see the Sun peak up
boom seven o'clock that timer should
come on
boom [ __ ] water your plants for you
right away and if it never does build up
to an adequate amount you need more drip
emitter heads yeah yeah more water
delivery in a nutshell I use the kind of
gravity system but it's a little bit
larger scale so yeah yeah yeah you can
always put your Reds at the top of the
hill and run your lines down the hill
basically without a really fancy still
anointing to open and close the tank you
don't have actual or too good of control
over it so just just by the pump in a
you know 55-gallon barrel or something
like that yeah then when you can almost
make your tea in that barrel you can
that would be good for the pantyhose all
of the ingredients we talked about to
put in our tea and do a thing a
pantyhose and just tie it into a knot so
that you just made a giant tea bag and
then just drop that inside there and let
that bubble around in there and you're
gonna get a bunch of foam up on top of
your tea we didn't mention that we kind
of did a little bit but once you get all
those ingredients in there let it bubble
let it stew for about 24 hours when
you're making tea we kind of skip that
step
put it set it in a container I've seen a
lot of guys buy
little Rubbermaid containers that a
five-gallon bucket inside of I love
gonna want the they have to know who
grows weed at Walmart in all the stores
cuz we buy the most random [ __ ] in bulk
no I need how many do I need I need I
need 33 of them like really yes the
whole room is gonna look if I have one
that's off yep get rid of my pervert man
alright we talked about tees kind of
randomly drip line would be a good idea
to research that be careful with it but
it's such a great idea if you can get it
figured out get it going
yeah if you've got a real job and you
know you got rocks and you're you know
you couldn't plant in the ground even in
grounds are great if you're having
watering issues you know you can't water
them enough drip line line you can get a
real simple setup at Harbor Freight I
believe for like less than 30 bucks I
want to say thanks so less than 30 bucks
for a drip on do this why am I not doing
that it halls my rooms
I think hand feeding is personal yeah my
plants every day I don't like McKenna
mcmechen eyes dreams eternal state of
the art when it comes to marijuana
growth I feel state of the art is
that just lets you know you probably
don't want anything to do with it here's
a weird question how do I adjust the pH
of my tea or whatever without [ __ ] up
the micro life or do I even need to
worry about it
I don't you don't you just all that
stuff and there is going to do what it
needs to do and be at the pH it needs to
be at yeah otherwise you may destroy it
right that's the theory I've gone on
even putting things like stuff that's
derived from Leonard ight putting that
in your tea you can just watch it to
kill it like right in front of you found
on the foam and it just excuse me can't
see it to fall the can yeah yeah oh yeah
okay there's some cow max yeah so okay
liquids into your teas is a just a
touchy area if you want your tea to stay
alive it's that's why you're mixing up a
TDI just to avoid that example one
greeting it I can recommend is called
sea green it's great for teas don't
apply it when you start the brew you
apply it after you're done when you're
about to apply it to the plant see green
yeah what is sea green that sounds like
some kelp [ __ ] yeah fish based kelp
so pretty low in peak a kind of like too
concentrated TM wow so nice a good start
yeah what's the fox farm product that is
a good tee starter you know it's one of
microbrewery I believe it's either it's
either big on its [ __ ] I'm gonna google
it
yeah I've actually used this a couple
but it was pretty neat had some samples
it's one of those original three that
Fox farms put out remember when they
first started there were three yeah I
think it's Tiger about oh okay okay
nevermind and I'm taking us somewhere
else one of those original three and
they've changed their website all up -
hey one of those original three can't
find it not here I'm trying to talk to
was a great one for making a tea I'm
looking another general hydroponics
floral assist plus is pretty good for
making some teas
[Music]
check that out it could be time one of
these three the tiger bloom grow big or
big bloom the Rev recommends in this
book heavily sorry guys I didn't mean to
rant on that for no reason because I
couldn't even find the correct answer
now I feel silly that's a good base for
it see you can add that one to the tea
and feel safe but yeah read what you're
putting in there yeah I'll get the revs
book look for the revs book I'll let you
borrow it come on over here you can use
it teeming with microbes Oh Stu
yeah oh that's a good one too teeming
with microbes hey listen to the show you
would appreciate this scientific story I
just I can look at the plant hungry has
to [ __ ] wants to outside or lost its
ball yeah it's deployed I could tell
that about my plants do it either needs
water it's too hot in here and [ __ ] it
needs to get fed or it's time to harvest
[Music]
babies so we've got good soil we've got
good teas big pots for bigger plants
we'll talk about a drip line that sounds
like a good project to work on got about
25 days 30 days from now until we're
gonna go into flower so we could top
them we could train them a little bit
right if we want to get out there and
play with the plants for sure
I've topped three or three three or four
times five times six different plants
yeah so you've got some dragon in plants
now like nine
heads coming off of them my personal
plans for a little behind this year
because of work obligations but you know
the little tiny guys with like like just
dragon heads
so hydras yeah hydras I'm experimenting
with low stress training this year some
bamboo soft I just kind of pulled them
down a little bit so grab some of the
tops of the plants and just bend them
down yeah so that we can get a little
more light to spaces give give the heads
a little more space to breathe right
yeah
airflow guys don't try to trap your for
plants like Jesse said in a few episodes
ago
don't try to trap them between the shed
the house and the garage and the fence
give them plenty of air or you're gonna
end up with moldy buds and the plants
know when they're crowded they can feel
it the roots the roots grow if you got
him in the dirt the roots will touch
each other and they'll be like there's
another plant here and they won't grow
into that plant or maybe well maybe
you'll choke the other one out I read on
old on a pop forum some Tom Hill wrote
years ago about how the plant will never
grow wider then it's been the mass of
his fruit structure right so
experimented with that a little bit last
year and noticed quite a bit of
difference and needless to say my my
holes this year were a lot bigger
circumference than they had been in
previous years okay that's I've been
telling my buddy Tony kind of the same
thing he likes the when he looks in a
grow room and looks on pictures online
when he sees just a bunch of tall skinny
plants so he's asking me how to do that
and I was like just keep them in small
small containers and that way they're
sure I told them essentially the same
thing I was like if you're wide you got
to branch out a little more you get a
spread your legs if you're tall you just
stand real
together in for sure same idea awesome
cool so what do we need to look for we
can have any problems right about now or
anything coming up what's - and [ __ ]
animals that help actually buddy of a
buddy I heard about a bear incident and
a bag of blood milk so he's lived in
bear country his whole life he should
know better you know the only thing to
keep a bear out of your garden is
[ __ ] nothing no I don't want to spray
that new crop so it's you know here
locally in southern Colorado it's been
real humid like like lots of rain this
year which is a good thing
[ __ ] I think this is the first day we've
hit a hundred degrees all summer yeah no
I mean yeah and the plants are noticing
that - I very much chose to [ __ ] me -
this big mop on my head it's like we're
not asking all day yeah it's like I got
one on my chin so not quite as dense as
yours but I still in the face man oh
that drives me nuts
so the humidity is you know potentially
could be I I haven't had any issues I
didn't sound like a dick when I stepped
outside Oh [ __ ] feasible is that
ridiculous I mean oh no not at all I
don't hesitate to do that also gets
go to Lowe's and be that guy buying for
fans and put one in each corner of your
garden folks you don't see come up don't
make them all look like a comic-con
turned oh when they're turning all at
the same time synchronized make them all
go at random if you can put two at
different speeds and make them turn all
different times it's what you want you
want to stir the air you don't want to
just move it around you want to stir it
when its moist around here last year I
had a hard time there was a real good
breeding season last year - it seemed
like and I had a hard time getting the
soil to dry out so I could get teased to
it and stuff so you know if that's an
issue you're having
I used fans however I should just top
dressed but you know do both I could see
that as a potential issue yeah spider
mites I suppose yeah this is a good time
of year for the hydro shop if you go to
the dispensary wherever your clones came
from we talked about that Indiana pop
open people's indoor gardens around here
so I'm sure you know depending on where
your plants came from treat your plants
with neem oil guys you got plenty of
time if you're outdoors the spider read
I've always thought spider mites were
like extraordinarily easy to
to beat outdoors so just really just
loose pretty neem oil there's a product
called Kapow it's just like essential
oils and stuff like that um some of this
Sierra natural science products it
probably worked for a braid yeah a lot
of those products that's what I use a
lot of their stuff um
the mighty wash you know let's just do
you not deionized water
it's not called mighty one what's the
word light in there
I forget the new name but it's mighty
washing tomorrow I liked it because you
knew what it was right
[Music]
I've heard things good things about
liquid ladybugs but never had to use it
about just some ladybugs or some praying
mantis or some predatory mites praying
mantis I had them hang around plants for
a whole season it's pretty cool
ladybugs it's a great picture up outside
because there's no real way to contain
them they like to leave unless you got
something up in cages I've always found
them if you use them in your grow room
it's just basically fodder for your fans
and
[Music]
sound like a good outdoor girl lesson
we're right about 30 minutes sweet how
long until you think you need to come
back and give us a heads up on what's
going on
a couple more weeks I don't know 25 days
till flowering so maybe you will come
back maybe right at the start or maybe a
little bit in and see what you're gonna
yeah for sure cool cool they really do
you really Oh STUV my comments are about
outdoor grow lessons like what's next I
haven't checked them out I tried to on
stitcher so speaker used to - yes I
found the place to go for the comments
it's really an obscure place it has
nothing to do with the rest of my
episodes you have to go to a certain
little tab deep and find it but once you
get there then they're all there it's
kind of weird if you leave it on an
episode previous and I don't look at
that episode I won't see the comment so
leave them on either the main page if
you can find it or on episode 13 is
where I check for comments it just makes
it easy
thanks for coming seriously yeah thanks
for have you back it's really great
having you help out a lot of people
there are a lot of people this dude
brought me some organic cherries I can't
wait to put those in something I'm not
sure what I have but why might just make
a salad put a little dressing on there
try those yeah I use them
I don't know the sign you know there's a
word for but uh you know I'll cook them
down and kinda like introduction be a
production yeah I kept wanting to say
gelatin for some reason but I'm a
meat-eater so but but I eat really good
meat so like oh you know home ground
chicken just all soaked in Vesta
fantastic something some ladies would
love you wrapped in bacon bacon that's
the American Way
I haven't eaten bacon in probably close
to 15 years yeah haven't had any meat at
all in probably 15 somewhere between 12
and 17 s years yeah thanks I guess maybe
I was a humble brag we're gonna take a
couple more dabs and let Jesse get out
of here the students getting married
everybody so congratulate him forever I
met your wife finally I'll be back to
wrap up the show thanks for joining us
we'll see you soon for sure see you guys
[Music]
another episode of agriculture podcast I
want to thank you for listening I want
to thank Jesse for coming out doing a
lesson with us of the next episode I
will be recording live from the
Brickyard in Pueblo the Brickyard is
currently a hookah bar we are trying to
get the City Council to help us change
legislate legislation so that we can
make this building a dab lounge we'll be
talking more about that on the next
episode I plan to have members of the
citizens for the responsible regulation
of cannabis on the next episode they're
the group that is working with City
Council to get the recreational smoking
areas open here in City Limits they were
kind enough to open
- let us open them in the county but
that's we wanted in city limits a lot of
us live in the city we don't feel that
the county should have all the cool
stuff so listen to that episode when it
comes out now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for agriculture find the
review section give us a five star
rating after that type in a comment and
let me know what you think of the show
and I will read your comments on an
upcoming episode don't forget - the show
is available on iTunes stitcher swell
that I am I always [ __ ] that one up huh
swell a.m. and also all of the episodes
are available available been at this for
a minute
all those dabs are kicking in all those
episodes are available on I read
genetics Colorado calm alright we're
gonna end this episode with a song from
task rock this one is called woody Brown
check it out big shout out to task
shout out to my ninja spits thanks again
to Jessie for coming thanks to you guys
for listening take the fat dad
[Music]
right
and where we're at pretty
[Music]
[ __ ]
I'm so glad that you made it free later
my we are kicking babies across the
nation tell me who yeah the blaster top
shelf extracts I won't settle for the
rest of chapters
[Music]
like a mobster leaning low with my chair
with the judges extract extraordinaire
[Music]
so got the rig look at cleaning their
bar do it thick where's my number have
you seen it that's the game of the
opinion most of never find these enough
yeah happy fourth of July weekend
everybody
hope you're all shaking off your
hangovers and trying to glue on the
fingers you blew off welcome to another
episode of the iGrow culture podcast
this is episode number 18 and it's a
very special episode
I took the podcast to the Brickyard a
local hookah bar we did an episode live
from there but before we get to that
part this podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies calm make sure
you check out nature's green remedies
calm for Gabe green genetics lopata labs
Sin City rare dankness mile high can
adventurer IRA genetics and many more
trusted brands if you purchased two 10
packs of ira genetics you will receive a
free five pack of dub wild dub wise
while supplies last natures green
remedies is running a special for the
podcast listeners type in coupon code
podcast for 15% off any order and you
always get free shipping at nature's
green remedies dot-com spod cast is also
brought to you by our good friends at
Highgrove indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the new flood location on
618 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
check out Highgrove for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies don't forget to check out
www.hsn.com
why not give a big shout out to tree
hugger com this episode is brought to
you in part by tree thugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert festival news
and reviews www.rediff.com once again I
want to thank all the sponsors for
helping us out - opening song in this
episode was by hydro big shout out to
hydro the song was called the secret
cuff anthem this is the episode that'll
come out right before a seven-ten so I
hope everybody has a happy
safe dad filled 7/10 wherever you are
whatever you do make sure you take a big
fat dad for me I don't want to waste too
much time let's get right into the the
live show here we go yo what's up guys
we are coming to you live from the
Brickyard hookah bar in Pueblo Colorado
the Brickyard is actually a hookah bar
right now we're trying to get city
council to give us the ordinance to turn
this place into a social cannabis club
but so far the city has been hesitant to
do that so what we've decided to do
tonight is have a live podcast from here
I brought several of my friends misty
brought several of her friends I am a
member of a committee called the
Citizens for the responsible regulation
of cannabis we've got four members here
they're gonna talk with us I'm one of
those members Misty's a member my friend
Lee is here wanna say hi bro glad to be
back I guess we should start with do you
have any idea why they won't let you
turn this place into a dab bar a social
cannabis club sorry I'm not gonna I'm
gonna try not to see bad bar that sounds
not classy well first I'd unless a
thanks for coming in and doing your live
show here I am so in debt to you for you
know bringing this out in the open for
sure and when it comes to the city I'm
not sure there's not an ordinance in
place I'm not selling marijuana
I am simply giving people a place to
come and socialize play pool throw darts
listen to music let's watch a great
stand-up comic that I would like to
bring in you know just come and enjoy
themselves without having an alcohol
based atmosphere and that's what this is
a social club on the same as we do with
our local bars part of what I was
heading for I invited a bunch of my
friends you invited several of your
friends there are people here that have
never met each other does anybody here
feel unsafe we could all be friends and
be adult here and do this responsibly
and if you saw somebody here [ __ ] up
would you feel free to call them out and
keep this place safe for us as a
community that's what we do right cuz
we're all adults awesome see nobody
should be there's a bunch of people here
that are all I'm gonna say everyone's 21
or up there probably I don't want to
guess how old people are but there's a
nice age range here and everybody's
friendly we're all having fun there's
nothing gonna happen here the only thing
I am worried about my biggest fear is
police interaction that is the only
thing I'm worried but I don't want to be
the I don't want to be the one breaking
the law I've been to City Council and
I'm trying to say listen there they're
coming in there to our city and they're
buying marijuana and they're going and
sitting in our parks they're driving our
streets they're parking in this Kota
Sachs why not just give them some place
to come to sit down enjoy you know I'm
some company of some people maybe they
don't know maybe they do know just to
play a game of pool play something great
on the jukebox that they've been waiting
to hear I mean it doesn't matter this is
a social atmosphere and why are they
stopping us from having this kind of
atmosphere yeah I agree completely
cannabis dispensaries every direction
ten minutes from here you can get to a
dispensary but there is nowhere to smoke
it exactly I've got friends that run
work manage they all have dispensaries
and they say a lot of their recreational
customers are actually coming from Texas
so those people have nowhere to smoke it
you can try to smoke it in your hotel
but if you're only here for a day people
are shaking their heads like no can't
smoke in the hotel did you get have
experience you want to come grab a mic
for a second I'll let you talk on a mic
this is my buddy Adam he's from out of
state he's been on the show once or
twice we kind of just derailed the
structure the show but [ __ ] it it's
going well yeah we came from out of
state and that was one of the main
things we were worried about is finding
a 420 friendly hotel we did have to look
on Craigslist and actually find one and
then once we found one it definitely was
the one that I wanted the kids staying
so you're talking about feeling safe and
having a place to use cannabis safely
the only hotel in town that was safe to
use cannabis is not exactly the place
where I wanted to bring me my wife that
makes sense
dude thanks for being on the show all
the time thanks for coming out tonight
yeah that's what people are driving
around they're like she said hanging out
at the park which is not cool that's
where we take our children and I know
the park is a cool place to go smoke
weed but that's where I want to be able
to take my daughter I don't want to be
hanging out with her throwing a frisbee
and her having to watch you take a DAB
in the car
well you're right you know the great
thing is is that you know if you wanted
to take the kids down to the park that's
not too far from here you know you can
let them do their swimming thing and
come up and enjoy the adult activities
you know a distance away I mean this is
a community thing in marijuana shouldn't
be something that we should definitely
fear you know I have a lot of my
customers that come in to have a a drink
next door when their kids at soccer
practice there's nothing wrong with that
you just mentioned the drink next door
you do run legends the bar next door yes
do you think that's going to affect City
Council's decision and letting you open
this as a smoking establishment well I
hope not I hope they don't judge me on
my performance in either place I mean
you know I ran a great bar for four
years and I don't hope that they don't
have a problem with that
I don't know how I feel about that I
should mention that I really appreciate
you said you appreciate me coming in
really thanks for letting me have all my
friends here come take dad's my friends
are making new friends you guys what do
you guys trade places all of those
couches the Brickyard for sure that's a
great we'll get more people here next
time to announce the next date really
soon on the show I kept this one kind of
secretive I didn't know what to expect I
didn't want to fill the place and then
having issues absolutely and you know
we're gonna fill the place over this
next month because we've got that thing
that we're doing with the education on
the 27th yes the committee for the
responsible regulation of cannabis on
7:27 we're hosting what did we decide to
call it a seminar right
yeah yeah this is leaveth speaking
introduce yourself my friend tell us
what you do who you are for now we can
just call me Li and I'm a local business
person I run a couple of businesses here
in Pueblo and I want to make my first
appearance about a couple of messages
that I have and the first one is that
Pueblo has an opportunity to steer its
future and its revenue through the
industry and it's up to citizens to take
that opportunity and responsibility
misty looks like she needs to speak to
you grow it into a future for the city
and the second message is it's not all
about the dispensary model there are all
kinds of satellite companies and
industries that go along with marijuana
[Music]
that should be developed and long term
industry brought to the area I'm gonna
have to take a break and take a drink go
for it we'll let Gary talk for a moment
you have anything to add it out Gary as
part of the committee for the
responsible regulation of cannabis yeah
I do actually
with misty situation they're telling her
that she needs a permit that doesn't
exist so she can't open so she has the
permit but the permit doesn't exist so
my feeling on it that that's completely
illegal it's certainly you know not in
the spirit of city government right it's
it's ridiculous but you know the rules
governing private clubs are pretty
specific you know and there are a couple
here already
like the VFW in the American Legion and
those places are private clubs they
allow smoking of cigarettes and things
like that that you normally couldn't do
in a regular bar but they do it every
day not to mention that those are great
clubs and they are very well maintained
and they're very organized and they're
recognized you can smoke in here well
and there's never been any issues with
any of those places even though they're
outside the norm you see what I mean
there's really no grounds for them to
say that this can't happen we can comply
with the Clean Air Act right I mean so
what there's no basis for it except that
they won't write a regulation and issue
a permit I should mention that they did
just allow shops or not shops but
businesses for you to open and Medicaid
or recreate in the county with outside
of the city limits but right inside of
our County I know that hurt me I just
feel like you know people now we're
gonna see the potential but not that I'm
knocking anyone who wants to open a
cannabis club that's a social club for
people to go to because I think that
there is a need for it and all of our
communities I was a little disappointed
I've been open for a month and a half
two months because I'm afraid to get in
trouble yeah I'm afraid to break the
rules I wanted to everything right right
right yeah so you are closed right now
outside the door pacing back and forth
you just checked two of my friends IDs
that came in speaking of rules
one of the basic rallying cries that
everybody can understand is that we want
to be regulated in the same way that
alcohol is we want the same kind of
oversight we want the same kind of
regular brandy
regulations we're all about public
safety
we just want common sense people making
the rules instead of people that have
nothing to do with the industry and
that's what to see our RC is trying to
do right now that's why I'm part of it I
try to be the young influencer that's
the dabber that's the smoker that's the
grower I try to bring that to the table
absolutely and you know that's what's
great we have a great diversity between
all of us I mean we're we're kind of at
in the whole movement and this is a
movement that I think that is necessary
in our society what we've seen with
Pueblo and the City Council and their
moratorium is that first of all the
dispensaries sprung up on the outside of
town right so what Pueblo is
experiencing and now they've allowed
smoking clubs so that will spring up so
what Pueblo is experiencing as a city is
all of the ill effects that that brings
with none of the benefits to offset it
they don't have any regulatory control
because they're not in the city they
don't receive any tax revenue at all but
they're still getting smokers staying
here smokers in the park coming through
our city they're leaving because you
know what's great is this 30 miles north
of me you can go and you can smoke you
just can't buy marijuana so basically
they're stopping here and they're going
this is awesome town they're all right
where do I go smoke and they're going
Colorado Springs go ahead and go to
Colorado Springs speakeasies places like
that and that just took revenue out of a
lot of people's hands I'm talking Taco
Bell you know yeah they're just leaving
and going to Colorado Springs yeah so we
can sell a product right outside the
city limits and then they drive away
right I mean there's no reason that with
as many places as there are in the
county already there's no reason to not
allow them in the city it's just it's
just ridiculous it's
pointless all right there are just as
many cannabis users probably more in
city limits
everybody here live in city limits
everybody nods yes you know we've seen
some progress lately right they've just
allowed the grow operations concentrate
manufacturers they give them the mic and
edibles manufacturers the City Council
has just passed that
Misty's husband's asking for a
microphone I'll pass it to them and let
him introduce themselves
[Music]
hi my name is Greg and I'd like to say
you know you guys were talking about the
revenue aspect of this and everybody
looks at it as a business hacks best
aspect of it which it is a business
aspect of it but when you guys are
talking about Pueblo and like you guys
talked about Pueblo County and all that
stuff and they're making revenue out
there well the city's hurting for some
revenue as well so the taxes that the
city would make off of these taxes that
you would get for opening these clubs
that you're gonna revenue inflate the
city taxes I think they forget about
looking into that situation as well so
it's not only a business prospect for
the personal owners or the personal
people that are trying to make a profit
or trying to make a business that works
it would also help the city and the city
is also going to benefit off of these
prospects that are coming about so if
they can just let things happen the way
they're supposed to happen it's already
been voted in it's already been the way
it's supposed to be it's already been
around us so if they can make this
happen it would only benefit the city as
well as the people are trying to make
this happen to benefit themselves as
well so for as it out of business aspect
it would help the city and the state as
well as the people that are trying to
but you know I'm moral right now sorry I
because I have a question for you in a
second I you know I the way I feel about
it is is that more that this should be a
place of socialism
well how many how long has people than
saying a combined smoke you know we're
the drug that they're so afraid of
that's called marijuana is something
that people actually hang out and do
great things with and socially hanging
out and being people and I just I wish
that they would just see that that's
what it is a social environment one of
the reasons that the City Council said
they don't want to open places like this
is because if the police our fire
department did have to come here they
would walk in and there's so much smoke
in the room that they would be too high
to do their jobs and they would be
unable to perform Greg you're not a pot
smoker are you he said no sir I didn't
given the mic back for that are you high
being in here he said no sir and shook
his head you've been here the whole time
right hour and a half or so he's not
high you guys so if you're paramedics
are getting high if the cops are getting
high that's on their own time that's not
from being in here first sir so that
excuse sucks find a new excuse you guys
I just want to break in and say that we
have the situation that we're facing
because the municipality did not seek
the citizens input before these laws
were put into place so we had a
situation where the people making the
laws were not the people in the smoking
community and one of the things that the
see our our seed is a vehicle for the
public to interface with this government
and I just want to break in and say that
yeah that's what sparked the CRC this
will be given information on how to
interface with us sometime doing the
program yeah I will do an intro and an
outro tags on this and I'll make sure to
get all the Facebook information all the
website anything there is thank you I'll
get all that on there try to keep up
with all that stuff so when is the next
stop
what can the City Council the city
members here do can we go to City
Council meetings and try to talk and try
to just show
presents to help get these places open
absolutely the public is invited to City
Council meetings once I believe it's
twice a month is every other month every
other Monday every other Monday citizens
can come out they can sign up to speak
to the council they can ask questions
and basically make themselves make
themselves heard to the people that are
affecting their lives every day that's
not just here in Pueblo you guys you can
do that wherever you are if there's an
issue not just cannabis but if you want
to support cannabis if you have
something in your local region that you
need fixed go to City Council start
finding out the steps you can take to
get it on a ballot to talk to sometimes
all you have to do is talk to a council
member and they will solve a problem for
you we had a local issue here recently
they got a little blown up and a city
council member called the guy that had
the problem and he said hey here's the
solution and that's all it took was for
them to talk so maybe all you need to do
is get with the right City Council
people everybody I'm is kind of snicker
into this room I don't know if we should
say any of that stuff
the City Council meetings wherever you
are and contribute be part of that you
can't [ __ ] and complain if you don't do
something about it what we've done so
far with the CRC working you know on
Misty's behalf is we've gone to one City
Council member the only one we could get
an appointment with and our proposal at
that time was they want to put this on
the ballot for recreational and medical
sales within the city limits but they
want a tax on that all right so they
want that on the ballot in November
so we're cool with that but we want them
to go ahead with the club rules right so
we went in there suggesting that maybe
you could put the clubs on the ballot as
you want to in November but in the
meantime issue us a provisional permit
so that when people go to vote in
November they can vote based on actual
facts the actual operation of this
business for a few months and we were
you know willing to accept a 30-day
permit you notice
just to show them how this business
would operate and and we were told now
well they steered us to why don't we try
to get this moved up on the agenda but
we've hit a stone wall with that so now
we're asking for both we're asking for a
provisional permit and we want this on
the agenda now rather than in November
and that you know that's really where we
are and that's what we need support with
we need you to call we need you to email
your City Council members and tell them
that we want this on the agenda and we
want some places open now so we can see
how it works before we vote it's working
well tonight Gary Gary will take the
responsibility of emailing me all of the
phone numbers and email addresses and I
will tweet them Facebook them so that
all the iGrow culturalism everywhere you
are if you have legal cannabis and you
don't like what you have you can you can
fix it if you don't have legal cannabis
you can fix it let's get it going
everywhere legalized the world is my
opinion I agree so you look like it
something profound about to say I was
just gonna say that one thing that
Puebloans
and Coloradans in general should be
embracing is their ability and their
right to produce their own medicine this
is going unaddressed basically since the
laws have been enacted and it's so much
cheaper to produce your measure
you know what you've got there's so many
other benefits and things you can do
with the whole plant as opposed to just
having the buds that you get at retail
and I just wanted to throw that in the
juice your leaves can make tea out of
the roots there's so many great things a
lot of that on the educational you know
I don't think that a lot of people I
think that they see that word marijuana
as a fear factor and I hope that on the
27th of this month here at the Brickyard
people are gonna come in that are so
curious that they want to get that close
but they don't want the smoke around
they want knowledge and they want to
know about it and that's exactly what
we're gonna do on the 27th or so on the
27th I don't know if we've talked about
this very much yeah on the 27th here at
the Brickyard in Pueblo Colorado hauled
post the address and everything online
we are going to have an educational
seminar we'll have six or seven speakers
Gary Lee Misty myself a couple other
folks are gonna speak Terry from Mary
Jane's shout out to Mary Jane's glass
haberdashery for sure today I'm she
called me early and she said that she
was not feeling very good but you know
what if it wasn't for Terry and that's
the honest-to-god truth I wouldn't have
taken the leap that I've taken
she couldn't me and Tosh I put her in
touch with Gary just kind of have a
great relationship she just is a
wonderful woman I appreciate her
immensely yes so we're doing this uh
this seminar we're gonna have some
education our friends gonna do a little
history lesson Lee is going to bring
possibly bring businesses we haven't
solidified this yet bring businesses and
do like a job fair Gary's gonna run
around and try to administrate
everything well something will have
going on on the 27th is will have free
memberships to the CRC so we want to we
want to sign up as many members as
possible
and you know we're just an
organizational stages we've been you
know we've been assembled for less than
a month right so what we'll be doing is
you know when it's the day to come to
the City Council to speak we'll be we'll
be issuing action alerts to our base so
we want to get everybody signed up who's
willing to you know to come out or send
an email or make a phone call at those
critical times and we want to start
collecting that as part of our seminar
so that'll be you know what I'm doing
you know trying to drum up business
memberships things like that and you
know we want to create you know after we
get Misty's problem solved we want to go
forward with an organization that can be
an activist for cannabis related
businesses in the community and the
cannabis community in general
and you know from us smokers from
medical users recreational users for
everybody and we see the influence we
have already as a small just forming
group and we see the huge vacuum of
influence on the local county and state
level that there really needs to be an
organization that's pushing for those
interests because there really isn't one
right in different chapters you know
like I know that Lee was talking about
possibly having his own group of you
know north and I think that that's an
awesome thing and that's an awesome idea
to have someone that you can rely on in
a statewide you know community that we
need live you know 2530 minutes away but
we have someone we can connect with out
there if we needed to I think that's
awesome we definitely we definitely want
to go statewide with your organization
and one of the reasons goes back to
about the satellite businesses around
the marijuana industry and a an
organized group can go out and court
industry that can bring long-term jobs
there needs to be a distribution club
between Denver and the Front Range
there isn't one now and nobody's going
out to court these businesses nobody's
going out to court the production of
packaging all kinds of businesses that
could be a hub in Pueblo and on the
Front Range and we need jobs here we
don't want the big corporate [ __ ]
coming in here either we want to keep
this local we want to keep this a
Colorado thing you know what I mean well
I don't I don't want these big
corporations from California and New
York and these billionaires to come here
and scoop something up they you know
maybe a guy that's starting with two
hundred thousand you know what I mean I
don't want I think that it's gonna suck
if we just get bought out Colorado
and what's not here is the level of
education that makes those people
comfortable investing in what we've got
going and and we take it upon ourselves
as citizens and as business owners to
start this group to to educate people
and bring that level of education up to
where it's not a dirty investment
anymore something that's above the board
something that's appreciated for what it
is it takes good management to run any
company not just one in the marijuana
industry I just think my biggest fears
is that we're gonna have another you
know another company come in here and
they're going to bring all of them a
young millions in and they're gonna
bring their corporate people and their
workers from other states to move to
Colorado to work their big grows in
their big plants I mean that just I
think that that's a fear for a lot of
Coloradoans that this is gonna become a
corporate thing because there is money
to be made in cannabis those of us in
the cannabis industry with small
cannabis businesses but I see why I have
a seed company I breed seeds I have a
seed company that's well known and does
all right
but I see there was just me and I don't
know enough about it recently a member
of Monsanto was part has become part of
a dispensary team and that's got a lot
of us small-timers kind of scared
shitless right so squeezed out instantly
the people that work with small
businesses like us know we offer that
loving [ __ ] just like you can get the
same thing at Applebee's at every
Applebee's that you go to but when you
come over to a different restaurant
that's homegrown you get a different
atmosphere and you get a different feel
I agree with that yeah but I still don't
think you know that I don't know I'm
willing to put it out there with the big
companies coming in here and we have
people that can do it right now you know
what I mean that it just seems like
there's a niche on it but you have
enough dollars in your pocket and it's
deep enough things are gonna be changing
drastically over the next
years this is gonna be totally different
so if you bring a cannabis business here
please utilize our talent that's here
don't bring your own your own staff that
sucks they'll come here and bring your
own California people whose Colorado
[ __ ] yeah we need jobs we're talented
we're smart so we have this event that
we're talking about my portion for the
event on 727 I am going if the lawyer
will will approve this I'm going to
bring a small gross setup here to the
Brickyard and set it up here over there
in that corner is my intention people
bring a grow height a little 4x4 grow
hut with a 600 watt maybe a thousand
watt light in that [ __ ] in a few live
plants over there in the corner for a
few hours and for my part in that I plan
to do a presentation about the health
and holistic side of not only marijuana
but of several different botanicals a
lot of people know but marijuana may be
good for medicine but they're not quite
sure how and one of the things that on a
business level I tell my clients is that
most pharmaceutical products are
synthesized from or based on a botanical
that you can find in nature and so once
you know that you can start to help
yourself to affect your health situation
affect your health situation I'm sorry
and so I'll be talking about how you can
use marijuana and other botanicals as
medicine we'll have some samples to give
out we'll have medical personnel on hand
to answer questions and try to bring a
level of understanding about the medical
uses of marijuana
[Music]
come on check it out you guys it's 7:27
that's July 27th at the Brickyard it's
gonna be great you're gonna learn a lot
if you haven't ever seen live growing
plants I'll have plants that'll be about
28 30 days into flower you'll get to see
some female plants I may have some that
are like 70 days in if I decide to let
it go that long it may be a little too
far but I might let it go just for the
listeners to come check out for the
people to come see blue dream that's
just yellowish we have several
businesses that are represented we have
Mary Jane's glass of course we have
legends represented we have the
Brickyard here and we have non-stop
nursing and nurturing which has a
Facebook page you can find grow pueblos
on Facebook and that company supports
growing all kinds of botanical products
in Pueblo some people may have come to
the super bud bowl and you can find that
page on Facebook as well and a lot of
this information will trickle down on
all these Facebook pages so you can
connect with us to see RRC in a lot of
different ways not just trying to catch
us at a council meeting we are part of
your community and you you know us
already yeah I've been here for a while
you probably know me already
from Texas we need guys like that are
articulate and do the research and can
speak while we're bit misty is running a
business and I'm breeding seeds you guys
doing the research so what is our main
goal on the 27th are we just trying to
educate them what we trying to show them
that this isn't scary this is gonna be a
smoke-free environment
27 is there an age limit
you know we kind of talked about it
we're gonna have live plants here we
might need to be careful I think that I
think that we're focusing on adults and
I think that in our society right now
we're considering adults 21 years of age
okay even though you can go and you can
fight for your country at the age of 18
right
what bothers me a little bit but in our
society right now I think that we need
to abide by the rules and I think this
is 21 up I don't want to teach a 16 or
17 year olds out of your plant focus on
other things
it is the adults responsibility to take
knowledge home and share that with their
children so absolutely we're trying to
start from the parents and the adults
the pillars of the community and have
that knowledge trickle down into the
next generation which is gonna view this
industry as something that has always
been there so we need to make their
impression and their opportunity in
their future in this industry something
that's gonna make them want to stay on
the front range and not just run away to
Denver or some other state I hope some
of my friends from Denver come down to
check this out cuz I got all your stuff
up there guys come down to Pueblo it's
not as bad as you think come down and
check it out so that way you can find
out if it really does suck or if it's
cool and if it does suck and you've been
here then you can actually talk some
[ __ ] come down see me check out the girl
I've got set up here I'm gonna try to
talk misty and to let me have a little
VIP After Hours party here in the
Brickyard maybe record another podcast I
haven't mentioned that till just now but
you smile another one of these sessions
here right after that little thing so
yeah come on down everybody from Denver
everybody from Pueblo Kamiya agriculture
crew I'll be here come learn a lot it'll
be a good time until then come to the
City Council meetings when is the next
one you guys know 7 p.m. what's the date
you got me it's coming up because we're
recording on like a Tuesday or something
everybody in the room just went for
their iPhone
[Music]
and I think it's called City Hall place
isn't that the street it is yeah we'll
be there come support us help us get a
cannabis social club open the Brickyard
1027 South Boulevard so something that
way to frame this just as a final
thought is right now the city of Pueblo
is proposing a half cent sales tax to
pay for police and fire who's gotten
their fingernails in here that's weird
[Music]
so why couldn't we have smoking clubs
and their taxes fun the police and fire
seven another half cent sales tax has
anyone proposed that to them no they're
worried about their firefighters and
their police officers let's give them a
half percent of our sales here your
sales here this is close to my neighbors
this is my hood this is the part of town
I represent for point low I will be here
often everybody sitting on that couch
will be here if I'm here davon those
guys will be here dabbing I said she
females here guys yeah it's not a
sausage fest so come on have fun with us
at the Brickyard let's get this place
open thanks for having me I want to turn
it into kind of some fun since we've had
a lot of serious talk do you guys have
anything to wrap it up with yeah alright
Misty's got a run she's gonna go who
wants to come sit in misty spot and talk
some [ __ ] on the agriculture podcast who
wants to come take a big dab
[Music]
I'll just put this mic in a mic stand
you're gonna hear a thump guys sorry
about that should be producing their own
meds I can't stress that enough if
you've got a closet if you've got any
locked space you can produce
high-quality meds you don't you don't
have to you can use a dispensary or
retail outlet sometimes but the whole
idea of having legal marijuana is so
it's accessible to everyone and it's
such an easy plant to grow it's a
[ __ ] weed and you know a lot of our
interest and a lot of our focus is gonna
be on education on how to produce your
own marijuana growing your own makes you
it slows you down take time or slow down
and and and take care of things besides
just what's going on with everyday life
like if I've only been growing for a
couple years and it does it really it's
like meditation in a way you know and in
it was one of those things that I didn't
know about I was a gamer I've had fish
and all all those things stopped when I
started growing you know it took over my
life so you can't rush a pot plant no
you can't hold out and it it brings
understanding of other other things in
your life believe it or not will
parallel what you're doing in the
growing phase for insight it's a place
for stimulation you can continue your
education it's there's so many benefits
in getting involved in something new
something you always did you always
smoke but you never could quite make the
leap we're gonna try to make it easier
for everybody to get growing in purple
and and I'm sure Jeff will attain to
this that you learn something every day
growing there's it never stops because
if you don't learn something every day
than your girl gets old and you're never
having and I'm that guy that always
strives to get to the next level well
you seem like a fairly fit and healthy
kind of guy do you think that growing
your own cannabis has contributed to you
paying a night I know you're a farmer
you grow other fruits and vegetables
does it contribute to you taking better
care of yourself as a as a being I'm so
glad you asked that question
for the past month I've been working on
a surface mind out and right and so for
six hours a day I move for hundreds we
do about two tons a day of marble
granite rocks laughs and you know it's
such a beautiful setting up there in Rye
we can we can smoke there we can we can
kick it but the work is hard and I
wouldn't be able to do that work if
these myths about marijuana was true I
even smoked a pack a week of cigarettes
believe it or not so don't buy into all
the stereotypes about you've got to be
unfit because you use marijuana it's
just not true
thanks for coming Greg if you were a
lazy pothead like they claim you
wouldn't be able to work in a mine I'd
never into Lee after he was working one
day I happened to be stopping at the
same gas station this dude was covered
and dust from head to toe he looked like
he had just been buried and dug out of
the dirt that man was doing work that
day he looked burnt - he looked fried
that was a man that had spent his day
you guys
go to Facebook and check out grow
pueblos it's a Facebook page and I've
got a little plot of land and I use that
plot to show people how much produce you
can produce yourself in a small area
last year girl Pueblo donated over 2000
pounds of fresh produce to the Salvation
Army
the Pueblo soup kitchen the Pueblo
women's shelter and the YWCA I was fresh
watermelons cantaloupes squash peppers
you name it and the gardens bigger this
this year so go to go to Pablo
like the page there's a lot of
information we give not only on growing
produce but on producing marijuana as
well take care of yourselves guys here's
something I want to mention it's kind of
random Gary just took a gigantic dab and
I'm gonna put him on the spot I heard
you say that since you've moved to
Colorado you've gotten off of a lot of
the medications you were taking and you
have lost 10 pounds per month since
you've moved here is that accurate it is
and I can see it now that we've hang we
hang out a little more frequently I
could definitely see it start shipping
off you yeah it's uh I was I have a
three fused vertebrae in my neck
cervical spine it's a really bad spot
you know real painful all the time like
sleeping is painful sitting this painful
standing walking is painful so when I
moved here I had quit my last job
because at the end of the day I was
unable to get out of the chair like
literally unable to chair I had to have
help
getting to my car so I just quit and you
know started doing the freelance thing
did that for about six months it was
going really well and I decided to
relocate here and when I got here and
had access to cannabis regularly I
stopped taking I was taking six
hydrocodone a day I stopped taking all
of them within thirty days of being here
you know I can be more active I can be
more productive I'm a full-time student
working on the MBA at a CSU and you know
I get my schoolwork done faster my
grades have improved everything you have
lost 10 pounds a month steadily since
I've been here
and made some changes in my diet and
that's actually accelerated now so
compared to from when I first had you we
had Jonah podcast you've been on a
couple of our shows you were on Episode
four of the agriculture podcast this is
I think 17 or 18 ish so we've been
cranking about your thought process is
longer and you can speak longer when I
think that's probably from switching
pills to cannabis exactly you're a
little more with us you know that really
focuses in like on the smoking club
thing right how many people are out
walking around high on pills you look at
the numbers of people prescribed pain
medication yeah that's gotta be a lot of
[ __ ] people bottle of some kind of
pain medicine that they were just given
that they don't need that the doctors
kind of and it states use this 90% of
all the pharmaceuticals uses 90% of that
and if the rest of the world gets
headaches and and has back pains but
they don't but they don't go to
pharmaceutical route do they do they not
still use natural stuff I mean and that
goes I'm glad you asked that and so uh
there's a practical example you go to
the doctor you get a scrip for and be
kind of an adapter or something like
that for
issue and it's got a high risk of
dependence
it's got terrible side effects and that
doctor could very well have told you
Larry everything the exact same thing
with no side effects is you're not gonna
get hooked on it but no one wants to
chew on no damn root anymore man pop
into pills done can make a tea with it
you can compress you can bake it into a
cake and have that cake which at night
and excuse me at that time and so across
the across the medical board across the
scale of illnesses there are botanicals
that affect those illnesses in a
positive way and my core company is
called nonstop wellness and that's what
non-stop wellness does is empowers
people with the information they need to
affect their health outside of
traditional medicine and I've been here
in Pueblo for four years now I've run a
doctor's office that provided access to
the red card registry and provided a lot
of services to people with serious
illnesses illnesses like bone cancer
like multiple sclerosis skull bro stirs
you have to excuse me you're good even
arthritis ocular pressure across the
board and there are specific strains of
cannabis or other botanicals that under
proper proper medical super-fit
supervision have just as high
success outcomes as their pharmaceutical
counterparts do you work with the
principle of hot and cold herbs so if
you give me valerian you got to give me
something cool to work well exactly and
some herbs are cooling herbs some heat
the body and so mint versus cinnamon
would be a good example of of those two
working at opposite good heart health
absolutely and so the the heating herbs
are effective with things like people
who are cold who have chills
the cooling herbs lower blood pressure
and even something as simple as a tepid
bath versus hot bath versus a cold bath
can have a positive effect on a wide
range of illness and I'm speaking
generally because I'm not trying to give
any health advice I'm just trying to
point people in the right direction it's
alright I didn't need to see your
medical degree dr. Lee we got you man I
got I'm with you oh well I'm pretty
buzzed and different plants and stuff
like that and like you were saying
earlier if you want to learn to grow you
don't have to grow marijuana growing is
growing you know like getting out there
in the garden will alleviate the stress
that you have in your life absolutely
you know if you if you live in a state
where you can't grow get out there and
start a garden grow corn grow tomatoes
you know tomato plant is just about the
same except for you can actually eat the
fruit Tony's gonna argue with you that
well yeah responsibility every morning
with it you got to play with the dirt
you got to get rid of bugs you gotta
learn when to harvest it's all the same
principle different plant the whole
works on the agricultural principle and
even for you religious people biblical
principles become clear when you grow
things and so you know you may hear
someone say nip it in the bud or or they
want to get down to the root of
something but until you've grown
something and experienced a growth cycle
a lot of things just aren't clear people
were meant to have that relationship
with the earth and it's been sorely
neglected excuse me neglected by the
past couple of generations absolutely
yeah we've taken the taking the plants
out of the ground we ground them up and
we've made little pills that are mixed
with a whole bunch of other you know
other countries where people eat fruit
and vegetables all day long they don't
have the cancers craps and tumors and
craps that we have here they're not
obese they're not crazy the problem is
in our government what happens is our
elected officials are bought by the
corporate interest and you know there's
a very good chance that Barack Obama
will become part of the staff of
Monsanto when he leaves office that's
the kind of tricks they pull in in
government and he's appointed several
people that have taken away our right to
be informed about what we buy it at
retail for our bodies
I got to give Tony a pretty big dab here
so he hears some choking that's my web
designer dude we've had a lot of traffic
in and out I like it this is kind of a
success thank everybody that's still
here for hanging out I know you guys
waiting in line for dabs I'll get you I
promise I'm just [ __ ] rambling thanks
for coming
sorry I didn't say hi to Arnie he's
outside having a cigarette big shout out
to pervane Arnie for showing up Preveza
listener she listens all the time so I'm
glad she's here we got iGrow culture we
got Mary Jane's glass legends these
places we've got Facebook pages the CR
RC has a Facebook page that's up we've
got we've got some people standing here
so they should probably get the mic in
[Music]
this is Andrew just chilling here with
these guys um yeah I wanted to add on to
what you were saying about cannabis
growing just being good overall for your
health like time for me today and it
really is I mean it can be it can be a
lot of heavy lifting involved you know
if you're even doing like aquaponics or
stuff like that it can be like
construction and you know it really is
good to grow as a person that way you
learn a lot about different things that
don't even have to do with growing that
you can utilize in your everyday work
you know so it's it's all around a good
thing for you and I've lost like tons of
weight since I've started doing it you
know like it's a great thing for
everyone involved it really is that's a
great point
and and and to that point I also want to
kind of debunk another myth that goes
hand-in-hand with that people say you
smoke and then you gotta eat you get the
munchies and so you get fast but that's
not what's what's happening at all what
happens is you smoke marijuana and it
raises your metabolism and people
identify that with
but it's it's not hunger it's your body
opportunity for you to get moving and
it's your body telling you that it's
switching from using food to burning fat
somebody told me if I brush my teeth
right after I smoke I won't get the
munchies I don't know if I tried it or
not if you normally get the munchies
smokeable on the brush your teeth as a
new grower as a new grower since you're
paying attention your plants now do you
pay attention to your pH a little bit
more because you gotta pay you said
aquaponics I assume that it takes a lot
of pH adjustment yeah think about what
you're putting into yourself and your
own personal pH balance when you work
with the plants and feed them properly
and love them they grow and look healthy
and I can only imagine I've seen what
happens when I feed my plants a shitty
nutrient and that's what I think of when
I eat a Snickers bar make fat buds from
eating a Snickers bar yeah the proper
carbo load would be a good idea I'm
gonna take a DAB who's got something to
say I mean I met you the same night that
I met Jeff you know which was that which
was at another dab association type bar
or gathering and I mean dude you look
great since then so I mean any anybody
trying to tell you that marijuana's is
not working as some cue fat yeah I mean
dude I've smoked pot pretty much all my
life my parents both smoked smoked pot
they grew up hot maybe it's my mom my
Hobbit metabolism but I highly doubt it
you know it's one thing I can't I don't
eat until I smoke pot yeah that's that's
one of the things you know we'll get a
bag and I won't eat three or four hours
afterwards just because I want to be
able to enjoy my high I'm one of those
people that if I get in the shower or if
I eat a burger or something like that
I'm done it's done it's gone you know
and then I'm going back into my bag and
you're never you're not gonna get high
after that you know it's right wait as
long as I right
don't think that hunger pains are gonna
kill them and that's that's not that's
not the case law if you just and it's
also a something to do with my hands I
just get bored you know I need some
chips or some you gotta grab a whole
[Music]
there's all kind of stuff to do to Rhian
yourself to have better habits and it's
it's it's a tough proposition but it's
worth it in the end and so growing
things and growing things is a great way
to do that there's plenty of grow
lessons coming up from this show and
already given on this show so absolutely
don't be afraid we'll teach you how to
grow up plenty of great weed something I
want to mention be hungry once in a
while there are plenty of hungry [ __ ]
people and plenty of places don't have
it as well as you do hungry see what
that's like quit being a whiny [ __ ] all
the time be hungry feel that and when
you're like damn I'm hungry you'd be a
little hungry just once better often
almost 70% of the population in my house
yeah yeah so Adam stands in front of the
freezer puts his head in there and fans
himself - cool
you put your feet in a pan of ice water
just a few points to kind of kind of
kind of refocus we want the same kind of
representation that we've already got
for alcohol we don't want anything new
we don't want anything fancy we also
want the citizens to be involved in in
the law making part of the industry we
also want the government to understand
that the people voted for marijuana and
they didn't vote for bans they didn't
vote for moratoriums and we have that
sisters situation because people just
didn't get involved and so see our RC
that's the organization that we've
started to interface with our government
and be a part of the laws that are gonna
affect you so you may as well get
involved yeah you can't complain about
the rules if you did not help make them
when you had the chance did create the
marijuana board they passed that and
I've applied to be a kudos to them for
that they acted fast on that to us on
the show adversarial to us the situation
is just no one has has stepped up to
feel the need for citizen participation
and that's happened we welcome anyone
who wants to be a part and
again City Hall third floor 7:00 p.m.
Monday the 7th and you can show up will
have applications for the marijuana
board you can sign up to speak to the
council and get a lot of information and
and meet some good people lots of good
people and if you can come to the
meetings or even if you can't come to
our event on 7 27 at the Brickyard in
Pueblo Colorado I'll post the address up
we're gonna wrap it up we're about an
hour does anybody have any final words
the best thing you can do is show
support I like you Adam and show support
you know for the amount of credit I give
you sometimes you say some good [ __ ]
sometimes doesn't take much effort to
make a phone call or send an email to
three to five minutes out of your day
smoke levels that's how much fun we're
having does anybody fear for their
safety
no responsible I'm gonna drive home
safely
we recorded for a full hour we've been
here for close to two or three hours
nobody's gotten crazy you guys want to
give everybody a big shout out for that
one we are the responsible citizens I
don't think all the listeners for
listening for this long hour and
something minutes episode I want to
thank everybody they came if people
already laughed hopefully you're
listening thanks for coming while you
could wait thanks for showing up dude
that was really cool of you thank you
Jeff thanks to all the people we've
mentioned the sponsors and the people
that helped us out thanks misty misty
Hosting there are three pretty ladies
waving to us from drinks and everything
our podcast my podcast was catered
there's vegetarian food Humber
sandwiches yeah there's some salmon
something over there sounds good you
guys better eat and the next one will be
even better and so again in closing you
can find on Facebook super bud bowl
pueblo grow pueblo non-stop nursing and
legends has a website so look us up get
involved yeah get involved like Adam
said get involved thanks to you you you
you you thanks to everybody that came
tonight once again do this again man
take a few dabs more dabs just a second
enjoy this episode I don't wanna thank
everybody once again for tuning in if
you're in Pueblo Colorado Monday July
7th please come to the City Council
meeting help support our movement also
make sure you attend our event
7:27 at the Brickyard in Pueblo Colorado
I'll post the address and everything on
the Twitter and on the Facebook so that
you guys all know where to go I'm
writing down right now post address see
post address I'm gonna forget what the
[ __ ] that means later but I wrote it
down so that I'll try to remember to do
it
so come to that event I'll have some
live plants grow in there you'll be able
to come check out live plant to get a
small cannabis education also make sure
you email City Council and Pueblo and
tell them that you want them to loosen
the restrictions on social cannabis
clubs and allow a cannabis club in the
city limits because that's what we want
that's what we need so email them I will
post all those email addresses on the
Facebook and on the Twitter so check it
out there at I grow culture on Twitter
and just I grow a culture on Facebook so
find it there and now that the show is
over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for I grow culture
find the review section give me a five
star rating type in a comment let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on the show if
you tell me that I suck if you tell me
that I'm awesome I will read your
comments don't forget the show is
available on iTunes stitcher swell dot
am and also every single episode is
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm so you can listen all the way from
the beginning
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening
take a phat dab
give your mom a hug for me I want to
close out this episode by playing the
whole version of the secret Cup anthem
before you buy hydral big big shout out
to hydro make sure you follow him on
twitter instagram plus some pretty
killer pictures on instagram you might
learn some [ __ ] from the guy shoutout
bro thanks for letting me use your music
here's the whole tune
[Music]
I'm so glad that you made it from l8
again what we are getting
tell me
[Music]
with the judges extract extraordinary to
the so got the rig looking cleaner do it
big where's my number have you seen it
that's the opinion most of never find
[Applause]
I gather ring that is then appreciate
the movement a battle led the best when
they discuss how to do it a friendly
competition this cool will take the
[Music]
cuz it understood trying to do it again
come on
[Music]
[Applause]
and put it
[Music]
[Applause]
podcast episode number 19 it's great to
be with you I promise it is good to be
with you may not sound like I'm having
fun some dying from a DAB but here in
just a minute we're gonna get a party
started
it's a rainy day here in Colorado I'm
hanging out relaxing listening to the
sound of the rain and thunder I've been
wondering what to put on the show it's
been a few days since I put out an
episode and I messed up the rhythm by
putting out a show on Saturday but I'm
back on schedule with number 19 so
thanks for joining me gosh I think I've
recovered from that dab last night over
to the 710 cup award ceremony in Denver
the 710 cup is a hash festival it's kind
of a competition there were about 50
entries in the hash contest what they do
is the hash makers enter their hash
already their concentrate already broken
down into small samples so I think there
were 50 contestants which means they had
to turn in 50 samples those entries are
then assigned a number and they make a
little kit for each of the judges so
you're given a little like a pencil box
full of samples labeled one through 50
and you basically go through and you
spend a couple of days smoking each
sample and you judge them by flavor
texture appearance there's a nice little
list of things that we judge them on I
was not part of the judging this year I
did it last year this year I did not do
any of the judging but you go and you
judge all the stuff and then you turn in
your judging all your paperwork's and
then on Saturday night last night they
announced all of the winners and they do
it by numbers to keep it anonymous so
that way nobody knows which sample is
which so I did not attend the Friday or
Saturday portions of the event I was
only
able to make it up to the award ceremony
at Quixote's on Saturday night but that
part was tons of fun the party kicked
off with a marijuana comedian
I was a little dabbed out and distracted
by conversation when they introduced him
so I did not catch his name and I
honestly didn't pay too much attention
to most of his set I had bumped into a
bunch of friends hadn't seen in a while
we kind of got into conversation I
apologized to the comedian for not
paying any attention I feel a little
rude about that but you know what I was
there for a party so after the comedian
there was an award ceremony where Sean
Tron took home most of the awards we'll
go over a full list of the award winners
just a little bit so there's a funky jam
band that played a Grateful Dead cover
that I really appreciated they played a
version of shakedown Street that I
thought was pretty damn awesome I get to
visit with a bunch of friends and I only
see it for 20 or 710 events and to top
it all off I stuck around to hear a few
songs from old school rappers Slick Rick
food Slick Rick was wearing more gold
than I've ever seen I've seen full rap
groups not wearing as much gold and
bling a Slick Rick had if he could get
it
diamond and gold watch he had his rings
were bigger than most people's pendants
he had the links in his gold chains were
more gold than most people's gold chain
that dude was bling the [ __ ] out so a
big shout out big 710 style shout outs
my buddy Kevin he saved me a really
prime seat to sit in a spot in which to
sit I don't know the proper grammar
there Kevin save me a [ __ ] killer
seat thanks bro
I big shout-out to Josh and Jeff from a
lot of labs also a shout-out to Lenny
lane for bringing the killer solvent
less that was tasty bro thank you and
thanks for the good conversation about
breeding that conversation is not done
we have to finish that conversation or
continue it at least also big shout-out
to J dizzle for the super tasty and
ultra smooth dab that dabba Chino but
the email on it that is [ __ ] stylish
and it hits like a boss so thank you
also a big shout out to ruga from grass
roots for throwing and hosting the party
the award ceremony went fairly smoothly
I was just ran by Mike fro and Ryan Rua
Connolly from grassroots and they did a
hell of a job so I also want to give a
big shout out to Big D
D was given a Lifetime Achievement Award
from the 7:10 community I was great to
see somebody honored and for his
dedication and his work in the community
and not just for his hash making skills
he's received plenty of awards for that
it was good to see him get an award just
for being a good dude that was well
overdue
the part of the event I saw was great
during one of Slick Rick songs the whole
sound system was dead for a couple of
minutes and they had to figure out what
went wrong to get the show started again
so I was kind of curious how you know
he's kind of a superstar I was kind of
curious how he would handle it but he
just waited it out he stood on stage to
kind of cool it down it was hot in there
I think he took a minute to catch his
breath and cool down it was hot in there
so after that first band played he got
really hot by the time Slick Rick came
up it was way too hot for me so after a
couple of his songs I took a final dab
and I headed out and that was mostly my
7:10 cup experience I said we do a
rundown of the winners let me scroll
over to that right quick here's a quick
rundown I guess a quick rundown would be
Shaun Shaun [ __ ] cleaned house Shaun
Tron won everything not everything but
like most of it was just Shaun Tron he
walked away with a handsome cheque
I got a sweet custom-made rig from Mike
fro he had to grass roots hat deals he
got a vape pen
he got enough goodies to fill a suitcase
and then they also handed him a bunch of
gift cards so a big shout out to Shaun
Tron here are the official results of
the 2014 710 Cup this is from their
Facebook page let me scroll to it
alright starting at the bottom of the
list best taste went to advanced medical
alternatives with entry number 20 Durbin
poison best effect went to Shaun Tron
and the health center entry number 19
pre 98 bubba kush best consistency went
to infusions entry number one blueberry
plus Grape Ape best aroma went to kind
Bill and a cut above with entry number
29 legend of 91 number 3 and chem 91
best solvent list third place snake
Vitus us best solvent list number two
second place cannabis for health best
Ovilus first place intrigue 2:06 Cindy
white plus the boss CBD number two
infusions entry number eight sharp shock
CBD first place the health center Shaun
Tron once again entry number 19 398
bubba kush sativa wax third place THC
cannabis company second place sticky
business and first place advanced
medical alternatives with entry number
20 Durbin poison indica wax third place
third place God's green earth
second place growing mines first place
was advanced medical alternatives with
the entry number 13 oh gee bubba kush +
Strawberry Cough that sounds [ __ ]
tasty I don't know if I got a dab of
that one a lot of the dabs I tasted were
Jillybean heavy in my opinion and we'll
get to that here just a second was I see
Teva shatter third place TFC cannabis
company second place sticky business
first place advanced medical
alternatives with entry number 22 Durbin
poison into kowax third place God's
green earth
second place growing mines and first
place indica wax advanced medical
alternatives with entry number 13 oh gee
cush oh gee Bubba Kush and Strawberry
Cough that sounds like a delicious entry
let's see sativa shatter
third place God's green earth second
place steel rollin and first place it's
a health center with entry number 37 pre
Jilly
let's see indica shatter third place
native roots extracts
second place kind bill a cut above and
first place in indica shatter category
was in fusions entry number one which
was blueberry plus Grape Ape
these are pluses not times so these are
not bred together these are two strains
that were blended together their blends
not crosses is what I think I'm trying
to say so there were two special Awards
for the 2014 7:10 cup one of the awards
was the People's Choice Award and guess
who that one went to that went to the
health center which is Sean Tron once
again with number 37 the pre Jilly and
then drumroll please first place overall
you may be able to predict this one it
went to guess who Sean Tron once again
with the health center number 37 pre
Jilly so I'm gonna count them there's
one two three four five five winning
that I see six six wins from Sean Tron
in the health center they're out of one
two three four five six seven eight nine
ten eleven twelve categories
Sean Tron took six of them so congrats
bro I don't know if you listen to the
podcast or not but hope you do dude
congratulations I got to taste your
entry when I hit it I said right away
there's some Jilly bean in there except
a fan of the jelly bean strain so a big
shout-out to accept it to sub cool and
miss Jill for make of the Jilly bean I
guess we should say in Big Big Love to
the health center the grow team there
and [ __ ] super killer job - Sean Tron
and once again much respect to Ryan from
grass roots for throwing the competition
that's really cool of them to do there
was a scare that the competition was not
going to happen this year and I'm glad
that they pulled it together and made it
happen I apologize I'm getting a
Facebook message I'm reading these these
winners off of Facebook Facebook so that
doesn't happen again
sorry message me later whoever that was
I feel like that was enough about my
weekend let's do a quick ad or two and
then we will work our way into some news
who do you want to do an ad for I think
nature's green remedies has an ad let's
see this podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies dot-com visit
nature's green remedies dot-com for gage
green genetics the flauta labs Sin City
rare dankness bio hi can adventure IRA
genetics and many more trusted brands if
you purchase two packs of ira genetics
you will receive a free five pack of dub
wise while supplies last
nature's green remedies is running a
podcast they're running a podcast for
our special listeners you know what I
mean right the running is
special for you guys that are listening
because we appreciate you for listening
simply type in coupon code podcast for
15% off any order can you always get
free shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com coupon code podcast does expire
July 31st I'm pretty sure they do have
some hydrogen etics in stock they just
got a refill a couple of days ago so if
you're trying to get some of that stuff
the black cherry Kim the Grateful dog
act now they always seem to sell out
really quickly I can't help that that's
just what they do they order when
they're ready I send them their order
when they ask for it so I apologize
let's see this podcast is also brought
to you by our good friends at oil slick
oil slick tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick pad comm for more
information make sure you follow oil
slick on twitter find them under an oil
slick pad send them a tweet tell them
you're listening to the agriculture
podcast oil slick is a really good
sponsor and it's also a very practical
product I use my oil slick every single
day I've got a big oil slick pad that I
like to set a couple of my favorite
glass pieces on I got a couple of my
favorite glass rigs on the oil slick pad
I've got a carb cap on there I've got my
favorite concentrate sitting on the oil
slick pad I know that my concentrates
not going to stick to the oil slick pad
I know that I'm not gonna leave a bunch
of sticky rings on my table it's a place
to keep my stuff kind of organized it's
a nice little dedicated spot is what I
feel like and also you hear this sound
right here I don't know if you can hear
it
that's a rig hitting a table that's just
sending a rig down on a table here's a
rig sitting down on a slick bed they
made a little noise because I set it
down really hard it was out of my reach
but I mean did it I'd much rather
centered on the oil slick pad than the
wooden table it just feels a little
better for my rig one side sticks to the
table real well so it won't slide around
then the other side is nice and nice and
soft and your dabs won't stick to it
get yourself an oil slick pad also quit
carrying your hash around and fold it up
parchment paper
that doesn't look classy at all bro get
yourself a oil slick container they make
them in every color so have some class
it's an oil slick products step up the
game a little bit alright guys feels
like I need a dab so I'm gonna take a
quick dab and we will work our way into
a little bit of news hang tight for just
a minute
alright guys I'm back on the microphone
after way too many fat dabs is speaking
away too many fat dabs I want to
recommend another podcast I think you
guys should be listening to the Adam
Dunn show I know it seems weird that I'm
advertising another podcast that may be
considered a competitor but I don't see
that as a competition in any way at all
I would be doing you a disservice if I
did not recommend that I'm done show
specifically go back and listen to the
all about dabs episode 2 &amp; 3 and really
pay attention to what those guys are
talking about about what we're doing to
ourselves health-wise with dab some of
that stuff may be interesting to you it
may reduce your dad intake I'm known for
taking some [ __ ] huge dabs Ravine for
being a dab monster for love and loving
to take a lot of dabs that episode has
changed my dab intake and my approach to
dabbing a little bit those two episodes
I'm not anything I'm just more conscious
and I think that we should all be a
little bit aware of what we're doing to
our bodies and what we are potentially
doing to ourselves I'm not trying to
scare you but listen to the episodes of
the show big shout out to Adam Dunn I've
kind of saw it from across the room at
the 7:10 event last night
he was the guy wearing the shirt with
his face on his own shirt so shout out
Adam Dunn shout out to Mitch and NASA
all the guys that helped out on that
show all the people that are the guests
on the episode they talked about listen
to that that's good [ __ ] that's enough
ranting about that so let's get into
some news where do you want to start
let's start here at home in Colorado
Colorado about your [ __ ] pot heads
dude this one comes from the Denver Post
written by John Ingold published July
denied so we're a little bit late but
here we are
Colorado study pegs annual pod demand at
a hundred and thirty metric tons goddamn
you smoke a lot of weed Colorado a state
produced study has included that high
taxes and fewer stores are keeping
Colorado Medical Marijuana consumers
from switching to the recreational
cannabis market a trend that if
continues will have a major impact on
the state's predicted Marilyn
tax windfall the study released
Wednesday found that out-of-state
visitors make up nearly half of the
recreational marijuana sales in the
Denver area and 90% of recreational
sales and mountain resort communities
tourists though account for only about
7% of the annual demand for marijuana
and the state which the study estimates
at a hundred and thirty point three
metric tons that's a lotta weed dude I
can't even fathom a hundred and thirty
point three metric tons I was in Denver
driving yesterday for that 7/10 Cup my
past dispensary that's right there there
in downtown Denver and there were a
group of people that were obviously from
out of state because they were gathered
in front of the sign of the dispensary
and they were taking turns taking
picture of each other throw in there a
local gang sign up in front of the
dispensary sign I found it entertaining
I take it for granted we here in
Colorado we've forgot Blake we just go
to the weed store buy some weed or we
don't most of us are probably growing
our own by now
they said that 50% of the recreational
sales is from people from out of state
my buddy Kevin that's on the show
sometimes he works at a shop he says
most of the people are from Texas
so most of that's gone to Texas it
sounds like one quarter at a time so
I'll continue with the article the study
finds total marijuana demand to be much
larger than previously estimated the
study's author write in their report the
reason the authors conclude is that
previous studies have underestimated the
level of demand from heavy users the new
study finds that the top 22 percent of
marijuana users in Colorado account for
nearly 67 percent of the total demand
the bottom 50 poor four percent users
account for only about four percent of
demand my lips are all sticky you guys
can hear it that's from the big fat dab
I took think about that if my lips are
sticky how far down into that sticky
shake is that all in my throat is that
all of my lungs because I felt it on my
teeth the other night that kind of
freaked me out it made me start thinking
about this that's just a weird random
side note so this just said 22% of
marijuana users in Colorado account for
nearly 67
percent of the total demand I'm not a
mathematician or a math magician but 20
if there's a hundred people smoking all
this weed 22 of them are smoking sixty
seven percent all that weed that's funny
to me there there are some serious
hardcore pockets or are there people
doing what we call the dispensary flip
or they go on and get in there outs then
are they taking it around and doing what
they can do I don't even want to
encourage or talk about that but a lot
of that is probably that unfortunately
the prevalence of heavy users in
Colorado is higher than the national
average the authors right so it says the
department feels it is important to
understand marijuana usage and the
demand in the state to effectively
manage production within the regulated
industry Colorado Department of Revenue
executive director Barbara Brawl said in
a statement the marijuana Enforcement
Division said it used survey results
demographic data research literature and
Colorado specific specific primary
source data to compile the study I'm
kind of curious because they don't ah
they're not supposed to be taking our
information when we go in we show them
our ID at these right shops but they
don't photo copy your ID they're not
supposed to be taking any notes on who's
in there so I'm a little curious where
this data came from I'd like to find out
more about that if anybody's listening
that has input on how they got that info
if you have input on how they got that
info tweet me message me at hydro
culture on Twitter
agriculture on Facebook or I grow
culture at hotmail.com if you want to
email me a long stuff I would appreciate
it so I don't know where they got that
they're not supposed to be copying our
data Colorado specific primary source
data anyway among the most significant
conclusions listed in the report few
people are switching from shopping at
medical marijuana dispensaries to
shopping at recreational marijuana
stores well no [ __ ] it's more expensive
there the study concludes that the study
concludes that could be because of
higher taxes for recreational marijuana
and fewer available outlets discouraging
switching oh no [ __ ] you charges 25%
extra a Colorado resident is gonna go
and get their car that costs you a
hundred bucks at one time
see I get your red card and save all
that money to save all the money like if
you shop twice the cost of the doctor
and then every time you go after that is
just a bonus
so the retail demand is derived
primarily from out of state visitors and
from customers who previously purchased
from the Colorado plaque in gray markets
the study's authors write the trend
though has major implications for the
state's marijuana tax revenue
predictions for revenue from the
recreational marijuana tax once reached
as high as thirty five million dollars
for the first six months of 2014
instead including numbers released
Wednesday form a tax collections the
state has brought in only about fourteen
point seven million so far the summers
here I bet we're gonna increase that
number through the summer and April
probably boosted a month and got them
all excited because a lot of weed so
medical marijuana sales meanwhile
continue to outpace recreational sales
through May medical marijuana
dispensaries had done nearly a hundred
and sixty five million dollars of sales
compared with the ninety million dollars
from recreational stores tax revenue
from medical marijuana sales though has
amounted to slightly less than five
million
trading system more people who are using
cannabis medically can access their
medicine without paying higher taxes is
not a bad thing said Taylor West a
spokeswoman for the National cannabis
Industry Association from the Denver
Post let me go find another related
article there's a leak here I think I
just gotta go back yeah they talked
about 130 metric tons of pot how heavy
is that state of Colorado estimates that
its annual demand for marijuana is a
hundred and thirty point three metric
tuan tons about how heavy is a hundred
and thirty metric tons anyway it's the
equivalent of two hundred and eighty
seven thousand two hundred and fifty
nine pounds as I'm making any more clear
to you
me neither that's also such a mammoth
number that context doesn't come
naturally but thankfully the cannabis
crackpot data team is here for you
Colorado's annual marijuana demand is
heavier than a space shuttle or a blue
whale but not quite as heavy as a
locomotive so yes it's a lot of wheat
how heavy is a hundred and thirty metric
tons they've given us a little graph
here
a hippopotamus weighs about 3,300 pounds
with that big ugly Mustang dia sculpture
that weighs 9,000 pounds a school bus
weighs 25,000 pounds bulldozer weighs
7,000 pounds of b-2 bomber is a hundred
and eighty-five thousand pounds of blue
whale is two hundred and fifty thousand
pounds annual estimated Colorado
Marijuana demand two hundred and eighty
seven thousand two hundred and fifty
nine pounds so our point is we are
smoking a whole bunch of cannabis and
nobody's going to jail for it that's
pretty awesome alright let's find
another news article to talk about here
on that article is obviously from the
cannabis let me find the author of that
piece for a that one was from Ricardo
Baca
let's see what's our next news article
I've forgot to even give a big
congratulations to Washington so this is
the part one where we're gonna do that
Washington they have opened up their
dispensaries now this article is also by
Ricardo Baca Thanks for writing all
these articles and making it easy for me
to do my news stuff there are a lot of
great news sources out there the
cannabis is always reliable they're here
in Colorado so quick shout out to the
cannabis this article headline is the
Washington sha this Washington shop
served over one thousand grams of pot to
four hundred buyers in four hours goes
like this
Thomas Beckley and John evic I'm
guessing on that we're on cloud nine
when we spoke with them on the morning
of July 8th an unbelievably bustling
cloud nine with electricity in the air
and cash in the registers we've had
about 400 people in four hours said
Beckley and odor at top-shelf cannabis
in Bellingham Washington we opened it
exactly through the news we saw that we
were the first shop to open in the state
of Washington congratulations guys
Friday you pretty stoked said the owner
of top shelf I'm not gonna murder your
name again I apologize for doing that
I'm not good with these names this is so
new and we're lucky just to get open and
that was a huge task right now traffic
is flowing smoothly and we're thankful
for that top shelf served around a
thousand grams of legal retail marijuana
to more than 400 customers in the first
four hours of business on July 8th
Beckley said after referencing his
in-house tracking system since the shops
median per gram price is $12.50 that
makes for roughly twelve thousand five
hundred dollars in sales for those four
hours or about three thousand dollars
per hour the line right now has dwindled
down a little bit Beckley said tonight
when everybody's off work I think will
be twice as much as it was earlier the
top shelf owners made international news
earlier this week when they talked
publicly about using about possibly
using one of their crab boats are
renting a helicopter to transport their
marijuana stock from Bremerton to
Bellingham to expedite the process of
finally opening their doors for their
first legal retail sale that grant an
elaborate plan didn't work out not using
it because we ran into some aviation
rules and we couldn't go on the water
because of the Coast Guard
Beckley said the FAA and the Coast Guard
told us they wouldn't recommend trying
it oh I bet these guys would have gotten
their whole stock taken from them that
would have been shitty out of it funny
and shitty at the same time it would've
been like a movie so anyway one of the
owners I can't say his name properly
evic iva CH attributed their smooth
launch on July 8th to a couple factors
including his request for a smaller
manifest for their weed delivery which
allowed them to count 50 something bags
of marijuana before starting sales
instead of counting 2,200 bags the shops
bio track THC plan of sale equipment and
software
even given all the excitement Tuesday
morning top-shelf cannabis actually
opened its doors a few minutes after 8
a.m. our door opened at 8:03 a.m. he
said because complying and working with
the state is the number one priority
even over customer service which yeah
that's got to be the truth so they have
their Washington stores are open so
anybody
I think 21 and over can go buy cannabis
there I was looking at a few other
articles the price per gram there you're
looking at paying between 15 and 25
dollars a gram just depending on what
strain and what shop some of the top
shelf stuff it seems like the trend well
is that a lot of these shops were
selling two gram packages so you're
getting two grams of the same strain and
it was already sealed he didn't get to
look at it there's got a jar on the
Shelf there like they've got there
several jars I'm just gonna make up
names it got headband they got Sour
Diesel they got Bubba cush on the in
jars they probably had six or seven
eight or ten strains lined up in jars
you can look at those and you're like I
want the Sour Diesel and they give you a
pre weighed bag of Sour Diesel that was
2 grams and it was costing about $45
plus tax about 40 plus tax in a lot of
places it just depends on where he went
and what strain you were looking for I'm
looking for more information on yeah
pre-tax was twenty nine dollars and
ninety two cents post tax was forty
dollars and that was the price for two
grams of a strain called sweet Lafayette
but I scroll down there are pictures of
some people's tweets $13 a dram at this
spa twenty five to twenty seven dollars
for two grams at this place here's what
one of the first customers bought a two
gram package cost them forty dollars
plus tax they don't have a picture of
the receipt on here with taxes it looks
like two grand bags are coming to fifty
four dollars so that's a little bit
pricey hopefully it'll come down but you
know there's nothing encouraging them to
lower their prices they're selling
plenty of weed already so it's probably
gonna stay like that for a little while
so I've got a couple more stories coming
from Washington since they just launched
their shops this one's kind of
entertaining
it says Seattle's City Attorney bought
weed for his enjoyment
Denver's did not
when Seattle's lawn recreational pot
shop cannabis City opened its doors on
July 8 seattle City Attorney Pete Holmes
was fourth in line and no not the Pete
hauled you're thinking this is not the
comedian not the guy with the big funny
teeth that had the TV show not him yes
he bought some marijuana for posterity
but he also bought some for personal
enjoyment pretty bold homes that's funny
because this guy just wrote the phrase
pretty bold homes and it sounds like
he's being a gangster pretty bold homes
anyway most important takeaway here is
that today marijuana sales became legal
and I'm here to personally exercise
myself this new freed up holds told
media on Tuesday
I bought two two grand bags of OG pearl
which was recommended I'm keeping one
bag for posterity and one bag for
personal enjoyment at some point when
it's appropriate so this dude just
admitted he's gonna puff down two grams
that's pretty nice
hopefully he shares with a good friend
they have a good laugh customer vivian
McPeak who happens to be the executive
director of seattle Hempfest said he was
proud of his city attorney I've been
terribly proud of our city attorney I'm
inherently proud r/c attorney has played
a groundbreaking role in making this
happen the shift in public policy
McPeake told a reporter he's backing up
his words and is going to take some big
nice long deep talks at home I think
it's all right Holmes bold move got us
wondering did Denver city attorney Scott
Martinez buy any marijuana for personal
or professional reasons On January 1st
if I bought any no I have not bought any
on January 1st or since then Martinez
told the cannabis on July 8th oh by the
way I didn't mention this article comes
once again from the cannabis thank you
but I do know Pete there city attorney
has elected and he campaigned on the
issue Martinez his point is
straightforward well he was appointed
city attorney by Denver Mayor Michael
Hancock Holmes was elected by the people
of Seattle as an elected official he
certainly has it different well he's an
elected official so I wouldn't comment
on what his path is Martinez said but we
both have an obligation to uphold the
law and I know what an important job it
is and wishing him the best as he goes
forward in this new time for Seattle and
Washington Martinez said Holmes had
visited Colorado and has seen legal
recreational marijuana industry in
action previous
Washington's opening day of retail sales
on July 8th we certainly share
information because it's important to
share best practices especially as we're
on the forefront of a unique legal issue
Martinez said he's a smart guy
well-educated he's got a big job ahead
of him we're going to continue that
sharing of information so the city
attorney bought some pot right and then
I got a scroll back because right after
that there was another article that came
out and the headline is and I'm sorry
I'm going slower my internet is slow
right here right now it says no pot
allowed at the office Seattle City
Attorney cops - breaking the rules so
Seattle City Attorney Pete Holmes
admitted he broke a drug-free workplace
rule and he brought marijuana on the
first date when he bought marijuana on
the first day of legal sales in
Washington state all just been a big
supporter of the legal marijuana wand he
says he wanted to be one of the first
customers in Seattle's cannabis City on
Tuesday to honor what he called a
tectonic shift in policy he says he then
bought the to honor he brought the two
unopened packages back to City Hall
before taking them home the next day the
city's personnel Department issued a
memo reminding employees it can't have
marijuana that are on if when they're on
official business or at city offices
holds issued an apology Friday and City
volunteered to donate three thousand
dollars to the downtown emergency
service center organization that
provides housing for alcohol alcoholic
mentally ill or otherwise vulnerable
people that turned into an expensive ass
two grams of weed for City Attorney Pete
Holmes man there's a picture of him here
shaking hands with the clerk from
cannabis City and he's got a big grin on
his face looking at the weed like huh
weed everyone's smiling at him like
that's the city attorney one guys not
sure what to think he's like can he
arrest me kind of funny so even the City
Attorney kind of [ __ ] up he bought his
weed and he took it right to the office
he was proud he didn't know what to do
with it he walk around with your new bag
all excited so there's another article
related to the Washington cannabis the
only pot shop in Seattle sells out 11
pounds of marijuana are gone in three
days with taxes the shops prepackaged to
grab bags sold for forty six dollars and
seventy seven cents San Francisco this
article is actually from Allison
affection from Bloomberg News cannabis
City the only licensed marijuana
retailer in Washington's largest city
ran out of stock on the third day of
state approved sales its owner said the
store one of 25 licensed statewide this
week had 11 pounds which is four
thousand nine hundred and ninety grams
of pot when it opened July 8th then it
sold out around 5:00 p.m. local time
Thursday owner James
Lathrop Lathrop Lathrop sorry I [ __ ]
last name so bad I apologize James said
with taxes to grab bags sold for forty
six dollars and seventy seven cents we
knew it was coming we didn't have any
guaranteed additional deliveries
according to the Associated Press this
guy doesn't expect to get more supply
for ten to fifteen days
Washington home to amazon.com Microsoft
and Starbucks became the second state
after Colorado to prevent the sale of
marijuana for recreational use
voters in both states approved the
ballot initiatives in 2012 Colorado
retailers began sales in January this
guy said growers didn't receive licenses
in time to produce enough marijuana for
the stores opening this week the plants
take three to four months to mature he
said Washington issued 90 licenses to
pot growers and processors as of last
week according to Brian Smith a
spokesman for the Washington State
Liquor Control Board an agency charged
with regulatory regulating the industry
so they didn't get their gross sent up
in time and they had to open up and
guess what not enough reefer
welcome to the pot world with 11 pounds
that's not that small talk like any
hustler should move through 11 pounds in
a week what he doing okay so they're
sold out of weed at some places and
they're saying right here that 2 grams
is going for forty six dollars and 77
cents that's a little pricey
all right I've got one more little piece
of news that comes from Washington they
put out a press release thing there was
a whole bunch of answers to Washington
weed sale six questions answered there's
one question that I found interesting
that I could share with you guys it says
how much can I buy and this is
Washington keep that in mind because the
laws are different Colorado I found this
interesting because in Colorado they
forgot to write this law and so now
they're trying to figure this out now
and in Washington they've put it in
there correctly at the beginning so it
says how much can i buy state law allows
the sale of up to an ounce of dried
marijuana 16 ounces of pot infused
solids 72 ounces of pot infused liquids
which would be teachers or solves I
would assume SABS whatever you want to
call that that liquid [ __ ] you rub in
that I don't I don't like it it doesn't
do much for me but 7 grams of
concentrated marijuana like hashish 2
adults over 21 whether you're a
Washington resident or not but there
isn't expected to be any infused food or
drink available right away as of last
week the Liquor Control Board had not
issued any licenses to processors for
those products or approved any edibles
for sale some stores are talking about
limiting customers to 1/2 gram package
each to make sure there's enough for
everyone
to buy some which appears to be what
happened on the first day of sales a lot
of the shops in Colorado ver lemonade
get to 1/8 or 1/4 I was actually lucky
enough to be the first person to buy
recreational cannabis at the greener
side dispensary in Pueblo Colorado and I
actually picked up two eighths they were
not limiting sales that day but they
were not doing grams sales is what they
were doing it was 1/8 minimum and they
had everything prepackaged and yeah they
weren't doing any grams so they didn't
have any of that like let me get a gram
of this a grandma this a gram of this it
was let me get it ain't let me get in
aids and I picked up the Girl Scout
cookies and some Tahoe OG and to tell
you the truth those packages are still
sealed on my desk with the receipt
sitting next to them I have not smoked
it I haven't touched it
that's nostalgia I hardly smoke herb
that I did not grow myself I'm picky
like that but I had to be first you know
I've been the the weed guy in this area
since before we
talk about being the weave guy feel like
I had to be that guy it's kind of fun
shout out to but the greener side to
Spencer e shout out to Hank and all that
crew garden of Wheaton all those guys
right on
they love I walk doing shoutouts I
should do one quick ad and then we're
gonna do another news topic here where
is my ad page here it is this podcast is
proudly brought to you by high grow
indoor growing supplies you guys have
noticed I only use sponsors that I trust
that I actually use their products I
don't have any [ __ ] sponsors I don't
accept sponsors that I wouldn't fully
recommend to my friends so high growth
growing high grow indoor growing
supplies hydro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street unit F or stop by the new
location in Pueblo Colorado at 618 East
4th Street check out high growth for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out ww-why are a Denver
calm for current store hours and special
sales stop in the Buffalo store tell
them you're listening to the iGrow
culture podcast they'd like to hear that
they've got a lot of cool [ __ ] that I've
never seen in grow stores in Pueblo
before they've got the og T there I
highly recommend Oh G T feed it to your
plants at the recommended dosage every
two weeks I stopped feeding it to my
flowering plants about week four cuz I
feel like they've gotten enough by then
but all the way up to week four
flowering from the time I put seedlings
I put that [ __ ] in there like the first
feeding my seedlings get that on their
very first feeding all the way to week
four a flower so OGT I recommend that
[ __ ] strongly and you can get it at high
grow Denver I grow up webelo tell them I
sent you
alright I want to find this other
article I'm clicking around trying to
find it it's in here it's in the
computer somebody typed it I promise you
it exists who remembers the episode
where we gave thanks to mr. Marc Emery
bara Camry is guy who was in federal
prison in America and he actually did
not commit any crime in my opinion he
was a Canadian guy he was shipping seeds
across the world and
the Canadian authorities and the
American authorities United and they
extradited him to America and they put
his ass in prison he actually served
let's see one thousand five hundred and
ninety days which guess what that means
he was officially his sins ended July
ninth he's not home yet there's a bunch
of crap you gotta go through once you
get out of prison and you're not a US
citizen so I'm gonna read something this
is from a Marc Emery's blog this
actually comes from cannabis culture
calm a lot of it is written by his wife
Jodi I've been paying a lot of attention
to what's going on with Marc through his
Twitter his wife Jodi updates the
Twitter for him quite often and he was
actually a lot of internet access in the
prison he was in so I'll quit rambling
and here is by Marc Emery written Monday
June 30 is with a few updates from Jodi
Emory's spattered in there I'll let you
know when those happen so this says this
is my last blog from the terminals of
the US Bureau of Prisons my sentence was
four five years which would be 1825 days
and I earned all 235 days on my eligible
good content conduct credit so my sense
officially ends at one thousand five
hundred and ninety days which is
Wednesday July 9th on Thursday July 10th
the u.s. immigration picks me up and
takes me to the private for-profit geo
group or geo group lasalle Detention
Facility in Jena Louisiana where I will
be processed for deportation back to
Canada but then this is where Jody
Energex with an update it says July 11th
update by Jodie Emery mark is not at
LaSalle Detention Facility he has been
sent to ten teen saws ten SAS I don't
know how to read that one tenses Parish
detention center in Louisiana they give
his alien ID number and she says I don't
know how long it will be there you can
look up his alien ID number at the
immigrations and Customs Enforcement
website detainee locator page for
information about where he currently is
she gives an address to cinmarc letters
or books you can only order the books
online
they can't be sent from an individual to
have to come from a distributor or a
vendor so that they know you're not
sticking [ __ ] in there but then there is
an address to ship books
- I will read it right now he will be
there until August he predicts so here
is the address
marc emery gets ma RC eme ry and then
you've got to put this number this is
his number numbers zero seven nine zero
six seven seven one zero I'll repeat it
for you if you're as high as me it's
zero seven nine zero six seven seven one
zero and then you're sitting sending
some books or a letter of encouragement
- it's te and SAS Parrish tenses Parrish
P AR is H P AR is H I say that right
sorry I'm reading it from high tenses
Parrish detention center it's a spelled
c-- e and TR e because it's in Louisiana
they spell [ __ ] silly there it's eight
six zero six highway 65 waterproof
Louisiana which is LA and then the zip
code is seven one three seven five I
will try to remember to tweet that I'm
writing a note to tweet that
all right sorry that took second to
write the note so you can send letters
have encouraged me you can send him all
kinds of letters don't send him anything
[ __ ] stupid it's a prison come on
be smart please but you can send him
letters so you can send him mom
like anything he might want to read hope
I'm not passed the time so mark
continues and he says my understanding
is that I'll be dropped off ultimately
at the border in Windsor Ontario I'm
thinking sometime between August 10th
and August 25th that's a month after his
release date but we have no way of
knowing for sure you'd think that you
think that would be a straightforward
process taking a few days at most but
LaSalle is a for-profit G EO group
Detention Center and thus they're making
money for every day I am there and
because the Canadian government is
involved these bureaucrats have a
tendency to be slower than they ought to
be so I may need your help in providing
motivation for them to repatriate me
back to Canada on a more reasonable and
timely schedule the former Canadian
Conrad Conrad black got out of Coleman
federal prison in Florida last year he
was given he was driven straight forward
to Miami and able to go immediately to
Toronto on a flight with his wife
Barbara me oh that was extraordinarily
not the least of which because Conrad
black is not even a Canadian citizen
anymore it has never happened to any
other Canadian in the US prison no doubt
his friendship with former Prime
Minister Brian Mulroney and others got
him an instant express immigration
approval back to Canada but it shows a
clear unfairness that a man who
renounced his Canadian citizenship so he
could be lured in the British House of
Commons gets treatment far beyond what
any actual Canadian citizen like myself
currently receives from the Canadian
government I say like myself that's what
Mark wrote I am NOT Canadian I'm an
American I'm from California but from
Colorado now I get no connections in the
high places long drawn-out delayed route
to it unceremonious drop-off in Windsor
Ontario at that not even to my home in
Vancouver sorry mark right strangely in
long sentences and I'm hi know cuz she
flied for me back to the airport of my
choice alongside my wife like Conrad my
point being if they could get non
Canadian Conrad's paperwork ready in
advance to get to Toronto immediately
upon his US federal prison release they
could have mine ready
- last I checked I am still a Canadian
citizen
so then Jody updated she says July 11th
update the following information is not
completely accurate because mark is not
Atlas L he is at chances Parish
Detention Facility stay tuned for
updates as they come
then mark continues at any rate once I
arrived in LaSalle I will be given an
alien number and Jody will update this
blog to indicate well my eight number is
but you see my a number in this blog
I've been told that you can actually
send me messages over the phone or by
calling a phone number which doesn't is
no good anymore some won't even bother
reading it the receptionist will deliver
messages okay gonna skip all this
because Isis by phone cards and I can
call out without limits on phone time
it's not quite a prison okay but he's
not there anymore he says done with my
official u.s. sins but I still can't
leave until they take me so it's
purgatory of sorts I get my a number I'm
also assigned by deportation officer I
will fill out my temporary passport
information I have my photo taken I'll
fill out my forms and my deportation
officer fills in his bar and afterwards
it's on to the Canadian Consul in Dallas
Texas a fellow by the name of - a fellow
by the name of David Martinez once I am
at LaSalle Jody will post that phone
number here which she can't do because
he of course didn't make it there all
the communication between LaSalle and
the Canadian Consul in Dallas who
liaisons to his boss and Ottawa is done
electronically so that ought to be done
quickly that is within days but I'm
certain that precipitous actors in
Ottawa could choose to be deliberately
slow lazy or obstructive simply because
it's me and the Harper government is
hardly eager to have me back in Canada
that is where many supporters can
influence events should this procedure
get unduly tardy they need all of you to
call one of those three locations or all
three locations for several several
hours a day
urging an end to any questionable delays
if they should happen but we will see
just be ready to help if you are so
inclined what's the government paperwork
is completed and my temporary passport
is done the hi NS people at LaSalle
merely need to book my flight then take
me to Alexandria Louisiana and fly me to
Detroit Michigan and escort me over the
border point into Windsor Ontario
however many US and prison Canadians
have waited weeks for their flights to
be booked because the prisons make more
money the longer we are there but then
again let us be optimistic and hope that
big can hope that a big campaign to urge
my speedy return will prove to be
unnecessary this is getting a little
long there's only a little bit more guys
thanks for paying attention this is Mark
Henry we're talking about so it's worth
listening to this facility we don't get
outside much but I can buy items from
the commissary daily I can't take
anything with me
he's just talked about the place he
thinks he's going to which I won't even
read it because he didn't get to go
there if you want to send me anything
tell me get comfortable comfortable upon
my arrival and during my hopefully short
stay you can use your credit card to
send me $20 or $30 to help pay for my
phone calls and I'll thank you all and
buy food and clothes refer to my a
number refer my name and a number when
he gets jodeo posted she's done that
we've read that part I believe all US
credit cards will work but I hope the
Canadian credit cards will be okay too
because that's all Joey has this guy's
he's out of prison and he's still locked
up and still in prison which sucks the
prison he was in was much better than
where they're putting it down for this
temporary time so he's got a [ __ ]
deal with that [ __ ]
after he's supposed to be up he says
when I'm finally placed on the plane to
Alexandria Louisiana and flown to
Detroit oh yeah me [ __ ] I'm trying to go
fast I will be met by two US Marshals
and then driven through a tunnel to
Windsor Ontario Canadian customs and
immigration office I hope I will have
enough advance notice to call Jody and
have her fly standby to Toronto from
Vancouver didn't get to Windsor to be
there waiting for me and if you live in
the Windsor area I hope to see you there
also so he's inviting you Canadians out
if you're in Windsor and when Mark gets
out and you're in the Windsor area he
hopes to see you there so follow Jody on
Twitter us twitter.com slash jodie emery
for regular updates because that's where
she posts most of the stuff online we
will have an impromptu gathering
somewhere windsor after my arrival and
within 12 hours i will take the train or
some transport to toronto where we will
have another party at vapor central then
I won't give a talk the following
evening there two other venues for
meeting people will surely be planned
and announced but everything will be
done short notice so stay tuned for news
alerts
he keeps going he keeps going he says I
want to close this final prison blog
with a sincere thank you to our
supporters which is myself and you guys
who have been listening to the show who
helped in so many ways during these long
years of my incarceration Jody and I
appreciate everything you've done for us
both and the movement in large in my
absence I can't wait to get home and
thank you all in person in the weeks and
months ahead and resume the unfinished
battle to finish off marijuana
prohibition with renewed vigor I hope
you'll be there with me so this dudes
getting out of prison he's been in
prison for five years how many days did
we say that's up at the top that was one
thousand five hundred and ninety days
plus whatever time and we're gonna add
another thirty or so days on to that
right so students been in there for
1,600 days and he wants to get out and
get back on the [ __ ] streets and
start battling for cannabis again that's
a die hard [ __ ] right there here
is he gonna be drug tested because he
said he's headed to vapor central or the
vapor lounge is he gonna be able to puff
is he gonna be able to dab Oh madam ajan
being in prison for six years and taking
a DAB at a rock your world Marc Emery is
gonna be high so let's give a big shout
out to mark Emery wish him the best if
you can afford to send him something
with your credit card please do so get
up on Jodie's Jodi Ann Marie's Twitter
if you can't send it money you can send
him a letter I will tweet the address I
wrote down a note to do that so support
marc emery he's done a lot for you even
if you don't know it if you're a pot
smoker if you're a pot girl or if you're
a pot supporter marc emery is part of
your team you should be helping him out
now it's our turn to return the favor
you know I've done a 50-minute episode
let's let's wrap up the news I'm going
to take a DAB you know I usually turn
off the recording to take a dad let's
just keep it dawn I'm gonna take a sip
right here we're gonna dab what are we
gonna hit I've got some lemon Jeffrey
dabs
oh yeah nobody knows I've got the lemon
Jeffrey dad that's my secret stash so
I'll bust off a little lemon Jeffrey dab
I'm using my highly educated carb cap
oh yeah bust off a nice chunky dab here
what's rigged we want to hit I want to
hit the I'm gonna use the air across 4.0
prototype with the highly educated
duality nail domeless so take a dab with
me guys if you guys got some dabs or
something dude if you got some live
resin smoke that [ __ ] oh I don't wanna
stay addicted because I'm not addicted
to it but I don't even have any of it I
love some live resin that's the new [ __ ]
right there if you're not smoking live
resin if you haven't tried that yeah you
gotta try some of that you gotta find
one of the other guys in crowd get you
some live resin shot at the Spence he
died me out with that live resin on 710
and that stuff was delicious so I'm just
talking while I'm heating up the nail
that's it's getting hot it's going it's
gonna do a dab with me guys we're gonna
cop a little bit to it did I mention
tree hugger calm this episode is brought
to you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews guess what it's WWWE
thugger calm go check them out shout out
to Ryan what's up buddy thanks for
helping to support the show it's a good
sponsor right there like I said alley
sponsor I only have sponsors that I
trust and respect here we go dude AB
with me guys
yeah that's what I like big fat dad's
all right so it's about time to end up
the show I'm trying up to coffin your
face a whole bunch let's get a big shout
out to everybody that made the 7:10 cup
fun
shout out to Kevin for saving me a spy
hey Adam what's up bro shout-out to you
both Adams I've got two friends named
Adam and both you were going older if
you win if you met me I mean both of you
on the south side what's up guys so the
next episode I'm gonna put together a
really nice veg growth episode we'll
talk a lot about the vegetative stage of
growth we'll talk about how to feed your
plants and veg we'll talk about the last
gruel lesson we had cloves and cups and
seedlings in cups so we're gonna talk
about how to get those little babies
into your finished pots your Forever pot
that they're gonna finish in talk about
how you can root it and healthy in there
we'll have Jesse back in one or two
episodes he's getting married so he may
be hard to get on the show for a couple
of weeks so shout out to Jesse for
getting married congratulations my
friend
congratulations burn she's an awesome
lady I met her a couple times show's
over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for hydro culture find the
review section give us a five star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future show
don't forget to the show is available on
iTunes stitcher swell a.m. and every
single episode all the way from the
beginning is available on I read
genetics Colorado com
you know check out I read genetics
Colorado calm anyway just for fun
also follow I read genetics Colorado or
it's just I read genetics on Instagram
check that out there's a lot of great
cannabis photography on there
shout out to Nancy bud well for her
contest winning photo make sure you
follow the show and I grow culture on
Instagram and Twitter also the Facebook
page also if you want to send anything
longer than 140 characters feel free to
hit us up at agriculture at hotmail.com
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening make sure you tune
in next time
take fat dad give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
number 20 of the Hydra culture podcast
I'm your host Rasta Jeff thank you for
joining me for another dabbed out
episode this episode is brought to you
by nature's green remedies dot-com visit
nature's green remedies calm for caged
green genetics La Plata labs Sin City
rare dankness mile high can adventure I
regen etics and many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners
clicking over their website right now to
get the specifics on that because they
just updated it for us right now buy any
five packs of ira genetics get a free
two pack of dub wise buy any ten packs
of ira genetics get a free five pack of
dub wise is also running another special
for you guys type in coupon code podcast
for 15% off any order and you always get
free shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com oh my gosh a delicious thanks to
a garden of Weeden for blasting that for
me
oil slick oil tools to help you
concentrate check out oil slick pad comm
for more information make sure you
follow oil slick on twitter find them
under at oil slick pad cinema tweet tell
them you're listening to the agriculture
podcast and also need to give big love
to tree thugger calm this episode is
brought to you in part by tree hugger
comm live music lifestyle magazine go
check out tree hugger calm for concert
and festival news and reviews WWWE
thicker calm much love do all the
sponsors for making the show possible
company give a big huge shout out to
Brad wines for leaving a comment on the
stitcher channel sorry I'm coughing from
a DAB it's got me all choked up Brad
your comment has me choked up bro
I met Brad at a dab festival at the
right Event Center who see that 710
covered the secret cop or one of those
he's a photographer he takes great
photos
my current Twitter picture was actually
taken by Brad so thanks for taking good
pictures dude thanks for being a good
member of the community he comes all the
way from New Mexico to Denver to all of
the dab parties and the cannabis events
so that is [ __ ] cool of you thanks a
lot man I appreciate that if you guys
leave comments on iTunes or stitcher I
will read it on the show I also find all
the comments on Facebook and Twitter you
guys don't want to leave your name in a
comment if you want to email that to me
on Facebook we do that I've been putting
out these fliers for culture podcast my
friend Adam puts a malformation Adam
takes a lot bro he puts these little
flyers there this just the sciences
quarter sheet of paper says listen to
buy agriculture podcast for free grow
lessons in cannabis news something funny
that happened we did that episode at the
hookah bar and I left a few of those
there on the table and the police have
been going to that hookah bar randomly
trying to bust people smoking weed there
it's not happening but the only thing
they found are these flyers on that
flyer it's just a flyer to get you some
free weed that's really funny again from
a good friend Ricardo Baca the headline
is edibles recall at home bakes use of
washing machine for hash question it
says a popular denver-based brand of
marijuana infused edibles was recalled
by Denver Department of Environmental
Health on July 17th because of the
possible contamination from unsanitary
equipment and use of equipment not
intended for food manufacturing
according to the department's Public
Health inspections of division the
manufacturer of the recalled edibles at
home-baked operates on the same state
marijuana licenses dispensary group
advanced medical alternatives we're
really frustrated with the entire
situation said AJ hash car AJ he's also
known to me as AJ hashman that's what I
would always call him so I said I saw a
sh card I just said hash car because it
seemed like it worked they came in and
the machine which we were utilizing to
make water hash was not food not a food
safe machine food safe machines to make
water hash do not exist they deemed the
water hash that we were making unfit for
human consumption even though nobody has
gotten sick from our hash the Department
of Environmental Health verified that
there haven't been any reports of
illness yet but a food safety inspection
was the reason for the recall ash car
has been using a modified washing
machine to activate his water hash a
common practice in this industry to get
the centrifugal action that is essential
to the water hash that Ashgar also known
for his popular marijuana
meet-and-greets in Denver Colorado some
great parties he hasn't been able to do
them anymore because the Denver Police
have actually been shutting those
parties down because we're smoking
cannabis and not drinking alcohol anyway
the article says my business partner and
I both have culinary backgrounds food
service backgrounds and we look at water
hash as a concentrate not a food ash car
said but they say as soon as you start
working with it with the food has the
intent or the end result it is food
which I kind of agree with that you know
it's got to be food we're going to keep
that hash that's the active ingredient
that we're searching for so it's got to
be clean it's gonna be food great in
June ash card received a variance from
the state through September to find a
food safe alternative and he purchased a
bubble magic machine he hopes will
satisfy their regulations in the
meantime the state demanded that he
recall all products made in his old
washing machine at home baked products
were recalled on July 17 Z read that
sense for you the at-home baked products
that were recalled on July 17th include
its infused brownie mixes blondie mixes
rice krispie treats and sticks candy he
continues to say please pull our
products off your shelf in place in the
backroom and contact me to replace them
published on its Facebook on July 16th
so sorry for the inconvenience we look
forward to restocking you ASAP once we
have more info and a time frame at
Homebake swar place all products in
question or refund purchases ash Carter
said any of the above at Homebake
products should be removed from the
retail shelves and destroyed immediately
pursuant pursuant to state medical and
retail marijuana regulations but what
does this mean for at-home bakes
business it's an extremely difficult
blow Ashgar said it'll be difficult to
keep our head above they were talking
about if you go to an event in Colorado
Ajay's got a booth there they're giving
out sticks they're giving out free
samples he's done a lot for us so when
he does get his products back on the
shelf somebody one of the dispensaries
needs to send them over to steep hill
halen labs get them tested get the
profile printed out post that online
show buddies going on and then we should
all go buy those if it's a good product
again and we should support AJ to help
him get back on his feet this is a big
blow for a small company like what AJ's
got going on
I want to make the news real quick
there's only one news article this week
because I want to get to the grow lesson
I've got quite a bit of information that
I want to try to cram into just a little
bit of time here before we do that I
need to shout out this portion of the
podcast the grow lesson is brought to
you by hydro indoor growing supplies
hydro indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F were stopped by the new Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out WWE trading for calm
for current store hours and special
sales go check out the new location of
Pueblo don't Rasta Jeff sent you they'd
like to know that I'm sending people
advertising dollars are going the right
direction alright let's get down to a
grow lesson a few weeks ago we cut some
clones we germinated seeds and then we
put those seedlings and clones into cups
to let them develop roots so it's
probably the time schedule I've been on
it's probably past time to get those
into pots and start the vegetative phase
I apologize a little behind schedule
have had a lot of podcasting to try to
cram in anyway let's talk about the size
pots we're gonna use I like to go
straight into the pots that I'm going to
finish in like the pan what I transplant
into now from the cups is going to be
our finished pots we were in cups we're
gonna go into pots using your pot size
is important is an important thing to
consider I like to run my test plants in
three gallon pots and my big plants in
seven gallon pots some of you guys like
to go even bigger but for an indoor crop
you think of seven gallon pot is plenty
large enough if you're going outside you
can go it's 50 to 100 I've seen 250
gallon pots outside earth pots but
treacle on that baby shoot is going to
the ground I think anyway I think I'm
rambling three or five gallon pots are
great for vegging plants for a few weeks
and then flowering I don't like to let
them veg in three gallop aughts for
longer than like 45 days or so well
Sublette start to get too big for that
they'll get a little bit root bound
so if you want to vet your plants for
more time to get a bigger plant to
bigger buds usually larger pots if I
want to run a fast crop I run about 16 3
gallon pots under a thousand watt light
these are usually from seed if I'm
running like a little tester crop is
what I do that for if I'm running a
production crop I'll put between 4 &amp; 6 7
gallon pots under a thousand watt light
depending on the strain if they get
taller and thinner I'll put six of them
if they're like bushier plants like I'll
say dog I only put four lemon Jeffrey
I'll put six just gets taller than it
does wide so I'll put six of them under
there and pull a pretty nice harvest
about a pound and a half from 6 lemon
Jeffrey plants in seven gallon pots
under a thousand watt light of course
[Music]
from four of them but I have to let it
veg just a little bit longer maybe like
two weeks more and then just that's the
difference in the pot size and the veg
times and how many pots that's where you
start doing that kind of done correctly
the smaller plants take less time to veg
but I like the production from a gallon
they just seem to take off the they grow
larger and flower in their growth phase
in flower limited by plant counts so a
few larger pots is better for the
medical growers if you have a small grow
space of course use smaller pots if you
have room for larger pots go for the
larger pots you can experiment and see
what and why and how it all works best
for your needs and your environment how
much herb you need how often you need it
what strains you're gonna grow those are
all things that are gonna kind of decide
this stuff for you excuse my dad cough I
record a podcast animals here watching
me record he's like dude how do you even
record with that many dad's going on I
recorded some stuff with him I'll make
another episode out of that we got a
little out of hand and just started
rambling so anyway I'm doing that again
once you've chosen your pot size it's
time for a good soil I like a nice
fluffy soil
to perlite in it I had plenty of
amendments so I buy a fairly inert soil
if you have access to a good drawer
supply store than I recommend starting
with something like roots organic
centrally mixed number four something
similar to that these are all create
starters I use a recycled and amended
soil mix that can get a little complex
and it can make it hard to diagnose
problems if one comes up so I recommend
learning with the basic soil and organic
bottled nutrients unless you have
experience with farming horticulture
education once you understand the basics
of the plants we can make a super soil
mix and work on eliminating the bottle
feeds but for now let's keep it simple
and develop a good understanding of
these plants that's where we want to
start so you've got some you got some
pots we've got some small plants that
are in cups let's get those babies into
the big girl pots and then we'll talk
about feeding for the vegetation phase
babies and cups is really gonna help out
make it easy to transplant I fill my
pots with soil and I pack it in there
slightly tight I just press it down with
my hands and I don't pack it so tightly
that the roots can't dig through but I
do want to pack it tightly enough to
where the plants gonna have plenty of
support once I bury that roof all in
there if the soil is packed too lightly
you'll know because as soon as you water
the water's gonna run right through the
dirt and the soil is gonna cave in and
then you'll have to refill in there but
anyway fill your pots about two inches
from the top or more for bigger pots we
want to save some space for watering a
seven gallon pot will take a gallon of
water or more and that needs some space
in your pot and a three gallon pot
you'll easily take half a gallon up to a
gallon so save yourself some space so I
get the pot mostly full and I dig out
fed a large handful of soil out of the
center of the pot I set the clone in the
cup it's still in the plastic cup right
now for a minute I set that cup in the
spot where the clone is gonna go and I
backfill the dirt around the cup this
makes a perfect little spot for the
clone to fill without disturbing the
roots I do not leave the cup on the
clone only for that one second while I
was making an indention I don't leave
the cup I only uh I only use it to make
a little space with the clone once I've
got the perfect little space in there
mean for my clone
pull that cup out what's a clone in it
and then I hold the cup upside down with
my hand on top of the cup with the clone
coming out like between my middle and
ring finger when I flip the cup upside
down give it a little squeeze and then
usually just squeeze it and shake it
until the clone slides out of the cup
try not to disturb the roots and that
soil ball that come right out if they're
just shaking it'll come out that little
ball perfectly into that perfect little
spot that we just made it should be the
same shape as the cup since you just
make it so just set it right down in
there when the cup comes off falling out
[Music]
just stay calm you could drop dirt and
[ __ ] just don't drop the plant just
focus on getting that tiny little root
ball into that hole that we just made
and everything should be just fine
so now you've taken a cup you flipped it
upside down then little baby plants
falling out you got a handful of dirt
you're holding your new [ __ ] life
right there in your hand right in there
and now the whole plant I just put the
new freshly planted plant and you just
kind of camouflage the upright and
carefully
label your newly potted plant label
that's not labeled if the couple is well
labeled comes off the cuff' is still in
there sometimes that helps I'd sometimes
I just use the cup but once in a while I
knock the cup out and they get confused
so that sucks and I keep working until
all of my new babies are in pots once
everything is potted is what I'll feed
them and make sure to get the pots
thoroughly wet so you've got a crop a
freshly transplanted planted babies
under the lights and now that's pretty
much the beginning of the vegetative
growth phase it's time to mix up some
nutrients and feed them
first full veg nutrients I'm soil grower
so I pretty much focus on a dirt garden
if you're running a hydro garden we're
gonna hydro guy on the show here in the
future and have him teach you guys some
stuff I recommend mixing your nutrients
in a five-gallon bucket using accurate
measuring device for your nutrients on
it for small applications for larger
stuff there's a pint glass that is
marked with milliliters and a few other
measurements you can find those at your
local hydro shop I found a half gallon
pitcher that fits perfectly into my five
gallon bucket I've learned to mix my
nutrients into that pitcher instead of
mixing my nutrients directly into a
five-gallon bucket you don't want to
pour out five gallons of water when you
mess up mixing your nutrient feed that's
a lot of water to pour down the drain so
fill your pitcher 3/4 of the way with
water add your nutrients of choice to
the pitcher nutrient ocula and some good
enzymes specifically I would use 50
milliliters of botanic air pure blend
pearl fetch soil formula is my base I
would use OGT or great white shark as my
mykos which is your inoculant and I
would use 15 milliliters of hydros I'm
as my enzymes so in my garden I would
add a little bit of liquid karma and a
few other supplements but they're not
required
I had sweet to feed my beneficials for
extra vitamins and amino acids and
vitamin B also required but I like to
spoil my plants after about a week the
next week I'll feed cal-mag and
potassium silicates and then I run most
of the botanic here botanic air pure
blend ProLiant when I run bottled
nutrients botanic air is not a sponsor
but I've been most satisfied with
botanic hair and organic hair more than
any other bottle feed that's that's just
my opinion
I ran to advance nutrients I've ran the
Aurora Seoul synthetics which produce
some super tasty products
I ran psycho which was probably not my
favorite I've ran a bunch of them I've
ran to the Fox farms basic stuff I've
done a lot of feats I've done something
I can't even remember them all anyway
you can find a pretty good pre-made
botanic hair feature on their website
I'll try to remember to post some of my
notes of the feeding programs feeding
programs for that somebody tweeted me to
remind me a hydro culture I've got this
paper here in front of me so hopefully
that'll remind me mix up your bottled
feeds in a small container of water but
don't ever mix your nutrients together
without plenty of water
don't pour like a shot glass the
measuring device don't pour the veg
stuff and then don't pour enzymes into
the same shot glass at the same time mix
those two water the followed stuff is
sold in separate bottles to prevent
bonding of specific elements so always
mix into water once your picture is
mixed put that into the five-gallon
bucket and fill it up the rest of the
way once the bucket is full you need to
adjust the pH of your feed solution
adjust your pH to 6.5 using pH down it's
unlikely that your pH is too low make
sure you calibrate your pH meters
frequently that's always a good idea so
you got a bucket full of nutrient
solution that has been pH adjusted to
6.5 we've got our freshly transplanted
babies under a light the next thing we
got to do is pour the feed into the
plants so oh I hope you've got a some
type of saucer or something to catch the
runoff on your plants also likes it your
plants and a saucer or a tray if you
don't have something like that sometimes
I used a I've got a Rubbermaid tray
that'll fit three three gallon pots in
there perfectly so I can just pour water
into the plants and then it'll drain
right into there if not you're gonna end
up with water on the floor so you need
something to catch the runoff that comes
out of your plants so I kind of use the
pitcher that I'm using to stir up the
solution before I go right to the plants
to try to mix up the water a little bit
to stir up the stuff it's always a good
idea stir everything thoroughly
sometimes if I'm using a big batch
sometimes I mix my nutrients into a much
larger batch I throw an air stone in
there to pump it up a little bit to
aerate it and then while
doing that I also use a big stick like
the kind that you'd use to support your
plants I used to stir the water up it
just seems to be effective I like
stirring it's a good idea a little bit
then simply pour about a third of the
gallon of water of the feed into each
plant if you're using larger pots you're
gonna need more you know pretty quickly
I feel like crumbles down in once we had
the water all the airspace is gonna get
pushed out its gonna move around you
have to adjust everything and refill any
pots that you need to fill with soil and
get the plants under good lights t5
lights are good for veg if you have
enough for them close to the plants
metal halides are also ideal for a fetch
growth you want to focus on getting
those pots full of roots right now so
the blue spectrum is kind of what we
want LEDs seem to be really good for veg
plants but I personally don't have any
experience with the LEDs but I have seen
some great photographs coming from an
LED garden shout-out to Nancy bud while
she's growing some Bounty Killer right
now and it looks amazing so try to keep
your veg area around a 72 to 77 degrees
if you're using co2 you can get it let
it get a little bit warmer maybe low 80s
during the light period during your dark
cycle try to keep them about the same
temp or norm or no more than 10 degrees
cooler than your daytime temperatures
try to keep your humidity around 40 to
55 percent if possible in Colorado it
gets hard to keep the rooms humid so
they get dry here honestly you'd rather
have it to drive into humid if you have
the option if you can't get it right
where you want it if your floors are
messed up and not the way you need them
to be if you can't correct it I
understand you're grown in a house it's
not gonna be perfect you'd rather have
it to dry than to moist if you've got
the option so also remember to keep your
air fresh you don't want stale stuffy
air in your Dro rooms your plants need
plenty of co2 and they deplete the co2
in a room very quickly
having stale air in a grow room can lead
to powdery mildew and it slows down the
growth of your plants quite quickly so I
keep my vision plants under 24 hours of
light I think they grow more quickly
under 24 hours of light than they do
what the dark cycle during veg
most books will tell you to run a
16-hour day period and an eight-hour
dark period I think it's great because
it's how nature works and you can't
argue with that I've experimented with
both sometimes if I'm earning a seed
crop I will run a 16-hour light cycle
and then go to a 1212 cycle sometimes I
will run an 1113 cycle which is odd but
we'll talk about that later on to learn
that from DJ short so that 16/8 life
cycle is great like I said nature works
it also lets your equipment cool down
and take a little bit of a break and it
lets your electricity bill chill out for
a second let's your meter quit spinning
so as long as your veggie
plants are under 16 hours of light every
day they should be happy you can
experiment with it I'll do another show
with more info on light cycles before a
photo period later on one thing I've
really noticed is that when I flip my
plants to 1212 to flower from this 24
hour light cycle they show flower faster
than the plants that had a dark cycle
during veg that's just one thing I've
noticed so if you're really looking for
a production crop that's something to
keep in mind since I just remembered
that that's kind of what inspired that
for me I think I might switch back I
also like to keep my mother plants under
twelve twelve just to keep them from
even thinking that they may have the
chance to flower once they get rebounded
stuff they sometimes some of your mother
plants may try to OTO flower on you so
we've got our babies and new pots and we
fed them under good lights I put a fan
lightly blowing over the canopy to keep
the air circulating and if the temps and
humidity or humidity are correct in the
room the plants won't need water for
three or four days if you watered them
enough right now so this is a good time
to start thinking about pest management
if you have neem oil on hand give each
plant a good spray when the lights turn
off you don't want to spray them when
the lights are on that creates what I
call it over reflector bubbles from the
you know the bubbles plant on your plant
the light hits it just like a magnifying
glass did when you were a little kid and
used to cook ants it'll happen to your
plants the grow light will work as the
Sun and the bubble will work like a
magnifying glass
and you get a little burn mark a little
white spot so spray when the lights are
off always try to spray when the lights
are off
yeah if that's any book will tell you
that knee will keep most of your passed
away once you're in Flour you'll need to
rethink the knee because you do not want
a spray meme on your flowering plants
don't do that it'll taste terrible
if you make concentrates with neem
sprayed plants excuse me if you make
concentrates with neem sprayed plants
you can definitely taste the neem so
once you're in flower stop spraying me
I've got a new product I'm testing out
if it works for me I'm definitely gonna
share it with you it's it's all organic
it was recommended to me by somebody in
the horticultural industry not the
cannabis industry so it's used for food
crops so it's completely safe I didn't
smell bad when I used it I'm kind of
testing it out now I'll let you know
what I think so you're now officially in
the fed phase I feed bottle nutrients if
I'm using bottled nutrients I only feed
them once per week with plain pH water
throughout the rest of the week so I
personally feed all my plants on Monday
so if you guys are listening to this on
Monday I'm probably waiting for the
lights to come on the flower room comes
on at 10:00 so click on I will actually
have my nutrients mixed up already these
plants are mixing up through week five
stuff get the pH adjusted in there and
then I'll throw some air stones in there
and let that stuff just bubble around
and let the nutrients mean go for a
little while and as soon as lights come
on I'll go in there and feed them so
I'll need water again usually by
Thursday
once again heavier into flour it may
step up to Wednesday they won't go as
long so you can let your plants get
that's something you got to keep in mind
to think about how tall your plants can
get think about if you want to top them
or let them grow naturally because your
plants some sativa plants can double it
in size during flower like if you're
good on the Bounty Killer that thing is
going to double in size during your
flower period so it's time to think
about how tall and wide your plants can
get before you need to flower them out
because that is going to be the next
major phase of your plants get a little
veg probably got another month to forty
five maybe two months if you want to go
crazy but I recommend about 30 days veg
time from here out so don't get any bugs
burn with nutrients take good care of
them that's super important I think that
gets us basically started through the
veg phase I plan to go in-depth with
each of these little topics in the
future we'll make little branches from
everything that I've mentioned I want to
get everybody up to speed with the
basics before we go too deeply into
specific stuff about growing I've got
tons of information to share with you
guys if you want more details on
anything I mentioned please just ask me
because I would love to help you out I'd
love to elaborate tweet me agriculture
Facebook me and agriculture on Facebook
or send me an email it's agriculture at
hotmail.com I feel like I say that all
the time I will answer almost anything
you ask I love to just interact with my
social media people it's fun so I feel
like that was a lot of talking I'm gonna
freshen up my throat here probably take
a DAB I'm gonna be right back and we
will see what else we got for this show
hang tight guys I'm gonna show up right
there you tend to listen to more of the
show if I put out a 30 minute episode it
gets a better response so now that the
show's over please go to iTunes go to
the iTunes Store search Fri grow culture
find the review section give me a five
star rating after that type in a little
comment let me know what you think of
the podcast and I will read your
comments on the show I love the
interaction don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes
stitchers weld-on a.m. and also every
episode is available on I region etics
Colorado com
so if you want to go back and listen to
old episodes that aren't available on
iTunes or stitcher all you gotta do is
go to www.sceeto.com and you can click
on the podcast tab right there and every
episode should be available big shout
out Swindon just spins big thanks to
Adam Adam came and hung out with me for
a little while and watch me record part
of the show big shout out to everybody
that helped me out this week with a few
things I needed it's been a busy week so
thanks for all the help in the area
genetics family I'll be back in seven
days with the brand-new episode for you
probably have more grow lessons for you
and I Jessie is getting married so he
won't be back for a couple of weeks to
do an episode
but he will be back so you guys keep
tweeting me and asking me where's Jesse
he's planning a wedding we got to give
him some time and some space he belongs
to his wife now he's not ours anymore
shout out to Jesse congratulations on
the wedding that's not for another week
but it's coming up and we're proud for
you I need to give a huge shout out to
DJ nicotine music you heard at the
beginning of the show was DJ nicotine
the song that I'm about to play right
here to end of the show will also be DJ
diggity so thanks for letting me play
your music need to give a big shout-out
to my ninja Spence does the end of
episode number 20 thanks again felicity
[Music]
all right podcast world that was episode
17 18 19 and 20 of what used to be the
iGrow culture podcast now known as The
Grove from your heart podcast I hope you
guys enjoyed it please tweet me email me
let me know what you think of these old
episodes I would love to hear your
opinions you can find me on Twitter at
JFK I'd cast or you can send me an email
it's girl from yarn at a hotmail.com
please let me know what you think ladies
and gentlemen this pile is long enough I
will see in a few days with another
podcast until then take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you