[Music]
and what's up podcast will defrost the
Jeff it's time for episode number 195 of
the girlfriend of our podcast doing that
thing where I throw old episodes this
time I'm putting out episodes 21 22 23
and 24 of what used to be known as the
agriculture podcast currently called
it's the girl from your heart podcast
ladies and gentlemen before we get to
the old episodes let me make a couple of
quick updates and disclaimers the new
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you'd like to contact me
that is probably the best way to do it
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you I'd love to
answer all of your questions but you got
to send them to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you
they're also the twitter feed is now @gf
wih podcast if you'd like to follow us
on Twitter I would love that
also if you want to find us on Facebook
simply search for the grow from your
heart podcast also I've recorded a
hundred and ninety five episodes a lot
of my opinions ideas and techniques and
methods may have changed I may have said
some things in the past that I don't
agree with now I may have taught in
method that I don't use anymore please
don't hold anything against me please
keep in mind that this is an
ever-evolving project and I will try to
keep you updated the best I can so some
of the old information may be outdated
that's why I do a podcast that's why I
didn't write a book because I can keep
new info coming so ladies and gentlemen
without any more rambling without any
further ado here are episodes 21 22 23
and 24 of what used to be known as the
agriculture podcast now known as to grow
from your heart podcast thanks for
listening everybody
[Music]
this episode was brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics lot of labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can adventure
hydrogen etics and many more trusted
brands coupon code podcast for 15% off
any order and you always get free
shipping and you can see metics products
sell quite quickly tools to help you
concentrate for more information make
sure you follow oil slick on twitter
[Music]
tweet till then you're listening to the
agriculture podcast song in it and it
got real quiet that was awkward stops
and all they can hear is you yelling
you're always saying a really stupid
word at that time so at nachos in my
butt or something like that
yeah well slick shout out to those guys
between listening to the show big shout
out to our friends at Treehugger calm
this episode is brought to you in part
by Treehugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews
and also this show is brought to you by
hydro indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
or stop by the new pablo location on 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check
out high grill for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor grill
supplies don't forget to check out WWE
grow denver calm for current store hours
and current store specials actually I've
got an extra added bonus for you hydro
has an awesome sale on roots organic
soil you can get one tote of soil for
five hundred and fifty dollars in-store
pickup or $600 delivered this deal is
available at both locations the Pueblo
and Denver's door please contact hydro
to verify delivery
availability delivery availability how
far those guys are willing to drive to
haul you either that tote of soil I'm
sure a lot of guys are saying how much
is a tote of soil Rasta Jeff it's a
really good question the answer is a
total soil is 54 cubic feet which is
about 350 gallons it's all in one bag
also so instead of buying a whole bunch
of bags you got one big bag friendly so
if you're running three gallon pots
that's a hundred and sixteen three
gallon pots if you run five gallon pots
that's 75 gallon pots if you run seven
gallon pots like I like to do that's
fifty seven gallon pots so that's not a
bad deal at all there hydro indoor
growing supplies let me read the address
to you one more time that is sixty to
seventy one beach street unit F or the
pueblo location that addresses in Denver
the Pueblo location is 618 East 4th
Street in Pueblo on the east side so go
check out high grow much respect to all
those sponsors they make the show
possible big shout out to you guys for
listening we've made it 21 episodes you
guys it's pretty awesome I've got a
couple of things I wrote down
to talked about where did I put the
paper Oh big shout out to natural mystic
cannabis caregivers in Colorado Springs
I was running low on chatter mmm
natural mystic cannabis caregivers came
to the rescue I got some delicious and
reaching for the container right now I'm
also recording this podcast in video I
don't know if I will do anything with
the video but I haven't actually
recording it so this is guava sky I'm
just showing the container for natural
mystic cannabis caregivers and this is
mystic is what it's called the mystic
has Tora Bora in there it's a high CBD
mix and the guava sky is the sativa that
they had available I got more of the
sativa than I did the CBD mix that's
just my preference also take a picture
with the video take a picture and post
this up online but I'm not focused so
huge shout out to natural mystic
cannabis caregivers in Colorado Springs
what's up Julia what's up Shelly I hope
you guys listen it does require a red
card to get in there so if you do need
your medical marijuana that's the place
in Colorado Springs I would send you
right now they have your back cancer
survivor so she knows what you're
dealing with if you're sick she
definitely knows how to help she's
compassionate she's friendly Joe he's
hard to find he's the he's the boss
there so he's always busy working but
Joe he's a great dude he's super
friendly they'll shake your hand in a
minute with you if he is in the shop so
those guys got much love for you today
is as I'm recording it's 4:20 in the
morning on July 23rd so it is officially
the birthday of his Imperial Majesty
King Haile Selassie I'd the first so if
you know what that is who that is you
understand why I'm given thanks and
praise many thanks and praise many
birthday blessings to king Haile
Selassie I the first let's take a little
half a second of silence because it's a
podcast a moment of silence would be
ridiculous so here's a half a second of
silence for king selassie i the first
all right gotta keep moving much respect
I am sad to inform you I'm gonna turn
the music way down for this one also I'm
sad to inform you we had an event
scheduled for July 27th at the Brickyard
I've been talking about it quite a bit
we're trying to get that hookah bar
turned into a dad bar unfortunately it's
not going to happen the event is
canceled and that place is not going to
get to be turned into a smoking
establishment I apologize for
advertising an event that didn't happen
the city is against us every step of the
way they do not want us to get this
place open they do not want us to have
our event I planned on taking live
plants to the event so that we could do
a little bit of Education and I could
show a male plant a female plant I had
plants in different stages of flower for
this event but we can't teach plants the
city would confiscate the plants we
can't risk taking plants and getting
them taken I just can't do that to
myself that's medicine for my patients
on the caregiver and they're gonna need
that medicine so I can't do that so
unfortunately the event that I had
planned that I had talked about for July
27th at the Brickyard is canceled we
couldn't come to an agreement with the
city they do not want us to do the event
I don't want anybody to get in trouble I
don't want my plants to get taken so we
have we have backed out of the event I
do apologize for that
the other day I said something on the
show I don't remember if I said it on
the show were just in conversation with
people but I need to correct something
that I said I'm going to go to a website
here this is actually from edy
Rosenthal's I've just got her to my
computer it's easier to do while we're
doing a show and Rosenthal's marijuana
growers handbook I'm trying to show it
to the camera I'm not watching the video
I should put the video up on the screen
so I could see the video feed here we go
this is the book that I'm coming from so
I said something about red spectrum
right and I may have gotten it backwards
for what I told you guys so this is from
the book I just showed you all credit
for what I'm saying right now it goes to
Ed Rosenthal and don't get mad at me for
saying this on the show you'd want
people to know this that's called the
critical light period let me give you a
quick explanation of what the critical
light period is in my opinion the
critical period is the amount of dark
time specific cannabis stream will take
to flower so let me elaborate with Ed's
article here this 12 formula has been
accepted without question by growers all
over the world probably probably one of
the reasons for this was my discussion
of the technique in some of my early
books the 1212 regimen was selected
because my co-author and I reasoned that
no matter what critical period of
variety might have given 12 hours of
darkness
it would flower however most marijuana
varieties need fewer than 12 hours of
darkness to flower now what I was
talking about was somebody was they were
saying that their plants are starting to
flower and it's not 12 hours of darkness
outside yes that's because of the sunset
and the sunrise have specific color
spectrums that are triggering hormones
in your plants is what I was telling
them all this info from memory so I
think I got it backwards to tell you the
truth so if I said that on a podcast or
if I said that to you in person
I need to correct that here's what Ed
Rosenthal has written a little bit more
about it if marijuana plants grow
outdoors required a 12 hour dark period
to flower they would
be induced to start flowering until
September 21st the first day of autumn
when day and night are equal lengths
they would ripen six to eight weeks
later in real life most modern varieties
ripen between early September and late
October budding was triggered sixty
weeks earlier Friz instance an eight
week variety that requires 55 days from
forcing to maturity which would normally
ripen October first would start
flowering August first at that date in
San Francisco sunrise occurs at 5:14 and
sunset at 9:18 which is 718 a total of
14 hours and 4 minutes
dawn and dusk add another 15 minutes of
red light plants used the absence of
this spectrum to measure the dark period
the total lit period came to about 14
hours and 20 minutes leaving nine hours
and 40 minutes of darkness the critical
period for this plant was 9 hours and 40
minutes if you were given just 10 hours
of dark period daily indoors rather than
12 it would still flower gardeners
growing indoors who discover the
critical time need to induce flowering
the critical time needed to induce
flowering can use this information to
get more efficient use of their indoor
garden currently plants grown under a
1212 cycle spend half their time in the
dark if these plants have a critical
flowering time of for instance 10 hours
of darkness daily they can provide be
provided 14 rather than 12 hours of
light each day so that they can receive
almost 17% more energy which they use to
produce sugars used for more and faster
growth
so does that make any sense guys it's
the it's uh called the critical period
for the specific strain most of your
you're like strains your indica stuff
that's gonna have a critical period
apparently closer to that's gonna have
like your 12-hour stuff you're more
equatorial stuff you may be able to cut
that down just a little bit actually I
heard DJ short say that he runs most of
his plants on a 13 off 11 on and he said
that that shows a little bit more
phenotypic expression is what that does
which means that if you're growing from
seed and you're trying to find that
keeper you'll get to see larger
variances in your seed stock if you've
got a little f1 hybrid there
I had another article I gotta click back
a couple of steps here maybe I've lost
it a lot of stuff about me here it is
sorry looking for stuff on the internet
I'm talking this guy broke something
down there are things cannabis plants
where's this coming from let me give
credit this is from marijuana growers
hq.com
slash light cycles and flowering
cannabis cannabis plants are referred to
as long night or short a plants because
they require a long period of Darkness
to trigger the hormone that tell the
plant to switch from vegetative growth
to flowering these light receptors are a
color pigment in the leaves called
phytochrome red and phytochrome far red
and they're gonna start abbreviating
that so i need to try to remember which
is which these pigments get their names
from the types of light they absorb
phytochrome red absorbs red light
between 600 and 760 it doesn't give me a
definition of what those are and
phytochrome far red absorbs far light
between 760 and 800 Nm I don't remember
what M is and that's I should sorry I
went blank on that one just now when
they wrote it on the screen these two
pigments chemically react to the light
and trigger the plant to flower or not
this is where it gets a little confusing
in cannabis plants the normal presence
of phytochrome far red switches off the
flowering signal the level of
phytochrome far red is what you can
manipulate to adjust the photo period
phytochrome far red is quickly produced
when plants are exposed to light that
contains far red wavelengths when there
is light the phytochrome far red and
phytochrome red maintain a balance when
the sun goes down or the lights go out
the darkness gradually switches the
phytochrome far red to phytochrome red
because of this the phytochrome red
levels gradually increase and the far
red gradually decreases during the dark
period the presence of red is neutral is
a neutral condition to the plants and
essentially tells them nothing when the
light returns or if a small amount of
far red light interrupts a dark period
the red immediately switches back to far
red if the plant is without light long
enough the far red will decrease past a
tipping point
this decreased level of phytochrome far
red signals the plants that fall is
approaching and the plants begin
flowering ensure the presence of
phytochrome far red due to long hours of
light and short hours of darkness keep
the plants in the vegetative phase if
the plant experiences enough hours of
darkness
most of the phytochrome far red turns to
phytochrome red and the low level of far
red signals the plant hormones to begin
flowering that's a really technical
version of what I tried to say the last
time I gave this a little rant and I
think I got it completely backwards to
tell you the honest truth so that goes
to show you right there that sometimes
you got to do your research you got to
remind yourself even if you think you
know what you're doing you might [ __ ] up
and say something wrong on a podcast and
try to embarrass yourself but you know I
don't feel embarrassed I'm glad that I
got to learn with you guys we're gonna
go find out what that one little
abbreviation that they wrote there I've
never seen it written like that before
I'm gonna find out what that means so I
can share that with you or was it
right they're gonna Google that and find
out what that means googling it right
now nm light measurement definition pops
up as soon as I start typing that
visible light is usually defined as
having a wavelength okay so that's that
is nanometers what I thought it was they
just wrote it small and capital M like
that so that's nanometers is what I
thought it was there and that that
article all right doing pretty good on
that one and tell Safari just decided to
freeze up there we go cool all right I
really just wanted to come on and talk
about having to cancel the committee for
the responsible regulation of cannabis
party that we were going to have at the
Brickyard I want to say that once again
in case you guys are skipping through
this episode the party the seminar the
educational seminar we planned to host
it has been cancelled I was gonna take
some live plant to show you guys those
we had people that we're gonna talk
about all kinds of cool stuff we had a
miniature job fair planned out does not
want that to happen so I apologize it's
beyond our control the police department
have threatened us and scared us and we
don't want police interaction so we're
gonna back out we're gonna foul down and
just not do that sorry it's the best we
can do right now for what we've got all
right enough begging for your
forgiveness I do apologize if you were
planning to come out message me and
we'll find something else to do how's
that so if you're listening on Twitter
or Facebook or whatever message me and
we will hang out since I had that night
booked because I thought I'd be doing
stuff anyway let's wrap up this episode
it was kind of a quick episode I want to
give another I want to mention that
coupon or both do it you can get
yourself a gigantic bag of roots organic
soil for five hundred and fifty bucks or
six hundred dollars honestly do 25 7
gallon pots or 57 gallon pots worth of
soil that's two runs in a four light
room in my opinion you know so if that
tells anything with what you could do
with that amount of soil
that is awesome big shout out to all of
our sponsors I want to give a shout out
to the Grammy gatsby the Grammy Gatsby
thanks for hooking us up good folks over
there check out the Grammy gatsby com
what's up much love much respect so
let's do that into the show wrap-up
thing oh I'm gonna try to get Jesse back
I was talking to Jesse he's getting
married and he actually texted me what
am I gonna be back on the show so I
promise he's coming back soon looking
back on the show do that outdoor to grow
lesson for you
big thanks to do that give thanks
portion but I've been cramming so much
stuff into one episode that I haven't
done it so officially give thanks to
king selassie I the first is my give
thanks on this episode I'm not gonna go
on about that if you know you know
that's all there is to that one check us
out on Instagram I read genetics is
where I post a lot of good photography
there that's anti read genetics the show
has an Instagram it's a tied real
culture of course we do a lot of Twitter
stuff and I grow culture there's a
facebook you can email me I grow culture
at hotmail.com what I really like is
iTunes comments and iTunes five star
ratings so here's what I wear I read the
part I typed now that the show's over
please go to iTunes go to the high tune
store search for Agriculture find the
review section give us a five star
rating after that type in a comment and
let me know what you think of the show
and I'll read your comments on the show
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher swell dot a.m. and also
I read genetics Colorado comm every
episode is archived on hyeri genetics
Colorado comm episodes 1 through 21
once again shout out to my ninja Spence
shout out to the whole garden of Weeden
family shout out to Adam Gaskins I made
him [ __ ] run around with me all day
we went to Colorado Springs had some
lunch he laughed at me for eating hippy
food it was a fun day Adams wife for
letting me borrow Adam all day thanks a
lot I appreciate that that was cool we
had fun today thanks for listening take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
open this edible that I'm trying to eat
a mountain medicine 350 milligrams
cannabis delightful chocolate peanut
butter bar Mountain medicine get your
goat on medical marijuana edible these
packages have to be childproof I got a
couple things to talk about nothing
super super planned out so I'm sitting
here watching him struggle with this
packaging
a pair of scissors probably 20 thanks
dude that reminds me part of our talk we
may talk if I even get into 350
milligrams welcome to episode number 22
of Agriculture podcast of course I'm
Rasta Geoff another episode we'll do
sponsors in just a second
Adam for coming big shout out to my
friend that helped me trim tonight if
you're listening to the podcast short
person with dreadlocks you hope that a
lot save me a lot of time we were using
a trim to open this package their
package compliant dude this company
there's an expiration date on here
there's a barcode inside of here Kevlar
fireproof bomb-proof plastic scissors to
get through this [ __ ] and they struggled
a little bit to get this open right
quick this podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit our
friends nature's green remedies calm for
Game three in genetics the plot of labs
Sin City rare dankness mile hike an
adventure I region etics and many many
more trusted brands those guys Ritz
Cannabis Cup this weekend I hope they
had fun I saw a whole bunch of rain I
hope you're safe calm if you buy the
changes are special often right now they
have a special running if you buy a
certain amount of ira genetics you will
get a certain amount for free i don't
remember exactly what the special is it
changes so frequently I'm not gonna
quote it on the show the code word we
gave out does expire the 31st of this
month it will put out a new one at the
next podcast the start of August so pay
attention for that we've got a really
special deal coming up for the podcast
listeners on episode number 25 so he
actually may have to listen to episodes
22 23 24 and 25 to put stuff together to
have an answer to kind of a puzzle and
if you have that answer to the puzzle
there will be prizes and special offers
for those so we'll keep listen to the
podcast one episode 25 comes up will let
you know what's going on and
it may work out for you I'm struggling
with this [ __ ] package I got it
mostly open and now I'm struggling with
not shoving it into my face in the
middle of a commercial I want to get
these done and then we'll go for it this
podcast also brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado is at the Denver store at
80 to 71 beach street unit F or stop by
the new publication on 618 East 4th
Street in Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection on indoor growing
supplies make sure you check out
www.paigeedraw.com for current store
hours and special sales also that
running a special I don't have the paper
in front of me it is five hundred and
fifty dollars for one tote of soil I
talked about this last week a tote of
soil that's if you pick it up at the
store it's five hundred and fifty
dollars it comes in one bag its roots
organic soil it's good [ __ ] how much is
a tote that is approximately in my
measurements I think that is about 28 or
up is about 48 to 57 gallon pots so you
can run an 8 light setup pretty decently
with this one package of soil if you
need it delivered it is $600 it comes on
a FedEx truck to your house so it's not
like the hydro shop has shown up with
the truck or anything it's actually
FedEx it looks like you got a package
that's [ __ ] huge that's gonna be a
lot of weight so hopefully they can haul
it right into your garden area or
something so check out our good friends
at Highgrove oh give a huge shout out to
Jesse and Bernadette they got married
this weekend Bern actually works at
Highgrove so that's what made me think
about it they got married it threw an
awesome party just want to give them a
quick shout out to congratulations at
the start of the show we're gonna talk a
little more about that in a few minutes
here congratulations was awesome
oil slick is next shoutout to oil slick
oil slicks a loyal sponsor they've been
a longtime sponsor I use an oil slick
product every day there's almost one in
every room of my house they take one of
the most used products in this house
carb caps dabbers oil slick pads and a
rig and a torch I need a torch sponsor
vector vector torches company because
this one's starting to lose its luster
you know company wants to sponsor us let
me know let's review your product and
we'll shout you out on the show all the
time
enough pandering oil slicks were friends
at oil slick oil slick tools to help you
concentrate check out oil slick pad comm
for more information dude go find our
friends oil slick on twitter seriously i
say that every time but go find them
they're an oil slick pad cinema tweet
and let them know that you're listening
with agriculture podcast let them know
you heard this ad and that my
advertising is effective let them know
that you're paying attention and that
it's working for him I know right now
you're probably in the garden it could
be driving in the car maybe you're on a
treadmill what do you do when you're
listening to the podcast just tweet us I
know I asked for a lot but that's all I
want is simple tweet come on man just
pay attention sponsor is because I use
their stuff because it's necessity it's
useful if you're dabbing you need some
oil slick products you need something to
keep your hash in if you're smoking the
live resin that we've got now you don't
want to carry it around in parchment
paper you want your live resin to be
kept in like a nice smooth looking oil
slick container my red gold and green
Rasta colored oily container on the
table with my oil slick pads it just
looks like they got these things here
with like the magnetic sides to where
you can just put your slab I'm gonna
have to look in google docs I'm not sure
if that's actually their product or if
somebody's making that modified version
because that's a good idea if you have a
miniature sized slab you can take two of
these oil slick mini pads pad minis and
you can rubber band them together with
your slab in the middle or you can find
other ways to stick them together and
just have your slab right in the middle
make it easily accessible there are
great things I actually use it almost as
a wipe my dabber off on it that's why
it's all sticky on this edge near me so
I take another tab wipe it
they're my next dad doesn't have residue
of my last dab on their everyday
business you know you have seen you use
them to set pipes down on just for I
usually try to have a good coaster
because the tables would and I think
it's just a little better than [ __ ]
dropping my glass onto the table have a
little underneath it right in my domes
for my donor eggs I know I don't there's
one dome Drake on the table now that the
dome sits on there because you leave I
made an ad that said stop leaving sticky
rings on your mom's table because
everybody's got those little rings you
can tell who's a dabber and who tries to
hide it yeah so that's a huge shout out
to our friends at oil slick and a huge
sponsor
I totally represent that [ __ ] all day
long so thanks guys thanks for
sponsoring us I also have to give one
more ad shout out to tree hugger com
episode is brought to you in part by
tree hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert festival news and reviews WWE
thugger calm somebody was like tree
hugger huh sounds like you doesn't
wreaths ugh bro this is the revolution
this is the revolution I just got seven
Facebook messages in a row I guess the
Internet's back the internet is back on
yeah we might be able to read some news
since the Internet's back I wasn't able
to research much news because the
internet was tricking but so we got the
ads out of the way much respect to all
those sponsors I do want to give a big
shout out to our friends at natural
mystic
cannabis caregivers and Colorado Springs
Shelly you're awesome big digital hug to
you I'm not sure if you get to listen to
the show but either way I'm sending out
a big digital a thoughtful hug also Joey
what's up bro thanks for bat clone I
don't know if I should say that on the
show he didn't give me a clone but man
thank for that clone I really needed
that that helps me out in a big big way
huge shout out to natural mystic
cannabis caregivers I think that's all
the ads I'm responsible for this week
I've got this thing open
let's eat an edible this is where we all
started ten minutes ago
this is six ounces a hundred and
sixty-eight grams of chocolate and
peanut butter is what it looks like to
me 350 milligrams active cannabis
medicinal product keep out of reach of
children the packaging is quite fancy
I'm gonna read you the back just because
this isn't really they did a hell of a
good job on the packaging this is outer
box this product is infused with medical
marijuana and was provided without
regular regulatory oversight for health
safety or efficacy and there may be
health risks associated with the
consumption of the product keep out of
the reach of children processed in a
facility that make you may contain nuts
I hope with the consumption of this
product for women who are pregnant
breastfeeding or planning on becoming
pregnant it's pretty much anyone in
Pueblo the state of Colorado the
intoxicating effects of this product may
be delayed by two or more hours do not
drive the motor vehicle or operate heavy
machinery while using medical marijuana
it's got a phone number and an OPC
license like it should the ingredients
caught my attention eggs flour baking
soda salt cocoa powder everything all
the whole [ __ ] wrapper I know but
I've got a point
peanut butter butter powdered sugar
chocolate hash butter 0.5 grams cannabis
weight point five grams dosage 50
milligrams so this is supposed to be a
seven dose edible here is what their
haven't ended well what's got my
attention is it lists other ingredients
it has P 51.9%
K 38.1% and eleven point sorry I should
back up nitrogen phosphorus nutrients
use in the plan phosphorus potassium and
nitrogen calcium magnesium sulfur I
don't know what that one means I should
but I'm I don't know you can't do it
either the table of elements I'd the
periodic table of elements I couldn't
say it I was reading these five sugar
malt extract so they list also what it
was grown
on the bottom here organic neem oil so
they also list some of the stuff that
was used to treat the plants that's
pretty interesting that they list that
on there so I know almost everything
that went into this products that I'm
gonna eat so let's get down to the
[Music]
[ __ ] won't rip its bullet make
parachutes out of this [ __ ]
greenhouse material almost to the first
[Music]
it's like texture you know it's not like
hard the top layer is straight creamy
peanut butter the bottom layer is soft
it's like a almost a soggy brownie but
better already
I don't know what that texture is it's
almost a fudge like a nougat no it's our
than that okay I want to give you some
but I want to [ __ ] experiences as I
said I think they have these down here
at the shop and the speaking of shops
because you know we can turn this out
[Music]
delicious I get chocolate it's supposed
to be seven doses and if that's supposed
to be seven doses I'm a good four doses
in by now yeah that last drink that I
bought that's what I thought too you
know I was like a little earlier to work
at a shop she said she used to drink
those and sometimes it would Recker and
sometimes it wouldn't do anything she
said it may have been that's what she
was saying the lady of the shops he said
next time try fruit flavor and that's
what I wanted I wanted they had like an
apple cider type all they had was some
cappuccino and I'm like I said it was
like watered-down you who do they
no cannabis at all hi guys when he said
watered down you who did anybody else
think of the Beastie Boys song if
anybody else knows what I'm talking
about tweet me about it that'd be really
cool just tweet me a hashtag professor
booty agriculture I'll send you stickers
or too much like the interaction begging
for attention
this thing's delicious it reminds me of
remember the Little Debbie nutty bars
[Music]
another bread because they're delicious
opting to buy that I chose this over I
asked for a monkey bar because the
monkey bars I love it I love the monkey
bar is delicious I was gonna buy one of
those the lady the worse at the
dispensary is a friend of mine and also
a patient she's a cancer survivor and
she uses these products and she said I
know you like The Incredibles they're
100 milligrams they're $10 this Mountain
medicine peanut butter bar is $11 and
it's got 350 milligrams so it's like
three and a half of those for a dollar
more didn't take a lot of convincing
money and thanked her for being such a
great person the flavor so far I am
happy with my decision I know that I'm
gonna be it's almost like a different
kind of chocolate almost kind of imagine
that a chocolate chip or something
inside of some peanut butter batter
stuff it's got the works dude it's a
layer
semi dark chocolate over peanut butter
with this peanut butter chocolate it's a
thick mousse a light fudge sort of a
texture it's uh I can eat it quickly you
know it does it's not too peanut buttery
that I'm stuck while I'm trying to talk
but it does take a little effort to
clean up the face while you're grabbing
it and in the summertime eat this in the
air conditioner don't try to take this
out anywhere because he told you to kind
of put it in the fridge yeah for five or
ten minutes beforehand or microwave or
warm it up first
[Music]
he didn't say long she said like one
second two seconds you know but yeah
take a couple more bites I I think got
your attention because they had some
great looking herbs so you know that was
my only comparison about the one words
that she opened the jar and it was like
a punch in the face before she handed it
to me yeah and I mean like I said there
was no small nugs in the jar everything
was frosty everything was right to that
point where I feel like I could have
brought it home and kept it in my jar
for a couple days and it would have been
like you know I could have judged where
how dry or how like Adam tends to like
his wheat a little crispier than most
folks likes it a little drier we'd like
so we'll cure it perfectly and then give
it to Adam to destroy for us yeah
exactly
but still it's it's nice to have that
option instead of you I'm where I'm from
me it's always dry so
you know you get something wet you're
like what is this I'm all in now I just
resting my mouth up I wasn't about that
final filled with butter cuz that last
bite tastes like butter
not even like chocolate or pie there's
no like butter I've never had a chance
to say this on like a public platform
but [ __ ] Paula Deen no [ __ ] before her
racism but extra [ __ ] for her racism
so I had an Italian girlfriend and we
would watch Giada De Laurentiis and
Paula Deen back-to-back and I think
Alton Brown was on in the mix sorry I'm
wiping my face again [ __ ] chocolate
peanut butter butter all over the place
[Music]
it's movie theater popcorn in that last
bite so Paula Deen one day she's making
a meal she's like this meal got a little
something for everybody well except the
vegetarians but screw them they can go
outside and eat grass [ __ ] you Paula
Deen I'm gonna go outside and eat grass
while your shows on and never watch your
[ __ ] show again we'll go outside
until Giada De Laurentiis comes back on
[Music]
you can drive the podcast today bro hey
I wasn't trying to drive the podcast
correction you're right you're totally
right you're gonna have to keep me on
track you're gonna have to do that guys
we've been smoking live resin yeah about
the unicorn hash the live resin or the
but Nick you don't even know bra that
love present the love resin that's it
you heard all that [ __ ] here first on
the hydro culture podcast remember it
you're gonna ask questions later
yeah we've got answers the correction I
didn't episode about veg growth
at some point in the episode I said keep
your veg plants on 1212 don't [ __ ] do
that I [ __ ] up I said something wrong
I'm correcting myself right now on the
captain of this [ __ ] [ __ ] it up turn
it just the music test got a little loud
for me but I want to make your drawing
better so yeah my first mistake was I
don't even know if I set it on the
podcast or in a personal conversation
but I mentioned the red light spectrum
and I got it totally backwards and then
my second mistake was saying to keep
your vegging plants on 1212 do not do
this
keep your vegging plants on at least 18
hours of live at least 16 hours of light
18 would be better 24 is what I do to be
perfectly fair you didn't say it like oh
by the way put your plants I know it was
at the end of your sentence at the end
of your lesson at the end of your ramble
of how lights work I apologize and I'm
driving this button just telling you
from a listeners point of view tighten
your [ __ ] up it's so good chocolate
peanut chocolate peanut butter is a
potheads treat I've got it in my mouth
and it tastes so good I'm a peanut
butter fudge dude from Sonic this song
that's popping up right now it's called
hash tag and you can't get enough though
perfect because peanut butter you can't
get enough though
yeah let me know because I'd like I said
I would have definitely been like yo 11
bucks you'll see what happens alright so
we did a correction reception I wanna
give a big shout out to Jesse and burn
of course mr. Winn I got to meet Jesse's
father that's a character there yeah
harder than you and me
each of us to us I think he listens to
the show so a big handshake mr. wit no
wedding reception was great the bride
looked beautiful the groom well he was
pretty awesome so about halfway through
the night he decided to wear a young
lady's wife-beater for the rest of the
evening
each nipple stuck out just a little bit
and he's quite a hairy man so it looked
great in the beard everybody showed up
looking classy as a [ __ ] and I
think if you say classiest [ __ ] that
describes them perfectly Spence look
sharpest [ __ ] daddy has always looked
beautiful Big Mike was [ __ ] dressed to
the nines Joey even brought a skateboard
to skate in this cool place and then of
course my my homey sloppy Luke sharp as
hell fun we wish we were there bro I
don't know if you listen to the podcast
Fung is out of town right there
but the wedding reception I didn't go to
the actual wedding the pothead Cruz I
was calling us wasn't we chose to just
go to the after there was like a wedding
and then a reception and then kind of an
after-party that started about 8:30 once
the kids bailed out we set up a dad bar
and Spence from the garden of Weeden and
myself with also the help of Maddy and
if I missed anybody the garden we'd
enlisted people I'm sorry I was trying
to do a podcast again like 9,000
thoughts in my head at once I don't mean
to miss anybody I love all you guys at
the garden Whedon Ciroc Inanna included
and even honey so spin sin Matty and I
were pretty much to the entire wedding
party that was over 21 and after the
children left people were because the
wedding party with your life it was my
job I volunteered to go there if you've
seen that commercial that that girl
smoked and she [ __ ] melts into the
couch and becomes like playdough if you
have any of that weed and or hash
[Music]
it's that pink stuff in that and then so
I think we dished out probably 7 to 10
grams alive resin last night to the
wedding party some people kept coming
back and coming back we we probably
broke the record for Pueblo County in
one building at one time on an average
day and people are gonna [ __ ] their
pants I take 25 dabs no problem on an
average day maybe 30 or 40 on a heavy
bad day I've gone to secret cups and
we've had to judge 42 samples and I've
done those all in one day and was okay
and went back for seconds on a couple
twenty-five to fifty dabs per day range
which I don't know if that sounds a lot
and when you see the size of dabs he
does it is a lot
so and what's odd is all I'll wake up
and I'll rock for a few hours before I
take a nap I try to do a couple things
like I try to get food water in my body
and if you get up a reasonable time
somewhere between eight and ten you know
do your day get some food in you get
functional get your blood moving and
don't take a dab till 710 in the
afternoon or the evening you get wait
till like 6:00 or 7:00 or 4:20 lately
it's been too hot to get dad out all day
so you gotta wait until [ __ ] 6:00 and
the Sun starts going down and about 90
and get dad the [ __ ] out I'll take seven
per hour I'll sit down and take six dabs
in succession flour that's what I'm
thinking though is you know I smoked
flour most the time so it's not sitting
there smoking you know 10 bong hits a
flower to another four or five hours
later two more you know so I get what
you're saying I I go slower with the
dabs and I do with the flower so that's
probably your like any anything I smoke
or two you've got a certain amount of
inhales and exhales your lungs are going
to give you before they start to burn
out just like any sort of equipment or a
[ __ ] device or moving anything that
moves is going to break eventually and
if I've only got seventy two billion
ins-and-outs half of those on a DAB then
3/4 of them trying to smoke herb
[Music]
vapor to smoke ratio tonight would have
been the ninth we would have done that
event at the bar ona give an apology to
everybody that was excited about that I
myself was excited me too there were
some bureaucracy discrepancies and some
stuff that happened and I'm no longer a
member of
the citizens for the responsible
regulation of cannabis I don't know if
that even exists anymore to tell you the
truth I've backed out of that just gonna
stick with being a breeder and a podcast
toast and doing what I know I'm good at
I don't like the I used to go to City
Council meetings and stuff when I was
with another dispensary group I don't
like being in that realm that's a little
uncomfortable to me it's one thing going
there when you have to you know but when
it still feels like court yeah it still
feels like I don't feel I backed out of
going to those meetings because I felt
like I was a hindrance to the group
because I'm just a cliche looking quiet
and I didn't speak anyway we had
spokespeople for the group so I just
quit go and you wanna know the worst
thing I may tell you how I dry trim some
of this weed a lot of people to con
performed without Bouguer didn't show up
but he still killed it by himself
despicable dialects rapped who else
performed I know I'm gonna miss somebody
Jesse grabbed a microphone and rapped
that was pretty entertaining yeah a lot
of people did a lot of cool things and
it was a great time I'm gonna put in the
request for next I thought the music's
fading out get the music back let's get
it going
it was awesome it went off without a
hitch everything was fun everybody got
home safely we made sure but he got home
safe because they got kind of silly
wanna make sure to give shoutouts to the
garden of Weeden crew for running the
dad bar like a champ shoutouts to those
guys for getting married we'll get off
the topic of em getting married I don't
have a lot more to say about it why Bret
and I keep talking about live resin
everybody's tweeting me messaging me
what is it WTF live resin what the [ __ ]
is great it tastes great right Adam a
text message saying hey bro I got some
love resin what I actually meant to say
it was live resin and so he's been
laughing at that ever since take a
pretty chunky dab of some live resin
right now some friends that were kind
enough to give me a little bit of live
resin super awesome I hate the torch or
heat seal a little bit less heat and
make sure to use the carb cap with a
live resin I don't want to burn it up
cuz it's a lot more Turkey it's more
terpenoids you know about Terps that's
what mostly gives you the flavor there
flavonoids and Paley it's the contribute
to that but mostly it's the terpenoids
that you want to taste very clean yeah
you can see the cleanliness and the
clarity in the hash I think I might have
talked about it a little on the show
here we go doing a DAB
yeah that was a dab of live resin here
take that part take torch shut up the
task rod for making super awesome nails
and carb caps sponsor the show but they
should be one day they will be I just
got a task and I've been talking the
words are complicated right now I'm
trying to say that you can pick up
highly-educated products heated a little
more bro sorry I recommend if you've got
a rig with an 18 or a 14 millimeter male
joint sticking out of it I recommend the
duality nail that's probably the way to
go there it's gonna fit if you've got a
10 millimeter there is a 10 millimeter
domeless that works perfectly as well
catching my breath carb caps as a new
[ __ ] and they're awesome you don't have
to heat your nail is hot you start you
drop your dab in there you let it puddle
up a little bit you cover it with the
carb cap and it requires less heat so
you choke less and your dad tastes a
little bit better
you'll need a little more heat next time
bro that wasn't too bad you got a dad
but a little more he'll be better for
you oops try not to heat it up because
of what you just said yeah there's that
you'll find it I usually hate the tin I
usually heat it for you when you're here
but what's your nail gets a little bit
older you'll need to give it a little
bit more heat is something that you guys
will learn what starts getting too too
worn out that's the truth
to the show he's harvest and pull off
all the leaves on this is basically the
buds off the sticks
frozen fresh you cut down the plants
okay you cut them down you let them hang
for like three to four hours and take
off the leaves and then freeze them
that's all the dry right frozen chopped
down frozen and then blasted in the
closed-loop system out of the
closed-loop system and vacuum purged
really really gently and I'm not the
hash maker this is the process I have
observed and gathered from hanging out
with all of my friends that are extract
artists don't rush out and most people
and I can ask what most people don't
have access to the Machine you need to
do this a couple of specific machines
that you need to do this they're only a
couple brands everybody would recommend
to fight over so if one of them wants to
sponsor the show they even start to look
once this this develops where would they
look for it there was and it's gone now
so I'm was there it went [ __ ] quickly
there was tangi live resin at the clinic
I was 250 bucks for three grams for one
of our friends at bought some I think
that's $85 a gram is roughly what that
comes to but it's you gotta thank you're
paying for the Machine well and it's
kind of a hype that's part of I mean how
many people have you seen on Facebook or
anywhere yeah right and it's pretty much
the Denver crew has got to figured out
the Denver crew is smoking the libraries
and I think it was giddyup is one of the
first people that I ever saw smoke and
resin garden of Weeden
maybe greener side Empire that crew I'm
gonna give them credit for inventing the
Barenaked and the was their idea
giddyup was definitely one of the
pioneers of that [ __ ] and now that I've
recovered from my dad let me tell you
[Music]
people are arguing that it's not cured
so it can't be as good that the [ __ ]
weed isn't as good because it's not
cured before it's blasted is the taste
not incredible it is more flavorful than
anything it's an apple tasted like
cookies weird a bit if you had a Girl
Scout cookies flavored apples and you
bit into it you know how Apple's take a
second
that juice to come out of the fiber of
the Apple and the is that is where to
shatter would be like buying slices from
a bag we explained that enough we're
blasting fresh frozen plants don't try
and blast them fresh frozen really
lightly because the vacuum purge [ __ ]
up your terpenoids and it collapses a
lot of things if you're doing this
process you should know what I'm talking
about
all the vacuum Persia lighter and a
little longer just go lighter and longer
less II don't expect to get shatter
through the same process and it looks
like we [ __ ] up it looks like old
school hash that we [ __ ] up but it's
almost closed and that's and I'm higher
from it yeah it's uh it's cleaner I
don't cough yeah I do because I smoke so
well if I take you know a dime from it I
don't know if I do a half gram dab of
live resin why would you want to though
because I like drop it half gram dabs
and [ __ ] regular shatter I like that
they like kicking the dick kind of
feeling that gives you a level sometimes
it takes a half gram dab YouTube video
in the making
how much live resin is on this little
sheet ring I don't know
that's not even big enough to be
impressive eighty-five dollars a gram at
the clinic drop $45 gram or $45 I'll
post that picture I'll post a picture
somewhere he's talking about me burning
things it was a hundred dollar bill as
the fourth of July because I may get in
trouble for that form of protest that's
acceptable political protest yeah
there's a story behind that if you guys
didn't catch it the first time the new
dating catch did so I'm gonna toot my
own horn but also I'm going to recommend
that you guys go and check out cannabis
sativa the essential guide to the
world's finest marijuana strains edited
by St owner the name is stoner this is
volume three released by green candy
press this book is $20 it should be
released very soon I'm a good amazon.com
I'm not sure that it's even out yet but
when it comes out you gotta get this
[ __ ] book dude because on page I
think it's forty five or fifty four I
suffer from it's 54 page 54 there are
some glorious photos of golden goat by
myself
I actually took those pictures with a an
Olympus
what's it called now I can't remember
the [ __ ] little Olympus camera it's
not even anything fancy Olympus it's
just a little 16 [ __ ] is what's real
nice about it and that thing took all
the pictures in this we're taken with
that cheap is a $200 camera from Best
Buy yeah so publishing a book guys that
should be so thanks I'm gonna give a
shout out to them thanks for putting me
in the book I also want you guys to look
at the book support these guys they put
our great puss strain guides the
description I wrote some of it and then
it was given some Liberty I think is
what I'm trying to say I didn't write
that the way that it's written there so
and also I'm not taking credit for
creating golden goat I did not create
golden goat guy named mr. dank from
Kansas created the golden goat and that
was not me I simply put it into seed
form its in feminized seed unfortunately
right now it's sold out I made a test
batch and they went pretty quickly to
all my test crew and they showed [ __ ]
huge potential and they look like gold
and go mommy so then I made more and I
put them online buy that book check it
out guys it will be available on Amazon
if it's not already marijuana stuff and
it's getting to be legal everywhere
people are gonna want to know about
these strains they're growing all this
crazy [ __ ] you know we've actually got a
book to kind of document it to the
picture from sub cool on page 72 of Jack
the Ripper
just excuse me never sneezed on a
podcast before the first time excuse me
sorry guys I didn't mean to do that I
can't forget about it I still have the
taste of chocolate peanut butter in my
mouth do you remember which strain it
was easy to spot because they take
amazing photography shadow to apply to
labs it's Josh and Geoff I'm going for
it their photos are great why the
picture of white diesel is glorious you
guys we're gonna want this book somebody
did a good job this is a lot of these
are better than my Instagram feed no
close though close it's that style yeah
to help out the buyer that was an
amazing picture too they had a lot of
labs on page 86 amazing picture green
house super Lemon Haze times alien Bubba
tested 16 percent THC check out La Plata
labs calm those are friends of mine so I
definitely do support them they are
available actually nature's green
remedies calm so if you need to get your
hands on some apply to labs products
nature's dream remedies dot-com the
coupons that I give out are good for
every brand somebody asked me if that's
only good for eye region etics products
that's weird people don't realize that I
am IA genetics as well so I read
genetics is the largest sponsor of this
podcast they never get a promotion or
anything so first time I've ever done
that big shout out to Ira genetics
Colorado check out I read genetics
for great cannabis photography some
information on myself I haven't updated
the website in a while there's a forum
there if you want to join the forum it's
kind of a fun little thing to do new
screen remedies those coupons expire I
was gonna say the [ __ ] seed um hi those
coupons expire this month but I'll give
you another code but they're good for
any brand not just mine so if you wanna
get some lip lot of labs if you want to
get there's so many good brands on there
I think alpha chronic is on there gauge
green is definitely on there I recommend
highly recommend gauge green highly
recommend gauge green I used a dream in
my breeding projects all the time
Daybreaker f2 Daybreaker f2 x + berry is
actually black cherry Kim talked about
trim stuff we better do that for 49
minutes in holy crap dry trim you need a
long episode you know I understand I get
it structured but this was fun giraffe
[ __ ] but you have to Joe Rogan quote
but they're usually followed by Adam
looks like I'm gonna do is watch this
cartoon called king of the hill just
like lucky
we get a shout out to anybody gab
anybody all I know is that this stuff
that you're dabbing is is 100% and I
want one of these next time because you
do and make her extremely jealous my
wife she's sitting at home I'm sitting
here after how high this is gonna be a
fun Comcast come on dude you're
expensive I wasn't even gonna say the
c-word should work come on guys get it
together thought they should work they
should work past 12 o'clock to four
o'clock because unlike them other people
do things at those hours yeah and it's
like you know I'm not gonna say what
people do I'm just gonna say that people
need to do that yeah on the Internet all
right guys after I finish this cough
here we go with the miniature grow
lesson on dry trimming and bear in mind
I ate a 350 milligram aníbal that is
highly effective to slow down a little
bit [ __ ] working yeah Adam will help
us out so I'll even turn on the music
cause it's highly distracting so I love
these songs task rocks awesome in my
opinion dry trim what rubber gloves for
almost all of everything that I'm
talking about it the blue nitrile gloves
great they're cheap they got him in like
Walmart and Walgreens they're affordable
so pull the plan out of the room I guess
and just chop it down to the base and
then hang it upside down I use that
bottom branch the very bottom branch
where the first [ __ ] set of buds are
I hang that over sometimes you can
string up a line across the room or
maybe use like hanger depending on how
many I have going on but you're hanging
it that's your new little hanger that
little wide that first intersection and
then I'll grab like a fuzzy stick pack
fuzzy sticks from Walmart it's kind of
like a pipe cleaner anything like that
[ __ ] the finger around your bread bag
they got a bunch of those kind of things
a little twist you tie sort of thing
wrap that around the stalk and just kind
of secure it on to whatever you're
hanging into a little bit because
sometimes that branch will break if you
got a heavy plant mmm you want to go to
the second branch go for that secure it
on there a little bit I like to secure
it either way just cuz I'm [ __ ] OCD I
don't want my plants falling on the
floor after they've been growing for
alright princess your turning colors hey
don't call me princess this works if you
guys want to buy an edible
I recommend the mountain madness know
your tolerance yeah if you were I'm high
yeah working for you I know it's gonna
work for my I like to say my channel and
this is [ __ ] me up in such a good way
when I bought that 315 milligram drink I
thought that it was gonna [ __ ] me up I
mean you literally told me I want one I
wish we could play some Grateful Dead
music without getting the show in
trouble right now that's where I am hi I
want to listen to Jack Straw so
anybody's a Deadhead out there you know
where I am
I see I just need to hear Jack Straw man
somebody knows where you are somebody
knows where I am somebody weren't a
[ __ ] tie-dyed shirts out there code
yeah man they're gonna play Jack Straw
for me all right
so we got the plant it's hanging upside
down right you need to get off the fan
leaves now is a good time to do that
maybe you did that some growers do that
a few days before harvest maybe I should
have recommended that maybe a few days
before harvest go in there and take off
all your big fan leaves or you can do
that right as you harvest or you can do
it as it's hanging up just get those big
fan leaves off now your plants are
hanging upside down in a room you want
that room it like [ __ ] I should've wrote
this down cuz I'm getting really high
you don't want a lot of humidity in
there maybe like 25 to 30% max maximum
humidity and then then you wanna have
some air moving but not like your fans
blowing directly on the plants that'll
crisp em up a little too quickly you
want them to dry a little bit slowly
while they're hanging upside down so you
got whole plants hanging upside down -
fan leaves just hanging upside down the
humidity is kind of low keep your
temperatures you don't want to go cold
but you want to go hot either
so like 7075 you know right yeah yeah
where you are is where they're cool yeah
my tank kind of like in a work area
where it's a little dark keep it dark in
there go to possibly 80 if you have to
[Music]
air because moving air prevents mold
just remember that in every gross
situation moving more air prevents mold
that's like one of the growing is humid
you may not even realize how much water
is involved in growing but every gallon
you pour in is coming back out some
water you get rid of it or utilize it so
you got these plants are upside down
there in the room with the right
humidity they're in the room with the
right temperature hopefully it's dark
right as dark as you can get it you got
a dedicated space you got a lot of air
moving so you don't get moldy now just
let them dry up for [ __ ] I've got some
that have been hanging in the plants we
trim tonight we're cut down
on a Monday so they've almost been going
for two weeks hanging up there and it's
been a little a little humid because
we've had a swamp cooler going in that
area not in that area but in a room like
three at a whole way down I guess
there's this whomp cooler in there just
cuz that's what that room came equipped
with yeah but it's still getting it
still it still makes a little humidity
in the rest of the the grow environment
so well they're sitting there hanging
for about 14 days is where they've been
they don't have any fan leaves on them
you might want to check them every other
day every day like start checking about
four days five days six days give them a
little squeeze and when those families
are little sugar leaves start crisping
right off just by hitting them with your
finger grab those plants and just take
like I've had these long bins and I just
take branches off I have the plants
hanging and I cut branches off and lay
them into the bins and once my bins are
full I go to a sit down to trim dude
drive you nuts trying to stand up I'm
getting old that's how I know I'm all I
can't stand to trim anymore so you sit
down and I just gonna hold I cut one bud
off at a time and just knock the leaves
off of it with my thumb's because now
that it's dry those leaves are pretty
much just gonna fall off and you can see
what your finished product is as you're
going so trim it to your liking at this
point if you're selling it to [ __ ]
for stupid cheap a pound and just hustle
and wait to get it out don't trim it
worth the [ __ ] that's why cheap weed is
cheap if you want connoisseur grade weed
take your time and trim it and wear
rubber gloves
yeah please if you eats that sticky then
definitely you can like rub you learn
how to don't scrape the [ __ ] latex
right out of that [ __ ] but you learn how
to rub the hash off of your fingers that
makes my little hash ball or a little
hash watch watch a video on making
what was it called you know I'm talking
about no I don't cuz you're saying it
[Music]
figure out real quick yeah so the butts
are pretty much dry right uh we've got
them in the room they hung there crispy
now we're hand trimming them so cut off
like you got a bunch of sticks in a pan
you take that [ __ ] stick you cut off
little individual buds and you just
knock the leaves off with your thumbs
you can use scissors now if you want but
it's kind of pointless I am faster just
thumbing it it looks like you're playing
Nintendo with the button your hands
should just take you a couple seconds to
get each bud and you can see I like I
said you can see the finished result
what's really cool is if you wet trim
you got to trim it and you're all sticky
and it [ __ ] up your scissors and it
takes so long and every time you set a
butt down or touch a but it [ __ ]
sticky there and stickier and sticky
here dry trimming is way cleaner you can
weigh your [ __ ] sure anyways I mean
they're essentially yes I believe you
know like they're they're ducks to
further the place they're there what
struggling to suck up the moisture not
the the bud really I would imagine
that's yeah that's mostly right but also
it helps slow it down because you want
the water to leave more slowly the
chlorophyll evaporates with the water so
what's the waters gone you can't take
away any more chlorophyll but if you let
the water come out slowly then that
chlorophyll dissolves with the water and
goes away okay it happens in the cure
process also you start the gases start
we're getting into cure that's different
yeah yeah it's just I can tell you now
like most of the videos that I've made
in an hour and I'm high on that edible
it only took like 45 minutes I'm a
little better now I've calmed down but
for a minute there I wasn't really high
your hands are still like on your chair
[Music]
guys seriously if you are not an
experienced and don't try to be cool
because I smoke a lot of dabs you'll be
that lady from NBC or whatever
yeah dude you'll be writing a story
about freaking out no you'll piss your
pants yeah don't eat 350 milligrams
unless you're experienced because you
will piss your pants and being a bad
example on my own podcast no like you
said you are you're an experienced dude
you're in the comfortable ability of
your own home you got a homie here
you're good like you're you're in the
perfect spot to do this to be like I'm
going to this is no different than
drinking a bottle of tequila I'm not
gonna drive I'm not gonna go anywhere no
I'm a I'm a troll the internet you can
tell how many times a grower or a person
in the trim circle has been around by
how [ __ ] eager they are to trim third
maybe fourth time if you're like I got a
[ __ ] trim a bunch of weed tonight
you're an experienced girl you've got a
couple of crops down yeah I still love
it I love it and hate it I love it
because I get to finally check out my
babies I get to see like oh here we go
get to [ __ ] take those pretty flowers
and I'm just kidding
I get to tickle that trim and make
shatter and that's one cool thing about
dry trim as soon as you're done dry
trimming you can haul that trim off over
to your extract artist guy and you can
do his thing with it I've cured trim the
floor and blasted it it was very very
unnoticeably different ya couldn't tell
the difference between batches some
people say that's good you know really
if I make an hash out of the whole plant
Girl Scout cookies whole plants and just
make dad's out of it
I'll cut it down a little bit early a
little bit early I like to take it 63
days usually I'll cut it down to like 55
56 already ten to eight weeks like a
mocha frappuccino it's got that dirt
coffee chocolate Girl Scout cookies guys
man let's put some music in the
background again I turned it down to
give that girl lesson and talk and it
disappeared forever if you got more
questions about dried trimming weed
please let me know because I seriously
am [ __ ] high as [ __ ] off that edible
[Music]
thank you for helping me help myself a
little trim girl that came over I wrote
that down I might have said that earlier
did she help dude she saved hours of the
night this song makes me think of hacen
de Moura [ __ ] singing at one time
ending like every it's the one point
where it was like you're running videos
[Music]
like you've died nobody will tell you no
but I would be coming out on a Monday
morning what's wrong with him he's off
[ __ ] sloppy today
it's been an hour dude what else do you
wanna cover [ __ ] up to grow tip please
please let me know
correct me cuz I have said wrong [ __ ]
before and like I said I'll fix it I'll
try to tell you the right probably just
enough for two dads it doesn't do any
good sitting on a piece of parchment
paper
I just want to as somebody else sitting
here at the table I want to share the
wealth and like goodness anybody out
there listening that is one of you folks
you know let's get this we're running
out of butane we're gonna have to switch
to the email pretty soon you came
prepared I got the email sitting on the
table right here with a highly-educated
infinity nail rigged up ready to go
well it's impressive just say the least
see you like yeah yeah it's only the
second time I've seen it but um from the
south we don't have no fancy [ __ ] like
that tracks behind his trailer park the
power plant oh man they just like do a
bunch of studies and research you know
I've had the bong for the past ten years
or so you know everybody would come
around smoke my dual-chamber water ice
cool bong it was amazing a lot of the
people that are coming here to buy the
REC wieder straight up from the South
[ __ ] Florida to Colorado if you're in
Colorado and you're on the very south
into Pueblo at exit 91 you need to go
north just a little bit from the exit
and there is the greener side dispensary
there's a certain time period early
evening right as the Sun sets the led
UFO lights come on in the greenhouse to
keep the plants flowering earlier the
bloom season from about a mile and a
half away this [ __ ] 120 by 30 foot
greenhouse I think it is illuminates
this purple spectrum and if you don't
know what it is it is the craziest
looking [ __ ] thing ever dude it was
all lit up
[Music]
I don't recommend that but yeah you
could probably call him and ask him what
time the UFO lights come on and tell him
that you want to come check out the
purple greenhouse and they'll probably
tell you what time those turn off
because I you know there's a greenhouse
so the schedule is gonna change they're
just trying to keep the plants come
visiting the flower or a little fun
people there's tons of fun stuff to do
here
we got a frisbee golf park couple joints
they're like nah dude we don't we don't
want you we see stoners everybody yeah
there's like 50 guys in Tennessee going
[Music]
so that's that did you take a DAB or
just take one of you stingy
[Music]
the divers clean I must have
just like you sure didn't just like drop
off my body or compete I'm like a
hundred and thirty seven percent sure
which is that's that's a big yeah I
don't know if that exists there's some
accountant out there pull it out right
now going [ __ ] you
then again they don't come to the hydro
culture podcast for statistics and I
haven't seen how many grams per watt I
pull this girl say she can pull two plus
pounds of copper thousand watt light
she's using a four by eight [ __ ]
botanic air trays on tables like
elevated [ __ ] lights every 5000 watt
lights every five feet and rows of five
lights yeah it's a lot of details for
this chick's room but she's claiming
that you apply and I'm not doubting her
but she's saying that she pulls [ __ ]
two plus pounds of Kong per [ __ ]
cycle has to be funny a lot of details
little bit like a dress that's a fat
pool if she's doing that
props yeah again coming from East and
just watching videos the only place you
can watch videos of that nature
forms and YouTube and stuff like that a
lot of people sometimes exaggerate and
I'm not saying she is pictures that may
do her juice may have just ice
[Music]
podcasting someone needs to sit me
subjective within [ __ ] 44 seconds of
this being released your Twitter hey you
know what you asked for support for your
family with cancer and people will
ignore you yes for a dick pic on a
podcast [ __ ] everybody in America is
gonna flash you with dick pic a fast
you look you let me ask for what I want
to ask for okay as long as you [ __ ]
clearly give your podcast Twitter please
refrain I like pictures of fat buds I'll
go home and I'll make my wife's a
Twitter account you can send her pretty
sure that's the first she likes the
penis reference on the podcast this
president wasn't from wait so I wanted
to [ __ ] kind of roll with that random
random [ __ ] up aggro lesson people
counted me I'm super high so well asked
for details
so what do we do after we got the leaves
bucked off you throw them in a bucket
let them sit there for a couple days
after that you put them in a jar and
start curing that's from there as curing
and I don't know how to get into curing
yet I'm not rekt so write that down
[ __ ] in two or three episodes from
now guess what we'll do
cheering here's some weed that's right I
mean that's a I know we went way out of
order because we're only advanced but I
was trimming we deny it so it's crispy
and a lot of people don't even know they
literally thank you dry it and that's it
[Music]
yourself or with your homies reason for
medical purposes we got a cure right you
want to be proud of it
holy crap that tastes like [ __ ] weed
[Music]
but I can't this thing got me high good
it comes in waves
is it worth eleven dollars to me yes
it depends that's hard to say because
some people like their spending habits
are different yeah where you choose to
put your money my mom will see
everything is expensive how much is it
it's two pennies she's from back in the
day when that was a quarter of a penny
oh my god yeah it's just so it's kind of
here but for me as well worth 11 bucks
is my [ __ ] really short answer of a
lot of long words
I'm just saying usually things on that
level is 10 15 bucks maybe 20 bucks or
something really potent if you're going
to a concert or something and you want
to get [ __ ] high as [ __ ] and not have
to worry about smoking through it cuz
that's why I like edibles I go to a
comedy show and you can't smoke if the
comedy works they will throw you the
[ __ ] out and you're highly visible in
there the place is tiny yeah they're in
like a [ __ ] the whole night this would
be beautiful if you're driving up from
Lowe's I can eat that [ __ ] stop and
get gas at that one gas station they eat
that [ __ ] in the parking lot and then
get back on the road by the time you get
to comedy works you'll have a smile on
your face yeah it was worth 11 bucks so
if you're glad I was at least
get some weed that $11 included tax
right there dispensary includes tax so
11 bucks flat out the door that is great
if you're like [ __ ] vegan or
something I don't know what their option
is for you because that's super
chocolaty and if you're diabetic you're
gonna have to be careful with that but
of course you're not supposed to eat
seven doses all at once like I did
that's got me ramble in everything in
moderation yes go big or go home on the
hydro culture podcast that's right
listen to me ramble I hate the [ __ ]
edible so I'm gonna go find something
super entertaining to do with myself now
thanks to all the sponsors thanks to
natural mr. cannabis caregivers big
high-five across the table to Adam for
coming and doing a [ __ ] hour and a
half long podcast with me it's quite
entertaining
sorry for Dragutin on dude it's awesome
the [ __ ] if you're having fun they're
having fun some comments you know that I
love [ __ ] comments on Facebook on
iTunes on Twitter on Instagram on
stitcher I didn't read any comments this
time I didn't even check to see if they
were there we're just trying to have fun
go to iTunes oh yeah part of that
culture or find the review section give
us a five-star rating after that type in
a comment let me know what you think
about the show I will read those
comments I won't be as high when I read
your comments so that they will make
sense
don't forget the show is available still
availabl and always will be on iTunes
stitcher so well that I am each episode
is archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm you should be checking that out
anyway try not to Jesse Witten burn I'm
shadow to my ninja Spence thanks for
listening everybody take phat dab give
my mom a hug for me
[Music]
no I'm sucking pretty sure I could walk
straight up that wall right now if I try
dude watch yo it's Bobby hustle
representing for the real Big Bite sound
Joseph Starr the boy can't play we're
lettin a broken guitar hey yo nicotine
you know we stay smoking hard it's the
hustle
[Music]
number 23 of the iGrow culture podcast
Jeff thanks for joining me for another
episode
today's intro music was brought to you
by DJ nicotine check out DJ nicotine on
soundcloud big up and much respect to DJ
nicotine in this episode jessi joins us
for another outdoor grow lesson but
first some pills this podcast is brought
to you by nature's green remedies
dot-com visit nature's green remedies
calm for gauged green genetics apply to
labs
sencity rare dankness mile high kena
venture IRA genetics and many more
trusted brands she purchased two five
packs of ira genetics you will receive a
free two pack or purchase two ten packs
and receive a free five pack so that's
buy ten get two free buy twenty get five
free matrix green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code Rasta Jeff for fifteen
percent off any order and you always get
free shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com once again that coupon code is
you can purchase any brand on the
website and you will get that 15% off
with that code and of course free
shipping also brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies drawing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street unit at or stop by the new Pub
location at 618 East Fourth Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out www.engvid.com for
current store hours and special sales go
to the location tell us - Jeff sent you
and of course don't forget about the
special they're having on the soil it's
one tote of soil for five hundred and
fifty dollars we've talked about that on
a couple episodes it's a whole bunch of
soil for a really good price six hundred
dollars if you need it delivered
anywhere in Colorado's
give them a call or check out hydro
Denver comm for more information on that
one and this also brought to you by our
good friends at oil slick oil slick
tools to help you concentrate
check out slick pad calm for more
information on twitter Sinemet we tell
them you're listening to the hydro
culture podcast also this show is
brought to you by our friends at
Treehugger calm sweet sucker comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews over there thanks for
[Music]
supporting the show distracting for me
once again shout out to nicotine fella
you play the music I really appreciate
that let me tell you the name of the
song that we're listening to that was
the summit turn up 2014 electric
dancehall music vol 1 live on DJ duties
soundcloud page there's a [ __ ] sweet
shot of DJ nicotine DJing at Red Rock so
you look stylish in that shot brother
let's respect thanks for letting me play
your stuff excuse me my voice is of
course raspy from jabbin that's uh
that's par for the course right so it
says tougher rules on Colorado marijuana
edibles for serving size and child
safety this article is by Erik Gorski
from the Denver Post it says Colorado's
recreational marijuana edible
manufacturers face tougher rules on
potency serving size and packaging of
their products under stopgap rules
adopted by state regulators Thursday the
new guidelines in response crafted in
response to concerns about
overconsumption by inexperienced
consumers will do away with bite size
products that pack in 100 milligrams of
the psychoactive chemical THC the
maximum allowed by state law products
may contain up to a hundred milligrams
of THC but they must be easily broken
off into pieces that have 10 milligrams
or fewer the standardized edible serving
size under state law so now there we've
standardized apparently 10 milligrams is
a serving of edible cannabis so if you
buy a hundred milligram bar they want it
easily divisible in ten pieces I
shouldn't see names of products but you
know the cat is already kind of
separated into servings that's kind of
how I see they could do it and
sorry KitKat that I used you but you're
serving [ __ ] it's perfect for my example
our Hershey's bar has got they're
already divided perfectly so that's what
they're gonna require of all of these
pieces and I gotta say that that edible
that I ate on the show was 350
milligrams it was small I'm trying to
measure it in my head to give to have
something to compare it to but it was
quite tiny I don't have anything in my
range that is about the same size about
the size of the top of a pill bottle
[Music]
like an inch and a half by an inch and a
half and it was slightly thick but the
thing was there was no way to judge you
could break it in half I guess and kind
of eyeball it but there was no way to
really judge the size of that sort of an
edible so they're gonna make it or they
have to be easily broken up and then
that way you eat ten milligrams instead
of trying to guess and get rekt another
change manufacturers will be required to
put single serving edibles and child
resistant packaging before shipping them
to stores instead of relying on stores
to provide the packaging as customers
leave with their purchases so I think
that means more costs also that's gonna
go up because the manufacturer now has
to pay for that and then that's just
gonna get moved right on down the line
to the dispensary and that's gonna get
pushed right on down the line to you
because now you're able to bring in they
give you this big white it looks like a
money envelope kind of like a bank bag
but it's got a child resistant zipper
thing on it it's got like a clasp on the
zipper that you have to know how to open
and if you bring that you can put all of
your edibles and stuff in there and they
let that count as your childproof
container you actually you can buy those
or they charge you for them at a lot of
the dispensaries so there's gonna go put
that right on the product already you're
gonna pay a little more
but I guess a couple of bucks to keep
kids safe as well we got to do and then
you get into the argument of what about
parenting it's not uh it's not all about
the products it's about the parenting
but that's another argument probably a
whole other podcast that talks about
that so the rules this one says the
rules which still must be made permanent
in a process that will include public
comment will go into effect in November
first
they grew out of meetings with health
officials regulators industry
representatives and activists on both
sides the marijuana enforcement
divisions primary concern is to ensure
public safety at trees Bryant a
spokeswoman for the Department of
Revenue wrote in an email marijuana
Enforcement Division feels that clear
serving size requirements within the
industry is a vital part of responsible
regulation Rachael O Brien a founding
member of smart Colorado which supports
tighter restrictions on marijuana said
the rules are a step in the right
direction the time will tell whether
they go far enough edibles manufacturers
responding to public demand already
shifted to lower potency edibles since
recreational sales began January 1st
said Mike Elliott executive director of
the marijuana industry group the free
market has largely addressed this
problem he said I kind of agree that's
350 milligram in a bowl that I ate it
[ __ ] me up and I'm a professional pot
smoker I take dad's all day I wake and
bake on a regular basis you know I'm not
bragging about how much I smoke or
anything but I get down I'm smoking live
resin right now I probably took a couple
of half gram dabs today rekt me so if
somebody if a normal civilian got ahold
of that thing and eat the whole thing
they'd be destroyed and they would have
a miserable experience so I think
clearly marking it as a key that's a
great idea
we all remember the story of the lady
from New York Murray no doubt that ate
too much edibles and thought she was
[ __ ] turning herself inside out and
dying in her hotel room
nobody wants to be that guy
because I think that's enough news for
the day I just kind of wanted to read
you that one article Jesse came over we
did a little outdoor girl lesson sounds
like my voice is about to blow out
anyway so I'm gonna turn up the music
and then we'll be back with the grow
lesson thanks for joining us hang on for
just one second if you got a dabber if
you got a joint if you got a bowl if you
got an edible if you've got a drinkable
if you've got some topical hey consume
that at this time because I'm gonna take
a DAB and that means that kind of
technically we are getting high together
so when this music starts count to about
thirty and that means we're getting high
together right about then here we go
[Music]
all right guys you got the nail hot you
got your bowl packed you got a joint
rolled you got something going on let's
get stone together I'm gonna take a nap
cookies live resin made by a close
friend I'm gonna hit a hit man mini cake
with that highly educated
it's the infinite I nail hooked up to an
email the old temple because at one
point I had a had arranged a sponsorship
deal or something with the temple but
they have since sold the company so I've
got the tip temple it's set at 460 I
like it
[Music]
yo what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to the show hey I've got
Jesse back we're gonna do another grow
lesson before we do that man I want to
say congratulations on there Jesse just
got married his wedding was awesome I'm
sure you've heard us talk about it so uh
welcome to the show and congratulations
bro thank you thank you you look like a
new man you got a hair is half way
combed yeah smile on your face got a
haircut groom the beard a little I
wasn't gonna mention the grooming of the
beer did you have to get refitted for
your dress after they know cuz it still
stayed in place his beard is manly as
[ __ ] you guys if you let me post a
picture of them we'll put a picture up
on the Instagram or somewhere so you
guys can see what a man beard looks like
a Colorado man beard hey turn myself up
a little I'm not loud enough sorry it's
an ego thing I got to come up more on
the computer here awesome
so Jesse is a part of the high grow
store his wife works there are you how
involved are you are you an employee or
are you just kind of helping them behind
the scenes I am a helping be behind the
scenes helping with training uh
employees I'm product lines and stuff
cool I'm also doing uh commercial sales
for dispensaries caregiver grows stuff
like that so sweet get at me I'll I'll
beat anyone's price they'll be that's
his ego thing speaking of egos closer to
his face you guys can do a little bit
better I'll turn me down and him up
that'll make this happen so speaking of
high grow a couple of people that have
been listening to the podcast kind of
called us out they said five hundred and
fifty bucks for a tote of soil if I go
online that's only 299 dollars there
correct they did some research the
caveat is if you pay two hundred ninety
nine dollars shipping is two hundred and
forty nine dollars yes because it's got
to be shipped on a FedEx truck we were
just talking about how big a tote of
soil is it's about the size of a
Volkswagen
it's probably three and a half four feet
wide by three and a half to four feet
tall depending on how much it's been
compressed cuz it's gonna kind of squish
down by gravity and being moved around
there their heaviest [ __ ]
yeah how are they getting that off the
truck when they bring it to your house
with a pallet jack so dance you know
right to your front yard so figure out
it you know figure it out from there ya
know where it's gonna go when they get
there maybe you can sweet-talk the guy
this show is brought to you by hi girl
into our growing supplies make sure you
check out hi girl pretty sure I already
said that once in the show but I like
giving them love cuz they give us a lot
of love Jesse's back he's gonna give us
a grow lesson we should review a little
bit of what we've done by now we should
have some big-ass bushes that are in the
veg stage right oh yeah yeah
we've talked a little bit about feeding
we've talked about topdressing a little
tiny bit we're gonna talk more about
that we should have them kind of let's
see we're about to start the bloom phase
in the stretch phase so if we want to
top them and do some training now is
kind of our last chance we should stop
topping by now right
unless we got plants that are gonna
clear the fence yeah unless you know
molest Heights a concern and that's your
motivation for topping but you know and
in that case by all means you know do
what you need to do to get your crop in
so the neighbors in that [ __ ] you don't
the people walking down the street to
see that [ __ ] so if you need and if you
don't have to do it we can pull the
plants down a little bit if you have
been taking care of it you should be
able to grab some branches the tall ones
and just pull them down and then maybe
time to a stake or maybe tie them to
something in the garden that's already
there like a rock or something you can
use a stake in the ground I use big
bamboo poles just spread that plant out
to where instead of growing straight up
you kind of got it girl in a little
horizontally now's your time to get it
going cuz I think within the next 10
days here we're gonna everyone's gonna
go into flower real heavily yeah I
believe so I've got some
I've got a strain that's Tom Hill's deep
chunk crossed with a g13 sorry I fixed
that noise guys I could not find it I
think I just noticed it you know I've
got a straightener Scot you know some
kind of Landry stuff in it and it is
started flowering okay actually snuck up
on me and I had to take clones that are
kind of pre flowering so guys that's one
thing we're gonna talk about get clones
if you've got some outdoor plants and
you're waiting for them to go in flower
and he needs some clones from so you can
grow next year get clones now I always
say and this is I'm gonna go off on a
little side right here I warned Jesse
there'd be a rant about this if you're
growing from seed or a clone that is
brand new to you take some clones before
you go into flower it's really
frustrating when you grow a plant and
it's done and you smoke it with some of
your friends and know like what the hell
is this and you're like it's the best
and you all agree and they go I can't
wait till you grow it even better next
time and you go oh yeah I don't have a
clone of that so we're never gonna get
to taste this ever again except this one
round that's the most frustrating
heartbreaking feeling so take clones you
guys definitely take clones from
everything that you grow if you've got
the option that's them that's some
killer advice from a seed company owner
well yeah find that keeper what
appreciate that how about when you do
get that harvest heavy a taste dank it
[ __ ] gets you high as hell you're
gonna wish you had a clone of that yep
yeah I always you had a clone of it too
because I want to cut when I find you at
the Cannabis I need to clone of that one
so get some clones all the time I'm glad
you mentioned the seed company thing
even yeah that's that's sound advice
right there if I'm the seed guy yeah for
sure so yeah we're talking about getting
those plants below the fence line you
can kind of you can do the low stress
technique you can do a little bit of
super dropping like soma does kind of
crack them and bend them a little bit
now's your last chance really because
you're going into flower in about ten
days and I really don't like to mess
with plants there are hormones in your
plants auxins and cytokinins that move
around with they find the tops of the
plants and affect the Grad the top of
the plant in the way that stuff grows
you don't want to disrupt that right
now that's gonna that'll freak your
plants out a little bit yeah
mess up bud sizes yeah but you can still
you can still kind of pull them down and
low stress training them but you don't
want to go and kick their ass real bad
or anything
I've unpadded for my first seasons
growing outdoors I didn't top and all
the plants were from seed so the hoe the
meristem you know it's just her the main
stalk was uh you know just the
straightest could be and I tied a rope
around the top of the sari even on the
microphone like like keep doing it -
yeah Jesse brought over some live resin
really good oh you're gonna like the
live resin
unicorn hash the unicorn hash yeah
so uh the the ones he did from seed yeah
um tied the rope around the top of the
plant and just pulled the whole frickin
thing down almost like a bow and arrow
looking thing yes yeah yeah and the
result was just like this whole head
road of buds was supercool all the
second branches took over and started
they all cannabis wants one dominant top
on the plant something I know what it is
but I'm not gonna go I'm trying to go
slowly with the listeners and get
everybody up to speed and not try to Ed
Rosenthal people when you talk to who
forgets that we're not all doctors and
scientists yeah weed scientists and
he'll just blow your mind so I'm trying
to go slow for you guys will talk about
the auxins and cytokinins and their
hormones and plants that make them want
to grow a top bud but when you cut out
that top blood all the other bottom buds
go hey I've got the opportunity it's
like when you kill the you kill the
leader although with the top the bottom
buds do so if you guys that plant
pull it over like a fishing pole would
Bend when you got a fish
all those little branches that you've
got those little sucker buzz that
oftentimes we cut off those will create
nice little bud sites is another they've
got the chance to become a top and
they're also exposed to more light yeah
oh yeah yeah cool it's a real neat
effect so we should be in the stretch
phase or starting to pre flower right
yeah Oh totally yeah
are you doing anything for bugs now I I
sprayed with neem oil and I just did it
the last time as soon as I know this
flower i I really don't special outdoors
I really don't like spraying the plant
with anything meet you mom
so I stopped the kelp Mills compost tea
sprays and the neem oil sprays I do that
individually I don't you know just stop
the whole garden as each uncus train
starts flowering it's like Oh can't
spray that plant anymore so you know so
in southern Colorado we're getting a lot
of rain right now there's some weird
bugs pop it up yeah I've never seen
yeah stuffs gonna be out of balance I
personally haven't noticed any you know
then being a predator plant predators
but um it could be those things are
gonna look for homes and they're gonna
lay eggs because there are normal homes
for laying eggs are gonna be disruption
gonna have to go look under your leaves
yeah [ __ ] put on some gloves and just
clean them out of there just clean that
stuff out yeah if you want to give here
a hippie you want to give those bugs a
new home feel free to relocate them
[ __ ] burn feed them to the chickens I
bet your chicken to love you for that
hey how are you dealing with all the
rain because it has been raining every
day from about 6 o'clock to 9 o'clock
for the past week until today when it
was [ __ ] sweltering hot once again um
I keep my plants hollowed-out
so you know the the foliage on the
inside there isn't really any even and
veg I do that especially as it gets
later in bed but uh and you guys will
learn when I cut up your plants a little
bit that that helps I think a lot the
biggest thing the rain has been doing to
me is saving me from half of the water
my plants yeah
my main outdoor gardens in a depression
so a couple acres drained into it works
out real nice there's plenty of water
for the plants there you go yeah I have
yet to be out there so I just bought my
dad is a first dab rig so man yeah I got
to meet your dad at the wedding yeah I
was I I thought that was who he was he
didn't introduce himself it was loud he
just walked up shook my hand nodded at
me and gave me that like a man handshake
and a man not like you're welcome walked
away he didn't speak because it was so
loud at the where we were yeah I
wouldn't hurt him if he did speak and I
was like that's probably pops right he
he beams this energy of you [ __ ]
respect me I don't want to know what'll
happen if I don't because I have no
intention but he just looks like a man
that commands a little bit of respect
yeah he's uh yeah his younger days he
was um I've seen him do some stuff
mortal man can't do right yeah well I
watched him do immortal [ __ ] and out
drank everybody at the [ __ ] table
where he was and then stood up and
called us youngsters [ __ ] because we
couldn't keep up or what [ __ ] man I'm
falling out of my chair dab down over
here well I could use a dab in good fun
I had fun with you your whole family was
great this is awesome your wedding will
be talked about not only on this podcast
but in Colorado years to come I hope so
that's what I was shooting for with its
dad bar and a Colorado wedding that I'm
aware of
yeah me too so um it was funny the day
after the wedding I saw I still haven't
gotten to read it with the Washington
Post or the New York Times had an
article about a marijuana being a
welcome guest
Colorado and Washington weddings and I
was like damn Wow right absolutely
correct you know that we're usually at
weddings and this is just a cliche thing
there's usually one fight and it's
usually like a sisterly thing or some
[ __ ] oh my god I can't believe you you
know just get some it's a drunk family
member we didn't have that we actually
almost did but I derailed it so but yeah
no that's uh yeah it was very chill and
laid-back so good job to everybody for
getting home safely I watched everybody
at the end of the night search for rides
and all the people that were sober were
kind enough to get all you silly drunk
[ __ ] home yeah yeah we we party hardy
but uh we did you know try to be safe as
possible
yeah well drive him from there you had
to be safe all the cops everywhere she
goes
but no one yeah yeah all right guys
we're talking about aggro lesson we're
starting to bloom do you guys know what
you're looking for when you're going
into flower are you looking for your
males are you looking for your females
pretty similar hope so yeah if you're
drawing outdoors near us I really hope
so
purpose and then so quickly if you're
looking for females it looks like the
girl on a cotton ball when they start to
flower it looks like you're getting a
dandelion when they're making flowers if
you've got some balls and literally it
looks like you're growing a little
little pack of bananas yeah mr. green
they start green yeah and then they turn
into balls kill those plants unless
you're looking to make seeds and piss
off all your neighbors the girl we even
see the ball drops kill those male
plants or just kill them and if you have
clones call me so yeah you're looking
for the you want the dandelion looking
ones that's the easiest way to describe
it for sure honestly we gotta do you
guys got to read some books if you
aren't familiar with males and females
you got to catch up a little bit do a
little bit of reading that's kind of
what a grower needs to know that [ __ ]
you should be doing so I didn't find the
males pull the males and even feminized
seeds keep an eye on them yeah it's fit
feminizing is not a 100% we say 99% way
still there's
problems happen when you're making if
you use certain methods you're less
likely to get Femmes but if you use
certain methods then fims occur often
I've seen it at a big dispensary girl
grew out of like 250 feminized seeds
they had like four males pay attention
no no um and it all got wrecked and the
owner was quite pissed and you know it
was explained to him you know that 99%
do the math 250 plants yeah no he's got
a problem with feminized seeds right yes
I want to make sure that people hear you
dispensary owners in general don't like
growing from seed so yeah the ones that
do mad props to you guys yes man you get
such great [ __ ] when you grow if you
don't know what you're gonna proprietary
genetics and you don't have the clone
that everybody in your neighborhoods
growing everybody around here right now
has a damn blue dream clone flow-flow I
kind of like I give outflow to new
growers if you like I'm new and I need
to grow them like try this flow cup and
actually I think that's flow to cut I
don't really think that code we have is
flow I've always thought the exact same
things
there's somebody in Colorado that posted
on Facebook that they know that that's
flow data and then they actually got
that cut from Ed Rosenthal okay if
you're listening to this show please
tweet me or Facebook me you can go to
hydrogen etics or I grow culture on
Facebook or Twitter please because I
want to know more about the cut of flow
that goes around Colorado yeah there's a
cut called tangerine that is not tangi
it's to the tange which a man that's is
so confusing I think that is v'lo and
urban poison okay okay okay okay yeah
it's not Angie everyone calls it tange
and they called it the tange Tanjore the
tank tank for a little while around
there okay slow and urban poison crime
gang they remember a big full full
spread
um dispensary has about that strange way
back somebody near the Fort Collins area
made that one really is from what I know
yeah there's a lot of it's a problem
with the weed world because by the time
I give you a clone the story has changed
and then you give it to somebody else
and the story has totally changed and
then they pass it on and now it's not
even the same strain and it's being
hoarded or it's being hoard out for way
too much money it's not being grown to
its potential because it's not being
called what it is yeah so we're in the
stretch phase we're blooming we're
getting off track here it's cool ya know
it's cool that they seem to like the
listeners have responded man they like
it when I get all high and just talk
nice yeah they like it when I kind of go
off course cuz I ate a big ass edible Oh
guys I'm late I gotta tell you I felt
like [ __ ] for the whole next day though
eating that whole edible really took a
toll on my body I'm getting old as part
of what I'm trying to say I'm 35 now and
I think when I was 25 I probably could
have done it and not felt like [ __ ] the
next day but I had to go get some
kombucha and [ __ ] put myself back on
track but no disrespect to that edible
company I was not supposed to eat all of
it at once no so listen to that episode
I was you were yeah not at all you
weren't even supposed to eat half of
that yeah
why do they make this stuff so good
though it was delicious dinner or a
restaurant dessert I'd order that thing
you serve put some ice cream with it
it'd be delicious so since we're going
into flour we're starting to stretch a
little bit we're looking for the males
we're looking for hermaphrodites also if
it's question if it's weird keep a
really good eye on it lower inner
branches yeah that's a good spot to look
for hermes where you don't get as much
light straight on the top tube top plate
buds that's a common area too so get
those out of there the males in the
rooms get them out of there put them in
the fire pit
it gets be careful when you're throwing
away your trash if you live in a non
legal state that's something that I just
want to throw out there for you just
compost it
yeah composted if you can't feed it to
your chickens come on Jesse not all of
us have a farm
city folk here there's another there's
another podcast where one of the guys
has chickens I shot those guys out so we
could shut up - crunchy yeah weirdo me
dinner one time indirectly I was at an
event or at a party where he was the
chef and he made dinner for everybody on
props man good cookin he actually asked
me about my dietary needs cuz he saw
that I got dreadlocks he knew I was a
Rasta dietary restrictions and he was
respectful to that made a meal around
what I can and cannot eat always do that
when I perfect you with vegetarian for
this you don't know that yep appreciate
that guys respect your vegetarian
friends pressure don't make fun of them
that's just stupid yeah so stupid we
make funny back when you do it because
good telling me I'm stupid I don't even
know any good vegetarian jokes
oh yeah that's a classic one I got rare
all right
vegetarian let's feed our ganja plants
we're going into bloom so we can slowly
decrease the nitrogen and increase the
phosphorus and potassium if you're top
dressing you can switch your teas to the
more phosphorus and potassium based teas
for sure if you're using the light
granulated products that they sell in
the store you can go ahead and switch to
the bloom version of those products now
you don't have to keep using that veg
stuff yeah slowly switch that stuff
[Music]
still well I don't yeah assuming you've
only applied it one or two times
something like that it makes it look
just make sure you have nitrogen because
a lot of time those products are pretty
low on nitrogen okay on the blue side
maybe well actually when I feed my
indoor plants I don't switch the day
that I put them into flower I don't just
say they're in flower let's cut out all
the veg newts and go to just my bloom
schedule I kind of phase it out there's
like a week period and I also keep my
metal halide lights in for about 14 to
21 days to keep them short and stocky
and then when you switch them you really
see them they stay low and the buds
fatten up so that's yeah so just slowly
I like to phase out my veg into my bloom
feed is what I think I'm trying to say
yeah start that Mexican bat guano epsom
salts if you're using that it's a good
time to be fuller you know my last
foliar spray next weekend are Jamaican
bakkanna
jamaican there you go yeah it's one of
correct I think you said hi BK like some
companies have blended guano's with
different ek values so just you want a
high PK so any alfalfa meal with this
feed I love that stuff yeah I mean it's
a great time to go ahead and top dressed
so man alfalfa meal you know it's really
accessible nitrogen so what else he
putting in your tea right now some
Jamaican guano yeah alfalfa meal yep
molasses molasses all the time so Rocky
Mountain earthworm the factory or yeah
yeah he's got the bomb stuff I can't uh
I'm kind of stone I can't Rocky Mountain
uh I don't remember the name one company
I think is one okay yeah yeah if you
google Rocky Mountain worms you'll find
what we're talking about I've had my own
I've made my own worm castings before
and they didn't look as good as his do
so
it's all about what you feed those worms
for sure for sure ya know he's got a
real cool setup go check him out up in
springs that's a free shout out - we do
a lot of free shout outs for sure it's
good stuff though people groan it's not
all about business all the time some
mykos so you know there's several
different brands of OGT great white
shorty yeah zho if you use a botanic air
yeah the Orca stuff liquid that's half
dead yeah I know I always fear that
liquids are gonna wreak havoc on the
rest of my stuff yeah because you don't
know what preservative there is yeah
yeah and the powders you can sprinkle it
right near the root zone and yeah yeah
and see that it's on there and be happy
with that
yeah GT is available at Highgrove blah
blah for sure that stuff's awesome
that's what I'm in doubt of all that you
can I can see a difference when I feed
my plants that within 24 hours the next
light cycle 2 light cycles later I guess
when they come on their prey in their
honor
these are pointing straight up like yes
we can pray yeah they love that it
should be their slogan ya know that's
the OG T's the bomb a great white shark
is really good at getting rid of soil
based insects nice doesn't like I've
heard the crow Kashi does the same thing
too so well doing some experiments with
that right now so yeah Jesse mentioned
before we were recorded that he got some
grow Kashi if you guys aren't paying
attention to the crow Kashi its
probiotics big love to the probiotic
farmers alliance what up gage green and
all the guys running the probiotic
farmers alliance key play and I don't
know if I should use Mike's real name
but what's up Mike
those guys are inspiring people ask
where I get a lot of my inspiration and
a lot of my ideas and [ __ ] a lot of it
currently comes from gage that's who I'm
on now guys well there was a time war
was also a force yeah yeah I didn't know
soma I had no idea what that was and
then a friend of mine was like you
remind me of soma and I googled it and I
was like that could be my father
[ __ ] whoever told you that knows all
about the vibe is more than five someone
talks about mimetics and I'm really big
on the mimetics if we're about more
about that later that's the like the
vibes so cool always good to be going so
cool for a little while not to be a
hater I lost interest when it got
dramatic with him and miss Jill on the
weed nerd show that's when I fell off
sorry that's where I lost interest and
then I've always been a big fan of Jorge
and Ed Rosenthal for sure all that stuff
but I like reading yeah lately gage
dream has been one of the best reader I
was it I was a Cali connection fanboy
for a little while and pretty decent
friends with swerve and had a mil so
we're sure dude that's that's a good
company right there you work hard you
get paid good they were kind enough to
let us hang out in their booth for a
4:20 at the Cannabis Cup bonds 4:20 at
4:20 so everyone else is crowded couch
taking a dad with a DeMille so anyway I
was at the Cannabis Cup anyone who got a
couch anywhere was chilling that was a
hot cup yeah can't wait for 4/20 again
this year I hear big things are coming I
thought two years ago was crowded but it
was worked chaotic two years ago for
sure though on that year when you
couldn't walk through yeah yeah Ali was
ridiculous big shot it's the High Times
crew Danny Danko Bobby black Nico I'm
gonna miss a lot because a lot of you
guys mr. Dan's got you guys for coming
to Colorado and doing a huge-ass even
that's a lot of work you guys look like
you're going [ __ ] crazy when you come
here and do it running around all
chaotic for sure
yeah and Danny Day Cole take time to
talk to you I walked by basically I said
the same thing and he turned around and
shook my hand and talked to me and
there's gonna he didn't need to do that
he was busy you know yeah I had erupted
them right in the middle of conversation
was a hey thanks for recording freely
dude you haven't put out a podcast in
over a month
yeah we were free weed I'm trying to
fill your gap dude I'm trying to fill
your gap for you that's
I'm never gonna say that feeling Dani
Dinkas gap there's a podcast called free
weed hosted by Dani Danko and Mike
Hughes it's a high times production I'm
not sponsored by them in any way I just
have respect for people Dan Evancho and
the free weed podcast are actually part
of what inspired this show for sure I
like to do things my way and I kind of
combined a lot of my favorite people
shows and do my own thing here and we
have the iGrow culture podcast what's up
Mike Hughes - yeah how I mentioned I
made sure to say Mike it's love I feel
bad for the for Mike yeah he should be
free weed with Danny and Mike they're
mr. Danny just kidding just kidding well
tag Danny Danko in this episode I'm not
sure if I follow my cues but we'll tag
him also papers jesse grows it's Rasta
Jeff and Jesse grows said your full name
on the other podcast
sorry it's gotten to the point I don't
really give a [ __ ] I tried to keep my
identity kind of separate from the
Huayra genetics agro culture stuff but
everybody knows it's Rasta yeah I threw
the first cannabis cup people took
pictures with me and I like look I'm
getting high with I read genetics and I
was like well they know one the [ __ ]
year ridiculously tall white Devils game
over I remember when we first met you
told me something about that and then
within like a few weeks you're like try
to keep it on the down-low man yeah
after the concert I went and sub cool is
there with packs of seeds in his hand
like what's up I'm so cool here seeds I
was like I don't have [ __ ] to worry
about like yeah yeah he doesn't even
live in this state and yeah changed my
whole outlook on things for sure alright
guys we've talked a little bit about
outdoor growing we're starting to bloom
I told you how to find your males your
hermaphrodites get those out of there we
told you to cut clones make sure you cut
clones you don't want to grow some [ __ ]
and then be like this is my best strain
ever
it's gone I've done that actually grew a
strain I don't know if I even want to
say the name Kevin if you're listening
it was that uh that strain that you and
pops loved I couldn't get it to root
those clones would not take roots for
the life of me so it got away I've got
another pack of those seeds we'll see if
that works
you got to stop topping but you can
super crop and train your stuff we were
talking about what Jesse puts in I try
to he doesn't realize I'm trying to fish
out what he's putting in his tea cuz he
doesn't like to tell us he doesn't slow
ly pry it out of him we got molasses we
got how foul Emil we got guano
we got worm castings we got mykos are
you using any sort of seek help right
now
yeah kelp yeah dr. Neptune stuff like a
couple cups yeah and now it's flower
time so blood meal bone meal any of that
stuff yet I've never put any in that
stuff oh you don't like slaughterhouse
products well no I use it I've never put
it in a tea but top dressing yeah okay I
do have an issue with slaughterhouse
products but I also have a [ __ ] ton of
slaughterhouse properties so you're a
farmer and you understand yeah you
balance it out yeah I mean there's
nothing wrong with blood mills just like
where well I mean I guess the argument
could be made that there is something
wrong with it but the biggest thing with
commercial blood mills we don't know
where it came from and you know those
very least that's my big issue with it
and those accounts were fed [ __ ] that I
probably highly disapprove of so yeah
and don't want to put into my body part
of why I'm a vegetarian is because the
way they treat cows yeah for sure
there's no need to contribute to that in
my opinion in general I don't really
like eating beef and I can't stand
ground beef it's one of the most
disgusting things I can that's the most
questionable meat yeah what I hate when
I'm working and in a hurry
yeah as a farmer and a grower are you
bothered by like fast-food joints by
seeing what people are eating yeah
prostates any kind of processed meat and
I'm just as guilty of it
I try hard when I get busy in life you
know it's just it's hard to cook and
it's easy to drive through drive through
and but yeah that's that's why this
country so fat that's why we have cancer
that's everything it's just yeah I agree
I have a huge issue with all that stuff
you know we paid people will pay top
dollar for their booze pay top dollar
for their herb but then spend ninety
nine cents on the [ __ ] cheeseburger
yeah yeah those books on yourself guys
yeah cancer is expensive later just life
just cook at home that's good for
relationships cook with friends eat with
friends eat with you know your wife your
girlfriend your kids it's just you know
it's just good cook with friends for
relationships that's the sound advice
from Jesse you learned some [ __ ] on
accident today you didn't think that was
coming alright we've done 30 minutes man
you got anything else you want to add it
the girl lesson before we kind of start
wrapping it up a little D vegging go
ahead pull up the bottoms of the plants
so clip off any shape their legs shave
their legs that's make them sexy all
that bottom stuff is gonna be crap and
larf and it's gonna kind of take away
from the top of your plant so take that
bottom the little sucker leaves you can
tell what I'm talking about if it's not
making and you can do this all the way
up to like three or four weeks into
bloom if you keep doing it yeah yeah
just yeah is in the way you'll know well
if he doesn't look like it's gonna be a
bud worth trimming take it off it
doesn't need to be there and throw it
away don't just throw it on the ground I
see a lot of you guys cut your leaves
off throw them on the ground do that
reuse it in some way
yeah I've been oh mulching decimals
there real quick and mulch it up a
little bit a little off alpha
some old hay that we had laying around
actually I think it was straw whatever
all the city fun yeah that's the same
[ __ ] some compost and you know just
helps hold water it's getting into the
hot time of year and normally of work
monsoon season right now apparently but
you know this other people in other
parts of the country enos bowls turnips
good and it's also a great way to get
rid of all your green waste so you know
that's it it's just a big ole cycle if
you're juicing you could juice your
cannabis leaves if you haven't been
spraying [ __ ] on them if you've put gym
oil or some chemicals do not do some
please don't if you're if your leaves
are clean go ahead and juice those and
taste that up yeah so we're mulching now
you have taught us a lot of stuff
everyone's gonna move to the country and
abandon the city and all move out to the
middle of nowhere to start these organic
small not even large scale just small
scale organic ganja farms yeah you don't
have to do much I mean just do your part
draw your own food or on Erb get some
chickens make your own eggs you know I
really try not to eat eggs if you like
it's just not that just seems funky to
me I can't eat but grocery store eggs if
yes i kind of where i'm headed if i had
chickens bro we'd eat eggs every day
hey so i get two or three eggs from the
chickens and we do it like the your
shirt you were in there you know the
that yellow it's like grocery store
yellow and their oranges like what my
eggs look like wow you know that's
probably ten times the nutrients in
there yeah man all state they have a
flavor yeah oh you just think except
flavor too do you have good ones so you
have a good farm-fresh egg and I have my
chickens in the city too so we haven't
met the farm too but I also have
chickens in my backyard so you can have
chickens over there yeah cool yeah I
don't know you could do that can have
info you can have don't quote me on this
but I think it's six or seven
no encroachment which means you know you
can't build it right next to your
chicken pin right next to your fence
it's got to be five feet from a property
line
no roosters so yeah and and they can't
be a nuisance which you know takes a
while to develop a nuisance I have one
that I'm about ready to kill I can't
believe none of my neighbors have called
it wakes me up too early I'm like you're
next [ __ ] chicken noodle soup awesome I
want to get broke congratulations we'll
quit talking about the wedding on the
show it was so much fun guys enjoy talk
about it so much birdies so
congratulations to your wife also thank
you I don't know if she listens but I
hope you do burn usually I forced her to
she always laughs at me for listening to
myself yeah you're getting really good
at this so I'm looking forward to more
episodes because your start getting
comfortable what do you think you come
back about two or three weeks and we
start kicking into flour for sure yeah
I'll give you a call soon as like I
guess some good bud set so yeah sounds
good to me yeah so guys we're gonna take
some dabs go check out high Gro Denver
comm I think is the website yes yeah go
look at that while we take some dabs and
I'll be back to wrap up the show in just
a minute
dude thanks again for coming on we look
forward to back yes
[Music]
coming up in future episode I plan to
have a little debate on not a debate but
a discussion a friendly discussion on
the classic question of clone vs. seed
and also we'll have a little subtopic of
feminized versus regular seeds and a lot
of people are opposed to feminized seeds
so we can talk a little bit about that
clear up some myths give some people
some information now the show's over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for hydro culture review
section give us a five star rating after
that type in the comment let me know
what you think of the show and I will
read your comments on a future podcast
you can also leave your comments on
stitcher and I'll read those comments
too it's a little harder to get to those
comments but I will read them I search
for them don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher swell a.m.
and also each and every episode is
archived and I read genetics Colorado
calm fiction follow us on you can follow
us on Instagram Twitter Facebook make
sure you check out at hydro culture on
Instagram and Twitter follow us on
Facebook at agriculture you can email me
hydra culture at hotmail.com
you want to see some awesome cannabis
photography you can always check out at
ira genetics on instagram
think that's all I got for you guys this
episode so uh number 25 is coming up
make sure you listen to 25 it'll work to
your benefit
[Music]
shout out to my ninja Spence
shout out to DJ Nick UT shout out to
Peter and Jaden get off the couch you
lazy [ __ ] sakes listen you guys take a
fat dab hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 24 of the
iGrow culture podcast glad to be back
with you in this episode Jesse and
Spence join us for conversation about
seeds and clones but first I owe a huge
shout out to Terp ex and the grimy
Gatsby and of course this podcast is
brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies dot-com 4-gauge green genetics
La Plata Labs Sin City rare dankness
mile high can adventure I read genetics
and many more trusted brands nature's
green remedies is running a special for
our podcast listeners type in coupon
code Rasta Jeff it's capital R asta
capital je FF all one word Rasta Jeff
for 15% off any order and you always get
free shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com also this podcast is brought to
you by high Gro indoor growing supplies
high grow indoor growing supplies has
two locations to serve Colorado visit
the Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street
unit F or stop by the new pub location
at 618 East 4th Street in Pueblo
Colorado check out hydro for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies don't forget to check out
www.hsn.com and Rodolfo 57 gallon pots
worth of soil if you need it delivered
at 600 bucks anywhere in Colorado so if
you want more information contact high
grow Denver and they'll get you all
taken care of
also this show is brought to you by oil
slick oil slick tools to help you
concentrate check out oil slick Pat comm
for more information make sure you
follow oil slick on twitter fine
at oil slick pad and send them a tweet
to let them know you're listening to the
iGrow culture podcast also big respect
to tree hugger comm this episode is
brought to you in part by tree hugger
comm live music lifestyle magazine check
out tree hugger comm for concert
festival news and reviews WWE Eggert
comm much respect for to all of our
sponsors for making the show possible
a couple people are asking about
sponsoring the show if you're interested
in being a sponsor of the I grow culture
podcast please contact me it's hydro
culture at hotmail.com and we'll get you
all taken care of so in this episode
Spence and Jessi drop by we had a little
conversation about seeds versus clones
and we also talked a little bit about
feminized seeds and Otto flower seeds
none of us really seem to like Otto
flower seeds but we did talk about one
very useful application so we'll go
ahead and get right to that we did get a
little dab down so if we got off-track
and you have questions please please
contact me online somehow call me text
me tweet me Facebook me Instagram me I'm
sure you know all that contact
information by now it's in the show
notes agriculture at hotmail.com anti
grow culture on twitter and or instagram
you can do I read genetics at
hotmail.com please do check out at I
read genetics on Instagram I post a lot
of great pictures there so without any
further ado let's go get to the
conversation with Jesse Spence and
myself check it out
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen we are back I've
got my homie Jesse Jesse grows on
Instagram and Twitter and also we guys
he goes on Twitter I look for you
brothers another person called Jesse
grows on Twitter it could be like your
your German clone or something be just
like also with us over here on the
microphone is our buddy Spence what up
Spence what up guys
Spencer's got his microphone
strategically placed so that he can i
phone it up on the table and talk and
talk at the same time he's got the
elbows out he's chillin it up we've had
some fat dabs today what did you give me
a dab of a minute ago that live resident
what was that Yeti og oh yeah
okay that's why I loved it we've been
smoking on that yet EOG around here for
a couple of weeks big ups to the the
people making the live resident happen
we appreciate it there's a whole chain
of people to make that happen it's not
one or two people it's a big [ __ ]
chain-of-command
I appreciate that [ __ ] very much chillin
he told me what you did today I think
it's [ __ ] funny we won't talk about
that on the show
[Music]
Jesse Doug [ __ ] fence post holes all
day so he's lively he's over her hyper
not at all I think we all took fat dabs
over here that was a largest a but I've
ever seen Jesse voluntarily take on his
own
I've seen people give him a dab that bit
but I've never seen a bit I've been
practicing the last few weeks what's the
music up for you guys
sorry turned it down way so low we
couldn't hear it nice well we're here to
gather and talk about the subject of
hand which today I decided we want to
talk about clones versus seeds and maybe
we'll do a little bit of talking about
feminized seeds and we might talk a
little bit briefly briefly about Auto
flowers I got one thing I wanted to
mention in there this mix that I'm
playing really has a lot of volume jumps
in the background so I apologize that
it's so jumpy you listening to DJ
nicotine in the background again I got
to give them a shout out shout out DJ
nicotine thanks for let me play your
music that's awesome so everybody at
this table is a pretty damn experienced
grower you got I'd call myself a breeder
Jesse's a pollen chucker maybe a breeder
I don't know if you'd call himself a
breeder yet more practice
Spence is a hell of a grower we had some
stuff tested and Spence's tested higher
than all of my stuff and he grew
somebody else's strain do you remember
what the numbers were bro um Capleton
was 20% there's a Girl Scout cookie
cross which was creepy OG and Girl Scout
it was 25 maybe 24 probably 24 Ryan's
Rhyno 100% sativa 25% and then form
scout or reformed Girl Scout cookies
tested at right around 27 so this guy
crushed it he had some great great tests
my veganic lemon jeffery tested right
around 24 probably ever smoked well
thank you how much have you got ik weet
have you smoked do you know um I've
smoked some I smoked some from there's a
place in the springs I think it's Valley
actual mystics they say lit that's
really the only really place and then I
tried some of buds and roses so mine
stood up to Kyle kushman oh definitely
definitely
you have a thing for sativas and not a
lot of people like sativas but I like
the you know the citrusy really high
highs like take more time to grow like a
sativa does he let you get more out of
it it's nothing but the longer the
better in my opinion for sure
depending on your technique yeah yeah
guys quit cutting your plants down too
early
alright so I was just and Jesse to give
him some credit in the game he won the
Pueblo super Blood Bowl and they gave
him hell a huge compliments if you guys
listened to past episodes we talked
about that the judges of the super Blood
Bowl said that Jesse strains stood out
in flavor aroma taste in affect overall
without a doubt he was the hands-down
winner the freakin champ right yes yes
grape OG hell of a strain too I took
some
of it today we'll see what atlases so
these guys are we're all experienced
growers here I'm of course the breeder
from Ira genetics so I know what I'm
doing
we're gonna talk a little bit about
clones and seeds do you guys do you have
a preference Jesse from going growing
from clone or seed has more to do with
the admission I guess of you know
whatever particular round but I'd grow
from seed if that was you know all I
could do from now on okay so if you're
gonna I guess a better question would be
if you're gonna set up a giant warehouse
not a giant what if I give you 20 lights
and I was 20 flowering lights and it's
all yours you're gonna start brand new
would you grow from clones receipts at
that point all right how about you
Spence if you had 20 lights to play with
if I had it to play with I'd probably
take like two lights
that's bad scale you want something
that's proven give you what you want
that's a perfect segue into what I was
gonna say clones the pros of clones are
that you know you've got females those
have been ran and tested so if you've
got a clone I'll talk a little bit about
a clone and give some setup for what
they are cuz people are new listeners a
clone is a cutting taken from a plant a
mother plant that you hopefully have ran
before and flowered out and you know
that that's some good [ __ ] or someone
else or someone else has when your
trusted bros like Spencer Jesse at the
table if they give me a clue I
definitely appreciate it trust it I
don't usually get dispensary clones and
stuff that are mediocre most of the time
so you know you're getting it from but
usually it's a reliable crop it's a
female you're familiar with it somebody
in the crew has grown it we can say that
takes eight weeks that takes nine weeks
that takes ten weeks or be careful
because that [ __ ] might herm if you
over nitrogen it you know there there's
things we know so that's one of the
super super pros of a clone
we know the growth patterns we know if
we need to top it we know if we need to
train it a little bit we know how tall
it's gonna get I know that the Sour
Diesel could I've got if you let it grow
more than two feet tall and veg it's
gonna be eight feet tall and flower and
I know that from we've grown it several
times I grew that one time
and I'll learn yeah you learnt quick on
that [ __ ] tickling your lights and then
you know what to feed it also because
you know how long it's gonna take you
know when to begin flushing you know
when it's gonna be done
the cons of clones this is why I was
asking about the giant warehouse clones
are where you get most of your damn bugs
I think when some one of your buddies
tries to give you a sweet cut a Sour
Diesel and you get it to your garden and
your irresponsible and it's partly your
responsibility to quarantine but
sometimes you fail yourself just like
that guy did and you end up with spider
mites the feared hamper us at my inner
weed garden right now those things will
take down your entire crop in two days I
had a friend told me he had those he's
like you want to see them ever get those
just start over yeah fire is the cure
actually I have something I'm
experimenting with a product I don't
know if I've mentioned it on the show
because I don't want to say anything
until I'm familiar with it it seems to
kill everything unfortunately if you do
it wrong it will kill everything yeah I
volunteered a few plants and I did a few
different applications and a couple of
them but if I were to do it right I feel
like it'll work well so I'm gonna learn
it cool that's gonna make you hard to
hear Jessie's afraid of the microphone
[Music]
that's good if you guys were wondering
what that furry sound is it's music in
the background it's not just on the
microphone so we get our bugs our
problems our diseases our pathogens
powdery mildew comes from clones seeds
do not carry bugs they do not carry
diseases they do not carry pathogens
something about a clone if I if I grow a
pack of seeds and I pick the keeper out
of that so you grow ten seeds there'd be
different phenotypes in there hopefully
you find that one that's stellar maybe
my opinion of that stellar plant is way
different than Spence's opinion or way
different than Jesse's opinion or the
other guy growing or so you like the
ability to pick my own which is a
benefit of the seed and a guard of the
clone
and maybe my grouse style or what I'm
looking for is way different than what
you guys are looking for yeah when you
get a ten pack of seeds how many keepers
do you hope to find out of those do you
hope for that just water are you looking
for all ten of I usually um I just look
for differences throughout because some
of them depending on what you're you
know what kind of seeds are popping
you'll find differences and whatnot so I
usually try to keep three just so I have
a you know if I have three plants that
don't all look the same maybe you know I
just want a better chance of finding
something yes not as or that's better
than one of the other it's good that you
say three in my opinion because usually
I find the one that looks like if you're
crossing male and a female plant I like
to find the male like the one that looks
like the male the momma looks like the
female and then that one that's a hybrid
of the two and that's usually good good
way to do it and then smoke all those
get them tested do what you can have the
crew smoke them make shatter out of them
make live resin out of them see what
happens to all that stuff to him a long
time cure him a long time that's
something I failed at when I was a new
grower I would take that stuff and as
soon as it was dry enough to start
smoking it start smoking it up see which
was my favorite I'm sure I got rid of a
few keepers I just didn't even know yeah
man yeah yeah so I guess that leads us
into seeds a little bit when you buy a
ten pack of seeds I really like that
variation so you buy a ten pack you pop
them sometimes there's [ __ ] seven
males numbers game like bingo it is like
bingo so hopefully you get that one good
one so hopefully get some five five
males five females is usually what I
hope for somewhere in that area
oh you hope to get one that you can spot
right away that you're like and we got
to call that [ __ ] and you got those
four to work with and like Spence said
you get three so that's where you find
new stuff that's one of the pros of
growing from seed you find all that new
stuff and there's something I thought
about earlier everything we're growing
came from seed in the first adventure
nothing down the road the way it's
supposed to be yeah yeah we couldn't
have a plan without the seed we've
nobody took a clone of OG Kush yeah
everyone you know keeps growing from
Cologne
there are very bad consequences to that
so what could happen big major companies
could maintain control of it have the
seed stock similar to some ornamental
flowers that I can't quote species of or
anything like that but ok I know it's
really hard to find like genuine seed of
sunflowers yeah and a lot of the
vegetables you can only find specific
seeds ok damn see so we it there you go
more beneficial to grow from seed or a
benefit of growing from seed or they'll
just start so and only for thy seed
that's something is a breeder I try to
pay attention to I try to make and you
guys have probably noticed I've been
pulling out a lot more reg seeds lately
yeah we got to have reg seeds because it
you got to have the males to keep the
breeding alive or it's gonna get stale
f1 hybrids are where it's at hey guys if
you're breeding please throw away the
[ __ ] there's gonna be some stuff
that comes out of your breeding projects
that is not worth three breeding or
giving out those seeds just toss those
cuz you're polluting the gene pool
you're making it weak you're making a
bunch of runts and mutants and you're
[ __ ] it up just get rid all that Nani
wheat star non-elite stuff yeah all the
poser stuff and just kill it just kill
it we can breed more seems more common I
definitely give props to the people who
actually try their own seeds like if you
if you produce some seeds actually grow
it or you give it to people for cetera
give a bunch of it away all so that
other people can so you can see what
Nancy bud well shout out to Nancy bud
well under LEDs I'm not even a big fan
of LEDs and she is killing it yeah yeah
yeah I'm actually like that you say that
you keep saying good [ __ ] to make more
good [ __ ] to talk about I'm growing the
night nurse right now looks stellar
there's one that looks really grateful
dog dominant but smells like Tora Bora
right I hope so I hope so I need some
good CBD medicine so to cloud the seeds
to get new stuff like we're talking
about you get to do that phenotype line
that's uh that's essentially when you
pop a pack of seeds they call it mapping
or searching or hunting sub cool calls
up something different I forgot what
even
but it's a phyno hunt in this group is
what we call it you run as many seeds as
you can get up one strain if you can do
20 of them do 20 that's awesome 25 of
something is cool if you've only got a
10 or a 6-pack or a 5 pack that works
too just work on your scale but the more
the better because that gives you you
can see what that strains potential is
and you know what you're looking for a
little better and you can get that one
like I know what I want out of a
grateful dog pack of beans you may want
something totally different out of a
pack of dog beans and we'll find it by
doing that phyno huh and that's fun to
me run it down seeing the variations and
as a breeder I love seeing the
variations from my creations that's a
lot of fun if we're growing clones we're
all grown the same [ __ ] there's a blue
dream cut going around this town right
now going around Colorado I don't think
it's just this town I think it is just
Colorado in general that like every time
I see somebody post a picture of blue
dreams like dear God
[Music]
conditions and she'll give you some
product I can pull 6 ounces out of a 7
gallon pot with four of them perlite so
that's a pound and a half of herb come
get your stuff it's just terrible no we
love the Andes Blue Dream I didn't mean
call terrible how about the the cons of
growing from seed some people are not
good at spotting males that's the main
problem yeah I would I mean if you're a
beginner grower you know sometimes you
don't even know like I know people that
have seen male plants and like is there
ever gonna be flowers from there and
it's like no these are two completely
different things and I just think it's
about paying attention if you pay
attention there's there's you've gotta
see ya read a book the book yet every
grow book has a picture of a male and a
female right next to each other yep yep
so yeah spot your males what about
mutants sometimes you get that crazy
mutant [ __ ] they're fun they're funky
a mutant is a person or than shout out
to Kim dog and if you write in CHEM dog
its CH e md OG d OG he corrected us it's
do ji kim dog are used to have a dog
named that that's pretty awesome nope no
do gog uh my buddy Ryan had a dog named
do gene he was a cool ass dog cool dog
what's up guys I miss you haven't seen
you guys a long time you don't listen to
the show but still thinking about you
selection time when you're drawn from
seeds there is always that Fino hunt
when you're going from clones at first
crop you're gonna grow that's blue dream
you're cool you got all the blue dream
you could handle when you're running
from seed you got to run a crop to find
what you're even messing with and then
run a crop to keep again of the ones you
like right and then if you need to
eliminate more then you're gonna run
again and again and narrow it down yep
so uh and now hopefully you take clones
like I said on another episode take
clones of everything you ever grow
before it's in flower right before you
put it in flower take some clones that
way you know those clones are gonna root
and if you don't have clones you can try
again like give yourself a chance plan
ahead plan ahead when you're growing
it's always it's always beneficial give
yourself the advantage yes
yeah the advantage the heads up for
yourself is I don't put yourself behind
because once you're behind and growing
you're behind and growing and that
probably means your plants are stressed
out yeah if you're stressed they are
[Music]
so the concept seeds if you need
you gotta learn each phenotype like when
you find those phenotypes you gotta
learn them you gotta learn it's like
having three different girlfriends if
you found three keepers one's gonna like
a lot of nitrogen one's gonna get mad at
too much nitrogen one's gonna be really
picky one's gonna be really easy it's
gonna butt out one's gonna taste real
good you can all have to learn each
phenotype one may go a little longer one
may come down a little sooner one may
need to be topped one may climb up into
the [ __ ] lights real high you're
gonna learn all that stuff the con of
course that comes with that is wasted
space so if you're a cash crop er the
seeds that kind of messes you up but
what about fem seeds I've seen it I mean
I've grown thin they take away the worry
about having a male there are still
chances where you get some funky stuff
but you just gotta still pay attention
I've made some funky stuff you've grown
some funky stuff for me that uh I'm not
even gonna say the strain to discourage
anybody but because I'm seeing excellent
types coming out I've got some
downstairs it looks normally spin screw
one that shot out it was shot at a stick
with a gigantic leaf the size of bigger
than my hand and then another stick and
then like normal size leaves because I
just looked away as like seeing a car
wreck do you look for a minute reattach
amputee arm but it was cool I like
sometimes I like things like that you
know if it's gonna be a female I'm the
type of girl where I'll give it a chance
if it doesn't if it doesn't work it
doesn't work yeah there's always more
seeds to plant there are always more
seeds yeah don't be afraid to call
something and like if you guys have
something that is a level eight
let's work fun getting you guys a level
10 oh yeah get you some good seeds
I know seeds are expensive and we just
talked like he could just pop more but
it's well worth it and if you're growing
herb you should be doing all right you
should at least be able to afford a pack
of seeds after the harvest
so I mentioned fem seeds fem seeds just
a quick little let's read Ratan the
background there that got my attention
we're gonna turn the music we're gonna
dance around like wookies for a second
[Music]
take that with us guys we got some
really cool ass people in the room today
I'm really honored to have these guys as
guests I got some acid cookies he didn't
that was a joke actually battery yes
yeah out of your way
which ricky gone for spence do it you
can hit the hit em with a
highly-educated titanium dilma snail
there's some stuff in the works with
highly-educated right now
there's that classic reggae airhorn
gotta love it
I know we're doing a podcast now
suddenly we're taking a break and
Abigail's work I hope you're taking it
down while I am - that only be right
grab that beer Rick just take a DAB with
us we'll have a three rig session there
aren't three torches but we'll make it
happen
that's Sumpter packs if you want that a
little there's some live over there
yeah we're spoiled here in Colorado if
we're in Texas this table would equal
life in prison and you're black so if n
stays
hey you won't catch me there
[Music]
the best thing about Texas is seeing the
state line in your rear-view I won't I
don't have a reason to go to Texas or a
reason to hate on Texas really but I
don't have a gun some food and people
down there know how to party you know
and I've got some good friends that are
from Texas and they're actually all good
people so they die out we'll tap on the
thing they'll work again
[Music]
headphones working bro cool yeah if you
guys are buying gear for the podcast
never buy a livewire Solutions headphone
for channel headphone amplifiers this is
the third one I've gotten dude and I
know you're like why'd you get a third
one because if you go to Guitar Center
with it you yell at them they keep just
giving you a fresh one so steep you're
using it your phone is probably the only
thing without how-to hash on it up until
now pretty much my life everything is
all sticky I wanted to call the
recording studio the sticky knob studios
that part of the show was brought to you
by oil slick tools to help you
concentrate I just set my stuff down on
this fancy oil slick pad here I'm not
gonna get any sticky rings on my table
that's awesome it's a really nice oil
slick better yeah don't you don't you
work in a hydro shop what were they
called again hi Jesse does a lot of
lifting and moving so all the
organization and stuff give shoutouts to
Jesse working in the [ __ ] it's August
9th I want to give a quick shout out to
Jerry Garcia oh yeah much love much
respect Jerry Garcia Jerry changed my
life dude I never got to see Jerry live
but the music of the Grateful Dead and
the culture of the Grateful Dead are
definitely in my heart that is big part
of my world so we'll get back to the
point here podcast time feminised seeds
always females most of the time I'll say
99% of the time females Jesse told us a
story before about a dispensary owner
running 200 and something feminized
seeds and having four males yeah perfect
math [ __ ] up everything yep yeah did
you get a bunch of seeds you bring go
blank
your house in your [ __ ] balance
clicks you just went we do you get a
bunch of seats from that run man and
then they tried to sell them to you no I
do and the problem with FEM seeds me
being a feminized seed maker I know this
is the big problem you don't know you've
got a problem until like week 7 or week
8 when you've already invested a lot of
time into that plant so if you're
running fin seeds my advice and this is
what I do I flower them little I run
them in a 3 gallon pot I bedroom for
very minimal time until I can take 3
cuts off of them
and once they're all big enough for
three cuts I flower about the first time
to find out what I've got and then you
can find out if you've got trouble or if
you've got gold
so go early with the fins if you can
just to find out I would do that with
any plant I've had some some fire seeds
from Tim that's an odd noise you don't
hear that that could be Spencer's phone
somebody was growing hops that [ __ ] was
tight on your phone yeah growing hops
yeah it looked like weed there it's
related to wheat that's like the cousin
just like fine you clamp that's my [ __ ]
hops I could say that Smith said I could
say that I can't believe way to send
them on the podcast though working well
I can kind of hear now I can really hear
I have a beer making friend and we had a
serious conversation last night about
making marijuana zero I was I don't
drink but I would try one of those yeah
just to see I drink a marijuana beer one
Spence and I might split it yeah I get I
get a little turn off one beer we were
talking about like a really small recipe
so
and then you could ferment that beer in
your grow room and use your weed beer
co2 to enhance your ganja plants there
yeah would that be a little sacrilegious
cannibalistic almost fermenting brothers
all right shout out to beer I miss you
beer I haven't had a beer in a long long
time I'm better off without it you know
I haven't had a beer since I got my very
first medical marijuana card I was like
you know I need to drink I got the car
let's smoke all the herb I want nice
trade off with myself my dad kind of
sorted it's the same thing he still
drinks occasionally shout out to mr.
Wynn if you're gonna listen in to the
show man what's up bro
it's me he's cool ass dude cool ass dude
so we're kind of rant about FEM seeds a
little bit FEM seeds I've noticed and
you might you guys I don't know if
you've paid enough attention because I'm
looking more on the breeder FEM C's are
always a closer representation of the
parents I have found you don't get as
much like when we run gages F wands
there's not there's not as much
variation right FEM seeds are more
uniform they're closer they look a lot
alike when we run gages F ones we never
know what we're gonna get a ten-pack
varies so much unless it was a spur era
those were awesome do you suppose that's
because they are supposedly missing the
male chromosomes that and you're not
introducing it feels like when you're
bringing out the F ones I feel like
you're getting a lot of recessive traits
and you're just not bringing it could be
because of the male chromosomes are
missing but it feels like you're not
going back as far in the lineage they
forgot who their grandparents were
somehow just by selfing them it's what
it feels like and I'm also doing a lot
of selfing of one plant and using it to
pollinate the same strain so those are
starting to come out I've done that I'm
on the it would its inbred but it's kind
of an f3 is what level I'm at and
there's a mess it read yeah The Grateful
dog has three of they are almost all
looking the same by now oh nice yeah I
have no idea
well thank you thank you that's a dang
strain by the way yes that's the one
that put me on the map honestly shut up
the callee connection and swerve because
just shout-out to those guys they did me
a favor
so shoutout yeah I was gonna actually
bring up in this conversation that uh
there's so many s ones and F ones out
there and you know we were talking about
say protecting the lineage and
everything and you can't really do that
with F once s ones so yeah you got f3 f3
you know DJ short says f2 is crucial
really that's where a lot of stuff is
really where you got to pay attention
cuz I've [ __ ] up the f 2s I've been
like oh no I used the ride chose the
wrong the wrong f1 to know it to that
and it was like no that's not I got to
go find a different male out of this mix
because this is now or a different
female and try this again for sure you
just have to go back you have to keep
seeds of each one and label them what
they were like this is the say golden go
times day breaker this is the first run
and make sure that those are legit and
then find it good I want to find a
golden goat dominant one out of there
and hit it again with the day breaker
male and I'm hoping to make it look a
lot like day breaker it's smell like
gold and go have the goats the go bigger
but if it doesn't I could just have to
back up again and go find another female
to use and just keep yeah eventually
I'll ditch a project if I have to go
back too many times twice second time
I'm like yeah that obviously doesn't
want to do what I want it to do out of
so many seeds you should get what you
want the first or second first or second
try oh yeah the Depot dug straight ahead
or have I had to do it three times
before I was too happy with it the first
time there you go they continued from
there yeah dudes light leaks and stuff
like that no man yeah and something in
me says if it doesn't work the first
time or the second time I'm probably not
gonna get what I want I keep cutting oh
geez II got a little too much sorry
here's a random this is kind of off
topic but on topic how do you guys feel
have you seen where Arion goes to places
are in from greenhouse seeds they travel
to places and get land race genetics
from I'll say Jamaica and they went to
like
they went to somewhere in India Nepal or
somewhere like that I don't pay enough
attention I just have to watch things
quickly while I'm trimmin so they go
these places and they get their land
raise seeds and so now our Ian's got all
land races from everywhere but in
exchange he leaves them a handful of
wrecks eat fancy pens and rags but he
gives them handfuls of seeds to grow and
he tells them what they are but now
those land races are gone and he just
made off with the last but the last of
the land raised seeds introducing
hybrids and modern and developed world
genetics into fragile places that have
land race genetics like that is a that's
kind of a douchebag thing to do it's the
same thing is releasing [ __ ] animals
that are not from that area insects that
are not from that or they're gonna wreak
havoc on [ __ ] and destroy the ecosystem
that's already there just the balance
they're asking all the farmers to grow
some GMO corn yeah that's he's kind of
doing the same thing to them yeah yeah
you guys think about that when you're uh
when you're doing what you're doing
we've gotta think about the effects that
you're having like the ripples that you
make in your life cuz little stuff makes
big big ripples what's that uh saying
about a butterfly in the rainforest
denim on to somewhere else yeah yeah if
there's a tidal wave in China somewhere
something like that happens all right so
that was a random rant on the pros and
cons of seeds so I guess the it's still
I think they're equal in my opinion I
think there's benefits of both there's a
reason to run seeds and there's a
benefit to run clones and as a seed
breeder
I should probably big up the seeds a
little bit more but to tell you the
truth all those famous cuts that you're
getting their famous cut for a reason
so we all have everybody in this room
grows the cookies everybody's got a
Gorilla Glue for a cut so no no yeah no
you will by the end of the day then
I could use another cut event that
beautiful that come from you want to
give someone a shout out shout out
Mariano's clones that's his Instagram
he's out of Cali Southern Cali central
Cali Cali okay probably some of the best
clones have ever received as far as a
month and I got got in like a month and
four days ago or something and they have
literally blown the [ __ ] up I've seen
pictures they're healthy they're happy
Instagram garden of weed capital n at
the end of it it's all attached to the
garden of Weeden there's websites
Facebook Tumblr that's it Instagram
Instagram yeah we did not talk about
auto flower plants it's one thing I
wanted to two minutes okay let's just
[Music]
Auto flower plants are that's just I
will never breed people always ask me if
I will make an auto flower as a breeder
and I always say no that's uh that's
word that's not for big boys and then
some people are gonna hate me for saying
that if you need a fast production crop
and you're not familiar with the
cannabis plant that may work for you but
it's not kind of super great herb in my
opinion Jesse and I are familiar with
one epic freakin use a lot of flower
plants to discredit all this should I
just talked we live in a community that
is about 40 minutes away from a national
forest maybe an hour depending on which
routes you take there was a legendary
[ __ ] bust of there was a Mexican
cartel in the National Forest running a
giant grow operation all year long
very covertly in like a valley that they
were hiking in and hiking out they were
camped there they found food there and
said these guys had been camped for a
month
very very covertly yeah the people that
owned the land around there were
oblivious to it and they had irrigation
system set up coming from the river
running downhill watering all the plants
it was perfect it was like a movie set
up
I can I mean they had three different
places out there yeah I mean it's it's
high Keable there's area where we can
hike to just went out there hike so
we'll let them tell you about it I mean
they they clear-cut a good 7 acres of
you know just prime national forest
trees you know full-size trees just cut
them down clear cut them no thought to
drainage or no respect for the
environment whatsoever to be the hippie
yeah I was told it was a mess out there
I knew one of the knots a blow too many
[ __ ] whistles but I know a friend of
Mines father is a retired cop and he's
cool as [ __ ] my buddy's a dab head and
dad just sitting on the couch next to
his dad who was a cop at the time he was
telling us that there were plants out
there of all stages eight inches tall 12
inches tall three feet tall and he said
there were bags of buds and a manicuring
station and I was tripping out because
when this place was discovered was not
flowering season it was it was like
spring or some [ __ ] and he was saying
that they already had plants six foot
tall three foot tall with big buds on
them in flower and there's no way that
they could have setup like a light DEP
out there on seven acres
I mean without being busted they were
using auto flower plants which that's
the best use of auto flowers I could
ever see so if you're trying to do some
crazy outdoor where you've got enough
time before the cold comes right after
the cold get those in the ground you
might be able to pull off an outdoor
crop probably so yeah I mean they were
living up there they had quite the
little city and I may may have found a
plant and may have moved it down just to
see what happened and
yeah it was - Leonardo flower could
there have been any seeds up there by
chance
probably so the plan I found was
actually a mental auto flowering plant
yeah I killed it burned it stomped it
into the ground you [ __ ] a male auto
flower money oh that's super super
dangerous yeah this is just gonna bust
one day Spencer's eyeballs are about to
pop out yeah find a male in the grow
room about three weeks into flower I can
compare it to the feeling of when a
condom breaks if you can't tell
something's wrong it's just kind of
heartbreaking because at that point you
don't know like you don't know what it
hit if it hit if it's dropping pollen is
it not dropping pop there's just too
many questions oh yeah and then when you
find some seeds in your nose you know
I'm one thing our three months later
it's like BAM
there he goes there's a results yep I
saw it go oops
so guys pay attention with the males
that rule of that plant in the back if
you see a yellow dust on your leaf
that's I've discovered him now one time
by that yeah be careful keep an eye on
your feminized seeds do because femme
seeds can turn into hermaphrodites or
males
we got dab this [ __ ] on this episode
talking about this so I hope we made
some sort of sense I want to stress my
point again grown from seeds is awesome
everything came from seed yeah that's if
you grow for the curiosity and just the
level of the plant and you've never
grown from seed well I question your
curiosity though well if I grow from
seed because there's a possibility of
finding something that people don't have
and that's my that's my answer for you
right there like yeah I would literally
all grow a pack of seeds to find a Fino
that
you know maybe two people out of what
couple hundred people that have bought
in packs have you know you know who
knows one day that string could be
everything and I've seen seeds I forget
the term for it but I have bred seeds
that the outcome has been better than
both parents like it got more vigor and
more trichomes than the two parents I
used and I've upgraded yeah so that's a
good good way to look at it you got
something in your brain there yeah I
know that term yeah I can't I think DJ
short might have recently said it yeah
yeah somebody said it somebody tweeted
to us at agriculture I'll send you to
eye region etic stickers I really will I
really really will maybe something
cooler if I can find something to send
you it will not be seed there anything I
promise I won't ship seeds don't do that
hey guys stop shipping [ __ ] friend of
ours got in trouble for shipping [ __ ]
yeah this person in the community that
is not anymore in the community I got
[ __ ] busted ship and [ __ ] and it
makes us all look bad it makes Colorado
look stupid it makes you look stupid
stop shipping [ __ ] please if you want
some [ __ ] come get it it's legal in
Colorado for 21 the dispensary has what
you want we don't have to mail it to you
sorry to bust up anybody's business
ringing for making some money ship and
[ __ ] but there are plenty of sick people
here that are plenty of recreational
people here we fought to get this [ __ ]
right here that's legit here stop
shipping [ __ ] everyone's agreement yeah
[ __ ] [ __ ] middleman anyways yeah
straight to the grower grow your own if
you listen to this podcast you're
probably not one of the people that ship
and [ __ ] anyway so I don't even need to
pitch you you're growing your own herb
you got some quality dabs hanging out
with like avignon we don't need to cut
off a conversation here just cuz I'm out
of material to talk about on the seed
stuff you got anything fun dad there was
a news story in the news
[ __ ] I can't remember huh
Jessie's hi do you remember where you
saw it I'll go Google I'll hit the
cannabis right quick all the weed news
hits the cannabis what was it about
remember I think it was comical that's
why I'm trying comical
yeah I want to say that kind may have
seen it in the post or something I am
NOT sponsored by the cannabis store
anything a lot of people disagree with
what the cannabis says sometimes they
print some articles that i will agree
are [ __ ] wacky yeah right as I open
the cannabis there's an article that
says cannabis Q a grow room tour and
other reader questions check out that
grow room tour I want to read that I
haven't read it yet but that'll be sure
any grow room tour is fun you might
learn something there ask me if you have
questions about that the three of us in
this room we could design and build you
the most [ __ ] amazing grow room let
me build one yeah what the three of us
build it will crush it it'll be the
Lamborghini room bro I don't see much on
the the cannabis worth of reading on the
show yeah next time next time we'll have
some news for you I'll find something to
read Because got anything call dad shout
out to everybody over at the garden of
Weeden while spence's away I hope
they're all behaving themselves and
having a good time Big Mike
Matty slop Nani's Rock boy ping pong
sloppy big shout-out to ping pong we
love you always bro we miss you good to
ship out had to ship out so you could
shape up little pups names those are
cutest [ __ ] I was forgiven I forget his
name all the time those dogs are cute as
[ __ ] yeah good work on those two little
pups bro for sure all right it doesn't
[Music]
sorry I'm not very familiar with that
one can we can you pause recording real
quick I want to ask Spencer question
yeah possibly have a story to tell
that's cool I'll hit pause right here
hold on guys we're gonna hit pause and
make sure that what we can talk about is
talk
about Abel on a show hold on actually I
just turned the mics down and the music
up you guys get down for a half second
I recording now we're coming
we were bad you know that story was not
appropriate for listen you missed a
story I apologize we can't hear that
somebody's personal I think the secret
cops coming up right yep see great cop
the regional I think I've got my my VIP
spot set up I'll be there don't be a
bunch of people it'll be fun
Oh everybody in the industry that is in
Colorado will show up shout out the Big
D for putting that on do a lot of
shoutouts on this show it's in the
mountains yeah a lot of us were - we're
all prima donnas and didn't want to go
dab in the [ __ ] woods because it's
just hard to plug in your email out
there a big shout-out to - tur pecks and
hunt from the grimy Gatsby turkey
Slurpee boys turkey slurpy slurpy they
know what's up bro that's a code word
right there that's a code word for peace
lerp exactly turkey Slurpee man this
dome is stuck on this rig like a [ __ ]
we're gonna have to do a DAB on this
other rig here hey guys I appreciate you
listening to us just ramble for a couple
of minutes it doesn't sound like we got
much left on this little chatty part of
the show and I think these guys were
showing up once again I people really
like having you guys on the show I get a
lot of listens when you guys show up
when you shout me out on your social
media so thanks for doing that
anybody you want to shout out before we
wrap this little section up anyway it's
silent how about - shut up - hankie be
the boss the chief the champ does not
[ __ ] matter
yeah hustle harder hustle every day
alright guys we're gonna take a couple
of jerry garcia sized dabs here thanks
for listening to us if you have any
questions cuz i know we kind of went
over that quickly we're all dabbed on we
all have a TD here and we just wanted to
hang out with each other a little bit so
if you have any questions you know how
to do it email me tweet me i'll say all
that stuff i'm gonna be back in just a
couple of minutes to wrap up the show
enjoy a little bit of music here and
we're gonna get down
I'll leave the mics on so you can hear
his dad
[Music]
all right I hope you guys enjoyed that
little conversation about seeds versus
clones the part about Otto flower seeds
I wanna give a huge shout out to Jesse
and Spence for coming and taking time
out of their day to be on the podcast
make sure you follow them on Instagram
at Jesse grows and at garden of Weeden
it's garden of weed and just a capital
and at the garden of weed so garden of
Weeden also big shout out to everybody
from the garden of Weeden even the
people that don't come on the show
there's a lot of them much love to all
those guys big shout out to Ciroc and
nana also so now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search Fried grow culture find the
review section give us a five star
rating after that type in a little
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comment on
the show you can also leave comments on
stitcher and I will read those on a
future episode as well don't forget -
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
swell dot a.m. and every single episode
is archived on I read genetics Colorado
dot-com big shout out to my ninja Spence
make sure you guys listen to episode
number 25 I don't even know what I have
planned yet it's gonna be that exciting
I usually start planning the show around
Wednesday so put the show out on a
Monday planning on Wednesday it works
well for me it's got about a week to put
it together I'm sure there will be some
sort of give away to the loyal listeners
so much respect everybody that's
listened thank you thank you thank you
we're excited to come up with episode
number 25 until next time take a phat
dab give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
all right podcast that was episodes 21
22 23 and 24 of what used to be known as
the high-growth culture podcast
currently known as the girl from your
heart a podcast I want to thank
everybody again for listening once again
if you didn't catch it at the beginning
if you want to follow us on social media
the Twitter is at G fyh podcast on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast also if you want to
see me an email let's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen if
you would like to contribute to this
show financially you can help by going
to patreon.com and checking out patreon
patreon is a service where you can
contribute to the podcast what that
would do is help me pay for the website
that I have to host this show on so if
you'd like to help me out simply go to
patreon.com/scishow from your heart all
the information that you need will be
right there for you ladies and gentlemen
I will be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
repossessions would be long
what you live is what you live with
although it's the only thing that you
everybody's to my mind winner
[Music]
his eyes are
Biman
[Music]
these are the father
because we know
we cannot walk away
it's our past is the way to abide in
your presence is the only thing I pray
for
storms on our own
elie-san in my long
[Music]
the rest are far
I
[Music]
I resign
I know
these are the times when I hear a star
[Music]
you