hey what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
Rasta Jeff thanks for joining me doing
that thing where I release old episodes
today I'm going to put out episodes 25
26 and 27 of what used to be known as
the agriculture podcast currently known
as The Grove from your heart podcast
before we get started on the show let me
make a few disclaimers a lot of my ideas
opinions methods and techniques may have
changed I've been doing this podcast for
two years now when I first started I did
some [ __ ] differently hopefully we have
all learned a lot of things since then
stuff may be different don't hold it
against me if I have different ideas and
techniques now than I did then also all
of the social media has changed all of
the I grew culture stuff it's gone I
don't answer any of that I don't read
that I don't answer
open reply respond or think about any of
that stuff so if you wish to contact me
please send me an email let's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com once again
that is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also you can find me on
social media on facebook it's the girl
from your heart a podcast and on twitter
its
@gf wih podcast i want to thank
everybody again for listening and once
again here's episodes 25 26 and 27 of
what used to be known as the agriculture
podcast currently known as the girl from
your heart podcast ladies and gentlemen
please enjoy
[Music]
episode number 25 of the iGrow culture
podcast what's up Kevin looks like he's
having a seizure while he's trying to
dance it's funny [ __ ] to watch I looked
up from the recording equipment and I
gotta catch my breath from some 25th
episode I'm excited this is cool so what
are you guys doing how are you guys man
what's going on great I'm pumped man
ready I'm glad to be here 25 you just
showed up bro thanks for getting here
[Music]
all right in the morning listening it's
1:00 in the morning on Friday night
that's my fault
I'm sorry well we all had [ __ ] to do I'm
a grower myself and another friend we
saw a comedian called Todd Johnson
called Johnson I sound like an Asian guy
when you saw the community name Todd
Johnson who's gonna clean for my taste
he's kind of good old boy comedy you
said nasty on the right there so I was
really expecting dirty comedy works is
hooking me up I've gone to a lot
comedy works shows and they see my email
address on a lot of [ __ ] so they called
me and they're like we'll give you free
tickets to a bunch of shows or you can
get $5 tickets to a bunch of their shows
and they do it just to fill the seats is
when they're trying to do that and I see
why now that we got there why that
counts or that comedy show is $5 but uh
I told him next time give me somebody
dirty I know it's something dirty or a
little filthy the opening act
there was a host who I always forget his
name it's Ron something and I feel bad
that I forget his name he's a comedian
well-known for doing dabs dab jokes weed
jokes he's pretty funny he's a good host
he's better at being a host comedy group
dude sorry bro but I'm six five
everybody's [ __ ] pretty sure he's a
real friendly looking for these a
comedian man from Denver that were
[ __ ] hilarious
and did some awesome jokes and actually
tipped him with some goodies because the
host following him was a guy named
Deacon gray right was a comedian before
Deacon gray yeah Deacon gray came out if
you guys don't know Deacon gray Deacon
gray is a Denver local as far as I know
he's funny as [ __ ] hilarious dude and
he's had time to calm down he's not a
hyper kid and he's got his delivery is
flawless he doesn't look like he's up
there performing he's up there having as
much fun as we are
and he did quite a bit of high humor too
and I mean that's that's not easy I mean
it seems easy to write jokes about pot
but it's you know right and it has to be
in Denver now there's the thing where
everybody's a pot comic so you can't be
a Paco McHugh have to have
you can throw in your pot set for when
the crowd right is there it wasn't it
rely on that because it wasn't about pot
it was more about the high humor you
know about being it was about my weed
for cheap great I recommend that dude
check him out if you can see him go see
him I didn't do any research on that
also a big shout out to Melissa from
Comedy Works she probably does not have
any clue about this podcast but uh she
should listen I'll tell her next time I
talked to her on the phone you should
listen to my show I'll be catching Joe
Rogan a comedy works next week and I'll
let you guys know how that goes on the
next episode excuse my little miniature
pauses that is not me dying at all I'm
also kind of cold air on until [ __ ]
64 degrees I've been used to being like
85 90 and then I walked up here and it
was 60 64 shivering it was kind of weird
anyway random talk on the show sorry so
before we get too far this is a
celebration show but we have something
really awesome to add to this
celebration I'm excited to announce that
mark Emery is home in Canada with his
wife Jodi congratulations
you know the mark Emery was arrested and
held and in an American federal prison
for distributing cannabis seeds to trust
the world most listeners the show would
agree that mark was in prison for
complete [ __ ] so I think it's great
to know that he's back home with his
family where he belongs he's cuddled up
was with his wife saw a picture of him
smoking a joint with some people I saw a
picture of him hugging up on his wife
that's what a man should be doing you
shouldn't be locked up and he's right
back on the fight I don't know if you've
watched any video oh he's right up there
and I never really noticed that he spoke
with a whisk
maybe he has a retainer or something but
it really was pronounced when he like
when he very first step back into Canada
and got in front of the microphone I
don't remember that
I can I can link you to the video I
always remember him going on and on for
days me too and I'm
that's something that I I never really
noticed but he's right back on it and
his wife's gunning for liberal liberal
some kind of liberal office up there for
good good it's good to see him back on
it that was quick so big love and much
respect to mark and Jodie Emery I did a
little bit of checking it out mark was
taken into federal prison on September
10th 2010 he was released July 9th 2014
I used Siri I used a calculator I just
asked Siri how many days was that it's
1398 days in federal prison plus the
time he was locked up while awaiting
trial the time during the trial and a
couple of weeks in limbo after he was
released from federal prison 1398 days
Adam you look speechless are you
familiar with that sort of time period
long time dude it's but I did three and
then 54 and I felt like I mean that's
kind of what I was gonna ask this now
that he's pregnant he was the principal
before he came in now yeah does he knock
re-and off his king throne that's close
to four years though in federal prison
that's 46 months 200 weeks so imagine
your life being disrupted for 200 weeks
he'd be in prison that's cool
mine was a county jail not federal
prisoner level even like that's amazing
and I'm glad he's free [ __ ]
Georgia's [ __ ] charges it makes
awesome makes every seed breeder pot
grow or it makes us all a little bit
kind of
not only that what he was worried about
ourselves before the rules have changed
and now that they've changed you know I
can just imagine the culture shock I
mean from where he was Markham or where
he could probably puff on the street
anytime you wanted to but now in Canada
they don't really seem to care from what
people have told me they like come here
and smoke we don't really they don't
talk about it like we do they don't get
all hyped about it but they also don't
give a [ __ ] about it
all right so a big shout out to mark
Emery if you guys are longtime listeners
you know that we actually did I used to
do a portion of the show called give
thanks which I will do again in the
future but we've been packing the show
it's been like an hour and 15 minutes
sometimes and I don't feel like we need
to stretch it out with another gift
thanks portion and once we're that long
yeah welcome home marc emery much love
to jodie emery for being strong and
keeping herself active in the movement
while we were down one soldier all right
or the music go
[Music]
so why need take one second to making it
important make ending stuttering all the
contests we have started on the show
will be ending soon I left a few
contests open-ended and I've been
waiting for answers do a few like
questions and stuff like that I think
those episodes have gotten old and the
giveaways have just faded away so I want
to reuse the prizes so I'll end all the
contests that are happening now on the
podcast August 17th at 11:15 59 p.m.
mountain time unused prizes will be used
for future contests and giveaways to
look forward to that I just wanted to
make an official ending date on those
contests so that when I do reuse those
prizes nobody can get mad if they try to
go win the old contests official [ __ ]
all right
so I do have a Ginnie cush pin and a
couple other pins and things that I
tried to use in contest before maybe a
Jinni pushpin available pretty soon I
need to check the little box I've got
some prizes set aside we're gonna put it
back in pins or boys ladies and
gentlemen we're hoping to see me he's
told you where to find me
I want to do six miles every morning
without [ __ ] getting winded that's
what I want
eating soda and he's cut out 23 bro the
dr. pepper he's cut it out of his life
so give him some straight used to be
strongly addicted yeah I think you guys
are crazy that smoke cigarettes and
still I'm trying brother I'm trying to
get rid of it trust me it's killing me
harvest so you just roll a bunch you
should get some get some tobacco like
some well then you'll get your nicotine
fit that way and then just slowly take
the nicotine out I can just quit my
problem is her smoking next to me
doesn't want to quit then she doesn't
want to so I'm trying to I told her to
get a get a pin and just smoke wax you
know like you wanna say we have a
platform to give a review you're tied up
in the headphone cable so you're gonna
be stuck for life now go ahead and go
ahead and tell him the name of the thing
and then I hit it once I'll tell you my
opinion it's the company is neos in my
opinion it's an easier draw and better
tasting and more effective than some of
the other companies to try out to see if
you know it's a good product it is not
it's not dad kid dabs but if you're if
you're looking for a vape pen yes it's
it's really attractive is that okay so
you just replace the cartridge on the
end okay cool
and the very end of it is a stylus if I
were if I were a wreck patient what
would that cost me we haven't started
carrying them yet so I'm not sure but
similar companies with smaller batteries
like I said that aren't as great starter
package is about 58 dollars and some
change for a small cartridge just a 150
milligrams cartridge and a battery you
don't have to replace the battery you
can recharge it
you just have to come get cartridges and
they make them in three different sizes
but these ones that were these new ones
that we're testing out we're probably
gonna start carrying those different
high from it we've been dabbing for a
while and I just took another rip off
there and my high changed some fur packs
of course I might have friends at Archer
pecks or the guys but those are the guys
I know it's definitely a very attractive
like I mean why not why not get
something like that and fill it full you
know of wax that she'll hit maybe she
probably won't clear the damn thing in a
week you know last your wife a week it's
very smooth you don't have to push a
button you know it's simple it's like I
said you wear it with the black shirt
it's I didn't even see it you know I got
a message on facebook from a listener
named Fred and ironically he was asking
me to talk about acquiring seeds it's
really great because this email came
today while I was preparing for the show
sorry excuse my cough guys that's from
dabs that's from big dabs so I want to
talk about acquiring seeds but before I
do that let me give a little bit of a
legal disclaimer because we don't want
to be the next mark ever it may be a
label to acquire cannabis seeds in your
location is your responsibility
I'm not even gonna try to edit any of
that it is your responsibility to know
the laws in your location any company
online that will send you seeds is only
sending them to you for souvenir
purposes germinating seeds germinate
cannabis seeds is illegal in most places
I'm not here to help you break the law
if you decide to buy and/or germinate
cannabis seeds I cannot be responsible
for you I live in Colorado this is
legalized most of my advice is for
Colorado California Oregon Washington or
Michigan residents be careful and don't
get your ass into trouble because I'm
not a lawyer and I'm not responsible I'm
simply the host of a badass podcast
because if you're ordering seeds you
must be 18 or 21 and you got to be
responsible you have to be smart know
the rules where you are but still do
that [ __ ] here's what I can tell you
about acquiring yourself some seeds
yourself acquiring some seeds quality
seeds from reputable breeders I mean
I've only heard a few and of course
that's that's me of course old guys who
really paved the way and helped a lot of
the new seed readers get good genetics
to breed with
so you can't take anything away from
those guys but I mean some of the I read
genetics will applaud labs gauge Green
genetics like they're all doing some
really awesome stuff and they're
thinking about what they're crossing and
what they're trying to get out of their
crosses and not just finding a good
phenotype they're actually looking for
flavor profiles and cannabinoid profiles
and they're getting what they want out
of it and a lot of that has to do with
the way they do things a lot of the new
seed breeders are really community
friendly and dispersing a lot of seeds -
a lot of people and allowing them to
perform their methods of growing and
find you know different there's an
occasional plants there's an occasional
secret meeting at a place in Denver
where a few of us are chosen to meet at
this mansion shout out to the caves
there since it egos alpha chronic shows
up a bunch of us breeders IRA Genetics
goes and we all take packages of our
newest [ __ ] or whatever our secret
weapon and we trade and like Mile High
has given me as Apollo x brothers Hayes
and I gave him my grateful dog you know
like just trade packs of seeds around
the table and we all yeah we try to keep
it together with each other instead of
trying to compete we're trying to be
like what her brothers some faceoff og
for some heart of gold
you know like barter that's right that's
right
so that's a few of our favorite breeders
buy some seeds from reputable breeders I
I'm a breeder
I am I region etics I would say since
it's hard to get I read genetics seeds
gage Green is one of my favorites I use
gage green for breeding stuff if you're
gonna if you want to get into a breeding
stuff and you want a reliable male I
can't believe I'm [ __ ] telling the
world this but gage green is a good
place to find a nice reliable male
that's true [ __ ] right there
that's how friendly I am
but be careful with your breeding
because you can still [ __ ] up even with
that good mail so much I like you guys
you listen to my show it's awesome so
bag seeds are fun but they're not as
reliable bag seeds are seeds that you
find in wheat of course right they're
not as reliable as something you'd find
you want something with specific Paris
bread for certain traits like Kevin was
saying earlier so it's kind of cool that
he touched on that your first option is
bag seed that [ __ ] that you of course
found in that cush that you bought from
that guy in the park and it had a seed
grow that out see what happens but keep
a close eye on any bag seed because it
could be a male or it could be a
hermaphrodite yep you can possibly get
seed at a dispensary or a co-op many of
the shops in California Colorado
Washington and Michigan have seeds from
reputable reputable breeders available
on the shelves and the dispensaries
almost everywhere and the Pacific
Northwest has [ __ ] TGA sub cool seeds
all over the place most of the shops in
Colorado you can pick up yourself some
rare dankness genetics because our
friend yankee up and down the east coast
there and takes care of them with the
cage green he's green rapping he's
awesome so they're taken care of so
there's seeds on shops and shelves I was
reading I forgot there we go
you can also pick up seeds cannabis
events like the Cannabis Cup in Hempfest
or whatever else is happening this month
because there seems to be an event every
damn month now the breeders go they set
up a tent do a little bit of research
online look what you're find out what
you're looking for find out what you
should be paying expect to pay about a
hundred bucks for a ten pack of seeds
honestly between 60 and 120 but about a
hundred bucks for a ten pack of seeds so
before you go to the events go and find
out what you want and then go there and
see if you can find those breeders and
you'll have a little shopping done it'll
be a little easier for you but those are
only viable options if you live in or if
you can travel to a legal state like
Colorado or Hempfest which is happening
right now will be over by the time you
hear this sorry be an option for most of
you guys so in this case
you're gonna need to order your seeds
online if you're the United States I
strongly recommend nature's green
remedies calm my company has a great
working relationship with nature's green
remedies I'm friends with most of the
breeder stocked on nature's green
remedies and I trust everyone that I've
done business with involved with
nature's green remedies so I strongly
recommend nature's green remedies calm
for seeds in the US like I said expect
to pay around $100 for a 10 pack of
seeds sometimes you get a 12-pack some
brands are a little cheaper some are
slightly higher feminized seeds often
run a little more expensive because
they're harder to produce you get way
less feminized seeds out of a breeding
project than you do regular seeds it
takes more time it takes more space it
takes more energy so of course we want
more money for that I do not charge my
regular seeds my feminized seeds are the
same price I charge the same price all
the way around
nature's green remedies uses these
discreet that's discreet that means they
don't right these are seeds on the
package these discreet priority shipping
and they're right here in the United
States so you know your seeds will
arrive in just a few short days they
don't have to pass through customs and
get held up they take all kinds of time
America so speaking of nature's green
remedies this podcast is brought to you
by nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm 4 gauge
green genetics la plata labs sencity
rare dankness mile high can adventure I
read genetics and many more trusted
brands they add new stuff all the time
there's some stuff that I'm not aware of
I'm not familiar with so check them out
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our loyal podcast listeners
I'm gonna drop the music out this part
it's important check it out guys and
gals here's a special promo offer from
Ira genetics
[Music]
here's a special offer from Ira genetics
nature's green remedies and I grow
culture you guys ready from Monday
morning when this podcast launches until
11:59 p.m. mountain time Sunday night on
August 24th any order over $25 on
nature's green remedies calm will
receive a free five pack of arise from
Ira genetics if you use coupon code
25 episode 25 all one word you will also
receive 15% off your entire order and
you will receive a free priority
shipping so here it is again any order
over $25 it's a free five pack of a rise
15% off and free priority shipping if
you use coupon code 25 before Sunday
night at midnight you can order any
brand in this promo and the price is
still valid you can get rare dankness
gauge green genetics ira genetics the
plot of labs sin city mile high alpha
chronic bog or any other brand available
at nature's drain remedies dot-com and
you still get 15% off your entire order
with the coupon code 25 at nature's
drain remedies dot-com I'm trying to
hook up the loyal podcast listeners with
the free five pack of seeds because I
[ __ ] love you guys I need a drink
right quick hold on
man as deal and it tells a long
promotive one day without taking it
breath or a drink arises the new stuff
right that's your uh it's a golden go
female that was pollinated by a gauge
green genetics Daybreaker male bomb
sounds tasty it grows it grows there our
fee knows that look like the golden goat
there our fee knows it look like the
Daybreaker and there's one right in the
middle buddy there's almost no leaf on
it
it's big leaves and no leaf so you don't
have to trim it it's it's some head
kicker that lasts for one week you guys
hopefully I don't run out because I
bunch hopefully I do run out I have to
give you a ten pack of something in
substitute because you ran me out I hope
that's what happens guys please try to
just do one order per household or one
order per person don't try to it's a
freebie dude come on just be kind with
the freebies is what I'm trying to say
it share the wealth
so big things much respect to nature's
green remedies calm for the promotion
and for the continued support and thank
you to you guys for participating in the
promos that we do I hope that helps you
guys out hope it shows that uh I love my
listeners so while we're on this little
advertising kick let's just do this
podcast is brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street unit a four stop by
the new publication on 618 East 4th
Street in Pueblo Colorado you guys hear
my voice crack on that one that's from a
DAB
I'm trying to keep it going over here
but I'm running out of moisture I check
out hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
don't forget to visit
www.gfi.com/webmonitor hasta Jeff sent
you and don't forget about the deal on a
tote of soil for five hundred and fifty
bucks or six hundred dollars delivered
anywhere in the state of Colorado also
shout out to our friends at oil slick
oil slick tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick Pat comm for more
information make sure you follow oil
slick on twitter find them under at oil
slick pad send them a tweet and let them
know
listening to the iGrow culture podcast
one more commercial guys big love to
tree hugger calm this episode is brought
to you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews WWE sucker comm let's
respect to all of our sponsors for
making another drink you guys talk about
[Music]
the first 24 I'm not so sure about this
not even the Facebook the Instagram the
Twitter my email they've all been
blowing up lately regarding the show
regarding everything Irie genetics the
podcast life everything at all don't
even look at those we just paid all the
bills here cast 25 it feels like a
milestone in the podcast world they say
that your show isn't anywhere until
you've done 25 episodes they don't
expect any listener interaction don't
expect a tweet don't expect a comment
don't expect a five-star review at least
until you've gotten 25 episodes under
your belt and I do have to give a little
bit of respect to the podcast that
helped me get my feet wet and learn how
to do podcasting it was simple one-line
the blocks podcast no disrespect to
those guys I just had to end that
relationship and or not that
relationship that podcast that didn't
have time for that [ __ ] anymore so those
guys it's kind of where I got my feet
wet and podcast Answer Man dude you
taught me a lot of [ __ ] I know you don't
listen to my show but cliff ravenscraft
taught me a lot about podcasting so
since we're doing all that I should send
some love to a lot of people big shout
out to Kevin of course Adams Tony Clint
Jesse Spencer the whole garden of Weeden
crew big respect to DJ nicotine task ROG
Edison demora Hunter pecks
Ryan a tree hugger Big D of course
everyone at handmade apparel and oil
slick white Mike Geary Angela coral
reefer Yankee and the boys at nature's
green remedies the boys I mean the
little tiny dreadlocks
shout out little guys burning the crew
from high growth webelo nurse Nelly Lama
Vox logistics mr. Omni Oh who listens
all the way in London UK I'm Nick from
Pueblo Henry 710 m for cane key play
Joey and chilli from natural mystic
cannabis caregivers in Colorado Springs
a big sky from the forum cut proof good
drew good drove and all the other
members of the IRA genetics forum also a
big shout out to Nancy bud well
shoutout to Brad in New Mexico and Rob
in Massachusetts and also I want to send
a huge shout out to all of my listeners
who have stuck around this long finally
comfortable on a microphone and I've
wondered what I'm doing with the
recording gear so stick with me and I'll
bring you grow advice and cannabis news
every week until they make me freakin
stop I obey didn't miss anyone if I did
please know that I love you dad the [ __ ]
out and I'm on the spot so take a
celebration dad we got the commercials
done we got the contest I wasn't sure
but yeah big shout-out to pops a big
shine it's John 14 carrot pops pops pops
[Music]
lung cancer he looks like hell Pop's
look like a skeleton several months ago
and with the little treatments from his
doctor not little treatment [ __ ]
big-ass treatments from his doctor that
almost ploughed the [ __ ] out of pops and
the love from Kevin and the nurturing
from Kevin and also the help of cannabis
pops looks like a freakin million bucks
now help from a lot of people gave free
donations just to help out his cause
because he couldn't smoke anymore and
things like that so really you know he
gained weight throughout his entire
treatment the only bad news we received
was the original cancer so cannabis has
done a lot for the man he's made sure
you could eat kept him going through all
those those hard treatments and we're
just waiting on the scan next month to
see what the final answer is but he's he
says he has more energy he feels better
than he has in over three years so I
mean he looks better he's it's awesome
take care of yourselves guys
thank ya I have to thank the community
for that because
to be quite honest I could but I was
well I got a lot of from other sources
and things like that just given just
here it does it gives you love back he
wants me to shine a podcast but a friend
of a friend came down with stage 4 liver
cancer and it was in deep [ __ ]
was actually looked worse than Pop's
lips and I'm not the only thing that was
gonna work for this guy so and I posted
on Facebook I need some RSO and I got it
within five days delivered from
Leadville just a friend of a friend who
that's compassionate care right there
you know it wasn't for me they knew that
that was for that guy yeah I wasn't
asking friends they're like yeah we got
it man
of Dammam so if you have somebody if
anybody out there this shout outs free
if you hook up medical patients if you
don't charge your medical patients if
you give medical patients extra I know
you got to recoup your flight fees you
got to pay for your soil you got to do
that [ __ ] so charge of the bare minimum
if you guys are hooking up cancer
patients with RSO you're doing that kind
of [ __ ] you know who you are if you
deserve a shout-out for this [ __ ]
Big Ups if you're a medical provider big
love respect thank you that's a shout
out for you some of you guys are just
falling out looking like gangstas living
off the caregiver life but some guys are
doing a proper and mad love for that
because it's hard to do it proper
medical grade know no sprays no crazy
[ __ ] on it is it definitely a challenge
I want to keep the grow lessons coming
and [ __ ] and always do episodes with
news if you guys want to hear me talk
about something something random
something like this guy the whole seed
topic today just happened to be good
timing I had a giveaway planned and that
guy asked about where to get seeds so
now hopefully he's listening to episode
25 and he can get seeds to buy some IRA
genetics products right now I think his
email said he's in California he's got
that 215 and it's legal out there good
deal but he doesn't have to even buy IRA
genetics products you can go buy some
rare dankness or some horrible plata
[Music]
genetics scarlet Kush or starlet cush or
aspirin I'm trying not to come oh there
it was hmm okay I'm better now
I should just let it happen but go get
some of those and then use that coupon
code episode 25 it's all one word
capital e and then the number 25 episode
25 you get a free five pack I read here
and I don't want anything except your
loyal listener ship which is pretty
awesome yeah
yeah I'll talk about it on the show I'll
try to read those on a future episode on
including in under certain code things
like that but now they're out long even
that in Colorado Springs and what
apparently what it was some one one guy
from I forget his name from the
building some building department or
something in Springs kind of decided
that you know these electrical codes and
certain things were not sufficient to
even have a closed loop so here you know
here the industry is there's a lot of
people you know making new new rooms and
everything under all these new codes all
these guidelines and this guy just came
in and said that wasn't good enough and
apparently this department has like
final say over fire department all this
other stuff they're working to figure it
out and you know I think the guy from
what I understand is going to tell you
know the industry what he wants as
regulations or whatever and you know it
may be like it just happened yesterday
afternoon so let's do you know how many
extraction amol so this is blasting is
actually technically illegal anyway this
is only relating to dispensary OPC
Grosso state regulated any deregulated
grows that are blasting their pry it's
not even blasting anymore at this point
it's processing in a closed loop system
legal Emme deregulated MIPS OPC
regulated blasting sites processing
facilities I guess we'll call them how
many of those do you think or know of in
Colorado Springs I I know of two for
sure I know there's probably a couple
more just because some of the you know
dispensaries have their own mips
licenses yeah that they can process
under but i know two of for sure and
once fairly new to colorado
and that's kind of a bummer and it's
getting shut down now which is you know
that's they can still run their garden
run co2 you can still run the garden
that we're talking about it
okay garden in spring so it was actually
being grown so what happens guys if
you're listening from we've got a
listener that listens in London
everybody music yeah we have to keep in
mind that not everybody knows Colorado
right these places grow a large Gardens
like a thousand plants and they harvest
the entire gardens and then they run all
of that through a closed butane
extraction machine and turn all of it
into hash into BHO dabs process I want
to concentrate yes and that sells for
somewhere between depending on where and
if you're getting into live resin it's
85 to 100 dollars a gram right so these
guys are making large portions and
portioning it up into grams and then
they deliver it back to the dispensary
and then the dispensary sells it or the
dispensary takes their grow that they
have leftovers of and sends it to the
extraction company for them to blast or
process and then they take all of that
product back to the shop and sell it on
the shelves so these guys are large
large gardens just for processing so
what I see them doing you run your large
garden you chop it you dry it you drive
it up to Denver to your processing
facility or down to pueblo to your
processing facility where it's legal and
then you run it there and then you just
have to drive twice is what the industry
standard is now you can't apply so
that's that's what I'm saying
this not doing anything but like
upgrading the hash I mean it kind of
sounds negative when it's coming from
YouTube it to me it sounds like more
people gonna be making unicorn hash and
we're gonna go away from the butane it's
gonna drive the black market guys that
are unlicensed like me I'm a grower and
I'm a breeder I don't I don't know how
to make the dabs honestly I I'm going to
have to if I can't get it's not being
made I'm going to have to go in my
backyard and open blast my prohibition
banned all the recreational blasting I
[Music]
think it's a great idea he pushed the
mountain regions back I'm sure it was a
community decision to some extent wasn't
just big but they just wrapped up the
East Coast most these Costa Bobby mugs
apparently that was badass good job I
watched the video good job so after that
you know secret cup administrators
decided that they needed the home states
so Big D in Jeremy yeah as badass as the
beast coast was you know and they didn't
feel like they could do that within like
a week and a half
and they have had several venue changes
several issues with Denver yeah they're
getting everything else squared away and
they pushed it back to the end of
September also a big d offer to pay any
expenses that were extra incurred on
people who had already had plane tickets
I had to trade a man or anything like
that just prove to me what your airline
fees for changing tickets if there were
you know it's awesome it was like that's
that's pretty cool dude so yeah if you
guys are trying to come to the secret
cup it's the date has been changed have
they announced the new date September 27
Thursday announced like the week yeah
probably pinned down a date it was the
same day as a Phish concert and sorry
but 28 September cool cool guys got any
any plugs you want to do anywhere you
want anybody to check out anybody you
want to [ __ ] mention well you got
your twitch
[Music]
whatever that other t1 is Twitter there
you go yeah
plugs advertising you're so fun to our
friends that are crushing it in Las
Vegas they've got a large girl facility
in Clark County I don't know if he wants
me to see his name on a podcast or not
but he knows who he is
he's got that Hells Angel og that tested
at 30 bucks all right my plug my turn
check me out
it's hydro culture on Twitter I post all
the episode updates and I grow culture
on Twitter I'm gonna just keep the music
down for a minute I like that I read
genetics on Instagram I grow culture
hotmail.com there's more but that's
enough dude you guys know what's up
right you know where to find me it's 25
episodes in the world's would you want
to find me I don't even know all right
oh there's constantly links to all your
other things too from there yeah as long
as you find I grow culture on Twitter or
I read genetics on Instagram or I read
genetics on Twitter ah you'll be happy
you'll find all of it I linked them up
so yeah
that's 45 episodes you guys I want to
thank everybody for listening to the
show sending me tons of tweets and
emails and Facebook messages it's really
cool this part always sounds fun we'll
turn up some music for this now that
shows over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search Fri grow culture
find the review section give me a 5 star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on the show if
you tell me that I'm awesome if you tell
me that I sound like [ __ ] Charlie
Brown's teacher if you tell me I'm a
stupid
go ahead if you tell me I should be
President you told me I sound like
Martians landed and you [ __ ] cut off
my brain I'll say that on the show I'll
do it I'll read almost anything you type
into that comment section which is kind
of scary for somebody to say don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes
stitchers well dot am and also on I read
genetics Colorado calm the other day
stitcher was messing up and not posting
the episodes so if it freaks out you
guys go find me on I read genetics
Colorado calm that's my website I own
that it will not go away every episode
is posted there one through 25
I promise I'll keep them coming shout
out to my ninja spits shout out to these
boys for sitting through an hour-long
episode with me and kicking ass you guys
stayed on the mics great thanks for
coming thanks for having me for the big
two five I wanted you on cuz you've been
here
[Music]
I'm gonna try to get that right take and
give your mom a hug for me big shot at
the task rock we're gonna turn up some
music we're gonna take some dabs you
guys have a wonderful [ __ ] evening
I'm gonna find a specific song for the
end of this episode number 25
agriculture prod prod casts episode
number 25 of the high-growth culture
podcast I promise to keep bringing you
the best of cannabis news and education
news radio you're now listening to TAS
Brock it's d-day from the album that was
the Royal Hall a nobody even noticed
that
[Music]
yeah good morning good afternoon good
evening good night whatever time it is
for you I hope you were enjoying
yourself if you got a fat joint or a fat
dab of something tasty welcome to
episode number 26 with the iGrow culture
podcast I'm your host they call me Rasta
Jeff thanks for joining me for the 26th
episode in this episode Jesse and Adam
and myself talk about some outdoor
growing
I've got Adam hanging out while I record
this intro on a Sunday night what's
going on bro what's that man a little
bit wrecked record this episode last
night Adam another friend of myself went
to Denver to watch the Joe Rogan record
his special for Comedy Central we'll
talk about that at the end of the show I
want to give a huge shout out to
everyone who participated in the promo
with nature's green remedies and of
course this podcast is brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gage
green genetics will apply to labs sin
city rare dankness mile high can
adventure I read genetics and many more
trusted brands patron screen remedies is
running a special for the loyal podcast
listeners use coupon code to Jeff for
15% off any order and free priority
shipping thus coupon is good through the
month of August and it's valid on any
brand on the website big thanks in much
respect to nature's green remedies for
the promotion and for the continued
support this podcast is also brought to
you by high grow indoor growing supplies
hydro indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the new publication on 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check
out hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
don't forget to check out WWE grow
Denver for current store hours and
special sales also don't forget to go to
the pueblo location and pick up that i
think you get in pueblo and denver you
can get a tote of soil roots organic sol
for five hundred and fifty bucks or six
hundred dollars delivered anywhere in
the state of colorado parts of this
podcast are brought to you by our good
friends at oil slick oil slick tools to
help you concentrate check out oil slick
pad comm for more information make sure
you
oil slick on twitter find them under at
oil slick pad send them a tweet and let
them know you're listening to the iGrow
culture podcast I want to send Big Love
to all of our friends at Treehugger calm
the show is brought to you in part by
tree hugger calm wife music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews
WWWE thugger calm much respect to all of
our sponsors for making the show
possible really appreciate you guys for
helping us out so let's get right down
to it Jessi came over for a Gro lesson
taught us a lot of stuff about outdoor
growing Adam hung out learned a few
things so I'm gonna let the music play
for a second we're gonna go ahead and
fade in that conversation and then after
that Adam and I will be back to wrap up
the show hang out listen guys thanks
[Music]
eventually there's gonna [ __ ] stick
my iPhone in my head and I can just
think like text Adam and tell him to
come over and take dabs with me that
would be funny yeah we're recording not
just that you guys are aware no it would
be a little weird we're just here having
a little random conversation we're gonna
have a grow lesson we got Jesse back as
promised hey what's up
thanks for coming bro also uh Adams back
Adams uh he's on the show all the time
but you guys might not know that Adams a
new grower he's gonna new to Colorado
it's his first grow season here and he
does have some outdoor plants yeah well
I invited him to stick around while
Jesse's here he may have some good
outdoor questions he may bring up some
[ __ ] that we may overlook so it's always
good to have a new guy in to kind of
referee us because Ben told what kind of
snobs and we go a little fast and we
talk about [ __ ] like everybody should
know so well slow down we'll try to go
slow for you guys and keep it at a pace
where you can keep up but I do plan to
increase the knowledge in this show
slowly but surely over time so that you
guys can all improve that's right
knowledge is power that came from Adam
yeah never stop learning that might be
the smartest thing Adams gonna say all
day I said I was too loud in the
headphones I gotta turn that [ __ ] up now
you guys are crazy no you were too loud
my headphones
all right so of course we're back for an
outdoor girl lesson it's full bloom time
your plants should be starting to flower
you guys lookin rollin rocking and
rolling alright alright
signs a flower hopefully you guys have
pulled your mails it's time to pull the
Mail's now right mails you've got a seed
crop and your neighbors have a seed crop
and someone else on the block has a seed
crop and they're all pissed off at you
so you [ __ ] up but hopefully pulled
your mails by now cuz you're in full
bloom so that means we're probably 25 30
days in silence yeah sure for some
assurance for some strains okay Adam was
saying he had one that took a long time
to switch into flour
it's just now getting to the point where
it's like visibly flower it probably it
probably switched last week or so
officially you know but it is it's
definitely taken it might be a little
bit longer but it the other two had
switched into flour three or four weeks
ago obviously and now have
these insights quarter-sized buds nice
there's a random question how long since
you're an outdoor girl I'm asking Jessie
he's an experienced I'm a city boy I
live indoors I grow indoors I don't
worry too much about the outside I don't
know the answer I am a city boy yeah he
took me to the sticks and I'm [ __ ]
scared bro protect myself out there but
okay okay how long do we have
how many weeks or about when do you
expect frost one busy get too cold for
outdoor crop that's that's always good
question if I know the answer to that
you're not mother nature are you yeah
okay
sorry good would you agree that in
Colorado in Pueblo Colorado nature loves
to snow on Halloween and [ __ ] up all the
kids costumes on Halloween that's kind
of our traditional you know okay so get
them down
October 30th yeah you'll start to be
able to tell if you guys would snap so
I'm gonna grab a calendar right quick I
don't see how many weeks I'll just ask
Siri she'll tell me cv is great yeah how
many days until Halloween oh there we go
she'll tell me oh she failed series been
a not friendly chick today fire how many
days until Halloween she's looking 70
days oh so most strains should be done
yeah even your stuff they just started
flowering should be done alright yeah
cool seventy days from so today is
actually Thursday the show won't go up
until Monday morning so you're gonna
have closer to 65 but and you probably
won't listen till Wednesday so for nine
weeks you got about nine weeks to flower
guys nine or ten weeks depending on
where you are if you're in California
you could get that [ __ ] out no problem
but if you're in Colorado you got about
nine weeks if you're higher up if you're
towards Denver you may want to cut that
little closer to Thanksgiving
people folks in California have been
flowering longer than us it seems like a
lot of them you know from the pictures
I've seen they definitely went into
flower sooner I can imagine several
things that why that would be but I
wonder what the actual reason is do you
think they've selected better strains
well to the coast maybe like just their
different region they're at a different
latitude and longitude in the Earth's
north and south makes a huge difference
they get the Sun you know a slightly
different angle or so because if
somebody understands why those plants in
Cali flowered sooner I think we just
nailed it but if you got that if you get
the science e reason tweet that to me
email it to me agriculture hotmail.com
had agriculture on Twitter let me know
we'd like to understand more of that
agriculture on Facebook we get it but we
want you to explain it because we're
podcast host and stoners and
that's [ __ ] you can explain it but
we'd like to understand yeah yeah so
when he got here we took a bunch of dabs
of course and then we talked about we
wanted to do he talked about topdressing
a little bit do you want to talk about
the mulching and the topdressing
yeah for sure you know I think it's safe
to say to go ahead and switch over all
your top dressings and your teas and
stuff too you know throwing that that
hypee stuff hi PK you know pretty much
chill out on the nitrogen atoms got some
plants that are nitrogen deficient
visibly on the lower lower bottom lower
third of the plant I told him to hit it
real good with nitrogen one more time
real hard I was feeding you think okay
Jessie train a podcast will be a lot
more audible now I just noticed that
oh yeah look at that we can hear him
yeah sorry no worries bro wait I got a
compliment you're way more comfortable
way more losing on the show now compared
to the first episode I think you want
number 8 or 6 there's number 8 and we're
at 26 now bro so you've been coming
quite a few times maybe you'd like a
little foliar feed of locally just to
that part of the planet a high nitrogen
you know several different ways you
could do that option is basically to put
grow in a bottle and spray it anything
that's my problem is I'm a little under
feeding you know I'm saying yeah I mean
you gave me the chart and I've just been
basically going off of that besides all
the additives that I should have gotten
probably by now that I don't have yes I
told him to buy a couple of things you
[Music]
don't have a budget to allocate to
growing because when you harvest try to
either if you have a patient friend that
needs some medicine or I don't know the
[ __ ] straight way to do that but see
the money that you normally would have
gone to your caregiver or your
dispensary save that money next year
because you're gonna have your own pot
if you're growing it and buy those
bottles that you could not get this year
absolutely make your shoots a little bit
better next year and then the next year
a little bit better than every then by
the time you're just an amateur girl you
don't need the [ __ ] rock star drum
set yet yeah by the time you're a good
rock star you'll have a rock star setup
you'll know what you're doing it is
easier to learn I think these leg days I
became a good growler because I started
with struggle bud you know I started
with the shitty set on the socks and
then had to grow a whole crop through
that because you don't want to rebuild
your room in the middle of a grow and
then bother the next upgrade and then
realize they had a room
I've always had like a small box was
playing and then now it's outdoors so
you were never in a state where you
could just go to the grow shop and be
like I need this yeah we could walk in
it almost feels like we're cheating it's
almost too easy too is bleeding at this
point it's almost too easy let's go back
to top dressing with mulch you should be
with your full bloom feed like he was
saying pull back on the nitrogen
get your phosphorous and potassium and
they're heavily for sure um so you're
mulching your uh explain that to the
guys that like [ __ ] I'll tell you I'm
[ __ ] on mulching I know how to mulch
my yard of my trees outside what are we
using for mulch for our weed plants I've
been using a fresh green matter most of
us from the plant itself the leaves and
weed seed things I've been pulling up
and then also I've been well I've been
mixing that with straw that's been
composted and I'm you know I'm building
a mulch mound around the plants that's
probably eight ten inches tall and the
circumference of the ya-ya
picture Ninkasi can is kind of what I
see I mean it's up it's a frickin mound
man okay yeah no it's pretty you know
maybe closer like 10 or 12 inches in the
center then we're coming out probably
I'm feeding circumference but when I've
removed part of the to apply top
dressing the root growth that I've seen
it's just phenomenal
this soil just looks better it looks
happier it's not as tight as it normally
gets when it's getting sun-baked
and you know I've always top dirt
mulched a little bit but never to this
extent and I've just so we'd nature
wouldn't leaves fall off of a plant to
kind of decompose for one of the plants
growing and provide that nutrient for
next year so that makes a lot of great
sense here's my question do you ever
worry about heat with that no I know I
mean I did initially because
yeah but that's why I've always kind of
steered away from it but doing the big
mound with you know it's just this work
great you know it'll be dry on top but
has it worked out into it look there's
somebody to keep the heat off my soil
because my soil is just baked and my
sand yeah because somebody was like put
a layer sand on there and I went out
there and my plans for like dirt bugs
with sand if you do it use a really tiny
tiny layer reapply it every single time
after you water we've kind of worked
over to one of the things that we wrote
down to talk about watering good outdoor
growing it's been at ninety something
degrees in Pueblo Colorado how much
water okay Adam I'll ask you first cuz
Jesse's gonna have a lot to say you're
kind of a new guy what size are your
pots five gallon your plants from what I
see like to be about four feet tall
Wow one's four foot the other two are
right at my chin so about five foot okay
I'm just guys haven't gone over there
look I don't want to spider mites yeah
yep four-foot tall plants in it worms
and five gallon pots how often and how
much
are you watering those girls every day
before the Sun comes up getting the hose
out and literally filling it up to the
top three different times by the end of
the day they are dry and I can pick them
up with one hand
Wow water single day and if you think oh
wait until noon no you won't they will
be sad pieces of lump and you'll be like
oh my god what have I done
yeah I've waited till nine or ten and
went out there and they're screaming for
water so water your plants water your
plants
rapping some like a stick around him
okay yeah why so sure okay and get you
the mulch I just pulled a whole bunch of
weeds out of my yard they were tall and
atrocious can I just throw them in a
bucket and start molding them I'm
worried about bugs you know I'm saying I
mean that the plant matter I can
definitely work with you know like I'd
be a little nervous about that okay so
don't just grab any weeds and start
mulching it yeah yeah you know select
about my my tweezer actually Morning
Glory seeds nice and if anyone knows
anything about Morning Glory yeah highly
highly invasive so it's he easy to find
so how much water sorry how big are your
plants outdoors can I even ask today I
can avoid questions you don't want to
answer
we're doing like a six to eight foot
each one's probably minimum of four foot
in circumference pictures the stalks are
as big as my forearm rubs how much how
much water does a plant that size take
every day seven and a half to ten
gallons a day
Wow times however many plants he's got
we won't even go there so d4 nated rural
area because there's not enough water to
do that if you're just coming out of
your well sometimes you don't want to
drain the well I'm gonna have water for
your life federal government regulates
most well so yeah they're real
understanding of pot grows as they
understand it so they're real inviting
for that sort of thing alright so we've
covered a lot about water halt man there
was a hum and I just found it there's a
squeal in my headphones I hope it only
happened in my ears but
I was my headphone could have been my
head so yeah that's something we talked
about a few episodes ago the federal
government is banning [ __ ] water use
for dispensaries and grows which if they
catch if a federal agent
federal agent if somebody for like the
Department of Water Works or somebody
something that works in a federal agency
discovers water in their municipality
being used for a cannabis grow they're
supposed to report the cannabis girl in
the water that's something we talked
about a few episodes ago whack [ __ ] be
careful you guys be super careful try to
be super discreet alright we talked a
little bit about worms you were saying
that the worms were crawling up into
your mulch yeah that's crazy
that means happy mulch yeah the worms
get up there they're probably eating
those leaves
they're probably secreting their enzymes
all over those leaves those leaves are
breaking down and becoming nutrients
that are more bioavailable to the plants
so that's a win-win situation for
everybody yeah do you guys hear that no
my headphones or something yeah it's
this hero4 from livewire solutions I've
talked about it on the show before [ __ ]
this thing got me is it completely cool
things works I will not say the name of
the company one more time it's alive
we're solutions
hero4 for channel stereo headphone
amplifier don't buy that thing
that's my anti sponsor right there how
you guys keep saying won't you buy
something better well I bought this one
and it keeps breaking so I go to Guitar
Center and I say this thing broke again
and they just give me another one of the
same thing so it just cost me a trip to
Guitar Center every few weeks which you
know they're cool over there and I
always find new toys so what the hell
let's do it hopefully their company goes
out of business thing
upgrade there you go if I recall now
you're thinking some store credit on an
upgrade or something yeah that's just
random talk guys I hope you enjoy
hearing us talk about messages that are
like just hang out and talk we love
hearing you talk so that was some of
that but that's right
so worms yeah worms are awesome put
worms by the roots of your plants all
the time if you find a warm don't bury
it that it's not how that works okay let
me explain that and not still in our
talk it if you find a worm I mean you
want to put it into your plant don't
bury it gently put him on the surface
him working his way down or its way in
there so I'm sure yours are in the
ground so finding worms and your plants
are one thing but should I go out and
get some worms would that be beneficial
at the beginning of us you know when I
first put the plants out there I don't
think it would hurt
that's your feeding bottled nutrients
there's a lot of I've never Tinley had
worms in indoor plants before but never
purposely so pop mushrooms in your soil
on accident those changes yeah I got
some crazy coke grow Kashi compost going
on right now that's about to start doing
some mushrooms nice shout-out to the
probiotic farmers alliance in genetics
key play with that looks great looks
amazing you know I've been talking with
Jesse a lot about farming and stuff and
talking to not talking to the listening
to a guy named Jim frere on Facebook
he's a excellent grower he's he's a
scientist dude he's awesome he's a
organic chemistry guy he does a lot of
things between all use organic farmers
and you outdoor guys I need a compost
pile I'm a vegetarian and I'm over there
chopping up pineapple watermelon
strawberries kale lettuce onions
tomatoes carrots cucumbers whatever else
you brought me today I didn't even get
to look into the bag
but I chopped up all that and every one
of those has a piece that you chopped
off and don't eat I mean that little
motor the stem comes out or the little
tip that's funky
for sure bananas have a peel my avocado
I need a ton of avocados they all have a
peel they always have some shitty brown
spot in them no throw that damn trash in
the compost pile all of that no just try
the girl cause she just what I've been
doing is just a bucket I've got one
right now it's just all veggie scraps
which would be all greens I've got
another one I'm doing started a little
earlier it's half carbon half grains
explain the carbon to the retards greens
are living things carbon would be like
peat moss I've I suppose would be carbon
coconut or cocoa shell tried up sticks
try to believe that shells
that's eggshells but you have to have a
50/50 mixture well you don't have to
have but two guys ideal yeah I'm not to
get what you're shooting for yeah yeah
all right so I just took that 1/3 cup
1/3 of a cup of cocoa she makes that
[ __ ] in there threw it away six days
later I mean I can visually see stuff
turning into humate you know can you
send one to my phone and then let me
tweet that from the shows stuff for sure
I totally will tweet jessee's and I've
lots of different styles of composting
before and this is hands down the
easiest yeah that sounds right up my
alley I'm super stoked because they'll
be able have fresh compost all through
the one I can
oh that soil is ready to grow some [ __ ]
dude oh man that's and just and then
just add that to my let it go for like a
month
nice kind of what I was reading from
this guy yeah I'm gonna sift it out but
if it needs to be a which is like a 1/4
inch screen
you just take it all dump it on there
sift it through it'll catch anything
that's not composted yet and then
everything that comes through is BAM was
beautiful beautiful beautiful compost
that's guys I'm sold on that that was a
quick rundown and I'm sold on that two
five-gallon buckets and some table
scraps and a bag of grow Kashi then you
make an awesome compost let's see I got
a picture of this was day one it's a
bunch of celery some coffee tiles or
carbon okay almost everything I eat yeah
I've just you always got something yeah
there's always watermelon has a Ryan
little green thing at the tip
everything's got something some sort of
waste to it bananas have a peel like I
was saying everything comes off the vine
at some point and where usually where it
comes off the vine we as American
[Music]
experiment with some you know scraps
from different grows and stuff like that
yeah clean leaves clean leaves old stems
could be my my fiber part carbon part
for sure
awesome that's a great idea man you guys
just learned something with me I'm glad
we could all learn that your fan leaves
to buy a juicer I also have another way
of composting this is actually the
easiest way composting I've ever
discovered I feed it to my chickens all
right what was about to say oh I don't
even remember there were so many things
happening to my brain just now that's a
lot let's get back on topic here it's
not serious
yeah all the stuff we're eating we
should think about what we put into
ourselves cuz that's what we should be
feeding our plants kind of the same way
you don't want to feed your plants
watermelons but like think about what's
in what yeah think about your health
think about your pie health it's all the
same [ __ ] once you start paying
attention you'll match up you'll start
feeling better you'll definitely pay
attention I notice that from the last
show that you were here and you said you
know
we we go out and we spend the money on
expensive bud and expensive water and
then we just put 99 I'm the worst at
that dude I've been I told her straight
up after that I go get meals go make
food for sure it's fun I mean me and my
wife cooked together so I didn't do that
[Music]
fun
I cooked lunch with a little lady today
and it was a great time I cook for her
sometimes usually she can't make bacon
the best but I'm saying see well that's
your job and you make the bacon that's
why they said making bacon bacon the
bacon yep yep all right let's get back
on track maybe a little bit I agree with
you but I mean if you want to say try to
get drinking and driving as cool off to
children let's you know let's clarify
that and it's like okay you know but
he's slammed by the end of every show
[Music]
all right
we're hitting flour hard our plants are
in flour were shown the fuzzies we
pulled our mails we've topped dressed
our worms are happy we've switched to
full bloom nutrients they're feeding
your feet even bottled nutrients go
lightly on the nitrogen there the grow
or the bloom stuff now if you're feeding
teas and stuff what should we be mixing
into our teas at this time seabird guano
that's pretty much where I get all my
nitrogen for the bloom faced from okay
and then also most sea bird guano's
typically you know kind of high in pee
least a little bit yeah
[Music]
the actually had a conversation with
this listener
he's a shopper so that's a lot of
support he Shops at the stores I
recommend he buys the seeds I recommend
he grows products I recommend he listens
to he listens to your advice to the
[ __ ] ward bro he wants to success is
proven and he wants to do what we are
doing so he was a loyal listener he's
become my friend he's gonna come hang
out with us the next time he was away
from my pocket but just because I feel
like I'm not the wrong guy we're gonna
go look right now we're going to
Facebook get this out before it yeah the
high P bat guano's if you got him you
know that's they're good they're not
very sustainable any of those bat
guano's really really suck but it is
what it is so don't you know not
everyone's just conflicted as I am I
suppose but I'm sure I got the right guy
yeah nice I'm happy now sweet but uh
yeah switch to the high P and rock it
out any molasses yeah I always do
I always do molasses almost every feat
in flower after a 21 passes or something
similar humble honey the Mendocino honey
those are I like the humble because it's
got the yucca extract in there
it's dirty cheap there might be yucca
extract in that one but not as much oh
he's taking a pretty big dad right now
carb cap if you want it there you go
it was just hard to pull it up with that
other dad or how it needed the cutting
edge on that one brother fishbone mill
that's always high in P that's some good
stuff too and I always go with the kelp
so and I've noticed something
I wonder what's up with this I've had
some kelp that is one zero one and then
I just recently bought some kelp that is
zero zero one
it's the exact same strained or you know
if that's to the assister right from and
it's that whatever strain that you
always see but yeah I wonder what's up
with that you know I don't pay enough
attention to the packaging I should
start looking at that there are certain
things I never pay attention to because
you know the look on my face doesn't
convey a podcast but I have got a very
curious look now like huh do they make
different packaging for different runs
or because you know different companies
- okay it's - I mean where did the
nitrogen come from all the sudden you
know yeah this be the same product yeah
just different testing calibrations for
sure yeah well they supposed to be
standardized though supposed to be
supposed to be supposed to alright it's
my turn I'm gonna take this bag big
dabbas gonna give it to Adam but I
realize how big it is and he doesn't
want to do this
it doesn't do that sort of thing
lightweight homeo I should ask a
question before I take a DAB
I asked about T's asked about feeding uh
it's time to finally train those things
right now if we want to do any LST
training or anything like that we better
do it before they start butting out like
crazy
give them some sticks to support
themselves I said support themselves
support I guess I'm excited about this
tab so tell us about what we need to do
and then we will talk about after that
we'll talk about problems to look for
and the biggest fear of all gardeners
we'll talk about those two things so I'm
gonna take your data Jesse will talk
[Music]
let's see so word [ __ ] I'm stoned we're
training so if you got the bamboos I
kind of like to stick them in the ground
as an angle attach the plant at a at a
lower angle on the bamboo so that it's
still going past it are you angling in
toward the pot or out from the center of
the yeah
so you actually went to the bud dangling
above the bamboo and that kind of gives
it a chance to develop its its girth and
then just gonna kind of fall towards the
bamboo and and you wrap it up kind of
predict where it's gonna fall yeah also
I mean just straight up bamboos without
doors make sure you tell your plants in
at least two places the wind once you
start pinning plants with bamboos and
steaks and stuff like that
[Music]
he knows this you put them be you know
the supplies in dorks to but make sure
you get him tied up and good in two
places real good so that anything
doesn't break over there was such a
stone bramble that was perfect you said
exactly what needed to be said while
Adam and I both got to take a DAB and
kind of get our [ __ ] back to
I gave us big dads um see now I'm kind
of new to the bamboo sneaking just
because I never had plants big enough to
even need stuff like that
I can asked him he told me the same
thing the other day and I asked him you
know what's really the purpose of it and
he's like you know just to hold it there
now I have a tomato cage and I went out
I purchased the only sticks that were
because you know living here in Colorado
things are not quite as available as you
think they would I had to you know I got
little ones with the little rings in
them the I can just hold up my side
because those ones right now I figure I
can just tie it with a loose string I
got some branches coming in you know
just holding it up against the the the
tomato cage so yeah I mean if nothing
else you could you know that may be an
earlier stage running through the tomato
cage or yeah yeah the way you did it is
perfect though the only thing that Adam
did wrong is he tried to put the tomato
cages on a little late so he had to
struggle with that next time I'll show
you a really smooth trick it takes like
a I use a twisty tie or a [ __ ] like a
pipe cleaner than home fuzzy sticks just
grab the plant from the bottom and go up
and then just tie that [ __ ] in a couple
of spots then you get a slide the cage
on for the size cages I got I think it
was still a little too late for that cuz
I tried that trick when I went out and
bought the last one and it was just like
no no no I just stuck it down in the
middle and it kind of branched it all
out yeah there you go you can also cut
them open and then just wire them back
together but next year I plan to to have
the small square fence lines around
that's something that I've been seeing a
lot lately on you know so I actually
tomorrow have to try to put one on
actually sell a 16-inch tomato cage that
comes apart
the sticks are three different pieces
and the cage is two different loops that
come apart so you can put that on after
I really endorse those tomato cages
yeah they're good mother a good product
I like them actually might have learned
about him through some cool hey my
ninety-nine cents so I can't really
complain when it's user error trying to
get it on to something all right that
was Adams words of the wisdom yep
so problems you guys were talking about
moths and worms what the [ __ ] they are
referred to in America as Kornberg
borers and here's a little side
conversation they're actually in Europe
called ahem poor when Prohibition hit
the wasn't anymore hint plants around so
they went for corn and jet you know a
little bit on here that's not quiet I
know what a hillbilly knows I don't know
what a he's about to read for us
hopefully the European corn borer all
right yeah I'm just reading it straight
from Wikipedia the European corn were
more European corn borer also known as
the European high flyers a pest of grain
particularly maize the insect is native
to Europe originally infesting varieties
of millet including green card it's an
ugly [ __ ] bug dude so huge yeah well
it says the European corn borer
caterpillars damage the ears of corn as
well as stalks by chewing tunnels in
which to which caused the plant to fall
over biological control agents of corn
borers include sorry I'm just gonna read
that part yeah but they dig a tunnel in
there I can't see and read it all and
then they lay a little eggs in there and
then it shows these [ __ ] disgusting
orange worms that grow out of there this
is when I got all freaked out like what
is this dark spot on my plant you know
this is the kind of stuff that I knew
that stuff will burrow and lay eggs
inside of and then rot from the inside
out
I've never seen him like in the stalkers
mine were like right at the base they
lay clusters of eggs on the leaves
usually the undersides the egg masses or
clusters relate an overlap in an
overlapping configuration a lot of it
develop inside the eggs become more
trousseau
things are ugly they eventually turn
into a flying insect I believe yeah well
they fly they land on the plant they
burrow in or they lay eggs on the bottom
then they turn to these worms at 200
plants also so the original flying thing
eat your plant the new worm they left
eat your plant and then it turns into a
flying thing that eat your plant comes
back and drops more of these [ __ ]
demon bugs on your plant yeah yeah good
ways to get rid of them
prevention is the best way I've came up
with I've spent hours dude picking them
out by hand because wow they they
destroyed you know fortunately it's not
gonna destroy an entire crop and at the
end of the year it is very easy to
locate
they're looking for our good old friend
neem oil but it really sucks cuz you're
spraying neem oil on a flower I was
gonna ask is that product okay with
flowers but I mean not anymore
I know a neem oil doesn't yeah don't put
neem oil under flowers monterrey what
can you do yeah I mean it's yeah that's
that I sprayed my plants with it all
through veg riously
arranged every four days they got
sprayed with something different mixed
it up kept it all the gunk and yep yeah
so there's something to scare those
plants away yeah those bugs away
sorry an ounce of prevention is worth a
pound of cure that's the God truth there
you know for sure alright so so we've
gotten man
[ __ ] the moths that's gross I wonder -
dude they're like the size of a bit
lighter but except triangular so your
praying mantis isn't gonna do [ __ ]
against those no actually no it's great
to watch yeah oh yeah I've seen one rip
it out of the bug yeah it's pretty good
moth dust in your mouth gross so those
things are huge - I've seen them it's a
cool story that you [ __ ] said that
they used to be
hemp moths before they were a corn
because wiki didn't say anything about
that
probably links me to those yeah same
here we'll do it just for fun
otherwise known as the corn moth right
there did you mean this yeah actually uh
an old timer told me that there's not a
wiki for it but there's all weeds nasty
bugs it's the same picture yeah yep like
forever ago it was professional now we
have talked about moths and worms do you
see other than the obvious problem that
you know I'm gonna bring up do you what
are any other problems we can look for
right now that we can work with right
now we can kind of try to prevent you
know I mean it's still pretty early in
flowering so you know spider mites are
gonna come up and you know if you don't
have a lot of air circulation and it
gets moist and I mean creates the
conditions for powdery mold
plan for the worst alright so get the
damn I can't remember any brand names
tonight bhakti nove mesto rocks
that's for powdery mildew yeah actively
yeah Jessie shots that out I'm testing a
product called witch's brew
well as soon as I find a situation to
use it in not to be a dick but but yeah
it's called witch's proof and supposedly
it's just like totally annihilate
powdery mildew but it's totally organic
and made in up in Denver somewhere maybe
Boulder you know up north summer so I'm
is cheap too and a lot of you guys are
sorry I don't mean to cut you off no
you're you look like you might need a
hand you guys are not in places where
you're able to walk into a hydro shop
and be like you I need forgiveness ed
sorry hit the volume button on the wrong
way there you can't be like I need a big
bottle of Monterey Spray so Tennessee
Georgia Florida that might I don't
condone your growing I can't support
that don't [ __ ] do that illegal
against the law
that's up to you you're a grown man but
if you happen to be doing that cuz I
can't condone it already for the right
to do that yeah but but I'll go to jail
if I say hey you in Kentucky girl [ __ ]
weed but if you insist on doing it you
can get your products at like Lowe's and
Home Depot if you're really careful
about what you do look for that Omri
certified [ __ ] there are a few products
that Monterey sprayed that we were
talking about just as Monterey insects
brands but it says contain spinosad
right on the bottle spinosad kills a lot
of insects that you'll find on the
garden yeah it's organic it's safe neem
oil is also out there neem oil is there
for veg you should use neem oil and veg
often it's your friend it's cheap it's
affordable you can dilute it and you're
really not gonna hurt anything unless
use it in flour even spray the ground
around
yeah yeah I saw a product I can't
remember the name but it contains white
oil it's a little tiny bottle it's nine
bucks it's got some white oil in it I
have not used it yet but I'm sure that
that would knock out your flying insects
and mites really quickly I'll have to
research the name but it look for it
guys if you need some stuff you can
actually get your products at a Home
Depot or Lowe's or something similar
just be careful don't be discreet don't
talk about your weed when you're at any
store even the hydro shop the only place
you can talk about your grow is in your
grow or at your table with your true
we're talking about problems in a garden
right now we're gonna we're talking
about bugs and [ __ ] one more thing is
[ __ ] homies and [ __ ] be careful who
you tell everybody's your friend today
but in like a week when you guys have
the stupidest fight over the dumbest
song on the radio that reminded you with
that girl oh you were with her to [ __ ]
you now you're not friends anymore
he's got aggro officer or we're gonna
steal his grower everybody in Colorado
grows there's so much of it here that
it's not is threatening it's not as
crazy everyone's draw their own crops
here but you guys that are in those
other places just be careful with your
grow you guys have been I might have
grown a planner too before medical and
there was no such thing as talking to
anyone about it yeah
anyone at all I remember that vibe when
you go to the hydro shop before
everybody had a medical card it was
hideous you could hear the cashier going
as she run up your [ __ ] in the hydro
store and she'd mumbled numbers cuz she
didn't want Jesse to hear how much I
just [ __ ] spent at the hydro shop so
paper or the classic are you gonna say
when you run into friends at the hydro
shop if you and I used to run into each
other hey bro can I get a cut of that
White Widow sure I'll trade you for that
great up for weed
the shop owner will tell you to shut up
in there that never happened to me at
least back then and I've just alright
Jesse's got a horror story he's gonna
share with me after the podcast anything
that I ever had outside and was like yo
check this out it was gone know what
yeah it's always your friends I mean
that's I'm here to tell you right now
nine times out of ten if something
stolen from me it's somebody you know
you know I'm saying it's somebody you
bragged about so you just you know keep
it quiet they just talk randomly and if
they don't have any business being there
don't bring girls if you're just trying
to be cool don't bring girls to your
grow to be cool
that's failure I've seen women bring
down girl rooms until the harvest it's
like I love you ladies I love the loyal
ladies boil to their man but so many
girls don't know when to stop talking
about the growing room that you saw and
that's not your fault
I'm a man that's that guy's fault for
taking into the growing room without
knowing you well enough I may or may not
have had a plant snapped in half times
all right so this leads us to something
that we all dread other than the police
in Colorado we don't worry a lot about
the police anymore we all obey the law
we either have a medical marijuana card
or we are an adult in Colorado any adult
over 21 can grow six plants I think
you're allowed to grow six plants at any
house I don't know that if Jesse and I
lived in the same house I don't know if
we could grow twelve outside I don't
know how that works but as a medical
marijuana provider a lot of us have
increased counts you look like you might
have something to add to that I've heard
it does okay but you know I don't I want
to be accused of giving anyone illegal
I'm in that spectrum you know I'm saying
of where I'm allowed to have six plants
but I'm allowed to have three flowering
and three I'm not firing right that's
the law in Colorado you can have six
plants three and flower three not in
flower I don't know the the freaking
logistics or whatever the bottom into
the fine print I don't know if
if Adam and I and Jesse lived together
can we do 18 plants in the backyard I'm
not sure they seem to kind of be up on
that they kind of seem to cock-block
along those moves they're smart Colin so
they're catching on anyway
we digress Jesse's walking so he's
tiptoeing and his Jordans through the
kitchen trying to get a bottle of water
I actually heard a rumor that County is
going to state so that could happen that
sounds like [ __ ] that Pueblo does but
yeah so we're allowed to have six plants
God you just [ __ ] change my whole
thought process I'm like we're gonna
have to go political well I got a
setting with the town hall meeting the
other day with Sal pace it was pretty
much a he was campaigning for himself
but uh ad he did someone brought up
marijuana and he was real quick to bring
up the fact that uh they're planning on
in stating that and so I've already
called him twice and I left a message at
the end of the town hall meeting so yeah
those little tiny hydro plants are like
six inches tall you wouldn't be able to
get [ __ ] off it yeah he need
clarification it was he just talking
recreational that's okay yeah we'll get
into this and figure out what's going on
so far it's just the start we've talked
about bringing the wrong people to your
grow we've talked about trying to
impress chicks here's the biggest
[ __ ] problem thieves you guys people
are gonna steal your outdoor weed it's
gonna happen if you go for three years
in a row one of those years you're not
gonna get a harvest it's gonna be
[ __ ] stolen take a break that's
that's the old-school rule do two times
take a break find a spot yeah okay two
years later a year later okay make sure
they're gonna know that crop is there
they'll go and look in the really coats
not here I give up
all right so things are gonna come your
garden I don't even want to talk too
much about this story it's just
something that needs to be
recently in our community a
thirteen-year-old boy was shot in the
back because he was attempting to steal
somebody's outdoor marijuana grow the
dude was arrested he's in [ __ ] jail
he's gonna go to court he shot that
person in the back I wasn't there what
I'd like to point out this was a pellet
oh yes it wasn't a high-caliber pellet
gun pellet is now was not an actual
firearm right but the pellet is lodged
in this kid's organs and he had to be
taken to Denver Children's Hospital to
be rescue you almost died he's in
critical condition I'm not on either one
of these guys sides I'm not on the
shooters side I'm not on the kid's side
the kid was a thief he was in the yard
he was actually the newspaper said he
was out of the yard and he shot him in
the back but we're just gonna act like
that he was right next to the pot plants
in this story think about this it's
[ __ ] 3:00 in the mornings with it but
he was part of a gang as well okay yeah
if there's multiple than he got it so
he's the one that got it then yeah he's
the one let's let's put everybody that's
listening to this that has an outdoor
crop I want to put this story in their
heads right now it's 3:00 you've got
your pot plants outside it's like seven
days before you cut them down you've got
a hard-on you're just [ __ ] droolin
you're rubbing your hands together like
it's like a porno is strip about to
start your [ __ ] droolin like food is
cooking you're about to go on the ride
of your life you got your outdoor crop
about to come down it's 3:00 in the
morning you get woken up to the dogs
going nuts you get woken up to the
[ __ ] lights coming on you look on
your security cameras that hopefully you
have we're gonna talk to a couple in a
couple of seconds about things to do to
prevent some thieves but I want to set
this story here what are you gonna do
those alarms are going off the [ __ ]
up on your security camera you can see
them cutting down your plant he's about
to it's a [ __ ] 19 year old kid he's
wearing a black hoodie you can't tell
who he is he's about to run out of your
yard here in Colorado
like a 90% chance there's a gun in your
house probably you got a baseball bat if
you're a camper you got a machete think
about what you're gonna do because it it
could happen to you and you could walk
out there and put yourself in a more
dangerous situation than what you're
ready for you could walk out there and
be like this guy in our town that shot
somebody and has to deal with a kid that
could die right now
and I don't think that that kid's life
was worth any
in my house if you want something I'll
let you have it when I won't kill you
and that sounds like something [ __ ]
stupid to say but if you need it that
bad it's not worth killing me for I'll
make more money I'll grow more next year
leave my mother plants in my seeds where
they are will be just fine you haven't
liked that where is somebody like me who
is depending you know on those three
plants not only for me but for my old
lady you know and it's it would be rough
for that you know I'm trying to put that
story in these growers heads now these
new folks had said haven't had to deal
with this let me break it down from the
from the suspects perspective he's you
know he got woken up at 2:30 in the
morning he grabbed her of BB gun and he
shot someone in his yard
protecting his plants in an effort to
protect his plants well the cops showed
up because he shot someone and the cop
saw his plants and he shot someone and
the cops realized that he valued his
plants more than he valued human life so
now he's sitting in a jail cell because
these people otherwise didn't you know
he was yeah well I'm highly conflicted
on this I don't even if he gets away
with it
his face has been on the paper his
plants are still there everyone in town
knows they're there the cops won't touch
him because they're not gonna maintain
that evidence so he's gonna just spend
lower fees he probably lost his job his
dad's been on the news and even if he
gets away with it all he still lost his
plants was it worth it I mean so just
don't do it yeah like you know you just
coming out the door with the pellet gun
you can walk out put yourself in worse
danger than what you
prepared for to deal with for those
plants and if you love your dogs don't
turn them out either yep yeah plants
like it this sucks man it's happened to
me they're gonna run off hopefully turn
the lights on yeah if you can get a good
look at the situation try to scare them
off you know maybe he's gotta elevated
you know maybe you can walk out on a
back balcony or shot like that you know
just scaring them off you know throwing
a rock at him I don't see you know with
the damn hand sighs Rock and probably
that's true that's true yeah that's my
point is think about be prepared what
you're gonna do because I don't want you
to have to the only way to be prepared
for that situation is to think about it
today while I'm telling you about it so
that when someone's in your yard
stealing your [ __ ] you don't panic and
[ __ ] your pants hopefully if you prepare
for it think about it you've got a plan
of action you know how to get out there
quickly you know how to get rid of a
thief I don't want anybody to try to be
your hero for a pot plant I don't want
to hear about anybody else shoot more
people for weed plants we don't need
that kind of publicity
I think the gangs in jail for you know
anything industry yeah just yes we don't
need that so in Colorado we shouldn't be
growing enough to make it worth robbing
us which that sounds weird yeah and and
don't don't we're not defending thieves
yeah they are the lowest you know we
worked so hard for what we have and in
one night in a couple hours they take it
all away from you and you know they
leave it scattered down in your alley so
you have to clean it up at 8 o'clock in
the morning and your neighbors you know
finally realized what this but you know
it's just it's not worth it yeah I've
had one plan taken from me I've grown
one plant outside got something I got
taken from me one [ __ ] plan
neighborhood that plant was in a nice
backyard tucked away
the gardener's are the ones that [ __ ]
took that yeah yeah like I have never
grown in my own yard before or anything
like that and the year I tried it it got
taken so three plants so damn yeah so I
guess we scared the [ __ ] just be
prepared guys I'm not I don't know what
you're gonna do I don't want you to
shoot people I don't want you to fight
people I want you to protect your crop
peacefully use your voice scare the [ __ ]
out of them at your cousin or I'll beat
his [ __ ] ass example if you're
stealing Adams plants and he catches you
Adams [ __ ] if he walks out and tries
to stop you if Adams stealing your
plants and you catch him Adam is [ __ ]
if you try the array of outcomes could
be very broad if there's a thief in your
yard cuz but then again me knowing that
I'm going to steal his plants I'm not
probably not coming with just my little
mini arms either right I'm saying that's
and but you're going to his house so you
know he's got more than his big ass yeah
[Music]
yeah outside next month or next year
yeah try again next year
girl doors so don't shoot thieves that's
my advice please jail sucks you don't
want to go to jail we need to talk about
if we don't want to lose our plants and
treat people how can we prevent this
dogs right Big John dogs in your
backyard keeping them through that night
don't you're gonna use them as security
don't believe them you know don't you
know these these are working dogs they
need to stay outside and have a good dog
house it's summer yeah yeah it's summer
in Colorado they should be outside
protecting your [ __ ] yeah I like a
mixture of big dogs and little bugs
those little yappy dogs they wake up the
big ones and then and then it's on
yeah [ __ ] big pit bulls have come to
business we've got one he doesn't sleep
during the night during the summer he's
just gotten those crops are important so
also if your dog bites somebody you're
gonna have to [ __ ] deal with that put
your dog in quarantine make it as a nap
make sure it doesn't have rabies if your
dog really eats the [ __ ] out of somebody
hopefully it doesn't come to that
hopefully I want to use two dogs as
examples if I got into a yard and Ciroc
and Nana rushed me and barked at me I
would be gone I'm not a very good runner
but I would run a record lap with those
two dogs behind me so hopefully that's
all you gotta do though
yeah lights and cameras for your best
friend white some cameras or anybody's
best friend if you live in a sketchy
hood put some lights and cameras up on
your house
floodlights and cameras and once people
see those cameras they know that it's
really still a lot of aroma yet so you
guys hung bells on your plants just like
their Christmas decorations is that
effective it would be and what use are
cowards it doesn't take much to scare
them off okay especially I mean put
yourselves in their shoes they're in
someone's backyard they do not know in
the middle of the night it is and
they're doing something you know they're
breaking two or three rules and and laws
and all kinds of [ __ ] it's not gonna
take much to spook them and it's likely
somebody you know so they don't want you
to see their face
yeah or their clothes or their don't
tell anybody about those either
like you know tuck them up in there
another when mine got taken uh they were
heavily heavily bamboo I had uh you know
kind of ADA they will freaking Bush
outta one little thing and the bamboos
actually played it was hard for them to
pull the plants out you know I still had
you know a couple branches left to each
one you know so the bamboo serve couple
purposes
oh go ahead you might be leading to what
I was gonna say if they ever tripped and
fell onto you know it works good for the
VC so a great point Jesse brought up
earlier guys be friends with your
neighbors be a friendly polite courteous
neighbor keep your yard clean keep your
backyard clean keep your music down keep
your Gro discreet and make friends with
your neighbors and if you think they're
legit you can almost let them know
you're growing and not have to hide that
[ __ ]
and maybe sure with them smoke out your
neighbor and then they'll know that that
daint crop in the backyard they got to
keep an eye on it too and then maybe
they won't steal it from you cuz some
neighbors will check your [ __ ] but then
maybe if someone does come in the yard
they'll help you out also they'll keep
an eye on that [ __ ] because they know
that they've been keeping an eye on it
maybe you'll throw them an ounce or two
when it gets done maybe they'll come
over and help you trim you know our
neighbors on the farmer like so I made a
little spike shape on my paper here to
remind me to talk about something a lot
of you guys are gonna set some kind of
weird booby traps or some kind of thumbs
for the thieves to get hurt don't do
that yeah we can't condone that
that's just like shooting somebody it's
just like let your dogs out you're gonna
get in trouble for that you don't get
manslaughter I think there's also ten
places called man trapping don't don't
do it
yeah and it really really pisses cops
off when they see it because they think
oh I could have stepped on that that's
mm especially if you're in a legal state
you know what if they what does they
arrest you at the front door you know
and they lead you to the car and they
just go walking around
it's dark you know I mean step on
whatever you put in you just assaulted a
police officer it wasn't not not doing
anything you're handcuffed yep
let's if if you're doing things like
this that's you've probably got a
substantial crop and you probably doing
a lot of things wrong and you're not
really doing anyone but your sofa
there's those somebody showed me a
Google map I might have talked about
this a Google map where there's a
community in NorCal dude set up like
lots of housing it's like Jesse owns one
lot Adam owns another I owned another
but divided all this land and set up
gigantic crops
looks like you built it looks like one
guy set up all these crops for all these
families so those guys have a lot on the
line man what if somebody goes in there
and tries to take ten of those plants
they've got a lot to [ __ ] lose those
are five ten pound plants each yeah I
would hope at that point of scale you
know you can pay two dudes to sit around
with flashlights like the ones awake in
oil I don't even want to set up the
scene for a shitty movie but that's a
lot of money on that mountain bro
there's a sure window when it's done and
not harvested but could be cut when the
growers are trying to let it get that
final few days yeah man just a few the
three of us the house dressed out here
sorry to cut you off no you're good
[Music]
could you imagine just like so another
thing that can help you from getting
ripped off I wrote this real big we
talked about it be discreet always quit
showing everybody quit talking about it
it's so much fun to post Instagram
pictures and [ __ ] though man
but there's a way to take pride in your
work though you know like save all those
pictures
until the stuff is done you know and
then maybe say look what you know this
is the build up you don't have to post
an Instagram under your real [ __ ]
name either it's not even gonna call out
a couple of people that do it but I know
where you live and I know where your
backyards located and I see those
gigantic plants on your Instagram I'm a
nice guy not all of your friends and
your friends lists are you that's
taunting people don't show Jeolla
geographical landmarks in your pictures
yeah chiller your house stuff like yeah
the mountain in the background yeah yeah
we're gonna finish this part up if these
guys don't have anything to add and then
Adam and I are gonna come back we're
gonna go we're recording on a [ __ ]
Thursday right now mm-hmm Saturday Adam
and another friend and I are gonna go
see Joe Rogan at the Comedy Works in
Denver no I don't think we're gonna do
that but that is what Adam just said
with the funny look on his face we're
definitely gonna be Joe Rogan is
recording his next Comedy Central
special at Comedy Works Saturday night
and I was lucky enough to score some
tickets so and thank you by the way IRA
jannettek shirts and you know what I got
told I said they're 20 bucks
I'm looking for that 20 bucks so Adam
and I will be back in a couple of
minutes we're gonna take a couple of
dabs and wrap up this portion of the
show if you guys got anything fun to
save for the end of this part go ahead
and anybody cool I did not get to shout
out to people that listened back east my
homie stumps and QP James I know they
both listened so whose is that one of
your foot I don't I don't know a dick
foots a hellacious Twitter handle of
course that Apothic Ana that you you
know you recommended we did not and last
episode I know there's a way you can get
in touch with me he works for you would
probably make that happen whatever time
he had he could do it yeah I'm available
36 hours a day so Shawn if you listen
and bro come on the show we'd love to
have you we'd love to hear you talk
about organic as [ __ ] I know that's how
you roll I could learn from you the
listeners could definitely learn from
you we'd appreciate John so you
listeners you guys hear me inviting
somebody really cool on if we get him on
you'll be proud oh he really knows what
he's doing yeah yeah he's actually ran a
pretty cool little urban farm kind of
deal before so that's on the show you
can bring now you can bring the lady if
you want if that still happened
intervening a long time so hope I'm not
touching on a sore subject there
her either way she was always fun to
dabble with it looks like it's time to
wrap up the dab portion of the show I'm
gonna give one quick shout out to
dreadful Jay what's up mama thanks for
listenin to the show thanks for all your
support grow those seeds with all your
love um we're gonna take some dabs we'll
be back in just a couple of seconds
listen to the music shake your booty get
down alright guys thanks for joining us
for another grow episode I want to give
Jesse huge thanks for coming out I hope
you guys learned a whole bunch hey Adam
did you learn anything bro I sure did
man you look like your dad out over
there I'm [ __ ] high nice nice
speaking of [ __ ] high we had a super
great time last night
Adam myself and a little friend of ours
got to go see Joe Rogan record his next
stand-up comedy special for Comedy
Central at Comedy Works would you think
of that show bro
it was awesome dude i I've never seen a
professional comic so to say you know
I'm saying besides when we went up to
Denver but it was great man I woke up in
my cheeks and my ribs were still sore
from laughing so hard absolute my cheeks
yeah
Tony Hinchcliffe opened up for Joe Rogan
at Comedy Works last night he did 15
solid minutes every second of his set
was ripping you know it was he was a
funny dude I've never heard of him
before but he was definitely an
interesting comic he's a little dark
he's a little twisted so that was
perfect and then of course Joe Rogan is
a legend he crushed it yeah he came out
a little bit nervous I felt like he used
somebody tried to heckle Joe Rogan about
10 minutes into a set and that's when he
calmed he totally broke free of the
level of I'm recording a show and he
kind of chewed that lady a tiny bit of a
chewing of a new [ __ ] he just made
her feel really stupid for a second like
a comedian should do and went back about
his business I had a hell of a good time
so shout out to Joe Rogan it's gonna be
a great comedy spent Comedy Works is it
is a great setting it's a great place
yeah we eat dinner at a place called the
something mushroom you remember the name
bro the mellow mushroom mellow mushroom
yeah this was dank that pizza was
delicious our server was pretty chill it
was
the best pizzas I've ever had for sure
and I'm not really a big pizza fan yeah
you ate all the way to the end of the
crust and everything I ate all of it
yeah killed that large pizza between the
three of us it should have been enough
pizza for four people but three hi
people that was a good if you're
listening a guy named Phil approached me
after the comedy show and he asked me if
I was the guy that owns the seed company
because I mean I'm a tall white guy with
dreadlocks and I'm wearing it wearing an
IRA genetics t-shirt in the middle of
downtown Denver he's like do you own
that seed company I was like that's me
dude so Phil if you're listening to the
podcast if you founded the show
congratulations and thanks for your
support bro that was really cool meeting
somebody that just knew me from my seed
company and my Instagram and Facebook
presence that was kind of cool so shout
out to Phil bro do you have anybody you
need to give a shout out to in this
episode no man that's that's pretty much
it the guy's cool I feel like we kind of
ramble in the Joe Rogan part for a
second shout out to our friend Angela
they got to join us thanks for coming to
pizza and being a really cool passenger
it was fun we're gonna wrap up the show
if you guys ever get to go see a show at
Comedy Works go check it out it's a good
time Doug Benson will be there look I'm
giving Doug Benson a plug Doug Benson
will be there if you guys are pot
smokers and you live in Colorado go see
Doug Benson at Comedy Works I think the
date is September 15th to Monday I will
be there maybe we can arrange a little
smoke session so let me know if you want
to do that tweet me about it I drove
culture on Twitter or email me
agriculture at hotmail.com or of course
find me on Facebook under I grow culture
and we will we can smoke out at the Doug
Benson show after the show not in there
you can't smoke and comedy works they
will kick you the [ __ ] out I've got a
note here that says watch your mouth I'm
trying not to watch or I'm trying not to
cuss so much I know that's one of my
downfalls at being a great podcaster
I'll quit saying the f-word a lot
because it's really not good class
they're not good tastes so I'm gonna try
to quit I on the other hand you can talk
like a [ __ ] pirate if you want you're
not the host of a show yeah shout out to
all of our pirate friends all right guys
we're gonna wrap it up now that the show
is over please go to iTunes
search for agriculture find the review
section give us a five-star rating after
that type in a comment to let me know
what you think of the show if you're
listening to us on stitcher please leave
a comment there and give us a good
review all those reviews help the show
move up in the rankings which in turn
gets us more listeners I want to spread
my message to everyone who needs help or
wants grow information we have about a
thousand listeners on the past couple of
few episodes we crazy man a thousand
people are hearing us I think 1,100
listeners on episode 24 by the time I
looked the stats are a few days behind
because it takes a minute for the
analytics to get there but there were
1,100 listeners on episode 24 and this
is the night we're recording 26 so it
takes him two weeks and we get 1,100 in
the first week we usually get about 800
listens and the first week in episode is
posted so I wanted so awesome that's a
lot of people here in our message so I
wanna give a huge thank you to all 1,100
of you that are listening absolutely but
I want you guys to do me one favor 1100
of you were listening everybody tell two
of your friends about the iGrow culture
podcast this a man I was you know
everybody grows smokes loves weed has
something to do all know two stoners or
if it's your mom and she's afraid of
weed she can listen to us be semi
educated and we're good people
we preach a good message on the last
part of the Jesse we said don't shoot
people
absolutely so we're good people you can
you can break myths you can educate
people you can if somebody's lonely and
want someone to listen to we've got
great radio voices absolutely but yeah
you can spread the word so all 1100 of
you a thousand of you 1500 by the time
this episode posts all of you guys tell
two people and that way if one of them
listens to the show then we got three
thousand listeners and that's when
iTunes and stitcher really start paying
attention once you break that 2500
marker and that's that's all the the
ratings is really doing I mean it tells
people that the show is good but more
than anything else that helps your
relationship with iTunes or stitcher but
when it moves us up in the ranking it
shows people that we exist and then it's
like it's just our brand has more
integrity if more people are listening
people say oh people are listening it
must be worth listening and so you know
nobody you know
when you're seeing a killer band nobody
wants to dance until that first idiot
dances mm-hmm just dance guys get out
there and dance because people far
behind yeah yeah
nobody wants to be the first dancer but
those fifth and tenth dancers those guys
are all gonna love you for a break in
the ice so I just want more people can
learn how to grow high grade cannabis
less people will be afraid of cannabis
and more people will be properly
educated about cannabis and the things
that go with cannabis that's my goal I
want to you preach a good message
brother
I want to big up the weed lines I feel
like I'm an ambassador to the planet NOW
to the whole industry into the movement
I kind of speak I'm the voice you know
there's a few of us that have podcast
and we're starting to be recognized and
I want to be you're helping very
positive for the plant yeah I don't want
to be a bad vibe for the plant I don't
want people to think I'm a stupid
pothead people do cuz I take [ __ ]
granddad's and I have dreadlocks but
that's just that you know you prove them
wrong every day well thank you that's
really appreciated because I thank you
guys all for listening and I'm ranting
and rambling again so don't forget the
show's available on iTunes stitcher
swell a.m. and also every episode all
the way from episode 1 is on I read
genetics Colorado calm somebody told me
today a friend of mine that I just met
in person today another listener what's
up dust and shout out bro
Dustin was saying he listens to episode
he was listening to episodes 1 &amp; 2 and
he's starting to go from the very
beginning and he will catch up while he
gardens so what's up bro in quite a
while
you'll hear this 26 26 27 26 all right
so what do we do at the end we give a
big ol shout-out to my ninja Spence
what's up bro love you is supposed to
come hang out tonight I got tied up
doing a podcast we went a little later
than expected so a big shout-out to my
ninja Spence in the garden of Weeden
huge thanks again to all the listeners
thanks again for listening
take a phat dab hey Adam thanks for
coming so take that dad give your mom a
hug for me
yo it's Bobby hustle representing for
the real Big Bite sound Joseph Starr the
boy count playing we letting a broken
guitar hey yo nicotine you know we stay
smoking hard it's the hustle culture
podcast
they call me Rasta Jeff I'm your host
thanks for joining me got a very news
filled episode for you guys this week
joining me across the tables my buddy
Adam how you doing buddy what's up man
[Music]
we're doing 420 right wait a little 710
with our 420 smoking a big ol fat join
us some heart of gold this afternoon
anyway will be filled with a bunch of
news and some chatting because uh this
weekend the weekend that just passed by
the time this comes out this will be out
on a Monday that means that the weekend
I got to see fish at Dick's in Denver
and they played all of my favorite songs
and we had a wonderful time so that's my
prediction hopefully that comes true so
let's uh let's get to some ads real
quick here and then we'll get into some
news this podcast is brought to you by
nature's dream remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm 4-gauge
Green Genetics La Plata labs Sin City
rare dankness bio hi can adventure IRA
genetics and many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our loyal podcast listeners
use coupon code September 14 it's the
word September and the number 14 all one
word for 15% off any order and free
priority shipping coupon code is good
through the month of September and is
valid on any brand on the website big
thanks and mush respect to nature
Green remedies for the promotion and the
continued support
podcast is also brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 beach street unit F or stop by the
new publication on 618 East 4th Street
in Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to visit www.gfi.com/webmonitor
five hundred and fifty dollars or six
hundred dollars delivered anywhere in
the state of colorado big shout out to
hydro pueblo hydro Denver also port
parts of this podcast are brought to you
by our friends at tree hugger com sepsis
brought to you in part by tree hugger
comm live music lifestyle magazine check
out tree hugger comm for concert and
festival news and reviews woke out at
the cookout with tree hugger calm much
respect to Ryan a tree hugger thanks for
helping us out bro alright we're gonna
take a couple of dabs and then we add
them and I are gonna come back and
review a little bit of news we haven't
done the news in a while so we're gonna
get you nice and caught up I am gonna
turn up nicotine for a couple of seconds
while I take a DAB Adam if you want to
say anything now is your chance buddy
[Music]
the way you look it may be best if you
just keep your head down right now bro
I'm not even sure he's there you guys
[Music]
all right I want to give a huge shout
out to Spence and the entire garden of
Weeden crew I'm dabbing some some live
resin what strain is that I'm so high
just to Cadabby I can't even remember
what it's called oh gee thanks bro it's
written on there but it's upside down
over there I can't see it's the Eddie og
live resin it's dank it's so high I
couldn't remember the name or it's so
dank I couldn't remember the name of it
I'm all dabbed out right now and
everything sounds like I'm in a tunnel
it's epic
I just said the word epic alright guys I
am took off my brains out and then we're
gonna scroll to some news all right
check this out this news I found
entertaining this is coming from the
cannabis and it is by Ricardo Baca from
the cannabis staff the topic says pot
shop owner 80% of our customers come
from out of state Adams over there
shaking his head you're an out-of-stater
bro I do realize that when they check
your know if totally not yeah yeah I
just I feel that because I'm a red card
patient and the place that has my my
card or the place that I like to go to
anyways my preferred place is now
recreational and it's uh it's a line
there's a line to get in to get your
meds it's the same place you know they
can only take the same one to people
back at one time and it's the same
building same how long does that line
take you now I've been out there since
they've really done in besides one or
two times one time I've walked right in
there cuz there was nobody on there but
the other times there's been five or six
people ahead of me and people walk in
behind me and they're like oh no and
they turn to walk out yeah that's a long
time to wait we used at a shop downtown
they're not hurt and for the business
people would wait in line for an hour
because the whole front of the place
would be full all right I'm gonna get in
this article a little bit right it says
rhinorrhea Ryan
Griego owns a recreational pot shop in
Covent Southern Colorado
and he's putting out a bold informed
estimate saying that decidedly decidedly
clear majority of his customers are from
outside of Colorado I'm gonna take a big
breath here cuz I can't even read after
that dab I think the dispensary this guy
is from is actually they posted a really
cool shot of the can ASSU and this
article online here a really cool angle
of the sign and the building stylish
looking place with a great Colorado
background is that a dope shot a dope
shot right haha I didn't even mean that
pun alright I'm back on my game let's go
80% of my customers are coming from
other states predominantly Texas New
Mexico Kansas and Erica Arizona said
Griego owner of Kennesaw and pueblos
West which opened its doors in May for
recreational marijuana sales I knew
there would be out-of-state customers
coming in but I thought what thought it
would be more of a 30/70 split with 30%
of my customers from out of state but
it's more severe than that on the flip
flop
I don't think severe was right how does
the tourists account for 44% of all
retail sales and dinner in the Denver
area at about 90% in mountain resorts
such as Aspen or Telluride according to
a recent study produced by the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division as we've
talked about the marijuana Enforcement
Division or the Med they're the guys the
division in charge of regulating the
dispensaries and the grows and all of
that stuff they are in charge of the
marijuana and they regulate all of that
stuff they make the rules and they are
also are also a branch of the IRS so
that's pretty legit they're a huge place
that make a lot of rules they [ __ ]
put their foot down and it matters guys
tweet me every time I say the f-word
every time I say [ __ ] just tweet me and
tell me to stop doing it please go I'm
trying to stop doing that on the show
trying to cut that word out of my
vocabulary it's not even a cool word to
use for anything but anyway but for a
shop in Pueblo hardly considered in the
same tourism league as Aspen or
Telluride to make 80 percent of its
sales to out-of-state visitors is
something an oven anomaly even given
Pablo's proximity
less than 100 miles to the New Mexico
State Line they're not joking at all
about the differences between Aspen till
you ride compared to Pueblo Pueblo is
it's a cool place if you live here and
you know where you're going but is a
to steal town it's a steel mill town
it's a blue-collar working man's town
and Aspen and Telluride are places where
you go to spend some time we don't have
we have a reservoir here we've got a
Riverwalk here we've got some really
cool trails and things there's a castle
definitely nice to come and see but
there's nothing here to like oh it has
everything that a normal town has and
it's pretty yeah so to say that eighty
percent of our sales are going to
out-of-state visitors is kind of
shocking well we have a lot of
recreational weed shops here in the shop
that you're talking about is 100 percent
recreational so do you think that the
numbers are the same across the board at
the shops at the rec shops that it's
70/30
I think it depends on your product
that's true and that's something I was
gonna get at because the reason that the
Colorado market is not shopping in a
recreational shop we are either and I
haven't read this article in advance
very well I skimmed it because if I
found it interesting for the show I
think that a Colorado resident like you
did you became a resident you got your
medical marijuana recommendation from
the doctor you've got your red card now
you can shop at a medical shop and not
pay the 25 percent tax that's added on
to the REC weed and probably you get
better herb there I think if the Med
shops but also most of the Colorado
residents have been here and we have a
guy or a caregiver or just I literally
used the rec shops and until I got my
red card and then once I got my red card
then I I used it all the time you know I
don't I went into the wreck shop with
somebody who just came here recently and
I was looking for a certain product and
that's I went in there because for one
she had never done it before and it's an
experience you know everybody should go
yep there you go stuff is amazing I've
got a bottle of Apothic Anna
extra-strength pain cream arnica
peppermint juniper cannabis this stuff I
have said on this show that I'm
skeptical of topicals and lotions and
such 24 bucks this was actually kicked
down by the grimy Gatsby to me because I
mentioned
some shoulder pain I had a guest over
the other night who looked like hell
when they didn't look like they felt
good I was like what's up and they said
neck hurts and put some of this on my
hands and rubbed her neck for about ten
minutes and my hands were high my hands
yeah I hate to quote Pink Floyd but my
hands felt just like two balloons after
yeah I can only imagine what that girl's
neck felt like after I rub that I bet
yeah I'm sure Colorado cannabis that I
grew with a lightweight and it kind of
wrecked their world yeah that's funny
all right I'm gonna get a little back in
this article we got high and got
distracted shout out to the person that
got a massage with the freaking cannabis
arnica peppermint juniper cannabis
lotion from apothecary Jenna huge shout
out to Grammy Gatsby you guys don't even
know he's behind the scenes working [ __ ]
and you don't even know it this article
continues to say so how did Griego land
at these figures especially given the
state of Colorado's restrictions on
tracking recreational customers
information we keep seeing these
statistics and that's a question I've
raised twice now all right once and this
is the second time somebody's raised it
for me
go for it but you're you've already
explained it word they're not tracking
your name so much as they're just
tracking your purchase you know he
comments on it so he says we have a
media group that we hired on and they
monitor all of our social media and
Google Analytics and we've paid close
attention to the progression of people
searching on PCs and mobile devices
Griego said a lot of these numbers come
from inside the store everyone has to
show ID and we check IDs twice once in
reception and again in the dispensing
area plus our blood tenors are always
making friendly conversation asking
people where they're from
sure 80% is griego's educated guess but
while he knows he sees traffic locally
as well as from nearby weedless Colorado
towns Colorado Springs Wallenberg
Trinidad and Lahontan said he
says definitively that he sees more
Texans than anybody else our bro Kevin
works at a shop he's not here tonight
but he works at a dispensary and he says
it's a lot of Texans yeah
not surprisingly the out-of-state
customers are also spending more than
the Colorado Z said I want to know what
you guys are paying for herb you might
have we did this on my Facebook page on
the IRA genetics I want to know what you
guys are paying herb in your location
tweet me at I grow culture let me know
give me good don't tell me exactly where
you are but let me know what state
you're in maybe what part of that state
and let me know what good high grade or
whatever herb is available let me know
what it costs I'll tell you in Colorado
I don't go to the shops dude do you know
what it's heaven knows where that's I
just had a friend I think she said it
was for 60 as a caregiver my patients
you can find them for 350 if you shopped
around and it wasn't really like I want
this quality and this you know you can
still find it cheaper depending you know
where you want to go recreational all
right so I want to know if you guys are
paying huh on this street right now in
Colorado ounces depending on what you
want you can find an ounce for 150
dollars it's not the dank it's not the
chronic it's maybe biomedical but for
the fire it's about 200 blocks 225 for a
good dank outs right now in Colorado
dude if you got the hookups that top
shelf cush yeah if you go to the
dispensaries and get it it's gonna run
you for that same 225 200 all the routes
Wow all right it makes sense but and I
guess it's the Colorado people are
getting that stuff that their caregivers
are growing or they're buddies with the
caregiver dro or having some extra on or
something all that private cush is a
little bit better than the shop weed I
think it's it's harder for someone to
get on with the caregiver you know
especially if you don't have a medical
debilitating condition where you know
um I'm not I'm not medical because I'm
in a wheelchair that's for sure you know
or I have cancer issues knowing somebody
that you trust and want to assign as
your caregiver so here's something we
kind of skipped over guys we were
talking about caregiver and stuff when
you get a and now actually the word is
now provider in Colorado correct when
you're back in the day it was caregiver
but that was sounds confusing when you
get your medical marijuana
recommendation from a doctor there is no
license it's a recommendation it's not a
prescription they recommend that you use
medical cannabis they sign papers and
you send that paper into the Colorado
State registry and they send you back a
card that is a registry card that says
you are registered with state of
Colorado to use medical marijuana when
you fill out your paperwork you were
allowed to sign designate a person that
has called your provider which used to
be your caregiver this person the
paperwork says they have to be
responsible for something other than
just procuring your cannabis so you
should drive them to their medical
marijuana doctor's appointment you
should probably make them a kale
smoothie and work on their [ __ ]
person I said [ __ ] again somebody tweet
me and tell me to stop doing that I'm
trying I got a note in front of me still
watch your mouth so you make them it you
spend time with them you make them a
shake you try to do what their overall
well-being and if your caregiver I think
sitting like you and I do we hang out
I'm not your caregiver but when you're
having a bad day when something's
driving one of the guys is an older cat
his 60 year old guy and he's my bro
because like you come and sit on the
table sit at the table and we talk and
you feel better about that some people
that have AIDS cancer major [ __ ] they
don't have those people they need
someone to talk to you because a lot of
people are afraid of them once you're
sick people abandon you or you just need
a distance support you need extra
support even if those people are there
you can always use I'm a young energetic
youthful dude with a good attitude I
just spit right across the table at you
my bad I apologize for that one but I
didn't say [ __ ] about it I think being a
caregiver that's part of it going and I
write down spiritual counseling on my
when they say what else do you provide
as I make smoothies and shakes for these
guys that drive into their appointments
and I provide spiritual
just being your friend but so the
caregiver is a person that is
responsible for providing your medicine
the actual Colorado law does say that
they are allowed to charge you money to
cover the cost of your labor and your
lights and your expenses but you're not
supposed to profit off of caregiver
care get your caregiver ship your
provider ship so uh yeah you can so you
can be a caregiver in the state of
Colorado all you have to do is decide
that you want to be a caregiver and
learn how to grow and then find somebody
that trusts you enough and then work out
something with them the dispensaries I
don't think are the sinners don't give
you a good deal they just give you a
little bit of a discount my guys there
are people that I'm responsible for
right now there are four people and I
know pretty much exactly how much I can
predict when they need medicine I'll be
sitting around wow it's about time for a
patient a to give me a call tomorrow and
I'll put them a little package together
because I know what he needs and
[Music]
specific and exactly what they need you
know high CBD exactly I grow that Tora
Bora cut exactly the night nurse was
bred for a specific person his two
favorite strains are grateful dog and
Tora Bora and I bred them together
basically to make the perfect medicine
for one of my patients absolutely I went
that far for this guy plus I know it's
gonna be a killer string but I mean that
he was inspired that string on the table
if you want to give that thing a little
smell well thank you that's the night
nurse it's definitely frosty but DNA
genetics lets me use their Tora Bora
they gave me permission to breed with it
I've got their award-winning cut they
let me use that to breed to the grateful
dog and it came out pretty stinky smells
well I'm gonna run a bunch of tests errs
and maybe one day we'll put that to
market I definitely have
because I'm more of the indica smoker
where's your more this TV guy what's
weird about me I like indica flowers
if I'm gonna smoke a joint I wanted to
make me sick Wow like I just want joy
seems more like sitting in a hammock
with my feet up with the little
dreadlock girl cuddled up next to me and
some Grateful Dead on the radio and a
nice breeze that's smoking a joint dads
are like taking shots I don't drink
alcohol but it reminds me of when I used
to drink Jagermeister or tequila it's uh
it's more energetic it makes my head
spin a little bit more I don't relax
well after dabs it makes me want to do
[ __ ] yeah we won't do that tonight on
the show we will do a large job
it's almost time the large dad thing is
almost coming to an end I don't feel as
good about it as I used to I'm getting
older I guess your lungs have so many
inhales and exhales and I'm assuming by
doing a half I'm probably using multiple
inhale and exhales for each dad I'd like
to live a little bit longer than I
wanted to when I was a kid I didn't
realize one day I was gonna fall over
and die so uh we may do a grand finale
we may do like a Gram dab or a two gram
dab or something that's a long time I
just want to do it so that that way we
can retire the super large dad thing we
can put the dad challenges to arrest and
say hey we're all alive and we can do
the life challenge after that so we're
way off topic on this news thing weeds
expensive it could be 200 150 an ounce
but these shops are selling it for 500
now it's close enough so do you think
we'd ease expensive where you live even
though it's legal here it's not the
cheapest for recreational use yeah but
it's available yeah available between
the hours of 8 and 8 here's a random
question you're from a state where
cannabis was hard to get you've told me
stories about waiting on your deed for
hours and hours it was hard to get it
everybody is too busy there's other
drugs that are more important than your
okay
yeah it's Florida so you guys could
imagine what kind of hard I grew up
there so I moved back so would you
rather have
whoa the internet just it's refreshing
multiple times and freaking me out but
it went right back to where it was the
music didn't cut out so let's go would
you rather have
so street weed is cheaper a little bit
cheaper I'm gonna say thirty bucks an
eighth on the street how much is an
eighth of weed at the dispensary where
you would shop for recreational that you
can go get your med weed and how much is
it REC recreational sorry sixty bucks an
eighth holy crap so fifty five to sixty
just a parent which store would you
rather have the convenience of going to
the store and just paying the extra
money or would you rather sit there and
wait for some high ass dude to show up
with a sack that's probably know by a
gram or a just a joint you know from the
pre-roll or something like that we're
gonna get high and it was eight bucks or
ten bucks you know I'm saying and I
could go out there it cost you a little
bit of gas because it's here at the
outside of town but some places have it
you know closer closer yeah yeah you
know if I lived out there it'd be a
different story
but you could go buy a joint you know I
mean it's as simple as that and that to
me I'm not gonna go out there and do it
just because I yeah everybody in
Colorados a damn weed snob now I was
already a weeds move do you even flush
bro yeah to flush her weed we'll talk
about that in the future flush your weed
dude it's easy as one of the easiest
it's almost free and it's one of the
easiest things you can do just flush
your wheat it'll help out so much and
cure sure well that's a whole that's I
can talk for hours about curing weed
maybe I will one day what a lot of
people are failing on I see a lot of
Facebook post about does anybody in
Colorado know how to cure weed yes I do
and I'll share it well it's different
here what's dry here so you need to
build a humid room and control your
humidity all right I'm just ranting yeah
let me get back to the article because I
said I had a lot of news and if this
we're not gonna get a lot of news and
news story it's it's going the way it
should these out-of-state consumers
because remember we're talking about
people from out of state that's how far
it's been these out-of-state consumers
are spending much more than locals
Griego said they're spending about twice
as much as locals about 120 to 140
dollars edibles are the most popular
with these people
out-of-state consumers can buy up to 7
grams of cannabis total so you see them
by one to two grams of Bud and the rest
of their allotment made up of edible
products I'm not sure I am NOT up to
date with that rule we're gonna have to
look that up in the future here and talk
about that what is your edible what
helmet they don't really distinguish
between the two I've seen your edibles
for this is for recreational purposes
devastators how much does my edible
count as it was gonna be weighed by the
metric gram or whatever you know I mean
remember that we're gonna have to google
that we'll find that out for you guys
remind me to check that out we'll put
that on a future episode of course I
just saw fish this weekend after your
while you're listening to this so I'm
forgetful I need some some pep talks in
the future remind me alright yeah we're
gonna get back to the future across
state boundaries with legally purchased
Colorado marijuana does Griego and his
staff inform these consumers says
customer sorry about that very serious
state law and here's where I have the
problem this person that I got to try
that cream was very vocal inside the
store and asking where she could take
here said product since it was high in
CBD just product into you in general and
he after informing him after informing
her three times he kind of got like hey
can we stop saying
anything about taking it where you're
not supposed to that yeah I've already
said it's because when you come to go
Colorado Wed Adams kind of alluding to
is have some class be careful what you
say in the dispensaries no the answer is
no but not thinkin can I put this in my
car and go back to Texas no can I put
this in my suitcase and fly back to
California but what maybe maybe you're
not allowed to take it there's mg boxes
in the airport even there is ways to
California to fly and figure that one
out for yourself I'm not gonna encourage
you but you're not supposed to I'm gonna
leave all the medical states out of that
but no you're not supposed to leave
Colorado with Colorado marijuana
products you're really not supposed to
do that I shouldn't encourage it in any
way even if you're going to California
if you're going to [ __ ] Washington
yes and laws and procedures because I've
seen people you know for cups bring
right substantial amounts just in their
in their backpacks you know so there is
forms and procedures go through that if
you really want to do it but you're not
gonna be like can I bring my quarter
home to Kentucky you shop at
dispensaries this guy says when people
come in we're all about safety and state
compliance and we make sure that the
out-of-state consumers are aware
that they're the it says then they're
aware that they're purchasing their okay
this is written weird but it says there
is for in-state consumption only we also
remind them that they can't do it in
public is that true - the shops remind
you that's no fun you're there because
you have an out-of-state ID a few of
them have not all it just really depends
on how busy you know if they're having a
slow day there's ten people in the
waiting room they're not there they're
not informing you have nothing there
what you what you want okay how much
okay you can buy this much you most you
want to buy this much that's what it
really is
most of the recreational shops the
pre-rolls are actually just shake and
[ __ ] and you don't want it so does
that count the cuss jar that was that
fair hey check out the can of sewer in
this picture they have I'm not I don't
endorse any dispensary honestly I'm not
paid I'm not sponsored by any dispensary
I don't shop it most dispensaries and I
hate this picture is the picture the
canister here has a picture there got a
window cut out and you can see into
their grow room so if you are from
another state and you want to see a
pretty stylish looking grow room check
that out anything about their broad many
people it looks cool in this picture I
don't like I said I don't know what
their product is like if you go in there
and they sell you hey I apologize
so somebody looks like I may be right
about that you can say that on my show
you're allowed to have an opinion bro no
no no I just out of five stars how many
I've never been there
okay so I don't want to give any rating
all right I've just heard stories all
right yeah I've heard a lot of stories
as well from that a lot of the shops
here
80% of our customers are coming from out
of state so that's a good article there
I thought you guys would be interested
let's click over back to the recording
and see how many hours we've gone we're
at 30 minutes here we're gonna squeeze
in some more stuff you guys I sent an
email to Jodie Emery asking if I'm
allowed to play parts of a marc emery
video on a podcast and if i am i plan to
play a little bit of mark's speech that
he gave recently after he was released
from federal prison so i look forward to
doing that I need a drink yeah I watched
this and actually linked it to him it
was a powerful motivating speech he is
on the ball and if he does get you know
everybody should watch it you know we
can or we can just talk it's about you
know I mean let's click over here and
pause the music and then I think I'm
gonna play a little bit of this video I
wasn't prepared to do it but we're
talking about it and it seems like the
thing to do if you kind of play towards
the end of it it would kind of relay the
message more of it unless you want to
play the whole video later on how about
I'll play a couple of intro seconds when
he takes the mic he was introduced at
one point and he brought his friend back
on stage - that's good he gets
introduced Marc Emery is introduced by
somebody else mark Emery comes on stage
and gives thanks to another friend and
hands the mic to him that guy talks for
about eight minutes and then Marc Emery
comes back on stage and starts his
little not little his big speech will
start with it's about ten minutes and 25
seconds into the video we'll start there
I'm gonna give a shout out to the
YouTube page that I'm playing it from
I'm trying to be polite here these guys
are as permission I haven't gotten the
email back saying yes or no yet but uh
they're busy I feel like then let me do
it and it's Jodie Emery she's cool why
wouldn't she want marks preach the word
yeah and it's coming from pot TV on
YouTube it's on cannabis cannabis
cultures website big shout outs all
those guys so please I subscribe to you
so and thanks for your forgiveness if I
wasn't supposed to do this but I'm sure
you'd want this message out
and then we'll play a few seconds of it
and then we'll find out if we can play a
lot of it and if we can play a bunch
we'll go ahead and play that would be a
couple of minutes for everyone yeah guys
I'm gonna take a drink we'll take some
dads I'll start off this marc emery
video this was kind of a weird
transition here that would randomly
happened this is marc emery right after
he I think he's like 48 hours out of
prison when he did this absolutely
48 something like that he said so here
he goes I'm gonna click playing I will
have to adjust the sound while it goes
on I apologize we'll figure it out we
said that while I was in prison because
you know doing something lets almost use
the word no both doing something on
principle late you know giving a good
chunk of your life in sacrifice I guess
for principle even in prison was highly
regarded you know in the four and a half
years I was in prison I really never
heard an unkind word spoken to me by any
inmate and I was in a medium-security
prison for almost all that and a lot of
these people are serving life
imprisonment without parole they've come
down from the penitentiary they're
covered in tattoos they're badass dudes
a lot of the Marley's they think they
are and and they're serving horribly
long sentences by and large for drugs
mostly methamphetamine crack cocaine but
certainly there were many many people
there for marijuana serving 10 15 and
even in one case 25 years for marijuana
distribution so I was able to be very
productive in jail I wrote a lot I
blogged I read a book every week I had
25 magazine subscriptions I got the New
York Times every day I learned how to
play the bass guitar was it an
outstanding rock and roll band of
incredibly talented musicians and and
all of them were very patient in
teaching me at no charge for anything
music
music principles on how to be a bass
guitarist and I must tell you that it
was a very redemptive and meaningful
experience being in prison and I hope I
always carry the message forward that I
saw there that you know it is a very
wrong society that punishes people for
drugs and puts them in jail for decades
it takes them away from their family and
their children and essentially ruins
their life because of a lifestyle choice
they made and we manufacture crime with
the drug laws we actually act as mark
Emery can talk for quite a while and I
kind of fade out Adams telling me that I
should play the stuff at the end of the
video because it's a lot more moving and
compelling I'm gonna save that I'm gonna
do a little bit I'm gonna make sure that
I can get permission that was about a
minute and a half there I hope I don't
get in any kind of trouble if they take
down this episode I apologize all it was
was some news in a Marc Emery rant
anyway what I did in jail you know I
mean that's moving trust me but his
message is definitely what you need to
hear we need to do the video if they let
me play that I'll play the last few
minutes at the end of this show here I'm
gonna wait for the email try to be
respectful and if I don't get the email
by the time I post episode in Denver
part of this article I'm gonna kind of
paraphrase it cuz it's a lot of stuff in
episodes getting long already I got a
couple more things I want to read about
this is from the cannabis tall so this
was actually published August 12th it's
by Aleta
lebec from the cannabis staff I didn't
say that right I'm sure but I'm sorry
this one is so governor Hickenlooper
John Hickenlooper placed these giant
cages around places in Denver he put one
in front of a skate park he put one in
front of a library in Denver the Denver
Public Library and there are big cages
that look like your hamster cage and
they call it a lab rat cage
it's a lab rat cage that says don't be a
lab rat and it's on the inside it's got
a little thing that tells you about
cannabis and the problems that cannabis
can cause you and it's saying don't be a
lab rat to cannabis to encourage kids to
not smoke weed well if you put a big 12
foot tall lab rat looking cage with the
giant looks like those water bottles
that hang upside down that your hamster
licks to get water and then it's got a
little green thing on the outside that
talks about cannabis on it a little note
if you want to come round on the side of
the computer bro take a look it's
definitely worth looking at it's funny
you am i right it looks just like a
people cage for hamsters or a hamster
cage for people's it is a people cage
and so the article says well that didn't
take long
the state of Colorado debuted 'it's
don't be a lab rat youth campaign on
Monday August 11th by dropping human
size laboratory cages around the Denver
area including outside the Denver Public
Library and the downtown skate park
vandalize vandalized signs at the skate
park
installation were reported Monday
evening by cbs4 the cages feature
posters that cite controversial
marijuana research studies and ask
open-ended questions about about pot use
about youth pot use sorry that was a
hard sentence some cleverly crossed out
a reference to negative effects of
marijuana and changed it to positive
although another message left on the
poster says critically smoking weed
saved my life the campaign which targets
teens with messages that marijuana
research is ongoing particularly in
studies of studies of the developed
developing brain is trying a different
tact from the just say no anti-drug
campaigns of yore
there are a few variations of the
posters that adorn the giant cages so a
new message is sure to replace the
vandalized signs the vandalism was taken
in stride by dr. Lurie wolf who leads
the state health department if they are
defacing it or they're doing something
with regard to graffiti or gathering in
the cages at least they're taking notice
and let the debate occur they're
probably just breaking that [ __ ] there
while they're smoking a joint
oh there was also the man who toked up
inside the cage at the skate park
according to the TV station report you
know it's not like there's you know
obviously people got off their ass and
sign papers that it's legal here you
know the two million dollar project
which includes a stylized website is
funded by a grand by a grant paid by
illegal sediments with settlements with
various pharmaceutical companies
according to the governor's office
another component of the don't be a lab
rat lab rat campaign are the TV ads as
seen below we're not gonna watch these
pharma get off by telling you not to be
a lab rat but they they need your money
I get that they want you on zoloft
instead of wheat but yep well these most
of our listeners probably haven't seen
these gigantic lab rat cages it's quite
entertaining they've posted there are
three or four stories on the cannabis
about it you know that's a good idea we
should have gone and checked it out if
you want to jump around on this side
again and take a look there's actually
people inside of this one as they were
building it they'll move the email out
of the way that's that's the people cage
they're working with right there it's
essentially a lion cage yeah it's why it
looks like a lion cage it looks like a
large cat small enclosure there's a 10
by 10 by 10 by 10 by 10 yeah but then I
don't even think it's that it's probably
12 by 10 yeah and there's a lot of
scrutiny about how kind of ridiculous it
is to from a lot of people by the looks
of these websites so let me click and
see how long we're going because I don't
own a jail cell I'm just gonna keep
moving on with that one we are about 40
minutes in so we can keep going we got a
couple we can make this a perfect hour I
bet if we do this right all right I'll
try to save a couple of minutes for the
marc emery part if we get a chance to do
so this is something random and this
only support I'm reading this because
this supports the legalization the
nationwide legalization and
decriminalization of cannabis New
Hampshire declares state of emergency
over spice no [ __ ] right yeah how to
cure that let us just smoke the weed we
want to smoke and smoke faked spice a
lot of that is probation probation and
prohibition and job testing yeah I mean
I had personal experience whatever and
dude I will never again I was in the
toilet for six hours like hacking my
lungs up felt like a piece of [ __ ] try
anything twice yeah the only did spice
once yep alright so I'm gonna read some
of it doesn't even seem like we need
this gets the point across right yeah
don't [ __ ] somebody tweet me tell me to
quit doing it I'm sorry guys so it's
gonna obviously legalize cannabis they
won't have to smoke spice employers and
probation probation you can't drink
alcohol but the employers don't care if
you go out at 5 o'clock or 6 o'clock or
if you go down to panic hour at 6:15 and
drink twenty two beers your employer
doesn't care but if you smoke a fat
joint man you might get fired from your
job which is terrible I'll read part of
this Governor Maggie Hassan has declared
a state of emergency to allow public
health officials to investigate and
quarantine synthetic drugs linked to
recent overdoses in Manchester and
Concord this is New Hampshire by the way
authorities say at least 41 people in
the Manchester area have experienced
serious medical reactions to synthetic
cannabinoids known as spice that are
chemically engineered substances similar
to the active ingredient in marijuana
let's scrutinize this sentence just for
fun cannabinoid synthetic cannabinoids I
don't think that that's what that is
it's poser pot known as spice that are
chemically engineered that my subs
chemically engineered substances that's
close I think active ingredient in
marijuana marijuana doesn't have
ingredients it's a compound I think is
what you'd want to call it there so come
on guys are the cannabis brah cannabis
properly do you even cannabis bro
Concord police have reported at least
three cases since Wednesday Hassan's
declaration gives the State Department
of Health and Human Services the power
to investigate quarantine and required
the destruction of the products she says
the department will work with the police
to quarantine the bubblegum flavor of a
product named smacked such products were
labeled as herbal incense but are known
to be smoked or breed who wants to take
a product called smacked I don't know I
might take a dab of a strain called
smacked yeah but not a spice I mean
people have been doing this for years
but they put them in boilers and use
them in rooms you know like large rooms
to give everybody that kind of oh my
gosh frankincense myrrh has been used as
imagine and what if just like let's get
baked no they had herb for that because
it wasn't against the law all around the
world it still looked at as something
crazy and they wears awesome decently
uplifting news Utah Medical Marijuana
Program 11 cards issued several for
child patients this is by Michele L
price of The Associated Press in Salt
Lake City Utah issued nearly a dozen
registration cards in the first month of
its limited medical marijuana program
that allows those with severe epilepsy
to possess cannabis extract oil this was
August night so this is kind of old news
but I just wanted to put out some music
ketchup as a Friday evening the state
has issued 11 cards since the program
started July 8th set Janice Houston the
state registrar and director of the
Department of Health Records office
about half of those 11 cars were issued
for child patients Houston said an
application for another card is pending
Health Department officials on Friday
also announced the $400 annual annual
fee for the cards had been cut in half
the program startup fee were less than
its expected and the registration cards
will now cost $200 Houston said there
are 11 cards and one more being applied
for in this team I was at a party the
other day and there were probably 11
medical marijuana cards in the room yeah
it's a huge relief said Jennifer may we
have hope for children with epilepsy
we've been trying to find ways to help
the families come up with that money
along with the money for the oil itself
those who already paid the higher fee
will be refunded health officials said
Utah's law doesn't allow the district
distribution of medical marijuana but it
permits those meeting certain
requirements to possess the extract
after getting it from other states so
they can at least get what they need to
from Colorado they [ __ ] up right here
the extract called cannabidiol okay
that's good they're looking for at CBD
but that's not the extract
come on cannabis
please the extract called cannabidiol is
believed to help with severe seizures
particularly those experienced by
children with severe with a severe form
of epilepsy it's not an extract called
Kenna pity all Kenna video is a
cannabinoid but one of the cannabinoids
in the extract but I see what you're
doing nice article so the oil doesn't
have the psychoactive properties it gets
users high and can be mixed with foods
such as applesauce I wonder if they'd be
able to bring back the og caps because
those og caps from essential extracts
available at natural mystic cannabis
caregivers which is a medical shop man
so they're gonna have to get a Colorado
residency and get a medical marijuana
card in Colorado to even acquire this
type of medicine to Utah hopefully all
right we'll keep going the cost of
cannabidiol varies depending on the size
of the patient and the level of the dose
the patient is receiving for 100 pound
person a month's supply of a beginning
dose is about 40 bucks a maximum dose
for the same patient could cost up to
$900 a month what they are talking about
seems to be Phoenix tears Rick Simpson
oil full plant cannabis extract full
extract cannabis oil
it's orally eaten it's black usually or
greenish colored they're not talking
about dads or anything so it's basically
Rick Simpson oil if you guys are
familiar with that there's a movie
called run from the Cure I believe is
what it's called Race for the Cure rice
run from the Cure that Rick Simpson
story searches for the name Rick Simpson
and then put cannabis oil and you'll
find the movie I'm talking about learn
about Rick Simpson oil a lot of people
say rick simpson may have stolen that
recipe and got famous off of it i don't
care he's helping a lot of people do you
think shut out rick simpson give thanks
we just did a section on accident
the main producer of the extract in
Colorado has a waiting list with
thousands of names and doesn't expect to
have or supply until fall and other
producers of the product have also also
have a waiting list may said because
Utah's registration cards expire year
after year many families are expected to
apply later this year about a hundred
families are expected to take advantage
of Utah's program Health Department
officials said may whose twelve-year-old
son can suffer hundreds of seizures a
day said she and many other families are
also waiting to see if they can secure a
spot in a pending drug trial by a
neurologist at Primary Children's
Hospital in Salt Lake City once families
receive a registration card it could
face additional hurt or sticky hurdles
to actually get the extract from other
states including enrolling in that
state's medical marijuana program all
state marijuana programs medical or
otherwise are still illegal under
federal law and some doctors
advocacy groups have warned there's no
proof the extract is effective at
treating epilepsy but family say it's
worth the time and cost if it brings
relief to those suffering from seizures
all right do you think these people are
gonna pay $400 or now $200 to get the
medical marijuana card that they require
and then go spend money in another state
they're gonna travel to Colorado to get
this oil that costs up to $900 for a
freaking dose of month dose they're
gonna drive from Colorado to Utah
they're gonna spend a couple hundred
bucks and gas they're gonna spend a day
away
they're probably traveling with a child
with seizures are they gonna waste an
excuse this one are they gonna waste
that [ __ ] time if this medicine
doesn't work if they're just know there
must be something working right there's
literally you watch these people up root
they're like they come out here and they
try it I'm pretty sure I've seen oh yeah
then they go back to their home state
and their home states giving them a
point zero or zero point something CBD
value and they had to uproot their lives
and move to Colorado I mean there's a
million stories like it all over you
know if you throw a stone here and you
can pretty much find what they're
calling the marijuana refugees yeah so
it's it's hard absolutely this dude the
story you just read said half the people
we get are coming from out of state why
would why would people not come here to
help their children that is yeah people
are packing up their entire lives and
moving to another state because we can
offer them a medicine that is obviously
when your everybody the union was the
first time I ever saw that
he's all shaky and I don't mean to be
rude about he's really shaky and they
smoked and it was gone yep he goes right
back to not shaky so we got time for one
more quick news article Seattle pot
tickets one cop wrote 80% of citations
what were they calling that one guy out
there in California when it really
boomed
was stay was on you know there you know
who I'm talking that that was just
standing outside of hot shops like right
and people citation so this is from
Seattle a Seattle police officer has
been reassigned after review after a
review found he wrote about 80% of
marijuana tickets issued in the city
during the first half of 2014
Seattle Police Chief Kathleen O'Toole
said 30 her said July 30 on the
department website that the unidentified
officer issued 66 of the 83 citations
for public pot use in Seattle she says
that in some cases yet it notes to the
tickets or addressed them to Seattle
City Attorney Pete Holmes another case
the officer report reportedly said he
flipped a coin when deciding which
person to cite tool says the officer
also wrote on the voter approved state
initiative legalizing recreational
marijuana was silly the police chief
said that the case has been referred to
the department's official of
professional accountability
she says the officer won't be on patrol
duties during the investigation big
middle finger to that cop yeah falls on
top of you or you're thinking about just
burn this on top of me nothing I'm just
gonna wrap that part of this all right
guys we have gone we're pretty close to
an hour now so I'm not sure if they are
going to let me play more of that Marc
Emery video if they do it'll happen here
I mean that's that's if you told me mark
you're gonna spend the next 25 years
you know smoking joints and bongs and
selling seeds and you're gonna go to
jail for many many years of your life
but one day after 25 years have you been
arrested if you go to jail have you been
taken away of you losing all your assets
of you being separated from your family
and your wife after all that you're
gonna have one day one day in 2015 and
if you can get your people together
it all ends on that day on that day the
next day after that day the stores will
start selling marijuana people will walk
the streets confident about the
marijuana in their pocket they're not
gonna get arrested there will be medical
marijuana science experiments and
advancements every day after that
because it'll be legal to study
marijuana in universities it'll be legal
for doctors to recommend it it'll be
legal for doctors judges cops
politicians to smoke it and share it and
understand it it'll be legal to go and
buy it it'll be legal for ordinary
people to grow it it'll be legal for
people have a business that grows
marijuana it'll be legal for everybody
to make fake prices and bongs all the
books and magazines about marijuana will
all be legal no one will ever try and
ban them ever again no one will ever say
a bad thing about pot smokers as a
culture as a way of demonizing them and
sending them to jail because mark in 25
years that one day everybody showed up
and it was a happy wonderful world ever
since because everybody showed up so
that's my message we've got a big
opportunity coming at 14 months I'm
gonna be touring the country
relentlessly telling everybody even in
other countries you just need one day
where everybody we know who smokes pot
shows up
that'll be my message in Ireland it'll
be my message in Spain it'll be my
message in Vienna is gonna be message
all across Canada and it's certainly my
message to all Americans who go to vote
in Oregon and
in Florida and Washington District of
Columbia on the first Tuesday in
November if you show up you'll never
need to think about this ever again
you'll just be allowed to enjoy you'll
be allowed to be part of a culture that
ought to be the one of the most
respected cultures in the history of
mankind because I'll tell you this the
cannabis culture has given more to
humanity and mankind humankind in
science and entertainment and theater
and arts books and culture and
especially in music than any other
culture of the last hundred years the
cannabis culture is one of the greatest
cultures in the history of mankind
starting with William Shakespeare who
smoked marijuana cannabis actually you
know so many great poets and writers and
musicians and scientists and doctors and
explorers and to this day are movers and
shakers spill jobs there sorry bill
gates even jobs pot smokers you know
Carlson again pot smoker every musician
you've ever cared to really enjoy a pot
smoker most of the people right today's
great bestsellers and make today's great
movies or pot smokers including actors
and we are a great culture but we've
been denied our official right to be
regarded as first-class citizens like
everybody else who makes contributions
and who ought to be acknowledged as as a
culture it's so if they'd have told me
25 years ago mark it's gonna be a long
road with a lot of difficulties but one
day in 2015 one day it all becomes real
if you can get your people to show up so
that's my message thanks very much I
look forward to parting with you tonight
[Music]
alright guys that was mark Emery that
video came from the pot TV YouTube
channel I need to give a big shout-out
to Jodie Emery she emailed Jodie and she
gave me permission to use these videos
so we got to give them a big thanks I
also need to give a big shout out to
cannabis culture calm if you want some
great cannabis news if you're online and
not able to listen to a podcast - make
sure you check out cannabis culture calm
there's a lot of videos and updates for
mark also go to youtube and check out
the pot TV channel there are a lot of
great mark Emery videos I will start
I'll try to play some mark Emery videos
at the end of the episodes that are
short that way we can fill in a little
time if the episodes are long I won't
put that in there we'll just try to get
them closer to an hour all right guys
I'm high and rambling so let's get back
to the regular part of the show thanks
for listening to mark Emery support
those guys so uh hey out of Beauty made
it through a whole nother episode thanks
for hanging out with me you make up you
make tips let's go a little bit smoother
it's better than me sitting here talking
myself and looking at the wall like I'm
us with two fennec I appreciate it yeah
like always where can these guys find
you see Twitter
and then the website for 20s calm I've
never checked out that website guys so
games and fun
no it's nothing it's nothing bad in
offensive I apologize you can find all
of our Twitter's and all that big shout
out to my homie bender he's been working
hard on server stuff to run game server
so play some video games donors come on
there you go who doesn't want to play
video games with stoners guys you can
find me I read genetics on Instagram I
grow culture on Instagram at agriculture
on Twitter agriculture has a Facebook
you can email us it's agriculture at
hotmail.com I gotta give a huge
shout-out to DJ make a tea that's was
playing in the background big shout out
thank you let me play the summit turn up
the electronic dancehall music vol 1
it's not even on the screen anymore I
remembered it so much respect to DJ
makeup TV follow him on soundcloud and
now that the show is over why should I
do this watch just in case alright guys
and that was a little speech for Marc
Emery thanks for listening to that now
that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
agriculture find the review section give
us a five star rating after that type in
a comment let me know what you think of
the show and I'll read your comments on
the show and I'm really serious if
you're listening to us on stitcher
please leave a comment there and give us
a good review all of those reviews help
with the show move up in the rankings
which in turn get us more listeners and
I want to spread my message to everyone
who wants to grow and wants to learn
more about cannabis this is an important
message to spread don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episodes is on I read
genetics Colorado calm big huge shout
out to my ninja Spence thanks again for
listening you guys take the fat dad
for me
[Music]
all right podcast well that was episodes
25 26 and 27 of the girl from your heart
podcast I hope you enjoyed it ladies and
gentlemen let me tell you about a
service called patreon if you feel like
contributing to the podcast if you feel
like this podcast was worth a couple of
bucks you can go to patreon patreon comm
slash grow from your heart all of the
information will be there it will teach
you how you can sign up and financially
contribute to the podcast I would
appreciate it I'm not trying to get rich
just a few people offered to make some
contributions so I created a way to do
that if you'd like to contribute there
is your way ladies and gentleman I would
love it if you'd follow me on the social
media all of the new social media stuff
is @ g f YH podcast on twitter on
facebook search for the girl from your
heart a podcast if you want to follow me
on instagram it's Irie underscore
genetics I post a whole bunch of great
cannabis photography there of course
there is a girl from your heart a
podcast YouTube channel currently there
are only 25 videos but I promise I will
post more I think that's all I've got
for you if you'd like to contact me you
can send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear your opinions on
these reboot episodes ladies and
gentlemen this file is getting really
long weird 3 hours and 17 minutes so I'm
getting out of here thanks for letting
me suck up all of your data plan this
month you guys until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me