yeah welcome back in this community it's
time for episode number 199 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new growers if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you cutouts my friends in the
mystic roots band to let him use their
music on my podcast big shout out to Kat
ku and the entire mystic roots crew
ladies and gentlemen today was the day
after the dude grows cup and I'm sure
you can hear it in my voice I smoked a
shit-ton a metric shit-ton of dabs last
night smoked a bunch of good flowers
smoked a bunch of good shatter I met a
whole bunch of great people everybody
hung out with it the dude grows cup also
super huge shout out to the dude and
scotty real and miss real and i
everybody took good care of us at the
dude grows cups I'm sure you've heard me
talk about it a little bit you guys get
into the show so there's another podcast
what's up guys at the dude grow show
there's another podcast called the dude
grow show super good podcast hosted by
the dude accompanied by a dude that
calls himself Scotty real both really
cool guys got to hang out with them last
night spent a little bit of time with
Scotty got to take a super cool photo I
hope that photo turned out well but they
threw a cup they threw a cannabis
judging event I can't call it a cannabis
cup because that word has already taken
but they threw an event where people
were they entered their flowers and
their extracts and people got to judge
them will talk about the judging process
in just a minute
but they threw a really cool event it
was super successful there were quite a
few people there the event was at
cultivated synergy the place was it
wasn't crowded but it was comfortably
packed there was just enough people
there to make it a good party and it
wasn't too overwhelmed where you're
bumping and everybody there's plenty of
seating plenty of tables for us to chill
on take dabs great place so they threw a
huge event through a cool-ass party I
got to taste some of the entries I got
to taste some of the samples I get to
meet a whole bunch of cool people Mike
and Lindsey were supposed to come the
Gavin granny was supposed to come bubble
blaster hose posed to come but some [ __ ]
happened Mike was gonna ride with me but
yesterday afternoon he sent me a message
he's like hey bro I don't feel super
good I think my kid got me sick and I
was like you know what if you think
you're sick don't even go to an event
like that cuz we're all gonna be smoking
together and I don't want to get sick
from you hitting my rig and I don't
think we should go get everybody else
sick so Mike decided to stay home
Lindsay the traveling stoner and Bobo
blaster CO and the dab and granny all
cruised up but when they got to the door
one of them I will not single anybody
out but one of those dudes the dude in
that group that forgot his ID forgot his
ID and kind of hosed every once and
nobody else went in since one person did
not have his ID so they I gave all them
a hug and they turn around and draw
I don't know where they even way I
assume they went back to Springs or
pueblos but they left the event and took
off they didn't even get to get in I
apologize guys that sucks it was a good
time it would've been even more fun with
you there because a lot of podcast
listeners were there and they were
asking for you guys also in attendance
jesse grows showed up the dude grows cup
with the legendary 44 i got to hang out
jesse grows and 44 that was a great ass
time and then i met a whole bunch of
cool as people you guys i parked my car
directly across the street from
cultivated synergy and i got out of the
car and i wasn't ten feet from the car
before people started yelling yo it's
Ross - Jeff yo take a phat dab I just
soon as I got out of the car so I walked
toward the line a couple people greeted
me I got to the end of the line and as I
was getting in line a dude named Tony
was like what's up bro I'm Tony from New
Mexico I listen to the podcast and I was
like [ __ ] yeah I started talking to Tony
another guy and his girlfriend came up
and started talk to me but honestly I
had so much abd I talked to them briefly
and got sucked in Tony's conversation
Tony and his friend I think his friends
buddies buddy's name was Paul's what I
try I'm thinking that's what I remember
I see Paul I see her face in my head
dude but Tony and Paul were cool they're
from New Mexico
they actually have picked up the arize
clone that is available at argh antica
so they've got the 35% tested THC clone
from morgue and together growing it out
there in New Mexico also shot it to my
new friends that I made from New Mexico
also shot it to my friends that I made
from Kansas City I can't say your guys's
names I respect your privacy that much
oh I made some really cool new friends
they listened to the podcast from Kansas
City a pair of brothers cool last dudes
I was great chatting with you guys I
hope you learned a lot from me it was
definitely great hearing how much you
listened to the show and how much you
have learned from listening to the show
I also made some friends from California
I don't know if you guys want me to see
your names but there are three dudes
from California to nudes from Cali well
guys from Colorado
those guys were super cool got to hang
out them for a few minutes also there
was a couple from Denver that I met it
was super fun to hang out with and then
I met a guy so I met a guy who remember
if he said Iowa or Idaho but either way
he said by listening to my podcast he
was able to learn how to grow and build
to grow and fun to grow and fund his
move to Colorado and now he is employed
by one of the leading dispensaries in
Denver and he got to give me a fist bump
tell me thank you for that that type of
stuff means the world to me you guys all
these people coming up to me and telling
me hey you taught me how to grow you got
me through this you made my garden so
much better that [ __ ] blew my mind I had
the biggest smile inside and outside all
night I was hard to hide
I was just cheesing out I big shout out
to all the cool people that I got to
meet all the people that we're giving me
love for what I do for the podcast it
makes it all worth it you guys I made a
joke about how I if anybody ever has any
questions let me know because I know
that if you send me a question I'm
answering your question I know I'm not
just talking to myself and somebody I
think is from Texas he goes man you're
not talking to yourself so that guy if
you remember who you are I know who you
are bro you're wearing a San Antonio
Spurs hat shout-out to you thanks for
letting me know but I'm not talking to
myself out here it was super awesome the
greatest part was you guys this even had
nothing to do with my podcast this was
the dude gross Cup but they have given
me several shout outs I have given them
several shout outs and people knew that
I was coming and so they were excited to
see me at the dude gross Cup I had a
little girl from your heart section
hanging out it was super cool so big
shout out much love much respect much
thanks to Scottie and the dude from the
dude Crows Cup and especially all the
people that came and said what's up to
me that meant a lot to me feel like I'm
rambling about that but it really meant
a lot you guys
it's huge when people give you praise
for the work that you do in person when
you get to meet a large group of people
and they're thanking you for what you do
it means a lot especially people that
you know are already able to grow
without your guidance like dude you push
me to the next level that means a lot so
like I said it wasn't even and we were
going to talk a little bit about judging
the event I like the way that they did
this a lot of the events we go to the
judges are offered a judge's pack or
you're given a bag with every entry
labeled with a number and then you're
supposed to consume that and your choice
of method if it's a bowl a joint however
you want to do it so say there are 40
entries you're given little baggies with
numbers one through forty written on it
and you've got to take your own notes
and decide what the winner was they did
it a little bit differently at the dude
gross Cup and I kind of like the way
that they did it instead of giving
everybody a gift bag there was a section
ah one whole section of the venue where
there were little bud bud tender
stations lined up there were basically
countertops with jars of samples of
entries and all of those jars were
labeled with a number
like I said I think there were about 50
entries so they were labeled one through
fifty and you would stand in line and he
would go up to the front and then you
would tell the the budtender
what number samples he wanted to try and
the bud tenders had a few different
samples in front of him it looked like
each bud tinder had three or four four
or five different samples so you'd walk
up you get in line you'd walk up to one
gate like I want to try whatever he had
in front of him one two three four five
and they would give you a fresh one
hitter when you started so you had a
brand new little clean one hitter pipe
and then you get to smoke each sample
but you got to stand in line a few times
to get through every sample it was a
cool way of doing it instead of just
sitting there and hoarding your 50
sample pack it made it a little more
communal because everybody had to go up
to that one area where the samples were
and he had to meet the budtender and he
kind of had to hang out and be in line
and that being in line right there
forced more people to interact because
when I see a lot of it these events uh I
used to go with Kevin a lot I would go
with pops uh now a lot of the times I
end up up there with the traveling
stoner and bubble blaster Co and Bret
from evil labs we've got kind of clicky
we've gotten kind of click is what I
think I'm trying to say and when you put
us all in a line like that to go taste
the samples all those clicks go away
because you end up in line next to other
people for five minutes and then you end
up making friends with new people and I
really like that aspect of it it was
really cool I knew some people when I
walked in there I knew a lot of people
when I left there was a really good
social experience a lot of the other dab
and smoke events that we go to do seem
to be a little clicky a little elitist a
little there's a little bit of a
[ __ ] vibe at them there wasn't any
ego at this event this was a bunch of
people hanging out smoking out and one
cool thing that they did they they did a
huge raffle they were selling tickets
for this raffle dirty cheap and I kind
of regret not participating in the
raffle but there wasn't anything that I
absolutely would have loved to have have
but they were giving away [ __ ] deluxe
bulbs they were giving away double ended
ceramic metal halide bulbs which are
brand new they were giving away nutrient
packs they gave away tons of stuff you
guys I've given away a few things on the
spot cast they gave away a truckload of
stuff I've got a nice little kitchen
area here where I record the girl from
the heart podcast studio is honestly my
dining room all of the stuff they gave
away would fill this space in a little
pile that's all my [ __ ] they gave away
so I thought it was super cool
the dude grows cup was able to give back
to the cannabis community I'm pretty
sure way to grow sponsored them mammoth
P sponsored them there was a bunch of
whose the company that they use recharge
recharge was heavily involved so there's
a bunch of good giveaways they gave away
a bunch of [ __ ] deluxe bulbs I think
they gave away a quest dehumidifier
bunch of [ __ ] was given away ah so huge
shout at some things for giving stuff
away that means a lot to me that they
give back I was gonna talk about um I
talked about the entries and I talked a
little bit about the judging now I kind
of want to talk a little bit about what
I saw from the entries there were
approximately 50 entries from what I
remember and I was able to I did kind of
an [ __ ] move but I just wanted to be
quick about it and I think I made myself
clear on what I was trying to do to
anybody who's paying attention so
imagine all the lines are going one way
right the lines are run it back and
forth
I walked up about three people into the
line and I didn't cut anybody cuz I
wasn't getting in the line but I just
cut through the wrong way I just like I
crossed all the intersections and I
walked from one end to the other and
just eyeballed all of the samples I just
gave a quick visual visual glance kind
of a flyby X I'm so tall I just did a
flyover and crept it all the tables to
see what the samples looked like and
they gave me a good idea of what I
wanted to try before I even got in line
to waste my time to go smoke some
samples I'm not trying to be an [ __ ]
here I'm gonna say that 40 of those 50
samples needed to be trimmed they did
not trim them worth a [ __ ] there were
samples in there that could have been
winners
if the grower or trimmer would have
taken another step and just knock off
all those little shitty leaves that were
on there Jesse said yeah they do you
have a bunch of trichomes on those
leaves but it doesn't look good and it's
not appealing to me and I'm certain that
it effects the flavor and you can knock
those trichomes off and put it into your
hash and make some concentrates out of
it so I think the main problem that I
saw with most of the the product most of
the entries was that it was not trimmed
there was some ribs there was something
that tasted like a blueberry I'd had a
real funky blueberry flavor to it that
one was delicious
there was one that was definitely Girl
Scout cookies I dominant that one was
delicious there was one that looked like
it was gonna be real good but it tasted
kind of hey like and kind of burnt my
tongue then all of the others I kind of
ignored because
were so leafy that it didn't even look
appealing to smoke so let's talk a
little bit about how to trim your
products if you want the best bag appeal
and if you intend on entering something
into a cup that is going to be judged so
let's talk about that but first I need
to take a DAB in a drink so I feel like
I'm talking away too fast so I'm gonna
take care of my head in my face
hopefully you guys take a quick dab too
and then I'll be right back all right
back I'm well hydrated I'm well
medicated I'm smoking some golden goat
shatter today shout out to the barefoot
grower barefoot extracts for keeping me
laced up with super fresh super clean
super delicious super potent shatter
good job dude good job I appreciate it I
grow the products and then I pass it
over to our buddy will and he takes care
of the extraction process for me there's
nothing like knowing that the products
you're dabbing were grown with love and
extracted with love there's something
something sweet about knowing there's
safety and quality in your medicine I
really enjoy it before we go into
talking about proper trim technique
there are a couple things I missed in
the intro here because I was just
rambling my face off I mentioned in
previous episodes that I was going to
record a podcast at the dude gross cup
that did not happen you guys I had all
the recording equipment that I needed
with me it was really loud in there I
would not have been able to get any
useful recording even if I did try to
set up and record the music was [ __ ]
loud there were a bunch of people in
there you had to kind of yell and it
sucks when you're in a place that loud
and you were smoking dabs and you're
trying to yell over everybody that's
kind of why that's why my voice sounds
like I am a mr. Moviefone
press one if you know the name of the
movie you'd like to see that's that's
from taking too many dads and trying to
yell over everybody all night so excuse
the throat and the excessive throat
clearing but that's why I did not record
that's why there is no live stuff coming
from the dude grows cup that I recorded
also I talked about the judging I never
talked about the voting when he walked
into the dude Rose Cup you were given a
lanyard which meant you were a judge and
around the lanyard are the it's right
over there it's out of reach I'm not
gonna walk away from microphone to get
it but around the lanyard are numbers
and that's how many entries there were
so when you go and you sample the entry
they punch that number off of your
lanyard say they know the tubes tested
sample number one
and then they were so number one two
three four or five however many injuries
there are I think there were 40 maybe 50
they punch out the number that you've
tried so that that way you can't just
keep smoking the same entries over and
over so that if you fall in love with
one he can't go smoke all of it
so the voting went also when you walked
in they gave you some tokens they look
like some Pirates of the Caribbean
tokens they're just plastic tokens they
probably got him from the dollar store
the party store or something but there
are some plastic tokens and if you
appreciate it a strain you were to give
the budtender that token and ask them to
put it the jars were behind them so you
would give them the token and they would
put it in the number you'd say hey I
like number 22 the best we throw this
token into number 22 and I think you
were given five tokens when he walked in
and he were also given one free raffle
ticket when he walked in so that you had
it to everybody won something but I left
before the end of the raffle because the
raffle was taking for freaking ever and
then they even Scotty and the dude had
to take a break in the middle because
the raffle was taking so long so I've
talked about the voting I talked about
the tokens they gave us I apologize for
not recording any live material at the
event honestly you guys I was having a
good ass time taking dad's with my old
friends and my new friends it was cool
introducing so Jesse Jesse grows is a
cool guy he's a little bit shy I don't
know that shy I don't he's just not as
socially outgoing as myself and so when
people would start talking to me
sometimes I need a little bit of a break
my throat starts burning out and I want
to take a DAB and chill so I'd be like
hey that's Jesse from the show and
several people were super excited to
meet Jesse people were thinking Jesse
for all their outdoor xyx s especially
Tony because aren't my new friend Tony
is growing out New Mexico he's growing
in an outdoor environment and jesse has
taught him a ton of useful information
so Jesse I hope that wasn't too much for
you and 44 was there I got to introduce
44 - a few podcast listeners so that was
kind of cool but my point is I was too
busy being social and having fun to
record and it was too loud in there so
recording didn't happen a lot of people
are gonna say hey who won which strain
won the dude gross Cup honestly you guys
it was 10:30 I was tired
as high as giraffe [ __ ] I had a two
hour drive to get home plus I had to
work today so I had to pack up my stuff
and get out of there around 10:30 or
11:00 I boogied out drove back down to
Pueblo
no incident on the drive nice straight
two-hour drive made it about 130 miles
to the house I get home late crashed out
for a couple hours woke up and I had to
go take care of the grow because I'm a
nice boss and I gave the whole grow crew
the day off today so ah yeah I did not
stick around for the judging I do not
know who won the dude grows Cup here's a
good plug if you want to know who won
the dude grows Cup Monday you've got to
listen to the dude grow show that's what
you can do go check out their podcast
it's a great podcast it's a little bit
different format than mine but you will
certainly enjoy it since I'm talking
about pitching podcasts you guys I am
gonna talk about trimming buds here in
just a minute but I've got a bunch of
other stuff on my mind I took a DAB and
so I just made my a TD fire up speaking
of podcasts several people mentioned my
friend beau Nellis we would be talking
about podcasts we'd be talking about
whatever and people would bring up beau
beau you were loved in the community we
need to get you out here to Colorado to
one of these events so that you can
partake in the dad's you can hangout the
people and you can just feel what it's
like to have a bunch of people saying
hey thank you for doing a podcast that
helps me connect with myself and my
medicine it's really cool it's a good
feeling so beau you got to get out here
people love you you're part of this
podcast world that's helping the
cannabis community come take some dads
with us I guess that's a good time to
tell you guys about patreon right right
here in the middle of the podcast
patreon if you'd like to help myself or
Bone Ellis or any podcasters out you can
go to patreon.com/scishow and you can
read all about how to contribute to the
Grove from your heart a podcast patreon
is a service that allows listeners to
financially contribute to podcasts we're
not trying to get rich it costs us money
to put the website up so that we can
host the show guys my website sucks I'm
sorry I do not spend a lot of time
working on my website right now it's
basically just a it's a crash but that's
how my podcast is hosted to itunes to
stitcher to Feedburner to pod Bay
wherever else you're watching it that's
how it's happening is through my website
so when you go to patreon when you
contribute what that funding does that
helps me pay for my Bluehost account
which pays for my website that's what
that does so if you want to help out a
podcaster most podcasters do have a
patreon account so you can go to my
patreon
it's a patreon.com slash girl from your
heart
I am not exactly sure what the bone
Ellison spliff podcast patreon czar but
if you search you will find it you can
help out a podcast or maybe in the
future we'll set up a patreon to try to
get Bo to Colorado so that we can all
record a big we'll get the dude grows
we'll get Scotty real we'll get myself
we'll get Bo Nellis and we'll do like a
giant MVP podcast well record an episode
together we'll drop it on everybody's
feed that would be epic Cannabis
podcasting alright I keep talking about
trim and weed I'm holding this Kabletown
nugget in my hand it's I could use a
little bit of love it can use some
attention to give you some trimming
let's talk about trimming your weed I
don't want to go into too much detail
about harvesting because I've done
complete episodes about harvesting full
plants that is a whole nother podcast
and if it's not in the feed I'm sure you
guys are aware that I've been putting
old episodes out on Thursdays I put
chunks of three or four episodes out
every Thursday those are episodes from
the past a long long time ago the show
used to be called agriculture there's
another organization that goes by the
name hi grow I kindly changed my name so
that I don't get myself in any trouble I
don't want to be associated with them on
accident so now the show is called the
grow from your heart podcast which is
much more suiting in my opinion but
anyway I've been putting out old
episodes because a lot of the episodes
fall out of the feed iTunes and stitcher
only hold 100 episodes and a lot of the
good stuff is in the past and the old
episodes we're up to 200 now and there's
that means there's a hundred episodes
that are no longer in the feed so I'm
going to put in chunks out so that I can
try to get those old episodes in the
feed without knocking out current stuff
another thing I'm doing is I am making
those YouTube videos I talk about that a
lot it's coming it's time-consuming I
have a life I have a lot going on I'm
trying to get those out for you but I'm
trying to get the old episodes so the
episode all about harvesting will be
either in the feed on YouTube or coming
soon in those old episodes is what I'm
getting to today we're just gonna talk
about the kind of fun the final fine
trim let's say you've harvested your
plant I will just will real quickly go
over this you flushed your plant that is
the beginning of harvest flush you all
you need to do is feed your plants clean
pH balanced water it's free all you
gotta do is get a container however many
plants you use however much water you
use fill that container use some pH up
or pH down probably pH down
most locations use some pH down get that
water to the proper pH you wandered
around somewhere between 6 and 6.5
that's up to you I like to do about 6.2
when I'm flushing pH that water 26.2 and
pour it through the plants and for the
next days next 10 days just keep doing
that
don't ever add nutrients whenever the
plants get you water them you let them
get dry and show you that they're
thirsty mix up some more water that's
six point two and water those plants you
do that for at least ten days you can do
it for 10 to 14 maybe 17 I've seen
people do it for 21 full days all you
got to do is flush your plants it's free
you don't have to put nutrients in there
that's that much nutrients you were
saving flush your damn plants sorry I
get on a rant when I talk about flushing
because it's so easy and people do not
do it and it's evident as soon as I take
a hit off your bowl before that smoke
hits my lungs I can say you didn't flush
that and the funny part is one of our
friends that I met at the dude grows cup
passed me some weed and he's like this
one's got like a spicy taste to it and I
hit it and I blew out the hit before I
got my smoke all the way out of my lungs
I could taste it and I said do you use
worm casting tea in your in your mix and
he said yes and I said I think you're
using a little too much worm castings
because I can taste compost and worm
castings and his buddy excuse me my
throat's clogging up I apologise let me
take a quick drink anyway this dude's
friend said I told you you've been going
too hard with the worm casting so I
could taste that [ __ ] in there so floss
your plants that's what I'm saying and
don't use too much stuff it's hard to
flush out anything that you've used
excessively I like veg bloom you guys it
seems to flush out really clean that's
not a paid advertisement or anything but
veg bloom seems like it flushed out very
nicely in my plants so flush then pre
trim you can go in and take off all the
large leaves a few days before harvest
just chop those off take them off it
makes it easier then cut your plants
down let them hang upside down you can
either wet trim or dry trim at this
point wet trim obviously means you go at
them while they're still wet you're
gonna need some scissors
you're gonna need gloves no matter how
you do this wear gloves please get
yourself some nitrile gloves some latex
gloves glove up you don't want trichomes
all over yourself and I don't want to
smoke your skin flakes that shit's gross
so get some gloves they're cheap they're
affordable just go to go to Walgreens go
to Walmart I like to order mine off of
Amazon
come they come straight to the house if
you're gonna buy a bunch I recommend
uline uline sells a lot of gloves but
you gotta buy a bunch of them
get yourself a bucket of extra-large
black gloves they're awesome that's it
that's how we do it anyway let's get
back on track here I'm high as giraffe
[ __ ] today so you can white Rimmer you
could drive em obviously wet trim you
cut it down you start trimming now while
it's wet it's super sticky it's kind of
a pain in the ass but once you're done
trimming it's over there's nothing left
to do you can get it all handled at one
time you gotta let it hang there and dry
and then you got to cure it that's all
that's gonna have to happen dry trim you
can cut the plant down let it hang
upside down until it's dry and then you
can trim it like that you still need
gloves but it's not as sticky it's not
as funky you could just wear gloves I
like to kind of grab the buds and get in
there with my finger at my thumb nails
you want a glove so it's not really a
thumb nail bits like your thumb tip and
you can just knock the leaves off with
your thumb and you can go super fast so
the thing when you're wet trimming I
like wet trimming because you can get in
there and really cut off everything and
then when it dries the bud shrinks up
and you can't see any leaf in there at
all some bud textures it's a lot and
it's very advantageous to trim it while
the buds wet a lot of stuff my stuff
that like the Grateful dog the Capleton
the Capleton I'm holding right now this
is really dense and it's not super leafy
so I like to dry trim this so I cut down
the plant so I flush it of course I take
off all the big leaves I cut it down I
let it hang upside down for four I'm in
Colorado it's dry here I hang it upside
down until the sticks snapped like grab
a stem and bend it and you want it to go
crunch that's when it's ready then I
take that plant I cut all the buds off
of the sticks into like a bucket it's a
like a big dish I just cut all the buds
off the sticks into that dish and then I
throw all the sticks away the sticks are
gone now I've got a bucket or a bowl of
nice buds with little leaves on it then
I go through and I cut off all of the
like the sugar leaves I keep all of that
sugar leaf and I make hash out of all of
that anything that's got a little bit of
trichome on it goes into another
container and it dries out real fine and
that gets turned into hash and that is
my cheap get crazy take giant dad's and
waste a bunch of dabs hash when my
friends come over when I spoke with a
bunch of people that's the you can take
as big of a dad as you want because this
is just trim run
that's that's what happens with that so
I'd find trim once I knock off all that
big stuff I find trim the bud which so
I've got this little butter Capleton all
the big stuffs have basically been taken
off you can see the bud shape there
these little tiny tiny buds sticking out
and I'm honestly just knocking them off
with my thumbnail you can almost hear it
that that was excessive that was my
thumb hitting the microphone after it
knocked it off but you can I'm just
basically rubbing this bud and brushing
off most of these little leaves cuz it's
dry enough but it's not super crusty and
those leaves are coming right off it's
really easy to knock excuse me for the
clutter for the clogged up throat you
guys that's from the dude gross Cup in
like a billion dabs but it's real easy
just to knock those leaves off there's
no reason to leave that stuff on there
there are two things that really drive
me crazy ah and you're gonna laugh when
I say the words but when I explain them
he will completely understand one thing
that drives me [ __ ] nuts is something
called crow's feet those little tiny
tiny leaves that are sticking out like
there's a part where this one bud meets
another part of the bud and there's a
little leaf just sticking out of there
that right now I'm just gonna pull it
off with my fingers if you leave that on
there that's called the crows foot it's
just a little pokey you know it's a V to
leaves a stick off like a V it's ugly a
[ __ ] when you got a pound of weed with a
bunch of crows feet in it it makes it
look ugly if you take out all those
crow's feet that pound away it looks way
better just clean that [ __ ] up I hate
that stuff then there's another thing
that is still on this bug because it's
not done being trimmed it's called
handlebars at the bottom of the bud
where the buds been cut off of the stick
there are two little sticks little tiny
tiny stems where a leaf used to be on
each side those are called handlebars if
you if you have a button you hold it
upside down you'll know exactly what I
mean it looks like GI Joe can make a
jetski
out of this little bud and that's where
GI Joe would hold on these two little
sticks where there used to be leaves
those drive me [ __ ] crazy
get rid of your handlebars get rid of
your crow's feet and it will make your
buds look way better it's not a lot of
effort it's just a little bit of time
slow down get in there take that [ __ ]
out bet that was the main difference
between the winning and losing buds that
I saw last night so just trim your [ __ ]
up you should be able to see the shape
of the bud don't get excessive and get
in there and mash it up so if you're dry
trimming you should be able to rub it
and you'll see exactly the shape of your
bud and if it's not a dense button
you may need to work on having some Celt
products you need to get some airflow in
there and you may need more light or you
may need a better phenotype but when
it's dried trimmed you should be able to
just kind of rub it knock off all those
leaves if it's wet trimmed you don't
need to pull it open too far but pull it
open a little bit and cut those leaves
out and when the bud dries it'll shrink
around those leaves and you won't even
see them in there it'll be just fine but
take that stuff out because it's making
your weed look terrible you could have
and it also leaves contain chlorophyll
you don't want to smoke chlorophyll it
does not taste good it takes it longer
to cure it's funky
we're not here to smoke leaf we're here
to smoke buds we're honestly here to
smoke trichome resin we don't even need
this green part so let's minimize the
green [ __ ] that we're smoking focus on
the good part smoke what we want also
what drives me crazy ah sticks when
people try to have a gigantic bud this
bud that I'm holding in my hand right
now is probably the size of a golf ball
by the time I'm done playing with it
it's gonna be five or six a little tiny
bowl size buds because there's a stick
in the middle of this and nobody wants
to buy or carry around a stick so I'm
gonna take you can hear me just breaking
off the buds off the stick right now oh
it looks so much better yep so I think
if you instead of trying to give me big
impressive fancy buds give me buds that
are well manicured take them off the
stick take off your crow's feet take off
the handlebars and when you start
looking at your buds when you're
trimming you will know what crow's feet
and handlebars are as soon as you see it
and the cabbage leaves at the bottom
that's that's part of the handlebars and
crow's feet but that cabbage [ __ ] at the
bottom
take off the cabbage you guys trimmers
will know what I'm talking about right
away it'll dawn on you it's gonna make
mediocre weed look like much better weed
it's gonna upgrade your weed that much
just by trimming putting a little bit of
effort into it so also think about
something that's called the rule of
thumb you guys if that butt isn't the
size of your thumb
why are you trimming it you're wasting
time if you're making hash or if you're
making edibles put that into the hash
pile don't spend 10 minutes trimming a
bud that market value would only be
worth 50 cents don't don't don't waste
your time on something that's not
monetarily worth it
grab a bigger bud trim it throw the that
other [ __ ] in the hash pile and move on
but I say wear gloves enough times order
gloves please because I don't want your
skin flakes no matter what you're doing
with cannabis you should wear gloves if
you're touching a plant you should wear
gloves if you're touching the pot if
you're in the grow
you should probably just put on some
gloves we talked about pesticide
contamination just wear gloves in the
grow especially when trimming don't ever
rub your eyes when you're trimming you
guys they'd only take once ok everybody
does it
you'll start trimming and then your eyes
will start itching because there's so
much just the weed smell in the air and
everything is sticky and your eye will
itch just naturally and you're gonna rub
your eye and you're gonna it'll take
about seven seconds before you go ah ha
[ __ ] and you'll know what you just did
and it's gonna burn you gonna have to
quit trimming for a few minutes
everyone's gonna laugh at you we know it
sucks you're gonna be ok deal with it
alright you guys that was 30 minutes my
voice is blowing out because I took so
many dads last night at the dude grows
cup I want to give you huge shout out to
everybody that I hung out with
especially the dude and Scotty real I
had a great time right on to Jesse and
44 for hanging out because the people
that I had anticipated playing with
didn't show up to play so I had to go
play all by myself and make new friends
so it was good that those guys showed up
had somebody to kick it with um I don't
think everybody for listened to the
podcast I put out 3 episodes last week I
did the normal Monday episode I did an
episode with Lindsay the travelling
stoner and then I also did the big block
of old school episodes I hope you caught
all of those I wanna remind you again
about patreon I don't want to harp on it
too much but patreon.com slash grow from
your heart I would love it if you
support us there of course I would love
it if you find me on all of the social
media you can follow me on twitter it's
at g f YH podcast you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast also on Instagram
I've been posting what I think is some
pretty high-quality dope as cannabis
photography if you want to follow me on
instagram its Irie underscore genetics
that is my breeding company I make seeds
check me out on there you can see what
I'm working with you can see stuff from
my personal grows you could STIs see
stuff from commercial facilities that I
go to you could see stuff from Three
Rivers a whole bunch of great
photography there in my opinion of
course anyone can email me if you're not
into social media send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you also you
can go to itunes you can leave us a
review on iTunes go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart podcast scroll down to the
bottom click on the part where it's got
my ugly face on the red golden green
logo in the middle of that page there
will be a ratings and review sections so
far everybody has given me a five star
review
I would love it if you give me as many
stars as you feel I deserve and then
type in a little comment I will read
your review on a future episode I love
reading listener comments I love the
input from the listeners it was great
meeting everybody at the dude gross cup
I was blown away at how many people
listened to the podcast I really blew my
mind I drove home with a big goofy smile
that was partly because I'd had about a
million dad's but that was partly for
making so many great friends ladies and
gentleman you can listen to the podcast
on iTunes and stitcher
the episodes are available on my website
I do apologize that my website sucks I
have not put any time into repairing
that updating and fixing it making it
look good it's a train wreck right now
bear with me the episodes are there
that's all that matters
it probably does me best if you listen
to them on iTunes or stitcher that's
where the numbers count the most to me
but however you're listening I
appreciate it
please continue to listen if you've ever
got questions like I said send them
right to me I will get them answered for
you because I feel like I am rambling I
hope I improved your trimming I hope you
listen to the dude gross podcast and I
hope you join me for another episode I'm
gonna give you huge shout out to my new
friends Jeremy and Cheryl and until next
time take a phat dad and give your momma
[Music]
[Applause]
they asked me why I play music music
[Music]
music is the most
you