[Music]
yeah Bobby hust representing for the
real herb
nior stand
uple the hle
[Music]
keep guess what that
means first of all it means I'm dabbing
the [ __ ] out but more importantly
welcome it's time for episode number 20
of the Agro culture podcast I'm your
host Rost and Jeff thank you for joining
me for another dabd episode this episode
is brought to you by natur Green
remedies.com visit Natures green
remedies.com for gaug green genetics La
pla Labs Sin City rare dankness mile
high can Adventure I genetics and many
more trusted Brands Nature's green
remedies is running a special for the
podcast listeners clicking over their
website right now to get the specifics
on that cuz they just updated it for us
right now buy any five pack of iy
genetics get a free two pack of double
eyes buy any 10 packs of iy genetics get
a free five pack of double eyes Nature's
green remedies is also running another
special for you guys type in coupon code
podcast for 15% off any order and you
always get free shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com
can you hear that dab in my voice oh my
God that thing was awesome dabing some
lemon Jeffree shatter my secret stash
dabs I got over here so delicious thanks
to Garden of Weeden for blasting that
for me also I want to give a big shout
out to our friends at oil slick oil
slick tools to help you concentrate
check out oil slick pad.com for more
information make sure you follow oil
slick on Twitter find them under
oilslick pad send them a tweet tell them
you're listening to the igro culture
podcast and also need to give big love
to tree Thugger dcom this episode is
brought to you in part by tree Thugger
dcom live music lifestyle magazine go
check out tree Thugger decom for concert
and Festival news and reviews www.re
Thugger docomo to all the sponsors for
making the show possible I want to give
a big huge shout out to Brad wies for
leaving a comment on the uh Stitcher
Channel sorry I'm coughing from a dab
it's got me all choked up Brad your
comment has me choked up
bro I met Brad at a dab festival at the
Wright Event Center it was either the
710 cup or the secret cup or one of
those he's a photographer he takes great
photos my current Twitter picture was
actually taken by Brad so thanks for
taking good pictures dude thanks for
being a good member of the community he
comes all the way from New Mexico to
Denver to all of the dab parties and the
Cannabis events so that is [ __ ] cool
of you thanks a lot man I appreciate
that uh thanks for those that comment if
you guys leave comments on iTunes or
Stitcher I will read it on the show I
also find all the comments on uh
Facebook and Twitter if you guys don't
want to leave comments uh if you don't
want to leave your name in a comment if
you want to be read on the show but
remain anonymous feel free to email that
to me uh ulture hotmail.com or send me a
private message on Facebook I won't say
your name on the show but I'll get your
question out there if you're in a place
where people can't know you're a
cannabis user we'll go ahead and read
your question without anybody knowing it
came from you uh we going to uh do a
grow lesson on this episode I want to
talk about something real quick before
we do that I've been putting out these
flyers for the AG culture podcast my
friend Adam puts him out for me shout
out Adam thanks a lot bro uh he puts
these little Flyers they're this just
the siid the quarter sheet of paper says
listen to the igro culture podcast for
free grow lessons in Cannabis News
something funny that happened we did
that episode at the hookah bar and I
left a few of those there on the table
and the police have been going to that
hookah bar randomly trying to bust
people smoking weed there and it's not
happening but the only thing they found
are these Agro culture podcast Flyers
with a weed leaf on there and they
insist that that is some sort of code to
like get weed or something somewhere and
it's not guys if you uh if you took the
time to scan the QR code that is on that
flyer it brought you to this podcast oh
God sorry I'm coughing because I took a
dab in the privacy of my own home like
I'm allowed to do as a Colorado resident
but if the cops are listening to this
show that QR code worked the flyer did
exactly what it was supposed to do it
was an ad to get people to listen to the
podcast so I think it's really hilarious
they thought a little it's just a flyer
that says to listen to a show they
thought that was some sort of code to
get you some free weed that's really
funny uh inaccurate guys great police
work there all right uh I obviously
can't breathe from the dab that I just
took so give me a second to take a drink
and I'll be right back we'll read some
news and we will get on with it with a
grow lesson hang out
guys all right guys I think I've
recovered from those dabs got a nice
drink of water got nice and comfortable
want to read you a news article that
comes from Colorado this is actually
written in the Cannabis again from our
good friend Ricardo Baka the headline is
Edibles recall at home baked use of
washing machine for hash questioned and
it says the popular denver-based brand
of marijuana infused Edibles was
recalled by Denver Department of
Environmental Health on July 17th
because of the possible contamination
from unsanitary equipment and use of
equipment not intended for food
manufacturing according to the
Department's Public Health Inspections
Division the manufacturer of the
recalled Edibles at home baked operates
on the same state marijuana license is
dispensary group Advanced Medical
Alternatives we're really frustrated
with the entire situation said AJ ashar
AJ ashar sorry he's also known to me as
AJ hashman that's what I would always
call him so I said I saw ashar and I
just said hashar because it seemed like
it worked but anyway uh the coner of at
home baked who is known in the Denver
marijuana industry as AJ hashman uh they
came in and the Machine which we were
utilizing to make water hash was not
food uh not a food safe machine food
safe machines to make water hash do not
exist they they deemed the water hash
that we were making unfit for human
consumption even though nobody has
gotten sick from our hash the Department
of Environmental Health verified that
there haven't been any reports of
illness yet but a food safety inspection
was the reason for the recall ashar has
been using a modified washing machine to
activate his water hash a common
practice in this industry to get the
centrifugal action that is essential to
the water hash said ashar also known for
his popular marijuana meet and greets in
Denver Colorado uh dude AJ throws some
great parties he hasn't been able to do
them anymore because the uh Denver
Police have actually been shutting those
parties down uh because we're smoking
cannabis and not drinking
alcohol anyway the article says my
business partner and I both have
culinary backgrounds Food Service
backgrounds and we look at water hashes
a concentrate not a food ashar said but
they say as soon as you start working
with it uh with a food as the intent or
the end result it is food which I kind
of agree with that you know it's got to
be food we're going to eat that hash
that's the active ingredient that we're
searching for so it's got to be clean
it's got to be food grade uh in June
ashar received a variance from the state
through September uh to find a food safe
alternative and he purchased a bubble
Magic Machine he hopes will satisfy
their regulations in the meantime the
state demanded that he recall all
products made in his old washing machine
at home baked products were recalled on
July 17 uh the at sorry let me reread
that sentence for you the at home baked
products re that were recalled on July
17th include its infused brownie mixes
Blondie mixes rice CR be treats and
sticks candy sorry I'm fired up on this
episode I'm going really fast cuz I want
to get to that grow lesson uh he
continues to say please pull our
products off your shelf and place in the
back room and contact me to replace them
at home B published on its Facebook on
July 16th so sorry for the inconvenience
we look forward to restocking you ASAP
once we have more info and a time frame
uh at home baked will replace all
products in question or refund purchase
as ashcar said the Department of
Environmental Health is saying that any
of the above at homebaked product should
be removed from the retail shelves and
destroyed immediately pursuant pursuant
to State Medical and retail marijuana
regulations but what does this mean for
at home bake's business it's an
extremely difficult blow ashgar said
it'll be difficult to keep our head
above
water uh man that's rough times for AJ
hashman and the at home Baked company I
want to give a big shout out to AJ he's
a uh he's been a huge supporter of this
community he actually threw those meet
and greets like they were talking about
if you go to an event in Colorado AJ's
got a booth there they're giving out
sticks they're giving out free samples
uh he's done a lot for us so when he
does get his products back on the Shelf
somebody one of the dispensaries needs
to send them over to Steep Hill halent
Labs get them tested get the uh profile
printed out post that online show what
he's got going on and then we should all
go buy those if it's a good product
again and we should support AJ to help
him get back on his feet cuz this is a
big blow for a small company like what
AJ's got going
on I want to make the news real quick uh
there's only One news article this week
because I want to get to the grow lesson
I have got quite a bit of information
that I want to kind of cram into just a
little bit of time here so I'm scrolling
through my notes and before we do that I
need to uh give another shout out this
portion of the podcast the grow lesson
is brought to you by hyro indoor growing
supplies hyro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 6271 Beach
Street Unit F or stop by the new PLO
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out highy grow for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out
www.hr denver.com for current store
hours and special sales go check out the
new location in Pueblo tell them rosta
Jeff sent you they like to know that I'm
sending people and that means they know
you're listening to the podcast that
knows their advertising dollars are
going the right direction all right
let's get down to a grow lesson a few
weeks ago uh we cut some clones we
germinated seeds and then we put those
seedlings and clones into cups uh to let
them develop Roots so it's probably on
the time schedule I've been on it's
probably Pas time to get those into pots
and start the vegetative phase so uh I
apologize if I'm a little behind
schedule I've had a lot of podcasting to
try to cram in anyway let's talk about
the size pots we're going to use I like
to go straight into the pots that I'm
going to finish in like the p uh the
what I transplant into now from the cups
is going to be our finish pot so we were
in
cups uh we're going to go into pots
choosing your pot size is important is
an important thing to consider I like to
run my test plants in three gallon pots
and my big plants in seven gallon pots
uh some of you guys like to go even
bigger but for an indoor crop I think a
s gallon pot is plenty large enough if
you're going outside uh [ __ ] you can go
50 to 100 or I've seen 250 gallon pots
outside Earth pots but if you're going
that big you should just go into the
ground I think anyway I think I'm
rambling uh 3 to five gallon pots are
great for vegging plants for a few weeks
and then flowering I don't like to let
them veg in 3 gallon pots for longer
than like 45 days or so
once the plants start to get too big for
that they'll get a little bit root bound
so if you want to V your plants for more
time to get bigger uh plants and bigger
buds use larger pots uh if I want to run
a fast crop I run about 16 3 gallon pots
under 1,000 watt light uh these are
usually from seed if I'm running like a
little tester crop is what I do that for
if I'm running a production crop I'll
put uh between four and six s gallon
pots under 1,000 watt light depending on
the strain uh if they get taller and
thinner I'll put uh six of them if
they're like bushier plants like I'll
say The Grateful Dog I'll only put four
lemon Jeffrey I'll put six uh just kind
of cuz the lemon Jeffree gets taller
than it does wide so I'll put six of
them under there and uh pull a pretty
nice Harvest about a pound and a half
from six lemon Jeffrey plants and seven
gallon pots under 1,000 watt light uh of
course I can
get I can get that pound and a half from
four of them but I have to let it veg
just a little bit longer maybe like two
weeks more and then the but that's just
that that's the difference in the pot
size and the veg times and how many plts
that's where you start doing that kind
of math but uh both of these methods
will harvest me about a pound pound and
a half if done correctly the smaller
plants take less time to veg but I like
the production from a seven gallon pot
they're a little bit bigger they seem
like they're able to grow more when they
have a bigger root ball they just seem
to take off they uh they grow larger in
flour they seem like they keep growing a
little bit taller they don't cut off as
early in their growth phase in flow so
uh we're also limited by plant count so
if few were larger pots is better for
the medical Growers if you have a small
grow space of course use smaller Pots if
you have room for larger pots go for the
larger pots you can experiment and see
what and why and how it all works best
for your needs and your environment how
much herb you need uh how often you need
it what strains are going to grow those
are all things that are going to kind of
decide this stuff for
you excuse my dab cough I like to take a
lot of dabs when I record a podcast Adam
was here watching me record and he's
like dude how do you even record with
that many dabs going on I recorded some
stuff with him I'll make another episode
out of that we got a little out of hand
and just started rambling so anyway I'm
doing that again here we go uh once
you've chosen your pot size it's time
for good soil I like a nice fluffy soil
uh with lots of perite in it I had
plenty of amendments so I buy a fairly
inert soil uh if you have access to a
good grow supply store then I recommend
starting with something like Roots
organic Sunshine mix number four
something similar to that these are all
great starters I use a recycled and a
mided soil mix that can get a little
complex and it can make it hard to
diagnose problems if one comes up so I
recommend learning with the basic soil
and organic bottled nutrients unless you
have experience with farming horiculture
composting or some kind of soil or plant
education uh once you understand the
basics of the plants we can make a super
soil mix and work on eliminating the
bottle feeds but for now let's keep it
simple and develop a good understanding
of these plants that's where we want to
start uh so you've got some soil you got
some pots now you've got some small
plants that are in cups let's get those
babies uh into the big girl pots and
then we'll talk about feeding for the
vegetation phase
so having the little babies in cups is
really going to help out and make it
easy to transplant I fill my pots with
soil and I pack it in there slightly
tight I just press it down with my hands
and I don't pack it so tightly that The
Roots can't dig through but I do want to
pack it tightly enough to where the
plant's going to have plenty of support
once I bury that root ball in there uh
if the soil's packed too lightly you'll
know because as soon as you water uh the
water's just going to run right through
the dirt and the soil's going to cave in
and then you'll have to refill in there
but anyway uh fill your pots about 2 in
from the top or more for bigger pots we
want to save some space for watering
a 7 gallon pot will take a gallon of
water or more and that needs some space
in your pot and a three gallon pot
you'll easily take half a gallon up to a
gallon so save yourself some space so I
get the pot mostly full and then I dig
out uh about a large handful of soil out
of the center of the pot uh I set the
Clone in the cup it's still in the
plastic cup right now for a minute I set
that cup in the spot where the Clone is
going to go and I back fill the dirt
around the cup this makes a perfect
little spot for the Clone to fit without
disturbing The Roots uh but I don't
leave the cup okay I want to stress that
I do not leave the cup on the Clone only
for that one second while I was making
an indention I don't leave the cup I
only uh I only use it to make a little
space for the Clone once I've got the
perfect little space in there made for
my clone uh I pull that cup out with the
Clone in it and then I hold the cup
upside down uh with my hand on top of
the cup with the Clone coming out like
between my middle and ring finger and I
flip the cup upside
down excuse me sorry I flip it upside
down I give it a little squeeze and then
uh usually you can just squeeze it and
shake it until the Clone uh slides out
of the cup and then try not to uh try
not to disturb the roots and that soil
ball that come right out of there just
shake it and it'll come out and set that
little soil ball perfectly uh into that
perfect little spot that we just made it
should be the same shape as the cup
since you just make it so just set it
right down in there when the C cup comes
off there'll be dirt falling out uh
it'll seem chaotic and messy but just
stay calm you can drop dirt and [ __ ]
just don't drop the plant just focus on
getting that tiny little root ball into
that hole that we just made and
everything should be just fine so now
you've taken your cup you flipped it
upside down that little baby plant's
falling out you got a handful of dirt
you're holding your new [ __ ] life
right there in your hand you set it in
that like remember that little toy you
used to have when you were a kid you had
to put the little peg into the hole
thing so what you want to do Bo just set
it right in there and now uh you got to
get some dirt and put it over the top of
that I just get it like a small handful
of soil and I drop it over the top of
the whole plant like right where not the
whole plant but all the soil right where
I just put the new freshly planted plant
and uh all around the rest to kind of
level it out so that you just kind of
camouflage the where the spot was you
kind of just want to blend it in you
want all that to become one
spot now I press it down just tightly
enough to hold the plant upright and
carefully label your newly potted plant
label it it sucks having a plant that's
not labeled uh if the cup was well
labeled uh also leave that cup in there
so that way if your label comes off the
cup is still in there sometimes that
helps I sometimes I just use the cup but
once in a while I knock the cup out and
they get confused so that sucks so once
I've got that potted I set it under the
light and I keep working until all of my
new babies are in pots once everything
is potted is when I'll feed them and
make sure to get the pots thoroughly wet
so you've got a crop of freshly
transplanted planted babies under the
lights uh and now that's pretty much the
beginning of the vegetative growth phase
it's time to mix up some nutrients and
feed them their uh First full veg
nutrients I'm a soil grower so uh I
pretty much focus on a dirt Garden if
you're running a Hydro Garden we're
going to have to get a hydro go Hydro
guy on the show here in the future and
have him teach you guys some stuff uh
let's feed our new babies uh if you're a
new grower I recommend mixing your
nutrients in a 5 gallon bucket uh use an
accurate measuring device for your
nutrients I use the shot glass that has
milliliters and stuff marked on it for
small applications for larger stuff
there's a pint glass that is marked with
milliliters and a few other measurements
uh you can find those at your local
Hydro shop I found a half gallon pitcher
that fits perfectly into my 5 gallon
bucket I've learned to my learned to mix
my nutrients into that pitcher and add
that to the bucket instead of mixing my
nutrients directly into a 5 gallon
bucket uh you don't want to pour out
five gallons of water when you mess up
mixing your nutrient feed that's a lot
of water to pour down the drain so fill
your pitcher 3/4 of the way with water
add your nutrients of choice to the
pitcher uh I would use a good base
nutrient a good rud inoculant and some
good enzymes specific specifically I
would use 50 mL of botanic hair pure
blend Pro veg soil formula as my base I
would use ogt or great white shark as my
MOS which is your inoculant and I would
use 15 mL of hydrozyme as my
enzymes uh so in my garden I would add a
little bit of liquid Karma and a few
other supplements but they're not
required uh I add sweet to feed my
beneficials uh I add vitamino for extra
vitamins and and amino acids and vitamin
B also and uh what else to add in there
it seems like I added something else but
uh if you're not looking to spend if
you're not looking to spend the extra
bucks those aren't required but I like
to spoil my plants uh after about a week
I'll or during the next week I'll feed
calmag and potassium silicates and then
I run most of the botanic here botanic
hair pure blend Pro Line when I run
bottled nutrients B Botanicare is not a
sponsor but I've been most satisfied
with uh botanic hair and organic hair
more than any other bottle feed that's
that's just my opinion I ran Advanced
Nutrients I've ran the Aurora Soul
synthetics which produced some super
tasty products uh I ran psycho which was
probably uh not my favorite um yeah I've
ran a bunch of them I've ran the Fox
Farms basic stuff I've done a lot of
feeds I've done so many I can't even
remember them all anyway uh you can find
a pretty good pre-made Botanicare feed
chart on their website I'll try to
remember to post some of my notes on the
feeding programs feeding programs for
that somebody tweet me and remind me at
igro culture I've got this paper here in
front of me so hopefully that'll remind
me uh let's get back on focus a little
bit and talk about mixing stuff
up uh mix up your bottled feeds in a
small container of water but don't ever
mix your nutrients together without
plenty of water don't pour like a shot
glass the measuring device don't pour
the veg stuff and then don't pour
enzymes into the same shot glass at the
same time mix those to water uh the
bottled stuff is sold in separate
bottles to prevent bonding of specific
elements so always mix into water once
your pitcher is mixed put that into the
5 gallon bucket and fill it up the rest
of the way uh once the bucket's full you
need to adjust the pH of your feed
solution adjust your pH to 6.5 using PH
down it's unlikely that your pH is too
low and make sure you calibrate your uh
PH meters frequently that's always a
good idea so you got a bucket full of
nutrient solution that has been pH
adjusted to 6.5 uh we've got our freshly
transplanted babies under a light the
next thing we got to do is pour the feed
into the plants so uh oh I hope you've
got a uh some type of saucer or
something under to catch the runoff
under your plants also like set your
plants in a saucer or a tray uh if you
don't have something like that uh
sometimes I use a I've got a rubber made
tray that'll fit three three gallon pots
in there perfectly so I can just pour
water into the plants and then it'll
drain right into there if not you're
going to end up with water on the floor
so you need something to catch the
runoff that comes out of your plants so
I kind of use the pitcher that I'm using
to stir up the solution before I go
right to the plants and try to mix up
the water a little bit to stir up the
stuff it's always a good idea to stir
everything thoroughly uh sometimes if
I'm using a big batch sometimes I mix my
nutrients into a much larger batch I
throw an AirStone in there to pump it up
a little bit to air rate it and then
while it's doing that I also use a big
stick like the kind that you'd use to
support your plants I use that to stir
the water up uh it just seems to be
effective I like stirring it it's a good
idea so uh mix it up a little bit then
simply pour about a third of a gallon of
water of the feed into each plant uh if
you're using larger pots you're going to
need more you know if the soil settles
uh then you need to add more water
you'll notice pretty quickly if it like
crumbles down in uh once we add the
water all the air space is going to get
pushed out and it's going to yeah the
dirt's going to move around you may have
to adjust some of your plants and some
of the soil so uh water everything and
refill any pots that you need to fill
with soil and get the plants under good
lights T5 lights are good for veg if you
have enough of them close to the plants
metal halides are also ideal for veg
growth we want to focus on getting those
pots full of roots right now so the blue
spectrum is kind of what we want LEDs
seem to be really good for veg plants
but I personally don't have any
experience with the LEDs but I have seen
some great photographs coming from an
LED Garden shout out to Nancy budwell
she's growing some Bounty Killer right
now and it looks
amazing so uh try to keep your veg area
around 72 to 77° if you're using CO2 you
can get it let it get a little bit
warmer uh maybe low 80s during the light
period during your dark cycle try to
keep them about the same temp or no more
no more than 10° cooler than daytime
temperatures uh try to keep your
humidity around 40 to 55% if possible uh
in Colorado it gets hard to keep the
rooms humid so they get dry here uh
honestly you'd rather have it too dry
than too humid if you have the option uh
if you can't get it right where you want
it if you're blowers are messed up and
not the way you need them to be if you
can't correct it I understand you're
growing in a house it's not going to be
perfect you'd rather have it too dry
than too moist if you've got the option
so also remember to keep your air fresh
uh you don't want stale stuffy air in
your Grow rooms your plants need plenty
of CO2 and they deplete the CO2 in a
room very quickly uh having stale air in
a grow room can lead to powdery mildew
and it slows down the growth of your
plants quite quickly so I keep my
vegging plants under 24 hours a light I
think they grow more quickly under 24
hours of light uh than they do with a
dark cycle during veg most books will
tell you to run a 16-hour day period and
an 8h hour dark period I think it's
great because it's how nature works and
you can't argue with that um I've
experimented with both sometimes if I'm
running a seed crop I will run a 16-hour
light cycle and then go to a 1212 cycle
sometimes I will run an 1113 cycle which
is odd but we'll talk about that later
on I learned that from DJ
Short uh so the that 168 light cycle is
great like I said it's on nature works
it also lets your equipment cool down
and take a little bit of a break and it
lets your electricity bill chill out for
a second let your meter quit spinning so
as long as your vegging plants are under
16 hours of light every day they should
be happy you can experiment with it uh
I'll do another show with more info on
light cycles and photo period later on
uh one thing I've really noticed is that
when I flip my plants to 1212 to flower
from this 24-hour light cycle they show
flower faster than the plants that had a
dark cycle during
veg and that's just one thing I've
noticed so if you're really looking for
a production crop that's something to
keep in mind since I just remembered
that that's kind of what inspired that
for me I think I'm might switch back and
I also uh like to keep my mother plants
under 1212 just to keep them from even
thinking that they may have the chance
to flower once they get root bound and
stuff they sometimes some of your mother
plants may try to Auto flower on you so
we've got our babies in new pots um and
we fed them they're under good lights I
put a fan lightly blowing over the
canopy to keep the air circulating uh
and if the temps and the humidity
humidity are correct in the room the
plants won't need water for uh 3 or 4
days if you water them enough right now
so this is a good time to start thinking
about Pest Management if you have NE oil
on hand give each plant a good spray
when the lights turn off you don't want
to spray them when the lights are on uh
that creates what I call Little
reflector Bubbles from the uh you know
the bubbles L on your plant the light
hits it just like a magnifying glass did
when you were a little kid and you used
to cook ants it'll happen to your plants
the grow light will work as the sun and
the bubble will work like a magnifying
glass and you'll get a little burn mark
a little white spot so spray when the
lights are off always try to spray when
the lights are off uh yeah that's
any book will tell you that uh NE will
keep most of your pests away once you're
in flower you'll need to rethink the ne
because you do not want to spray neem on
your flowering plants don't do that
it'll taste terrible if you make
concentrates with neem sprayed plants oh
excuse me if you make concentrates with
neem sprayed plants you can definitely
taste the neem so once you're in flour
stop spraying neem uh I've got a new
product I'm testing out if it works for
me I'm definitely going to share it with
you it's uh it's all organic was
recommended to me by somebody in the
horiculture industry not the Cannabis
industry so it's used for food crops so
it's completely safe uh it didn't smell
bad when I used it I'm kind of testing
it out now I'll let you know what I
think so you're now officially in the
FEG phase I feed bottle nutrients if I'm
using bottle nutrients I only feed them
once per week uh with plain pH water
throughout the rest of the week so I
personally feed all my plants on Monday
so as if you guys are listening to this
on Monday I'm probably waiting for the
lights to come on the flower room comes
on at 10:00 uh it'll click on uh I will
actually have my nutrients mixed up
already I'll start doing that about 9:30
it's Monday they're going to get fed uh
I think these plants are in they're
going to start week five today so I'll
start mixing up to the week five
stuff um get the pH adjusted in there
and then I'll throw some air stones in
there and let that stuff just bubble
around and let the nutrients Mingle for
a little while and then as soon as
lights come on I'll go in there and feed
them so uh I'll need the water again
usually by Thursday uh once they get
heavier into flour it may step up to
Wednesday they won't go as long so think
about how tall you can let your plants
get that's something you got to keep in
mind think about how tall your plants
can get uh think about if you want to
top them or let them grow naturally
because your plants some sativa plants
can double it in size during flower like
if you're growing the Bounty Killer that
thing is going to double in size during
your flower period so it's time to think
about how tall and wide your plants can
get before you need to flower them out
because that is going to be the next
major phase of your plants you got to
let them veg you probably got another
month month to 45 maybe two months if
you want to go crazy but I recommend
about 30 days veg time from here out so
don't get any bugs don't burn them with
nutrients take good care of them that's
super important uh I think that gets us
basically started through the veg phase
I plan to go in depth with each of these
little topics in the future we'll make
little branches from everything that
I've mentioned I want to get everybody
up to speed with the basics before we go
too deeply into specific stuff about
growing uh I've got tons of information
to share with you guys if you want more
details on anything I mentioned please
just ask me because I would love to help
you out I'd love to elaborate tweet me
it's IG culture Facebook me at igro
culture on Facebook or send me an email
it's ulture hotmail.com I feel like I
say that all the time I will answer
almost anything you ask I love to just
uh interact with my social media people
it's fun so I feel like that was a lot
of talking I'm going to freshen up my
throat here probably take a dab um I'm
going to be right back and we will uh
see what else we got from this show hang
tight all right guys I'm going to wrap
the show up right there you tend to
listen to more of the show if I put out
a 30 minute episode I gets a better
response so uh now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for igro culture find the
review section give me a festar rating
after that type in a little comment and
let me know what you think of the
podcast and I will read your comments on
the show I love the interaction uh don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher swell. am and also every
episode is available on iy gentics
color.com so if you want to go back and
listen to old episodes that aren't
available on iTunes or Stitcher all you
got to do is go to www.ir gentics
color.com and you can click on the
podcast tab right there and every
episode should be available uh big shout
out to my ninja Spence big thanks to
Adam uh Adam uh came and hung out with
me for a little while and watched me
record part of the show uh big shout out
to everybody that helped me out this
week with the few things I needed uh
it's been a busy week so thanks for all
the help in the iy genetics family I'll
be back in 7 days with the brand new
episode for you uh probably have more
grow lessons for you and uh Jesse is
getting married so he won't be back for
a couple of weeks to do an episode but
he will be back so you guys that keep
tweeting me and asking me where's Jesse
he's planning a wedding we got to give
him some time and some space he belongs
to his wife now he is not ours anymore
shout out to Jesse congratulations on
the wedding uh that's not for another
week but it's coming up and we're proud
for you I need to give a huge shout out
to DJ Nick the music you heard at the
beginning of the show was DJ Nick the
song that I'm about to play right here
the end of the show will also be DJ Nick
so thanks for letting me play your music
need to give a big shout out to my ninja
Spence that was the end of episode
number 20 thanks again for listening you
guys it really means a lot to me take a
fat dab give your mom a hug for
me about some life get with it s every
day we got with it from the West make we
sh
[Music]
I