[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 200 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated Dabba if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I wanna thank you guys again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots been collecting Muse
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat coop in the entire mystic Ruis
crew
happy 4/20 everybody this episode is
coming out on 4/20 April 20th of 2017
thank you for joining me for 4/20 I will
be a work on 4/20 at 4:20 but I
guarantee you we will be taking a smoke
break or wait maybe we won't depends on
who you are if you're the boss we're not
taking a smoke break if you're the meed
if you're OSHA we will be in the
building working for 4/20 with you're a
podcast fan
we'll be dabbing the [ __ ] out for 4/20
it'll be a good ass time ladies and
gentleman happy 4/20 if you can't tell
I'm already high a [ __ ] it's for 19 I'm
recording the day before 4/20 obviously
Wednesday for $19 and some golden goat
chatter in my hand I've got a joint the
size of a small baseball bat this thing
is going to get several people stoned
out of their minds if this should be a
good time whatever this gets lit up
thank you for joining me for episode 200
this is a great lineup you guys this is
episode number 200 on 4/20 and also
we've been recording this podcast for
what I believe has been approximately
two years so it's a great celebration
thank you for listening everybody thanks
for being here for 4/20 I hope you're
smoking on something take some time to
roll up a joint roll up a blunt if
that's what you got to do I'm not really
a big fan of blunts I think we grow
really quality cannabis and then watch
you guys grind it up and put into a
blunt it's kind of heartbreaking that
blunt tastes like [ __ ] to me here grape
flavored blunt wrap what the [ __ ] is
with that those berry flavored blunt
wrap that you guys are smoking it smells
terrible it makes my lips feel funky
cannot deal with that I don't know how
you guys do it but if you're smoking to
pull out more power to you go for it and
do it smoke that blunt just not for me
I bet hopefully I know people gonna say
but you run butane over your weed and
destroy it you're right turns it into
golden sweet shatter that doesn't taste
like funky like I'm smoking incense
whatever you're doing smoke a blow with
me smoke a DAB smoke some shatter smoke
some live resin smoke some rosin
whatever you got smoke it up you got
some sauce take a dad and pass it down
over to me I'd love a dab of that [ __ ]
right about now hey guys I am rambley
this is going to be a short quick
episode I just wanted to jump in and
take some dabs and hang out with
everybody for 4/20 so that we could feel
like we spent some time together on the
national stoner holiday since this is a
cannabis based podcast since I'm doing
shoutouts and stuff let me start off
with something really really serious
here huge thanks to everybody who is
contributed and supported me on patreon
that is
amazing recently I had a couple of
sizable contributions that really helped
me move my project forward I appreciate
that it helps with all the new equipment
you'll notice that there is a video for
this episode it won't be up for a long
time but I am recording a video this
right now onto the iPad I'm running the
recording gear I ran a headphone out
into a device called the iRig 2 I'm
running iRig into the iPad the iPad is
recording a video that will have this
microphone quality sound coming through
it so in the future there will be video
of this I'm trying to get all the videos
up on YouTube it is a lot of work you
guys but anyway thanks to the people who
have contributed on patreon if you're
not aware of patreon let me tell you
what patreon is patreon is a service
that allows that allows my listeners to
contribute financially to the podcast if
you want to learn more you can go to
patreon.com/scishow and if you
contribute one time or you can sign up
for a subscription if you sign up for a
one-time contribution whatever amount
you decide to type in if it's one dollar
if it's nine dollars if it's a $9,999 if
you sign up for a one-time contribution
on the first of the month that one-time
contribution will roll through and that
will be deposited into my PayPal account
if you decide to do a subscription every
month whatever amount you decided to
contribute that will be rolled from your
card into my PayPal account once a month
I'm not trying to get rich I'm not
asking you guys to pay my rent I'm not
asking to buy me a new car what I am
trying to do is offset the cost of my
website it does cost me a little bit of
money to have a website which is where I
hosted the show honestly you guys my
website sucks it's a mess it's terrible
I am NOT a web guy I haven't put any
time or energy or effort into that
website it is there kind of it's nothing
impressive I apologize I'm embarrassed
but I don't have the resources or the I
don't know how to do that and I'm not
going to take the time to learn it'll
get fixed my buddy that does it's been
tied up he's a new dad he'll get to it
yeah but anyway so the website hosts the
podcast the podcast is then dumped into
all of the other services like iTunes
stitcher pod Bay Feedburner wherever
else it goes it goes to a lot of places
so people can listen to it but it does
cost money to have the website so the
funds that you guys contribute to my
patreon go directly to my PayPal and
then that goes directly to my web
hosting and it covers the cost of my web
hosting once the web hosting is covered
what I will do with the funds I'm making
sure I didn't press a button here I just
move my iPad cool we're good we're still
recording what I plan to do with those
funds is cover things like this iPad
that I bought and then also it will
cover more toys for the iPads I want to
add some accessories to it and it'll be
upgrades I buy these little foam covers
for the microphones that'll be part of
what the patreon covers but if you'd
like to contribute or if you'd like to
know more simply go to
patreon.com/scishow
your listens being the world to me just
being part of my community being part of
my team here being involved in this
that's awesome
thank you you don't have to give me
money for me to be your friend I like
you for listening I like you for who you
are you look good today
by the way has anyone told you that you
look [ __ ] great today alright guys
who can tell I'm high as giraffe [ __ ] I
am I'll admit it so I've been talking
about via the dude grows cut big shout
out to my friends at the dude grow show
the dude and Scotty real the whole crew
the dude grows crew a bunch of great
folks
I am honored to be a part of that little
crew there I went to the dude grows cup
I did not tell you guys who the winners
were because I left before that happened
honestly I was exhausted and had to work
the next day had to drive 130 miles back
home so I left anyway on the next
episode of the dude gross that I listen
to they announced the winners I was
excited you guys I'm gonna go through
these are just the flower winners is all
I've got here I did not list the
concentrate winners but here are the
flower winners from the dude grows Cup
that happened on April 15th of 2017 I
don't know when you're listening to this
hopefully on 4/20 with me dabs up if you
are but here are the winners from the
dude gross Cup third place for best
flower voted by the the attendees of the
event third place lemon Jeffery from Ira
genetics I did not grow it I did not
enter it apparently a guy named Cole who
was a well-known grower in Denver that
grows for a large dispensary a
well-known large dispensary in Denver a
guy named Cole grew some lemon Jeffery
and he entered it into the dude grows
cup and it won third place
Congrats shout out and much love to Cole
hey Cole if you're listening to this or
if anybody can read you out to Cole and
have him contact me and don't just go
trolling and act like you're Cole but
Cole have you got a present for you all
you got to do is get in touch with me
I'd like to put some things in your
hands thank you great work
congratulations and yeah man I've got a
gift for you so please do get in touch
if the dude grows crew can put him in
touch with me somehow I would appreciate
that and also big shout out to the dude
grows crew for the relationship that
we've built I think it's really cool
that we've got two podcasts serving two
different audiences and one joint
audience and there's no I don't feel
intimidated by them they're not
intimidated by me it's [ __ ] awesome
that we've built this community and this
connection in this bond
let's get back on tracks I'm high as
[ __ ] second place in the dude gross cup
was purple elephant grown by a guy who
calls himself stony Jack 420 so shout
out to stony Jack 420 with the purple
elephant they said that the difference
in second and third place was actually
one vote there were 35 and 34 votes for
second and third place so one vote split
it up so if you go to a cannabis event
and you were able to vote just like in
politics [ __ ] vote cuz your vote
counts I might not have a third place
winning strain if you would have voted
differently that's how it goes so one
vote is all it would have taken to knock
me out of there not me personally I bred
the strain I can't take too much credit
I made the seeds once those seeds left I
don't know what happened to him
apparently Cole grew the [ __ ] out of it
good work so first place first place got
over 50 votes that it was everybody's
favorite strain first place was a strain
called Brandywine grown by a person who
calls himself van rip ster I have not
met van rip ster but I hope to one day
great work nice grow much respect for
what in the dude grows cups so third
place Lemon Jeffries second place purple
elephant and first place Brandywine
grown by Van RIP stir excellent works
everybody at the dude grows cup it was a
great event I had a good time you guys
get ready cuz I'm gonna enter some [ __ ]
next year that's right I drove up there
and I had a good time and I partied wide
enough [ __ ] didn't I enter something I'd
have a cup sitting on this table right
now you guys so dude Scotty get ready
cuz I'm entering next year Stoney Jack I
get ready then rip stir get ready Cole
talk to me and get ready cuz I'm coming
for you next year you guys I'm gonna be
in this damn dude gross
it's no reason for me to drive up there
and hang out with everybody and not
bring some cannabis to injure right all
right I can't wait so uh you know what
was missing from the dude Rose Cup beau
you've got to be up here next year with
us that's all that was missing you got
to come so bone Ellis I look forward to
seeing you at the dude gross gut mixture
with the whole crew it would be a great
podcast experience all right you guys
I've got one question for you that I
want to ask everybody that's listening I
might have two or three questions once I
start rambling you never know how it
goes with me I wanted to keep this
episode short but yeah that might not
happen I want to know what you're
listening to when you're smoking down
what kind of music do you like to jam
obviously I like reggae music I like
Morgan heritage I like Steel Pulse I
like Marlin Asher I like stuff like that
of course I'm a huge Grateful Dead fan I
like any of the Grateful Dead stuff all
of the Grateful Dead stuff mostly but
stuff from like 1977 is kind of my
favorite if you're a deadhead the Betty
boards for a May of 77 the North East
Coast tour that's some of my favorite
[ __ ] ever 72 is good some of that
acoustic stuff from 72 the West Coast
stuff from the early years is great but
the Grateful Dead obviously you guys I'm
a [ __ ] Grateful Dead fan 72 74 77
that's my favorite Grateful Dead [ __ ]
right there but then I think if somebody
asked me what my favorite band was I
would probably have to flip a coin that
day and see what kind of mood I'm in
it's either fish or the Grateful Dead
I'm a huge fish fan also so when I'm
gettin blazed I like to listen to fish
the Grateful Dead or good reggae and
honestly when I was younger I was a huge
metalhead I liked the UH not not super
heavy meant well yeah I got it I dabbled
into the super heavy [ __ ] for a little
while but uh I was into like Metallica
Pantera Megadeth stuff like that kind of
into the Pearl Jam side of stuff but
more on the metal less grungy side the
more metal side of stuff so occasionally
when we're working at the grow and
things are draggin yesterday morning
everybody had a hard time kitten [ __ ]
started so I fired up Metallica radio
and just the kick drum and cymbals and
snare drum [ __ ] going everybody was
working at an acceptable pace after a
couple of songs so that's what I like to
listen to if I need to get it fired up
which isn't very often if I really need
to get moving I'll put on mo
I think mo is like super high-energy
maybe some government mule if I need to
wake the
but so I really rambled about music fish
mo the Grateful Dead ah
reggae music of course widespread panic
occasionally I just listened to a lot of
panic it's just missed a logic to me I
guess always some good Jerry Garcia
stuff that's always some of my favorites
so I want to know what you guys are
listening to send me a tweet send me an
email if you want to tweet me it's at g
f YH podcast if you want to email me of
course its grow from your heart at
hotmail.com i want to know what music
you're listening to when you're gettin
blazed also just cuz it's fun to know
what people are doing what are your
favorite snacks after you get high now
if you take a couple of fat dab in your
mouth starts doing that mmm and your
stomach goes wow what's the kind of [ __ ]
you want to walk to the fridge for or
what do you want to drive to 7-eleven
and get I want to know what kind of
snacks you like to get down on I'm
pretty simple I like cold dr. pepper and
a bottle fresh cold dr. pepper in a
bottle that I wanted to when I crack it
open that's like my favorite [ __ ] and
any kind of snacks I'm good just I
prefer crunchy over a sweet I think most
of the time most of the time but not
always yeah that's just my my snack
preferences I'm curious let me know what
you're snacking on once you get blazed
so I don't know what you're listening to
I wanna know what you're snacking on I
wanna I want to be friends with you guys
also tell me what you're smoking on 4/20
everybody it's 4/20 tweet me let me know
what you're smoking email me let me know
what you're smoking I want to know what
strain you're smoking I want to know how
you're smoking it you got flowers do you
have dabs you got live resin let me know
what's going on if you care to let me
know if you're not in an illegal state
let me know where you purchased it if
you got it at a dispensary let me know
which dispensary and let me know what
you think of it also that's a fun thing
to do so you could be like I'm smoking
like right now as soon as I start
playing the music to fade out the
podcast I'm gonna take a dab of grateful
dog shatter through a hit man rig with
the quartz nail on it a quartz banger
and the flowers were grown by me and the
product was extracted by our friend the
barefoot extracts I also may take her
this is better cuz this came from a
dispensary I'm a dab some women Jeffrey
batter from apothecary that's who
extracted it and I purchased it at a
place called elevate in Colorado Springs
elevated sorry elevated in Colorado
Springs so give me that kind of info if
you want to let me know what you're
smoking I would love to know once again
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
or you can tweet me at GF wih podcast or
if you're on the facebook just go to the
Facebook page of course its grow from
your heart let me know what you're
smoking on let me know what you're
listening to and then let me know what
you're gonna snag on after you get nice
and blazed for 4/20 you guys I've been
rambling for like 15 minutes I usually
stop and take a drink and take a couple
of dabs right about now but I think I'm
just gonna wish everybody a happy 4/20
and I am going to take a couple of dabs
while the music plays and I hope you
were dabbing with me I would take a fat
dab right now while we're recording but
I'm gonna COFF and it's just gonna be
kind of a waste of recording space so
know that when I hit play on the ending
music that I'm taking fat dabs and that
it's time for you to give your mom a hug
I didn't even thought about what song
I'm gonna play at the end here I think
we're gonna play ganja farmer by Marlon
Asher it seems like a very appropriate
song and I bet I could find it on my
phone pretty quickly to make it happen I
am recording a video also I'm not gonna
record the video I probably will not
record the audio unless I [ __ ] up right
now trying to find this song which I'm
searching for just bear with me for just
a couple of seconds let me turn this
down so don't screw up on you and make
something go crazy we're typing in ganja
and it doesn't find ganja farmer it's
really weird how that I phone work
sometimes Hey look what I found there's
a song called ganja farmer all right
ladies and gentleman I wanna thank
everybody for listening to episode 200 I
can't believe it 200 episodes you guys I
know I'm kind of cheating because I've
been putting out those long episodes but
there's still some work to those two so
it counts man there's there is there are
200 episodes I think it counts it's
official so thank you for listening to
200 episodes thanks for tolerating me
for what I think has been about two
years I hope everybody has a huge safe
exciting stoney as [ __ ] 4/20 I hope your
eyes get super red I hope everybody
makes it through it if you're going to
an event to be an activist don't be
stupid
don't go to jail don't cause any
problems be respectful of the plant
represent this planet in a very
respectful respectable way we are
ambassadors to the cannabis plant we
represent this plant represent it in a
good way don't be a [ __ ] please
that's my serious note for this 4/20
please if you're out there do it
responsibly you're gonna be on the news
think about it whenever you're doing
whatever you're doing picture the news
story in your head how's it gonna go
[ __ ] drives car into wall or [ __ ]
it's not gonna say [ __ ] on the
headline but that's how you're gonna
feel when you read it it's about you
[ __ ]
something dumb to put a black eye on the
marijuana scene you don't want that you
don't be that guy all right all right I
love you guys
hope you have a great 4/20 only give a
huge shout out to everybody who is
smoking with me today on 4/20 I'm gonna
play some reggae music I feel like a DJ
when I do this but this song is from
Marlon Asher and it's called ganja
farmer everybody has a happy 4/20 and
until next time take a fat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
Oh
come get you the money
two tablets angry no Fargo drives man
and to me of the