it's a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff I'm
back with another chunk of old episodes
this time we're doing episodes 28 29 30
and 31 of what used to be the iGrow
culture podcast now known as the girl
from your heart podcast before we get
into these old episodes let me make the
disclaimers I like to make um I've
learned a lot in 200 episodes ah I think
it's been about three years which means
I've learned a lot about growing I've
learned a lot about podcasting I've
learned about a lot about life if I say
something in these episodes that I have
contradicted myself with just keep in
mind that [ __ ] changes this is an
ever-changing industry and ever-changing
project this will always be changing
that's why I do a podcast and do not
write a book so I may say some things
that have been updated I may contradict
myself over time [ __ ] changes they'll
hold it against me
also all the social media has changed
since the show has changed from the
Hydra culture podcast to the girlfriend
heart podcast I changed all the social
media the Twitter is now at G fyh
podcast the Facebook is the girl from
your heart podcast and email is now grow
from your heart at hotmail.com so if
you'd like to reach out those are your
options I would love to hear from you
the easiest way to get in touch with me
of course is by sending me an email to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
alright I think that's all I've got for
the start of these episodes so without
making this file too long let's get into
episodes 28 29 30 and 31 of what used to
be known as the Hydra culture podcast
now known as the girl from your heart
podcast ladies and gentlemen thank you
for listening
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 28 of the
iGrow culture podcast
they call me Rasta Jeff and I'll be your
captain for this adventure this episode
Spencer and Jessi came back and they
brought our friend Michael and we
haven't talked about phenyl hunting but
we got really dabbed out so I apologize
if we were too high to be useful
hopefully we spark some questions so
please send those questions to me via
email Twitter or Facebook and I'll
answer them on an upcoming show
of course the email address is hydro
culture at hotmail.com can find me on
twitter under anti-guerrilla culture or
on facebook just search for agriculture
we've got three ways to get in touch
with us so please send me your questions
about phenyl hunting or anything else
you'd like to hear about on the show and
I will talk about it on a future episode
to announce that this podcast is brought
to you by highly educated titanium if
you're using high quality concentrates
you deserve a high quality titanium meal
made in America don't trust a Chinese
nail or an American knockoff made of
cheap metals trust the industry leader
highly educated titanium highly educated
products are available at Aqualab
technologies calm educated has been able
to fit any rig and they are the only
titanium products endorsed by this
podcast a big shout out to task rock you
were listening to hits from the nail by
tasking Linus this podcast is also
brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gauge green genetics
lopata labs since city rare dankness
file hi can adventure ira genetics and
many more trusted brands nature's green
remedies is running a special for the
podcast listeners type in coupon code
september 14 for 15% off any order and
he always get free shipping at nature's
green remedies dot-com
this podcast is brought to you in part
by hydro indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 beach street unit
F or stop by the new pub location at
6:18 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
check out hydro for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor grow
supplies and don't forget to check out
www.engvid.com for current store hours
and special sales big love to tree
hugger comm this episode is brought to
you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger comm for concert and festival
news and reviews lookout at the cookout
with tree hugger comm much respect to
all of our sponsors for making the
show's possible I don't want to spend
too much time on the intro let's get to
the good part here goes the pheno hunt
talk with the boys thanks for listening
guys alright what's up ladies and
gentlemen we are back we are gathered
today we got michael on the microphone
with us tonight what's up bro do you uh
do you have a twitter name or something
people can look for and find you on our
instagram so they can check you out
while there to listen into the show
colorado bearded dabbers in the house
[Music]
phenotypes everybody here is a pretty
experienced grower so what everyone i'll
have a lot of input i should explain
what a phenotype is it's the first thing
i'll take one step back we will explain
a genotype the offspring of two parents
will make genetics and that genetic
makeup is the genotype out of that
genotype there will be various
phenotypes the best way I can think of
to compare it would be when your parents
make kids they don't all look the same
your dad's probably tall your mom's
brother a little shorter one of them's
got blond hair one of them's got dark
hair when they make kids sometimes they
come out with kids with blonde hair
sometimes you come out with kids with
dark hair sometimes you come out
blue-eyed sometimes they come out brown
plants are gonna do the same thing and
that's to be expected
there are ways to minimize those traits
or bring out traits that you're looking
for but for the most part when you're
making seeds in the beginning the seeds
that most of you guys are able to get
your hands on what a lot of the breeders
are selling you aren't going to be f1 f2
s or f3 s there are very few breeders
going far further than f4 there's one
guy in of that bragged about f5 which is
really cool really respectable so you're
gonna see a lot of variation I just
talked a lot I feel there's a lot of
echo I feel like I've talked a lot about
variation in phenotypes and a lot of f1
and stuff so in f1 when you take two
plants a male and a female plant those
are now your pea ones when you breed
them the seeds that come out of that are
f1 that's the f1 generation you're gonna
have a lot of variety there some stuff's
gonna look like mom some stuffs gonna
kind of look like the dad you're gonna
get a lot of switching then you're gonna
get stuff way in the middle between the
mom and the dad you'll get that perfect
hybrid and that's a lot of times the one
that everybody is looking for then a
little further you'll make an f2 if you
take if you find a sweet male and a
sweet female out of those F ones and you
breathe those together you're gonna make
an f2 f2 is where you come up with
something that we call transgressive
segregation which means and Jesse smiled
when I mentioned this free show transit
transgressive segregation is when your
actual progeny which is your offspring
outperforms the parents so if you take
two seeds a male and a female and you
cross them and that plant that comes out
is way more badass than the parents you
have just experienced transgressive
segregation so the f2 level is where you
really want to buy the seeds if a
breeder selling those seeds a lot of us
don't really let you know what we're
giving you which F level how far it is
that's kind of personal stuff it's kind
of breeding secrets but those F 2's are
awesome if you can get ahold of those
that's where a lot of cool [ __ ] happens
so we're gonna kind of back up a little
bit the variation a lot of us at the
table seem to love the variation we do
what is called a feed ohan we buy a pack
of seeds you grow that whole pack is
usually ten seeds
and you look for if you're not gonna
breed you eliminate the female so
hopefully you've got else the males
thank you thanks I'm good thanks for
watching my back so you got to pull
those males and then you keep it going
to catch my breath also keep the females
going you try to find the good ones you
look for the traits that those are
putting off early on you could tell
structure speed of growth there's a
bigger leaf size you can tell kind of if
you get a more indica or sativa leaning
phenotype note spacing there you go
that's gonna lead to a lot of what its
gonna really smell like in the end yeah
sometimes early resin production get the
frosting if things are going real well
okay you want to require let's just this
thing over here talked about this
headphone thing shorter stocky plants
necessarily I usually like more indica
plants that's why I'm you looking for
you can you know figure out whether or
not your plants gonna be well depending
like sometimes I grow plants under a
scroll net so like the link your plants
you'll get will be better for a strong
net in my opinion and then you're you
know shorter stockier plants over your
just freestanding plants that you can
stake down and don't have to give too
much support besides that but you know
bigger smells and then I look for like
especially if I know what it's coming
from you can look at like your leaf sets
and see if they start matching parents
yeah stuff like that then you can know
which parent you've got a guy all right
you said some sort of interesting that
leads me to another point doing the
pheno huh run in a pack of seeds and
looking for that fee know that you like
both of these guys grow difference
everybody in this room droves a
different style I don't do any I like to
run a seven gallon so those plants you
guys are worried about waving around
early on in life some variation to talk
about s1 s1 s1 is when I do a lot asked
ones that's a feminized seed essentially
or usually like if I take my grateful
dog to grateful dog clones of the same
plant reverse one throw that pollen on
the other one in flower those seeds are
not a new it's not a new breed it's just
an s-1 I've selfed it and made seeds of
that same thing so that's an s-1 I find
that those a lot of people hate on
feminized seeds but if an s-1 is done
properly and I want to hear your guys's
opinions cuz you've been growing my see
it's a little bit do the s1 seemed to
mirror their parents a little bit more
than the regular was but it came out so
different there's so much like it's like
one of his original parents was it the
Kabletown I think it o female that I use
in the Kabletown cross I gave him the
first handful of seeds I made out of
that to run for me just to say thanks
but yeah I saw that in the pictures I
could see the Grateful dog but if you
knew that it was that white widow mom
you could see her I've got buddies
running it now and I can look at them
from you know four or five weeks
complaining and you can see in the
structure and then in the leaf is
leaning toward you can almost keep that
one full boss he makes dank water hash
and grows that stream like a pro so good
work bro thanks for doing my my seeds
justice what is your experience with
destitute I said compared to say f2 if
you know mine answer the S ones come out
I would say 50% of them look like mommy
and then the other fifty are a little
weird and you know that's hard to say
for a breeder but they it's not a
natural it's cousin [ __ ] essentially
I'm not supposed to say that word of the
podcast anymore but there's no better
way to put that it's that's cousin
[ __ ] as to come out even more uniform
more uniform but they're even more
uniform once you get into that and I
didn't realize I was doing something
unique when I was doing it I took the
same grateful dog the original female
and Kate kept taking the clone and using
that reversed female to make seeds again
and then making another generation
almost inbreeding it and I've gotten it
so far that those come out like clothes
those grateful dog sees no current the
s4 generation I think is kind of what it
would be I don't know a lot of people
that have done it so I don't know how to
label incest
or have come out there like clones of
each other growing seeds from clone
which is kind of nice for a breeder to
achieve in a feminized see eventually be
very popular
[Music]
you always find weird that's why I ask
because I don't think I've ever grown an
s2 that I know of so you know I've grown
up to 3 or 4 B x3 I'm at the point I
don't know if I want to back cross it
one more time because I'm pretty happy
with what what I got from it or if I
want to start in crossing it and start
making I guess would be a f1 f2
generation D nom and so on percentage of
those seeds now are coming out to be
what you have in mind well there's
there's two different phenotypes and I
really like components there were some
less desirable phenotypes and I worked
them out I believe on the BX 2
generation when I when I made the trees
so I'm in the threes of just the one
phenotype I called one-night stand and
it's the hazy the other one is just the
Depot dug and it's real but you know as
a Kim dog stabilization project so it's
a lot like Kim D a a little bit like
diesel a little bit more more more
unique thing or not unique but different
things slightly different than Kim D but
a lot like it so as we're thrown around
a lot of crazy terms here and my bad our
bad
they'll catch up we inspire them to
learn stuff if you're lost google it if
you want to or just keep listening and
eventually this episode but we're saying
will sound like okay if you want you in
for myself I like the explanations if I
have a problem that's the first book hey
bro no no no no this one was written
early 80s but the title is how to grow
or in the first chapter how to grow a
million pounds of skunk weed or so
but they're talking about pounds of UK
pounds so yeah they'll Thomas I keep on
to say my Googler is out of reach right
now so we'll just keep the conversation
rolling for sure
my favorite is at this point in my life
is Google so um you gotta sort through a
lot of [ __ ] but you learn where the
reliable sources are and when you see
one of their articles pop up he knows
and most the time I think they're
probably referencing all these great
books hopefully read three or four
articles on Google yeah think about what
you're gonna do go smoke a fat joint and
call one of your grower friends or
Twitter somebody here on the show yeah
and one of us on the show usually we're
pretty friendly folk if you catch us at
the right time won't answer your emails
it takes me a minute y'all I get a lot
of messages I grow culture at
hotmail.com I grow culture on Twitter I
grow culture on Instagram and of course
on Facebook feel free to message me you
can go to the I read genetics colorado
website and go to the forum create an
account log in there and i make it a
point to answer those questions there
personally because that is my forum i
feel responsible so log in there
create an account I'll answer all of
your questions and if not my buddy Tony
Orkut proof or good roll or somebody in
there will help you out really soon be
leery of information from a lot of
forums especially I'm not gonna say any
names but there's two specific ones I
never banned from two forums for talking
[ __ ] about people saying the wrong [ __ ]
yeah and okay with that you can oh yeah
[ __ ] those guys
yeah if you're gonna do stuff wrong and
I say that's [ __ ] you banned me
you're supporting [ __ ] so ban me I
don't want to play anyway there's one I
really want to say it's name
[Music]
Julie beam is something super popular
you always hear about that candy store
Fino in the orange vino there's
Chernobyl the golden ticket you know
when you grow my gold and go from seed
you're looking for that golden goat fee
no that's just like mommy plush berry
that's a great example there's a black
cherry Kim phenotype and then there's
the space clean dominant phenotype that
black cherry Kim or no black cherry soda
sorry bitrate in your dress black cherry
soda phenotype that's domina - that is
very noticeable you'll know if you've
got it about twenty days into flower you
can tell turn off the lights and turn on
the normal lights and look from the
underside of the calyx and you'll see
the purple for sure known phenotypes
yeah DJ shorts low DJ short said that he
put that flow out that he released that
clone that's in Colorado he said he let
that out
everybody what was possible with those
seats what the potential of flow was so
that cut that we all have supposedly
came from DJ short shout out DJ short I
have learned a lot of stuff from deep
yeah I like that he's doing the free
weed show a lot more a lot of I've
learned a lot from just listen to DJ on
that show that's great to hear that he's
not Canadians actually no I leaned up on
the mic like you're ready to go I'm hand
on the designer read your questions so I
can thank you some [ __ ] to say do you
this is why is variation happening and
useful we talked about kind of why it's
happening because we're bringing a male
and a female and now they're making
babies and we don't want all the babies
to look the same in the world that's how
plants survive so how do you find that
variation to be useful do you want that
stuff I mean different free knows gives
you you know like we talked about on a
previous episode we talked about how
many Dino's you should keep in a seat
pack so you know that's where you would
want to keep a couple different
especially if it's a seat pack that is a
hybrid you know something like that
where you can get multiple variations of
your parents so I enjoy you know the
different variations like some plants
grow faster some plants you know have
more side branching you know some plants
grow straight up people look for waiting
stupid clones well did something to the
water around here or something cuz
everybody's clones everybody that I know
in this circle of growers was like my
clothes bro clothes bro
I've lost the trees of
small triggers my games back on like
Spence set but for a minute there we
were all calling each other like you
[Music]
yeah what was going on it had to be
something in the water something in the
water it seems like every year this
happens about this time it's good to
know and also if you guys are indoor
growers in Colorado be prepared to be
[ __ ] for a couple of months because
nobody's gonna buy your product because
every other day with a really big burger
looking pretty nice yeah yeah yeah it's
a really neat greenhouse a lot of really
cool fluorescent lights I said I talked
about that place on the show if
anybody's gone by and taking cool
pictures of that greenhouse I talked
about tweet me some pictures I'd love to
see it how often do you get to do a few
no huh bro not as often as I'd like to I
wish I could go from seed every single
time but I have some other plants I have
to maintain and you know best way to do
that is clone and run clones and you
know I keep - Lance yeah yeah the
patients this winter I'm planning on
growing pretty much exclusively seed so
other than just mother maintenance so
have you ever ran a whole pack of seeds
and not gotten anything worth keeping
yes me too
you yes you're running you've your shops
got a nice amount of seeds going right
now
yeah I bet you've got high hopes for
that if you don't find a couple of
keepers of each one it's gonna feel like
a lot of work for nothing
already it's looking like there's a
couple that are setting themselves apart
from the others so it's pretty promising
and how many how many days enter those
they
there is still sighs I think they're on
day 23 in [ __ ] building your pictures
they look great check them out guys he
looks great on Instagram he's got some
stylish glass and some stylish plants
then he takes the biggest herbs this
might be a friendly it's a personal
challenge than that I was talking it
might have been the last one I'm going
to put the gigantic thing to arrest for
myself because I'm getting old I think
what I actually said was that my lungs I
realized my lungs have so many inhales
and exhales and I think taking a grab
dab it's just like you're just using up
cat lives when you do that two breaths
you could have had but instead you
smoked a gram of hash especially that
many but I mean what better way to do it
than taking a hit hash at least you
weren't breathing in concrete dust or
something that might have been my fault
off the honey hole even shoutout
suspense for bringing the Heylin honey
hole all right
this conversation has gotten off-track
because I'm dab down what else do you
want to talk about about phenotypes you
guys okay I got a question
I like to order backseats considered
like CT find in
like mostly yes once over he would say
you don't know the parent yeah it's
probably just an [ __ ] what if you
know the parent but you don't know what
the male was plants from there sorry so
mom spilling your beans
that's how Sola actually makes feminized
seeds he takes a female and flowers her
for too long okay and then after she
goes like if you got a nine week strain
he lets it go for thirteen and about
week thirteen Oh
gathers it on the next crop that he
makes you can smoke those buds do most
of the plant just leave enough of it to
her mouth and spit out Paul Anthony
smoke the rest even if you can't smoke
it you could definitely probably extract
it there you go
yeah have you heard of his fire
technique make sense yes I understand
this theory where he's coming from what
the forest fire no I bet his math is
more organic than mine yeah that's
that's pretty hardcore don't want to
smoke the flowers of the plants that I
have reversed you don't want to smoke
those you can smoke is that I don't
trust smoking yeah
chem dog was backseat guys so don't ever
doubt backseat could be aggregation
performance it will because you don't
know what the parents were well a girl
you know the person who was managing the
room could have a good idea
that's about I mean I've seen people on
Instagram so packs of s ones for 100
bucks not yeah one of those forum sites
I suck ass ones go for like freaking
eight grand
I've seen some old seats go for
ridiculous money some og rascal stuff in
a forum for a really high price recently
his when I went to Cali I met up with
another person through Instagram and
stuff and I had a the fire there
original fire ojika for rascal and they
said it was 20 G's is how much you're
small that's an expensive clone yes
that's an expensive what are you lemon
cookies full belt
shoutout to JP wellness I heard a lot of
good things about that place
Oh Spencer ringer just canceled it's
cool
when they try to cut that out of there
sorry about the torch you guys if you're
wondering it's not for me to take a bath
- I'm gonna take a sip of something and
take a DAB anybody got anything snazzy
to say any breeding projects right now
Jesse I'm I'm really happy with px3 of
depo dog so I think I'm on like a whole
bunch of seed of it and maybe get it to
the public so it's old-school Amsterdam
I don't really have a whole lot of
heritage on it but it's a I don't know
the producer of it but it was a scone
case I believe it was a freebie from an
old amsterdam seat back but had really
really heard early resident production
and it was a young case so the initial
reason I used to din the cross was he
was very different than Kim D and it was
very easy to spawn out the phenotypes
over leaning garter towards him so I
kind of used it as a tool to make the
Kim line more pure so glad that Kim was
discovered yes yes that's my favorite I
stay restrained hands down like a
allocate you know I need I need a Kim
for back fat Kim D even can be for Jesse
we can trade we can trade if you're in
Colorado and you're an adult we can do
this yep maybe we can find some seeds or
something for you I've got a pretty cool
Girl Scout cookies cut so
I've got the chocolate that's like it's
like a chocolate chocolate and really is
the word it may be an antique two and a
half years yeah that was a good nose
because that gorilla glue what's the
other number there's four and what's the
other one
[Music]
we need cuts of that one so we can
compare them you guys find us yeah yeah
I've got a lot of great ship for trade
will be bring in a tan G to Southern
Colorado since cuz there's the strain
that everyone calls the tange that is
not tangi doesn't taste like any goddamn
tangerines or anything
zero oranges yeah why did you call that
the tant what are you doing
I think it's whoa goddamnit
[Music]
yeah I think it's bloke we're trying to
front what are you growing now bro
Platinum cookies animal cookies blue
haze cookies and cream cookies and cream
that one that come cookies and cream I
wanted that that was but starfighters
rare dinosaurs
talking about that and then I have a
female hunt going right now by the way
which sucks everybody if you have timers
that have more than one program make
sure you go through your programs and
make sure there's no extra timers
shailen so that's cool you can catch it
but I caught it
[Music]
no I saw but it was just weird because
there was no off timers just on but I've
been in my room it's not on those fancy
digital timers so when you reset your
timer guy just reset it the whole days
like yeah just did recent and clear it
out don't just try to go and read set
everything actually hit the button
default that [ __ ] but I think they'll
be fine I've had a couple that are just
growing right through it and it didn't
matter to it so kind of happy with those
likes are you running you doing that
drunk over an 11 13 talk to offers
that's actually a good way to stress
test your plants I was mentioning this
this is since our fee no topic kind of
got side rails here we ran out of [ __ ]
to talk about I think
I stress test my plants before I breed
with them I'll take a female and put her
in a room I'll take a bunch of them like
I've got four or five new clones I'll
put them in the room and I'll run it on
twelve twelve for two weeks
and then about day fifteen I'll turn it
off for 24 hours day fifteen I'll turn
it on for 24 hours and then I'll put it
back on the opposite 1212 so if I was
coming on at ten in the morning now I'm
coming on at 10:00 at night I'll run
that for a few more days just watch them
grow freaked out then I'll put it back
into the normal some same goes for males
but I don't want to give away too many
secrets so we'll just leave it at that I
like your dad yourself yeah meal stuff
is all that's all proprietary stuff that
you keep on the down-low well at least
you want people breeding with a bunch of
armed ass males females the top clusters
are too close together to look like they
got fur between it start to look like
like a [ __ ] willow or something a fox
tail sort of that [ __ ] just want those
big juicy balls and I will never say
that about what kind of traits we look
for in a meal no we won't
oh we totally yes well maybe eventually
like on absolute like 500 once
everyone's listen for a long time it
loves us what do you doing over there
Spence that looks dangerous this is
being a power all right status fire of
plastic he just puts it down like I
already know how this [ __ ] ends for 35
minutes you guys got anything you want
to talk about on a podcast anything
you've ever wanted to say
everyone just kind of shakes their head
and goes that's good because that's what
everybody came to this show for thing I
look for is I grow mostly indoors so I
like type plants that respond well to
topping and super cropping so I can get
a nice even canopy versus having a lot
of overgrowth I remember that's
phenotypic expressions that is a very
phenotypic expression so things like
purpling even some strains it's kind of
because if you have an unhealthy plant
but I had something really great to say
and then backed up from the microphone
back down or not okay the notes are done
but oh we sent all the stuff on my notes
you're looking over here like what can
we say yeah it's um you're thinking like
a press pause well you think daddy said
don't be afraid to kill off those plants
that are not performing yes and when I
do for you know types it's all Fino
hunts I usually do probably like a
couple seed packs now just one and it's
kind of survival of the fittest for me
because seeds I like to not really like
feed them too much I kind of like to
just let them see which ones are gonna
do their thing until I have to start you
know giving it food um so yeah like I
kill ones that if it's gonna get
overgrown as a seat it's probably gonna
get overgrown as a plant so I just get
rid of it right
getting rid of it just makes your hunt
smaller more now you can focus on other
things instead of now you have one less
plant yeah it's like picking players for
the team you don't want those slow
runners or the guy that can't shoot you
don't want me on your team we're talking
about sports on a weed podcast see you
there
I should be at the secret Cup I think
I'm going with low cabs so that should
be a good time when I think that
September since you're playing with that
carb cap we're gonna give a huge
shout-out to the man task rock these uh
blue carb caps these new color titanium
pieces are dope you don't even know
about this [ __ ] right here we recording
this one because I was out of town when
we should have recorded this so we're
pre recording but this stuff is new and
they look good bro the color is not
coming off it's looks just like the
other carb caps I like it good work
brother shout-out task rock and
highly-educated titanium that's the word
but I'm not certain be a little more
variation in it I believe if that was
the process and ice I mean I have no
doubt task is uh you know top quality
[ __ ] so he's got a very high quality
anodization process
[Music]
oh hey guys thanks for bearing with a
bunch of potheads I know we tried to
have a phenotype discussion it feels
like we covered a lot see if we can name
off any other famous
or even some of your own heart of gold
[Music]
growing out oh gee there's one that's
almost looks when they look in the fire
[Music]
he just released a whole bunch I think
they're pretty much the same thing
[Music]
jeez okay yeah lately I think oh geez
just a sticker or a reader for dollar
signs you know yeah the original ones
from according to the story there's a
bunch of different phenotypes of the
genotype
I don't know underdog that's a good
story think there's another podcast it's
called the show they did an episode all
about it's because they have their own
because there seems to be just pulled
that out of knowing it's easy to
remember pothead thinks
have you ever drawn any th seeds
actually oh yeah I grew sage and sour is
a freebie okay I didn't really like
that's just my opinion
I've heard that called old man's one
cops yeah yes sage I did like it I know
it's an acronym but it does have a
let's see gee I take you to mental
probably now I like cush and I said
never spoke like a true cam or a really
really good Sauer I smoked some showers
but not like there's a Sour Diesel cut
that goes around here have you smoked
any of that I think I grew it like her
and I smoked it it just still wasn't a
fan of it I don't know I might be
looking for a different salary no taste
but I've had I work where I work out we
have one still have your smoke it it's
it's pretty good it's pretty first our
diesel diesel yeah when it's done well
this stuff is you know actually the my
friend Josh from a lot of labs rolled a
joint of that [ __ ] one night at a party
and there were a bunch of breeders in
the room and they all gathered around
that joint
yeah so for a bunch of breeders to tear
your joint that was not mine was hoping
to hear that Fino was more of a thing
actually it was Durango is where they're
from so I haven't been back in 13 years
regrettably every summer I plan a trip
over there and never happens but I'm
totally gonna cruise to their shop when
I do get over there it's hard to do it
being an outdoor farmer yeah yeah yeah
Jesse brought me some eggs and I cracked
open one of those eggs and it almost
freaked me out because the is it not
crazy do it old man
it was like just two times
[Music]
refirming to be eating it and he brought
me Tomatoes and honestly after eating
Jesse's Tomatoes I can't even go buy a
tomato anywhere they came with fresh
tomatoes and I bit into the tomatoes and
they taste like soggy mold there's a
deli downtown culture slips as my
produce their shout out to them both on
mass food they're on Main Street and
then I eat lunch at Bingo burger today
and someone is supplying the awesome
bomb ass [ __ ] produce - nice yeah
that's a free commercial for bingo
burger from a bunch of by its that's
pretty tasty you know I've said that I
won't eat fish anymore recently but I
[Music]
need to go if it's a fillet on the menu
today but I already decided what I was
gonna get tomato lettuce
[Music]
it'd be hard to in the winter it'd be
hard for me to have a vegetarian
restaurant because I'd just be so
disappointed by the produce I think
that's probably one of the downsides of
the cannabis industry now if you want to
build a greenhouse there's yeah that's
my retirement plan is but not for full
of cannabis and yeah flowers vegetables
yeah lettuce I feel like the music yeah
a long time I totally had some I was
gonna say we should talk about and just
forgot Oh have you guys ever grown any
produce and such actually I've done real
basic stuff lettuce basil tried it
tomato plant one time and there was
taking up room
[Music]
some great outdoors but never inside
yeah it's growing an outdoor vegetable
crop for yourself is awesome when you're
eating a meal and you're like I grew I
would be self-reliant we've almost gone
for an hour I bet if I put commercials
on this thing an intro and an outro and
a big shout out to task rock I bet I
could make this a nice even hour
you guys got anything fancy to say I
know I've asked him once but we've
rambled on for a few minutes since then
I want to give a shout out to chick on
Instagram I think it's 17 nurse or
something like that oh and she replied
to my dish shout out for the show nurse
710 I know who you are yeah she's a
loyal listener actually know that person
in person and we give her a lot of grow
advice
she shouted out on the show that's cool
what's up chick let me know that uh
she's listening she's listening she yeah
she's got some outdoor stuff going on
that looks pretty damn good yeah I might
give her advice on that once in a while
any shoutouts over there dude you're all
looking into your phone no Spence
shoutouts plugs let's see
shout out to my lady she just turned 21
happy birthday
[Music]
we all love you and then shout-out IRA
genetics Jeff Jesse Michael yeah anybody
that's you know everybody on the show
that's not here or anybody show yeah
thank you for supporting the show for
sure he gave me a shout-out and I got
like four new followers even if I met
you once or twice in your garden of
Weeden true you are still there are just
everybody get out in the community and
start enjoying you know what's going on
like other states you can't do it what
we didn't you know we've got places
where we can just go mingle and eat and
hang out drunk we're taking - you're
smoking joints you know so if you live
here go enjoy if you you know if you're
up to it if not you know whatever but if
you're in the community go enjoy come on
you don't have to be a certain type of
person come taste some amazing herb come
see what your herb can be grown like
commute a grower commute a breeder yeah
don't mess it up for everyone else you
gotta learn how to you know behave
yourself we're too high for crazy stuff
so just kick it yeah don't try to come
take a gigantic dab and fall over and
[ __ ] alcohol in these events don't
really seem to the cottonmouth most of
the time but it's usually a fruity drink
if you see it first this episode won't
go out until the start of next month so
I'll be kind of busy for a couple of
times here so we're pre recording but we
usually post it up on Facebook or
[Music]
Twitter on the show after I post a lot
of pictures I change pictures I grow is
high gross supply is about to launch a
nationwide website
with this shipping department and all
that stuff and we'll have our actually I
think the prices are gonna be a little
bit lower than they are in the store but
nationwide shipping and everyone can get
great deals like we get here and I
believe there'll be a in-store pickup
program - yeah that'll be helpful and
the tote of soil deal is now over you
guys oh yeah the tote bag came in I
really want one of those huge one knows
great for sweet all right guys we got
three minutes before it's an hour we're
gonna wrap up the show hey guys thanks
for listening everybody out there in
podcast world we've been getting over a
thousand listens a thousand people are
gonna hear all your guys's crazy voices
everybody's faces just changed word
Michael had no idea what he was getting
into when he came here I just wish I
knew how crazy I look but you don't well
we'll take some pictures we'll post them
up how crazy you are sometimes he wears
a grille he doesn't have the grill in
today but he wears the grille white
people get nervous I think it's really
funny it is a wedding
maxed it out weddings grill story normal
people that were more not normal or
Matty and myself and slop Big Mike we're
walking through the crowd and they kind
of looked and they weren't sure if we
were their family
[Music]
shout out to bullheaded and despicable
dialects Anton and boogie for just for
that 30 seconds of the show all right
guys I want to thank you for listening
in to a long episode I want to thank
Jessie and Spence for coming back and I
want to thank Michael for coming and
doing his very first podcast make sure
you follow Jesse grows on Instagram
follow Colorado bearded dabbers on
instagram follow garden of Weeden on
instagram and also follow IRA genetics
on Instagram I'm gonna work on that
harvesting and drying and curing episode
for you and we'll get that up pretty
soon so now that the show is over please
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for the agriculture podcast find
the review section give us a 5 star
rating and after that type in a comment
and let me know what you think of the
show and I will read your comments on a
future episode also do the same thing
for stitcher if you can find the comment
spot on stitcher leave a comment there
and I'll read that on the show don't
forget that the podcast is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is available on I read genetics Colorado
com
big shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening you guys take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's going on podcast world
welcome to episode number 29 of
agriculture podcast I'm your host and
they call me Rasta Jeff thank you for
joining me for another episode and this
episode Clinton Adam come by will talk a
little bit about cannabis and a whole
lot about comedy so I hope you like that
before we get there I'm proud to
announce that this podcast is brought to
you by a highly educated titanium if
you're using high quality concentrates
you deserve a high quality titanium male
made in America don't trust a Chinese
nail or an American knockoff made of
cheap metals trust the industry leader
trust highly educated titanium highly
educated products are available at
Aqualab technologies calm highly
educated has an able to fit any rig and
they are the only titanium product
endorsed by this podcast this podcast is
also brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gabe's green genetics
apply to lives since city sprayer
dankness mile high can adventure I read
genetics and many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon codes September 14 for 15% off
any order you always get free shipping
at nature's green remedies dot-com
podcast is also brought to you by our
good friends at hydro indoor growing
supplies hydro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street unit F or stop by the Pueblo
location 618 East 4th Street in Pueblo
Colorado check out hydro for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
growth supplies the show was also
brought to you by our good friends at
tree hugger com tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concerts festivals news
and reviews www.rediff.com much respect
and love to all of our sponsors they do
make the show possible I don't want to
spend too much time on a long intro so
here's the part where Clint and Adam
join me hang out
alright guys we're here we're hanging
out with Clinton Adam I think everybody
knows Adam he's been here a few times
Clint has been here a couple of times he
was a nonsmoker the first few times he
was on the show but now Clint has
converted to the dark side Clinton is
now a pot smoker so congratulations
welcome to the team hey thanks for you
guys do not know Clint he is a comedian
or an aspiring comedian he's just a
silly open mic er that's right he's
actually been hosting the open mic at a
local bar called Phil's radiator when is
that and how has it been going bro every
Tuesday Tuesday every Tuesday about 9:00
p.m. and come out it's you know it's
just a place to try out new jokes you
know it's I think it's great we've been
getting mixed reviews as to who's coming
down and stuff but I think it's starting
to blow up it always takes a little bit
to get stuff going in this town where is
Phil Phil's Pueblo Colorado C Street and
Union right you'll find it go downtown
it's the spot with the nice outdoor
patio you guys do comedy inside or
outside right now inside it's just they
got a stage and stuff oh nice what time
do we need to get there to sign up if we
want to be on the stage if you want to
come be a comedian try to get down there
by 9:00 and even then well I'm not gonna
hold you against the coals if you're a
little late we'll get you on it's a good
time have you performed it feels yeah no
I'm not performing to Phil's uh not yet
I went down there last week and just saw
the show and it's it's a cool place man
cool um good beer and Adams dreams of
doing some stand-up comedy he's done a
couple of shows unfortunately I didn't
make it but I've heard he's uh it's
alright he's shocking is what I was told
[Music]
yeah for sure it starts with the same
letters though so they may be in may
have been being nice to you buddy hey
I've heard what your act is we're not
gonna go into it here if you said that
on a show that is shocking
bro that's big balls if you guys want to
hear some guy with big balls talk about
funny [ __ ] go see him the next time he
gets his big balls ready to perform
somewhere oh boy you gotta go do it yeah
so I gotta go do Pils radiator fills
days 9 p.m. get all like monster truck
and another hot friend Monday night
I'm so pumped yes it'll be the night did
you guys are listening to this show
probably we are gonna go smoke cannabis
with Doug Benson yes we're going to be
doing actually getting high with Doug
yes listen to this on Monday this will
come out Monday the 15th
Doug Benson is at Comedy Works in Denver
tonight
the last I checked it was not sold out
Doug Benson is well worth your drive to
Denver go check it out I will be there
then will be a smoke session somewhere
and it'll be your chance to smoke with
Rasta Jeff it'll be a good time if you
show up and Doug Benson who is [ __ ]
hilarious hilarious my favorite weed
comedian probably the most popular weed
comedian oh definitely yeah I mean you
listen to one of his podcast almost
every week and then I watch the the
other one just about every week two
different tastes but we still work right
there yeah Doug loves movies is one of
my favorite podcast I know Doug loves
movies I guess go listen to that one
when the show's over you'll love movies
and pop comedy and then if you only have
a few minutes for a podcast Doug loves
minis is great to perfect a short little
show I listen to when I take a shower it
does about 15 minute episodes that's
long enough to throw hit play jump to
the shower to clean your ass get out and
dry off and get dressed you got about 15
minutes for a guy perfect so all right
so Doug we've promoted you quite a bit
man there is nothing like a good show at
a good comedy club has it freaking
correct you would know we bragged on the
show about seeing Joe Rogan Clint with
the night before us and sat front
freakin Road really I don't know how
that happened they let your hairy ass up
there of course they wouldn't let my
ugly ass up there when they were filming
they would put decent-looking people up
front
a sexy young lady and a guy showed up
and they had no problem telling those
people sorry you have to move and they
would reseach you and then this girl in
like a tangerine or melon colored shirt
with giant boobs and a lot of makeup and
you could tell she was they go out front
row and they just walked her right up to
the front row and put her in the front
bed no problem making people moved and
rainy and matt chapman over at the show
and they kind of got put up towards the
front but then they slowly move them
back to the government five times Jesus
I said they sat me down we got two in
line kind of early like maybe 30 minutes
before the doors were supposed to open
so we were in line pretty early and
that's they just led us in and then the
group ahead of us was like of six dudes
and there's only seven front row seats
so like they had already had most of
that so they're like alright you guys go
to the back and I don't know if it's
like an ideology of like they're gonna
want to talk more cuz there's six of
them yeah you know I'm gonna be talking
louder there's only two me and my buddy
Riley we go up and we thought Oh second
row that'll be cool and the guy goes hey
there's two more front you guys what
front I go yeah get that joke he did a
Grateful Dead joke and I felt as if you
were staring me directly in my eyes
telling his Grateful Dead joke and I
didn't say that to anybody but on the
ride home the girl I took with me said
he looked you straight in the face when
he said the Grateful Dead joke he was
talking about duck dynasty beards we got
to go to that show I didn't want to be
in the taping honestly I would rather
not next time yeah who's stressful you
couldn't go take a piss and I didn't
have to piss but just telling me that I
can't go take a piss now I have to piss
yeah
you're just I can't well suddenly I need
to pee yeah now I'm gonna be sitting
here I had to pee he was like I'm not
leaving no food or drink service during
the entire show they came and took our
beverage everything everything you know
the a comedy works they have a menu
hanging from the chair inferni you took
that they took the pen they made
everybody take off their hats like the
camera was right above my head that's
why that's why I feel like a couple of
the jokes Joe was looking me in his eyes
telling them to me because right there
yeah the camera was above my head and it
made it feel and talked to that machine
he could just talk to me and it felt a
little more natural cuz I was high and
laughing my it was a good time is a fun
place and it was fun having I had a lady
friend with me and a head at him with me
it was fun because the dude walked up
and recognized me he's like hey man are
you that guy I am Rasta Jeff from Ira
genetics and we talked about seeds and
stuff you know I don't think so okay
their brother Phil was his name so
what's up Phil if you haven't contacted
me yet hit me up on Facebook send me a
direct message I'm taking fires with me
to Denver Monday I don't care what you
say okay you've only got a couple few
left imprinted all right we need to give
Tony Hinchcliffe a big shout-out I don't
know if we do on the podcast about the
Joe Rogan show but Clint got to go too
so I'm reading yeah Tony Hinchcliffe
nailed it dude that is one hell of a
comedian it was really but you could
still see yes he's been doing comedy for
a while oh yeah but you could see
another step when you watched Joe Rogan
not to say that Tony inch cliff wasn't
great because that's that's what I like
seeing I like seeing guys that are
better than me cuz I can go oh I'm not
the big fish in the little pond
I'm a little fish in a little pond quit
being a like get better but that's what
I get to see like when we bring guys
down and they've been doing it for like
five years eight years ten years you get
to see like oh that's where I want to be
right but seeing Tony I don't know how
long he's been telling jokes I know he's
30 he said yeah you listen to the Joe
Rogan experience
well yeah that but he also said it when
he was talking about being did he do as
a knit cap bit yeah because he was like
I'm a thirty year old man and I listen
to him on Tony Rogan but it was no but
Tony edgecliff was on par yeah defconn
he's got some really good jokes but and
I mean not only that but you say Joe
Rogan killed it I mean as a comic to be
up there for an hour
Jesus yeah you know and I mean him
talked about it afterwards you know he
was really nervous like nervous he's
like what [ __ ] and he kind of went off
on her for a minute and when he came
back to the set he was on point from
then on I think that heckler kind of
helped him out kinda helped him and it
brought the crowd and him together
before before that there was a barrier
between the performer and the crowd was
called cameras yeah yeah that tension in
there affected our laughter and his
performance but once that heckler all of
that we became one yeah yes I do Tony
Hinchcliffe and you guys can laugh your
asses off if you want
is Tony Hinchcliffe slightly remind you
of Ania Lujan really mellow calmness you
can't shake him nerves of steel just
kind of feels like you know he's kind of
always up here slightly a hipster I
don't I don't know what I I looked at
him and I I didn't think that he felt
like like he was having fun he just
liked his sense of humor is so like yeah
that's kind of like this and so it just
it wasn't I wish he'd have been having
more fun while he was telling his jokes
they did invite him back for a weekend
so we got to pay attention to when Tony
Hinchcliffe is concerned
yeah I'd love to see I'd love to see
more than he probably did 20 do about 15
when we saw ya oh let's talk a comedy I
guess I'm gonna keep going
Sunday night I went to the oddball
comedy fest the oddball comedy tour with
Hardwick that was amazing
was he like headlining it was he was
actually second louis c.k headlined
there were nine comedians I think there
were Brody Stephens was the host and he
said nine comedians and he must have
been one of the performers that he
counted because I can't think of who
they are the others were it was Brody
Stephens Whitney Cummings
Chris Hardwick Demetri Martin Hannibal
Buress Sarah Silverman I'm gonna forget
somebody because I'm on the spot Marc
Maron already somebody and then louis
c.k who was before Joan Rivers it might
have been Joan that set was quite stale
I'm gonna google it because I feel bad
missing somebody on that list I'm
looking for I really want to get it
right so I feel bad it was just I mean
Red Rocks seems like I've been down
there yeah but it definitely I saw the
picture disease was great I think
everybody got 15 minutes but I think
Louie may have gotten it seemed like
Louie did 30 minutes and if you're a
comedy fan we've gone on for a minute
but you'll get this part every single
second of Louis cent was calculated he
knew where to were to breathe he knew
where to take a couple of steps I don't
see and I'm not a comedian but I paid
enough attention to you guys I'm friends
with all you comedian guys and I've paid
enough attention to what you say and so
I get it now and I could feel every
minute of him he crushed it always be
crushing was Louie's motto that's
[ __ ] awesome he was killing it dude
on it I need to see him now
yeah that just just to see his
mannerisms but you've performed you know
it's also performance you understand
like when the singer does it in this
note it sounds a lot better than the
right no that's like one octave fret
higher or the drummer my thing is to
play less if overplay as a drummer than
you sound like you're insecure when you
learn to get older and play less notes
it's when you sound better and I think
Louie has learned each note perfectly
Louie and honestly not to sound like an
[ __ ] he was one of the comedians I
was not most excited to see yeah
haven't you seen him before no I've
never seen though he can't perform
before I've never seen any of those guys
perform live before it was so I got to
see Nev the world's best ah
Aziz was good really high energy stuck
to the same joke basically the whole
time still told like a story with a lot
of tag lines and a lot of callbacks so
that was cool Hardwick I was being this
affects my podcast hosting I listen to
Nerdist afton i watch @midnight
I followed Hardwick since the frickin
singled-out days so I know he's from
Denver I know how he used to play in a
band with Furman called by a hardened
firm he comes out of Red Rocks and he
puts his hands up in the air in there
and he's like Red Rocks and I could see
the 15 year-old boy in him that's wanted
to do that since the first time he
touched a guitar I was like that was his
dream just he's he just combed his pants
I could see it that's [ __ ] awesome
yeah and I kind of got to share that
with my friend Chris Hardwick through
podcasting and that relationship that
that stalker relationship that you feel
like you have with oh I did feel like
that with Joe Rogan like I felt like
this is my buddy performin yeah and and
I've known him and then I wanted like as
he was walking off the stage I wanted to
shake his hand and stuff I was just like
also like he's not a guy you know yeah
and that's a weird thing to like have
this relationship with people that like
is a one-sided relationship yeah but I
could see that like I would probably do
the same thing with Hardwick just be
like I felt pride for him go to my
buddies just crushed it at Red Rocks cuz
he was awesome he did a great great set
his set was he's kind of a pervert dude
he did he did a joke and I don't want to
blow his bit but half of his bit was
about [ __ ] your mom that's funny yeah
yeah and for Hardwick to go that route
it was funny for me that's pretty great
Demetri Martin did his thing Demetri
Martin yeah he surprised me how funny he
was my date that I took with me she
loved him that's who she went to see so
that was good we got to chuckle at that
DJ Drama is a killer DJ by the way he's
the one that ran music between the
comedians and then we took a 15-minute
intermission there's about a 30 minute
intermission I believe if you do comedy
for too long he burnout you're funny oh
yeah we stood up and danced for a few
Hannibal Buress was great he did his
thing he made a joke about Colorado
having the ugliest crowd it looks like
you all came from a hike probably all
just did and he made a joke about who
was the white guy that broke down out
here and decided let's build a venue
[Music]
like I said Marc Maron was good his
closer was solid but you could tell he
was frazzled and didn't know what to do
with 15 minutes
Marin's used 2:45 to whittle Maron down
to 15 minutes is kind of like you gotta
give him time to get out on the stage
and sit down at the edge of the stage
and get pissed off about something yeah
and then he gets into that Marc Maron
thing 15 I didn't feel he was good his
closer was hilarious like I won't blow
anybody's been on purpose but his closer
was great Sarah Silverman surprised the
[ __ ] out of me her set was great but she
is funny like she is naturally funny you
could just tell Whitney Cummings [ __ ]
yells her set at you and it's what it
feels like the whole time it feels like
you're being barred with jokes she was
funny but it was a bit [ __ ] too much
for me just saying the way she delivered
him yeah it could have been better she
forgot she had a microphone and she had
to yell she was she was roman-style TV
shows like when she's on TV she doesn't
feel like she's speaking she feels like
she's over projecting to me too much and
then Brody Stephens needs medication
Bernie Stevens was the host Brody take
your medicine buddy I love you I respect
you too deep calm down Brody Stephens
[ __ ] harness that [ __ ]
like I don't know man maybe you smoke
too much of that good Colorado a week
but if that show you were [ __ ] losing
your [ __ ] [ __ ] I'm not a huge fan of
Brody Stevens yeah it's just not my
thing but personal preference there well
it's just like anything like I'm I'm so
glad that there's some people that don't
like my comedy because if everybody
liked it it'd be like wow that was that
was that's not right everybody's as
[ __ ] up as me that doesn't make any
sense nobody wants another Dane Cook
[Music]
wants to that's gonna be funny it's
gonna be hilarious I make sure that
nobody's coming to my shows like like
they don't know when I do stuff podcast
about consuming cannabis growing
cannabis cannabis education we should
probably talk a little bit about
cannabis especially but I think our
listeners enjoy getting a little inside
of our heads in a little bit of our
world and knowing what's up with us I
like like I said that Chris Hardwick
talk they're my friends now they know
what I'm doing there 29:30 episodes into
being my buddy we've spent 30 hours
together now absolutely Bros yeah I
guess what do you call it but we're not
if you're a lady out there you're my bro
I don't know what else to call your
family
you're awesome thanks for listening to
the show just as much as all the dudes I
have a female friend who is encouraging
me to do an all episode episode all
about women in cannabis oh I don't know
what to do I am told her to research it
for me and help me out if you guys have
any ideas for women in cannabis it feels
sexist a guy doing a show all about
women in cannabis so anything I come up
with I feel like it'll be gender bias
and will be weird so ladies send me some
stuff so that I can do a ladies podcast
oh I want to satisfy the listeners and
if you're asking for it that's what we
gots to do
I'm ranting against women in cannabis
yeah that's just the trimmers right oh
man so Clint is a comedian we should
remind you and I'm actually gonna give a
shout-out to miss green thumb Jessica
you're a badass grower I'll stand up for
you one of my favorite female growers as
they do not know any kind of people from
Denver then maybe you could travel down
and you know yeah definitely but we're
gonna do like an hour and it's easier
for ya but I'll talk to Jason get some
info from her because she's a badass
badass female grower myself looking for
that credit she grew some calling that
was amazing follow at miss green thumb
on Instagram I'll find out the proper
the exact Instagram address and I'll
tweet that [ __ ] out so you guys can
follow her she's a great girl
so click came I had plenty here Clint is
uh he used to be a nonsmoker now he is a
new smoker he took two puffs off of a
bowl earlier we obviously did not come
from here I brought it in myself I felt
I get plenty high off two good puffs of
some some shoe a glow weed it wasn't
really swag girls but it was not he's on
the team now so you know he's joining us
and now he's got some questions I do one
of his main guy wrote down the questions
because we got blazed um I remember
anything yes what questions Clint had
was storage I do cuz I don't know you
know I I my little bag of weed is my
plastic [ __ ] up my weed
well I hate this your weed that you got
now but that's fine to keep in a
sandwich baggy but when you upgrade and
he gets a quality weed from somebody
that's a good caregiver that likes you
and doesn't want to see you smoking that
[ __ ] anymore
keep your little to go portion in a
baggie maybe but keep the rest of it in
a jar I store usually you know most
people have like a corner doing out to
weed maybe an eighth we get I keep it in
a glass jar a glass jar size can depend
on the size of your stash I use baby if
I was just gonna say Adam uses a baby
food jar D 98 cents because if you go to
Walmart trying to buy a jar for number
one we live in Colorado and there's no
jars six dollars for a jar that's the
same size in the same price you know
yeah and you get baby food YUM
you know I like peas and carrots peas
and carrots
all right so butchered weed in a jar
hopefully when you get it it's not too
dry it's not too wet hopefully it's at
the right point if what I dry and cure
my own weed guys you keep asking for a
drying and curing episode that's coming
Jesse and I are putting that together
we're putting a lot of thought and work
into it that should be episode thirty as
the drying and curing episode to be
patient that's coming you got about a
week till that's out yeah oh god yeah
wait your turn I'm just kidding thanks
for listening and being patient if you
are listening to this next week I got a
big show coming up September 22nd at
Phil's radiator we're bringing Ron
Babcock through and he's a professional
comedian who's been on TV before like
he's been on HBO he's been on Comedy
Central he do we jokes he's gonna Phil's
Radiator Monday it's only $5 like its
22nd it's a good he's and he's gonna do
as long as he wants to do I'm gonna do
maybe 10 minutes Paul's gonna do 10
minutes Paul Rosales is really funny Oh
Garrett Waller is gonna be on that
what's up [ __ ] huge huge jokes yeah he
might do a fat guy joke he might he
might not
we'll then john-boy knows on that as
well john-boy no I hope he wears a fancy
sweater he's a [ __ ] killer
I just derailed to plug without asking
at school I've caught you doing it and I
like I like the natural flow of this
show we are because I took notes
[Music]
something called the something called
the the cuss jar here pretty soon every
time I say after starting on episode 30
every time I say the word [ __ ] I will
donate $1 to a charity I had a
conversation with a guy on Instagram
today and he asked me to donate to a
charity and I will find out the charity
that he was asking about and I'll donate
$1 starting on episode 30 every time I
say [ __ ] a podcast how about on each
episode however many times you say [ __ ]
you have to donate to a different
charity that way you're spreading it
around maybe well hopefully I'll say
[ __ ] more than like six or seven times
my feelings because after i spare I'm
gonna throw it on the dollars on the
table and watch them happen so hopefully
this guy something that I post around if
I say [ __ ] on episode 30 so anytime
after this episode the f-word cost me a
dollar I'll start doing what to keep
screwing up I will increase my value for
that work gonna keep track so you have
to tell that's fine just we're not gonna
keep track so dreadful Jay has been
tweeting me somebody else has tweeted me
so if they remind me of you saying
five minutes from the South and you know
[Music]
there be none
you know after you drive to both
Walmart's on either side of town and
you're like do I really want to go out
the west no I just 98
you know you scoop it out you clean it
out let it dry and then yeah it's it's
good in there and that's that's perfect
for an eight you know especially like a
fluffy eight yes you gotta wait until
you got to make sure your weeds dry
enough to go into a jar at sea that's
what this podcast thing when my weed
what I'm hearing and drying my weed I'll
leave it a little bit extra moist for my
personal so that I almost have to open
yes I do smoke flower still people don't
believe that I still smoke weed I do
it's not always dabs but I'll leave my
weed a little moist where I gotta open
the jar take the buds out and set them
down for 10 or 20 minutes before I can
actually roll a joint with it that's
just my personal if it's a production
crop for my patients I'm a caregiver and
the herb that's gonna get delivered to a
guy later on tonight
that stuff's dry it's been cured and
it's dry it's ready to go into his jar
he'll keep he's getting half so it's
probably gonna go in a mason jar
it'll be sealed up and he'll just he'll
probably pull out a little baby food jar
worth for himself every couple of days
when he needs it he hides the mason jar
away from the family and has that in a
safe place and keeps his charges pocket
and that will also if your weed is
really dry that may bring back some of
the moisture in the crispest a good
topic if your weeds really dry I see a
lot of people trying to put fruit and
[ __ ] in there don't do that you're gonna
bring pathogens and molds it doesn't
take a lot of moisture to start molding
up a jar if you leave it in there long
this company does not pay me [ __ ] but I
do highly recommend Oh Bovada or a
Boveda human a pack it's a great product
off your weeds a little bit too dry or a
little too moist even you put the proper
Bova too humid a pack in with your herbs
and it will properly moisten your herb
to the moisture content that is desired
[Music]
numbers I'll go to the Bolero website
right now it's the humidity the perfect
around 67 or 76 it's somewhere in
between there yeah well exactly there
are humidors for marijuana specifically
the name because I want to give them a
plug either but they're shiny metal
they're cans they got a blocking seal to
them so it's and they come in all shapes
and sizes that's if you're you know the
high roller you're the pro I see people
use them to transport cannabis for the
campus cups and stuff like that you know
they'll basically have four or five of
the big pound storage ones and there's
three of them in a backpack and they're
loading getting on an airplane whoo
you know and it's completely you know no
one ever knows because it's completely
sealed yeah you know still scary mark
that has your package or humidifier
package that he's talking about that
keeps it all at the same same humidity
and it doesn't really tell you what it
keeps it at it says that it keeps it
within a certain range of ambient
humidity so yeah they have so many
products on it you know they had so much
stuff so you guys go check out the bow
video website Boveda
shout out to coral reefer she's actually
the one that introduced me to the bow
vut of products uh-huh you big fan of
the coral reef over there buddy longer
than if you've got some herb that is
dried and cured and you know it's not
moist enough somebody hates the word
moist a lot of people hate the word
moist you hate the word you know so it's
not too damp and you're not afraid to
get mold in it you can put your herb in
a vacuum sealer bag and
Keem steal that [ __ ] vacuum sealers
aren't too expensive the bags are too
expensive seal it up label it market
some people DJ short says to put it in
the freezer at this point my dad always
did my dough in a brown paper bag and
then stick it put it in a bag put it in
a brown paper bag and stick it in the
freezer because that way none of the
light would get in threat yeah I was
gonna say that also keep your jars and
stuff in a dark place when you're not
smoking them if you have the opportunity
or if you can get an opaque jar to cut
white out a large you're good if you got
you got an ounce recorder pound keep
that out of out of the white really good
about that question now that took a lot
longer than I was thinking it would in
jars if you keep stuff in jars for
longer than I do obviously so would you
go in there once a month and kind of
dump it out now once it so once I feel
like we're gonna do a whole episode
about drying and curing once that
process is ended
once drying and curing is done you can
put it in your jar just leave it it's
almost better to leave it because every
time you open it you're introducing
oxygen and you're changing the gases
that are in the plants the plants are
actually releasing ammonia's and
chlorophylls I haven't studied for this
part so I'm gonna say wrong [ __ ] and a
lot of people are gonna correct me but
suppressing gases inside of there and
you're exchanging those gases if you've
quit introducing more gases the
decarboxylation and the changes will
stop happening starches will quit
becoming sugars everything will stay
right where it is all right it's like
opening opening a food product you just
get stale eventually cuz change same
thing will pretty much happen with your
weed yeah I've talked about this on the
show before I like mine a little bit
drier because I put mine through a
grinder and still get the kief off of
those but under the you know my my
grinder so I like it when I bring it
home I'll sit it in the jar and just
leave the the lid half on half off for
12 hours and then put the jar you know
the lid back on it's still moist inside
the butt a little bit but it's that
outer stuff is flakier and i could you
know get a little more a little more
sticky you get a little more flavor out
of it but it's a little stickier you
don't let it dry out so much its burns a
little bit better there you go I grow
culture you got a question answered
Clint came over and asked a great
freaking question after you
that was nice yeah he also asks since
he's a new smoker he asked so I hope you
wrap that up how to story we'd put it in
a jar baggies are cool but the baggie
has static electricity and it's stealing
all your [ __ ] and all your [ __ ] sticking
to it so keep in a jar enough jug of
some sort all right if you have to be
sneaky they smell skunk proof bags that
are smell proof they also at Highgrove
Pueblo they offer a duffel bag style bag
and a backpack that they claim is smell
proof I have not tested it am i putting
any products in it but they claim such
and they're they're decently priced so
if they work that's worth it
there's also stash cans and things like
that yeah of course you've seen them to
keep it secret I can you know yeah keep
it well you already got it like a little
case yeah so his next question was a
normal new guy question how am I gonna
pass my pee test working sucks right
everybody yes guys you with me ladies
working sucks
you guys want to tweet all that Clinton
not at all clip ladies I meant I know I
get you I just work anyway work sucks
but I like my job unfortunately my job
does not like people that smoke
marijuana and it sucks because I like my
job and if I could quit I would but it's
just life's expensive I got I got three
women asking me for money all the time
somebody to come crash your podcast to
buy the comedian
[Music]
more fun on the show it's always been
real tight reading news today on the
news there was weed stuff are you
worried about them popping random drug
test me are you worried about getting
hurt and them wanting you to pee in a
cup for workers in the comp those are
the two times that I can get us they I
mean like randoms I don't know what's
this you know time and time again
randoms it's just the dice that you're
rolling yeah I've got a solution this is
the IRA genetics only surefire way that
I think I know how to get past a drug
test that has worked for me multiple
times when I was a heavy smoker
I actually went sixty-three days without
smoking cannabis at one point and took a
pee test I was trying to get a badass
job I was promised a job sixty-three
days if could not pass I was still hot I
was drinking cranberry juice killing the
water test my family was mad at me like
you [ __ ] it up even smoking pot and I
was like honestly I went to ranking on
the rocks and didn't smoke weed like I
quit from the fourth of July puffed down
and then for 90 days after that or 63
days after that I didn't smoke and still
could not get this job that I wanted I
told that my was like I haven't smoked
in 65 sixty-three days and they're like
sorry you still didn't I was like can
you give me 30 more days and they were
already hiring for the position so it's
gone [ __ ] but so the next thing we need
to take a pee test I could not risk it
might be even going in the cup honestly
so your best bet is to use fake piss
because they are not checking for fake
piss or piss they're looking for THC
crystal meth opiate ecstasy whatever in
our case hopefully guys if you're
listening to my show hopefully the only
thing they're gonna find in your pee is
some [ __ ] medicine some cannabis but
that's not my spot to judge ah so they
sell a product that is straight-up fake
piss it is designed to be fake piss it's
usually it's some kind of a head shop
around here there's a couple spots you
can go you guys don't know where they
are if you live around here yeah yeah
there's two spots unendorsed either one
of them they gonna work out of
sponsorship if they want me to say their
names yes
[Music]
you get this fake P and it's got a
thermometer on the side of the container
the bottle has a thermometer on it it
should come with a it's a glove warmer
for the winter you crack the thing open
if you put your glove put it in your
gloves and it warms your hands in the
winter it comes with one of those if it
doesn't you got to go buy one so what I
do this is how I surefire passed more
than one drug test I get this product
and I microwaved it for seven seconds in
my microwave and that made it a little
too hot so I took a sock and I cut the
sock off and I stapled it to the inside
of my boxers to where it looked like it
was my dick swinging I put that warmed
up bottle of microwaved fake piss in the
sock I could tell that it was gonna be
warm enough I went too long in the
microwave the thing got down you needed
between 96 and a hundred degrees where
you needed to get that your body is so I
let it cool down you guys let me
intervene here I just used the heater in
the car in a plastic bag in my boxer
line you know in it's not probation it's
not jail no one should be watching you
piss taking you to a lab and you should
be going into a closed area where you
can pull out your dick and go right but
they wash your hands and check your
pockets so I got this swing in the
swinging sock with a fake pee in it
that's been microwaved that I've let it
cool now I've driven around long enough
to let it get to the right temperature
you got so much time to get there
hopefully if you're you're a union
worker I would yeah you get a couple
minutes to go drive by the house or
7-eleven even I got a piss and run into
7-eleven and use their microwave or a
crack have that so you're gonna if
you're working a job or you might get
pee test do you need this [ __ ] in your
locker or in your truck or some more
clothes if you carry this fake piss in
your cigarette pack you're a [ __ ]
genius it's a small bottle you don't
need a lot it's a little tiny bottle so
you got fake pee keep it in your shirt
pocket do something so you can hit with
this pee test you go you're driving
maybe they take another car to drive you
at the gas station say I got a pee man
or can we stop and get a pack of
cigarettes go there hit that microwave
for seven seconds whatever you got to do
to warm that piss up to the proper
temperature if you got that glove
cracker use that wrap it around it put a
rubber band around it put
tween your legs and squeeze they feel
your legs getting too warm and she's
probably right at the right temperature
yeah so you got that little bottle it's
tucked inside of a sock strapped inside
your boxers girls you're gonna have to
modify I don't know what you're gonna do
you got a dick if you follow my method
maybe it'll help you out don't worry
squirt pull out this little bottle and
just stick it out of the pee hole you're
flying stick your hand in there and
stick your thumb out so it's like a dick
because if they're standing behind you
or something you're gonna have to be
smooth stick your thumb out make that
look like your dog fart always for
during a pee test if someone's watching
that's just mandatory I squeeze the
bottle the first time I did it into the
little sample Cup tip it up so that you
don't make a bong sound when you're
[ __ ] doing that or for it right at
that point I screw the cap on to take
you back in your underwear
okay don't wash your hands leave the cup
there like you're supposed to and hope
that you just put enough at the right
temperature fake piss in there so that
fake piss worked for me more than once
fake piss don't trust my friend I will
say his name his girlfriend pee in the
cup and that's how they found out that
my buddy was pregnant he's got kids I
don't even want to ask any questions so
we're not trying to mask it we're trying
to replace it there's plenty of things
you can drink eat or whatever to take
and all they've done is upset my stomach
and give me diarrhea and by the time you
get to the lab you got a piece so bad
that your pee is clear and they go this
is diluted we can't even test it yeah
yeah so if it comes through you and if
you smoke like Adam and I do I dab at
least a half a gram a day you could
honestly probably quit for 15 days I
don't want to quit smoking weed though
and it's just a random that's gonna come
up you know yeah so I don't want to quit
if I wanted to quit I wouldn't have
started then you should you should
definitely get prepared I mean that's
best options that I've heard and then I
would just keep hand warmers on the
ready like I'd start wearing shirts with
pockets and like I'm not gonna use we've
got a 40 minutes 41 minutes you guys
want to you want to do one more question
I got one more but I bet we could go on
for quite a while about it if we do it
[Music]
well the question was what kind of
lights are you using for each phase of
growing all right that could be really
long
oh it could be really simple yeah so
quick rundown I've been oh I I know I
started off doing a bunch of grow
lessons and we got sidetracked because
Jesse came over and started doing
outdoor grow stuff we started talking
about all kinds of other stuff we kind
of lost track of the grow lesson the
promise to get you caught up on those
there's just so much [ __ ] going on that
it's hard to even catch up we get
sidetracked
just busy season it's such a great year
to do a podcast there's been so much
cannabis news and stuff to talk about
that's true yeah Jesse will be here in a
couple of days and we're gonna work on
finishing up the drying and curing
episode so that'll definitely be fun but
what kind of lights do I use that's
where I was for seedlings and stuff
that's just starting simple t5 s are
fine a lot of guys for essence correct
yeah it's t5 fluorescent sy t fives are
the little skinny bulbs so they name on
t5 - the skinny ones and ta - the bigger
ones just what size they are so I keep
my seedlings and my clothes under t
fives until they're good and rooted
depending on which room they're going
and what I'm trying to do with them
sometimes they'll stay under t fives and
tell flowers if I'm just doing a three
gallon pot of a little plant and the
reason why you run T fives is not only
because of the heat but because it's it
you can get closer to the plant right
you put them right on the plant and
they're more energy efficient than a big
lie and I don't think that the plant
really needs a thousand watt light when
it's a baby you can just give it enough
to
and that spectrum they sell to different
color bulbs if you get the blue ones
those keep your plants short and squat
that's what we want for van and until
your plants are two and a half three
feet tall that's plenty of light don't
keep them too crowded and they're given
plenty of space with the t5 s but yeah
it's difficult
I've seen people flower with t5 s I have
two it's not impressive but if you're in
Tennessee where you're not supposed to
be drawn weed and you can't get a big
light built that's gonna be better than
buying weed officer on the street and
I've seen some people grow some pretty
dank stuff okay you know with it so to
start I like the other T fives once you
get a little bit larger I will throw
them under I go straight to the thousand
watt metal halide for fetching I've got
a nice bedroom with metal halides in
there to keep them kind of close to the
plants the hoarder looks I think it's
the blue I forget which one they make
for it's the hoarder looks like they
make for vegging the blue one that's
awesome for vegging or deluxe makes a
high-pressure sodium that is red that's
super awesome for flowering I like to
switch to that now with tear when you
step from the t5 to the bigger lights
how just give us a range on like how far
you want to keep them you know I as far
as close as you can get them within you
don't want to you know you kind of want
to get them as close as you can without
burning the plants but there is a range
around a thousand watt light bulb they
is the unusable light for the plant it's
just too intense and it's the wrong
spectrum so you have to back up about a
foot and a half two feet from the bulb
okay
it's probably your best bet all right
but only the tops of your plants are up
there so the bottoms of your plants you
got a there's a lot of factors to keep
in there but about a foot eighteen
inches to a foot is probably about as
close as you really want to get unless
you've got some amazing cooling it off
you've got really well ducted and
ventilated lights then you can get them
ten eight inches but sometimes that that
bursts of light coming right out of
there isn't what the plants really want
that will kind of stress the plants and
change the flavors and kind of do a few
things that if you want a certain effect
that's how I achieve one effect when I'm
trying to do something is light stress
to plan a little bit but I don't want to
tell too much about that so I'm vegging
under the t fives I'm moving to the
metal halides and then I go to high
pressure sodium Stu finish a long time
ago I tried an experiment using high
pressure sodium and metal halides and I
honestly
get the best flavors using a mixture the
different spectrums yeah yeah using like
in the red I got for high pressure
sodium with with a 1 metal halide right
in the middle of the room and all the
plants in the middle of the room were a
little more dense had a little more
flavor I learned that by running the old
reflector cultic rozilla it holds two
bolts I put a 600 sodium and a 400
howlite in there and everything in that
little tester came out dank some of the
pictures I'm headband on my facebook or
actually from that Hut it was amazing
yeah I've seen this picture Super Dave
is that his headband yours I did not
make it no okay actually I got to talk
to dr. dank today or mr. dank today the
creator of the golden goat in a little
conversation on Facebook that was kind
of nice because I did not create golden
goat a lot of people try to give me
credit for that mr. daint created golden
God I simply put it into seed I
effeminate I reversed the female made a
meal out of it put the pollen on another
female yes it's a date cut so I made
seeds out of the golden goat they just
want to give credit to the guy that made
it thank mr. dank he did that not me
thanks mr. dink to let me use it he
actually gave me permission to put it
into seed and he said all he wants
everybody deserved good genetics that's
part of why I started making seeds so I
usually do fluorescence halide sodium's
a lot of people will ask about LEDs I
used to knock an LED light but my friend
Nancy kills both look frosty and I was
just about to see she's running a lot of
stuff that's from other growers not even
me that looks amazing just as well
what's the one that she's guys in DB
Cooper it's just giant nuggs it looks
really nice yeah yeah
it's he's doing a great job with the
grows well talking about lemon growers
individual that could probably you know
put a paragraph in that you could read
yeah there we go
support those women growers for sure
what Clint says
I like that you gotta have an approach
as a comedian and one time Clint told me
go on the chauvinist route and I
believed him it's it's the it's really
easy and that's why I don't like it
yeah is because it's for me it's easy to
write those jokes it's just not fun it's
just an easy target I'm saying women are
easy targets I'm gonna do some plugs
Clint has a lot of [ __ ] to plug tell us
about your Facebook's your Instagram
your shows how do we call you to cuss
you out or do we email you to send you
hate mail
yeah best way to get a hold of me he's
probably Facebook or Twitter find me on
Twitter it's at tall Clint and Facebook
find the wild cousins we've been doing a
lot of shows we probably have about one
showcase a month and you know this one
this one's a little rough cuz it's on a
Monday so it's just but he's just
passing through and somehow we booked
him that's a Ron Babcock and he's he's
funny looking mop he's a funny guy I
think I'm free that Monday so for five
bucks yeah I'm gonna try yeah like a
professional comedian coming to pueblos
like it's not like oh but it's like you
guys are gonna miss it and I don't want
anybody to miss it like oh I didn't even
hear about that you know I heard like
one of my favorite bands Baroness have
you ever heard they're like a metal band
one of my favorite bands and my buddy
Paul who does comedy with me told me
yeah we had them back in like 2000 come
through and play some house show they're
[ __ ] huge they're like a huge band in
metal and they're just like I missed it
and that's that's why you miss it though
is because you don't know what's
happening yeah and there's not enough to
do in Pueblo to where you guys can be
like oh is doing this and it's like well
that's fine during the fair but you
don't have anything to do right there's
something
down there everyday it seems like though
you know it's hard to distinguish what's
good and what's not well that's why I'm
inviting you to this we have I bucks
your bills and watch a professional
comedian you can watch me be a [ __ ]
piece of [ __ ] Paul and John are there
too and they're funny so yeah to Anna
for at least be a good show no I have
faith in you guys you guys we talked a
lot of trash about you but open mic or
comedians but you guys are getting that
for quite a while and you're getting
there you guys were funny now for a year
a comedy scene here has definitely
blossomed and evolved in quite a
transformer yeah sure there's another
one opening so that's pretty crazy
it's gonna be fun it's we're just
getting their comedy hills the world
guys comedy and cannabis they go all
together I guess that's a good way to
end this portion of the show Adam you
got me think the plug over grow the calm
on Twitter for xx calm Adam will be here
when I do the intro and exits to the
show so get to see a lot more cool stuff
for the show dude thanks for taking a
night out or a little bit of time out of
your night you gotta get to work pretty
soon I'm doing well buddy thank cool
cool thanks for coming you're welcome
back when you have more questions more
stuff to say it whenever you need
anything you don't have to just be on
the podcast to drop by you come by hang
out we like you at the table we do need
to yes all right guys we're gonna wrap
up this portion of the show right here
and I'll be right back to do the closing
alright that was another successful
episode of the hydro culture podcast
before I say goodbye I want to give a
big thanks to Clint and Adam for
dropping by make sure you follow those
guys on Instagram and Twitter it's at
overgrow the Gov and at tall claim also
go follow my friend Jessica it's miss
green thumb em ISS underscore green
thumb on Instagram now that the show is
over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for I grow culture
find the review section give us a five
star rating after that type in the
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode and don't forget
that the show is available on iTunes and
stitcher and every single episode is
archived on I read genetics Colorado
dot-com all the music in this episode
was from taskin lioness make sure you
check them out at asking Linus Van Camp
dot-com big shout out to highly educated
titanium the big shout out to Ryan from
true thunder calm only give a big happy
birthday shout out to my ninja spins
thanks again for listening to the
agriculture podcast take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
me myself concentrate connoisseur clean
my Regan o'clock
[Music]
at highly educated high quality products
by this podcast podcast is also brought
to you by our good friends at nature's
green remedies calm city don't forget to
check out all right we are back I was
turned around she said I know you know
the answer
[Music]
so I hope you listen to the podcast cuz
I told you that you should and now we
have proven that you're right I was only
ninety percent sure that when I told you
that the girl store it looks great place
is awesome we got some some big news
coming up i I can't say it yet it has to
do with a really popular new lighting
systems I don't even know the news I'm
gonna have to grill Jessie here in a
second find out what's going on
we gonna we gotta sell on the Black
Label Black Label nutrients are they 50%
off 10% above cost 10% above cost so
whatever
check it out guys whatever they paid for
these nutrients they're gonna sell them
to you for 10% above that but after that
it will no longer carry the light of
products yeah it's nothing wrong with it
it's just not a big seller for us it's a
small shop also you can't carry every
two single line in there we replaced it
with some botanic hair products and we
already sold out of the stuff we stocked
in today so I recommend botanic are
strongly to everybody that I teach how
to grow so that could have some small if
you listen to this show idle talk a lot
about the nutrients I use I try to keep
a lot of my uh that's kind of stuff that
I like to let people experiment on their
own botanic air doesn't pay me anything
go to hydro pueblos support their new
their adventure is it a venture business
venture I recommend it's what I use I
promise I've talked about grow feeding
recipes and [ __ ] and all of it is
included botanic probro
it smells almost drinkable Cannabis Cup
winning nutrients right there what we're
trying to do they're also good to the
environment that must seem to be real
dirty I like that
liquid Karma's a good product you can
add liquid karma to any feed regimen and
it will help you out vitamin e know is a
new product that they're putting out
that is a good product fold X in a
foliar spray it's a good product and OGT
see none of these we're not getting paid
for any of these free commercials we're
doing right now it's just this is just
from our heart that's what we do it's
what we use high quality products that
I wouldn't talk about [ __ ] on this
show alright so it is time to talk about
the end of the grouse season sorry that
music was kind of distracting both of us
let's focus a little bit our seasons
been fun
nobody's stolen your [ __ ] hopefully you
didn't have to shoot anybody hopefully
you got to harvest everything hopefully
you didn't get that frost on it that one
night it's coming up guys if you haven't
cut down yet you're a week or two away
maybe three or four weeks at the most
right in the backyard it's really time
to get your [ __ ] together it's time to
flush flushing is important even if your
this is something that I've always
wanted to touch on on the show let's
talk for a bowl give it however much
time this takes we'll talk about
flushing yeah flushing as you're feeding
all of your cannabis plants you were
pouring even if you're using organics
you're pouring stuff into the root zone
that is staying in the soil and your
plants are feeding off of that you don't
want to smoke whatever you're feeding
your plants you don't want that taste in
your buds at the end you don't want
nitrogen you don't want phosphorous you
don't want potassium in your buds so the
plant actually takes up nutrients it
puts the nutrients where they want and
then yes your plants do spit out the
excess nutrients through the roots again
it basically shits them right out I'm
keeping this real simple what we need to
do now is flush the toilet we need to
get that we just want clean dirt for
sure and if you're recycling your dirt
this is a good point this is where you
actually start recycling your dirt is
that the flush of an indoor plant so
this works for the outdoor we want to do
this to every cannabis plant you ever
grow before you harvest it 10 to 14 days
before you cut down that plant water
that [ __ ] out of the plant water it as
much as you can and from then on out
only give it clean water just clean pH
if you can but this is the end so just
give it a lot of clean water a watering
real well go ahead I'll let you jump in
container plants there's a 20 gallon
container probably give it 20 gallons of
water and that's I want to see you know
pretty much you'll have from 17 gallons
of water come out probably yeah I
dragged a 7 gallon pot to an area where
I have a drain and I will pour about 15
gallons of water through a central
gallon pot and repeat it you know this
is yeah just keep pouring water you get
get however much water you can fill that
pot with pour it in there let it drain
through it'll pour out go back in a
couple of minutes pour another pitcher
or a bucket or whatever you're using
pour more water in there if you can set
the hose in your plants on your pot
plants water them until you're afraid
that it's over watered up you're not too
worried about killing them at this point
it is the end of the season
you won't overwater on there outdoors
that water will go somewhere you want to
get all that nutrients off there the
indoor container plants Jesse's perfect
on that just water that pot as much as
you can if you have to it's kind of hard
to get a plant somewhere if you're
working a seven gallon pot you need to
get it kind of up off the ground so
it'll drain properly yeah a lot of you
guys are growing in the basement and you
got a dedicated bathroom set that sucker
in the shower put it up on two cinder
blocks under the pot so that it doesn't
go anywhere and that treats a lot of
drainage space that water will pour
right out of those bottom holes of the
pot if you've got a three gallon pot set
thought put a couple of cinder blocks in
your garage maybe where you can get some
water going or if you got a cool
backyard where your stash is kind of
hidden you don't want it don't show your
pot plants to your neighbors and be real
careful about bringing bugs in but this
is the end
you got to flush them real good always
14 it's 10 to 14 days with nothing but
water if you had any nutrient burn
problems get in there maybe a week
before you can I don't think you can
over flush the only thing you're gonna
do is kill it I mean it's gonna run out
it's gonna be starving to death down the
roots because you're giving it you know
15 gallons you know this is flushing
will help your plants burn better don't
dry and cure better they'll smoke
they'll smoke better don't taste they'll
smell better have you ever smoked pot
that uh it almost tastes like you just
stuck your tongue in a light socket
who's that burnt [ __ ] on your tongue
probably had not been flushed I feel
like I can name the brand a nutrient
sometimes I can taste worm castings a
lot of times in people's weed I can
taste advance nutrients honestly if you
overdo a couple of things in botanic air
I can taste it if you overdo it and
don't flush it
[Music]
I think gh always has a it brings out
the limonene smell I think a candy
lemony
lemonhead candy I think so so if you've
got something that you want that is a
lemon strain then you want to bring out
that lemon feed at the general
hydroponics also I don't say this a lot
this is kind of a secretive thing that a
lot of us know that one of those things
you have to like read a lot to learn
stressing the plant with light stress
and heat will bring out limonene so if
you're trying to lemon up your lemon
strains drop that light a little bit to
close around week six of ripening and
you'll bring out the limonene terpenoid
little also stress your plants a little
bit so you're gonna have to adjust on
that your top leaders are gonna brown up
sometimes we're not growing for pretty
plants sometimes cookies is gorgeous
right up until about week eight and then
she's so I'm teasing you check out this
girl's gorilla glue number four nugget
I'm gonna reach the finished product of
the gorilla glue everybody around here
is passing yeah that's nice
shout out to elbow he does not listen to
the show I don't think but I'll get him
to and he'll hear this that's well done
he did a good job with that glue number
four I don't know if it's ready
[Music]
hate the word moist throw in moist out
there you know does that all right
we've kind of ranted on about flushing
the point here is flush your damn weed
we can tell the people that can tell can
tell and they're the ones that you want
to impress if it's hydro
flushing is even more important don't
really talk about hydro growing very
much and there's a reason for that but
um I have zero experience in hydro I'm
not an easy cloner that's about as far
as I get I've seen Sparky weed for my
Joey from hydro system if you've got a
Red Bull of nutrients you're constantly
pumping that line it's very important
actually it's important throughout the
entire growth cycle every couple of
weeks you should be flushing and using
one of those flush products clear ex I
was just about to ask how do you feel
about those flush products not
necessarily for dirt in my opinion but
for hydroponics you need to help yeah so
flushing your plants really good is
really important you want to impress
Jesse and I with your weed and the only
way you're gonna do it also you don't
want to give sick people weed with [ __ ]
in it that's not what a caregiver does
it's not what a compassionate person
does it's not what a responsible person
does you're on the other team and you're
growing that weed that should be illegal
you're on this reason that makes
prohibition happen if you're going weed
that has not been flushed exactly he
said you think about not even sick
people like you know that's the II just
don't want to put that in anyone's body
right that's horrible thing to do to
someone
all right so you've flushed your plants
now it's time oh we're gonna talk about
D leafing after you flush a few days
before harvest time you want to get in
there and take off the fan leaves all
those big leaves that are in your way if
they've got what's called a pea deal
that's the stem that reaches to the
large there's some other people
pronounce it differently you can tweet
me and argue me that's just how I've
read it so it anything with the P deal
you can reach and cut off chop all those
leaves off clean those things out of
your grow room
don't just chop them and leave them on
the floor Hills bring bugs feed them to
your chickens if you've had a clean
drove room you can possibly juice those
if you're into it you can cut off some
of the outer leaf if you want but you
might want to save that if you're making
hash just decide how much trichome is on
that if there's not a trichome on it you
can take it off right now
like you mentioned Girl Scout cookies
they always have a little PTO coming out
of the nug
yeah such a long one too I you know
depending on how far it is like you said
with hash some of them are a little
closer I'll keep that one on there just
because I see that little little bit of
resin in there and I can get greedy with
resin resin farmers brother
but yeah if it's very long I cut that
[ __ ] off you know coming out out of
the bud so clarify that a little bit I
found a knob that'll turn everything up
a little yeah all right so uh cut off
all those fan leaves now while you're
flushing you've got a few days now you
know you're flushing you know harvest is
coming you've taken off the fan leaves
now is the time to prepare the
harvesting the trimming in the drying
area you need a space let's go back real
quick okay I like that one more thing
how do you feel about like this weeding
agents molasses and stuff like that I
use this [ __ ] out of molasses
with my outdoor stuff the first I start
fleshing really early like I actually I
started to plants flushing this week I
give them to molasses feedings before I
actually start flushing and it's just
glasses but it's pretty heavy so I know
what's going into my plants and this is
uh so trying to keep it basics I don't
want to steer anybody wrong I want
everybody to learn the right steps but I
do sort of something similar I feed them
enzymes carbohydrates and molasses at
the end for sure so they'll get some
high grows I'm has the enzymes I prefer
and they'll get the molasses and
sometimes maybe some yucca extract day
so I've got 14 days that's like day 14
that's that and then from there now I
feel like I don't overfeed I've got
plenty of space to flush properly like I
can I drank a plant to a watering area
just [ __ ] hose on it until it's flush
it's actually just converted the old
bathroom that was in the work joint in
doing this is the flushing spot so the
guy's gonna pee with no stalls my
building doesn't have indoor plumbing so
yeah guys if you have all that stuff
that you're taking for granted you're
you're way ahead of the game sometimes
ya been growing since before we could
talk about growing you need to go to the
hydro shop with your hat down in your
face then I've got dreadlocks to my ass
we're in a car I get looked at we
flushed we've used some sugars and
enzymes and coconut water and some yucca
extracts you don't have to use them all
at the same time you can use these
differently the sukkah net may need a
little while to break down so you may
need something to help that happen the
enzymes are gonna be good so we have d
leafed we're preparing the dry space
right is that where we are yeah very
very important yeah
clean up your drying and trimming space
any
dog hair hippie hair all the crap that's
on my table I think it's just a bunch of
dab resin to tell you the truth but all
that [ __ ] is gonna end up in your weed
that you're cleaning up and once again
that's just as important as having a
good flush you don't want crap on your
weed you just spent 70 day flowering
cycle plus however long we took to veg
that stuff plus if you're doing a female
hunt you're risking you know you gotta
tell which seeds are good order outdoors
yeah that's a big plant - yeah yeah put
a lot of work nervous nights into it
have a nice secure area while we're at
it I did not write that down but have a
nice secure area and think about this if
you're making concentrates every piece
of dust and hair and particulate is
going to end up in your concentrate
somehow like even if it blasting butane
over it you're gonna blast dog hair
juice in your concentrates you're gonna
need so any trimming area your work area
cover your table get a plastic cloth you
guys use rubber gloves when you're
handling your plants when they're
growing when you're chopping them for
god sake please you've seen how you do
finger prints when you commit a crime
you're doing that to your plants you're
leaving oils and hippie goop and human
goop and cheeto stains all over your
plants wear some rubber gloves our oils
actually affect the plants for long-term
storage and plants that have been
handled with bare hands
break down faster in my experience that
makes sense I think a BHO dab you can
decarboxylase a Pho dab a done with your
fingers and your fingers you can deep
the carpet enough to be edible like
processed is delta xi THC by your liver
you can do that by rolling it in your
hand imagine what we can do to a try
come on apply for sure it ruin it kill
it yeah it'll even weird oils that are
fighting when you said deke are piloxing
think it a deal axing and all that stuff
no man yeah somebody asked me what is
dewaxing
we need to get a hash maker over to say
more technically what it is but I'll
explain it on a later episode so in your
trim room you should have comfy tables
you should have some good music
everyone's gonna argue over the music
sorry put on the agriculture podcast
episode one and hit play I actually like
to put up stand-up comedian shows wow
that's a good idea I listen to comedy I
listen to a lot of Joey Coco Diaz and
Joe Rogan listen to a podcast when I'm
trimming one of my favorite podcasts
hasn't posted an episode in quite a
while I'm a little annoyed what's up
Adam ill where's my new podcast buddy we
gotta keep on track here we're getting
into the show I like to prefer in the
area gloves
comfy chairs good music let's go back to
dry area okay preparing that dry area
dehumidifier yeah humidifier yeah
fans possibly possibly a fan or two
we're gonna need to keep it between 60
and 70 degrees in go 75 degrees if you
need to if it's you know in your bedroom
or something you're gonna be alright
don't stress but keep in mind though
that he is one of the biggest enemies of
a dragon plants yes and also you want it
dark yeah light I know it sounds weird
you've had all kinds of light beating
down on your plants for months but now
we want it dark we want those to stop
growing and degrading we want the
animation right where we are it protects
the the trichromats
yes yes we picked him at the right
maturity we will don't want them going
much further we also want our humidity
at 40% if we can not much more than that
if you go any lower you're gonna dry too
quickly if you go any higher
of course you risk molds and it's gonna
take too damn long to dry if you're in
the Dirty South do the best you can good
luck
the US in Colorado it's funny that you
say that because in the South you read
stories alike so when you harvest your
weed you got to dry it for 20 days and
then you read in Colorado you're like so
cut it down five days later they must be
in Colorado in February it really varies
from region to region yeah and even like
what side of the state you're on humans
dry out in Colorado yeah so you got your
fan you got your dehumidifier your
humidifier trying to have if you can
afford it if you can do it put a carbon
filter and a blower in your drying room
harvesting plants stink very much
harvesting plants your neighbors will
smell it ten times more than you you've
been around them every day you're so
used to it you're so comfortable with it
I've had plants I had just gotten done
trimming it didn't have any plants on me
and somebody came over from the garage
what's going on so you get that carbon
filter also you need a hydrometer that
just tells you what the humidity is and
a thermometer they sell a great one at
Highgrove indoor growing supplies you
can get at Walmart anywhere in the
nation Lowe's has remote-control
thermometer hygrometers you'll set the
unit in the room and then you can carry
the thing around with you and whatever
you're curious you look at the thing and
it tells you you don't have to run to
the grow room and luck my dad has one um
it has a chick on it and he's seriously
got this at Lowe's or Walmart but when
it's hot she's in a bikini and when it's
cold she's in a coat in the scarf and
everything out bumbled of similar
that's a great dad smiling put more heat
on your mic there we go all right so
we've got yeah the road the rooms are
looking good we got a place to harvest
we got a place to dry now you need a
spot to hang your buds or your whole
plants depending on how you want to do
it we'll talk about that in a minute set
up a hanging space with plenty of space
between your plants if you have a small
crop you can use a coat hanger put two
plants on one coat hanger if they're a
little like three gallon plot kind of
guys if you've got a five gallon pot
hopefully made enough pot to where you
need a one coat hanger per plant any
bigger than that we're gonna need little
hanging lines I use hemp twine and
freaking hooks and just put hooks in
each end of the wall and run some twine
across them you guys may not have space
fishing line works good too
a fishing line is perfect any kind of
string to hang it up you just want them
you know I've seen guys take chicken
wire and make a big cylinder out of it
and that way you got a bunch of hanging
spaces at different layers that's
basically what we do at the farm tomato
cages work great too yeah recycle that
tomato cage a long time ago I harvested
a crop and dried it in the hydro Hut
that the crop grew in just took out the
light flip the crop hung it upside down
right inside there Capital blowers going
kept a carbon filter going beautiful
crop those awesome looks very well I
wish I had the space to be able to do
that yes
[Music]
avoid the drying racks if at all
possible yeah a lot of people are
talking about those on line the other
day when I was talking about drying
those put a dam here they make a flat
side under weed they make it take look
tastes longer when you sort of squishing
the bud together like that you're
messing up your trichomes and your
flavors you're trapping in air trapping
in chlorophyll you're trapping in
moisture which is what we try to get out
Ray's chance of mold it centralizes a
whole bunch of humidity and I've always
felt the mesh damages the but yeah just
shaking around and stuff trying to poke
through the mash and then you always end
up with I have to put something
underneath those to catch
the stuff falls out there's so much that
I always wonder what should I do with
this although that was a few years ago I
know what to do I don't know like
Wiesenthal so it is useful for if you
have gigantic plants all the large fins
a little but that you end up with
inadvertently you know so I always seems
like you have a pile of that stuff no
matter how hard you try to fight it
don't be mad if you chop a button half
on your first trim session either
that happens always happens occasionally
alright we've got the rooms built up or
wearing rubber gloves
let's have everything done before you
chop down
don't be scrambling around be relaxed
this is really when I've seen a lot of
good crops go right up to the point
where it's time to put scissors to him
and that's when somebody [ __ ] him up
or right after you put scissors to it
and trimmed it and then put it all in a
Tupperware while it was wet or hung it
out too long to dry yeah like this is
where it counts you guys if you've spent
60 days 70 days on a flowering crop
let's do the harvest right this is where
this is where this is where the
patient's realism where the money
happens my aunt in a highly illegal
state go crop when I was younger and she
didn't know how to handle any of this
and of course there was no information
this was the 80s she stuck it in a black
trash bag and then hung it in her
basement and they were swamps in the
area of the country she lived in and are
not her basement but her attic and
needless to say it created a whole bunch
of mold sounds disgusting yeah a
horrible waste of a summer's work
especially in this locale oh yeah time
airs your life or moldy bugs terrible
she was a crazy one so be prepared be a
Boy Scout when it comes to growing a
crop you should always be thinking two
weeks ahead in your pot plants because
anything you do today you're not gonna
see it for
seven to ten days probably anything
you've messed it up on in the season
here's your chance to you know make a
little right of it that's a good point
yeah get on it so I guess this is the
time where we are going to get the
plants and harvest that right yeah okay
we should also branch out to dry trim
and wet trim a little bit before we get
too far the way I'm gonna talk about how
I harvest a plan I'm gonna
hypothetically have a three gallon pot
I'm gonna drag that three gallon pot
with my three foot tall pot plant over
to a nice area where I've got plenty of
space I'm just gonna chop the whole
plant the way that I do it I chopped the
plant just just above where the first
nodes pop out
so that I don't have a lot of stick
hanging off the edge chop that necessary
water
flip the plant upside down I use a fuzzy
stick it looks like a pipe cleaner just
wrap that [ __ ] right around those
bottom two nodes so that I got a nice
hanger I'll leave some hanging off and
then I tied that under wherever it's
gonna hang from different situations at
this point I hang in different areas so
we'll see I'm using my main dry room
I'll just hang it from the dry line that
hangs up there boom it's hanging in
there I myself dry trimmed so I've got a
plant that's been flushed d leaved my
rooms are clean everything's goin
properly now I've just got this giant
wet plant this is mostly little leaves
just donkey dick buds hanging upside
down in my dry room mm-hmm
tips are perfect we were gonna wet trim
this is where wet trim and dried trim go
to branch off a little bit right okay
just want to keep everybody on the same
page sometimes we we go too fast we've
done all this and sometimes people are
like you skipped like four days worth of
growth so I just want to keep it all if
you're gonna wet trim the difference
between white trim and dried trim is
obviously you let your plants dry if
you're gonna dry trim and then you get
in there and take the leaves off wet
trim you would do it right now you've
got the plant down you gotta hang it up
now it's time to get in there and chop
everything off you trim it into the bud
that's gonna be smoked at this point
right you don't have to go as close as
you look like you want to because those
little leaves are gonna shrink up into
the bottle little but still do a hell of
a good job getting in there
Jesse said earlier I definitely prefer
dry trimming Jesse and I agree say dry
trimming we agreed earlier that some of
those southern states we're talking
about with a lot of humidity you guys
may want a wet trim because you need to
get those leaves off of there and kind
of speed up that dry process here in
Colorado there's not a lot of humidity
sometimes it gets super dry we're trying
to slow it down we need to slow it down
we leave those leaves on so we're gonna
talk about mostly about dry trimming
this is what trim is basically I cut the
buds off of the stick store I have a
good hand size bud worn rubber gloves I
try to hold on to just a stem let me
spin that but in my hand and just slowly
clip off all of the leaves you can trim
it to your preference if it's going to
you if you're trying to put it to market
you got to trim that [ __ ] close it's got
to look good take off if there's not a
lot of trichome on that leaf take it off
if that leaf is sticking out take it off
we don't we're not leaf heads we're pot
heads we don't smoke pot not leaves yep
so that's basically wet trim I have some
patients that they don't want it trimmed
it all with their old schools so I guess
you should leave it on the stick stone I
should say that leave it kind of on the
sticks don't cut it in just two smaller
parts because you need a way to hang it
you know how the branch is a branch and
then there's a little node coming off or
your buds grow say one of those little
branch parts there's a little hook and
then you can hang that in your dry rub
cuz after you get done trimming these
buds you want to hang them up so they
don't get a flat spot and your cure a
core your dry rack you want them hanging
so trim them up hang them up and then
let those dry they those wet buds need
to dry after they've been trimmed until
you grab them and bend the stick and the
stick should pop and snap it should just
go cracked right on you and that'll be
obvious when it happens so depending on
where you are
that should take between five to maybe
fifteen days just depending your
location and they drive from the outside
in so don't wear on what trim is still
right so like I mean the outside of the
bud is gonna be dry before
it's actually dry right doesn't don't
you know get to happy and jump the gun
there it's really gonna make a huge
difference just slightly wet buds to dry
buds to properly cured buds podcast the
console isn't that impressive the look
on his face was like did I just call
from a straw I don't do that so let's
guys straight trim I prefer it it's
easier dry trim you're gonna hang I hang
the whole plant
I've heard people chopping the Brandt
growing I'm talking about a three gallon
fire so I'd hang the whole plan some
people chop it into smaller pieces if
you get it into just branches that's
cool I like to let the whole thing hang
I feel like it dries up just the right
speed here just because where we are for
indoor plants I totally agree all right
you've drawn those big outdoor plants
you've got to chop them into smaller
part yeah
outdoor plants with three levels of
cages around them and also I told
somebody to cut down the whole plant
they said I grow across oh you guys are
gonna have to cut out branches so we'll
just go with this we'll go we've got a
bunch of branches now we're cutting off
one branch of time we hang those they
dry however long it takes just kind of
sort of similar to the wet trim we're
gonna let them hang until right right
before they snap when that first part
snaps now it's time to get to work
because your stuffs gonna dry slowly and
you're gonna catch up you're gonna get a
little behind in trimming but you'll
catch up yeah especially if you got a
lot of work to do hopefully you got a
lot of work to do yeah had that sounds a
lot like River and the 52 ounces we're
trying to grow up I hope you guys
remember that cuz I got where we're
headed so we got these dried plants you
chop you chop your plants down you hung
on me a little dry they've cut off a
stick go to your drying area and you got
your stick pretty much just take your
thumbs and just knock those little dried
leaves right off put them in a little
container and
that or you can just knock the leaves
right into that container because you're
gonna make some sort of concentrates out
of that hopefully or food or something
with your gloves on with your gloves on
keep your gloves on please I don't want
to eat your skin flakes and your
fingernail dirt so you got these buds
and I kind of hold it kind of just
picture the way I do it looks like a
play Nintendo I got my thumbs just going
and I'm just knocking leaves off and it
looks like he's playing snake on a Nokia
phone pretty much what you're doing you
just hold that thing and it's knock the
leaves off you don't even have to you
can see what you want to take off once
it's dry so trim it to your preference
his little triangle leaves it stick out
I'm actually trimming this but that's
another table with my fingers these
little triangle leaves you just pluck
those right off your letter pluck that
off and you can see where the bud is and
where the leaf ends if you've done it
right
I use scissors but it's exact same
process eat some strains Girl Scout
cookies and Yeti know says there's
necessary those dried leaves fall right
off yeah and then so these dried nuggets
they're pretty much dry I throw those in
a bin and then when I'm done I jus
that's kind of how or the cure process
starts for both of these plants once
those sticks are snapping on your wet
trim take the leaves off throw it in a
bin and they're ready to go into jars
when you're done trimming everything
the dry trim now that you've knocked the
leaves off you got that in a bin now
we're ready to pretty much go into jars
and that's kind of where the curing
process would start don't you think I'm
sure we have really stoned me too me too
um do we want to get into curing on this
episode or do we we've gone 35 36
minutes do we want to get it get into
the cure or do we want to save that for
another time little homework all right
we're gonna wrap it up I want to thank
Jessi for coming we're gonna hang out
leave the mics on for a couple of
minutes you got anything you want to say
while we're on there
oh yeah yeah I burn
I'll give it a minute that I had been
told that keep you out of trouble
[Music]
there's no reason not to keep the family
life in the podcast live sure understand
people listen authority and you remind
me of [ __ ] that I would skip I told you
we're getting close to 1500 listeners
per episode we're helping people make
quality medicine that's what the new
dabs a golden go for sure other paper oh
there you go see this is these devs or
the crazies look injection he was really
neat it looks like like the form of a
golden sort of look to it I could see a
couple of books tearing it for a couple
hours on just some kind of we're talking
about your hash road stank it didn't
work these big love to everybody at the
garden of Weeden I need to give while
I'm thinking about it a special special
super shout out to my friend Doug Benson
and also Comedy Works we had the time of
our wives Monday night I don't want to
brag too much but look at
the Facebook pages and the instagrams
and the Twitter's there's like a hundred
pictures of me smoking and daven with
Doug Benson oh you guys don't even know
the stories you can't tell it's cool
cool as hell
hey Custer listen you need to bring it
up look I even just stopped myself [ __ ]
cuss jar this is only a rule that
applies to me but if the guests want to
participate they can the cuss jar if I
say the f-word backwards the only one
that counts in this cuss jar if I say
the f-word do you guys tweet me and
remind me every time I say it on the
podcast starting on episode 30 that's
the show don't go back in time and cost
me money every time from now forward
that I say the f-word on a show it cost
me a dollar okay after a few episodes if
I quit saying if I don't quit saying the
f-word I will increase my donation
amount I'll crank it up to $5 and then
after it cannot committing to any amount
of episodes I want to see how I do
because if I do the worse I do the more
money I have to pay cuz it'll hurt me
more the dollar doesn't hurt my feelings
but it reminds me five dollars you go
damn well it's five dollars ten bucks
you start going so we're gonna increase
it slowly I have a charity that I have
in mind that I will tell you who it is
it's a friend on Instagram he we had a
long conversation and he does deserve
the donation it's not an organization
it's actually a person who needs help
it's a sick child so we will help that
kid out every time I say that word
here's a buck for you what the [ __ ]
there we go got a dollar coming your way
just to get it started that makes me
wanna make dollar for a sick child still
occasionally we're gonna start charging
the guests a dollar two just for that
one
[Music]
I got a big dad here I owe a huge shout
out to my man task ROG I really
appreciate my brand-new blue
highly-educated carbon cap pretty much
wraps up episode 30 mostly wraps up the
outdoor grill lesson I want to send a
huge thank you to Jesse for taking time
out of his grow schedule to come and
help us out it seems like the listeners
really appreciate that so much respect
and much love to Jesse make sure you
guys follow him dad Jesse bros og on
twitter and jesse grows on instagram
Stiffler follow will appreciate that now
that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
Fried grow culture find the review
section give me a 5 star rating
after that type in a comment let me know
we think of the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode also
read all the stitcher comments stitcher
just recently updated and it is a lot
easier for me to find the comments so go
to stitcher leave your comments there
give me a 5 star review and I will read
your comments from stitcher as well the
reason I like good reviews and good
ratings is because that helps us move up
in the ranks which just gets us which
gets us seen by more listeners which
gets more people growing quality product
which gets less [ __ ] product out on the
street so don't forget - the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is archived on I read
genetics Colorado com I want to give a
big huge shout out to my ninja Spence a
huge shout out to my buddy Doug Benson
shut up to the crew comedy works thank
you guys and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 31 of the Isle
culture podcast you know who it is that
roasts Rasta Jeff glad to be back with
you got a lot of great news for you guys
in this episode but before we get there
this episode is brought to you by a
highly educated titanium if you're using
high quality concentrates you deserve a
high quality titanium nail made in
America don't trust a Chinese nail or an
American knockoff made of cheap metals
trust the industry leader trust highly
educated titanium highly educated
products are available at Aqualab
technologies calm spot cast is also
brought to you by nature's green
remedies calm visit nature's Green
remedies calm 4 gauge green genetics
apply to labs sin city rare dankness
mile high can adventure eye region that
extends many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code September 14 for 15% off
any order and you always get free
shipping at nature's green remedies calm
[Music]
Podcast is also brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or stop by the new
publication on 618 East 4th Street and
Pueblo Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies parts
of this episode are also brought to you
by our good friends at tree hugger comm
tree hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews of
our sponsors that make this show
possible cuz they got a whole bunch of
news for you
so I'm gonna take a big fat dab and I'll
be right back with the news I'm gonna
keep the video running for you guys
watching the YouTube video that I
mentioned I'm gonna start putting the
shows on YouTube
[Music]
taking big fat dabs and I don't have
anything to drink next to me it's kind
of a fatal mistake
I hold a big fat shout out to my man
tasks Rob that's right hook me up with
this blue highly educated carb cap helps
out a lot let you get those low temp
dabs I also wanna give them a shout-out
for this nail I've got on my rig that is
a highly-educated duality nail it's one
of my favorite nails what I use the most
we're not sponsored by hit that's
probably the rig I grab first when it's
time to take dabs also sit next to me I
got a back-up plan in case it gets dirty
I got the mad Rob big shout out to Mad
Rob sport mad Rob glass or a hitman
glass I don't have any specific sponsors
so I can say all their brand names when
I said that s Solomon made me a great
Rasta color Greg I really dig that all
right guys I'm gonna turn down the music
it looks like that means it's gonna fade
out itself to make sure we don't play
any more songs need to give a big shout
out to the mystic roots band what you're
listening to is the doggy dub from the
album constant struggle shout out to dog
and Catherine some of the coolest people
in reggae let's get down to business I'm
gonna fight it makes it so much easier
for me to think and do a show and there
is no music going on that dad worked
y'all all right so I told you had a lot
of good news going on if I can get my
web browser to open I will read the
great news for the day
it says realm of caring announces
Charlotte's Web to be shipped to all 50
US states now what the [ __ ] oh man I owe
a dollar what the heck that's a dollar
somebody tweet me and remind me that I
owe another dollar to that charity realm
of caring announces Charlotte's Web to
be shipped to all 50 US states
Charlotte's Web is a kind of popular
strain of cannabis that's really high in
CBD and they're going to ship it to all
50 states that already makes you raise
your eyebrows and say WTF so I'm gonna
try to quit coughing oh look I have a
gatorade down here that I've spaced out
take a sip of this beer I'm Chokin
all right so families of Rome of Karen's
out of state waitlist received emails
this week that Charlotte's Web hemp oil
will now be available for shipping to
all 50 states something I find weird
here I'm gonna have to do more research
it says Charlotte's Web hemp oil it's
got the little trademark symbol right
above that so they've trademark
Charlotte's Web hemp oil the email from
realm of caring which will now be
referred to as Roc explains that
Charlotte's Web product they will be
shipping falls within the federally
acceptable limit of less than 0.3% of
THC for classification as a hemp derived
food product the email also states that
the legality of this product is still
ambiguous and recommends the patient's
sign up for their state's medical
marijuana programs to provide your
family more protection however the
organization will ship to patients who
have signed up for the wait list
regardless of their home States cannabis
policies and regardless of each
individual client status as a licensed
medical cannabis patient so they found a
loophole apparently there is less than
0.3 percent THC in the Charlotte's Web
cannabis oil that they're making well
let me call it the right things they've
trademarked it we've got to say it right
I got a scroll back up
Oh Charlotte's Web hemp oil it's right
there in the very first sentence I
scroll down way too far
ah so they're gonna ship it to all 50
states that means people in
Massachusetts they may you know pick a
state that you're afraid of if you live
in a state right now and cannabis is not
legal there you can get this product
shipped to you if you were on their
waiting list I don't know how long ago
you had to sign up to get on the waiting
list but if you were there you can get
this product now I find that remarkable
I find that quite ballsy ballsy's the
word I'm gonna use I find it really
compassionate and I really hope this
works out I hope this helps a lot of
people let me continue with the article
let me give some credit before I get too
far I forgot to give credit to where
this article came from it just says
photo by let's see I guess it's by
Vanessa waltz Medical yes uh Vanessa
waltz medical news and editorial
all right sorry I should prepared a
little better for that part
so yeah photos gives photo credit to
Vanessa waltz and I'm pretty sure that
the article is from her also I actually
this was tweeted to me by my friend on
Twitter
what's up point Mike thanks for tweeting
that he's Nikon an emo Punk on Twitter
I'm not sure which is which it's either
at Nikon or at an emo Punk here let's
just be diligent and go look at that for
you then I promise I'll get back into
the article I want to give my credit
because he hooked me up here this was
really something myles grint glad to see
because we see all kinds of bad news all
the time right that's good to see some
great [ __ ] I'm going through as quick as
I can on Twitter so it's Nikon Nico n
but he is at Nemo puck 15 any mo PU and
K 15 so give him a shout-out for me Tom
you appreciate hearing his story that he
sent me on the news here all right I'm
let's roll back down the cost of the oil
will be $250 per bottle which is equal
to 5 cents per milligram of CBD so there
are pros and cons of the new development
and an explanation of why it's likely to
be quite different than the RS h o CBD
debacle we're gonna have to that's got a
link to it so we're gonna check out the
RS o RS h o CBD debacle we're gonna read
that link also open link in new tab and
open link in new tab owner if that's the
same thing
we're gonna read those also sorry guys
I'm rambley because I took a couple of
dabs and I just wanted to get this news
out Mike sent me this and I just wanted
to get on the mic and read it so
according to ROC the oil will test at a
consistent thirty to one ratio and the
THC will be lower than the point three
percent allowed for food products under
federal law while naysayers may question
why this may why this is any more legal
than RSA chose products it is critical
to remember that our sh o has been
tested numerous times by independent
laboratories finding contents in excess
of 1% THC which is undeniable ly illegal
under federal law and in non-medical
states we can only hope that ROC is
testing and quality control will be far
more reliable than RSA chose based on
our OCS established track record with
products already available in Colorado
and California this is likely to be the
case although maintaining a consistent
ratio of 30 to one will undoubtedly be
challenging for the company's growers
and extraction staff so you guys haven't
seen a lot of initials here this are sh
o let's go see what that is
r sh o not a normal reaction to cannabis
so this is a product that shows a bottle
it looks like
nature's supplement there's some in a
syringe like an oral syringe and then
there's some in a bottle it's 18% CBD
I'm gonna read just this little quick
article that comes from I'll give you
some credit who wrote it it looks like
another Vanessa Walt's article in the
wake of reports of serious
gastrointestinal effects from the real
scientific hemp oil a real scientific
hemp oil so it's the controversial
product and people are claiming nausea
vomiting diarrhea people are saying
that's a normal effect so I don't know
anything about that I can't argue that
from taking this product from saying if
that's a good effect or not
another competing product we're just
gonna go back to the article I just
wanted to make sure we knew what that
was also I said the CBD debacle I
clicked that link let's see what that's
about
it's another go figure it's another
Vanessa Walt's article
article about marketing CBD so we're
gonna see a lot of that stuff because
it's gonna get really really popular or
it is getting really really popular
apparently I'll continue with the
article as far as the feds coming down
with Roc Oh as far as the feds coming
down on ROC with a question mark that's
actually a question so we're supposed to
say it like as far as the feds coming
down on ROC that would be an extremely
poor PR move on the federal government's
part with all the hype generated by
Sanjay Gupta CNN specials and the
widespread media coverage on CBD a
federal crackdown on Charlotte's Web
would cause a huge uproar and the Fed
surely know this arresting and
prosecuting the self-proclaimed
Christian CBD providers from ROC would
spurn an entirely different public
response than the arrest and prosecution
of RSA chose leaders many of whom have
already faced charges from the SEC and
other federal agencies my guess is that
ROC is essentially untouchable and
unimpeachable in this venture
as for the negative side the most basic
and critical flaw is that thirty to one
is unlikely to help most epileptic
children anecdotal reports from Colorado
families using the higher ratio of
Charlotte's Web which is reportedly
tested as high as forty eight to one CBD
THC indicate that their children read
these either switching to other products
to maintain seizure control or
supplementing Charlotte's Web with
higher THC products available through
Colorado's medical cannabis program is
THC supplementation in addition to
mail-order Charlotte's Web is a viable
option for children and other medical
states who have previously been unable
to find consistent sources of clean well
tested CBD products and in non-medical
States it is certainly easier to find
THC for supplementation in the
underground black market than it is to
find CBD oils or clones so yeah I was
thinking about that the whole time I was
reading this it's just CBD what about
that montage effect we've talked about
so many times we got to get that whole
myriad of CBD THC THC V what about the
terpenoids that we're missing I think
all of it does it together and they're
saying that they're actually trying
they're needing to supplement with some
higher THC products because the CBD is
not working completely it's probably
helping it's you know just like any
medication that you would take or
anything new you would introduce to your
box to your body the first few times you
consume or take that you're gonna notice
a stronger reaction and after anything a
few times a few times you're gonna quit
feeling is strong of an effect so I'm
pretty sure that this CBD does work you
know for a while maybe for a long time
for some people maybe forever for some
but some people that's gonna you're
gonna need that THC I think I've
repeated and rambled about that long
enough so let me wrap up the last
paragraph here ensure there should be a
positive step in the war on cannabis at
the very least it should force federal
opinion on the legality of CBD hemp
products it will likely benefit some
number of patients especially those who
were able to supplement with THC and
unlike the CBD only legislation that has
been pushed by ROC the shipping of
Charlotte's Web is unlikely to have a
negative impact on future whole planet
legislation while the concept of trade
marking a plant and hoarding a strain
still rubs many patients and in
history insiders the wrong way the
bottom line is that more patients will
soon be able to access CBD rich oil
without having to move to realm of
caring States and that's a good thing ah
this lady seems to know what she's
talking about on it if you guys want
somebody to follow cool on Twitter I
don't know if she has a Twitter account
let's read about her there's a little
article about Vanessa waltz Vanessa
waltz is a writer artist and marijuana
reform advocate living in New Mexico she
graduated okay check her out dude
Vanessa waltz she seems to have a good
head on her shoulders when it comes to
marijuana cannabis that's one thing we
got to do we got to quit sayin marijuana
and see cannabis all the time I just
kept reading the word marijuana and now
it's in my head
to
yeah one brand only Charlotte's Web
there's courting this dream if you've
got Charlotte's Web or high CBD medicine
share that stuff get that out there grow
clothes of that if you live in a legal
state cut a lot of clones whenever you
cut clones get to your plan account cut
that many clones give those out do you
have extras you know what I'm sayin
sorry I'm think of too many thoughts at
once right now trying to do a show and
ramble so if you've got clones of CBD
medicine put those out there so I'm
saying because we don't want these
companies taking over all that [ __ ] why
do we want a company and charger that
that doesn't seem that's why we're
that's why most of us are smoking
medical cannabis anyways because we
don't want a company getting rich off of
us or a company telling us what we can
and cannot consume so I'm gonna move on
to the next article because I feel like
I'm ranting super dab doubt I gotta quit
getting so high on these episodes it's
kind of fun to tell you the truth if I
want to remember a little while back we
talked about a police officer who gave
out a whole bunch of tickets 66
citations in Seattle he was the main guy
giving out all the pot tickets we gave
him the big metal finger here's another
article that came from Seattle the
credit goes to the Associated Press it
says Seattle's police chief has asked
the city to seek dismissal of all
marijuana citations issued by the
bicycle officer who wrote 80% of the
tickets handed out during the first half
of this year for using pot in public
Seattle Times reports that chief
Kathleen O'Toole said Friday the request
to the City Attorney's Office stems from
the conclusion that the 66 citations
were written as part of the officers
personal agenda the tool says the
tickets were written for the wrong
reason
bicycle officer wrote 66 of the 83 such
tickets issued in the first half of the
year of the city the student wrote 66 of
83 tickets in the first half of year so
in six months every month this dude
busted wrote 11 tickets for people
smoking pot
the officer wrote on one citation that
he used a coin toss to decide which of
two men got the ticket and on another
described state voter approval of
marijuana legalization as silly what he
freakin he wrote on the citation that he
used a coin to decide which two guys got
the ticket
how can cops get away with that he wrote
it on the ticket I guess he's not he's
they're trying to make him not count now
they're trying to say huh your tickets
don't count would that be a big middle
finger if the authorities gave the
authority a big metal finger like that I
like it the time since the officer has
apologized to O'Toole she's reportedly
still considering disciplinary action
the City Attorney Pete Holmes
spokeswoman Kimberly mill says Holmes
will review the Chiefs request
initiative 502 approved by Washington
voters included a civil fine per for
public consumption of marijuana so uh we
kind of got a some people on our side
because they let that cop are they gonna
they may let that cop stick it's a slide
that'll be kind of neat I'm scroll
through the neck to the next article
they were talking about in Denver about
banning BHO extraction and banning
certain types of extractions without
being in a licensed facility or what
they would call a MIPS I think that is
to be a little more accurate sorry I'm
chicken too many things on the computer
the video is going the recording is
going and I'm on the right website dude
we're golden tonight for as many dads as
we took this is working out pretty well
all right so this says some exemptions
and proposed Denver restrictions on
making home hash oil so it says
alcohol-based extraction process will
join water and food based method methods
as acceptable in Denver City Council
committees planned ordinance
this article is by John Murray from the
Denver Post it says Denver City Council
committee Tuesday
delayed proposed restrictions on home
hash oil production so that they could
be amended to accommodate residents who
use an alcohol-based process sorry
shit's fallen over on the table here not
even sure what's happened and that was
weird
several people argued for the change to
the safety and well-being committee
including the father of a little girl
who depends on cannabis oil to treat her
severe epilepsy the committee will
resume the discussion on the proposed
ordinance or could vote on October 16th
on whether to send it to the full
council the proposal would ban the
amateur use of butane or other gases in
extractions of oil for marijuana that's
resulted in dozens dozens of home
explosions statewide this year licensed
businesses still could use that process
the people who make hash oil at home
would have to use safe water and food
based methods
this is gonna have two different effects
well people do [ __ ] that's illegal
anyway so I don't think that people are
gonna stop doing it it's just gonna make
it a little sketchier and now that's
gonna cause more more people sneaking
around doing it you have to do it in a
little more sketchy place which means
you're a little more enclosed which is
the dangerous part of it and also I
think it's gonna make the street value
of pho dabs go up and already right now
dabs are getting kind of hard to find
around here and the prices are going up
really high and it's because they're
making rolls like this I agree I don't
want some uneducated dude next door in
his garage making hash while I'm sitting
here trying to record a podcast I don't
need the next-door house blowing up and
screwing up all of our lives so I guess
it's kind of you know the adult in me
needs a parent in me the freaking smart
guy says we should not be blasting like
that so that's kind of cool too but then
and we got to get the shops or we got to
figure out a way that we can get some
kind of private caregivers to be able to
blast it if we build our own rooms if I
have OSHA come and build me a blast safe
room can I make it in there then maybe
please you know there has to be some
kind of exception because the shops are
charging way too much right now for
shatter and a lot of it is [ __ ] to tell
you the truth I wouldn't dab a lot of
the hash that I've seen come from the
shops I am a little bit of a hash knob
to tell you the truth but uh I don't
want to dad a lot of that [ __ ] so let me
show you I've got a camera going here
guys I'll post some pictures of this I'm
kind of working on putting up YouTube
videos this got ha I can't see what I'm
doing let me switch to the video this
got hot in the car but this
golden dope shadow right here it should
be nice and stable it shouldn't be goopy
soupy and poopy and then I'm gonna
contradict myself by showing you some
live resin that is a little bit gooey
but this is a different product this
isn't shatter we're not marketing this
is shatter this is live resin it's uh so
golden and clear that is bra that's just
uh we've talked about libraries and it's
fresh frozen butane blasted buds down in
a closed-loop shoutout to the guy that
did it for me he knows what's up he
knows who he is I don't know if I should
say his name on the show right now good
work that shit's golden really golden
looking but the shops are too much for
doodoo and that sucks so they have to
let the artists the extract artists that
know what they're doing the people that
uh that kind of led this movement has it
make everything happen not everything
that'll make sorry I'm adjusting a
camera over heroin rambling the guys
have evolved all this hash stuff they've
done the research they've done the work
we need to be able to do it in a safe
manner and I know that open blasting is
not a safe manner
I wonder if this is let's see this is
gonna have anything to do with the guys
with the closed-loop system let's scroll
through this article one quick time and
see
would ban amateur use of propane or
other gases an extraction of oil foam
yeah that [ __ ] says closed-loop
system or not I think in the way that
that's worded so we're gonna have to be
careful I know a few guys that have
invested in a closed-loop system
thinking that that was solved the
problem and now look they're changing
the rules right around here all right
I'm gonna get back into the article it
says Brian Wilson whose family moved
from New Jersey to Denver earlier this
year so his three-year-old daughter
Vivian could use medical marijuana
treatments said neither of those methods
will produce the kind of oil suitable
for her he uses an ethanol based
extraction process I didn't move I here
to put her at more risk Wilson said
n'ver fire chief elected Eric tabe
excuse me told the committee that the
proposal likely could be amended to
allow all alcohol based methods with
limits on use of heat and amount of
alcohol to keep it safe say I guess if
and I don't like rules and stuff but I
don't like fires and explosions either
if I have a choice a couple of rules or
a couple of fires and the Rastafarian me
says [ __ ] the rules I owe a dollar but
uh the other part of me says I'm gonna
like fire um let me explain why I keep
saying that I need a dollar if you're
not a what common listener what's a
regular listener what's the phrase for
that or regular listener I guess
[Music]
every time I say the f-word I owe a
dollar and there's a charity there's a
guy he's not a charity it's a sick
person sick child that will get my
dollars every time I say the f-word you
guys have to tweet me tell me when I
said it tell me how many times in this
episode I said it it starts on episode
30 this is 31 so you got two episode
three can make some money off me
after a couple episodes if I don't stop
saying F word I'm gonna increase the
dollar amount I'll go from a dollar and
I'll be like alright now I'm gonna stir
not now I'm not saying this but
hypothetically in the future I'll start
charging myself five dollars for every
time I say that F word I mean if I still
don't stop will charge ten bucks and
then that's gonna start costing me money
and money counts and I don't want to say
that for it on the show and I don't want
to pay money so it's gonna work together
I'm rambly tonight guys that's why I got
behind the mic I got this cool news
about people send in CBD oil I want your
comments about the CBD oil story tweet
me that I'm gonna take a drink right
quick you guys give me give me I'm not a
we're gonna head at this part
I read
okay this article I said I had good news
this one isn't the greatest of news but
it's news says certain The Denver Post
it doesn't give a a reporter name
noop so seven people are now named as
plaintiffs in a class-action lawsuit
against the company accused on giving
people samples of marijuana laced
chocolate at the denver county fairs pot
pavilion which was supposed to be drug
free the suit filed August 25th in
Denver district court by law firm fresco
de Joyner Goodman and Greenstein alleges
that first name was a stumble sorry
alleges that representatives of beyond
Broadway LLC doing business as both full
melt chocolate and Live Well handed out
the chocolate on August 1st through 3rd
the suit is open to all people served
THC chocolates by beyond Broadway LLC at
the fair oh man so we talked about this
a little while back there was a pot
pavilion at the Denver County Fair they
had a joint rolling contest where
actually they rolled oregano instead of
rolling pot but they'd enjoy a rolling
contest they had a lot of stuff going on
actually had a pot drawing competition
off site where people had to draw their
paw and then people would go look at it
somewhere else cuz they didn't want it
there oh you were not supposed to bring
any pot products to this fair that's not
what was supposed to happen but full
mill handed out some chocolate bars and
people ate them
and seven people are now named as
plaintiffs in a class action lawsuit
against these guys
imagine and we had to stock a little
while back on the show but imagine if
you or not a pot smoker so me listening
to the show may not be pot smokers some
of you may be amateur pot smokers some
of you I know only have smoked a little
while some of you can only smoke very
occasionally and if you eat a hundred
milligram edible you're gonna get really
high so imagine if you went to the fair
and you're just hanging out and
someone's like you try this chocolate
man and you're like no you're like I
believe you you work for this company
and you've got the apron on that says
the company neither behind the booth I
believe you so you eat the chocolate
right probably 45 minutes later you're
just [ __ ] your pants because you're
too high oh man imagine that you gotta
try to drive home and the weird part of
the head trip of it made my opinion is
you don't realize that you ate something
that was gonna make you feel intoxicated
so now you're like tripping a little bit
because you're high right you're
starting to feel whatever whatever you
whatever comes on first you get the
tinglies in your arms and then things
are a little funny and you started
giggling but you don't know why and and
but now you really don't know why
because you didn't realize you ate this
[ __ ] so you're like I'm [ __ ] now you
think you just [ __ ] your brain is
flipping out I owe another dollar get me
on it hey shout out to dreadful Jay
what's up mama you remind me every time
I say the f-word and I appreciate it
keep those Instagram pictures comin guys
follow dreadful J on instagram she's a
badass woman she makes me good hash
she's an awesome lady check her out but
imagine you just be trippin dude you
just and you have to what if you had
your kids with you what if you're with
your mom and what if you have a job Oh
what if you have a job dude or they drug
test you what if you were a reporter
that was on the clock see this could
have caused a lot of problems we
shouldn't talk too much about it because
I guess there's a court case and
somebody can hear what I'm saying to be
like yeah that is [ __ ] up I didn't
realize that oh and other goddamn dollar
this is gonna be an expensive episode ah
so seven people are gonna make a lot of
money off of full mile chocolate and
live well so be careful if you ever go
to a fair or an event they're handing
out cannabis chocolates and you're a
lightweight or you're not aware of what
you're getting as carefully
I guess if you get the wrong [ __ ] sue
the hell out of them I probably would if
I wouldn't if you did it to me but if
you gave my daughter a medicated
chocolate and told her that it was a
regular chocolate that's I'm definitely
you're gonna yeah there's gonna be at
least a court case it might be against
me from me reacting to that [ __ ] but
hopefully I can maintain will do
properly just see the [ __ ] out of you Oh
guys I've been rambling for let's see
let's go look at a clock see how long
I've been going on Ziya I might have to
pee here coming right up on thirty
minutes so I'm gonna fade out we'll be
back and we'll do another segment right
after this I'm gonna dab and use the
little boy's room thanks for listening
to me ramble tonight guys video Watchers
I don't know what I'm gonna do for this
part I'll just keep the video rolling
and we'll figure it out in a minute
alright guys I am back while I was gone
I turned on the email and I grabbed
myself a bottle of water so I think I'm
gonna survive speaking of the email
let's take a big fat hit out of this I'm
using my blue highly-educated carb cap I
need to clean this thing guys keep your
card class carb cap clean it will help
you out a lot dropping it on to the
infinity nail with an email wrapped
around it off of an old school rig that
I like this one cuz it's sturdy enough
to hold up the email that's why I use
this one so here we go big fat dad let's
do it it's not really a big fat dad I
just need to be able to talk so I do a
little one on the show
you
[Music]
but right that'll do it I noticed that
dab
all right so I've mentioned a couple of
times that I'm doing a video on this
episode I'm trying to go through all of
the old episodes and just make really
cheesy iMovie videos so that they can be
up on YouTube so that people that don't
have an iPhone or don't have stitcher or
whatever who are more simple and more
familiar with the youtubes well it'll
just give us another way to be listened
so I'm gonna throw the show up on
YouTube they'll be really simple videos
at first I'll learn how to make better
videos as time goes by the first few
will be cheesy I promise you the first
two are goofy I made them last night
might have been medicated might have
been really medicated I would take a DAB
to this golden goat and you can't sleep
after you dab this golden goat so you
just got to open your computer and just
go nuts because you don't really want to
do anything important when you're that
dad so I'm recording this one I'm just
staring into my macbook with a the
camera going and just recording me
what's up if you're checking it out
right now
I may just post that to YouTube but you
got 30 episodes to figure that one out
so it'll be up there eventually I might
I might go out of order you never know
with us you never know with me I just
wanted to jump on here and record
because I got that really cool tweet
about that article that Mike sent me I
had to tell you about that I wanted to
talk about the video of course I am the
guy from my region that exceeds a lot of
people have been asking me when will
certain things be back in stock in
nature's green remedies they're sold out
because I'm sold out you guys cleaned me
the heck out of seeds I really
appreciate it I promise you I'm working
on more stuff I've got more grateful dog
there would be a little bit of grateful
dog that that one doesn't make a lot of
seeds it's harder to get C's out of that
one than a lot of the others would be a
lot of bounty killer to be a lot of
Capleton there'd be a little bit of
heart of gold there will be some Kalonji
there may be a little bit of night nurse
a lot of what I make goes to the people
around here before it makes it to
nature's green remedies it goes to other
places before it gets there I take care
the locals first they take care of the
people around me my patients I'm a
caregiver those guys get the seeds first
that I make and then I put what I have
on nature's remedies when
order from me so I'll let them know when
I have snuff they'll order it and then
they'll put it on the website guys it's
gonna be honestly coughing and counting
so we're looking about probably 75 to 90
days if I don't want to make any huge
promises and there should be some stuff
on nature's green remedies maybe a
hundred days I'm gonna say because you
know I need packaging time and all that
stuff drying time right around 100 days
there should be some stuff available
from Ira genetics again in nature's
green remedies calm I apologize for not
being able to keep them in stock
honestly it's kind of a good sign that
they're sold out that means I'd be doing
[ __ ] right um also I have a forum
I read genetics Colorado calm has a
forum if you go to I read genetics
Colorado calm you can check out our
genetics it is a work in progress I
don't run the website it's my buddy Tony
he's a college student he's a working
man
so we put together the website late at
night while we're chilling out so check
it out please support that join the
forum if you have questions we will
answer your questions I get a some of
the stuff from the show comes from the
forum and some of the stuff from the
show goes onto the forum so it's kind of
a little way to be interactive if you
guys want to participate also a speaking
of participation you can follow us
please follow us follow I grow culture
on Instagram Facebook and Twitter
and also follow I read genetics on
Facebook Instagram and Twitter that'd be
really cool um coming up in the future I
know we said that we were gonna do an
episode about curing your cannabis
that's definitely gonna happen Jesse and
I are working on that we want to put
together better episodes for you guys so
we're taking our time and going slow
this may just be like a midweek Booster
episode just kind of me hanging out dad
and I was eager to get a show out man I
don't have a lot else to say I got to
give a couple of shout outs shout out to
COO and cat and the entire mystic roots
band make sure you check out the mystic
roots band big shout out the task rock
and highly-educated titanium big super
shout out to the entire garden of Weeden
crew big shout out to Jesse big shout
out to add miss green thumb also a
shout-out to hippy nurse 7/10
and a shout-out to Angela so I'm gonna
wrap up the show and we do this part now
that show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for the iGrow
culture podcast find the review section
give me a 5 star rating
come on you know you want to give me a 5
star rating
what that does is it knocks me up higher
in the ranks people see the show or
people listen to the show which moves me
up higher into the ranks or people see
the show more people listen to the show
and in turn more of your friends get to
grow high grade cannabis more people get
educated the proper way about cannabis
more people will quit believing [ __ ]
about cannabis more people know the
truth cannabis will be freed cannabis
will be legalized everywhere this is a
small step for weed kind I don't know
what the [ __ ] I'm saying anymore anyway
a little comment let me know what you
think about the show I'll read your
comments on the show it means a lot to
me to know what people think I say this
all the time if you love the show go
write a little comment if you shot the
show if you listened for this long you
probably liked it but if you thought the
show was totally [ __ ] and you think
I'm an idiot tell me tell me what I'm
doing wrong
maybe I'll correct it I probably don't
give two shits cuz I like the way the
show goes I hope you guys like it too if
it's little stuff that I can fix I'll do
it if there's little stuff that you're
like dude that is so dumb or annoying
I'll think about it if you're like your
dreadlocks you're dumb
you already know what my answer is gonna
be listen I've got two different
monitors I'm looking at it's why it
looks like I'm darting around and I got
paper here that's the first time I tried
to do an actual thought-out video
there's another video maybe episode 21
it's goofy I was really uncomfortable in
that one getting better at the
podcasting oh thank you guys for
listening I know I'm rambly dad down
kinda had some caffeine daddy going out
today so leave your comments on the show
check them out
stitcher updated their page oh excuse me
I'm burping on a podcast stitcher
updated their page and you can leave
comments a little more easily now and I
can find your comments more easily so
leave your comments on stitcher and once
again let me the review so I move up in
the ranks we can legalize pot one step
at a time one clicked at a time right
that's under noon that's our new model
here legalizing cannabis one click at a
time spread that [ __ ] around the world
tweet me max I'm gonna forget it don't
forget that every episode is available
on Ira genetics Colorado calm the show's
available on iTunes the show is
available on stitcher and I'm going to
try to get all of the episodes on
YouTube that's a huge commitment you
guys it takes a lot of chunk of time I'm
gonna try to do it and uploading an
episode to YouTube it takes the computer
all day to get it up there so sometimes
it fails after you do it and that's the
fun part of life anyway I want to give
you a huge shout out to my ninja Spence
thanks again for listening
[Music]
all right podcast world that was
episodes 28 29 30 and 31 of what used to
be known as the agriculture podcast
currently known as the girl from your
heart podcast don't thank everybody for
listening to a really long episode
please let me know what you think of
these long episodes is it worth my time
is it worth your time send me a tweet
send me an email
once again it's @gf wih podcast on the
Twitter if you want to email me it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com i
would love to know what you think of
these long episodes alright I don't want
to make this file much longer I feel
like I'm rambling for no reason so I'm
gonna get out of here I'll be back
Monday with a brand new episode with
brand new content I look forward to
joining you I hope you're there until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me