guilty' Podcast world its Rasta Jeff I'm
back with the chunk of old episodes this
time we're doing episodes 32 33 34 and
35 of what used to be known as the Hydra
culture podcast currently known as The
Grove from your heart podcast this file
is gonna be really long so I'll keep
this intro short all of the social media
stuff has been updated I would love it
if you follow me on twitter it's @gf wih
podcast you can find me on facebook it's
the girl from the heart podcast and you
can send me an email the correct and
updated email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen
without further ado here are episodes 32
33 34 and 35 of what used to be the
iGrow culture podcast
[Music]
yeah ladies and gentlemen time for
episode number 32 of Agriculture podcast
is your host Rasta Jeff joining me on
the mic we got our buddy Adam with us
how you doing bro buddy Mike Mike was
supposed to come join us on the show
today but Mike he hurt himself he hurt
his back he's laid up he's taking a
night off big shout out to Mike good
feeling better man get well bro we'll
take some dabs for you I was gonna make
videos of this podcast making a video as
a big pain in the ass and it really
detracts from the quality of the show in
my opinion I was too distracted by toys
and equipment I wasn't able to make a
good podcast so I've decided to not make
videos of the show what I will do is
keep making cheesy ass YouTube videos
with iMovie and just put up videos that
are mostly still shot so it'll be some
video in there but it mostly be stills
of stuff that is involved in the podcast
I'll take pictures of rigs pictures of
plants pictures of the guests people
with pictures of myself stuff like that
because doing a video really wasn't very
fun this music here big shout out to
Cancun the mystic roots man thanks for
let me play your music on the show
really appreciate it make sure you guys
follow the mystic roots band
I'm speaking of putting pictures of rigs
up man oh yeah I got a new rig today big
shout-out to LSD gallery on Instagram
and also big shout-out to at slugworth I
think it's slugworth glass I should have
researched that but check out slugworth
glass whatever they're called on
Instagram I will tweet a link to that so
you can find them
I ordered the Master Shake rig from LSD
gallery it's a little smaller than I
expected but boy do I approve came with
this super-awesome chain saw dabber here
I think this little handle here they're
encouraging me to wear this is a pendant
as what I think's happening and this rig
is certainly designed to be worn as a
pendant this thing I think Adam said
what is that three inches tall
I would agree that's about three inches
tall bro
so I'm super satisfied if you guys are
looking for good glass that will get
shipped to you at a reasonable price
from good people that do good business
the glass is thicker than it looks like
it's gonna be yeah it's nice and heavy
it's not clear so you can't see yeah
stylish super stylish well worth every
penny I spent it got shipped here super
quickly it went out the day after I paid
for it I paid for it on Sunday
I got a tracking number when I woke up
Monday morning so if you need glass
check them out they're called at LSD
gallery
they're pretty fresh also a big shout
out to task rock because when I ordered
my new rig of course I had to get that's
a little 10 millimeter rig it's my first
10 mill I like the bigger stuff honestly
but this little one is cute and I love
the way it hits this will be my new just
when I'm dabbing by myself that'll be my
new personal rig shout out the tasks I
got myself a purple carb cap and a
little 10 millimeter Trinitite nail to
put on my rig and it works perfectly
love it satisfied much respect at LSD
gallery and at task rock and at
slugworth class I'll have to research
the slugworth one now that you're there
let's just do this this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
highly educated titanium if you're using
high quality concentrates like an
most of you are you deserve a
high-quality titanium nail made in
America don't trust the Chinese knockoff
or an American knockoff you don't want
that trap that's made out of cheap
metals trust an industry leader trust
our good friends at highly educated
titanium highly educated titanium
products are made for dabbers by dabbers
right here in the United States of
America you can shake the man's hand you
can tell him your ideas you could tell
him thanks it's somebody that we know
someone that's part of this industry so
big love much respect to highly educated
titanium if you want your own highly
educated titanium products you can check
out our friends at LSD gallery they have
a limited selection available or for a
big big selection check out aqua lab
technologies comm they've got a lot of
great highly educated stuff in stock if
you're in Colorado these place this
place does not pay me but dude go check
out illusions glass okay
on Broadway together and I'm probably in
the market of purchasing rig so I mean
oceans glass in Denver does carry highly
educated products it's not just a glass
shop it's a gallery that sounds like a
fun it's [ __ ] awesome yeah dude I owe
a dollar because I just said that for it
again you guys get me on that Oh
starting on episode 30 every time I say
the f-word I owe a dollar you guys gonna
hold me to that charity by the time we
get to 35 all-star doing $5 every time
that it does not slip by so thank you
guys for listening and making some money
for the person that's sick that actually
needs some money it's a good way to do
it make sure you guys follow task rock
on Instagram and Twitter it's at task
rock pretty simple their task dask rock
with a K R okay it's all one word task
rock
sorry I'm fixing some sound levels here
not happy with something I got it
figured you can't hear the mess alright
this podcast is also brought to you by
our good friends at nature's green
remedies dot-com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gauge green genetics
will apply to labs sin city rare
dankness mile high Kenna venture IRA
genetics and many many more trusted
brands nature's green remedies is
running a special for our podcast
listeners type in coupon codes September
14 for 15% off any order and you always
get free shipping at nature's green
remedies dot-com you know that coupon
code does end at the end of September
I'll put out a new coupon code next
month for you guys think we're running
out of weeks here yeah
also this podcast is brought to you by
hi grow indoor growing supplies hi grow
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the new publication on 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check
out high grill for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor growing
supplies go forget hydro is now stocking
a full line of botanic care products at
the pueblo location so if you're
shopping for a botanic hair get down
there now and tell them you're listening
to the hydro to the agriculture podcast
brought to you by hi grow indoors like
supplies that's a lot of grow in one
word grow grow grow grow from your heart
alright our last add this show is
brought to you by our friends at tree
thugger calm Treehugger calm live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
calm for concert and festival news and
reviews WWE thugger calm i hope you're
listening to the show bro I read your
facebook about your adventures that
you're gonna take off on you're gonna go
on a travel you hopefully are going to
end up in South America bro I wish you
the best of luck I'll miss you
I love you every day and I hope to see
you when you get back keep doing what
you do with tree hugger cuz we count on
you sure for sure he's got a big
adventure set up for his it sounds like
an adventure is the right word yeah yeah
I wish him well have a good time
together
alright so you want to take a quick dab
and then we will read some news for sure
guys if you want to follow the show on
Instagram or on Twitter it's at
agriculture if you want to follow our
guest he is overgrow the Gov sorry I
stumbled on that one at overgrow the gov
you can find him on Twitter and
Instagram you can find me I'm at Rasta
Jeff 420 on Twitter or you can follow I
know that's a lot of social media stuff
but that gives you some stuff to follow
if you're listening to the podcast if
you're killing time you can look at
overgrowth the Gov see the pictures he's
posting you can look at hydrogen etics
and see the weed plant site post you can
look at agriculture and see a bunch of
cannabinoid profile charts and stuff
like that lots of stuff to check out
also I encourage you heavily to check
out the forum on I region etics Colorado
calm I've got a forum there that is my
website you won't be censored unless
you're a [ __ ] talker I try to let
everybody have freedom of speech you can
say what you want it's not like Facebook
I'm not gonna go and take down your
stuff I'm not gonna make you use your
real name Facebook has been censoring
people lately Facebook has been taking
down accounts that are have fake names
we're not even fake names just pseudo
names so if I disappear off of Facebook
find me on the forum come join my forum
I'll answer all of your drug questions
there I've got a nice community of
friends that are there we post up our
pictures we post stuff about our gardens
I've been posting the notes from the
podcast if I type something out like a
long note I'll actually put it there on
the forum so people can check it out so
I encourage you to interact with us I
love interaction of course there's
Facebook I grow culture on Facebook yeah
it sounds like I'm just plugging the
show again so we're gonna take a quick
dab and then we will be back for the
news while we take dads I'm just gonna
turn up the music I got some mystic
roots band playing
[Music]
call this place enjoy I guess we'll
leave the mics on seeking here Adam cost
yeah speaking of which I gotta say big
shout out to bender and 428 coms
they've been doing it while I'm away and
held it down why I couldn't be on the
internet and stuff like that big
shout-out to you guys all the people
back out east we do not care Murphysboro
you know who you are man thanks for
listening dude half of the guys from the
just found out that I've been on you
know they just thought I was spamming
your
[Music]
to bender as well you make it up to you
get some gold and just make us call our
on the show big shout out to those guys
I mean you know which guys you were a
dad world that's okay who's gonna be
alright guys we'll just give minute
sketch up either I'm here you good good
well I mean they also they follow me on
Instagram we're sitting here with your
son and he's dab the [ __ ] out I was
wondering if you could just talk him
down a little bit
the thing is all set hearing on Kurt
people like yeah go follow and troll the
[ __ ] out of her you know on Facebook but
I don't really care you know do you want
people to troll your mom yeah that's
whatever that'd be funny it would be my
mom doesn't have any social media and
I'm glad about it
I'm pretty glad about it guys word is
ramble and we're having a personal
conversation cuz we just took dabs I'd
rather talk after just some rambles that
are incoherent trying to read the news
while I'm Chokin over a little
intermission so this is gonna go up
probably Monday I think Monday morning
how'd you guys like that bonus little
miniature episode that I put out
Thursday night was that cool or what
I've been trying to catch up it's gonna
go tonight there's one why as we're
recording I'll post another one when we
finish I know and then we'll have this
one going so we're my self this is on
Monday I'm living in the future you
living in the future all right I'm gonna
live in the now you've got social media
if you've got Facebook if he's got
Twitter if you've got YouTube if you've
watched TV in the past couple of days
you have seen the anchor lady guys
excuse my dollar on this one come on
don't charge me a dollar this one for
this one this lady went on TV and she
made a nice long speech in her speech
ended with [ __ ] it I quit you guys know
what I'm talking about right I'm gonna
read in our wonder if I could play the
video can I play the video and not get
in trouble it's on it's from the news
yeah they didn't get permission let's
turn down the music and let's try to
play this video cuz I'm gonna play a
quick video and you guys this happened
on the news and then I'll read this
story I'm not even gonna play it sorry
should give me a second guys I'm gonna
press pause we're gonna search for the
actual good quality video and I'll play
it for you hold on I owe you that much
give me a second
alright guys I'm back I did a little bit
of searching the video comes in kind of
late I should fill you in a little bit
this lady the news ran a report about
medical cannabis or cannabis in Alaska
and this lady was reporting on it and
then during her report she states that
she supports cannabis and that she
actually is the owner of the Alaska
cannabis club so this is kind of where
just to get you up to speed so that's
where she jumps in and I'll play the
video now and hopefully they don't take
it off of the servers legalizing
marijuana here in Alaska and I'll spray
this job well I have a choice so you
heard it right there the camera pops
back up to the other lady on the news
and this lady the other co-host looks
like she pissed her pants when she said
that but so this lady goes on the news
and she she's a news reporter and you
heard it right there she just said [ __ ]
it I quit live on the news so I'm gonna
get into the article it'll make a little
more sense [ __ ] it I quit
anchor explains her dramatic exit and
guys don't charge me a dollar for all of
these it's in the article I'm just
relaying the news
then I read who it's by I don't know if
I said who it's by it's by Molly Riley
from The Huffington Post I think I'm
gonna give me a dirty nasty recycled jar
to bring over here and set on your table
during these podcast just for ya just so
you feel dirty even dirty had to put it
like you have to stick it to the bottom
of the jar all right so it says a local
news the local news anchor who
dramatically quit her job on-air
following a segment on marijuana
explained her exit and a YouTube video
released Monday
Charlo Greene a reporter for Anchorage's
Katie VA announced on air that she would
be leaving her job at the TV station to
focus on marijuana legalization in
Alaska so like I said they ran the clip
about cannabis and then she says this
everything you've heard is why I the
actual owner of the Alaska cannabis club
will be dedicating all of my energy to
fighting for freedom and fairness which
begins with legalizing marijuana here in
Alaska she said and as for this job
well not that I have a choice but [ __ ]
it I quit so that's where she stirred up
a lot of controversy she in my opinion
the attention should have been on her
advocacy her support and her fight to
legalize in support of cannabis instead
she chose one wrong word on the air on
TV now and distracted it from all of
what she was trying to do she said the
word that cost me a dollar on the air on
TV so that I hadn't pointed it out that
that TV stations gonna face a fine
absolutely the FCC's gonna do something
even if it was early morning and there
was very small numbers yeah goes from
like 2500 to like can they find her and
her choice of words distracted from her
whole fight and made her kind of look
bad she could acquit on air and probably
send a better message but it wouldn't
have been heard it wouldn't have been
heard so broadly on my facebook it was
all anybody had posted all day so
apparently she she got herself popular
the way she was trying to do but I
there's also the you know I'm not saying
that the marijuana business is gonna
fail but maybe she hits a snafu and it
kind of crumbles from underneath her
maybe she trusts the wrong partner or
there's some kind of illegal there's all
kinds of things that could happen and
from here on out she's never getting a
reporting job again oh no you know
you're never getting on any kind of
cable access let alone you know making a
comedy show you know maybe that she can
come on our podcast whenever she'd like
oh there you go there's the invitation
yeah all right I'll keep going with the
article in the YouTube clip Green
explained why she believes the fight for
marijuana legalization in her home state
is so important
there comes a time in each and every one
of our lives or we must choose to
continue to spectate or stand up for
what's right she said why are Americans
arrested every 30 seconds alaskans every
4.3 hours why shouldn't aspiring someone
lose their ability to earn a higher
education to become someone they were
not meant to be and why should you lose
the ability to get public assistance in
times of struggle and need she continued
advocating for freedom and fairness
should be everybody's duty
I'm making it my life work to uphold
what America stands for truly life
liberty and the pursuit of happiness
ideals now need to be defended I agree
with her but as I've been told numerous
times throughout my life it's not what
you do it's how you do it and as hearing
it over and over again is you shouldn't
have said if you shouldna said [ __ ] you
shoulda said this you know I hear it
constantly but if that's the type that
you know I'm not the type of person to
bite my tongue especially if you cross
me and I felt like I haven't done
anything wrong so if they were gonna
fire her they were gonna fire her until
she said that she owned why she was
legit anyway she's got a backup job so
she could have just said and I since
that's probably my last report so it's
nice seeing you guys instead of I quit
yeah the opportunity to go on the news
in front of camera would you rather say
and tonight I respectfully design or
would you rather be like you suck you
suck [ __ ] it I quit yeah alright so the
last line of the article says Alaskans
are set to vote on ballot measure 2
which would legalize possession of small
amounts of marijuana for recreational
use in November Colorado and Washington
have implemented similar legislation in
the last year
they made it against the law to like
drink in separate counties that was
ballot initiative one I'm guessing a
minute ago when it was like every 30
seconds an American is rested in put in
for pot and every 4.3 minutes in four
point three hours in Alaska like get out
they're all after the Moose knuckles
[Music]
legalize possession of small amounts of
marijuana for recreational use in
November that would be freakin awesome
David give us a lot less to watch on
Alaskan State Troopers oh yeah all right
so guys tweet me what you think about
this like you know what I've seen so
much about it I know what you think
about this lady if you have more to
contribute to our conversation let me
know I'd be glad to hear it
add to it add to the conversation keep
the conversation going did she screw
herself by using the language she did or
did she actually help herself out by
using that language it's what I want to
know he's comment because see I'm on the
border of I'm down with saying [ __ ] it
quit but in all my friends who have
respectable businesses and respectable
things would be like no you really
should and that's usually afterwards you
know it's usually at this point in time
where we're talking now so you're just
about to put once I warn you you're
pretty on it I have been guilty to fail
you know you got to learn how many if
you try stuff and you do it perfectly
you're like I'm [ __ ] good at that you
have a dollar for that one but if you do
something you fail you're like boy I'm
humbled I really feel like I'll learn
how to do this right
yeah you don't learn anything the first
time you get stuff right so where'd that
article go where is it here it is
Adam actually brought this article to my
attention it's written by Jeremy P Meyer
we found this on the Denver Post calm
it says Colorado school's out millions
due to marijuana excise tax loophole
well it's not they're not out this
sounds like they had millions in their
pockets and somebody reached in and took
it out that's not the way this went
that's the way I read it yeah I read
this article it's a little misleading
but they have to do that with headlines
to get you to read it the schools did
get kind of punked a little bit but it
wasn't a loophole it was a business move
and it wasn't aimed nobody was like
let's screw the schools nobody did that
it was just what business people were
doing because it's how business was
being done at the time the law was wrote
yeah so it says a loophole built into
Colorado's marijuana system has allowed
thousands of pounds of pot to go untaxed
and has cost the state millions of
dollars that should have gone to school
construction fund in 2012 Colorado
voters overwhelmingly approved amendment
64 which among other things promised
that the first forty million dollars in
excise tax revenue would be dedicated
every year for the state school
construction fund but this year only
about ten million dollars is expected to
be raised thanks to a rule that allows
marijuana retailers to avoid paying the
tax in a one-time transfer of wholesale
pot sure sorry I declare my myface there
surely revenue will increase over time
as the industry continues to mature and
fewer license holders are able to use
the one-time tax free transfer so what
they're able to do I don't haven't read
far enough into the article here but
what they're able to do shops that have
medical marijuana are able to move it
from their medical marijuana side to the
recreational marijuana side to make it
available for everybody instead of just
medical patients but there must be a tax
paid when that happens because the taxes
are different on the medical side and
the REC side and Colorado tried to
protect the medical side a little bit by
doing this but in my opinion it has
failed so I'll continue into the article
whether the excise tax revenue will ever
reach 40 million is anyone's guess
Bishan is the amount will never be
attained as and was a pie in the sky
figure meant to attract voters if that
sounds familiar you may be remembering
the 2008 campaign for a man with 50 that
promised a hundred and eighty-two
million over five years to Community
College's from the expansion of gaming
however only twenty five point three
million has been generated through the
fiscal year 2012 to 2013 after people
are spending their money on marijuana
tax revenues would certainly grow if the
loophole that was created by regulators
to watch the industry was closed there
are still 275 license holders who could
take advantage of it according to one
source the loophole was created to make
sure enough pop would be in the retail
marketplace when doors opened on January
1st 2014
regulators allowed medical marijuana
licensees converting to retail a
one-time tax free transfer that transfer
was a big difference between Colorado
and Washington the other state that
legalized retail marijuana
and why the sorry I had to reread that
census it looked weird to me something
didn't sound right but okay that
transfer was a big difference between
Colorado was the big difference is what
it should say between Colorado and
Washington the other state that
legalized retail marijuana okay and why
the Centennial state was out the door
first
Washington had to grow its retail crop
from seed Colorado officials say nine
thousand seven hundred and eleven pounds
of medical paw was transferred tax-free
to recent retail stores four thousand
seven hundred and twenty four pounds of
medical marijuana was moved to retail
marijuana products and manufacturers an
eight thousand five hundred and seventy
six pounds of medical pot was
transferred to retail marijuana
cultivation facilities that last tranche
will be subject to the tax
once it is transferred or sold to
another marijuana establishment there
will be taxes made on this just not that
original transfer tax so it says it is
estimated the untaxed pot would have
provided three million dollars for the
state school construction fund or twice
what the fund received in the fiscal
year Cathie girp are a member of the
public school capital construction
assistance board yeah
provide the board that provides grants
for schools construction and renovation
knew the numbers were going to be low
after seeing February's receipts the
first month we were thinking we're going
to be rolling in cash she said then the
second month it was wait a minute we're
only getting fractions of what we
thought were we were going to get in
this this was not the voter intent she
said I don't think anyone who voted for
a minute
sixty four thought this would happen she
said they thought the money would go to
school kids this is coming at the
expense of kids in really needy school
districts sorry there's the Texas broken
up oddly with ads here sorry the
building excellent schools today or best
fund is a competitive grant program that
helps districts the districts with
capital construction it is able to
support projects in rural school
districts that don't have large property
bases necessary for bond projects the
best fund over the years has received
more than three hundred and eighty five
million dollars in revenue ninety
percent from the state land trust
this year the best fund is helping
construction buildings in the Edson 54
JT School District and supporting
projects and dozens of school districts
around the state for things like roof
replacements and boilers marijuana taxes
were providing less than 1% of the
program's funds or 3.1 million dollars
it would have made a big difference she
said whether there is a tax credit on
the other side there is somebody to whom
the tax credit should have gone okay
proposition double-a which was approved
by voters in 2013 mandates a 15% excise
tax on imposed imposed on unprocessed
retail marijuana but amendment 64 says
no excise taxes can be charged on pot
cultivated as medical marijuana a
transfer illogically of medically drom
pot couldn't be taxed which is the basis
for the loophole the simple solution
then is to discontinue transfers the
state doesn't need them anyway the
retail pot industry is up and running
now and doesn't need the influx of
medical pot to prop up retail stores
plus transfers disadvantage retail
growers who have to pay the tax when
medical growers don't for that one-time
swap it was never our intent to
manipulate the market said rep dan pay
bond it's correct it's a correction that
needs to be made he said also a draft
bill already had been written that would
stop the transfer after January 1st 2016
but the loophole should be closed sooner
to match the voters intent and make good
on a promise that the revenue should be
going to schools I agree and the revenue
should go to the schools but where's the
other money going like if why did he get
exempt from the schools if I understand
40 million 40 million sounds a lot just
that money they said would make 40
million in like the first
it's 48 hours maybe in total sales maybe
but what they're saying is uh this tax
that they had this tax set up this tax
was supposed to go here and the money
didn't happen because these guys found a
way to not make the money it was one
point nine point nine million dollars of
taxable money from this County alone
right all that was to go to different
places this one is the one that didn't
happen because they said this money
right here specifically was like cut the
kid down you know like in the council
was like I got a good idea that's what
I'm saying they didn't that's it wasn't
even aim to do that it's just kind of
this rule is set up to help them have
enough herb for when the shops open but
that was also they said when this
money's made it's going to the schools
but they just didn't get made nobody was
really like [ __ ] that fund [ __ ] those
kids that's two dollars nobody was
really like that it's just that's just
how it worked out that there's a way
around that
like if I told you it would be nice if
they were like all right this is we we
thought we were expecting you know maybe
a hundred million dollars for the first
year and they just said you know what
but why not you know drop that common
course [ __ ] and get on with your lives
tell the rest of the country that you
were the high ones yeah we're not gonna
do that
I kind of agree that they should change
the rule by 2016 they're right if the
shops are doing it right they don't need
to move herb around and if you draw a
medical herb it needs to be there for
the patients mmm yeah so they didn't
really purposely screw the kids out
that's just how like if I told you if
you drive around the block every day on
your work you don't have to pay the $3
toll fee mm-hmm but that three dollar
total fee goes to the skit to the school
kids still drive her on the Block he
wouldn't give a [ __ ] about three dollars
that's what they did they just drove
around the block they didn't really they
didn't go take the three bucks and stab
somebody for it and
just skip painted this speaking of this
whole taking medical and taking it
recreational I went out to the shop the
other day I won't say which one but it
was further special there was nothing on
the medical side zero and they're like
well you can choose from the
recreational there's literally four
kinds and it was all sativa heavy
seventy percent you know who knows what
they're talking fracture I know it shop
you went to and they've recently opened
up another location north of here and I
have a friend who stopped there just the
other day and they were hopping and the
place was full and had all kinds of
great [ __ ] so what they've done is
they've taken all their product they go
west location no it's full like oh oh
maybe there but they did a whole shelf
of shatter a whole bunch of new extracts
and things like that you know yeah the
shops need to get it together in my
opinion for sure I'm just saying that
affected us you know that affected us
here locally that affected me local
patients yeah that's so why that really
sucks is because as a medical on the
medical side the herb is cheaper to just
to start it's considered medicine it's
it's not even you know I I'm not gonna
lie about I have it for not strangling
my wife a little side they charge you
more then on the recreational side dad
attacks to it so let's just move the
same product from the recreational sir
from the medical side right over to the
recreational side mark it up ten bucks
an eighth more half let's half the price
it's so so yeah just mark it up way high
charge an extra tax for it and then
don't even care about the medical
patients anymore
how can a shop do that how can a
business owner do that and look his
patients his customers whoa
they give you priority over the wreck
patience that means the rec patience is
can just sit out there and have red card
patients come in come in come in and
they do and they just sit there so if
you got that's the only thing you get
though right is that red card priority
then they should take you into the red
card side and take care of you properly
Pablo they won't let him open up the
they already bought this the location
next to him had it all worked out with
the owner and the city came in and says
hold on no no no what do you mean no
we're doing banging business and that's
right there you know perfect location
and they're like you have it you're not
spreading and more of that we got enough
there's 12 of you right here yeah to
that and I'm sure to the north you have
to let me know but sure let's go in a 45
minute drive from here I'm doing one of
the dankest can we please go gasps oh I
think we're gonna go eat this place in
Manitou Springs the male factor in
Colorado Springs is amazing most amazing
veggie wrap get the veggie wrap with the
house dress if you want something hot
get that cheese deluxe the coffee the
dark roast Monta is amazing if you're
gonna drink something from their article
where did it go I have two on the screen
one of them's really long we've been
going 35 minutes I feel my throat
getting a little itchy so we're gonna do
one article and then really possibly
drive to Manitou we'll see what our
friend is doing shout out yeah shout out
to the person that introduced me to the
Mont a factor
[Music]
all right so here's another news article
this one was sent to me by our good
friend Mike who is laid out tonight Mike
hurt his back
Mike's a big dude to have a hurt back
that's gotta suck get better I was sure
here doing dabs yeah dabs would help
yeah he said he couldn't even get in his
car I mean probably wouldn't if he hurt
his back because the the longbow coughs
yeah Mike took off bro
[Music]
all right so prosecutors object to war
on weed is the title of this article
looking for someone who wrote it where's
the author on the road all right
prosecutors object to war on weed by
Chris Wiggins I probably said that wrong
but you know that's how I do stuff whoa
technical glitch there's sound like a
cutout for a second anyway all right the
prosecution objects that's one way to
put it at any rate to news stories from
the Pacific Northwest today pose an
interesting question our prosecutors
beginning to get fed up with the war on
weed the two stories are completely
unrelated I should mention one is about
a current prosecutor at the local level
and one is about a formal former federal
prosecutor making a noteworthy
endorsement neither has anything to do
with the other but both show some common
sense being applied in a refreshing ways
it's too early to call it a trend even a
regional one regional one but it
certainly is a step in the right
direction at the very least
so first the local story Seattle's
electric oh jeez Seattle's elected
prosecutor said Monday he's dropping all
tickets issued for the public use of
marijuana through the first seven months
of this year because most of them were
issued by a single officer who disagrees
with the legal pot law in a briefing to
City Council on Monday city attorney
Pete Holmes says he is moving to dismiss
approximately 100
tickets issued by the Seattle Police
Department between January 1st and July
31st his office also said it would be
seeking a refund for 22 people who have
already paid their $27 ticket so one
state to the south a former federal
prosecutor for Oregon has thrown her
support behind a ballot initiative to
legalize recreational marijuana for
adults in the state Chris Olson who
served as Oregon's chief federal
prosecutor during the Clinton
administration made the news by joining
House member Earl Blumenauer and a
former Oregon Supreme Court justice by
publicly publicly supporting the ballot
measure and here's the story I enforce
our marijuana laws but they don't work
Olson said in a statement announcing her
endorsement filling our courts and jails
has failed to reduce marijuana use and
drug cartels are pocketing all the
profits she said citing federal federal
statistics that show about 1 in 14
Oregon arrests is for marijuana
possession you know we're not the
government here in Colorado is not
bitching about the cartel really any
much anymore running pot now they're
starting to look at like you guys you
know I'm saying like the guys who take
care of patients they're like hold on
they're not just we don't have control
over everything so we need that and and
that's what it's become it's not even a
crime anymore so now they're starting to
turn into oh we're making tons of money
but how can we get just a little more
each year a little more each year
there's no worry cartels anymore the old
guys around here a lot of the old-timers
don't like to pay kind but prices you
know I mean you can get if you know the
right people you can get 1/8 the dank
weed around here for 25 bucks back in
the day those guys used to buy that
Mexican brick weed for $25 1/2 ounce and
they loved it
they only smoked a bowl of day 2 balls a
day so some kind bud would just kill
them you know - it's and they'd just be
[ __ ] but lately those guys are
calling up like the guys I used to talk
to years ago they like hey man I can't
get any decent weed because they can't
find any of their old schwag connects
anymore all that [ __ ] is gone that car
Mexican import weed is disappearing so
it's not around I've come up with that
high CBD so we got a first story here
and this is my interjection here I'm not
into the article right now the first
story here is about a prosecutor saying
that he's gonna drop tickets written by
a cop because that cops a dick and you
reported on this yeah and then we have
another person saying the laws don't
work and they state that they actually
the drug cartels are profiting so it
looks like the people are starting to
understand some people are starting to
see the light these are positive reasons
why we want to legalize cannabis so I'll
get back into the article in the first
instance this was nothing short of a
prosecutor using it using his
prosecutorial discretion to avoid
wasting a lot of time in the courts and
more importantly to rain and rain in one
police officer who was obviously on a
vendetta against the voters for passing
in law he did not personally approve of
one single police officer Brisbane was
responsible for eight out of all ten
tickets issued in the Seattle for public
in Seattle for public consumption of
marijuana during the first half of this
year the other 20% were written by the
entire rest of the police force to put
this in another way this officer wrote
one ticket he considered this officer on
one ticket row he considered the new
legalization law silly well the other
off well the officer has been reassigned
to new duties after this came to light
there are a lot of folks with cases
still in the legal system as a result of
his actions what a dick of a cop
cops don't realize what they're doing to
you when they screw you up for having
some a little bit of weed or whatever
you're doing they'll and some of them do
and they love it that [ __ ] sucks come on
guys if you're a cop some cops are
listening to the podcast I know you are
I know you're a law enforcement officer
we want to educate you about how not
dangerous cannabis is it's something
that asked us yeah I mean especially if
it's inform yourself listen to me I'm a
smart dude I'm an educated dude I'm
reading news I'm trying to educate
people I'm trying to keep people safe
people did you not just hear stoners
with words right there with ya that was
a
that was impressive smokes pot not a bad
person right yeah
in Washington State of course
recreational marijuana use is legal the
voters approve the change in state law
and the prosecutors actions quite
obviously reflect the peep the will of
the people but it didn't have to happen
this way prosecutors in general are
pretty much tough on crime types of
people and if this particular prosecutor
has agreed with the cops way of thinking
then all these cases would have
continued to clog the legal system all
the way to the bitter end
all $27 of it this prosecutor however
objected to that scenario and applied
some common sense he's even going the
extra mile and trying to refund fines
already paid that is truly commendable
that is a truly commendable action once
again reflecting the will of the voters
in legal reality the second news item
doesn't seem to deal with actual legal
cases it comes from a prosecutor who no
longer works for the federal Department
of Justice still this is a stunning
development federal prosecutors after
all are not bound by any state law and
therefore can apply federal law whether
marijuana is still the most illegal of
all drugs a where marijuana is still the
most legal of all drug illegal of all
drugs without even having to weigh in on
State Politics believe it or not there
are some extremely zealous federal
prosecutors all up and down the west
coast who are fighting tooth and nail
against any state legalization efforts
an unprecedented and creative ways so
hearing even a former prosecutor bluntly
refute the entire purpose of the federal
war on weed is a welcome development
indeed the language used is a pretty
strong condemnation of federal laws
she upheld while in office enforced our
marijuana laws and they don't work
prosecutors are practical people who
deal with the real end aftermath of
arresting marijuana users so the
argument used is not a ISM or is not a
moral one walking up marijuana users is
wrong or one of racial equality black
and brown people are treated differently
by the court system or even a political
one the public's mood is shifted instead
it's a view from the front lines of the
drug war which relies on personal
experience and applying federal laws and
the relative effectiveness of carrying
out this job I enforced our marijuana
laws and they don't work
so this person instead of just playing
by the book basically saying had we'd go
to jail had we'd go to jail had a lotta
we'd go to prison they're actually
looking at what they're doing to people
like I was saying they're saying you had
some weed human quit smoking weed here's
a fine get your [ __ ] together don't go
to prison forever don't go get butt
raped they're taking some compassion
into this finally the story and that's
all you nine times out of ten you got to
do yeah you know when you're going to
court and stand in front of the judge
everybody just kind of pushes you behind
your lawyer or public detent pretender
you know sitting there and that's the
they say you have your day but a lot of
times they just ask you if you
understand and it's a yes or no question
is all you really get so it's good
they're finally starting to be like what
did you have you know yeah so all right
so of all the pro legalization arguments
this could perhaps be the strongest one
the laws don't work they don't have the
intended effect the feds have been
fighting the war on weed for almost a
century now with precious little to show
for it
yeah and in fact they have severe
unintended consequences joke cartel drug
cartels are pocketing all of the profits
therefore mindlessly continuing on the
same course is nothing short of madness
I think that's what they call insanity
Chris Wilson is not the first law
enforcement officer to have this
revelation and begin publicly trying to
change the situation an entire
organization already exists Law
Enforcement Against Prohibition or leap
for members of the law enforcement
community past and present to advocate
the marijuana legal reform many members
are former cops who have first-hand who
saw firsthand how pointless the entire
war on wheat truly was throughout their
careers now free to the prospect of
ending their career over a public
statement many are speaking out on the
subject their message is a simple one
prohibition didn't work and prohibition
of marijuana isn't working either Chris
Olson is to be commended for raising her
own prosecute prosecutorial objection
and for knowing her public support
behind a ballot measure in the state
where she used to uphold the law the
personal connection to the state ballot
might convince a few voters even though
even tough-on-crime types that the sorry
let me move this page it's all scrolling
on its own there we go
where were we all the rest of the
arguments aside the law needs changing
because it doesn't work it does nothing
sure of waste time for the entire
judicial system for something which
shouldn't even be illegal in the first
place the Oregon ballot measure race may
be closed near Washington and Colorado
legalized recreational marijuana Oregon
had a similar but badly written
initiative on its ballot it failed this
time around the effort is a lot more
serious but reliable polling on the
subject isn't a Tory ously hard to do so
the vote might be very close in November
guys if you're in Oregon when this comes
up go vote to legalize cannabis so
pro-legalization groups will be very
closely watching the vote this year in
Oregon and Alaska and Washington DC so
assuming Lee assumably sorry my throat's
burning out I'm trying to go fast
assumably they'll also be closely
watching the impact of Olson simple the
laws don't work message Olson's message
is a powerful one because it could reach
voters not generally open to other
pro-legalization arguments if you're a
law and order type of voter a formal
former federal prosecutors opinion
should carry some weight in other words
perhaps more prosecutors both state and
federal both current and former can be
enlisted in this movement as I said it
is far too early to call this any sort
of trend but it certainly is a
development worth taking note of Dan on
the legal theme we began on perhaps new
voters will sustain these prosecutors
objections and you can follow chris on
twitter this was written by chris chris
Wigand at chris we get w EIG NT very
well-written article make sure you
follow him on twitter thanks for letting
me read your stuff man people are
catching on it looks like it for sure
it's glad to see the people or just open
for debate at least yeah and maybe like
they said maybe now that the state has
melted the older people don't want to
hear from you and me then weed is
harmless
cannabis is helpful that medical
marijuana will help you people don't
want to hear that but if you're a farmer
if you're a former from the Fed then
they have to listen to you because
you're obviously not full of [ __ ] oh
well at least they should trust you
because you're the one been feeding them
the [ __ ] for the best you know however
many years so well now what do we
believe do we believe all the [ __ ]
that you told us for many many years or
do we believe your new [ __ ] soon as
we start believing the new [ __ ] from
the person that used to be like
ex-military then we're crazy right along
with them you know I'm saying they just
label us as that they do you know yeah I
don't know if you guys heard their
quotations but they were there so
whatever man that's just crazy I hope or
we can get to going cuz they you guys
got so much talent I mean I've only seen
from social media and stuff like that
but I've seen people up that way just
you're right between two mecca's you
know like there's you can't go wrong
you'll be the perfect blend and I got
many respectable people up there already
under medical coma think coma may have
moved well yeah this is for wreck we'd
also so let's get the wreck weed going
on it doesn't always have to be medical
all right let's wrap up this show bro
we've been going for a long time it
sounds like we're gonna go get some dank
food over at the mate' factor I wrote
down some shoutouts and people we want
to follow make sure you follow I'll say
it again make sure you follow I grow
culture on Twitter and Instagram follow
over grow the Gov on Twitter and
Instagram follow
I read genetics on Twitter and Instagram
a big shout out to the mystic roots band
for letting me play their music I think
that's all I got for shoutouts today
yeah all right we'll do this part now
that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
agriculture find the review section give
me a five star rating after that type in
a comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
future episode I'm not joking you guys
leave comments I will read them I like
you I like the input like I said follow
us on social media Instagram Twitter and
Facebook you can email me if you'd like
it's a I grow culture at hotmail.com
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher and every single
episode is archived forever on IRA
genetics Colorado dot-com big shout out
to my ninja Spence thanks again to
everybody they listened to the show take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
here's some some mystic roots Bing
[Music]
tell me
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 33 of the
iGrow culture podcast they call me Rasta
Jeff and I will be your captain for this
mission on TV huge shot that's a hydro
you listening to the secret Cup anthem
by hydro the secret cup was in Denver
this weekend and our boy Spitz from the
garden of Weeden took called first place
in the secret cup mountain region coming
up in just a couple of minutes I'll have
an interview with Spence but first this
podcast was brought to you by a highly
educated titanium if you're dabbing
high-quality concentrates you deserve a
high-quality titanium nail don't trust
the Chinese nail or an American knockoff
made of cheap metals trust the industry
leader trust highly educated titanium
more info on highly educated titanium
products visit www.gfi.com/webmonitor
screen remedies com4 gauge green
genetics lopata labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can adventure IRA
genetics and many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners saipin
coupon code harvest 14 for 15% off any
order and he always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com once
again that coupon code is harvest 14
this podcast is also brought to you by
high grow indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street unit F or stop by the new pub
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies want
to send Big Love to our friends at tree
hugger com this episode is brought to
you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews walk out at the cookout
with tree hugger dot-com much love and
respect to all the sponsors for making
the show possible
spits over and we did a great interview
so I'm not gonna waste much more time
with an intro let's get right to the
interview part here we go
[Music]
alright ladies and gentlemen we are back
and we're hanging out with the winner of
the secret cup Mountain Regional we got
our buddy from the garden of Weeden it's
Spencer how you doing today buddy I'm
doing good brows just told that there's
a garden of Weeden song written by our
boy sloppy and it is freakin sweet your
song at the show thanks for permission
in the future it's all Spence
so thanks for joining me on the show bro
[Music]
so Spence is the winner of the mountain
region secret cup some people might not
be familiar with the secret cup so let's
take a little bit to tell them what that
is oh the secret cup is a it's actually
a tour which they go to different places
they go to places in Cali if I'm correct
I don't know if it's ever been put that
way as a tour because that would be a
hell of a marketing way to put some
shirts out here maybe Michigan not sure
Arizona
Rhode Island and then all that it's
basically a competition of anywhere from
30 to 40 hash makers all in ER a certain
amount of product and then each one of
the people that enter are considered
judges because we all receive a judge
pack go through them and kind of give
everything a score from smell you know
strength smoothness harshness color
flavor you know lunch so each contestant
actually gets 0.3 of every sample right
yeah you get to taste what everybody
else has a good thing about is you know
it's not being judged by just you know
random people or like
just it's not a most technically is a
blind judge there's nobody gets to see
what you know yeah so it's all just
numbered and whatever numbers are what
you vote for so when you got your
judge's kid how long did it take you to
find your your entry like two minutes
two minutes yeah yours you just had a
lot of taste I just in trees and kind of
just smell and I make the hash you kind
of get attached I guess you could say
you find it it's perfect yeah that's it
I could tell my flowers sorry guys I'm
all choked up actually I went to the
secret cup for two days and took a
amazing amount of dabs and then today I
would hang out some friends in Denver
and my lungs and throat are burnt out
from dab and you guys got a hydrate if
you're dabbing that's something that I'm
learning more hydration Spence reaches
for the water as I say that we're all
red eyed and throat dried so yeah
everybody got to I had the honor of
tasting a couple of my friends were
judges and entrance contenders I don't
know what the hell they were called they
were judges and they entered and I got
to taste parts of their sample packs
some were amazing some I don't think I
would take a second dad loved a lot of
those yeah I mean there's definitely
there was 38 competitors in this one so
38.3 you've got to go through and you
know it's kind of tough depending on
which kind of what kind of like I'm a
wheat snob so I'm definitely gonna be an
oil snob you know I'm saying so it's
just a lot of it's personal preference
whether or not you like it this way you
like it that way so it's kind of that's
why it's good that were the judges
because it's at least honest opinions I
wanted to wait a little bit to get into
live resin but I was worried with you
entering live resin people were gonna
say it's not stable because the popular
[ __ ] the rage is shattered and the live
resin is not chattery at all it's kind
of it looks like it's loyal yeah it's
like you know it's I think somebody said
66 degrees is when it actually gets
it'll shatter if you're if your house is
66 degrees you like your house cold
you'll have chattery live residence
but it's almost that in here tonight
it's getting nice and cool Alvarado
temperatures are changing like this oil
is cool right now it's chilly um hey
thanks dude the other day you gave me a
little sample of Earl and I didn't even
realize that I've been dabbing off of
the entry I've been dabbing the winter
hair for several days thank you tasty so
in a second we'll talk about what's in
that the event we kind of talked about
what it is the people that enter the
judges we every buddy gets to taste the
entries so that's what it's all about
and Spence was actually chosen as the
overall champion there's a couple of the
things I want to talk about there was
two location changes I was if not if you
could probably count three yeah switched
twice I want to give a huge shout out to
Big D right now Big D was smart enough
he hired a professional event company
who hired hired the right event services
group right event groups or something
you know what I mean the right group I
was in charge they booked and secured a
location as they got there and started
to set up they were told that they were
not allowed to do the event there Big D
is smart enough to where he just made
another phone call and said hey
everybody go to location number two he
had a second spot lined up unfortunately
ah that got shut down also so I think AJ
hashman made a couple of phone calls and
a couple of emails were sent and the
lazy lion sorry about the coffee can
guys I'm really sorry that sucks to do a
podcast with that I bet it sucks to hear
the lazy lion and the speakeasy vape
lounge volunteered to let the secret cup
come have their party there they already
had [ __ ] booked for that night they
cancelled it and they came and are they
let us come and have a huge party
they're so big shout out to Big D hey J
hashman and everybody involved with the
speakeasy and the lazy lion that was
super cool a lot of the vendors packed
right on up and came with them most of
the booths were full
most of the artists came saturday was a
little a little kind of bear but Sunday
it was pretty crowded yes crowded just
depending on what time of the day it was
yeah
the speakeasy was pretty neat I was able
to get into the speakeasy the lazy lion
was actually the
P Lounge so I didn't have my VIP badge
so I couldn't go in there yeah it's the
by far have the heaviest glass
collection I've seen ever have you ever
seen what is it Joe Peters queen bee
it's like huge like I saw the picture
that Matty posted of it that piece is
like I did with a goldfish it's not to
smoke with a big bass and it's a betta
fish actually I said goldfish into beta
that's pretty novel yeah yeah I'm
surprised no it's not of that before all
right so the places and people that made
that happen
let's talk about your entry now your
entry was live resin do you want to tell
the people what strain it was or are you
kind of oh it's already out its own
energy from us in city seat um and it
was mixed with Scott Shoji from air tank
this classy mix yeah yeah the synergy
was a kosher cush dominant yeah Scott 2g
was just an awesome og nice it was
definitely the lanky very very not super
tall but it was you know taller than I
would usually like plans to be but um
super fuel II a heavy indica just you
know awesome resin production and a
pretty decent yield err - oh that was
the one I mix with the sins which was a
kosher dominate which the Sensoji is
blue power and kosher fish
so there was a kosher kosher kosher
dominant um FINA I just had a way better
kosher like burnt rubber is she smell
which comes out in hash as an OG smell
it's got a few li functionally has a few
li funk to it it's delicious
I smoked a lot of sativas because like
you said I'm a sativa breeder I smoke a
lot of the sativa or a lot of sativa in
this indica kind of dominance in here it
really sits me down it makes my eyes
droopy I really appreciate it it's
really not a really nice cross what's
got the citrusy spice to it what's that
and that there's like sort of a spice to
the end it's almost got a lemony citrus
it comes from the Scot okay like that oh
gee pine this and sometimes the pond can
transfer over to like a citrusy lemon um
so was a very it was a good strain you
knows a phenol huh out of you know I ran
a pack and I kept you know three or four
of them and you know there's three or
four of them in the room and I got to
pick which ones I wanted it's really
cool being able to actually go in pick
one flavours a lot of a lot of the
people who would you know like thanks to
this person for let me get the product
you know and it was cool for us cuz I
don't have to ask anybody for products
all comes from us all in-house is great
it's good you know I've seen it's good
to know that it's a clean safe garden
where my medicine comes from I get a lot
of my comes straight from you guys I'm
kind of picky about where I'll get it
you guys are the first people I go to
when I need medicine how do you uh when
you're looking in the room what makes
you say that strain in that screen right
over that plant and that plant right
there or gonna make award-winning oil um
honestly it's more of just you kind of
literally go plant to plant and just you
know you can't you can't do it in the
day it kind of takes you know a week or
two you know as they're finishing to be
able to tell which flavors are gonna
come through
Oh
[Music]
I was only ever think I was gonna do I
made another batch the green ribbon
batch um but the green ribbon just
didn't carry it the same like when you
feel some plants you know how they're
like some plants like super sticky where
you touch them and then your fingers are
stuck together and there's some you
touch and you get like the string penis
present and then there's some you touch
where it's like just wet where you don't
even it's like slick uh-huh
so you just kind of go and look for
different you know okay for me it's a
lot about flavors so I like to you know
your hash is always flavorful I had a
bunch of your shatter with me and the
secret Cup and everybody I would out we
go that's tasty yeah and some cookies
that you made I've got some cookies you
did a while back I've got it on secrets
- secrets - hey shut up - somehow he got
to me some solvent less ash that tastes
pretty damn good right on bro good work
[Music]
so we talked a lot about live resin on
this show I am NOT a hash maker
everybody tells me that I've always got
great hash they complement it I gotta
say I don't make hash I know a lot about
making hash because a little keV bro is
my buddy you're my buddy I know how to
read the internet tells you all about
making dabs if you want to know I like
to be educated but I don't make hash
I've been trying my best to describe
live resin to people a lot of people
have asked about it after you exhale
that [ __ ] monstrous dab I owe a
dollar for that one I owe a dollar every
time I say the f-word on the show yeah
will you teach me and our listeners a
little lesson about what live resin is
and kind of how it's done
okay so everybody's heard of fresh
frozen bubble hash so basically where
you harvest your plant you essentially
freeze it or flash freeze it um and then
for ice hash you'd you know wash it in
your bags or whatever so now instead of
you know as far as opening blasting I
know people who do it live resin but I
think it's what the closed closed loop
game came out and we figured out you
could do that same process in a closed
loop at a bigger scale it completely
changes patched for the better in my
opinion I think so if done proper that
one he's taking plants that are ready
for harvest chop them down freeze them
in the deep freeze and then put them in
a closed loop butane extraction system
which we'll talk more about that
I think Kevin and I have talked about
that but there's open blasting and
closed loop Spence uses a closed loop
method and blasts the fresh frozen like
that does it need to be vacuumed first
after that yeah once it comes to Mew
it's really you know it takes a lot of
the butane out before you even get to
touch the product so it pumps it out
because it takes all the liquid back out
you know so then you're left which is
your product um as far as you know
flavors I really think it keeps a better
term profile it honestly if you can
alright so this is gonna be kind of hard
to understand but it tastes like it
smells when it's growing if you could
understand what you know you touch a
plant and you smell your fingers that
crazy smell you get that it doesn't ever
smell like that once it's dried and
cured but once you when you're stripping
or making hash from a fresh product you
get that fresh flavor it's like if your
bud was approved and you took a bite out
of that fruit that's what this hash
tastes like yeah and I love it
de turpan annoyed and that's the other
profile in there and that's just not
everyone's one new word now is Terps
terpstra yeah so I just feel like an
[ __ ] every time I say Terps but the
Terps in that is trippy Slurpee it's
just like a big it's like a bite of
candy every time you hit a dab it
literally like it could be desert one
somebody needs to make some Jillybean
life resin oh don't worry there's do
this crazy that crisis a blueberry Sour
Diesel that sounds ridiculous doesn't it
sounds delicious
yeah yeah I made cookies live it was we
got across some tangi and some grateful
dog
see the tangerine dog the look on your
face tangerine dog I've been writing
down strained names guys if you have
neat straight names you can feel free to
tweet those to me at microculture I
might use one of them I might send you a
pack of it when I make it if I remember
and if I can find you to eat but yes
saliva is basically you know from fresh
frozen vho just I think it's a more
flavor goes into an oven after you know
you're extracted from your system
because your system takes pretty much
good majority of it out so but she still
got to go through your vacuum process to
you know keep cleaning and removing
certain gases stuff like that do you
know do you do anything special to your
plants or flowers uh if you know you're
gonna make oil out of them for live
resin was it 48 hours of dark before but
no I really think with this far is live
it's all about the product you put in
you know the better you know the flowers
that are going in the better the oils
gonna come out so no trim run in this
room right yeah I'll pass no trim run
honestly from my trim like my personal
stuff I still open blast it and I'll
make it it's even smoke and shatter I
can tell the difference in oak and Earl
nug run and trim run yeah definitely you
can taste once you start smoking live
you can taste the difference between if
it's in a closed loop and if it's not in
the closed loop I feel super spoiled now
that I smoke so much like it's a good I
find myself hiding my live like just
over here and we can smoke this shatter
all day the live resin I'll bark at you
like a dog if you get in there
yeah all right so a little bit more
about the secret cup stuff dude you're a
freaking champion now bro you are a
secret cup winner has it sunk in yet
oh no well what's funny is about this is
I went to what was it secret cup last
year when they had it in Denver with a
couple buddies of mine and that was like
right when I was really first getting
into really making like oil like more
than just you know every now and then um
and I remember telling everybody I was
like dude we're gonna enter this Cup
next year and we're gonna win it and
then you know a year later we [ __ ] oh
my bad you could say whatever you want
I'm just trying not to say [ __ ] that's
another dollar actually every time I say
it I owe a dollar to a charity so
[Music]
as I said we were gonna win it and we
came out and you know brought I think we
came real proper and a lot of the
differences between I think which I
don't speak for everybody you know
because I don't you know I don't know
everybody that competed but like we
didn't have to source our product we
were able to actually go pick it and I
think that made a difference different
flavor being able to pick certain
flavors and knowing what you want - you
know it was just easy I would I would
hate to have to go source you know
changes find something that's good
enough to actually have a guy that comes
straight to me for his material yeah
he's always like bro for sure for sure
home and then I grow weed first before I
make hash so you know it's it's a lot
different when you spend ten weeks with
the plant and then make hash instead of
buying it off the shelf and making hash
with it it's a lot more full circle yeah
um which is important to us because we
say it's grown by us process bus and
seed to live resin to a cup yeah nice
that's that's super awesome so it's it's
cool it's been a fun experience hasn't
really I don't know if it's sink in
because I wasn't you know honestly I
went in with thinking I was gonna have a
top-three finish that's just how I'm
just competitive I hate losing um so it
was cool being able to go in I almost
thought I lost once they did all the
awards and in third second I was like oh
no we didn't win that's something I
wanted to ask you I they did they did
like highest CBD they did best Terps
they did crowd choice or something like
that
and then they do third second and then
Big D said so first place and he said
something to the equivalent of you guys
already know who it is and I was like oh
then it's probably somebody that's
already gotten an award yeah that's what
I assumed but then he said Garden and as
soon as he said Garden I think I peed a
little
I was like wow
he went through and did second place and
it was the bubble which the boat was far
I'll give it that you know I'm saying um
I didn't even know it was bubble that
want
yeah the solvent less bubble but I
looked at Mattie and I was like we might
not win I wasn't thinking I was gonna
win so like my speech was super like
short and to the point I guess you could
say it was it was perfect you said
something about where you're from this
is illegal so it's great to be here with
all these people making hash and
celebrating and we're sure that's pretty
dumb pretty awesome you didn't know
you're gonna win you know I think we
really just put in everything we had
into the competition so it paid off for
us there any other samples that stood
out there was kind bills you know shout
out to counting bill for you know coming
up with the live resin tech bill who one
third is actually the dude who came up
with love resident nice guy there's some
guys out here doing you know my same
technique that are killing it um I'm
gonna say he was regarding me his was on
point he did it it was sour D deep chunk
and Gorilla Glue I think it was just it
was really good but it was just too
complex it wasn't like straight to the
not straight to the point but just
there's like the glue and the sour
almost the same thing and the deep chunk
is I think a Sour Diesel deep shock or
something like that it's just a
perfectly strange I think if you would
have done
the sour Dean the glue would have been a
hole it would came out a whole lot
better in my opinion I think the flavors
would have pulled through just that sour
with
was it saint gorilla glue acrylic glue
is basic for the old school sours I'm
like a big gorilla cool it was a
ridiculous plant bro yeah some crazy
[ __ ] I've got one growing right now you
gotta tie it down and it will break the
tie downs it's like no I literally had
worn the head I think it started with
three tops literally just as it would
girl we're just super crop each top down
and then now it has like a teen top's
have a 10-gallon girl that has 25 stakes
in it I'm gonna have to take a plant out
of the room or something because these
two gorillas glues are taking more space
than I completely predicted yeah yeah
yeah and I read the cross too and I'm
not surprised that it's so killer now
that I know what is it Kim yeah yeah
that's what made me thinking that you
were talking about the chocolate I'm
taking a DAB so you gotta talk for a
second everybody who made the drive from
Denver to the springs to go dad like
that is so true not a lot of people you
know can say hey let's go drive an hour
down the street or down this beautiful
damn state we live in and go dab with
every all of our friends even even the
people we don't know that we're all you
know nobody's the best thing about our
type of advances there's no rowdiness
there's no drunk people around getting
mad and trying to fight you know it's
just people high and kickin it which is
right down my alley there's you one are
actually the award started in the the PA
system was kind of shitty yeah and
nobody could hear so everybody just
moved right up to the front you had a
rig a Toro rig sitting on a table a rig
a torch and a little piece of shadow
just sitting on the table you left that
[ __ ] I left it we all walked away left
it sitting on the table I found it there
an hour later just sitting there
nobody touched it all the shadow was
still there perfectly intact good
yeah you know you don't have to worry
about things like the good community for
sure dude you got a big old box of
prizes I saw a torch with shaped like a
cup like a cannabis cup looking thing
yeah it's a it's a vector torch that has
like a Cup trophy on it that has a gold
dragon wrapped around it and it says
like first place
that's just seeker cup on the back and
then inside that Cup it's filled with
like that looks like live so we'll call
it live just you know looks like a bunch
of oil but she was pretty sick I got the
torch
I got a rig from monsters glass company
if correct me if I'm wrong I'm sorry
it's a sticker has like a little puppet
flip disc in the bottom which it came
with like a matching pendant which
dependants huge it's a dope pendant
matching dabber
let's do be good there was a box of
stuff I'm glad you had Big Mike with you
that's what Mike was toting that box
around like a toilet that's what was in
there the rig new email in there oh I
got that from it was in the box but that
was a part of the prize and do you know
rocks nice made those shout out to you
for that because it might you know it's
gonna be in the corner getting dusty now
so got a pretty sweet grass roots hat
yeah and that prize box was huge you
know so there's so much worse you know
giving up you know 20 grams alive which
is you know I could keep that and smoke
for a while you get to spend two days
with Madi around brother that's like 20
days where the dad she dabs
but she doesn't yeah she gets high but
then she like take another DAP and get
on high and then she wants to take
another tab because she thinks she's
unhand then now she's high again it's
cool she wants Matty for sure keep davon
keep dabbing that prize box was sweet so
now you get to go to Vegas
yeah is that these semifinals are the
finals Vegas is the final vegas so it's
the top three from every place on the
tour that's how popular you gotta be
back we're talking about Vegas I'm gonna
have to think about going to Vegas in
Vegas every house is nice it's not just
like there's only one street that has
nice house
we uh so we're looking into like getting
a house for like a week cuz I guess I
don't know how long everybody's gonna be
there but if we're gonna get it we'll
get it for a week
that sleeps like ten people they all
have every house has a pool and
backyards so just go to I'm not gonna
I might party like one or two nights I
lose too much money you can get a house
I got a six bedroom house for a week for
like nine hundred bucks for the week oh
yeah so that's like 75 bucks a person
yeah
I'm Gucci with yeah we can we can afford
[Music]
somewhere in December what are the weed
laws like in Vegas we look like we need
to get pulled over if we're in Vegas
yeah yeah I'm flying there if I go I'm
not driving to Vegas well no you got a
draft of Utah or some [ __ ] no Arizona
yes see just get on a plane like an hour
later you're in Vegas I guess we're fine
I guess
Battier fine get your tickets now it'll
be cheap what I got dogs you'll be gone
for less time if you fly you don't have
to waste all that 14 hours worth of
driving
what are you take care of Sirach and
Donna is in December its top three from
every you know spot on the tour that's
such a good tour the secret time so it's
a competition that one is the champ is
the gets the gold I don't care but I
want that the pro-wrestling looking belt
how many winners have there been before
you I know there was
Brian Skipton was one year another year
okay well shout out to the previous
winners I said Mortimer says that the
always yeah so what else have you one
bro um you've been talking about this
thing you do on Thursdays Thursdays in
Denver at 7:10 in social lounge all for
Colfax Thursday night they do a
top-shelf Thursday's it's uh right now
we're in the process of a 16 person
extract tournament basically so it's
bracketed um so I won my quarterfinals
on Thursday before this week um so now
into the I'm one of four did you enter
the same material oh no I did a the
Cindy LePew killing it with different
[ __ ] even yeah um seen you a few times
freedom baby just awesome floral just
goodness and then I did that green
ribbon live sugar or whatever people
call I felt a sugar because it's not
like a butter butters like wet in paste
it does it almost looks like bubble hash
almost yeah so so tasty you know it's
awesome so yeah so we do that and then
I'm into the semis
so there's
two more rounds into the finals or in to
make the other side of the bracket so
it's I think it's me and kind bill kind
bills in gosh it and me and then there's
like four other people that are fighting
for the last two spots oh that's pretty
cool so I've won two of those and then
won the secret Cup you won the Super bud
bowl i won
nothing like Super Bowl okay in any of
those closet Growers Cup events no a lot
of my stuff I grow so if it's not timed
perfectly to where I can take stuff out
of my garden I usually don't enter which
is cool yeah which is now I've got ten
weeks to get all the flavors I want to
do for the Cup ready to go it's perfect
because I have just the right amount of
plants that are just big enough they're
out girl in their threes now so they're
ready to go into other like teens or so
just finish from now to dance and I'll
be able to pick what I want when I want
it much flavors we want to do stoked to
see what you enter yeah I get the
privilege Vince calls me up and he's
like brah
I just ran like seven batches alive I
need your expertise I don't know what to
enter that go over there and the heat up
to email and Maddie passes me dads they
won't tell me what they are but they
just watch my reaction and then I go
that one bro no it was definitely a good
experience being able to you know it's
good for you know I'm not from Colorado
I moved here so like it's cool cuz I got
called my parents that you know I just
want this hash competition mom my mom's
like what what does that mean so it's
good to know that my friend like I'm
actually you know progressing you know
I'm getting further into the scene I
guess the weed scene
[Music]
so it's cool being able to know that out
of what 38 people from Colorado or came
to Colorado in your hash I had the best
hash that's not just 38 random people
that should invite only you have to get
like the secret it's like kumite you
can't just show up it was a private
party for sure private party so what's
uh what's next for the the garden of
Weeden Vegas other than crush in Las
Vegas and taking home the belt and
bringing it to Pueblo Colorado for sure
to get all dusty a lot of people
traveling you know different networking
stuff this year a couple different
places to let people experience live and
kind of you know get people to show that
hey there's another form of hashim on
the map that take this to the other
legal states there's a couple people
that I talk to you know through social
media networking that you know hopefully
if it works out I it would be awesome
we're kind of just doing our thing we
don't really you know especially here in
Colorado it's such a legal scene you
have to you know you've got to have
money I'm just the guy that lives you
know makes good hash you know so that's
you know you know a business or
something like that in our future but
right now we're just you know I agree to
that
for sure I agree to that but that's a
great way to wrap up this little
interview with the champion well I'm
telling you the champion already [ __ ]
you're the champion why mine bro you're
gonna win that [ __ ] I got faith in you
thanks for coming to the show you got
anybody you want to give any shoutouts
to or anything like that
lady sloppy nah nice Rock Harvey bein
[Music]
Big Mike who's broke his iPhone talked
about that broke his brand-new phone he
just got a week ago that's really about
it shout-out to everybody that supports
our genetics garden weed anybody that's
doing something you know positive
shout-out to y'all
yeah big shout-out to everybody that's
growing their own we're gonna do
gardener weddings gonna be sponsoring an
epilepsy fundraiser in Denver into
November I think so I'll try to get some
more information about that which will
be you know it'll be our first time
actually going to an event like this and
kind of you know being out and the more
not necessarily hippie crowd but you
know just kind of being more in the
medical side hang out with these kids
you know this stuff saves our lives like
there's a kid heard was a team landing
yeah yeah I actually got to meet a buddy
of mine who makes all the oil form all
the CBD stuff his oil tested what was it
like 40 40 percent CBD knows the little
di K or Landon I'll be like hey mommy I
need my candid vision make me feel
better you know it's cool so we're gonna
go there and support you know the other
side of being free in the cannabis
industry you know just being able to
actually help people which is you know
cool for us giving back to people who
need it
gotta pay it forward for sure the
medical is what started this for us we
can't forget them no not at all if it
was
for the people who needed for medical
reasons the people who don't need it for
medical reasons wouldn't be smoking it
legally at least that's the truth
for sure dude thanks thanks a lot for
coming we'll have you back make sure you
go follow garden of Weeden it's garden
of weed and on Instagram Facebook are
you full on Facebook yet no but it's
coming 5,000 followers try to get in
there before he fills up so what you got
there's a checkout sloppy nine one nine
on YouTube and check out the garden of
Weeden song I'll post it I'll post a
link to it on my I'll be back in just a
second to wrap everything up alright
guys I want to thank Spence once again
for coming back and I want to thank you
for listening to the show only give a
bunch of shout outs before we wrap up I
want to give a shout out to John from
medicine man also shout out to AJ
hashman huge shout out to Big D none of
this event would have been possible
without Big D I want to give a big
shout-out to hydro thanks for performing
the secret cup anthem song for me right
before the awards that was dopest [ __ ]
also big shout-out to our dear friend
Jessica much-loved de kerbside
concentrates zet free tokahana sand
Justin from a 64 magazine also a big
shout-out to my friend Robert and his
wife Anita what's up guys it was great
to see at the show much love to J dizzle
j-dub and the weed pimp true Colorado
bearded dabbers shoutout to call me Big
Mike Madi of course shot at the Spence
in the whole garden of Weeden crew fish
Phil Stephanie also shoutout to Claude
and Melissa from sweet stone candy big
shout-out to grass roots shout-out to
Nexus creations and of course the lazy
lion and the speakeasy vape lounge I
also need to send some love to the real
OG Cushman need to send love to task
Julie dread white Mike the grimy Gatsby
DJ nicotine natural mystic cannabis
caregivers and cockroach 7 1 9 I want to
send a huge shout-out to sloppy nine one
nine I'm gonna play the garden of Weeden
song from sloppy make sure you go check
that out on youtube search for sloppy
nine nine
all right so now we'll wrap up the show
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
Agriculture find the review section give
us a five star rating after that type in
a comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I'll read your comments
on a future episode Citra listeners you
guys can do the same and I will read
your comments make sure you follow us on
Instagram Twitter and Facebook Instagram
and Twitter is at agriculture Facebook
is simply I grove culture you can email
me i grow culture at hotmail.com make
sure you follow
I read genetics on Instagram don't
forget to the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is available on I region etics Colorado
com I have started slowly uploading each
episode to youtube so you'll be able to
find cheesy videos there if it's easier
for you to watch the show on YouTube
thank you guys for listening to the show
once again big thanks to Big D thanks
everybody to hung out at the secret Cup
this weekend and made it a good time big
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening
take phat dab give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
grab your podcast world it's time for
episode number 34 the hydro culture
podcast in this episode my friends Jesse
and Mike join me for conversation about
some proposed changes in our local
cannabis laws but before we get that far
this podcast is brought to you by highly
educated titanium if you're using
high-grade concentrates you deserve a
high grade titanium nail don't trust the
Chinese nail art American knockoff made
of cheap metals trust the industry
leader trust highly educated titanium
for more information on highly educated
products visit www.gfi.com/webmonitor
screen remedies com4 gauge green
genetics apply to labs sin city rare
dankness mile high can adventure I read
genetics and many more trusted brands
nature's green remedies is running a
special for our podcast listeners type
in coupon code harvest 14 for 15% off
any order and you always get free
shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com this podcast is brought to you
in part by hydro indoor growing supplies
I grow indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street unit
F or stop by the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies parts
of the show are also brought to you by
tree hugger comm tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger comm for concert and festival
news and reviews
WWWE thicker calm big love and much
respect to all the sponsors you guys go
follow those companies and make sure you
let them know that you're listening for
the hydro culture podcast I had a great
long discussion with Mike and Jesse it
starts off with some random chatter I
decided to hit record in the show so
without further ado here comes the
podcast so six years ago Mike and I were
employed at a dispensary together I was
mostly the dude in charge I managed I
thought I applied for the job with you
and then like I was told you weren't the
manager and then you were them and I
don't know that place had structure
issues right yeah yes definitely
I was hired well I was I was hired as
the guy there to help transplant you
kept the place from like wandering away
like the customers from like carrying
the furniture off and the employees
showing up on time and not stealing
everything there were there were a lot
of chiefs and no Indians like I was
straight up with the boss was like dude
you were a great pot grower you're a
good man you've got a good business but
honestly you have no idea how to run a
damn business and he kind of laughed at
me the way that he did he's a southern
guy and he's real laid-back so he just
chuckled at me huh you might be right
about that and he handed me the keys to
the shop and he said here you have a
dispensary and see what it's like
[Music]
I pretty much had a dispensary we rocked
that place we did I had days over
$10,000 in sales and one day I think of
it as the time I had the best job ever
that was the wild wild west it was
wonderful it was it was crazy it was
definitely the Wild West kids coming in
with quarter pounds and backpacks and
[Music]
edibles at the beginning how they tasted
at the bud bar so they to be fair we
usually smoke joints upstairs away from
the customer services but there was
plenty of I was reckless and just
smoking joints because it was the rules
there were no rules everybody had a
medical marijuana card we could be
smoking medical marijuana so there were
19 things to worry about right so we're
all in there smoking and customers are
coming people would show up and be like
hey do you want to check out this Sour
Diesel that I grew and be like I sure do
and then they'd offer it to you I'll
give it to you for this much a quarter
pound and I'd be like what do you see
what we sell it for and eight so you got
to give me a deal on that and then we'd
get a good price together and we'd start
selling that person's quarter pounds NIF
so the good old days
[Music]
every employee had something on this
shelf that they had arranged and had a
little profit cut of I remember that I
was little infused candies yeah I of
course had herb on the Shelf that I was
growing a lot of white rhino and cherry
widows so I would take my quarter pound
that I grew in my basement and take that
to work sell it to the boss essentially
for a specified price and then gonna do
hourly rate to stand there and say
it'll sell out sooner so I could bring
another quarter pound a little more the
boss would come to you at the end of the
day it'd be like great job we want more
of that for you bud yeah one of the
benefits of having that job was I got to
see a lot of cannabis and one thing I
got one day off every week they made
sure to give me after a while we heard
more people I got two days off week but
I had one day off a week and I would
spend that one day I would drive to
another city and not be the dispensary
employee I would go in as a customer to
his mini shops as I could and just go do
recon work at all these dispensaries and
see what they had to offer and see how
their shops are set up see what who's
working there see what the bud tenders
know because I wanted I'm always that
guy if I'm doing something I want to be
really good at it the best so I always
go to see what the best looks like you
know let's go try to see what I want to
do and also learn what I do not want to
do because I saw a lot of ways to do it
wrong you can smell that musty hay
improperly cured and dried cannabis
smell in the waiting room right and
you're like I just want to leave I can
already tell that this is gonna be be
great product right I got my feet wet of
growing commercial cannabis in one of
those places so how how challenging is
it to go from being an outdoor grower to
being like you're a caregiver you're an
indoor but they call us basement growers
is what we're labeled as but you know
that's a derogatory term it kind of is
but if you've got the right basement
it's not that you can't be a really
awesome sexy basement grower it's that
it's sort of like private caregivers how
was your power changes going from being
a caregiver in a residential growth to
having a gigantic commercial growth I
always say it's you're on a commercial
grow you're not growing weed you're
managing a schedule it's more of a plant
management no fund intended but you know
you're trying to keep all the wheels
greased and rolling and functioning
properly and if you started to a grow
that didn't have that mindset to begin
with it's quite disastrous so you had to
come in and kind of take over for
somebody else I had to learn that from
you know I I have no card laying the
middle of it off yeah yeah exactly trial
by fire yeah
sink or swim because the shop that you
were thrown into they did not provide
the proper equipment supplies no
actually there was just as beneficial as
learning what to do sometimes it helps
to figure out why you do it that way by
seeing how what happens when it's done
wrong yeah some people can only learn
that way I've worked for a few of those
people just stand back and let it crash
I made a completely amateur mistake I've
got a gorilla glue plant and it's
growing out of control so I'm sort of
its kind of mainlining but not really
because I'm not cleaning everything off
I'm just trying to pull it down I split
that [ __ ] right down the middle trying
to pull one side too far from the other
one piece of duct tape and a twisty tie
it was all happy quick first dates she's
cool she's happy four or five days later
she's happier she looks stronger there
than she did before
so yeah they're Hardy made a super noob
mistake I was just gonna say there's a
reason they called it weed through I've
been dead shops from Pueblo Colorado
Springs Denver east and west of Denver
both directions I haven't gotten up to
Boulder Fort Collins to the dispensaries
but it seems like I have but you know
shops in Fort Collins I was up a couple
in Fort Collins before they got killed
along battle days again but they were
about like you'd see everywhere there
are good and bad examples and the good
examples range the spectrum from very
culture eat a very medical office II and
sort of the bad ones but these a lot of
both do you think that the huge
regulation has changed the quality and
product yes no I think it hurt and
helped it become a lot of the incredible
growers couldn't handle the regulation
when it first came down and then quality
dropped and it stayed kind of down I
don't want it to you know bash it too
bad but quality dip for a while when the
best growers were all forced out of the
legal industry and it took a while for
the people who were great at business
and great at following regulations to
catch up with making a great product
[Music]
there were industry leaders for a while
and I think now solid product is more
common than shady product but then again
I'm not up at the shops as often as I'd
like to be to say this [ __ ] with more
confidence right one of the things that
kind of annoys me we made all these
regulations to prevent shitty weed
pesticides mildew problems guess what
we're still getting it they have it they
don't go inspect the butter at all they
just pay attention to the dollars and
the sales and it'll care about the
products or the safety they check on the
edibles and make sure the edibles are
the proper dosage they don't really care
there isn't a regulatory system for
safety inspections for smokable as other
than through tobacco and
didn't really have that infrastructure
with the foodstuff kitchen safety and
all of those rules are already in place
and we saw what happened when those
first inspections came out everybody at
the table kind of smiled and just
recently started enforcing these over
the weekend and it's good to see him
smiling his lake is awesome what's up AJ
good to see hope you listen to the show
AJ Cashman shut up over a hundred people
got dinged and it's not like they were
doing anything that bad or that wrong it
was just their first taste of what the
high-end food quality regulations really
looked like in a medical edible
production kitchen like even Dixie got
hit and they're the ones that are like
the shining example in the industry as
the regulations come down the people
that were great at following them have
to step up and figure out how to be
great at growing weed too because they
haven't been practicing for 20 years
because they were terrified of breaking
the rules that's why they're good at
following them now
that's why you can't find my product on
the shelf because they changed all those
rules yeah I think when it was all the
basement growers and the care givers
doing it in the basement
yeah because while the cameras all the
regulations all that stuff is super
expensive but the big expense to start
off is the property like unless you can
find a landlord willing to give Uncle
Sam his property to let you live your
dream which thanks dad other than that
you ain't finding it so you gotta buy
the property yourself and unless you've
got a million dollars you're not owning
a retail property in Colorado sir other
people live anyway well I know several
people that are on the look for property
from a grower standpoint to most
business or most dispensary owners earn
more at this day and age they're more of
a business minded person and like he
said know nothing about growing and they
can be incredibly hard to work with from
a growers point of view I wish I would
have learned the business school instead
of learning to be a super good pot
grower I went to business school these
regulations are confusing [ __ ] it ain't
the lack of schooling you're better a
business than most of the people that I
went to do you Business School with and
you dropped out of society and went on
tour while they went to college like it
doesn't have a lot to do with how well
you did in business school
I think the life experience was
priceless right now following the
regulations is really a question of are
you willing to pay your lawyer gotta
have that capital to have that lawyer
because the way lawyers are ridiculous
right now from my perception I'm kind of
from the outside cuz I really don't do a
lot of shop shopping or not as much as
I'd like but the really successful shops
that have a handful of locations a
reputation for amazing consistent
product are the ones that really invest
it in a good grower and setting up a
grow
that grower can really run and paid the
[ __ ] out of that lawyer and there's so
many shops died because the grower and
the business people got in a pissing
contest then rather than succeed they
just peed on each other a bunch one of
the most popular dispensaries in the
state does not have their super popular
grower and grow team anymore because of
recent political changes they chose to
make I was kind of sad to see that but
it did make for some great new
opportunities upwards yeah fix it okay
it's cuz I got here my turned up real
hot cool learnin how to work sound
equipment only took me thirty four
episodes so the reason that Mike
actually Mike and Jesse have been
contacting me talking to me about this
topic this I was sleeping on this mic
thankfully is a super active member of
our community
he goes to City Council meetings he
supports cannabis any way that he can
jesse works at a hydro shop and try and
is also a farmer a grower and tries to
do what he can to stay up on politics I
don't pay attention to the local news to
tell you the truth I just pay attention
to the world international cannabis news
and the state news so luckily Mike
brought this to my attention and Jesse
had some stuff to add to it I put these
guys in touch and then they were like we
got to get on the podcast tonight so
their idea to do a show about this so
big shout out to these guys thank you
guys were giving me material thank you
Mike took some notes and I've got a
little opening an opening statement if
you will it says again without a frog in
my throat
it says city staff is attempting to
draft the new ordinance that would ban
all indoor growing in the city of Puebla
they want to make the rules that say
they want to make rules that say we have
to grow in a separate building detached
from our house and that is [ __ ]
because of many reasons
pretty accurate what I wrote there yeah
cool
not just indoor home growing though all
home growing so green Oh green house in
your backyard no just out in your
backyard no in your basement no in your
bedroom no little grow cabinet which
means everything at your local hydro
store is pretty much pointless because
you can't use any of it unless you build
a special outbuilding just for your six
personal cannabis plants which is
ridiculous how many of us can afford to
build a special outbuilding just for our
cannabis chieftain the last couple of
weeks has been revolving around most
people in this will not most people in a
city several people in the city not
being able afford trash service
electricity payments things like this
and we're talking about having people
build a special airtight smell proof
building so they can grow six pot plants
well technically three because you're
only allowed three in bloom at one time
so you'd only have three stinky
flowering plants in that building ever
at once this would also affect
caregivers he's using a 64 as a
reference but it would also affect
caregivers thank you so it would just
make it easier to steal harder to take
care of it's gonna be another building
you're gonna have to get a building
permit
you're gonna need to wire that building
everybody in the neighborhood would know
that that's why he has six people on the
block or in the neighborhood or whatever
just built that special new building
behind their house you'd have to only
said property it's the first place my
mind went is it's a huge kick to Black
Hills because everybody who's been using
a green house or following the very
letter of the law and just chain linking
their plants into a cage and essentially
growing them purely outdoors in their
backyard but in an enclosed lock space
now you've got to put them under
expensive grow lights with its fancy you
know air filtration equipment and all of
that is just a huge give the Black Hills
that you said that you had an idea of
why this ordinance was being drafted so
a couple weeks ago and I'm the City
Council policy nerd I go attend just
about every meeting I was there two
weeks ago listening to the interviews
for the new city council seat and then
for the budgetary meeting they had after
that and during the budgetary meeting
just sort of offhandedly a couple of the
council members referenced a complaint
they had all received to the previous
week from a homeowner on the south side
who's an elderly gentleman and wakes up
every day to the stink of marijuana
plants and now everybody's sitting at
this table is like you asked why'd you
say stink well it's because that's how
this old guy sees it that's how what he
called City Council about in being City
Council and not having a whole lot to do
other than please your constituents and
you know respond to stuff like this a
number of them drove out to this guy's
house and gave it a smell sandy Daffy
said it was very strong from the
driveway she pulled up into this
gentleman's house so next she pulls up
next door and she can smell this guy's
garden he said that he didn't really
smell it but when he was standing in the
backyard he could clearly see several
plants over the top of a privacy fence
so you know gives you an idea how big
this caregiver was doing in his backyard
it doesn't sound like he's meeting all
of the basic city code stuff because
they weren't enclosed or locked
they were just in his backyard but the
cops have been out at this guy's house
his neighbors are pissed like what any
of you ever sneak out your neighbors
like this it's a pretty easy way to
bring problems on yourself like it's I
would be embarrassed if my neighbors
smelled me every morning there's an
indoor grower I try to be really covert
my neighbors I'm certain my neighbors
know what I do because they've seen me
carrying things they see my dreadlocks
they know who I am
they've seen my facebook they probably
listen to the podcast
one of my neighbors was a vendor I don't
know what he sold exactly but he brought
me a large box of lighters fresh
lighters like just he's like this I'm
pretty sure you guys smoke you want some
lighters and that big gigantic box over
there is that's all lighters but I still
I don't city council on you saying
you're a bad neighbor because they don't
wake ups like I would be mortified like
clearly my mother did not raise
whoever's growing these pot plants but
you know so city council went out there
and during the meeting the other night
they mentioned sort of offhandedly that
they had all received this complaint and
they all agreed that this guy should be
able to wake up in the morning and not
smell his neighbor's pot plants and they
didn't really say anything else about it
they kind of chuckled about the smell
and the contact how I got thrown around
a little bit they were busy they were
going over budgetary stuff in the cities
millions of dollars in the hole so he
got dropped pretty quick and you being
Who I am and doing what I do all day
when I read the article in the chieftain
today I called every city council member
in Pablo and three of them called me
back today and discussed this issue and
all of them said that this isn't
something that they asked for or that
they're aware that any other council
person asked for rather it's something
the city staff has put together based on
those offhanded comments the council
meeting the other night so this is all
the brainchild of somebody in Planning
and Zoning who's attempting to please
his bosses who might not or whom he
decided might want to weed can't smell
weed in pueblo type ordinance the City
Council people I talked to all use the
word unenforceable or all agreed to any
sort of ordinance that covered growing
pot in a basement or in a garage like
all of that is unenforceable they can't
send somebody to every house in Pueblo
in check so essentially if you're not
being a jerk and stinking up your
neighbor to begin with there'd be no way
for them to find
you making this totally pointless so I
don't see it really going anywhere but
regardless everybody who gives a [ __ ]
needs to show up on the 13th at 7:00
p.m. at the City Council building down
on Union and grand you're the City
Council guy you should be telling me
don't look at me with a question I Drive
I Drive there without thinking at this
point I will tweet the correct address
guys we want to go on October 13th to
City Council and tell them that this
proposed idea is unacceptable and it
will not work for us great while you
were talking I came up with an
alternative a cannabis courtesy law it's
like a Don't Ask Don't Tell but if we
can smell it you got to turn it down
that's a cannabis courtesy good I'd like
to see more of a public service
announcement that's like don't be a
[ __ ] [ __ ] it's it's a common
courtesy I would be mortified as the
word I would use to describe and not
embarrassed not ashamed [ __ ]
mortified if my neighbor smelled me
every morning yeah and if you're growing
30 or 40 cannabis plants as a caregiver
you're putting yourself at risk your
patients medicine at risk just having
that wafting down the alley like we
already had one kid gets shot in the
stomach with an air rifle this summer
because someone's too stupid they'll put
their [ __ ] in a fence throw a chain-link
fence over it teenagers aren't gonna
bother they can barely work scissors a
long freakin wire cutters most of them
are so lazy that they're not ready to
steal unless it's right in their face
anyway right if you're growing in town
don't don't push the limits you know I
think that's the thing we're getting it
but all this is because one guys being
inconsiderate yes yes we're all gonna
get punished for that that kind of sucks
everybody who would like to grow their
own cannabis plants in the city of
Pueblo now has that right in jeopardy
because one jerk on the south side is
stinking up his neighbor's house but two
jerks because somebody had to shoot
somebody also and I'm sure that
contributes that's surely not helping
anybody
and there's another jerk out in County I
almost said too much of the neighborhood
but he's the the main thing for the
county kind of doing the same thing that
they're wanting to do the same thing
that the city's gonna do or try to do
the county's talking about proposed
plant limits as ever they are talking
limits but regardless of caregiver ship
or anything like that it would be 18
plants yeah 18 plants per single-family
residence and 12 plants per apartment or
multifamily residence and it limits or
forbids outdoor going to so that's you
know let's ridiculous especially in the
county the forbidding of outdoor growing
is just a silly gift to Black Hills that
they don't deserve the Sun is free
abundant energy and plants are meant to
be outdoors and the only reason
marijuana was forced indoors to begin
with was prohibition yeah ridiculous
[ __ ] but that thing you just said about
the only reason marijuana was forced
indoors was because the prohibition is
one of the greatest things I've ever
heard you say and I agree with you and a
lot of people moved to Colorado to the
Pueblo area to grow outdoors because
this is an ideal climate there's the
reason that uh most the army troops that
have been Afghanistan and Iraq now go
through Fort Carson for training before
they go there yeah similar environment
we're up this altitude the air is thin
the temperature is the same yeah the
Hindukush valley no does that mean that
when they take over and they all come
here that they're coming to pueblos my
favorite place on the planet before we
legalize what I think it's beautiful
here the weather's gorgeous the climates
wonderful the summers are amazing the
food here is great
Olathe sweet corn people you don't know
what you're missing
in Colorado right people are pretty
chill when family comes to visit they
always comment on how nice the drivers
are thirty people will shift lanes all
in unison to let a semi who slow up the
on-ramp on and the dude from New York
what are you guys doing we're not being
dicks in unison Communicator nothing we
just all weren't dicks at the same time
somebody was telling me a story about
the cannabis cup another person was in
from out of state I think New York
somewhere upstate where they talked all
crazy
they spoke all crazy but she said the
friend that told me the story said he
was walking up and down the aisles going
I can't believe it y'all is so nice here
people is so nice and we can smoke weed
believe how friendly and polite Colorado
people are not a lot is people looking
to come here and check out our legal
weed scene worried they're gonna be
embarrassed and cause problems we get
grief from locals if they come here and
get excited about legal weed no live at
the [ __ ] up celebrities words Jeff was
with me in line on January first did you
do much were you at the shop all day on
the first no I didn't work in the front
at all the first thing back in the good
old days but on the first watching
people make their first legal we'd
purchase and do the I've got legal weed
oh my god oh my god shuffle that's just
how I think of it is they're walking out
that it's more than a strut it's more
than a glide it's like a bounce kind of
ticker walks like this so yeah it didn't
matter if it was a gram or a half an
ounce
there's just the feeling of only [ __ ]
freedom it yeah no one can take this
away from you with it's magical and come
enjoy it just don't marine guide
yourself
it has become a verb it's so dumb it
became a verb instantly I was I was
actually I don't know if I've said this
on this show I was the first person to
buy recreational cannabis at the greener
side dispensary in Pueblo Colorado they
claim that that dude in Pueblo West beat
me but I don't care no with the vet
being the person the first person right
and I walk out the door and there's a
camera crew sitting there and they're
like say something and being I've got
always got [ __ ] to say so I was like my
name is Ross to Jeff and I was the first
person to buy recreational cannabis at
the greener side to Smith Street
football Colorado and then I screams I
have no idea where that video went I'd
love to see that it's on somebody's
documentary I would love to see where
that went I had some pictures on my old
phone that went first whim you sent me
it's a great one of my best Instagram
and Twitter photos ever came was
actually taken by our friend Jesse the
one where the reporter is that was a
really cool day those were all day I
remember a lot of stuff for that day for
sure so I was burst I bought weed first
and then I came home and met up with my
buddy that I did another podcast with
back in the day and him and I went back
out there it took our recording devices
and went and had a little bit of fun out
there for that and by then I was already
well known as the first guy that bought
pie don't know how everybody knew
already had only been three or four
hours there wasn't a lot to talk about
on that line so the news
came to my house and filmed us Mike and
I and another friend here hanging out
smoke I'm glad that they were way more
fascinated with the dreadlocks and the
dab rig than they were with the pasty
white guy in the corner two or three
dabs when the camera crew was here and
they put the tiny shitty week dab on the
news the news if I remember right they
didn't even actually put the whole dab
on either sister just me blown it out at
noon by then the camera guy was a little
lit his fault we got carried away in
sort of hotbox this room real fast and a
still camera lady and the still camera
lady was talking about how she wished
she could smoke but they drug test her
so I was making sure you know they did a
beep [ __ ] straight to Windy City last
year she started off like next to me
asking questions every other week
council meetings she's always a real
sweetheart and tries to block me out of
her shot of whoever speaking just by
fate lines of stuff if she was if she
wanted to she could tip her camera up a
degree and a half and have my dumb bug
in every background shot but she cuts me
and I appreciate you've been seen as the
guy smoking bud here at the house you
don't need to be the guy on city council
also that'll look weird for us she's the
one that got this important news on the
air that cleans up real good yeah this
holds this all started when a reporter
from the chief 'men sent me an email how
he got my email I have no earthly idea
but I woke up to can you please find us
someone from the cannabis using
community that wants to comment on the
City Council attempting to ban all home
growing in Iowa
wait what that's news to me and yeah it
seems like we need to remind people that
what's gonna happen is the draft will be
presented on October 15th to the City
Council well we've got to do is go to
the City Council meeting on the 13th and
kind of be pre-emptive show them look we
know this is coming we're here to
influence you first if come up with good
reasons why it's [ __ ] and if you
have if you got a speaking voice if
you're not scared to speak in front of
people go speak to the City Council it's
a public forum explain to them that they
can't make us grow in private buildings
because first that tells the robbers
right where our weed is second that
tells your neighbors that you are
actually growing cannabis if they didn't
already know if third you can't afford a
damn building for that's gonna make more
electricity for Black Hills to go wire
up that should be number one okay
see all these reasons already add up
second of all what are we doing wrong
there's a couple of people screwing up
go make those people correct their
things don't for a couple of people
screw-ups this does nothing to go over
to actor try to attack the actual
criminal element that does happen from
some home gross well the person growing
weed in their home on the black market
for sale on the black market isn't
bothering to follow any of the rules and
they're doing so they're doing
everything covertly because they don't
want to get caught and arrested the
people who are standing up following the
letter Aloha but being dickish about it
are just bringing a black eye to the
whole community and causing everybody
problems if we legalize if enough idiots
grew up they're gonna take that away the
next president could send the [ __ ]
Marines like it's not my head was just
like because it Romney will remember in
Boston bomb oh don't ever say
your outdoor garden will get drone the
Boston Marathon bombings they were going
into every single house and searching
every single room looking for the
suspects
[Music]
anymore we'd like to give you a dad but
on the show you're gonna like 30 minutes
give me the tiniest little baby girlie
dad start talking while I get him ready
I'll take one first and by the time
they're done I'll have a couple dabs
going so one of the things me about the
cannabis community is for the last 80
years or so we've been forced
underground and into the dark and then
out of the way and out of sight and
that's how we survived and that's how
we've thrived but now that it's legal
more of us need to stand the [ __ ] up
and show up to City Council and show up
to vote and show up during budget
meetings and have our voices heard
we're used to hiding and pretending like
we're not part of the system and we're
against the system but we live here too
it's our city - were we have just as
much right to have our city be like we
would like it as anyone else in the city
and if nobody shows up and speaks out
against a ban on all home growing that
requires you to build a building city
councils not gonna care that it's
ridiculous and unenforceable and a
horrible idea
they're gonna go ahead and approve it
because without thinking about it just
on a quick gut check it seems like you
ought to have the right to wake up in
the morning and not smell marijuana and
this ordinance might do that once for
somebody maybe so sure go ahead and
approve it and if nobody's willing to
throw on some clean clothes and show up
Monday night at 7 o'clock and say hey I
think this is a really bad idea and I'd
appreciate you not passing this
ordinance who knows what's gonna happen
I mean I think they're gonna kill it I
think that if I show up and one or two
other people show up and speak that
they'll go ahead and kill it on the
fifteenth or next month or whatever but
who knows nobody's willing to stand up
and that's part of the reason city
doesn't have any medical shops in it or
any rec shops yet because so far it's
just me down at City Council saying we
ought to have these for a minute we had
a little cannabis community group but
they fell apart pretty quick quite
quickly like you don't need a group
though you just you just need to be a
citizen who's willing to show up so
here's something that I've kind of
tossed around in my head way Mike and I
had a shop together you know we ran that
place there were a couple times when we
had to go to court for a couple of
things and to support a member of our
group that I always had a court trial
also we went to a couple of City Council
things to try to speak up I look like
your tip I I know it I look like a
cliche for you can pothead that's cool
to email out of my court no problem
[Music]
it's not the first time that's happened
to tell you the truth how to take with a
mic in front of me also so I'm talking
about I used to go to those City Council
meetings and then I'm saying I'm six
foot five with dreadlocks to my ass do
my dreadlocks go past my ass now I've
got four foot ropes hanging off of my
head he does a collared shirt and I look
good I still got these rastaman
dreadlocks dr. Carl Hart feels your pain
sir
I feel theirs
I'm almost a detriment to the community
when I go to city council meetings and
show like look here's Rasta man hear
that I feel like I'm a weight on the
community when I show up I kind of hide
because of that I would say that you're
a self-employed successful citizen of
our beautiful city and have as much of a
right to stand up and claim your piece
of it is the best dressed cleanest
shaved [ __ ] in here I was just
gonna say you don't have to change who
you are everybody gets a vote everybody
gets to say period the rules of this the
City Council meetings anyone who comes
and signs up to speak before the meeting
I they usually limit it to six but
they've been allowing more than six
people to speak at the beginning of most
meetings lately because of all the
hubbub and the recall stuff but if you
show up to speak you can't you get your
five minutes as long as you're not
cussing or throwing things you can say
whatever you want and there's these old
crotchety people that show up and [ __ ]
about whatever their passion issue is
every two weeks at every single meeting
they take five minutes at the beginning
of the meeting to stand up and say I
don't like any of you I hate what you're
doing I need all of you to stop right
now it's illegal I hate you he takes
five minutes to do every meeting and he
sits down and his crotchety friend gets
up and does the same thing
they're not any more valid or legitimate
than you with your dreadlocks or Jessie
with this beard or me with my earrings
just cuz I clean up a little better than
y'all as far as the cops your concern
doesn't mean you deserve less or more
space in City Council than I take the
only reason they talk to me is cuz I
show up all the time and I'm familiar
face most people leave halfway through
the meeting and then it's just the
people that are stuck there playing a
role in going through the pageantry of
city government and because I'm willing
to hang out for that last hour I can
call City Council on two o'clock in the
afternoon and by 8 o'clock I've talked
to the three of them personally for like
15 minutes each [ __ ] stoner do like
I'm just willing to stand up and claim
my little spot at the table I like it my
other question is am I gonna attract
unwanted attention to myself like I'm
not doing anything I shouldn't be but am
i bringing we'd had trouble to myself
that the cops are too busy yeah a friend
of mine likes to tell a story a
girlfriend got mad at him and called the
cops and said my boyfriend's growing too
much weed in the conference
we've got heroin falling off the truck
here we've got teen pregnancy rate that
rivals most counties high school
graduation rates like cops are busy the
kids that's going to City Council with
dreadlocks and standing up saying I
don't like this ordinance please don't
vote for it it's not someone they need
to worry about now if you show up to
throw a rock at Sandy DAF they're
probably gonna pay attention to who you
are and follow you out of the building
and give you a lot of problems but if
you stand up and act like a citizen they
will treat you like a citizen because
doing so anything else is technically a
crime can I wear a hat in the courtroom
yep nice people show up in pajamas the
trash haulers are down there a lot a lot
of them come straight from work
I mean Araki works full-time is a mail
carrier and more often than not is in
her work uniform like even Montoya shows
up in a t-shirt nine meetings out of ten
I mean if someone on the council isn't a
t-shirt
you should feel fine and a grassroots
hat keeping your dreadlocks out of your
face like it's a lot of us he's talking
to you guys it's really boring it's it's
city government it's a lot of people
mumbling about really hyper specific
rules and it's sort of bore yourself to
tears dull but it affects your life on a
number of in a number of ways regularly
and right now they're looking to kill
countless small businesses in every
caregiver in the in the city limits rule
trying to kill smells we just wrote them
a pretty nice little sales tax check for
her first quarter business to derail
Mike subject here but guys a lot of
people want to talk to Jesse about
growing stuff from the show catch him at
hydro indoor growing supplies distract
him so that he can't get his work done
it's much more fun to stand there and
help you guys out there it is the stack
[ __ ] up all day if you bring tabs down
that's a good way to distract you are if
you're taking dads while you're working
I'm just about to law
come to city if you live in Pueblo
Colorado is it just City or does the
county count if you're part of the
county come out to all of this stuff
affects you guys if if the city bans all
home growing the county is going to
experience a mass exodus of cannabis
caregivers into the county and with the
fit they've been pitching over one weed
farm out and whatever that road is I
don't imagine they'd like the 3,000 plus
caregivers in Pablo County in have since
the medical where medical marijuana
program started publishing that
information about a decade ago like all
these people gonna have to pack their
[ __ ] up take it to the county and the
county arity to handle that so County
folks show up and say this is a terrible
idea I'm a well-established caregiver
I've been caregiving for five or six
years professionally I call myself a
professional caregiver I do very well at
it my patients love my products right
they count on it they rely on it I have
got a system designed where I can
provide exactly what they need I know
when my patients are gonna call I know
when I know when my old friend I know
exactly when he's gonna run out I know
when everybody I've got him scheduled to
have to redo my grow to build another
building would cause me to have to leave
this town which would put five people
that I'm responsible for and some deep
[ __ ] with their cannabis needs yeah one
where are they gonna get it because
there's not there aren't gonna be any
other care givers to take my spot
because they can't grow no in their
indoor environment like not everybody's
got a breeding facility somewhere else
to work with
not to mention I mean just the the loss
of revenue I think a minute 64 even with
pueblos every corner they've been able
to stop being having retail stores and
grows in city limits and of Pueblo still
prospered from amendment 64 you know in
in in small ways but the secondary
employment this is come from 64 public
still enjoying all the electricians the
plumbers the caregivers you know the
grossed or people moving makes a lot of
money from us there was a higher profit
margin on it there's a last depression
the one gross store on fourth Streets
rung up what three new locations and two
new competitors bloomed yeah folks and
we've got four now they're five or six
driving distances here right and they're
all surviving just fine because there's
a lot of employment bleeding off this
industry yeah I'm gonna do a shameless
plug right here I've been to all of the
hydro shops in this town
that's no doubt at all all of them
several times and there's a reason why
I've chosen one specific shop to be my
sponsor
I was almost out there today just by
happenstance yeah he did something and
that was what dawned on me that's the
place to go yeah we're gonna have to
work out some kind of coupon code or
something yeah listeners I've been
thinking that too yeah if it right now
just off the top if you mentioned that
you listened to the show and you're
buying something tell us you know and
we'll take care yeah it'll probably only
work at the Pueblo location because
Jesse's not in Denver yeah but tell him
anyways and Denver nice we're gonna get
a coupon code or some sort of deal for
you guys for listening I'm also gonna do
some giveaways I just haven't decided
how to do it I've got a couple of cool
items possibly some titanium and
possibly a t-shirt and maybe a couple of
hat pins they need to be given away to
listeners
I just need good ideas on how to do it
Instagram and Facebook giveaways feel
cheesy to anybody who talks not [ __ ]
at council back on the subject of the
proposed ordinance they mentioned
something about realtor landlords in
there and I kind of thought that was BS
too I know a couple local landlords one
of them has over 30 properties and the
other one has 18 properties and some of
those are big duplexes or apartment
buildings they don't care they actually
tell their tenants they don't care that
you know I'm sorry I can't name them but
they don't care golden information
almost all of their tenants grow almost
all their tenants pay rent on time they
take care of their houses they love them
they you know so I don't know where they
came up with landlords are pissed about
this because no one in the industry
stands up if you're on City Council if
you're the police chief or the fire
chief you don't meet care givers like
you to you meet the care giver who said
his [ __ ] house on fire you meet the
care giver who got to got drunk at the
bar and back into the somebody's car
with three pounds in the trunk and like
somebody blew that garage apart open
blasting and smoking a cigarette at the
same time good point and because you
guys are good at what you do and you've
never blown yourself up or set your
house on fire they've never met you
they've never heard of you've never seen
pictures of your garden if I could take
pictures of your grow room and take them
to City Council I could give them an
idea of what looking or what doing it
right looks like because they've only
ever seen the one that the cops got
called on and the cops took pictures of
I mean that's part of the problem there
unless you're reading High Times or Kush
or which I'm sure they like I mean you
get to make friends with people like
Jesse you never see this if you guys
want pictures check out I read genetics
on Instagram
also check out Jesse grows on Instagram
lots of great pop pictures Instagram
while you're at it follow our friend
garden of Weeden on Instagram if you
want high high quality cannabis pictures
if the popcorn do what he just said yeah
no porn there's a reason he just want a
nice little secret cup sir
man I was dabbing I looked up and
suddenly Jesse was at the secret cup
that was pretty sweet
and then I blinked and he was gone
I was literally repotting plants I was
like [ __ ] it
[Music]
it was about 45 minutes to get there I
think your travel time was more than
what you spent there best drive time
ever you know there was so like exciting
yes so cool yeah big shout out to our
buddy Spitz for taking home the first
place at the secret cut Mountain region
I keep wishing him the best of luck in
Vegas but I'm pretty sure he's gonna
bring it home for us
okay he put this little town on the map
bro yeah and see I mean that's so
positive too we're always on the map for
some psychotically horrid [ __ ] you know
it's so nice when it's positive you know
um another thing I want to say is most
caregivers basements I've seen that's
just a general term for where their girl
is most of them are way cleaner than
most dispensaries uh girls I've seen
that's just the honest truth
nine days out of ten I'd be happy eating
off Jeff's grill on the floor I've got a
little bit of OCD and that plays very
well being a pot farmer it does notice
my front yard is clean my back yard is
clean the sides of my house are clean I
asked my neighbors neighbors to remove
some debris they had over there they had
a trailer with like old wood they had
chopped down and they didn't take it
away for a long time I was like hate to
be a stickler but could you possibly
take away that wood and if you need some
more reasons why I'll let you know why
it's bugging me I'm sorry we'll get rid
of it and they took every little board
my weeds are pulled all the time my
garden my back backyard garden is clean
because I can't afford the bugs that
that will frame I'll bring more problems
and it also makes your house look like
[ __ ] and being a pot grower I want to be
a good citizen and not make my house
look like [ __ ] I mean that's part of the
thing no one sees this no one sees how
well most of the industry does it the
most of City Council hasn't bothered to
go out and visit any of the legal
marijuana stores in town some of which
have been open for like seven eight
years now I mean how long's marisol been
open and they can't make that drive it's
not exactly the best example like this
run out but like it's been
that's the first dispensary we gotta
give them credit it's the first and I
mean you can't go out there and check if
it's something that's so scary and
should be fought like shouldn't you
understand your opponent to kill it or
at least some nonsense like that and go
see it once some Jedi [ __ ] right there
bro
but it's if they see it from the parking
lot don't have to go in and inject some
marijuana's walk into your grow room and
close your eyes and breathe and if it
smells like wet or smells like plants
you're doing it wrong
you need more ventilation you need more
air out and more fresh air in you don't
want to be able to smell that [ __ ] in
your own grow room you should be able to
smell it in there this random grow tip
has been brought to you by I'm just
thinking about filtration and if we're
gonna grow indoors yeah I got a couple
carbon filters by the way we're gonna be
growing indoors and doing it right
that's that's how you know you're not
putting humidity and mildew problems
into the house and that's how you know
you're filtering it to your neighbors
aren't gonna complain I blew a guy's
mind the other day uh sold him into a
carbon filter for the intake when I
first told him about it he was like
sounds like a waste of money and with
him
45 seconds he was like oh so I did it
even like it makes your light bulbs last
longer I mean everything is just it's
better yeah yeah carbon filters guys
carbon scrubbers if you're not using it
to just pull they're out of the room
that you're growing in put a filter with
a blower in there just right in the
middle of the room either on the floor
or hanging a ceiling to keep their clean
and keep air moving you can't have too
much air flow in your grow room
you really can't random tips from some
pros need a and we have really good air
here to had everyone in town taking that
advice at the beginning of the summer we
would not be here recording this episode
really you know I'm an outdoor grower
it's hard to keep that stink away I
don't have a good same time have you
ever had a neighbor
no I've been in many backdoor or
backyard gardens Jesus I've been in many
backyard get something on your mind that
kind of I haven't seen a lot of
pissed-off neighbors on either side
generally because unless you're doing it
in large quantities or you're really
good at it
you're not gonna produce a level of
stink that's there for more than two
weeks in any sort of obnoxious level I
mean we're not talking more than like
the [ __ ] from the guy next door
wasn't raked it up in a couple of weeks
or the compost pile that's baking in the
Sun type odor here it's not that strong
it's just peculiar and unless you're a
real dick your neighbors not gonna call
the cops and every member of City
Council instead of you those people that
claim just the smell of pot makes me
sick I get a headache and I think that's
[ __ ] because I've smelled some all
kinds of [ __ ] and no smells I've ever
really given me a headache just smelling
something probably that's but there are
some people that love to clean to a
problem or there's a lot of people
looking for anything about Mary gripe
about which we're seeing a lot of that
level rust right now in these folks that
are sneaking out there neighbors are
really you're hurting the cause man we
succeeded and we got full legalization
now we've got people looking to throw
anchors at us and it sucks good job on
the stink but man my live in pub West
every Sunday we go out there and eat
dinner RISM I grew up out there so oral
I went I just go out there I Drive
around and stuff like that take
different roads and every single time I
can find two or three plants sticking
above the fan
there's a place out there is the hoop
houses he have in his backyard kind of
remind me of what crash site looks like
you know I mean they're there they're
pushing it they're pushing the limits or
bein [ __ ] and that sucks
Mountains [ __ ] by doing some plants in
my backyard who's gonna buy one of those
ten by ten dog runs and a little
greenhouse and put the greenhouse inside
the dog run but Blake seven out of ten
growers that have grown some outdoor pot
this year have either had caterpillars
or thieves in this neighborhood and I'm
just gonna pass on the outdoor one of
the things most people don't take into
account for the outdoor is you're giving
up like 90 percent of your control so
that you can also give up 90 percent of
your energy cause I mean I just grew a
bunch of veggies outdoor this year in
the weather bugs pretty much killed me
but I still got a massive harvest at do
you use old pot dirt to grow veggies I
know a bunch of growers that gave me two
trifles uh old pot dirt mix it with sand
so holds water a little better I mix it
with that clay crap Pablo is built on
yeah worked like a charm folks I got
zucchinis the size of Jeff some Tomatoes
got a nice bag of produce one night it's
nice in the group because all my farmer
friends Jesse was bringing me killer
tomatoes I can't even eat a damn tomato
and he now anyway now after the stuff
that he gave me why sure tomatoes are
just
it totally got a second leg person wind
yeah crazy I barely eat eggs because
it's kind of a dietary decision but also
because eggs are disgusting
but then Jesse brought me a few eggs and
I was like let's give it a try and I
cracked him open and the yolk on the
inside it looked healthy they smelled
good and those eggs were tasty I fried
them up and made some Mike and I forgot
what I even did but those were so good
it's not store-bought processed GMO [ __ ]
those real eggs and that real vegetables
you brought me so good extra links and
experience to ensure non GMO food for my
chickens nice delicious it worked well
alright guys we've gone for an hour do
you guys have anything that you'd like
to say to start wrapping up the show
other than come to the City Council
meeting in Pueblo Colorado October 13th
I will tweet the exact address I will
Facebook the exact address so that you
guys have no excuse we talked about it
if you're up if you're to Baca you can
still come to the meeting if you don't
have any hair if you've got a lot of
hair if you got long hair if you got
tattoos if you got a facial piercing if
you have that's all you gotta do just
put some clothes in the wash Monday
morning throw some clean clothes on
after work Monday night head on down to
the City Council Chambers around 6
o'clock the meeting starts at 7:00 you
wanna have a chance to sign up right as
you walk into the City Council Chamber
on the third floor there's like a little
table with a couple of sheets of paper
on it and they'll have the agenda for
the night and then the sign-up sheet for
people that want to speak at the public
forum sign up on the public forum
sign-up sheet if you want to speak and
grab an agenda and find a seat I usually
sit on the right-hand side of the
chamber if you're looking at the City
Council over by the fire chief so
[Music]
okay you just show up walk upstairs or
take the elevator
it's really handicap-accessible
apparently they got a few years ago [ __ ]
them it should have been if you don't
feel comfortable talking or having
people know your name just show up stand
in the back and clap when someone says
something you like you know unless
you're going crazy they're not even
gonna notice you they're gonna thank you
for speaking and I mean even if you're
they're yelling at them and tell which
I've done before you can fully pull a
video of me berating city council for
dragging their feet online if we had
like 80 people show up do you think they
would ever bring up a pot ordinance
again if we had 80 people show up they
would do whatever we asked if we had
five people show up this ordinance would
never see the light of day with a public
meeting that we're asking you to attend
is on the 13th it's officially being
princesa fishel ii being presented to
City Council on the 15th if half a dozen
of us show up on the 13th and three or
four of us stand up and speak and say we
think this is a terrible ordinance it's
unenforceable it's really bad for
pueblos there's no point don't do it and
we're not psychotic about it when they
present it on the 15th it'll get killed
immediately and it will never make it on
to the official agenda
it will never be voted on by City
Council it will die quickly if 30 or 40
of us show up we'll have the City
overlay for the retail stores shaken out
of this Planning and Zoning Commission
months earlier than we would otherwise
right now no one shows up no one stands
up no one's called City Council to [ __ ]
about not seeing this yet and so they're
dragging their feet and we're not gonna
see it till after the elections in
November
and you want something else to do to
help out register realize what I was
doing your equipment so I got to the
word vote that's awesome but by then
petering off would have been silly yeah
yeah all right
dude I tried do I tell everybody to
follow you on twitter
tell us your Twitter handle Nemo Punk'd
15 nem o pu n k 1 5 there we go follow
that guy on Twitter Jessie's got a
Twitter its Jessie grows og right you
following there you can tell when people
have listened to the podcast whose all
week long after you did that like
randomly I'd get to two new followers on
Twitter and I'd look at it and they'd be
related and then two hours later I'd get
one more that's three in the morning I
get four more a lot of people listen at
4:20 that's good to know
3:00 3:00 in the morning stoner yeah I
think I posted something last night at 3
in the morning I you and I were
commenting on that I posted a video and
you commented on it last night
do you actually said I'm listening to
the podcast follow Jessie on Instagram
he posts a lot of good stuff it's at
Jesse grows Jes se gr OWS nice and easy
follow him he does a lot of cool [ __ ] on
Instagram follow
I read genetics on Instagram follow the
show on Instagram I don't post a lot of
stuff but I'm starting to post a lot a
lot more if you follow he will build the
posts that's right and hashed if you do
Instagram user a hashtag and I grow
culture home pictures on there yeah Wow
such a good idea from such a stone dude
I bet you can do that on Twitter too you
can do that on Twitter too still
learning it I'm new to Twitter I'm a
Twitter monster are usually in the show
and then come back and wrap it up but
I'm just gonna do it now because we've
got it going on because I want to ask my
listeners for one thing I need a theme
song I've been playing other artists
songs and I've been playing that one
reggae song you hear is it seem that I
made on iTunes it's not acceptable or on
garage man
sorry that's not acceptable if somebody
would make me a super cool theme about
two minutes long maybe see a few key
phrases agriculture podcast hosted by
Rasta Jeff brought to you by eye region
etics you know I would make it up to you
in some sort of way depending on what
state you live in and how old you are we
could work on a little compensation but
there would definitely be some pay in
there I'm not begging I just need a
theme song I'm tired of listening to
cheesy reggae tune I made and I've been
putting the show on you on YouTube and
YouTube gets mad at me for using all
those other people's songs I've got
their written permission all the artists
that I use I've got permission proving
that to Google's tricky exactly they
don't even care if you do prove it
they're like that email doesn't mean
[ __ ] to us we need a written letter from
a record label with notary and yeah
sorry dude have fun we'll call us
artists I'm using are actually my
friends it's like mystic roots and tasks
rock and I've been like hey can I use
your music like yeah of course bro so
there's like you know they've said yes
but that's as far as we've gotten yeah
you can't play Google that voicemail
that's right so somebody if you want to
write I like reggae obviously if you
wanted to write a couple of them that'd
be badass maybe one for the start of the
show one for the end of the show maybe a
short piece for like between segments
something with the real aggressive
dancehall reggae beat would be pretty
smooth I don't know I'm just begging at
this point I could use a theme song
that's what I'm trying to get at he also
likes death metal there's nothing like
getting real high just listening to a
thousand
[Music]
Podcast needs a theme song and you'll be
compensated in some way or another
I'll definitely hook you up with some
seeds if you're in Colorado I just have
to make sure you're 21 and in Colorado I
can't do that if you're outside of
Colorado if you come to Colorado
I'll get you seeds I got you one of my
favorite things to wear around town is
my IRA pen and you can wear the [ __ ] out
of that in Pennsylvania or New York or
any other state that sucks out loud and
you could also probably get a I read
genetics t-shirt if I have your size and
some stickers and a pan will make it
worth it trust me right there's other
stuff - I've got prizes the prize gags
could be built that's right so I grow
culture t-shirts but he wants to fund
some I grow culture t-shirts first
people have contacted me about
sponsoring the show if you'd like to
sponsor the show email me I grew a
culture at hotmail.com I'll send you all
the sponsor details I've got a little
one sheet made up it's nice and easy to
understand we'll get a deal going
thank you guys for coming to do a great
show this has been really fun we've had
a lot of it just just kind of chilling
out banters kind of stuff it's nice the
listeners appreciate that mike is very
well-spoken we've covered all the bases
I think I enjoyed this as well I've been
dying to get back on it's been what this
is 34 didn't feel well I almost died
last week with my back yeah almost
killed me it's good to see you doing
well again that's nice to be back on my
feet do you guys have anything else to
say I'm gonna do the end please go to
iTunes iTunes Store search for
agriculture find the review section give
me a 5 star rating
come on you know you want to give me a 5
star rating after that type in a little
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode he hasn't done it
yet but he keeps promising to do it so
somebody comments three people have left
comments and I've read all three of
theirs and thank those three people
largely when more people leave some
iTunes and or stitcher comments I will
read them
I skipped episode 20 once in my bed
please do leave comments the guys at
left comments I do appreciate you I'm
not forgetting I know that they're there
and I appreciate it also tweet us I like
that you can do the same thing on
stitcher you can leave comments there
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher swell dot a.m. I
don't think it's there anymore I think
so well dot AM is gone to tell you the
truth I'm just gonna delete that right
from my notes
it's genetics Colorado calm and also I'm
adding videos to YouTube I'm doing it
real slowly it takes me about an hour to
make a video each night sometimes I can
knock out two hundred hour but they're
kind of cheesy the videos aren't great
yet I'm just trying to get catched up so
once I get a better caught up I will
give you better shows so check me out on
youtube if that's easier for you iTunes
stitcher I region etics Colorado com
make sure you follow us all on our
Instagram and Twitter I gave those out
several times once again a huge shout
out to my ninja spits congratulations
for taking home the win thank you for
listening you guys take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me I think
Mike's always wanted to say that that's
awesome thank you listen you guys what's
up cannabis community
my name is Rasta Jeff and it's time for
episode number 35 of the hydro culture
podcast in the last episode I talked
about a proposed regulation coming down
in Pueblo Colorado we talked about going
to a city council meeting to prevent
these regulations and city council has
changed the date of their next meeting
the city's agenda did say the meeting
was on Monday but recently they've
changed the date the date is now on
Tuesday October 14th at 7:00 p.m. so
come down to one City Hall place in
Pueblo Colorado Tuesday October 14th at
7 p.m.
public comment will be allowed during
the public forum for those who sign up
before the meeting so if you plan to
speak show up around 6:30 and sign up
please come
and help fight these regulations what
they're trying to do is not allow us to
grow in our homes or in our backyards
trying to require us to make an
outbuilding to grow in which I don't
find fair so please join us at a City
Council meeting Tuesday at 7:00 p.m. if
you want to speak please show up around
6:30 I'll be there Mike will be there
Jesse will be there there should be
quite a few of us there we hope to see
you there
all right let's get on with the podcast
Jesse came over actually I'm waiting for
Jesse wall and record this to be honest
with you Jesse will be here any minute
now and we are finally going to do the
episode about drying and curing your
cannabis so hang on just a second while
I do some ads and hopefully Jesse will
show up by the time I get done with this
where do we want to start this episode
is brought to you by our good friends at
highly-educated titanium if you're
dabbing high-quality concentrates you
deserve a high quality titanium nail
don't trust Chinese nail or an American
knockoff made of cheap metals trust the
industry leader trust highly educated
titanium more information about highly
educated products visit highly educated
ti.com or if you just want to buy
something right now
check out aqua lab technologies comm
this podcast is also brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics the Plata labs Sin City
rare dankness mile high can adventure
alpha chronic bog MTV I said MTV's MTG
the Cali connection IRA genetics and
many more trusted brands nature's green
remedies is running a special for our
podcast listeners as they change they've
got a new coupon code check this out do
me a favor when you go to nature's green
remedies to buy your beans type in
coupon code helping hands it's two words
helping hands I'm gonna use that coupon
code you'll get thirteen percent off
your order and what that's gonna do
they're gonna send a percentage of your
order let me make sure how much I don't
want to lie to you I've got the message
right here scroll through for the
message it says that you will get
what this is gonna do they're gonna send
a portion of their proceeds to a
homeless shelter and the area where
nature's green remedies is located what
it says is it's to help a homeless
shelter in my area three bucks from
every order goes to help so if you want
to help out a homeless shelter keep some
folks warm for the winter use coupon
code helping hands and you'll get 13%
off and you will actually be helping
somebody so use that coupon code and
nature's green remedies dot-com I lost
my rhythm don't know where I wasn't that
read so let's move on to the next one
this podcast is brought to you by grow
indoor growing supplies Colorado Denver
Colorado
[Music]
with me and hopefully by the time I get
done with that our good friend Jesse
will be here to talk about drying and
curing your campus forgot to do a couple
things I want to give a huge shout out
to Joey cocoa Diez and also my good
friend Clint Clint and I went up to
Denver to the Denver improv on Thursday
night and we saw Joey cocoa Diez do an
amazing set of comedy Joey is one of my
favorite comedians he freaking crushed
the Denver improv and it was awesome
after the show he took a few minutes to
hang out with Clint and I well you know
with everybody but then Clint said
something too if it got his attention so
he hung out with Clint night for quite a
while and bullshitted one on one he
patted me on the shoulder and he said
Rasta Jeff you know I love you right
[ __ ] and for Joey Diaz to call you
a [ __ ] is actually an honor so it
was great and I had a good time so big
shout out to Joey Diaz thanks for the
great amazing show thanks for hanging
out with me for an hour after the show
hey Clint thanks for going with me dude
that was a good time
we need to go to more comedy shows
together also make sure you check out
the wild cousins that
Clint's comedy group that he is a part
of so if you are a listener a regular
listener
you remember that around episode 30 I
said that I would start paying a dollar
every time I say the f-word because I'm
trying to not say the f-word on the
podcast I need somebody to go back and
listen from episode 30 to 34 and let me
know how many dollars I own there's a
sick child in need
and I had a conversation with one of his
parents I think it was his uncle and I
said that I would help them out when the
time came up and so this is my my
obligation to them I know it's only a
dollar but what I'm gonna do now
starting on episode 35 every time I say
that hath word it costs me five dollars
I will donate five dollars to this sick
kid the sick child and try to help out
their life a little bit what I'll need
though cuz I need somebody to tweet me
or email me or let me know what I'm
doing it so the way you can do that you
can tweet me at agriculture you can
email me I grow culture at hotmail.com
you can Facebook me
it's just hydro culture just let me know
how many times I'm saying this and from
3234 it's $1 from 35 on it's gonna be $5
and it does not count to the guests the
guests can come and they can say
whatever they want so somebody start
tallying it up for me and send me a bill
I'm going to contact these people once
I've got a total and then I will let
them know that I want to do this and if
they accept the donation I'll send it to
them and also if they are willing or if
they want me to reveal their identity I
will and that way you guys can see who
I'm helping out all right one more ad to
do this podcast is brought to you by our
friends at tree hugger com tree hugger
com live music lifestyle magazine for
concert festival news and reviews check
out tree thugger dot-com I want to send
a personal shout out to Ryan from tree
hugger dude I see what you're doing with
yourself and I'm proud of you man I wish
you the best you guys I am still looking
for that theme song if anybody has made
a theme song for me please shoot it to
me can send it to me at agriculture at
hotmail.com
if you just want to send it instrumental
I can do all the voiceovers and say the
name of the show and all that stuff I
would appreciate it definitely make it
worth your time guys I'm gonna take a
couple more dabs when I get back we'll
do a lesson on drying
during your cannabis I just got a text
message and it's Jesse and he says he
will be here in five minutes hang on you
guys hi what's up ladies and gentlemen
guess who finally decided to show up our
good buddy Jesse grows his back how you
doing tonight bro pretty good
fashionably late fashionably late you
got a lot of fashion in you just
chilling out putting together a really
nice episode that people have been
asking for the dry and cure episode I
think they will be proud of what we
bring them today
Jesse actually said that he could use a
little foot is at a primer lesson is
that what it's called how to cure some
herbs I mean I've been told okay you
know I always I feel I have a lot of
room for improvement there your
standards on your own product are always
higher than everybody else's your
expectations you know what I mean I'm
never satisfied with my my herb or
anything and everyone's like that was
amazing yeah especially when I play
music like that could have been better
and they're like no dude you need I can
feel the same thing snowboarding as well
be on a snowboard it's like trying to
put a telephone pole on a snowboard it's
just a lot of me rolling down it I do
but I spend more time on the lift and on
my ass than I do on the actual board the
left-knee disagrees with the snowboard
now it feels like feels like my left
knee wants to fly out of the socket the
entire time I'm strapped in but I can't
ski for that this winter case-to-case my
snowboard friends have moved away miss
you guys hope you're listening so weird
to talk about curing herb not talking
about curing ourselves actually during
herbal cure ourselves I'm talking into a
circle because I'm really dab doubt
really really yeah we uh we burned out
the email I think switch over to the
regular rig the you know couldn't keep
up with the puddles we were putting on
it and I think it took a [ __ ] today so
hey giddyup remember what you're telling
me I shout out to giddyup I ran into
giddy on chatroulette that was amazing
and you said something about sending me
a G nail homey
don't forget cuz my nail just took a
[ __ ] so that'd be great timing um we
want to cure some weed that's why
everybody's listening you doing good bro
by the way I just kind of skipped right
over introduce for sure you'd have a
good day you look like you're working
hard tendon is very very sick some dads
take break what record will be awesome
so if you're gonna cure some weed you're
gonna need a few things you should have
a dehumidifier maybe you should have an
air conditioner maybe you for sure need
fans at least one fan you need what I
call a hydrometer that say it's a
thermometer with a humidity reading on
it also then you're gonna need some kind
of jars I prefer glass mason jars if
you're going a little bigger there's a
company I think it's called quick back
there a little suction fact live jars
they sell them at most of the head shops
those are pretty chill to cure your weed
and a lot of people don't like them
because those are plastic I don't think
they leave any taste or smell those
don't if you're going bigger I like to
buy those Rubbermaid 32 quart containers
I think that's what it is it's a big
container it's like a two handed
container you can fit a lot of herb in
one of those to cure it those work
perfectly so you're gonna need something
to cure it in and a room to get it
started to cure it ed Rosenthal actually
taught me that curing begins at the
start of harvest I'm not sure how much I
subscribe to Ed's teaching but in a
sense that is accurate
the minute you cut down that plant
you're starting the curing process you
need that herb to dry uniformly not too
fast not too slow and you don't want it
in a hot room you don't want it in a
cool room
so we're gonna kind of go from and one
of our lessons before we talked from
where we talked about harvest and drying
and we ended drawing as when where the
sticks on your buds that's pretty much
where we decided we were entering cure
so if you've done everything right
you've got all your leaves off your buds
have dried evenly in a nice room that
was temperature controlled not too fast
not too cool and now the sticks are
snapping and the buds are a little bit
damp a little bit juicy if you squeeze
them they kind of stick to your fingers
but they kind of spring back to life
they don't you don't crush them when you
squeeze them you wanted to have a little
spring left into it for sure all right
so I guess I should really and don't be
deceived by the crunchy layer some I
guess it goes strain to strain but
sometimes there's a lot more leaf on the
outside well yeah you know that's the
way you could get tricked either way you
know for sure if I letting it over dry
and also by taking this dry too soon so
right the weed dries from the outside or
from the outside in so even though the
outside leaves are crispy and dry the
inside could be really juicy still so
you got to be careful little buds or go
to dry quicker than the big buds when I
grow big but actually cut that all down
ball size nuggets if you if you're one
of my patients usually get a bagful of
golf balls is what I give you I do and
uh when I'm doing like the final trim
okay sometimes when they're hanging you
know the bigger butts are a little
harder to break down sometimes so
nothing to do with them yeah you don't
want to put them on a rack yeah let em
hang okay all right before we before
we're gonna cure this is when the sticks
will pop so everything's all trimmed up
now we don't have any leaves left
they look pretty they're manicured the
way you want when you grab one of the
buds you pick it up and you bend the
stick it should snap you don't want it
to bend like a straw you want it to
actually break pop you don't want to
leave it until it like explodes and
breaks cuz then you're a little too dry
too dry or too wet of cannabis will not
cure properly if you're too dry you've
already missed your point you're gonna
get stale buds you're just gonna put in
the jar waste
if you're too wet and you try to cure it
you're actually going to print but
promote mold so you want it about right
where those sticks snap and that's when
you're going to start the curing process
let me read you what I wrote of what
curing actually is and what the per the
purpose of curing is this is what I just
what I wrote down to give an actual
reason curing is used to remove excess
moisture to convert complex sure to
convert complex carbs back into sugars
while removing chlorophyll chlorophyll
is green pigment and chlorophyll makes
your buds taste harsh and smell bad and
it also makes your buds burn pork if you
guys ever smoked herb that kind of maybe
tastes like you just stuck your tongue
in a white socket you just want to
scrape your tongue off or you need a
drink real bad that stuff was not dried
and cured properly probably not flushed
properly either also as THC drives the
THC dries in your buds if it dries more
slowly there's more slower it loses its
water moisture it's a more psychoactive
it will become once the water comes out
of that THC that's when it's ripe and
nice and primed for you to smoke so by
curing it you slowly let that happen and
you don't destroy the THC you don't
destroy your terpenes essentially curing
allows aerobic bacteria to consume the
chlorophyll in the plants chlorophyll is
what we want to remove bacteria sounds
like a bad thing it's actually a good
thing in this instance aerobic bacteria
is made from air light and moisture
being sealed inside of that jar so what
I do I actually take my buds that snap I
fill my mason jar about 90% of the way
fool I don't want to squish him in there
I just want to lightly set him in there
then I seal that jar as soon as that jar
is sealed the aerobic bacteria begins to
form and that aerobic bacteria will
start eating away the chlorophyll in
there so when you open that jar that's
when the reaction will restart so what
you want to do what I do is I put the
buds in the jar I seal it up and then I
wait about two hours and then I go open
the jar and that first time I'll pour
the buds out onto my little tray and I
want to feel the buds and make sure
they're not they haven't gotten really
moist or they haven't
if you can see sweat inside the jar get
him out of there immediately
you [ __ ] up get him out of there right
away take him out of the jar nice start
squeezing him and I want to feel a
little bit of moisture at the edge cuz
it's coming out of the middle on the
surface but I don't want him to be damp
and sticky to where I'm afraid they're
gonna get mold so I'll leave them out
this first time I dumped them out and
check them all out I leave them sitting
out for a couple minutes if I feel like
they need it then I'll put them back in
the jar and seal that jar off if they're
properly dry like I'm hoping they are at
this point I'll leave it closed for four
hours this time and I know this sounds
tedious but this is where this is what
separates the pros from the regular
growers this is where you get that super
high-grade cured cannabis that's enough
you're getting at the dispensary that
tastes kind of hay like and I don't mean
to call out the shops but they don't
have time or space or manpower or the
patience to cure herb your caregiver or
your private grower or you are the only
way you're gonna get good cured herb the
dispensaries not gonna do it it tastes
you can taste the nutrients you can
taste the leaves you can taste whatever
other plant it was growing next to or
hang it next to in the dry room you can
taste that in these dispensary buds in
my opinion there are very few shops that
are actually curing their herb in my
opinion I don't work there so I can't
tell you what they're doing I thought
you're gonna say this for very few shops
flushing their stuff back to that to
adhering it well where I was you gotta
put your put your buds back in the jar
you seal the jar you wait for hours
that's when I open it again and then I
want to check the buds and make sure
that they're not getting too much
moisture is not coming out of there if I
feel like it's really humid inside of
the jar I said humid if it's not too
humid inside of the jar I'll put them
back in there seal it up and let them
sit for like six hours I've pretty much
increased the time just by a couple
hours until I get to about twelve hours
and then once you're checking them twice
a day so I'll do six hours and then I'll
do like ten hours and then I'll wait
till about twelve hours and then I'll
usually open them like every morning
when I wake up and then right before I
go to bed that's about 12 hours usually
in my world so you pop open the jar make
sure it's not too moist let it sit open
for just like ten Rafi
fifteen minutes you just want to
exchange the air and then seal it back
up and let it sit there once you've got
it to a point where you know it's not
gonna get any mold in it that's what I
like to just seal it up and leave it I
won't open it anymore it should burn
nice and smooth and that you can tell I
don't know if you guys have ever had
perfectly cured or if it's hard to get
honestly very but it you know that you
can smell down the block you're going oh
man that stuff was slowly dried and
cured I let all of the chlorophyll sneak
out and it let all of the flavor that
should have been there when the
chlorophyll disappears that's when the
other colors the Reds and the purples
start popping up and you can see in
those that's what gives you really
pretty buds and that's when the THC is
allowed to dry slowly that's when it
becomes more psychoactive I'm not
completely sure about the terpenoids but
it sounds like we need to give these
terpenoids a little bit of time to cure
they're also so they're not getting
destroyed or taken out along with the
chlorophyll or with the moisture if we
let it go slowly I think we're making it
smell better because we're doing
something to the terms and from what I
know about them they seem very fragile
too so this is you know mild to moderate
temperatures in darkness I think are all
very key to this I think I read that
terpenoids
evaporate at approximately 85 degrees we
read on another on another episode about
a hundred and six degrees was I think
where we said so I think it's right
around 100 degrees and something here
guys is drying and curing rooms or
getting that hot excuse me I need a sip
nice all those dad's got me all dried
out
thirsty dude we took some monster dad's
before the show that was pretty killer
so you need to keep opening those jars
until you're confident that it's not
going to mold up in there you want a
little bit of moisture Kyle kushman
prefers a bud he likes to open his jar
and take out a couple of nugs and set
him on the table and he would have sat
here and talked for 20 minutes before he
would have been able to roll him up he
would had to give you a lecture about
beginnings
and then after that the bud would be
almost dry enough to roll hump
sorry Kyle I'm just picking on your
brother great but so Kyle likes his buds
a little more moist our buddy Adam will
take a nicely dried and cured bud that
I've given him and he'll set that [ __ ]
out all day until it's crispy drive and
he grinds it up in the grind retorts
dust and takes heroic sighs bonk it but
what you want to do is I like to get it
to where it's it's not fluffy but it's a
it's got some squishy to it so if you've
got a nice hard den snug you want to be
able to give it a squeeze and it just
pops back up you don't want to crush it
and you don't want dust you definitely
don't I don't want that dry dusty buds
[Music]
how long do you try to store your
cannabis some of it gets stored for up
to nine months I suppose xenoverse stuff
some of my patients I can give them
their whole year supply at once and
they're fine with it
some of my other patients asked me to
hold on to it for anything you know some
of them on Endor but throughout the year
so you know it's all a balance but yeah
okay the last couple years my stuff
that's got nine ten months so it just
really wasn't happy with it
by the time it was that age let's uh
let's work on curing a little better and
I bet if those buds will store longer I
think I messed up in the beginning I do
pretty much you what you do for the
2-hour pull it out of the jar then the
4-hour but then it normally it'll go 24
hours 18 hours before I need it again
you gotta set some alarms I've got my
iPhone full of alarms just ridiculous
beeps if people think I'm doing
something crazy is every two hours I got
to run away I'll be back dude and got to
go somewhere go pop open a bunch of jars
and then go back and get them for sure
if you're using larger batches I guess I
should have covered this what I like to
do is get one of those big like purple
Tupperware containers or Rubbermaid
containers fill that up with your you
can leave it on the sticks a little bit
if you have to it's easier
right off the stick for this curing
process fill those containers and then I
actually flip them upside down and take
the container off the lid instead of
taking the lid off the container seal
even more exposed area and then just pop
that container back onto the lid try not
to squish any buds I hope that makes
sense pop it open lift the container off
the lid sit there like a tray full of
buds for sure yeah that gets a lot of
airflow in there yeah I like to use
those actually those same ones that
first same simiiar size but they're like
the size of a brownie pan yeah those
work for a short-term storage pretty
good okay in the beginning I talked
about we should have a dehumidifier and
AC unit fans a hydrometer I'm gonna back
up and talk a little bit about how Edie
Rosenthal says curing starts and harvest
hold on I got one thing let's do it I
like it how you packed your jar yeah I
don't like to over pack it mmm learning
but I think there's a lot of validity to
it yeah I think we need to over pack it
you create you know possible different
little microclimates in there you almost
prevent the aerobic acid from being able
to form in there when you don't have
enough oxygen for sure what creates
aerobic acid I think I said before was
oxygen light and moisture and so we need
plenty of that air in there Thanks don't
worry about giving it why you guys a
little bit of light we'll start it off
and once you get it started it's going
I'm fixing the echoes in here there's a
fan that we're fighting with but I'm
gonna make it happen I think I got it
just there sweet all right so like I
said II D Rosenthal says that curing
starts from pretty much when you cut it
down so if your buds have gotten too dry
they're not gonna cure they're gonna
crumble if your buds are too moist you
still have a chance but hopefully they
didn't dry too quickly you got to cut
down the plant and get all those leaves
off and let it dry nice and slowly
that's why we're talking about a room
with a dehumidifier with an air
conditioner and some fans and a high
drama
you want to keep your plants between 60
and 75 degrees at about 50% humidity
until you put them in this jar until
they reach that stick snap in period
that's how you keep from not drying too
fast I had a guy that a long time ago I
used to have to buy some herb and this
guy usually had the greatest bud anymore
that LA Confidential do you have any
more of that LA Confidential and he
didn't and he kept telling me I
harvested it it's almost ready I
harvested it's almost ready and I was
getting eager and so I asked him and
he's like sure man I'll bring it to you
tonight and he brought it to me and it
was it was a really weird texture it
felt like a pine cone it was hard but it
was also squeezy but the outside was
really hard then he broke it open in the
middle was soft and it was kind of
fluffy on the inside so I immediately
called him was like what the hell
happened bro and he said that he dried
it by opening the oven and setting it
next to the oven so that it would dry it
out on yeah so that is a prime example
of what not to do to dry your herb I
could taste it you smell it
I mean the weed smell like spaghetti
sauce like you smelled like marinara for
some reason it was the first thing that
came to mind that's gonna kill all the
Turks yeah yeah some sort of tomato we
paste or something it was terrible
better dried properly and slowly you
don't want to dry it up too fast
anything to add to curing bro I feel
like we went over that really super
quickly yeah um just really stoned me to
reject a lot of my spots II need crowns
so the dehumidifier they see you
and the hygrometer you need that
regardless of where you're at yeah you
gotta keep you need a proper room for
drying a lot of guys are just throwing
it in a closet or something you need a
good area for drying I'm gonna keep the
air moving the reason for a dehumidifier
what we're trying to do is we are
pulling water out of these plants that
water ends up in the atmosphere around
your plants and it has nowhere to go so
you gotta suck that water out of there
the dehumidifier is a perfect place for
that water to go and you can reuse that
water to water your plants later oh yeah
that's good water
yeah however I dunno if you if say
you're drying not a lot of plants in a
large room in the southwest you might
actually want a humidifier to help slow
things down right I'm trying to you know
kind of help out people regionally yeah
that's a good idea
we're kind of talking about Colorado but
yeah you need to keep about sixty to
seventy-five degrees that cool actually
I think will make your buds dry a little
more dense I think it hardens them up a
little bit also I got to mention dark
you want that dry room dark yeah drying
and curing should happen in mostly a
dark area I feel like literally a room
exact to same climates
when this dark an one that's light the
room with lights got a plastic out dry
faster it's kind of EF just kind of
experienced a half with my dry room and
keeping a window open sometimes and and
I know nothing else changed it is gonna
take a little bit of practice to get
your drying and curing method down right
you may have to ruin a jar or to seal
that jar up go to sleep open it the next
day and you open it it smells like
ammonia you might have just kind of
killed that crop if it's not moldy if
you don't see any mold break it open as
small as you can get those buds pour it
out on a tray let it dry taste it give
it a smoke see if it tastes all right it
might be all right it might be smokeable
if you left it in there too long and it
mold it up throw it away remember what
you did fix it next time don't do that
same [ __ ] again yeah always start with
clean jars clean jars yeah
I spend a lot of time today cleaning
jars and thinking man this really sucks
this isn't you know but it's you know be
every little thing counts has anybody
tried to cut off their feet and stick
cloning gel on their ankles so that we
can do the growing work you gotta do
life and then you gotta clean up after
yourself and that's always the part that
gets skipped in then you gotta go start
by cleaning tomorrow hey guys keep your
girl rooms clean cuz it builds up
quickly then you gotta clone yourself
cuz you just can't keep everything going
thank you - um you would crush yeah yeah
if you have a lot of money and you'd
have no shame and you wanna clean pots
and scrub floors and with us yeah yeah I
feel like we've covered curing I don't
know what else to add to this you're
gonna mess up some stuff that's where I
was it takes prick practice and patience
you're not gonna get it right the first
time
yeah what you can do is go you can open
it too often that's a good thing
leaving it close to long will screw you
up so go there and open it if you think
maybe I need to open it do if you have
another jar next to it don't open not
want to just kind of compare take notes
that's the best way to become a good
grower and a good sure and dryer is
divide practice it and take notes what's
your thoughts on rehydrating trade
company book the humidity the humidity
ex worked great for rehydrating your
buds been wondering what they'd be like
for long-term long-term storage as well
I've seen a lot of people throw their
herb in a sea vault which doesn't
sponsor me either
with a couple of human impacts and leave
it for a really long time yeah that'll
make your stuff not taste right it
doesn't it'll be funky flavor
unfortunately it doesn't work that way
[Music]
curing herb that you've possibly
purchased from someone you know just
trying to help out listeners here you
know ask them so if you've gotten herb
that you don't feel is dry enough if
you've got some patience you can cure it
if it's sticky you can leave it in the
jar and let it let it kind of dry real
slowly in the jar leave it in there
overnight
open it up check on in the morning and
leave it open for like 15 minutes and
just repeat that every day until it's
good or open it every six hours and
check on it if you're impatient yeah
brown paper sacks are great because they
kind of I did this when I was just
starting I kind of think that they kind
of make a little bit of a flavor in my
buds now and I've also lost a nice
amount of weed a whole brown paper
sandwich bag to mold I feel like it's
the mold process I kind of feel like
they may
very true but if you can time it right
it's a great step between the hanging
process and the jar it's that one if you
have to leave it out for if you've got
to be a way at work all day but you know
it should be in the jar but it's not dry
enough for the jar that bag is probably
gonna work for you
there's a company ideal for someone come
up with a brown paper sack that doesn't
have all those issues we just mentioned
the old shopping bags gallon bucket as
well oh yeah
doesn't seem that - I just prefer I
prefer the glass I feel like it doesn't
give me any flavor sure if you're doing
five gallon buckets get the I try to
find the good lids that have the rubber
seals and oh yeah and black buckets from
the coast or maybe we were Sherwin
Williams if your weed came in a turkey
bag it was not dried yes I'm gonna see
that we've covered the dry and curing
for the most part if you have any more
questions specific questions please send
me those questions there's a listener
that this episode was for I don't know
if she wants her name said on the air
but she just recently emailed me saying
she was excited I told her I was coming
she said she's excited if I missed
anything for you please let me know
anybody else let me know also I want to
I want to make this work for you
everybody needs to be a good dryer and
cure I know I skipped a whole bunch of
girl lessons we were doing grow lessons
on the show we got all the way through
veg we're in like mid veg phase just
before we're gonna flower and we've
jumped all over the place we've
harvested we've done outdoor grow we're
now curing we'll get back to the lessons
I've just been trying to do what's
current and what's relevant not trying
to mess you up throw you around we'll
get back to the lessons at the beginning
of the show I mentioned that the City
Council meeting has been moved city
council first planned the meeting for
Monday they knew it was a holiday they
still
wanted to meet but they changed their
mind the meeting will now be Tuesday at
7 o'clock at City Hall at 1:00 City Hall
plaza I wrote it down I said at the
beginning of the show it's on my phone I
better make sure but go there Jessie are
you gonna be there bro oh you know
[Music]
Tuesdays are actually much better for me
Tuesday was kind of hard our Monday was
kind of hard so Tuesday's way better
here so it's one City Hall place Tuesday
at 7 p.m. if you want to speak you have
to be there about 6:30 and sign up
please if you're gonna speak trying to
have some education about what you're
saying don't go in there and cuss them
out don't give them the finger I've seen
people yell at City Council before
trying to prove a point and that doesn't
help go in there and try to be if you've
got a suit jacket where that help us out
right nobody will have to speak if we do
it right a lot of us will show up and
we've got a spokesperson I know who I
would rather have speak for us Mike get
there first you go every week get there
sign up speak our part Mike knows
exactly what to say so if we need a
spokesperson he'll sign up and he
definitely will speak hopefully after he
speaks they just denied the thing what
they're looking for hasn't even been
submitted to or what they're talking
about hasn't been shown to them yeah
we're gonna preempted this maybe we
shouldn't do all 60 of us sitting there
at the City Council meeting telling them
why it sucks they'll just go okay you're
right they're pretty easy sometimes
sometimes especially on Tuesday after a
holiday no one's gonna be in the mood to
sit there you guys come out please come
out and support us at the City Council
if you're in Pueblo Colorado and you are
not working or babysitting or supporting
your own children or harvesting your own
plants or something like that you need a
really good excuse if you smoked pot if
you grow cannabis in the city of Pueblo
or the county you need to come to this
meeting cuz this applies to you please
come support us yeah this is a chance to
be this is real activism
you know that Facebook or Instagram
[ __ ] this is you know and come meet
Jesse and I yeah yeah that doesn't sound
like a real huge deal but I mean that's
some incentive we'll shake your head you
can talk to us you can give me show
ideas for sure yeah I'd love to meet you
guys
I like to meet the listeners it really
it's fun I did a couple people sometimes
it's awkward sometimes I'm just too damn
high for my own good alright guys I
really appreciate tm2 I can't even say
appreciate I really appreciate you guys
listening to the Cure lesson like I said
if you've got questions please let us
know cuz where is dab doubt as you and
though we may have gone over stuff we're
kind of experienced in sometimes we
forget the small details you missed this
part bro episode will actually be posted
in like three hours people will have
listened to it within four hours will
have a comment almost live pretty close
my friend that's listening late at night
I hope you're doing well
alright we're gonna wrap up this bar you
[Music]
down there
check him out it's a really great shop
also support highly educated titanium
don't forget about the new coupon code
at nature's green remedies your purchase
at nature's green remedies helps keep
homeless people in the Detroit area warm
it's getting cold as [ __ ] up there also
don't forget I need somebody to go and
count how many times I said the f-word I
don't think I said it all in this
episode so we're making progress
yeah see we talked about it earlier the
guest can say whatever they want I like
you to be yourself but I gotta be a good
host and be a good little boy what was
that coupon code again coupon code
helping hands
yeah so you can be a helping hand give a
helping hand it's two words helping
hands hands plural so type that in at
nature's green remedies calm that works
for any brand eye region etics is
currently sold out I apologize they're
cooking right now
the popcorn is popping so give it just a
few weeks here and I'll refill them and
everybody will be happy there will be
new stuff um guys join the forum at IRA
Genetics Colorado calm I tried to say I
read genetics Colorado calm but the
cottonmouth made my face stick together
so bad I don't know what even came out I
guess I'll just do this wrap-up part of
the show while Jesse sitting here
usually I play some music and come back
in it but there's no reason to take a
break because we're on a roll
hey please go leave me some comments on
stitcher and iTunes and give me a five
star rating on there I really like that
stuff make sure you follow us follow
Jesse on Instagram and Twitter
it's a hat Jesse grows on Instagram it's
Jesse grows OG on Twitter following he's
a good dude follow I read genetics on
Instagram and Twitter follow I grow
culture on Instagram and Twitter make
sure you follow us on Facebook just
participate we like the interaction we
get a lot of show ideas we gotta let it
want to info from you guys and it just
feels good to know who's listening here
we go here's the part that I always say
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher and also I read genetics
Colorado calm I am still making those
videos for YouTube I've posted 11 videos
now there are nothing fancy but they get
the point across so that people on
YouTube can catch the show I think more
people listening the better I want
everybody to listen and grow great
cannabis huge huge shout-outs went into
Spence and everybody at the garden of
Weeden they got big plans and I'm stoked
to see how that comes out and proud of
you guys big big plans big plans don't
be afraid to message us guys thanks for
listening take a phat dab give your mom
a hug for me
all right podcast well thanks again for
listening to a long episode I would love
to know what you think of these old
episodes send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
or send me a tweet at GF wih podcast and
let me know what you think of these old
episodes you guys I'm gonna wrap it up
before this file gets any longer until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me