you know it's a podcast world it's time
for episode number 206 if the girl from
your heart podcast I'm doing another
throwback Thursday episode this time I'm
doing episodes 36 37 and 38 of what used
to be known as the iGrow culture podcast
currently known as the girl from your
heart podcast before I get to the
episode I need to make a couple of
updates and disclaimers all of the
social media has changed the new social
media is @gf wih podcast on twitter it's
the girl from the heart a podcast on
facebook and if you like to send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also some of my ideas and
opinions may have changed some of my
methods and techniques may have changed
i've done over 200 episodes of this
podcast and i have learned a lot along
the way i hope you have too so if i say
something in these old episodes that I
contradict in a new episode go with the
new method because this is an ever
evolving industry and I learned
something every day and I hope you do
too so if I said somewhere dull hold it
against me ladies and gentlemen no
further ado here is episode 36 37 and 38
of the agriculture podcast thank you
guys for listening
[Music]
I'm your host today hey guys we've got
to go see Joey Cody I really want to say
also today we are celebrating
Clint's eighth year anniversary of
sobriety from alcohol yeah congrats
seriously you said it's nothing to to
toot about but that is eight years is
that strong it's easy now yeah yeah I'm
sure well congrats bro thanks for
sticking with it cuz I don't think we'd
hang out if you were the drunk you were
before oh I was a piece of [ __ ] I mean
I'm still a piece of [ __ ] I just don't
[Music]
pretty much anything under a thing it's
a depressant it is a depressant it
doesn't help me much you know I quit
drinking when I got my medical marijuana
card and my wife is easier happier when
I wake up I know where my money is I
know where my car is parked I appreciate
it I still drink occasionally like I'll
have a dough sekiz but for the most part
I quit like five or six years back just
cuz I got really good at throwing up in
bars
it was the Celtic in downtown Denver
thinking like yeah man we didn't get any
on you you're pro like 25 and all my
social life revolves around the bars and
the bar scene and it was a little while
but now it's just a big role yeah once I
moved away from my party town it was a
lot easier for me to quit drinking I
lived in Lawrence Kansas for a little
while and it's just really easy to be a
sponge in there then I came here where
there's a lot of drinking and I know
everybody so that sucked me in a little
bit but once I realized what I was doing
I just gave it up I can smoke all the
weed I can handle I took a gram dad last
night like why would I even need alcohol
in my life at all he's gonna do another
one's a night so I'm gonna do it again
tonight I filmed myself taking a gram
dad last night and the video was very
disappointing I put the dab on the
dabber kind of wonky and it just it
wasn't that was not an impressive video
it's gonna be a fun video if we could
have like the count from Sesame Street
[Music]
several inhales and exhales to get that
dab just partially because the way I
dropped it on the nail I didn't time it
right it was my breath and dab right get
the now using a teeny rig I'm gonna
practice big dab on a teeny rig dude
there's something about it
something about it speaking of big dad's
on teeny rigs this podcast is brought to
you by our good friends at cannabis
Grand Cru what's Grand Cru you ask you
gotta check out the website cannabis
Grand Cru com it's spelled Grande see
are you like the Motley Crue is a
private cannabis event in Aspen Colorado
hosted by the dry meet GATS me and
several of the industry leaders I'll
have a lot more information but please
check that out and support the Graeme
Gatsby cannabis Grand Cru com so we were
gonna talk about Joey Diaz before I got
done this a really huge sidetrack but in
[Music]
good that was I've seen a lot of
comedians and Anthony Jeselnik was one
of my favorites but every second of his
act from the time he walks out to the
time he says thank you every second that
is calculated yeah I can see him
counting between jokes I can see his
mouth going 1 2 3 and he counts to 11
and then he tells another joke really
yeah and so there's that style you know
what I mean he comes out and that's like
if that was a bad who would I compared
that to that's like rush every note is
they know what they're doing tonight
every single note all the way through
Jeselnik did that Joey Diaz came out and
kind of had an idea what he was gonna
say and just leveled us just being
himself good most of that maybe he's
told those bits two or three times one
of the bits he told I swear I heard him
make up on accident on the podcast just
a few days before he flew to Colorado
yeah he's a [ __ ] pro and he took that
like something like just right now we'd
be saying something and he'd be like oh
my god dog that's tremendous dog him
right in that [ __ ] down dog he can makes
15 minutes out of it brought yeah
brought it to us in Denver several days
later and ruined at the club with it my
stomach and ribs and this part of my jaw
right here was sore I was laughing so
hard I had to tense up my back because
it was hurting I had to move my muscle
tension somewhere else
you were sitting back like a little I
realized because I was sitting forward
on the edge of my seat the whole time I
loved it
and and we I was just sitting forward
and just excited it was so fun and and
just every word he was gonna say was
gonna make me laugh and Jeff Senate he
goes Clint you were laughing harder than
anybody else there it was good because
you appreciated the show and we talked
about being a good audience Clinton is a
performer and we know what it's like and
I'm a musician so I know what it's like
to have a stale audience yeah and it
wasn't us kissing his ass either Joey
was on fire [ __ ] yeah he was oh that was
the thing as he does about maybe an hour
hour 15 he'd somewhere in there yeah any
any crushes there was no point in there
when I was bored or anything and then
afterwards we're like oh can we meet him
you know we wanted to like get backstage
you know just want to say thank you
that's and spoiled you too Wow I took a
bunch of weed for Joey Diaz also know
jump we're gonna try to give him a
little bit of weed and so then all of a
sudden keep he talks to every single
person that wants to talk to him he came
out to the hallway of the club and just
hung out the only exit that you could
take and he's just standing there and
you could shake his hand and get a
picture he took a picture with everybody
everybody everybody he asks you your
name and then addresses you by name in
the conversation yeah he remembers your
name for that talk he's he's that kind
of guy if you listen to Diaz you know if
he probably still remembers our names if
we see him again he'd be like oh [ __ ]
Clint right Clint right dog is Ecology
dog every other word is dog and
[ __ ] we need to get some ski caps
bro and be Opie and kin jacks for
Halloween every day yeah that's a man
beard over there bro just gotta get my
wife killed somehow and then hook up
with a prostitute and I'm sad
just kind of awkward silence few find
beard trees growing along the Pacific
Northwest was plucking beard hairs out
of his beard and throwing them out the
window in hopes to plant little beard
trees I'm just trying to get back to the
community so everybody hangs out takes a
picture he taps me on the Joey Diaz taps
me on the shoulder and walks away and
says Ross the Jeff you know I love you
right [ __ ] and I was like holy
[ __ ] he just called me [ __ ] and
Clint was smooth about it he stuck out
his hand and wanted that one final life
this is my one-on-one he goes hey I'm
honest and I'm an open mic comedian and
what you did I think he told him
something about what you did just
changed my mic or something like that
well I just it was real inspiring yes I
think I told him and he goes dog you're
an open microphone come here dog and
like just took like seven steps away
from where we were into this little like
kind of ambient area and had a talk with
Clint about open mic and stand-up comedy
you wanna tell the world what they told
what he told you words you don't keep
that to yourself no I was so cool it was
so cool just to have this like
one-on-one with a legend in my mind he's
a legend and I you know I don't get
starstruck or stuff like that because
he's a cool [ __ ] guy and he just he
was so personable but he was just like
Dawg you gotta write an hour a day
that's all you gotta do
maybe for two weeks you're not gonna get
nothing but you just gotta write and
you've got a right and you gotta keep
after it you got to get on stage and I
you know and I was just sitting there
just listening you know and that's cuz
I'm not trying to tell him anything I'm
just Joey this is awesome and then you
know and I wasn't he was trying to get
out of there too so it's like I
appreciate it man we're gonna let you
get out of here I hope you have a great
time in Denver and okay he's great he
didn't want to leave he liked hanging
out and just having a conversation you
know what I mean he was like you could
see you could see tired but he was just
like damn I don't
leave it was a great guy and so if this
gets back to Joey Diaz thank you for the
great show thanks for hanging out thanks
for the advice
we love you and you gotta you gained a
fan for life by just hanging out for
that hour times to [ __ ] yeah uh and also
to thanks for just taking a minute like
you're a busy dude we know you had to
get to the hotel and smoke that blunt
they gave you [ __ ] yeah and those
animals that you got thanks for just
hanging out that's [ __ ] cool you took
a minute that means a lot he's been in
the longest yard he's on Joe Rogan's
podcast he's got his own podcast if you
can take an ear bashing if you've got
some balls listen to the Church of
what's happening now with Joey Coco Diaz
and Lisa at it's not for Gentiles they
tell you to go [ __ ] yourself in the
first episode you listen so be prepared
but if you can get past that it's a
great show though he's funny as [ __ ] and
then and and if you get a chance to see
him live there's there's if you miss out
you will be you will regret it if you
have an adult diaper where one piss my
pants I was laughing so hard I'm not
leaving for one moment if I I was so
happy to be there reasonable we saw him
at the Denver improv beautiful Club
beautiful Club I'd love to go back there
we will be back there also we made a new
friend that night his name's Abdullah
you just traveled to Mississippi and I
hope you're doing well there my friend I
hope everything worked out for you yeah
find us on the internet find me on some
social media you said you don't do that
but he actually downloaded the podcast
while he was sitting next to us so
there's a good chance he's listening
find me bro hope everything worked out
alright um I wanna talk about the City
Council meeting for a minute but first I
gotta do this part this podcast is
brought to you by a highly-educated
titanium I said educated its educated
sorry if you're using high-grade
concentrates you deserve a high grade
titanium male don't trust the Chinese
nail or some American knockoff made of
cheap crappy metals trust the industry
leader trust the brand that Rasta Jeff
uses goddamn love getting choked up it's
such a good ad trust highly educated
titanium more information on highly
educated products check out
www.imtcva.org
highly educated products are available
at Aqualab technologies comm and also if
you're in Colorado illusions glass Azzam
and I also heard JP Wellness has some
highly educated stuff they don't pay for
ads but if you're in Colorado go shop
there and tell them that that's where
you heard about this we'll do another
quick just while we're at it this
podcast is brought to you by nature's
green remedies comm check out nature's
green remedies calm for many of your
favorite brands mile hike an adventure
gauge green I read genetics there there
check them out when you shop at nature's
green remedies use coupon code helping
hands for thirteen percent off your
order and nature's green remedies will
contribute three dollars of every order
to a local homeless shelter in their
area to keep some folks warm so help
keep some folks warm this winter
using coupon code helping hands at
nature's green remedies calm got a
couple more ads but I'll sneak those in
in just a little bit there's a city
council meeting on Tuesday there's some
hilarious [ __ ] to talk about from that
meeting I go to every city council
meeting for the most part everybody
there knows me I'm used to the police
chief and the fire chief and the city
manager in the city attorney and the
council members coming up and saying hi
or waving or giving me two minutes to
talk to him about whatever not everybody
in our community is and I was sort of
early to the meeting I had signed up to
speak and from the seat I usually sit in
I can't see the doors that people walk
in from but I can see the city staff and
the City Council real well and they're
kind of milling around waiting for the
meeting to start and their decorum all
just they freeze like when somebody I
don't know runs through a room naked and
the rest of the well-dressed people go
wait did that just happen everybody
freezes for a second everybody froze for
a second so i swivel my head did I see
two and a quarter sets of dreadlocks
walk in the door
[Music]
thanks for coming guys Adam and Angela
thank you guys a lot for joining me to
the City Council meeting your numbers
made a difference we'll talk about that
in a minute two people or Jedi staring
me dude
I could feel one guy's eyes cooking a
hole through my shirt and reading my
soul like I was like I like looked at
him and nodded like huh I'm not sure why
you're standing in my translucent has he
seen a ghost and so like people start
speaking and I go I look at them while
they speak right and then I get the
creepy feeling again and I look to my
left and that dude is like this at me
and for the listeners it's an intense
stare but like this yeah and I never met
the man there's another guy who fits the
exact description of rich white guys
like rich white councilmen he's who
you'd think of if I saw him I go yes
City Council guy run some [ __ ] city
manager looked at him he goes who's the
guy in the Hat I saw him say it like he
didn't care that I was watching him it
was kind of awkward
that was funny through the whole meeting
he kept staring at my little group of
people so in a city council meeting they
do they have a little structure they
have their agenda meeting right at the
beginning and then they have like a
little they save the Pledge of
Allegiance and they pray and then they
open up the floor and they say they do
public comment and then right after that
they say thank you or they do City
contributions or something they called
it they call it public forum where
anyone from the public can speak for
five minutes and then they have council
commentary right after that where any of
the council members there was a part
right before that where the lady goes
this is the part where we would normally
say thanks to the people that have
contributed to the community last week
we did a hundred and one luckily there
are none this week my little group
chuckle be can I go huh no shoutouts on
the episode this week was what I said
like Mike said after that they let each
council member speak so the first
council member speaks and he's like so
first off I want to say thanks to this
person in this person and I chuckled a
little bit I was like huh and the next
one is like I want to say thanks to this
person so five people in a row go and
they all basically did shoutouts and by
the fourth one I giggled I giggled out
loud and the girl next to me
Angela giggled and then Adam leaned over
and giggle then we were all just like
Church giggling and Angela had the balls
to say it she goes shoutouts and we just
couldn't even handle ourselves anymore
it was so funny
wasn't at this meeting but her little
council commentary for the most of the
meetings is its blander than any
advertising you ever heard it's just
it's almost a bulletin board reading
session for a bunch of random local
events I mean her shoutouts are always
come to the Pinewood Derby or come down
to this softball game next week or we're
doing an Eastside Park clean up like
super duper simple shoutouts it's kind
of fun to watch every week the City
Council does some shoutouts brother
there's like 20 minutes of solid like
and big shout out to anyone one person
goes and also thanks to make it Parks
and Rec and it was hilarious hilarious
if you dare watch it's it's a play like
anything you would buy tickets to see
it's just about stuff that's usually
really this may get me in trouble but
it's really funny I should say this you
have to address the president of City
Council as madam president you don't
have to send a very condescending tone
of them were like yes $5.00 per episode
I promised it's gonna happen I love it
they have to they have to come after a
trees green remedies gets a refill but
there's been quite a bit of controversy
in like I don't know friction I suppose
you'd call it between the City Council
and city staff and members of City
Council dude a couple of months ago the
council commentary thing was like the
Politis book you know [ __ ] you you have
ever heard of the City Council man was
in the paper saying stuff two or three
of the other ones was doing was illegal
and he kept using the phrase shadow
government and like they were ready like
I seriously was waiting for him to rise
up with ice picks where I could hear the
whole production crew - that was really
privileged being a nerd like 11 tech
gear I was loving it oh yeah all the
sound equipment I could hear the camera
crew behind me it was awesome there in
five four three we're live I posted a
picture on Instagram of myself that was
on the knives on the news and someone's
like dude you look paranoid actually
that facial expression was when the city
council president announced her
resignation that's the face I was taken
[Music]
up in the council meeting you've got the
college education you got the good
vocabulary I've got the dreadlocks and
the beard they don't want to talk to me
they they stare me down just sitting in
council if I walked up there then well
you got five minutes and they would've
pulled out their phones and it started
tweeting I think and if I went up there
they'd be like we're not gonna let the
guy with the felony come a little closer
please yeah so City Council meeting Mike
went and spoke against the proposed
ordinance that was coming up we you want
to tell us how that went so that I don't
have to fumble through it fumble um the
proposed ordinance is still sitting at
the planning zoning level they are
what's called a recommending body they
suggest things to the City Council and
the City Council can run with that idea
or have them amend that idea in some way
or they can kill it altogether usually
city council tells Planning and Zoning
like hey we'd like to see this and then
they go work on that it's my
understanding that this is not that kind
of ordinance this is something Planning
and Zoning has been working on is their
own effort to sort of show City Council
as a way to solve some of the complaints
they've been receiving essentially
Planning and Zoning is fired up because
people can see and smell pot and that's
bad as far as they're concerned and they
would like to come up with rules and
regulations so that no one ever sees or
smells pot and if you're trying to grow
your own marijuana or know someone that
is you can see how problematic that
might become if you've got to get it all
the way back out of sight and out of
mind and you can't do that in your own
home the problems with this ordinance
sort of spin out of control real rapidly
and we as far as the community goes I
think don't like it on every every part
of it is bad and so we tried to rally up
people with the last episode and a
couple of other things to get down to
the meeting and this time we had a
pretty good show of support at the City
Council meeting on Tuesday night I spoke
during public forum and sort of pleaded
with them to think about how many people
in the city they're affecting with these
rules how many people's rights under
amendment 20 or many amendment 64 would
be restricted by these rules
I mean now all the sudden you've got
roommates trying to figure out who gets
to exercise their constitutional rights
and who doesn't because you can only
exercise so many of them at one time in
a home with the plan Mike with
statistics and counts he told the City
Council how many patients there are in
the city and county he told them how
many of them have a caregiver he told
him how much it cost to make a facility
like they're required most of the people
that spoke at City Council the City
Council kind of gave them the look of
yeah we've heard this before in your
back again this week Thanks gotcha
when Mike spoke they all kind of sat up
they actually leaned forward and
listened I was paying more attention to
their faces and just listening to Mike
but uh they like it when I speak a
number of council members have told me
like thanks for having like some data to
back up what you're saying are you
taking the time to read a difference
they get a lot of rambling at them and
like angry rambling and you know you're
fired up and you're passionate I'm not
I'm not a big fan of public speaking it
makes me incredibly nervous honestly I
we did our best to calm you down
you said I'm nervous as [ __ ] and so we
just started talking to him but
somebody's got to do it and I've been
the one that's been biting that bull
lately so I went down to his day and I
and said my piece and honestly like
usually when people bring supporters
down for their issue lately when the the
trash haulers speak there's like five or
ten trash hollers behind them that
really take a minute to cheer and clap
as soon as the whoever's got enough to
speak is done speaking and I
half-expected what were there six or
seven people behind us maybe Benson
there's about eight of us oh he plus us
I wasn't sure how well I did when I get
up and I start giving a speech honestly
I go into a weird little zone where I
know what kind of what I'm saying and
I'm prepared to say you know something
specific but once I get up and start
talking
there isn't a filter between like brain
mic and mouth mic there's nobody being
like don't cuss or make sure you
emphasize this it's all the best part
adrenaline did you realize what you said
at the end you stood up and he said
thank you for my time and he walked away
from
[Music]
by coming out and showing support by you
speaking and there was another guy that
went to another meeting who spoke about
his family and how this was affecting
them in such a dramatic way did you guys
make a difference did we all make a
difference
is first in a while okay guys so Monday
we had a city meeting or starting Monday
or since Monday we've had a city council
meeting of planning and zoning meeting
and at County Commissioners meeting at
each one of those three meetings they
were discussing rules that would take
away your ability to grow in your own
home will emit the amount of plants
you're you're growing to an arbitrary
number that they just picked they
decided I that ought to be enough good
enough will capitate twelve in the city
or sixteen or eighteen in the county and
if you live up in Beulah and have four
hundred acres and all that's one
property you can only grow eighteen
plants there it doesn't matter how many
different residents are set up on your
property and none of that they're just
really terrible rules so the community
kind of tried to rally we did the
podcast episode there was another
community meaning if the daily grind
there's another one tomorrow at four
o'clock if anyone wants to come on
Friday Monday morning so never mind guys
are late sorry we just have to record
another one for Sunday but the progress
we made you got everybody that could
make it made it everybody that felt like
they wanted to speak spoke I met the
gentleman who was quoted in the
chieftain who he's a young guy he's a
little younger than me I'd say he's
maybe 25 he's got a wife who's sick he's
got a mother-in-law who's sick and he's
got a child with cancer
and she's their caregiver he has a job
where he can't consume so he's just
taking care of them in his testimony I
mean it was like I was throwing
spitballs and he rolled up in a tank
like they could they heard what I had to
say it all three meetings and they
appreciated me coming down and saying my
piece but when he got up and spoke they
hit the brakes hard so you opened up for
this guy so what's come of your guys's
work did they stop it did they hesitate
are they gonna rework it the county is
they delayed the vote again to do more
research I think for two weeks okay
maybe three watch the County
Commissioners website they post their
agendas on Fridays usually their
meetings are usually Tuesday so you get
about five days to check it out and
heads up the city has the Planning and
Zoning Commission delayed presenting
this plan to City Council by two months
and they have given those that came to
speak at the Planning and Zoning meeting
a seat at the table while these roles
get reworked so a couple of us they came
to speak against and a couple of people
that came to speak for will be sitting
at the table while these get redone
that's something I kind of wanted to ask
you is hue you said when you address
City Council you actually said guys
please find somebody that knows what
they're talking about when you do this
you look them straight in the face like
you guys don't know anything about weed
please find somebody that knows what
they're talking about put them on your
committee if I almost considered
volunteering or asking you how I get to
be a part of that because I am a legal
grower and I'm a caregiver I'm not a
black market guy I think I can set a
good example it's more than once I've
fantasized about being able to like
kidnap and hood a member of city
government like sneak him through your
backyard and this is what it looks like
when it's done right this is what legal
looks like this is following the rules
like yeah because unless you've blown
your house up or you set your garage on
fire overloaded the transformer behind
your house they've never come to your
home that was Mike's main point to City
Council he said the guys you're messing
with are the not the
caregivers those are commercial growers
that are making a weed drop you're
making those rules to enforce upon
medical caregivers and you're totally
missing the point
yeah I think they caught on I think
we've got more time to deal with it so
did you get on that committee work it
out what then Oh like there's a handful
of us that are scrambling if you're
listening to this show and you are
interested in cannabis advocacy you can
find me on Twitter
Nimmo Punk 15 just like it sounds any mo
p1k 1/5 or I just created a Facebook
page it was something somebody else at
one of the meetings brought up it'd be
great if we had a Facebook page where we
could kind of kick out community
activism info and organize people for
when the meetings are because all of
that can be very confusing and I know
[Music]
this might sound like if you're on a
state or if you're out of Pueblo like
this is not like you're you're like oh
man these guys are just talking about
hometown stuff you guys gonna watch the
City Council wherever you're at I local
politics is interesting because it's the
stuff that most affects you so you
should be kind of keeping an eye on your
local council anyway and B if you're
trying to legalize marijuana on any
level getting the people that are
elected right above you is the place to
start
yeah so that was more what I wanted to
say I know that there's probably some
people like Oh cuz I know I was
[Music]
5,000 Facebook friends I had close to
7,000 followers on Facebook but Facebook
[Music]
as much as I used to be then I login to
Facebook and post if you are on Facebook
cousins we do comedy in wild cousins to
locations to serve Colorado seriously
guys hi grow indoor growing supplies is
the gross store where rasta Jeff shops
they give me everything I need at a
great freaking price check them out
there in Pueblo and in Denver 62 71
Beach Street unit F up in Denver or the
Pueblo location on the east side 618
East 4th Street don't be afraid to the
east side is just right over the
railroad track so you just go over the
tracks and then merge and park and
you're there pretty much little tiny
tiny shop but they'll get you whatever
you want they will order it they've got
plenty of room to stop
in the back until you come pick it up
check him out tell burn I said hi tell
Jessie I said hi when you're paying tell
them yo I listen to the hydro culture
podcast and Rasta Jeff told me to make
sure I tell you and we'll see what they
do for you they said they're working on
a special for me they don't know what
they're gonna do yet but get in there
and tell them that you're listening to
the show while we're at it big love to
treat Duggar calm this episode is
brought to you in part by Treehugger
comm live music lifestyle magazine
seriously go check out tree hugger com4
cool hippie concert and festival news
and reviews it's all the hippie stuff if
you got dreadlocks and you go on tour if
you're wearing a pen d if you listen to
sound tribe go check out this this pug
this website dude my buddy Ryan puts it
together
Ryan's a great dude just go check him
out support in place thanks a lot Ryan
all right that's enough commercials I
like doing the commercials in the middle
you don't like overload them at the
start if you listen to a lot of podcasts
like I do I like that you break it up
it's like you know what we're gonna talk
for a little bit we're gonna get off
that subject here's some more
commercials it's like watching TV or
something I learned to do them at the
beginning like Rogen does yeah because
if I prefer you don't but if you want to
you just skip right through so if you
look on my table I've not been paid for
this yet but there may be in the future
I ordered naturebox dude I approve of
naturebox they do not sponsor the show
in any way yet but it's awesome it
tastes good it's good serving sizes
I've been replacing by sugary desires
with something from nature box and I
feel better man my teeth aren't gonna
rot away as quickly my goats aren't
gonna die I'm not gonna get diabetes and
that [ __ ] is good it's tasty I wouldn't
go to the store and buy that because at
the store this don't sound like a paid
commercial dude but this is the truth at
the store there's chocolate covered this
discover that there's crispy this
there's and oh man so you just want to
chop lady one but then when naturebox
sends you a box alike there was tomato
basil covered almonds in there well
let's crack one open listeners don't go
there yet because we're gonna get you a
promo code on the next episode
[Music]
for the commercial for nature taking
care of myself while I take a couple of
mom right before I'm an ask Clint Clint
came to the show because he wants to
talk about not professional-grade we'd
had some questions he's like I'm not a
pro and your weed kills me I'm seriously
like I'll take one hit of a ball and
that's good for me like I'm done like
even right now
I took one you guys saw how minimal I
took of that one and it's [ __ ] me up
that's why I got all quiet when you were
talking you know I'm just gonna level
with you cuz I'm it's just it's too
strong too fast I've only been smoking
for two months you don't need rocket
fuel yet no I need [ __ ] nah give me
that unleaded [ __ ] that that 309 [ __ ]
number 85 [ __ ] the 85 octane and not
the turbo boost yeah please do not put
nitrous in my [ __ ] so you don't want
to take a half gram dad but the thing is
I'm getting like a huge high off of one
hit and that's and I know we've said
this since before I was smoking we said
start slow now if I think here in a
couple of minutes like it didn't hit me
well enough I might take another one I'm
not doing that today I gotta work
tonight but that's the things I need to
know how do I get my handsome on some
like mediocre weed unless I'm growin
sore fine in the ditch somewhere
my smartass answer is just go to the
dispensary or maybe you need something
more high in CBD THC would be beneficial
for you alone here there are a ton of
people that have either avoided
marijuana because the legalities or you
know for whatever reason and are now
walking into a dispensary going mm-hmm
and yeah they've rookie cookie is the
product name that sticks in my mind
there was an article about at the Denver
Post not too long ago is that an actual
Colorado product I'm pretty sure that is
a product that's sitting on Colorado
dispensaries that's just a cookie cookie
walked in as a 55 year old dude into a
dispensary and hadn't really consumed
cannabis ever and I saw rookie cookies I
would like clap and laugh that's me do
you have rookie weed too and they're
like well it's legal now what's the bar
I can join the military and go smokes
and that's fine but it's just I don't
want kids starting like with with some
goddamn Bruce Banner little [ __ ] yeah
it's like four hours I can't do anything
like I'm just like alright I'm like I
guess I'm going through the cosmos right
now my mom used to smoke occasionally
not to bust my mom out but back in the
day my mom's [ __ ] hippie dude she
smoked weed back in the day and she's
slowly quit and she doesn't smoked for
years now that she's got a good job and
[ __ ] but I joke with her every
occasionally you know like it was smoked
joint mom and she's like I would but
your your weed's too damn strong
she's like the last time I smoked with
you guys it was just hell she was a
pothead dude she's the wake-and-bake
like I remember when I was little earned
my uncle's hang out smoke joints all day
long and now she's like nope that weed
gets me too high at my uncle's were the
same way too they used to be that's
where I learned my [ __ ] was from my
uncles that were pious and party animals
and now now they're like dude you're
crazy that weights too good like it's
too good that's kind of funny
yeah well and then you're gonna get
those guys that used to smoke eight
joints and not get high back to the 70s
because it was dirt wheat and then they
come in they're like well [ __ ] I could
smoke whole joint why would I even be
worried about it and it's been 20 years
so they have zero tolerance and all of a
sudden they're thinking oh this is gonna
be the same thing as that [ __ ] dirt
weed if they go home joint take five
hits and get halfway through it yeah by
then it's too far the Colorado rules the
laws say that they're supposed to have
every product tested even the buds so
they should have a THC level turn it on
the jars we're not there yet a lot of
the shops aren't complying they just
can't afford it and there's not enough
testing facilities Yeah right once we
get to that point you need something
like closer to ten well you've been
smoking is in the 20 range 20% yeah
that's tested in the twenty sevens
Spence actually hit 29 from those
Ryann's Rhino from seed the Spence crew
also shot up the steep hill Haley labs
are the ones that test our stuff yeah
good job but that's what I'm getting at
is like there's just like I don't know
you know I guess that was more my
question was like is there a strain that
you would recommend to a newbie 50/50
hybrid it's not too overpowering it's
got a good body it's got a good high but
for me it doesn't hit me hard I almost
got rid of it but a lot of my friends
are like - you've got to grow the flow
so it's still here flows what I liked
for days for a long time when you've got
a whole bunch of stuff to do but can't
be in pain all day I roll up a little
flow for the morning and I'd be good all
day and it wasn't near as powerful
that's what I wanted for evenings but
maybe like zine Jillybean might be good
for you yeah just something to maintain
you know like I'm not trying to get all
[ __ ] blasted and go take a nap like I
gotta do the laundry
you know speaking of laundry these
cashews was that almonds or cashews
they're coconut cashews really good
those are delicious dude naturebox all
day that's why I set him down because I
wanted to have one of the time because I
was because I loved it so much and now
I'm a guy who is listened to Rogen's
podcast and everybody's podcast that
says oh go get a cheese box this
converted me right now it did I'm gonna
go home and and if I can remember and
not be high all the time
I think Nerdist even promotes naturebox
so they did a free thing they're like if
you order now it's free you get a free
box I didn't pay anything for this box
of munchies that we're eating
they came straight to the door but now
every month I'm gonna get a box for five
I think I think it's worth what I would
yeah it's like the Columbia House of
snacks response free stop for a second I
approve naturebox
hey naturebox if you're listening
contact me for a sponsorship because I
support your product and it would work
well did you hear that awesome ad we
just did yeah we bumped you up a lot
we've been recording for a long time and
I guess some news so save me a couple of
minutes to read a couple of listener
comments but tell us about the new
cannabis news that you were telling me
about when he first showed up to the
house the local prophets inside oh the
the locals Pueblo city budget came out
this week and the city seems to think
they're gonna get 500,000 worth of
marijuana taxes wait for the punchline
the punchline to that is is the the
number that they're gonna get next year
is zero not five hundred thousand and
it's zero instead of five hundred
thousand because we don't have any
marijuana businesses you actually have
to actually have to have
a marijuana business located in your
city to enjoy taxes from those
businesses in the public county has
already made about 500 grand this year
between the wreck shops and the medical
shops the local tax and the little
kickback that the state sends on the
statewide tags look most of City Council
in the face recently they seem like an
intelligent group of people where are
they predicting this money comes from if
we're not allowed to have a dispensary
the the city manager puts that budget
together and hands it to City Council
that's part of the meeting we saw the
other night and so they're probably
looking at it thinking the same thing
everyone in Pueblo the red the chieftain
today and the three of us are thinking
is well if it's really zero because we
don't have any marijuana businesses
where is this five hundred thousand the
irony in that is I honestly I rarely go
to City Council meetings and I will now
I'm an anxious person and I felt
intimidated to go I've broken the ice
and I'm not afraid anymore you'll see me
there more often thank you I don't know
what I was gonna say it remind me where
I was headed with that oh right at the
beginning one of their first things was
and we're proud to announce it last week
where our budget was like four hundred
and eighty four thousand dollars or
million dollars short
but we've presented to you a balanced
budget this week and that's one of the
things we fixed in our work sessions but
they didn't really present a balanced
budget
they just revealed their secret they
added in five hundred thousand dollars
that they're not gonna get they made it
up a little worried about if that 500
grand pot number was in there before
they carved out the three and a half
million or whatever that they carved out
over the last week they might have been
four million short and they only filled
the hole three and a half million worth
because they're pretending there's
another half million that's gonna come
out a couple of dispensaries build
within city limits the licensing alone
is three hundred third I think it's like
three thousand dollars for one each
license you have to have several
depending on what you're doing is five
grand to the city and the state
so it's essentially ten grand to do just
to grow ten grand to do the store ten
grand to do the hash making
so if they open five shops they make 25
G's right away minimum the cities are
five shops 50 G's oh you mean split it
but but the problem with that though is
what they're worried about is that you
can't just allow one cuz that's monopoly
and you can't just allow five cuz that's
still a monopoly in my opinion you can't
say oh you got here too late you're not
allowed to start that's not the American
Way this town doesn't really need more
than and this sounds ridiculous coming
from me but if a shop did it right three
or four shops would be more than enough
for this city I agree but that's that's
on the businesses to decide later like
oh you know I don't think we can make
money by starting one so yeah we're
gonna get influx of five and then all of
a sudden it's gonna be like wow we're
all not doing great but this guy's not
doing well at all and then he closes
down and we're gonna see that one of
these days we're gonna see the first pot
shop closed down we're gonna be like
that's weird
like if the liquor store goes out we're
like oh we get it because there's a
liquor store on everything every corner
[Music]
no but what I'm saying is like we see a
liquor store on every and there's a bar
on every other one so we see all these
liquor stores in a liquor store goes out
we're like oh yeah of course it did
there's super competition yeah that's
what's gonna happen with weed and so
prices are gonna have to start dropping
and that's better for everybody if
that's in Washington right now you're
looking at $60 and change for a gram of
legal marijuana yeah look dude you just
gave me a look that you shouldn't give
me because it's nuts but if you say $60
for a gram of marijuana you need to slap
yourself in the face with your own penis
good podcast you need to go to nature's
green remedies dot-com use coupon code
helping hands and order yourself some
frickin high-grade seeds I recommend IRA
Genetics gage Green genetics or maybe
some alpha chronic we actually talking
about $60 grams is that because of a
supply and demand thing yeah that's the
all of the shops in Washington there's a
very few shops that are open their
supply is extremely limited they didn't
have the time to bring in the crops
before this all went live like with the
licensing you weren't allowed to grow
for very long before shops were allowed
to open so they just haven't had any
time in a year to when you know shop
numbers have risen significantly
production numbers you know ahead of
time to come in all of that will change
a bit but it's gonna be a year too
before you can buy a reasonable gram
legally in Washington Seattle has no
idea what's coming to them I know a
little secret right now Seattle got some
cool news there's a lot of cool stuff we
didn't I'm always constantly afraid of
like whatever I get this gonna kill me
like is this the one that sends me into
like a panic or something like that like
unfortunately so far you know I've
gotten really [ __ ] high and it hasn't
like I haven't had like this huge bad
trip or anything like that then you're
probably not gonna know that's the thing
is I can talk myself out of it because I
know I'm on drugs right now hi now
you're just killing cancer yeah
[Music]
I was nearly I was I was like I felt
like I was on drugs I was jumping around
I keep saying to yourself committing
crimes how this sounds fun
[Music]
this is all an illusion I do live in
Colorado when I take dad's and I've got
the legal allowed amount of cannabis so
I all right we wrapping it up we're
close to an hour Mike you got any plugs
Ernie [ __ ] to wrap the show up with I
don't guys if you are a cannabis
supporter in the City of Buffalo
Colorado the county of Pueblo Colorado
please follow Mike Nikon on Twitter it's
[Music]
find him on there because he will tweet
when all the meetings are he's going to
take that responsibility the City
Council meetings that we need to go to
the commissioner's meetings Planning and
Zoning meetings if it feels like there's
a cannabis presence needed Mike will
start tweeting that stuff out for us
agriculture will start retweeting that
we'll have a little community action
it's all cleanse we'll help
it's all clean it's your turn buddy yes
find me on Facebook and Instagram tall
clint's twitter tall Clint it's all I
just stuck with the same thing because I
want to brand it I guess I don't know
works well words yeah yeah and I'm Tom
and I'm Clint I hope you don't think it
looks like another word the first time I
saw it did not look like it Clint
[Music]
that's funny I made it that word out
that's weird
yeah well we're not trying to offend
people and plugs check me out I no
longer have the IRA genetics Facebook
page that sucks so follow a culture on
Instagram and Twitter agriculture has a
Facebook page of course you can follow
me I've started posting dad videos and
weed pictures on at rasta Jeff 4/20 that
was hard to say for some reason um I
want to give a couple of shout outs
people left me some really cool comments
on iTunes thank you guys for leaving the
iTunes comments this first comment is
from hippie nurse 710 what up hippie
nurse hope you're doing well you were
having a rough day I hope listening to
the podcast and hearing a shout out
makes you smile you've got a rough job
and I appreciate what you do
she's a nurse at night for that she
doesn't know how much respect I have for
it but maybe she will know her comment
says if she gave us five stars thanks
for that her comment says I've been a
listener since episode one I can hear a
difference in the tone quality and flow
of each episode as you progress you guys
are getting better and better with each
episode I love that you keep it light
and informative it makes it easier for
newbies like myself to understand keep
up the good work
yeah that's what we're aiming for so
thanks a lot hippie nurse thank you for
listening since episode one she used to
always she would tweet me and message me
like when is the new episode coming when
is the new episode coming I was like it
comes out at 7:10 in the morning on
Mondays and she said I work nights can
it come out at 4:20 a.m. now it comes
out that's why it pops up kind of
randomly late at night on Sundays for
the listeners and she sent us a nice
comment so thanks it works out well I
hope you're doing well happy nurse yeah
we need some more five stars guys please
well we got another one that's this guy
Billy Bob ray no it's Billy Bobo ray
Billy Bobo ray yeah Billy Boba Fett's
ray that could be the guy girls she's
not just from organs too far Ian
or his middle name could be Bobo also
you might have the same from my up with
a bad handle though bro to listen to but
be prepared for some stoner moments like
where was this conversation going and
what were we talking about award-winning
hash award-winning flowers random [ __ ]
comes out I used to script almost
everything I used to listen to like this
good evening thank you for listening to
high culture podcast my name is Jeff and
now I write like bullet points and try
to rant on those bullet points and keep
it moving because it feels a lot better
but that does create those donor moments
that's for sure
Billy buh buh ray yeah that's when he
wrote he gave us four stars so that's
cool enough Billy Ray Billy Bob we
apologize for butchering your name
making it fun it's good I don't think we
had any where's this going moments I
think this whole episode was aware the
hell is going I felt like Jeff was
trying to drag me back to the point guys
I hope you heard me trying to put him
back on track
[Music]
I wish that I could get my nature box hi
growing or growing supply all right
we're gonna wrap this up guys
I have Jesse coming back in a couple of
episodes I'm not sure if he'll be back
this week or in about ten days he's hard
to get here he's a busy man he's married
to work several jobs he's an awesome
dude he's worth waiting for but we're
going to discuss building your grow room
people have asked also a listener said
they have a 500 dollar budget and they
would like to learn how to grow a small
grow room to supply themselves I have a
couple of good ideas on how that might
work so I'm gonna work on that for you
we'll put an episode together I have a
couple of news articles that I did not
read on this show so they'll be coming
up in the next episode thank you guys
for listening I'm gonna read that part
that I read at the end of the show goes
like this now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for Agriculture find the
review section give me a 5 or a 4 star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and
I'll read your comments on the show
stitcher listeners you guys can do the
same thing they've updated stitcher and
the comments work now don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is archived on
I read genetics Colorado com make sure
you browse around on I read genetics
Colorado comm check out the gallery
check out the genetics page if you're
interested join the forum I I will
communicate with you through that forum
quite often since Facebook kind of gave
me the middle finger I spend a lot more
time on the forum I'm also adding videos
to YouTube right now there's nothing
fancy as I get caught up the videos are
getting better and better and better so
if you can't listen through iTunes
stitcher or the website you can always
check them out on YouTube I post some
pictures in there also that may be
interesting to you also a big shout out
to my ninja spin so I want to thank you
guys for listening thank you guys for
coming to the podcast tonight taking
some time out of your night thanks if
you guys got questions like Jeff said
just ask it man ask the thing asked to
answer the questions that's what I'm
here for you know I don't feel I'm not
here to entertain myself I just feel
really great to put this out but I'm
here to help everybody out got a good
grasp on this I love podcasting so I'm
here to help you guys out
next time guys take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
welcome to episode number 37 of the
iGrow culture podcast it's me again
Rasta Jeff thanks for joining me joining
me on the microphone today is Jesse from
hydro how you doing bro how's it going
guys
doing pretty good dude thanks for coming
in this episode we're gonna talk a
little bit about building your grow
space honestly this may end up being a
multi-episode discussion because I know
we're gonna leave stuff out we're gonna
forget things we took quite a few notes
we wrote quite a bit of stuff down and
the more I wrote the more I feel like we
were missing so we're gonna try to keep
notes on to what we're missing while we
go and we'll keep this conversation
going but before we get to that part we
got to pay some bills this podcast is
brought to you by cannabis Grand Cru
cannabis Grand Cru Aspen will take place
at the sky hotel in downtown Aspen
Colorado Friday November 14th through
Sunday November 16th 2014
what is Grand Cru I'm glad you asked 10
crew represents cannabis culture
lifestyle business and community in a
premier event setting the event includes
lecture lectures seminars experiential
learning and entertainment centered
around the cannabis business in the US
and around the world industry
professionals and consumers alike are
invited to network and enjoy this year's
event in beautiful Aspen Colorado make
sure you visit the Grand Cru village an
area exclusive to ticket holders that
will host Colorado's best dispensaries
including wellspring collective from
Denver and silver peak apothecary and
Aspen located at the sky hotel at their
legendary pull deck the village will
showcase the latest products from top
manufacturers and companies in this very
intimate setting this is a Members Only
event due to the current nature of laws
in the state of Colorado attendance of
cannabis EBIT events must be by
invitation in order to protect the event
and our guests please complete the
information request at the bottom of
their website for your free membership
members will be sent information
directly on how to purchase tickets
located in majestic
has been and nestled in the Rocky
Mountains the event will take advantage
of the amazing community and provide
networking and fun for folks in the
legal cannabis industry new speakers are
being announced every day confirmed
speakers include Mason T vert John Hunt
and Meg Collins check out cannabis grand
cru dot-com for details only give a big
huge shout out to the grimy Gatsby make
sure you say hi to the grimy Gatsby
while you're at cannabis Grand Cru I'm
not sure if I'm going to that I might be
there I might not if I cannot make it
I'll give away the ticket on this show
sounds fancy it's gonna be fancy it's a
little far from here and I have things
going on that week so I'm not I'm not
sure I want to go really badly but
somebody may end up with a free ticket
so we'll keep going this podcast is also
brought to you by our good friends at
highly educated titanium if you're using
a high-grade concentrate you deserve a
high grade titanium nail don't trust the
Chinese nail or an American knockoff
made of cheap metals trust the industry
leader trust highly educated titanium
I'm dabbing cup-winning extracts and the
only nail I put on my rig is a highly
educated nail more information on highly
educated products check out highly
educated ti.com and highly educated
products are available at Aqualab
technologies dot-com this podcast is
also brought to you by nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for caged rain genetics
will apply to labs since city rare
dankness mile high can Avenger alpha
chronic bo g MTG the cali connection ira
genetics and many many more trusted
brands nature's green remedies is
running a coupon are running a special
for the podcast listeners type in coupon
code harvest 14 for 15% off any order
and you always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com coupon
code expires on Halloween so check them
out today this podcast is also brought
to you by our good friends at high grow
indoor growing supplies want to thank
Jesse for helping us out big shout out
to burn high grow indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store at 62 71
Beach Street or stop by the pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street and
Pueblo Colorado check out high grill for
very competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies shop
at hydro you guys I wouldn't talk about
hydro shop that I didn't support that's
where I go to get all my goodies I just
got a new carbon filter they took really
good care of me on that I got some OGT
they've got all the botanic care stuff I
need go check them out there's one more
quick add Big Love to our friends at
tree hugger comm this episode is brought
to you in part by tree hugger comm live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
hugger comm for concert and festival
news and reviews
WWWE sucker comm all right that's enough
commercials for today we're gonna get on
with some show Jesse and I are here last
night Jesse hosted a small gathering for
growers over at Highgrove party was a
huge success dude we didn't really
advertise Jesse didn't advertise much it
was kind of a test run we just wanted to
kind of see what would happen he wanted
to see what would happen we had about 12
people there for most of the evening
evening I'd say about 20 people showed
up for the peak of the night when Spence
and Matty and Big Mike and Michael
showed up they made about 20 people in
the room big shout out to everybody that
came the people that I met the people
that I already knew thanks for coming
and supporting something like that big
huge thanks to Burton Jesse and hydro
for letting us gather in the store that
was a great time we had some pizza
thanks for feeding me dude that was
great
last night was kind of just a test run
to see how many people we could get to
show up so do you plan on doing this
more yeah we're gonna set a date for
next month can anybody come yeah yeah
it's 21 and up but uh you know anyone's
invited just come down to the store and
ask for you know info or whatever or
didn't you did you make your Facebook
page or anything for it yeah oh yeah
yeah there was a so I will on Maya I
don't think I can do it from the
hydrogen etics page or from the hydro
culture page but I can do it from my
personal I'll make an event or I'll
share Jesse's event as soon as the neck
the next one comes up and we'll talk
about it on the show and we'll let you
guys know
we hope to get more growers from the
pueblo [ __ ] bubble area coming out to the
gathering we'll announce it for sure
when we get it figured out hopefully we
can get some listeners out there and
meet the people they come shake our
hands and we can find out who we're
talking to for sure
Armando we want you to come to one yeah
all right so we were talking about
building your drone rooms and last night
there were actually some new growers at
the party and we got to help them build
pretty sweet room that's kind of nice
too because we had the exact same idea
in our head like do this they pretty
much were gonna do that I think we're
gonna talk about a few different ways to
set up a gross space that is suitable
for your production needs
I also found a comment on the Facebook
page that asks for guidance in building
a space for $500 that's a really tight
budget for a grow room but I'll see what
I can come up with I Google the few
items to try to save some pennies but
that's a challenge dude 500 bucks well
she just said help me out teach me how
to build a space for 500 bucks she said
she's uh on a very low budget I have her
Facebook comment after read remember
exactly what she said but I think she's
also disabled so we're gonna have to
build her something that's not heavy
that's not a lot of work I have an idea
and I want to build like a PVC frame and
then wrap it in some sort of mylar type
thing and then we'll talk more about
that we'll get that going once we get
into the building that gross stuff a
little more let's talk about building
grows there's a few things to consider
when you're gonna plan your girl before
you even go to the hardware store before
you ever go to the hydro shop there's
stuff you got to think about the first
thing to think about in my opinion is is
it legal where you are I'm not gonna
help you break the law the first part of
this is move to a location where
cannabis is legal if you want to follow
my rules so don't do this in an illegal
State move to Colorado go to California
or even better do what you can to get
cannabis legalized or decriminalized
where you are so that you can grow
legally I don't want to be responsible
for you breaking the law so if you plan
on breaking the law just change to
another podcast
I don't want you to go to jail for what
I'm telling you but you're gonna do what
you gonna do so the next thing to think
about understand the risk you're taking
because if you're drawing in a state
that's not legal the consequences can be
quite severe it's not just you you're
putting at risk if you're drawing in a
house everybody in that house is in
trouble if you have a family and you go
to jail that's gonna just cause a tidal
wave of [ __ ] in your life so keep
that in mind the next thing that I would
say to think about is what are your
realistic needs if you're committed
you're gonna grow some cannabis for
yourself what are your realistic needs
do you need to grow for yourself your
family maybe a few patients or are you
trying to become the next big production
facility in your area so my next idea
would be set a goal and kind of stick
with that for a few cycles to see what
you're doing you can't you're not gonna
know how good of a grower or what kind
of crop you get on the first grow stick
with that set something up stick with it
for a couple of cycles and then adjust
to your needs after you've gone a couple
rounds like don't run your first lap and
then think my shoes are too tight my
shoes are too loose run a couple laps
see what you're good at then adjust so
my next thing to consider I would say is
does your location have viable
electricity this is something Jesse
really stressed on when he got here to
talk about this I run in more than one
or two thousand watt lights in a room
may require some electrical upgrades if
you want to be safe if your breakers are
flipping and you're scrambling to keep
everything running that's when you're
trading a fire hazard yeah you don't
want to be on the news for burning down
your house growing weed no in your
experience can you usually just run like
a thousand watt light is a blower that
it requires and a couple of fans and if
you have like a hydro bubbler or
whatever is that pretty much what one
room can do yeah most most residential
rooms about 30 30 amp breaker yeah so
that you're and if you're putting an air
conditioner in there you're taking up
half a breaker just with that the light
takes up about half a breaker all right
if you're flipping the breaker when you
turn on the dishwasher or whatever have
an electrician come and help you out
there are a lot of electricians actually
if you're in the Pueblo area I have an
electrician that I will refer because
he's looking for some work he's off and
he could use your your job so don't burn
down the house please please don't burn
down the house don't trade
fire hazard with electricity also if
you're any illegal in an illegal state
this is something I just thought of
you're gonna have to have an excuse for
all that electricity if you're one
thousand watt light is gonna kick your
light bill up about $100 per month
an additional hunt like the light and
the fan and the blower it takes to run
it you're looking about another 100
dollars every month if you're just a
dude in an apartment or something like
that that may spark some concerns you
might want to get a hot tub we've heard
of people using welding equipment just
get something to kind of make it look
like you're doing something put a bunch
of table saws in the garage if you've
got that option you know look like you
have somewhere for that power
consumption to go empty empty saltwater
fish tanks but you know all of that
stuff I bet you they can tell that my
timers are on twelve twelve over at the
crow you know they're like oh yeah every
day at eight o'clock this guy kicks on
thousands of watts o'clock they kick off
they're not [ __ ] sorry [ __ ] is
an offensive word to you so will you be
able to ventilate your space is the next
thing I would think about fresh air is
super important stale stagnant humid air
is the number one cause for powdery
mildew it'll also slow your growth and
makes your plants look ugly thanks for
room stink you want to be able to walk
into your grow room and close your eyes
and not smell pot you want it to smell
like a nice clean room so keep that in
mind you have to be able to ventilate
that space number five on my list of
things that you should consider is your
gross space safe and secure you may need
to hide your growth from the landlord or
your nosy in-laws that come over for
dinner are you ready to live the grow
life in your house that doesn't sound
like a huge question but dude when
you've got pot plants in your house your
whole house will stink if you don't have
it under control you might need some
carbon filters you might need an extra
carbon filter or two I always have a
carbon filter on the air that is going
out the exhaust but then also I'll hang
a carbon filter with the blower on it
just right in the middle of the room on
the ceiling to act as a scrubber just to
clean even more air and that eliminates
more odor we were talking about ona gel
last night there's no ownage our own
Angele Zin like a plastic jar they say
to take the lid off
just leave it sitting but I actually
poked a little pencil sighs holes with
the drill right in the lid and then just
let it sit and then once it gets down to
about a third of the jar I just add like
a half a cup of water in there to shake
it and it rehydrates all the trista 'ls
and it lasts a little longer
put those by your door like your
entryway to your home or entryway to
wherever you're drawing people's nose
will hit that first and now their nose
is already kinda they've been punched so
they're confused and when they smell the
herb they won't know that it's herb
hopefully yeah so you can put them
inside your ducting to move that odor
around instead of the cannabis odor I'm
gonna add a random side note this is
just a really random sidebar because I
just thought about it
I keep hearing a lot of people say the
word marijuana marijuana is a racist
word and it sounds bad people are afraid
of marijuana cannabis is the new word
cannabis sounds better it doesn't sound
as racist and I know that's a weird way
to put it but we were taught that
marijuana is the devil and if you smoke
marijuana you're gonna get crazy and
rape white [ __ ] cannabis will heal
you cannabis stops cancer so I think we
should just try to abandon the word
marijuana and say cannabis a lot more
that's just my random sidebar for the
day marijuana actually literally is a
racist word that's yeah I mean yeah yeah
yeah don't doubt that people it was
invented by the government it's a huge
history lesson who discriminate against
Mexicans yeah they didn't like the
Mexicans that were coming to America and
smoking marijuana and then bringing it
to the jazz musicians
that's all reefer madness you guys
hopefully you know about that already
and hopefully no hopefully you're but
not that brainwashed and you never paid
attention to that hopefully you just
call it cannabis all right live in the
grow life another big thing to consider
is the location of your grow inside of
your house or wherever you're doing it
the basement is generally the coolest
spot you're insulated by dirt and
concrete walls and you're underground
you don't get a lot of climate changes
there in the basement also hopefully you
don't get a lot of traffic down there in
the basement you got like one room in
the corner in the back or something you
can just dedicate the Attic is gonna get
hot attic is on top of the house it's
getting hit by the Sun you don't have
all this insulation from the dirt and
the concrete walls the attics gonna be a
little more challenging so you're gonna
need more cooling
power you're gonna have to adjust your
snow milks off her the snow melts off
your roof and little that's obvious as
[ __ ] also guys this is some cover a
little later but I want to jump to it
you're gonna have to get water there so
putting your plants in the Attic I once
you get all the girl equipment hung up
up there and everything's up there now
you have to get water up there often so
keep that in mind and then another go
ahead you got some dad attics just if
you can avoid it's just really not a
good place to grow it's actually a
pretty pretty good a fire hazard oh yeah
I mean it's I mean it's significant fire
hazard or something though and you can't
really do it like we can here in
Colorado nobody goes to option we're
talking about earlier be safe but safety
first bro you don't want to be on the
news for burning down your house growing
pot because when the news comes you
might have been growing legal medical
cannabis but as soon as that fire starts
and the news truck pulls out you've got
a drug lab they're not gonna be polite
this this medical marijuana provider
accidentally sparked fire to his home no
the reports gonna say we're here in
front of this house where there's a
major drug lab on fire right now that's
what the reports and you're gonna be the
[ __ ] that just went to jail for doing
that yeah lower in the house is better
in Pueblo they're trying to actually
push and push an ordinance where we have
to grow in an outbuilding and I was
reading a book doing research on this
and in Jorge Cervantes book he says
outbuildings are apps actually the worst
place you could think about growing
because that's where thieves are and the
cops don't consider that trespassing so
they can go into your outbuilding it's
not part of your home yeah so the cops
can walk right in that's not it's a
different rule you know it's not part of
your domicile it's a shed so they can
walk right in
they don't need a warrant that's
something we gotta remind all the people
that are opposed to this of Mike did you
just hear that bro you're out building
that they're trying to propose that we
build will not be part of your home so
it will not require a warrant is what
this book that Jorge Cervantes wrote
says let me know how that really works
shout out to Mike he's my legal counsel
groaning I said it has a lot of
challenges too
um so it's gonna be a lot like growing
in an attic as far as trying to insulate
it and cool it up it's gonna be very
difficult and I guess I should thing the
next step here is how are you gonna cool
the room keep in mind that you have to
use more electricity for that air
conditioner and the air conditioner has
to vent itself somewhere so you keep in
mind how you're gonna cool the room I
had a good point that I wanted to make
and it just left my head well were you
just telling me
okay goal is I guess I should have
covered this more in the beginning but
your goal you're building a grow room
you want as much control of the lights
the air the water the humidity the
temperature that's what we're trying to
do we're trying to build a room then we
can control to set the ideal climate for
these plants I guess we should Internet
just starting building a room we should
know what we're trying to build right
and that's what you want you want a room
that you can almost automate and let
that happen and just turn everything on
properly get everything set up properly
and let it run and then when the night
time comes you have a nighttime
temperature selected it'll get to that
when the day time comes again you have a
date I'm tempted the air-conditioner
kicks on at the right time your fans
move at the right time your blowers are
all at the right schedule then you can
hit that perfect like 50% humidity or
forty percent humidity mark you can get
your 77 degree mark in there you can get
it all perfect enough just a little bit
of wind that's what you're trying to do
you're trying to build that super happy
trying to build an aquarium for your
plants or like a cage for plants like
the perfect habitat for these plants so
climate inside your house inside your
house yes that's your goal I guess I
should've talked more about that at the
beginning once you achieve that you know
pretty dialed in perfect climate growing
becomes a lot easier a lot easier is the
room the genetics this what you're
feeding and then the grow like how you
grow that's pretty much what your
components are lights air water soil and
love you know cleanliness is next to
godliness when it comes to growing every
little piece of trash or scrap and not
just in your grow room if your grow room
is in like your mom's basement or your
grandma's attic or your bedroom closet
all of those clothes all those books all
those scraps of paper all those
cigarette butts all the dust that's all
a place for a spider mite to hide that's
all a place for a thrip to lay a bug
also all that dust and cigarette smoke
will end up in your concentrate and in
your flowers if your I've kind of
stopped sweeping my grow room now
after about week six because I don't
want to stir up the dust and put it in
my flowers I will let my grow room look
a little shitty on the floor for a week
to not sweep it up as often because I
don't and I'll turn off all the fans and
blowers and air conditioners now to
sweep up because I don't want that stick
into my buds because that ends up in the
hash and we're trying to make the best
hash we can now that's that seems to be
the point that everybody's headed to I
still try to grow the best flowers but
of course we want the best hash to go
with that yeah all right that was a long
rant other than things to consider there
are responsibilities that I think you
should practice being a good grower um
when you're setting up to grow you don't
want to piss off the neighbors you don't
want to attract unwanted attention by
thieves or thugs you don't want to get
cop attention you definitely this is
something people don't think about there
are kids out there that love to steal
pot plants now kids are getting braver
the younger kids are getting dumber and
braver they know what pot is they know
how to find a grow I don't want to steal
your [ __ ]
so keep the pot oh and there's also
innocent kids that will just see your
pot want to steal it just because
they're curious so be careful keep your
pot away from the kids I know I stress
that but I'm a father so I don't want my
kid finding your paw
sorry I needed a drink so some of the
responsibilities that I think and I want
to thank my friends on Facebook for
helping me out I asked for a couple of
pieces of advice on this topic a few
people chimed in I own a Oh a huge shout
out to mr. Chris Barca whit's you guys
know Chris Markowitz you'll know why
this is funny you can google his name if
you want I asked Chris Markowitz or
asked on Facebook what would be a few
things you could do to be a responsible
girl or and not get yourself in trouble
Chris's reply was don't do interviews I
love it that's the golden answer right
there
chris is finally free after that
interview and welcome home bro you look
good in that I read genetics t-shirt so
a few responsibilities being a grower
make sure your lights are not visible
from the outside when you set up your
draw room when the sun goes down turn on
all your Dro lights walk outside
whatever if you're in the basement attic
bedroom walk outside and see if you can
see your grow lights if you can see your
girl lights fix it your feeling that's
the problem that also means you have a
light leak yeah that means the lights
are getting in during your flowering
cycle which you're just gonna cause a
bunch of hermaphrodites also your next
responsibility make sure the blower's
and fans are not heard by neighbors or
people walking pasture grow if there's a
spot where you don't think people will
ever walk the day you build a dam grow
someone's gonna walk there the meter
maid the gas guy some kid chasing his
dog some cop looking for someone else
they're gonna walk right past that
blower and they're gonna go what is this
and you're gonna think no one's ever
gonna walk there but as soon as you put
a blower they're new they will that's
the way life works so just be careful
plan ahead make sure no one can hear
your blowers make sure no one can see
your lights there's ways to muffle you
know David insulating the duct
insulating the blower you can just guys
outlets as a dryer outlet
yeah you can try to put it through the
roof
you know just move the blower to the
other end of the chain so it's not so
noisy yeah not right in the window
yeah those mufflers are a great idea
they're actually available at a high
growing or growing supplies and actually
uh
a cheaper alternative to the mufflers
and better for your crow is a HEPA
filter yes those will you know if it's
sucking in those will help you know over
all of my ends where I have I've drilled
like six inch holes or eight inch holes
to have my ends coming in I get those
little square HEPA filters that are just
a sheet like it's not a rectangle and I
just staple those right over it with a
staple gun onto the wall and wherever I
do grow you want yeah that keeps your
bugs out keeps all their stuff that you
don't want in your hatch it keeps all
that out of filter everything twice if
you can people are going oh my god how
much is this gonna cost building a good
grow room does cost a little bit of
money people were asking last night
they're like we've got this much budget
should we buy better this or better this
and that's kind of where I think you
should get the best bulbs and ballast
you can
that's your first starter and then move
your air and then like if you have to
buy in chunks I think you buy the lights
and then your air moving stuff like your
ducting your blowers and then your air
conditioner and then you buy your pots
and soil and nutrients start with the
room and just buy slowly instead of but
yeah it's the weakest link is always
gonna be the weakest link it's hard to
decide where to pinch your budget there
get the good bulbs and good ballasts
that's definitely my opinion so here's
the big issue that we've been dealing
with here in pueblo this caused a lot of
most of our new laws here that are being
proposed in pueblo or because of this
issue
make sure nobody can smell your grow the
smell is the most offensive and
revealing part of your grow yes I said
offense if there are some people that do
not love the smell of sweet sweet sticky
ganja in the morning there's a guy here
in our city that keeps complaining to
City Council that he can smell pot every
day when he wakes up because his
neighbors are girl in the dank yeah keep
that smell down if you build your grow
discreetly and you don't bring attention
yourself your neighbors will never know
you've got a grow in your home it's a
security issue to be no
oh yeah you know don't you know the
system biting people in men when people
find out you grow weeds no dude you're
talking about [ __ ] dog games you know
several years ago I lived in another
house and I had a grow in the basement
there and the power went out and I was
mid flour so it stinks dude and the
power guys had to come through
everybody's backyard looking for the
problem and I wasn't at the place but my
girlfriend was there and the power guy
told my girlfriend ma'am I'd go in the
house and smells like you got a skunk in
the backyard like he could smell my
growth completely and she just made a
cringing face and went in the house and
told me about it later but yeah so
people can smell you even if you can't
smell it people can smell your drone
you're around it you sleep by it you're
in there you wake up you're smoking it
you're the you're the last person that's
gonna smell it yeah the church lady down
the block you can smell it down the
street so don't let anybody smell your
grow your step number four to be a good
responsible grower when you're building
a girl room do whatever it takes to make
sure no kids get ever get into your
gross space I stuttered when I said that
cuz I mean it make sure no kids ever get
into your gross space that's important
that's like the biggest black eye you
can put on the canvas community right
now is letting kids get caught with your
weed yeah here's something you might not
think about most of the stuff was kind
of uh kind of obvious but here's a good
one you're gonna create a lot of waste
growing plants in your house you're
gonna have soil you're gonna have plant
stems and stalks you're gonna have root
balls find a responsible way to dispose
of everything some of you guys live out
in the rural areas burn that [ __ ] if you
can compost did if you can that's yeah
but see I live in the city and my growth
is in a city facility and so it's all
got to be chopped up into little tiny
pieces and put into secured trash bags
and it's got to be destroyed on site
like so the other guys you're gonna have
to find what if the trash guy is dumping
your trash and finds all your pot leaves
in Connecticut in there grandpa
what if he's not cool what if he is cool
he's gonna
he's gonna Rob you if he's not cool he's
calling the cops
so be careful I they might find your
trash that's they cannot from Jorge's
book that I read they cannot start a
case based on your trash that does not
justify a search warrant but the trash
can be used in court as part of the case
so evidence people I lived in Lawrence
Kansas and now that I think about it I
know people that got busted and had
their trash used as evidence in court
now that I think about I can't remember
their names but uh couple of kids I
worked at a place with what's up guys
I've heard that uh for you know drug
dealing cases back in the day and stuff
let's find that tape they wrap around
the packaging yeah I had that happen to
a friend too
I worked at a bowling alley and I found
a bunch of that tape that dark colored
tape and you could tell it was wrapped
around like him I've seen plenty of
pounds of weed like brick pounds of weed
I don't know if his Raptor on weed or
some cocaine or something but it was
that kind of tape and I know exactly
somebody had a nice bulk of something in
my bowling alley one night well you
found that in the trash at the ball game
in the trash in the bathroom just
sitting on the top so you're telling me
that someone evidence lockup may have
been crooked so somebody had a kilo of
coke weed at the bowling alley which
isn't really surprising now that I'm
thinking about it sketchy places that
people don't think about think about you
guys are gonna do with your trash guys
you got a bunch of [ __ ] you're gonna
have to throw away and not look obvious
with it if you've got more than two
lights when you harvest four lies worth
of stuff three lights worth of stuff
that's a lot of trash to take care of
and if you don't know what to do if you
don't know how to recycle and compost
your soil
you've got soil to deal with - it's got
perlite in it it's got old nutrients in
it you got to be careful uh here's
another one keep your yard and house
clean and presentable don't give your
neighbors or anyone in the neighborhood
a reason to dislike you don't stand out
if the house is on your block get the
lawn mowed once a week go mow the lawn
once a week if they got flowers grown
outside and it's a bunch of yuppies look
like a bunch of yuppies and grow flowers
outside dude try to
in the best you can don't be just don't
be the neighborhood [ __ ] if you're
gonna grow cannabis uh help out you know
if when it snows shovel the extra house
and for our house next door on each side
of you just do what you can to kind of
be friendly friend of mine Amanda on
Facebook said she actually just moved
into a new house and she's building her
grow in there in a legal state so I can
talk about her she said she walked to
her neighbors on either side and
introduced herself and said hey my name
is Amanda I'm the new neighbor here's my
phone number if you ever have any
problems feel free to call me do you
guys ever want to hang out just let me
know so by making friends and giving
them her number she's done two things
if they get pissed off at her and won't
call the cops they'll call her or
they'll come over and be like hey dude
you're Grateful Dead music student loud
can you hit these and chill out with the
drum circle in here she'll stop you know
and then also if something's wrong they
don't have to call 9-1-1
they can call her and be like your house
is glowing like there's a bunch of light
coming from the basement window your
curtain fell what's happening they don't
have to get to the cops right away so
just be a good neighbor introduce
yourself make friends be social that's
my point
number seven we've talked about this
don't burn the place down and make us
all look like [ __ ] this revolution
is new there are tons of people who hate
the movement FoxNews hates us anytime
some [ __ ] burns down a house by
blasting and doors are overpowering his
breaker box it makes the entire movement
look stupid so please guys don't be the
[ __ ] we see on Fox News like I said
earlier they're not gonna say this
medical marijuana provider had a snafu
they're gonna say this drug lab erupted
in flames and you're gonna be on the
news and handcuffs in the back of a cop
car looking like a [ __ ] please don't
be that guy please and there's there's
no reason to grow equipment is pretty
cheap nowadays you don't don't use some
sketchy [ __ ] [ __ ] if you're running a
bunch of lights get yourself a power box
plug it into the 240 and plug all the
lights into that and you're pretty much
legit you can run like eight lights on
that even more you're 12 yeah yeah um
I've seen like 16 light ones
yes you know an electrical upgrades
aren't really that expensive so now if
you're going nuts you know do it the
right way
don't run extension cords all over the
data each extension cord is a fire
hazard each one if you need electrical
upgrades guys just call Craigslist is
filled with electricians that advertise
that they're MMJ friendly or 420
friendly get rid of those get one of
those guys to come wire up your [ __ ]
because when they do it you'll be so
impressed it looks so cool to have your
stuff the first time you get a
professionally wired up grow room you
got the wire going like the little
conduit going all the way across the
room in the box every like 8 feet or 6
feet for a plug in and then like a big
one big breaker box on the outside of
the room that you can shut everything
off so that you know you can work on
[ __ ] not get any electricity and that is
so sweet looking the first time you get
that so have a pro come do that find him
on Craigslist if you need to if you're
in the southern Colorado area I've got a
guy I got two guys for you so if this
first guy is busy we can send his his
old boss to come help yeah that's that's
what we're talking about there's no no
reason for it that should be you know
one of the number one things when you're
setting up a room guys I always add a
fire extinguisher smoke alarm I put a
smoke detector in the grow rooms put it
near the exhaust fan like if you've got
a carbon filter sucking air out put it
near there because the smoke is gonna
get sucked toward that that way put the
smoke alarm there I put a fire
extinguisher outside of the damn grill
room because you don't want to have to
run in there and get the extinguisher if
that room is on fire you want to be able
to kick in the door and just start
spraying that [ __ ] and hydro indoor
growing supplies you can pick up an item
called the flame defender I haven't used
it I've done a lot of research about it
ah did that
I need those those look like the way to
go I think we're gonna get ourselves set
up with hopefully we never find out how
good those work
so because once you figured out how much
herb you need to produce that's when you
can start designing your gross space
actually sometimes your space dictates
how you build your grow that's where
that's where the fun kicks in in my
opinion building and grow is all about
adapting to the space you're provided
some of you guys are gonna use a small
closet some of you might use the spare
bedroom some of you guys are gonna buy a
grow Hut
set that up I will do a lot of talking
about a grow Hut maybe not on this
episode already 35 minutes in but I will
definitely I'm writing that down crow hi
there very first tutorial yeah a lot of
people made fun of them at first but I
have done some breeding I've done some
Fino selection I've done some great
growing and just a grow Hut they're
great if you have limited space you
could put it in the corner of your
bedroom and it's awesome I've seen a
whole bedroom full of them it was quite
the little production area so a small
plant count here in Pueblo in my house
in a spare bedroom I run two 5x5 hydro
huts on a flip box with a 600 watt light
in each Hut but what happens I run one
ballast the ballast plugs into the wall
on a timer so it goes ballast and then
there's a cord that goes to the flip box
and then the flip box has two chords
that come out and a bulb comes from each
one and every 12 hours side a lights up
and then for 12 hours it stays on and
then it shuts off and the other side
comes on for 12 hours so instead of
adding electrical upgrades to that
bedroom that I'm just using in the
winter as a grow space for keeps the
house warm up here actually so I just
run that be using the flip box I can use
that room all the time and have it
flowering constantly and not have any
downtime in that room it's like an 11
there's like a 14 by 9 room so those two
5x5 Hut's fit perfectly in there he
gives me a little bit of room to work
because I really like the girl Hut's a
lot of people talk [ __ ] about him and
hate on him they're amazing it's my
friend that was doing it oh he didn't
have the flip box but um he had two
different ballast so he was you know one
was on for 12 hours just he just had the
extra ballast and I didn't want to go
buy another one
flipbox is the price of another
Palestinian it's kind of a test idea I
wanted to see if I could do that on a
larger scale because I've designed an 18
light room that's two nine room or two
nine light rooms on a flip box mm-hmm
and then I actually did some research
and a guy named Eric
fixa kind of beat me to the punch on
this room that I was trying to build so
it's a cool room 10 by 10 room with a 10
by 5 long room in the middle and all of
your equipment is in that middle room
and you cool off to all of the air in
the middle room and one side sleeps so
you're producing co2 in the sleeping
plants guys planted or asleep kick off
co2 if you can vent that co2 into your
flower room that's awake you can use
that but so yeah you're just you got one
air conditioner one set of ballast one
dehumidifier and then you're just moving
the air around both rooms killer idea
guys we'll talk about that that's a huge
room that's a lot of money
that's like multi-thousand dollar room
so some of you guys are gonna grow like
in closets and [ __ ] that's what I'm
saying right so because we can grow and
grow huts some of you guys might even
bust out 16 lights in a basement however
however you do it there will be some
obstacles presented by your existing
environment that's how it goes unless
you're building a building that's
designed to be a gross space from the
beginning you're gonna have to deal with
some type of obstacles that's part of
the fun for me honestly yeah I like
taking a space like a dirty basement or
a funky attic or the back part of the
dispensary and making it grow with the
space and power that I've got without
having to do any crazy dramatic
improvements to the place it's kind of a
fun challenge I think no I don't think I
know I do upgrades after every single
run sometimes upgrades that slow me down
quite a bit noticed some down time for a
minute I've heard you talking about it
alright so let's talk about a few things
that every grow will need there will be
more things you're gonna have to add to
this depending on your room in your
space but every room is gonna need these
things this is mostly for just one
flowering room if you want to have
plants vegging while your drop flowers
you're gonna need a small bedroom also
eventually you're gonna want a mother
room and a clone area and a veg area and
a breeding area and a place
your mail plants and a place to make
pollen and it gets ridiculous when you
start doing it a whole bunch but
eventually you're gonna want to add more
rooms my advice is build slowly and plan
ahead with realistic expectations
don't start count your chickens before
they hatch if you've got a light and you
expect a pound of weed start thinking
you got three-quarters of a pound of
weed budget for that because you're not
gonna grow as great as you plan your
first couple of runs
so make your upgrades like Jessie city
makes upgrades every time kind of plant
them don't go too ambitious your first
couple of times like be realistic about
it you can fail drops fail things that
kill crops spider mites air conditioner
failure if your air conditioner cuts out
in the middle of a flower cycle and
you're at work and it's 90 degrees
outside you're gonna come home it's
gonna be 108 degrees in your grow room
and you're gonna have crispy bugs
they're already dried and cured for
hydro setup if one pump dies while
you're at work or while you're asleep
[Music]
mutual friend that went to Las Vegas for
two days he was he was supposed to go to
a wedding and didn't want to go but he
had to go and there was like a five-day
vacation planned but he went for two
days he flew there and flew back right
away and came home and his pump took a
[ __ ] while he was gone in his whole 4x4
table yeah we had a double redundancy
set up you know two pumps and a
dispensary and both filled for the same
weekend by everyone was that the
cannabis cup man yeah good bye two
tables worth of weed two whole tea
Animas yes thank you good job yeah
everything every grow is gonna need
electricity right unless you grow it
outside you need electricity
they're gonna need lights and timers
you'll need intake an outtake fans and
you're going to need a water source
those are the basics that every girl
will need and we're 40 minutes I'm gonna
try to squeeze as much of this as we can
but we might not actually even get to
like it is just I've had news articles
set aside I've got a couple of things
Mike and I wanted to talk about it's
gonna kind of go between these two build
episodes I think but I might put it out
as like a midweek episode so I think
after we record here Mike's gonna come
over and [ __ ] with me again and talk
about some things so the next one will
be a news heavy ketchup episode and then
I'll try to get Jesse back as soon as
possible to talk more about building cuz
you're gonna send me so many questions I
can already tell yeah we love the
questions that means we're doing our job
if we spark your thoughts that means
we're doing our job
hey lb you ask me questions and I
appreciate it I hope I responded
appropriately I don't want to say your
full name because I haven't gotten your
permission but lb I appreciate you for
listening that's awesome
so lights everybody needs lights lights
are actually the main ingredient to your
grow space
lights dictate the cycles of the gardens
they tell you if you're in veg or if
you're in flower lights are also the
main fuel and energy provider for your
plants lights create photosynthesis
lights are the main thing number one
nutrient yes put his big of a light as
you can in your space is what I always
say you're gross spaces you will need
some sort of air exchange system always
you got to get rid of that old stale
funky air I can't stress how important
this is most of the problems I see from
low-budget grows is a lack of air flow
and air exchange
moving the air around the room is great
but you need to replace the room the air
in the room also if you leave a freshly
watered crop locked in a sealed closet
with a light above it you're treating a
very humid environment the plants are
trying to transpire but there's too much
moisture in there the plants can't sweat
like they should which slows down
photosynthesis and stunts growth it also
makes your plants look angry and sad too
if the plants were left in excessive
humidity for long periods they will
become very susceptible to our good
friend powdery mildew fu powdery mildew
as
but grow your risk of powdery mildew way
increases the insides of your buds if
you're not getting some airflow in there
and you got too much moisture in the
room that mold is gonna grow right in
the middle of your buds so lock yourself
in your car one day just lock yourself
in the car on the Sun and just try to
sit there and breathe for the whole day
that's what it feels like for your
plants when you just stay for one walked
up in a tight room yeah so we've
stressed the need for air exchange water
water should be easily accessible
I predict that your thought each
thousand watt light will require about
five gallons of water two to three times
a week and this works across the board I
like to put sixteen three gallon pots
under the light or I like to put nine
five gallon pots or between four and six
seven gallon pots underneath a thousand
watt light and either way I find that
that requires a byte about five gallons
of water for each watering actually yeah
I'm glad that works out so keep that in
mind that you guys are gonna have to get
water to your gross paste at least twice
a week
unless you set up a drip system late in
Flour and if your room is a little
hotter you may be watering three or four
times a week I'm hitting my plants is a
little cool now so I'm hitting a Monday
I hit him with nutrients real heavy and
then I try to hit him on Thursday or
Friday with just enough water to keep
him through Monday but since they
haven't been drinking a lot that means
it on their next day when they get just
water I'm gonna really water the [ __ ]
out of them to kind of wash out any
excess nutrients that have built up over
time and then we'll start refeeding the
soil again around day 30 I really bubble
them that's a lot of sugars and things
water a lot more often to did that Mike
Stan just fired after his performance
tonight we have a mic stand that needs
viagra talk to our sponsors about this
if you guys are interested in sponsoring
the hydro culture podcast email me I
grow culture at hotmail.com I'd love to
hear what you have to say I'll send you
one sheet if that's what you're looking
for let you know what my rates are we've
been hitting dude we've been hitting
between 3,000 and 5,000 listeners per
episode 5000 is our peak 21
500 is like our low on an episode now
Jesus that's that's how many people are
here in this show so thank each and
every one of you that are listening that
is awesome yeah thank you guys all right
talked about the very basics of building
a room we talked about setting a goal
for how much cannabis we need to grow I
wrote herb right here about it corrected
myself the next step is figuring out if
you're building your room to fit your
production needs or if you're building
the room to fit the available space
budget and electrical limitations
sometimes you can't always throw 24
lights in your basement cuz you can't
pull that many amps so find a happy
medium that lets you draw a few crops
and then see if this is something that
you can dedicate more time space and
electricity to and then after a couple
of crops expand your grows plan him out
but don't expand more quickly than you
can learn I keep saying that imagine
this imagine getting ahead of yourself
will cause you headaches in the future
imagine if you have 24 lights in Flour
with six seven gallon pots under each
light and now you have fungus gnats and
it's your first growth and you're like
four weeks in the flower
you can't spray if you spray you're
gonna put [ __ ] in your buds and you got
a whole lot of them you just man if you
got 24 lights 150 plants that should be
24 to 30 pounds of weed if you do this
right some guys are gonna get 48 pounds
of weed out of these 24 lights cookies
are hoping for those 25 pounds out of
that I'm cringing start small dude feel
small before you feel so large because
when you grow you're gonna fail I mess
up at this rate I still kill stuff on
accident like all the time but that's
the only way I learn I encourage a
little bit of experiment don't
experiment on your mom's don't
experiment on your patients important
crop pick a plant torture it see what
you can do to it but go small like
experience a few problems before you try
to battle fungus gnats in a 24 light
flower
all right we are 47 minutes in I'm not
sure if we should try to keep going or
if we should save this next part for
another episode cuz we're uh we kind of
got him on the edge of their seats right
now yeah we'll talk about we'll talk
about this one spot right here and then
so we're gonna talk a little bit about
row size in relation to how many and
what type of lights to use we got about
ten minutes to do this so a small closet
set up I would use some small t5 lights
little fluorescent lights I personally
don't like the coiled CFLs I don't feel
like they put out enough light they
weren't great as supplements if it's all
you got that's gonna if it's all you've
got and all you can power it's gonna
work but for the amount of heat that
they put off I don't think they put off
enough light for a closet I would almost
recommend it's a t5 light I think there
are eight bulbs and I think it's 24 by
24 is the dimensions of it and I think
it's actually made by Hydra farm if
you've got a small closet that is the
perfect light in my opinion if you can't
run a lot of electricity you can put
that and a small fan and leave the
closet cracked a little bit you've got a
grow room dude as long as you're getting
that steel air out of there and not
letting it get too hot keep the those t5
lights right above your plants and then
every night you got to close that closet
door at the same time and turn off your
light to start your flower cycle and you
gotta be on the money eight o'clock
eight o'clock every day and night but so
in a small closet I think that little t5
light I'm talking about is perfect or
maybe a small hid a high-intensity
discharge light maybe like a 150 in a
closet I really like a 250 watt high
pressure sodium I really find those to
be efficient those are cool lights it's
a great size light doesn't take a lot of
wattage but it does make a little bit of
heat even though know if your closets a
little bigger 400 sir exactly what I was
gonna say a 400 is kind of the biggest
you really want to go in a closet unless
you got like one of those fancy like
bel-air walk-in closets but everyone's
got a small closet they can dedicate to
a grow space so if you're just trying to
supply herb for you and your girlfriend
or something or your patient just you
the closet is fine especially with a
little t5 light I think you could pull
some some stuff out of a t5 is that
where your first girl was it was more of
a it was a closet that was actually
attached to the hot water heater area so
the closet had another door in it and I
actually took the ducting from my hot
water heater and my heater and used some
of the co2 to my grow room so yeah
perfect little closet it's a great way
to grow you can grow a little short
plants in there you can supply yourself
a small corner of a room works if you
need to like tarp off a room or like if
you have a small room that you can just
take the corner you can put a grow Hut
in the corner grow huts are awesome I
said I'm gonna do a whole talk about
those that will be another episode guys
we're at 50 minutes now notice you guys
don't listen
past 45 a lot of you listeners click out
at 45 minutes you're drilling of I mean
you're not drilling on this one I mean
it didn't mean a man after after while
we listen to the show it's like my
throat's done all the listeners are
getting drowsy so you got that small
corner small space you can put a t5 all
the way up to like a 600 watt light in
like a 6x6 space if you can vent it
we'll talk in the next episode jesse is
actually like a carpenter craftsman
house builder manly man so he's gonna
talk about framing up a space and stuff
in the next episode we're gonna try to
get this part done quickly here grow
huts and we'll talk a lot about them you
can put a grow huh in the corner of any
room you can put multiple grow huts in a
basement you can put one grow Hut in
every role if you've got limited power
find out where each room is on each
breaker and put one grow huh on each
breaker
plenty of cannabis in one house or one
location like this then of course
there's the whole dedicated bedroom if
you've got a nice bedroom that nobody
needs if you're a single guy no roommate
sucks kick him out build a girl room
they won't eat your food he won't bring
over ugly chicks
you got a grow room in there now that's
gonna produce dank cannabis and it will
pay for itself something I should write
down to talk about is the cost of
running the grow room because that's
just on my mind it's expensive rooms big
facilities and stuff like that
astronomical if you and I were roommates
and you kicked me out and built a grow
room in my space it would definitely pay
for itself in the long run oh it
wouldn't eat your freaking
it would get you high as crap in the end
so a whole room you can put multiple
depending on the size of your room if
you've got so I say like every six by
six four by four four by four two six by
six space you should put about a
thousand watt light if you can vent it
if you've got a room that's like ten by
ten I think you should put four thousand
watt lights in there yeah if you're
getting bigger and bigger I it kind of
depends on your wattage and stuff but
about every five by five square should
be a thousand watt light if you convince
that I try to leave people hate walkways
a lot of growers say that walkways are
expensive in a waste of space I like
giving myself a walkway so I can get to
every single plant and I think the
plants like the space to breathe you
don't like being crowded in on the bus
with everybody touching your plants
don't like that [ __ ] either give them
some room to breathe and keeping the
leaves off of each other will prevent
powdery mildew and places for bugs to
jump around so if you've got a whole
room put up one thousand watt light
every five by five space up to the limit
that your electricity will allow and
that you can cool here's a random
recommendation I think it's about 3,000
BTUs of cooling for every single
thousand watt light is what I think you
want 2500 to 3,000 okay so keep that in
mind when you have to power that air
conditioner also so in your big room
here
if you've got and you're 30 and your to
30 amp breakers you're gonna be able to
run one maybe two lights and an air
conditioner
that's gonna be about it on the 30 amp
breaker so you're gonna need an
electrician to come wire up your big
room yeah you're not gonna be able to
get the air conditioner if you've got a
big garage or a basement you need to
have the electrician come and wire you
up with 240 in the whole basement and
then you need to have a mini split put
in the basement and hang like 24 lights
down there in your basement and you have
an income yeah that many splits gonna be
fun to put in but you can keep it so
cool once you get it there and then the
next step up from there after you have
your basement or your big garage with
multiple thousands anything more than
nine lights I think becomes like kind of
extensive for a home grow yeah yeah if
you got like ten lights in a house
you're kind of pushing it but then you
move on to like the commercial scale
warehouses where you've got multiple
rooms with multiple thousand watt lights
or one giant room with 100 lights in it
I kind of prefer more separated rooms I
like to breed and if something goes
wrong in one room you don't have it
everywhere yeah it's a little more
containable so my main point is playing
the room before you start building think
about how many lights you want to run
think about how much cannabis you want
to produce I think about your electrical
limitations think about your budget it's
gonna cost you so we said about a
hundred bucks a month to run a light and
it's accessories so keep that in mind
until harvest you're not gonna have
you're gonna have to figure out how to
pay for that once harvest comes then you
obviously have a way to pay for that
we're gonna be in an hour real quick
here guys this is a good way to make
this a two-part episode the part we're
gonna come up with next is actually the
basic steps to building the room and
some guidance on building a room and
things to look for I'm gonna cut this
episode off right here and we'll make
that part - ah dude thanks for coming to
do it another great episode we just
crushed this one I feel like yeah we
kind of draw it on for a little bit
I feel like I've been talking for an
hour straight so I apologize if this got
boring I hope you guys learned a whole
bunch of stuff this time if there any
questions make sure you send them to me
you can message Jesse he's at Jesse
grows is the address he grows OG on
Twitter yeah cool add Jessie grows OG on
Twitter follow him on Instagram add
Jessie grows you can message me I grew
culture at hotmail.com you can find me
there's an agriculture Facebook page
there's an agriculture Instagram we're
quite easy to find there's a Twitter or
Facebook I've got it all
so dude thanks for coming really yeah
thanks for that party you through guys
we'll let you know when the next party
is coming I'm gonna go ahead and wrap it
up
give us some questions yeah get us
questions please and now that the show
is over now that you've learned how to
build a sweet grow room please go to
iTunes or stitcher find I grow culture
find the review section give us a five
star rating type in a comment and let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode I don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher I region
etics Colorado calm and I am still
working on adding videos to YouTube I
took a break from that for a minute it
was kind of busy this week but they will
still come up there did I want to give a
huge shout out to the garden of Weeden
huge shout out to my ninja Spence big
shout out to Jesse thanks again for
listening guys take a fat dad give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's going on podcast world
welcome to episode number 38 of the
iGrow culture podcast I'm your host
Rasta Jeff thanks for joining me for
another episode I'm coming to you today
November 1st the day after Halloween and
I am proud to report that nobody gave
any trick-or-treaters from Denver
Associated Press the high headline is
Halloween pot candy scare baseless so
far the article says police in Colorado
have warned parents to look out for pot
laced Halloween candy the parents don't
seem too worried a denver based testing
company offered a thousand free kits to
parents wanting to screen their
trick-or-treaters Hall for marijuana
psychoactive chemical however only 45
parents took CBC see be scientific up on
the offer as a Friday there have been no
reported cases of people slipping
marijuana into unsuspecting unsuspecting
trick-or-treaters in Colorado or in any
other state but the popularity of pot
candies in the new retail market in
Colorado prompted warnings this fall
from police in Denver Fort Collins and
Pueblo as of Halloween morning Denver
police and the Rocky Mountain poison and
drug Center reported no calls about
marijuana and Halloween candy my honest
opinion is that it's an overblown fear
that was created by the police said CB
Scientific CEO bill short the company's
$15 kits are usually used by medical
marijuana patients to test the potency
of their weed the kits include small
beakers and a liquid that turns reddish
in the presence of THC marijuana is
active ingredient I'm gonna jump in here
marijuana does not have ingredients
marijuana is a plant so you don't need
ingredients to mix it together and make
a plant but nice try sure it said the
free kits were available to parents
anywhere but that nearly all the
requests came from Colorado we stepped
in to tell parents don't be
spooped they're not trying to jump on
some fear-mongering bandwagon short set
since January Children's Hospital
Colorado has reported nine admissions
for children accidentally consuming
edible marijuana it's unclear whether
those cases were from homemade treats or
edible marijuana purchased boost
awareness because of wider availability
of candies the Larimer County Sheriff's
Department for example said in its
warning is necessary because marijuana
candies don't necessarily appear unusual
THC infused edibles are often designed
to look very similar to popular
name-brand treats the office warned in
Washington State the other state with
legal sorry I'm gonna start that
sentence over again in Washington State
the only other state with legal
recreational pot sales authorities have
been more circumspect a sheriff's
detective in Pierce County Washington
wrote a newspaper column saying pot
showing up in trick-or-treat bags is an
urban myth it's too expensive
sorry terrifying in nature that was
[Music]
terrifying in the people we don't want
to play tricks on people we don't want
to give people cannabis and I think most
of us have realized that if we do that
we are fighting down our own movement so
any cannabis infused candies over
Halloween by the point is that that's a
lot of hype and a lot of fear so if you
guys are believing that relax a little
bit it's not as big of a fear as we
thought it was everybody had a happy and
safe Halloween I am going to continue
with this next news article then we'll
do a couple of ads this one's kind of
related part of that article that I just
read said that a lot of edibles are
designed to look like popular candies
but no more
this article comes from the Denver Post
and it is written by David McCoy uh
the headline says gone to join no more
Colorado edibles firm settle suit over
Hershey
lookalikes article says the small
Colorado Springs based producer of
marijuana edibles sued in June by candy
giant the Hershey Company for allegedly
breaching a number of design and named
patents quietly settles the dispute
settlement pending late September
teacher Bell agreed to recall and
destroy all edibles it's sold that looks
like the famed chocolate company's
products or with names on their brands
such as Reese's almond joy and Heath
long before the federal lawsuit was
filed in June in US District Court in
Denver the settlement makes sure it
won't happen again so these guys were
making edibles and some of them were
delicious dude they make a reefers
peanut butter bar that looks just like
the Reese's peanut butter bar but it
says reefers on it the packaging was the
same color as the Reese's peanut butter
cups it looked very similar so I could
see why first she's kind of got pissed
at this the heath was I forgot they
called the heath bar but these candy
bars look just like the original candy
bar and that could cause a problem I
could see that if your kid saw that
sitting on the counter which should not
be sitting out for a kid to get but if
he saw that reefers bar sitting up there
the kid would probably eat it and that
kid would be also requires team Chevelle
not to use the product names hash ease
ganja joy hash hash sheets thingamajiggy
or and reefers nor to use the name
reefer for any candies that contain
either peanut butter or its flavorings
the company also agreed not not to make
packages with brown yellow and orange
colors which are those used by Reese's
brand according to a copy of the
statement
so now they can't even use any of the
colors her she pretty much cock-blocked
these guys pretty well from doing
anything like that her she's n her she's
had said Tinkerbell's products harmed
their brand name and could be confused
for regular candy by children which is
kind of what I was saying a Tinkerbell
neither admitted nor denied any
allegations in the lawsuit as part of
the settlement not gonna be able to get
your ganja joy or your reefers anymore
those were super popular in California
took them a little bit to get their way
out here to Colorado anymore guys I feel
like I'm talking really fast I'm fired
up for this podcast I've had a good day
it's a super nice day outside I got a
big package in the mail from our friends
at sweet leaf farms so want to give them
a big shout out thank you go check out
sweet leaf farms I'm gonna dab some
scott OG and sins OG mix grown by a
garden of Weeden and also extracted by
garden of Weeden super delicious
it's the secret are the secret regionals
in Denver but this is the shattered
version and not the live resin version
hitman phase 2 cake highly educated the
infinity nail with an email attachment
on it so let's take a DAB together guys
here we go
and that's how you take a quarter gram
dab on a podcast just a little bit of a
cough turn that's coughing you're here
I'm sorry guys all right where were we I
know where we were this podcast is
brought to you by cannabis Grand Cru
cannabis Grand Cru Aspen will take place
at the sky hotel in downtown Aspen
Colorado Friday November 14th through
Sunday November 16th 2014
what is cannabis Grand Cru I'm glad you
asked
cannabis Grand Cru represents cannabis
cultural lifestyle business and
community in a premier event setting the
event includes lectures seminars
experiential learning and entertainment
centered around the cannabis business in
the US and around the world industry
professionals and consumers alike are
invited to network and enjoy this year's
event in beautiful Aspen Colorado to
check out the Grand Cru village killing
me bro check out the Grand Cru village
an area exclusive to ticket holders that
will host Colorado's dispensaries
including wells brain collective from
Denver and silver peak apothecary in
Aspen
located at the sky hotel at their
legendary pool deck the village will
showcase the latest products from the
top manufacturers and companies and this
very intimate setting
this is a members-only event due to the
current nature of the laws in the state
of Colorado attendance at cannabis event
events must be by invitation only in
order to protect the event and our
guests please complete the information
request at the bottom of our website for
your free membership members members
will be sent information directly on how
to purchase tickets located in the
majestic Aspen and oh not in the okay
let me try that line again here we go
located in majestic Aspen and nestled in
the Rocky Mountains this event will take
advantage of the amazing community and
provide networking and fun for folks in
the legal cannabis industry new speakers
are being announced every day confirmed
speakers include Mason - vert John Hunt
and Meg Collins check out cannabis grand
cru comm for full details its cannabis
Grand Cru crew spelled C are you big
shout out to hunt the grimy Gatsby this
podcast is also brought to you by our
good friends at highly educated titanium
if you're diving high quality
concentrates you deserve a high quality
titanium nail don't trust the Chinese
nail or an American knockoff trust the
industry leader trust highly educated
titanium as I'm dabbing cup-winning
extracts the only nail I put on my rig
is a highly-educated titanium nail right
now on this rig over here I've got a
hitman phase 2 mini cake I've got a
titanium or titanium no [ __ ] it's
titanium right I guess a highly-educated
infinity nail that's the nail that can
be eighteen or fourteen male or female I
love it because it works perfectly for
my email coil over here to the right of
me I've got a mad Rob rig that's got an
18 14 millimeter
duality nail and then over here in this
little container I've got the Master
Shake rig
excuse me I've got on my table on the
table right now article news article
this one sucks you guys saw this in
Denver this was a real popular topic a
few days ago here in Colorado everybody
was talking about it let's see where was
it originally this is from jesse paul
and noel phillips and john Ingold of the
Denver Post Denver police and feds
conduct large-scale raids on marijuana
grow sites police officers summon hazmat
suits raided multiple marijuana growing
operations Tuesday part of an
investigation into illegal marijuana
sales in Minnesota a federal law
enforcement official said federal agent
in the raids which saw investigators
haul dozens of high-intensity grow
lights and thousands of plants out of
the operation was found in large bag
searches program officially authorities
release little information about the
case on Twitter Denver police wrote that
the investigation involved illegal drug
activity but a spokesman for the
department later said he did not know if
the operations raided were licensed
marijuana businesses or if detectives
believe they were exclusively illegal
the police did not announce any arrests
connected to the raids this boat's woman
for the state marijuana Enforcement
Division which regulates cannabis
businesses refused to comment on whether
the division was involved in the
investigation
likewise James Goethe group supervisor
of the Drug Enforcement Administration's
special support unit in Denver offer a
little comment it's a very large and
successful investigation both said I one
rated site on North Bryant Street near
West Sixth Avenue the denver police
officer was seen entering a building in
a blue hazmat suit the officer his suit
reeking of marijuana said several search
warrants were being executed around the
city building north Bryant Street isn't
is in an industrial area popular with
state legal commercial marijuana growers
and increasingly illegal growers trying
to hide among them to the grow operation
for a medical marijuana products
business state records show industry
insiders said they believe the address
is now occupied by people claiming to be
medical marijuana caregivers
smaller-scale providers that operate
west a neighboring cannabis business
employees were bewildered by the flurry
of police activity Nate Perini who works
edibles manufacturer and appear which is
next door to the raided operation on
North Bryan Street said cops already
were there when she got to work around
9:00 a.m. yeah they're getting raided
she said there was a house in my
neighborhood a few weeks ago there were
just like a block away such a weird
feeling anyway a police car was parked
in front of the shop and another was
parked in the alley behind it police had
been strung around the perimeter Tuesday
Tuesday's raids came 11 months after
local and federal authorities raided
several large marijuana businesses the
largest raids on Colorado pot businesses
excuse me since medical marijuana became
legal for people connected to the
businesses raided then have been charged
with federal crimes and prosecutors have
also moved the seized businesses have
moved to seize the business's assets so
I don't from what I have read and seen
recently and what's going on on Facebook
these facilities were not legal medical
marijuana Emmie deregistered facilities
these were caregivers who have kind of
vague rules but they were probably out
of their plant count and if they had
that much money on them they were doing
something that they shouldn't have been
doing on Facebook at least so we're like
the warehouse right here got raided in
the one right next to it did not and the
one on the other side of it did not you
see all these federal agents and hazmat
suits pull up and just start taking [ __ ]
apart and they come in with guns blazing
I'm sure business next door what you're
waiting for anymore oh man but from what
I've seen these places were not legal so
this wasn't the feds taking down medical
marijuana facilities this was actual
raids on illegal gross and I know that
sounds weird being in Colorado but there
are a lot of these large-scale illegal
crows going on toke of the town guys
look at the cannabis the toke of the
town I look at a lot of websites to find
my cannabis news unfortunately you have
to type in the word marijuana to find
good cannabis news I'm trying to change
that here's a reminder marijuana is a
racist word it was created with racism
it supports a racist connotation so
we're gonna stop saying marijuana and
let's all say cannabis cannabis is the
revolutionary term
the people before us the older folks are
afraid of marijuana they're not as
afraid of cannabis we've kind of it's
all about the words if you say the right
words you can convince people just about
anything so let's start saying cannabis
not saying marijuana the headline of
this article Georgia drug agents bust
man with okra and believe it is
marijuana it's kind of an old story you
guys might have heard about it from Mike
Adams the article says this is really
might summarize some of this Americans
are no longer safe to cultivate common
garden vegetables without risking the
violent wrath of the drug war Georgia
resident Dwayne Perry who told reporters
that he was raided by drug agents
earlier last week after an aerial
surveillance unit mistook his Oprah crop
for marijuana that's right it appears as
though Georgia law enforcement has not
had enough experience taking down
marijuana grow operations to distinguish
the difference between okra and the
cannabis plant dude there is a picture
of an okra plant here does not look at
all like to train these guys a little
more so I'm gonna summarize this article
reports indicate that a Drug Task Force
was conducting a marijuana suppression
mission when officers spotted Perry's
okra plants and immediately thought he
was growing weed okra plants
incidentally consists of five fat leaves
while the cannabis plant has very
distinguishable foil eat foliage it
smelled foil across foliage wrong here
they put foi o absolutely nothing alike
unfortunately that did not stop officers
with Georgia State Patrol from swooping
in on Perry's residence dressed to kill
is what it says here an attempt to
destroy the suspected marijuana growing
in his backyard they were strapped to
the gills said Perry explaining to
reporters how the officers seemed
prepared to shoot him dead on the spot
over a case of mistaken identity
oh man these cops went in and raided
this guy imagine would you get raided
it's traumatic I've been involved in a
couple of raids unfortunately knock on
wood I'm never in one of those again the
cops 47 you could have a bomb you could
have dogs you could be crazy as [ __ ] for
whatever you're doing in there if you're
doing some kind of crime rent a house
where there's some shoes going on you
might expect that he might be the type
of person that's prepared for that this
dude is a grower in Georgia I'm pretty
sure he's not experienced with the SWAT
team in the State Patrol so he probably
should his pants when they came in
probably traumatized him probably
traumatized his family kids there's no
excuse for this domestic warfare over a
plant there I am at home and retired and
you know I do the right thing said Terry
they come to my house strapped with
weapons for no reason it ain't right
several officers did apologize after
further investigating the plants but
that simply isn't good enough says Perry
because the situation could have
potentially gotten him killed or
seriously injured more I thought about
it what could have happened he said
anything could have happened that
article
good job was a good way to spend your
money but you scared the [ __ ] out of
this old retired guy for no reason
instead of making friends the cops keep
making more enemies by doing [ __ ] like
this if you put down your guns and quit
trying to be soldiers and just be
friends and police the community like we
design the police for you'd have a lot
more damn friends I think
and then when [ __ ] goes wrong the cops
would have somebody to talk to they
wouldn't have to like was wrong now
everybody disappears nobody wants to
talk to the cops
cops are the bad guy now here's a good
guy still we'd want to talk to you
because we know you'd help us
[Music]
this is a ridiculous article I saw this
unfold on Facebook this was highly
entertaining this story is a little bit
old but it's worth talking about we
haven't done any news on the show for a
while we've been tacking up such great
shows here's a funny article this one is
by William breeds the article is
headlined idiot allegedly rips off pop
grow leaves cellphone behind we had a
lot of fun with this money guys this guy
named Chris Mathers from Colorado I'll
just read the story Chris Mathers is
apparently a thief but not a good one we
know this because the junkie scumbag
left his smartphone behind earlier this
week while allegedly ripping off a
colorado growers outdoor garden one of
several he's allegedly burglarized now
thanks to social media he's got the
attention of local police see this
mastermind Mathers unlocked which
allowed the victim to pull up more than
enough information on the scumbag to
track him down and eventually get the
cops involved details are hazy mostly to
keep the growers identity identity
somewhat discreet but after getting over
the initial horror of seeing their
harvest still weeks from being finished
gone the owners of the drug were no
doubt elated to find some rather
concrete evidence leaking matters to
their grow no word on how Mathers would
even know about the grow it says the guy
left his phone his cell phone open for
anyone to use the grower handed things
over to the social media there's a post
from one of the growers friends it says
my friends out door was ripped last
night one of the rippers dropped his
phone I'm gonna post his profile below
and his buddy that was involved found
out through reading messages please hit
me up if you know them and quickly it
escalated
I actually saw these posts on Facebook
and it was really it was like it's like
watching a real soap opera or a reality
show happen on Facebook all day
so it says the victim pulled photos of a
passed-out Mathers his address phone
number and even a list of other grow-ops
he's allegedly ripped off while the
growers no doubt had the inclination to
go beat his head in
they wisely called the cops after all
pot is a legal thing to grow in this
state and this is outright theft so
there was a lot of talk on Facebook
about people just going and whipping
this guy's ass because we had his home
phone number we had his address we knew
all of his friends he was in deep [ __ ]
but like this article says it's legal to
have cannabis in this state so they
called the cops this guy was arrested
for this but let's read article says for
his part Mather sounds like he's near
rock bottom the grower was able to pull
a text message conversations about met
Mathers suboxone habit Adventures
normally the drover found photos of the
brick [ __ ] he sells for fifteen
ounce donations on Mathers Facebook
account you guys should see this earth
this guy was selling some doodoo weed
it's brick it's nasty this guy goes and
steal somebody's crop boot and he drops
his cell phone behind people had a lot
of fun with him on Facebook
we taunted him allegedly people taunted
him and a lot of his friends all day
long until he took down his entire
Facebook page in the end he did end up
getting arrested for stealing this crop
which is uh justice and hilarious
justice if you ask me this podcast is
brought to you in part in part by our
good friends at tree hugger com tree
huggers calm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger calm for
concert and festival news and reviews
www.rediff.com on this one but man how
about that Halloween Phish show is
anybody paid any attention to bat I've
been a fish kid for years nothing like a
good fish show and that Halloween show
was kind of crazy for at least 20
minutes here
25 minutes then another news article for
you guys this one is really silly I had
to read this twice because I didn't
understand and then I took a couple of
dabs dude what do you guys want to dab
this time I've got some some Sour Diesel
nug run you wanna take a dab of that
sour dee hit on my blue highly-educated
car cap and we're gonna dab out of the
Phase two you know you guys might not
know what the Inu is usually you'll heat
that with a torch right heat it up for
about till it's warm I know about how
warm I want it you can almost touch the
damn thing I like it so low temp but uh
if you don't wanna use a torch all the
time you can buy an email and you plug
the email into the wall it's got a
little box you set the temperature on
the box and it's got the cord that goes
to the nail and the nails got a little
coil wrapped around it and then keeps
your nail hot constantly so you don't
ever have to hear the torch on the
podcast you don't have to waste time
with torches reach up and take a DAB so
I'm gonna take a nap join me guys dad
with me here we go five four three
yeah Sour Diesel dougla that stuff
tastes delicious
okay now let's read this crazy article
this other are this articles once again
by our good friend William breeds I
found this article on the of the town to
pay attention governor candidate wants
to shoot wolves because Coloradans smoke
weed I'm gonna say that again Wyoming
governor candidate wants to shoot wolves
because Coloradans smoke weed article
says Don Willis wants to kill wolves he
also wants to be governor right now he's
all about killing him some wolves so
much so that he's made it part of his
campaign strategy
see Wyoming has permitted wolf funds in
the past but this year a federal judge
put the animals if he component to the
water ecosystem on a protected list that
pisses off Willis who has previously
noted just wants wolves to die despite
federal protection because Colorado has
legal weed the wolf tags have been
issued and hunters had already made
plans to start their hunts he said the
disruption to hunters Outfitters and the
cost Wyoming Game and Fish to refund
hunting permits caused by a single
black-robe judge who sits in Washington
DC and has probably never been in
Wyoming is outrageous and should be
defied by Wyoming yes apparently you
live in you have to live in Wyoming to
actually care about Wyoming's wolf
population well this is now calling on
hunters to go ahead and disobey the
federal order Colorado did just that in
the legalization of pot it's a federal
crime to commit commercially grow pot
and the state of Colorado's defied the
federal laws and it all worked out fun
he told the Billings Gazette both
carefully pointing out that he doesn't
think people should break federal law to
use cannabis nor was he endorsing
cannabis use he also taunted the US Fish
and Wildlife Service saying he doubted
they would enforce the judge's ruling
because they normally side with Wyoming
on such matters
current wyoming Governor Matt Mead
agreed that the hunt should go on but
stopped short of advocating advocating
people's disobey the federal protections
on animals which are purely shot for
trophy they do shoot wolves for trophy
Wyoming is successfully negotiated
against federal overreach and when
necessary they've gone to court he said
in a release I do not advocate taking an
extreme stand doomed to failure which
undermines Wyoming's interests instead
of moving forward article goes on to say
that they are going to pretty much
monitor the amount of wolves and then
they will doing [ __ ] so let's shoot our
wolves in Wyoming I bet the feds won't
do [ __ ] I'm curious to see how that
turns out that's coming up so uh I might
pay attention to that chances are I will
forget all about that one thing I won't
forget is a big shout-out to our friends
at hydro indoor growing supplies hi girl
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado check out
the big Denver store at 62 71 beach
street or check out the pueblo location
at 618 East 4th Street in Pueblo
Colorado make sure you check out high
grow indoor growing supplies for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies one
more news article we're gonna start
wrapping up the show I do plan to have
Jesse back over in a couple of days and
we're gonna talk more about building
your grow room I have a couple of cool
things lined up for you guys we'll have
an episode about growing in tents or
hydro huts there's a lot of great stuff
coming up so look forward to those
episodes I've got one more news article
let me get to it it says Colorado
congressman urges Oregon to follow his
state's excellent example on marijuana
so you guys in Oregon the time to vote
is coming up please go vote if you're in
Oregon register to vote go vote you
can't [ __ ] and complain if you don't
vote the article says this Jared ball is
said in an op-ed Friday that marijuana
legalization is sound policy and he
urged Oregonians to follow in Colorado's
footsteps and vote YES on recreational
marijuana in next week's election
Colorado is approaching the first
anniversary of legally regulated
recreational marijuana for adults Poulos
wrote in the Bend bulletin the
implementation of our new laws has gone
smoothly over all providing an excellent
example for other states to follow our
success has made it clear that when
marijuana is regulated like alcohol it
can decrease crime help fund schools and
drug education programs and keep money
out of the hands of criminals and
cartels voters are considering measure
91 which would allow adults to possess
up to eight ounces of marijuana at home
and up to one ounce in public taxes on
marijuana sales with schools law
enforcement and drug prevention and
education programs while Oregon while
the Oregon Liquor Control Commission
would regulate and monitor the industry
sounds like it makes sense let's do it
decide whether to join Colorado and
Washington and regulating marijuana like
alcohol wrote Paulus who previously
sponsored legislation that would do just
that at the federal level more than ever
I believe it's time to change course on
decades of failed marijuana prohibition
and demonstrate viable effective
alternatives to address the realities of
marijuana today
Colorado's Colorado voters legalized
recreational marijuana in 2012 with the
first sales beginning on New Year's Day
2014 guys I don't know if I've mentioned
this on the show before I'm sure I
haven't been a smartass I was the first
guy to buy recreational cannabis at the
greener side dispensary in Pueblo
Colorado I got there like five forty six
o'clock in the morning and sat in line
and bought weed first and one of my good
friends dispensaries kinda made me proud
anyway while the rollout of the new
regulatory regime has been has not been
perfect it has largely been deemed a
success voters supported the end of
marijuana permit prohibition by a 10
percentage point margin in 2012 and have
continued to support it within the
regulated marketplace 10 teens appear to
have been prevented from making illegal
purchases
the legal sale of recreational and
medical marijuana has been lucrative for
the state generating about thirty
million dollars in taxes and fees the
Colorado legislation camp Legislative
Council forecast that in the first full
fiscal year of legal recreational sales
the state will rake in forty seven point
seven million dollars that's a lot of
money if Oregon passes measure 91 the
state's financial estimate committee
projects that additional tax revenues
could range from 17 million to forty
million dollars annually a recent study
from the personal finance site
NerdWallet placed the forecast range for
Oregon between 50 million and a hundred
million dollars in tax revenue voters in
Alaska and the District of Columbia will
also decide whether to legalize
recreational cannabis on November 4th
I'm gonna say go vote go vote to
legalize recreational cannabis if you
are in Alaska and the District of
Columbia
you better be voting November 4th if you
were an Oregon go vote [ __ ] and
complain if you don't vote if you have a
mail-in ballot mail it in November 4th
is your day alright alright guys I feel
like that's enough of me ranting and
that's also enough news it's really full
of a lot of stuff leaving the news out
so let's start wrapping up the show guys
who gets a shout out this week I want to
send a big shout out again to sweet leaf
farms I wanna send a huge shout out to
task rock thanks for letting me play
your music in the background right now
you listen to the task rock CNL the
movement also a huge allah what's up
girl but a big huge extra thank you to
the menthe a factor in Manitou Springs
in Manitou Springs need a vegetarian
treat stop in there they've got great
wraps and sandwiches
get yourself a dark roast mante you'll
be wired up for the whole day shout out
to the monta factor they always take
good care of us
I drive an hour to go eat there and an
hour back so that's how good that place
is the next episode because Jesse should
be here if all goes well we will talk
more about building your grow room
then we'll have another episode that is
not about building and then we'll do an
episode about growth hence is what I
think is coming up and then we'll start
getting back on track about more grow
lessons and stuff like that so let's do
the part where we wrap up the show where
did I put that paper it helps to be
prepared you guys it goes like this also
uh I do need a theme song for the show
so I can quit playing task rock and make
a tea and that cheesy reggae song that I
made you guys have any musical skills
I like dancehall reggae maybe a nice
something like that I could play in the
background while I talk or maybe at the
opening of the show or stitcher search
for the hydro culture podcast find the
review section give us a five star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on future
episodes don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
episode is available on I read genetics
Colorado dot-com I'm adding some videos
to YouTube I think there are 14 up there
by now I'll get a couple more up
throughout the next week make sure you
check us out
I grow culture on Instagram Facebook and
Twitter
thanks for listening to me rant big
shout out to my ninja spins until next
time take a phat dad give your mom a hug
for me alright podcaster all done' thank
you guys again for listening to episodes
36 37 and 38 of what used to be known as
the hydro culture podcast currently
known as the grow from your heart
podcast i would love it if you follow me
on social media check me out on twitter
it's at g f YH podcast if you want to
find me on facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart a podcast and if you want to send
me an email you can reach out to me it
grow from your heart at hotmail.com also
i would love it if you follow me on
instagram simply search for Irie
underscore genetics it's iri e
underscore genetics i would appreciate
the follow i posted a whole bunch of
great cannabis photography i post photos
from my personal grow i post photos from
my commercial grow i post photos from
other facilities i visit i post photos
from outdoor grows i go to you would
probably enjoy the photo
I post so check me out Irie underscore
genetics on Instagram that's all I've
got for you I will be back Monday with
the brand new regular episode I look
forward to joining you and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me