yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 207 The
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're at news smoker or in
dedicated dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta jeboa
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band let him use their music on my
podcast big shout out to Kat ku and the
entire mystic roots brood
yeah I hope everyone is feeling as good
as I am ladies and gentlemen I am
smoking some lemon Geoffrey ambrosia
from my friends at apothecary extracts
this is some amazing concentrate the
ambrosia is there live resin line they
they call it ambrosia to differentiate
themselves to separate themselves from
the market their ambrosia line is always
delicious it's a kind of a sappy realtor
P live resin product it is delicious
it's fairly priced it gets me well
medicated this lemon Jeffrey tastes so
good you guys it saw and almost smells
like a scented candle in the room sorry
for the abrupt drop in music they're all
explaining that here in just a second
kind of smells like a lemon candle in
the room are like some lemon heads in a
package this the aroma is so
overwhelming and then now when you take
a DAB it just coats your mouth that
lemon candy flavor just coats your mouth
and then you get this amazing like a
freakin just a head high that you could
not believe it makes it hard to think it
makes it hard to focus it makes
everything cloudy I freaking love it big
shout out to my friends and apothecary
extracts great work on this lemon
Jeffrey I picked this up at elevation or
maybe it's called elevations in Colorado
Springs and is a medical only dispensary
they are on Razorback Road check them
out let them know Rasta Jeff sent you uh
call before you drive because they don't
always have lemon Jeffrey I buy a lot of
it as soon as it goes on sale and people
buy it up because I talk about it a lot
so make sure you call before you go to
elevation in Colorado Springs also you
can check out the Apothecary store in
Colorado Springs while you're there
they're not too far apart all right so I
turn down the music really quickly let
me explain something about that holy
[ __ ] I came home from work and my little
recording area my recording table had a
nice puddle of water all over it luckily
this oil slick pad has saved so much
[ __ ] one time the email came on
while the coil was sitting on the table
and it heated up the oil slick pad it
did not burn the table this time I had a
roof leak oh so there's a chandelier
just above my table where I record and
there was it there have been [ __ ]
thunderstorms you guys rain storms hail
storms thunderstorms for the past month
I'm sure you've heard me talk about it
on the podcast we've had random power
outages the Wi-Fi and cable have been
out a lot lately it's been
kinda sketchy trying to rely on
electricity and Wi-Fi but the rain has
been here and it knocked some [ __ ] off
my roof it [ __ ] up my roof a little
bit and I had a little bit of water
getting in my house so I planned on
recording yesterday I could not do it
because my table my recording area was
all wet dude I am a completely lucky man
thank you ja I am blessed
usually this computer that I'm recording
with right now is sitting directly in
front of me which is directly under the
chandelier I leave it here sometimes if
I'm doing something for some reason I
took it in the grow room because I was
looking up some aggro chart from
something I wanted to see some stuff and
I had it in the grow room and I left it
on the shelf and the grow uh and it did
not get wet you guys I got so [ __ ]
lucky my computer did not get wet there
was a puddle of water about I don't I
can reach I can put one hand where the
water was and I can completely reach my
mixing board I've got a 14 channel
Mackie 1402 Veals III mixer here this is
an expensive [ __ ] piece of equipment
and underneath that is a livewire power
Furman it's a power conditioner it keeps
all my power smooth so that I don't get
power fluctuations in my equipment that
will burn out my recording gear
underneath that is a dbx compressor kind
of expensive piece of gear that's what
keeps all the background noise out of
the show it's what makes me sound crispy
and clean so what limits me so that if I
yell into the microphone real bad it
doesn't blow up your ears it did get
louder but it didn't blow out because I
was actually really much louder than
what you heard also I'm snapping my
fingers to the right and left of the
microphone you don't hear that [ __ ]
because of the compressor then
underneath that is a task him us 1200
which is a USB it makes all of my audio
signal become a digital signal which
runs into my MacBook none of that [ __ ]
got wet you guys oh my god I'm so lucky
I'm blessed to think ja whatever you
believe in think that for me because all
my [ __ ] could have been destroyed us
thousands of dollars worth of equipment
they could have been [ __ ] ruined also
I had a bunch of hash on the table you
heard me talk about going to apothecary
and buying a bunch of concentrates for
some reason all of the water went the
other way my email and a hitman rig and
a bunch of concentrates were sitting on
the table and the water went to the left
and my shoot was to the right something
was looking out for me it's [ __ ] up I
got water in my house but
something was [ __ ] looking out for me
so uh with all of that talk about the
water in the house in my recording area
this means that I'm going to have
contractors here I'm gonna have roofers
here the roofers here today there were
people in the crawlspace they're people
in the Attic [ __ ] was going on um I have
been doing two episodes a week I've been
doing the Thursday episodes that are
long and these Monday episodes that are
regular lanes until I get my roof fixed
in my recording area cleaned up and
figured out I cannot promise you two
episodes a week I will do my absolute
best to give you one Episode a week I
will still bring you my Monday episodes
but the Thursday episodes may disappear
just until I get this recording area
fixed it's stressful trying to get this
all set up so keep putting I don't know
that it's gonna rain again if it rains
again the waters gonna come pouring
through there because the roof is not
fixed so when I get done recording I
move all of my [ __ ] off this area and I
cover up what I can't carry cuz some of
the stuff's heavy and some of its bulky
so I cover it with trash bags and I'm
dealing with [ __ ] roof leak so I
apologize for maybe not putting out
Thursday episodes I may do it it just
depends on how it goes I may have
contractors here my house may be a
[ __ ] mess and maybe go in somewhere
else to record I don't want to promise
anything I cannot deliver so I apologize
in advance if I skip a Thursday episode
or two I will put out a Monday episode
even if it's just me saying hey what's
up [ __ ] I apologize I will come and
do that for you so that's my disclaimer
on Thursday that's what's going on in my
world there was a [ __ ] roof leak
it'll get handled it's not a big deal
it's just gonna disrupt some [ __ ] for an
undetermined amount of time it's nothing
on nothing out of my pocket nothing like
that it's all insurance and homeowner
crap it's just [ __ ] to deal with I'm
actually really lucky cuz nothing got
destroyed I got water in the kitchen
that was on the dining room table and on
the kitchen floor I got tile in here I
got a good table it could have been much
[ __ ] worse it was stressful it was
scary
but it's not that bad all right I'm
gonna move on from that I feel like
you've been talking about that for a
long [ __ ] time I'm sorry it's been on
my mind thank you for letting me rant
about it and release it I feel better I
really do it was stressing me the [ __ ]
out you guys a roof leak in your home
you think that your house is where you
can put all your [ __ ] you work hard for
things I work hard for things I imagine
everybody out there there are a few
thieves and [ __ ] scumbags [ __ ] a
thief but there are people out there
that work hard for their [ __ ] and then
you get a nice home to put your [ __ ] in
and you feel like your home is a secure
place for your belongings and to come
home and find your [ __ ] wet oh that's a
heartbreaking feeling they made my chest
sink I walked in the house and I could
hear water
and I was like there's not water that
should be your putting in that where
that sound is coming from it kind of
[ __ ] with me all right you guys thanks
for uh being my therapist thanks let me
get that off my shoulders I feel a lot
better this is not just going to be a
therapeutic podcast I do have some
emails and stuff I would like to read
but before I get there let me do a
couple of quick things I would like to
tell you guys about patreon or I guess
I'd like to remind you about patreon
because I talk about it all the time for
those of you who haven't heard and if
you're not already tired of hearing
about it
patreon is a service that would allow
you as a listener to financially
contribute to the podcast that's right
if you feel like this podcast was worth
a dollar or two of your time you can go
to patreon.com/scishow and contribute it
is up to you you can contribute as
little as one dollar and I honestly
don't think there's a minimum or a
maximum on how many nines or zeros you
can put in there so test it out put in a
whole bunch of nines see what goes on
and I'm not trying to get rich on
podcasting you guys don't think I'm
trying to become a millionaire off of
podcasting what I'm trying to do is
offset the cost of my web hosting it
cost me a little bit of money to have a
website where I host the podcast and I
pay for that out of my pocket I'm not
trying to get rich I just want help
covering that cost if you guys don't
want to cover it any feel if you can't
help me
I don't mind covering it myself but I'd
rather not I put in a little bit of work
I put in some time if you guys want to
throw down a buck or two to help me pay
for that
I would appreciate it I'm gonna quit
begging but I want you to know that it
is there several people were like him
and I'd love to send you a buck or two
PayPal will not accept donations because
I have the word cannabis in my podcast I
say the word cannabis all the time we
talk
about ganja my website has the word
cannabis in it so they do not want
anything to do with me so I had to find
another service patreon is the best way
to do it
patreon you contribute to patreon
patreon sends money to my paypal it's
just a little buffer zone helps me out
and I want to say two huge thank you to
everybody who has contributed to patreon
if you sent me $1 or if you sent me a
lot of dollars every dollar matters and
I completely appreciate it and also if
you cannot contribute to patreon and
you're listening to the podcast don't
feel bad
this podcast is free for everybody there
are a few people out there they can
contribute they will cover you don't
worry this podcast is free I get it not
everybody can throw down money for a
podcast that's why I'm doing it for free
I want you to spend the money on your
garden don't stress just keep listening
and I still love everybody equally
alright I'm gonna move on because I feel
like I'm ranting about patreon for way
too long let me remind you about my
social media on Twitter you can find me
under @gf wih podcast I would love the
interaction there on Facebook it's the
girl from your heart a podcast just give
that a search also I've got an Instagram
I would love it if you followed me on
Instagram search for Irie underscore
genetics
i reaiiy rie underscore genetics that's
my seed company I'm a seed breeder I
make regular and feminized cannabis
seeds they are available at the dank
team.com I cannot ship you anything
personally I do not send seeds to
anybody if you're here in Colorado hit
me up I may have some gifts or trades
available for you alright
where was I I feel like I am rambling on
Instagram that's right Irene or genetics
a lot of people ask me what I remains
irie is just the best you could feel you
know that feeling when you're sitting
under a tree on a sunny day and it's
just the right temperature the winds
kind of blown it feels real good your
hairs bone back not hitting you in the
eyes maybe got your best friend next to
you maybe your dogs with you the grass
is that nice cool feeling
you know what the grass feels good to
sit in it's nice and cold maybe you
don't have no shoes on maybe you're
smoking a little joint and that feeling
we're just like damn I wouldn't rather
be anywhere else everything is cool that
is Irie that is just feeling Irie there
are a lot of versions of Irie but right
now that's the one we're gonna go with
just feeling Irie feelin good
all right let's me get me back on track
I'm super blaze from this lemon Jeffrey
I am rambling my face off
also if you are not into the social
media and you would like to contact me I
would love to hear from you through
email you can email me at grow from your
heart at hotmail.com that's nice and
easy that goes directly to my phone to
my iPad to my computer I won't miss it
I'll get your email that way also I
would love iTunes comments you guys if
you listen to the podcast on iTunes I
would love it if you go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart podcast it's kind of toward the
bottom click on the little icon with my
face on it then in the middle of the
screen there's a section that says
ratings and reviews click on that and
then go leave me a rating in a review so
far everybody has left a 5-star rating
leave me as many stars as you feel I
deserve I would appreciate it but if you
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show I will read your
comments on a future episode it's almost
time to do that again I haven't done
that in a few episodes so it's coming up
soon so go sneak a comment in there
before I get to it
alright I do have several emails that I
want to read here on this episode but
I'm sure you can hear this thing in my
throat I'm not gonna try to clear my
throat one last time I'm just gonna
press pause I'm gonna take a drink I'm
going to take a dad and then I will be
back with an email about Auto Flowers
I've got an email with the nutrient
question and then we'll see how much
time we've got left after that ladies
and gentlemen take a DAB while I do and
I'll be right back
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back I just
took a gigantic dab of some strawberry
banana high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract from apothecary extracts and I
am lit I was a little bit cold a few
minutes ago it's a cold rainy night and
I am currently sweating and I want to
open the window that was a great nap so
if it sounds like I'm lost for the next
couple of seconds it's because I am I'm
like a small child wandering around the
mall wondering where my [ __ ] mom went
right now holy [ __ ]
alright before I took a break and took a
dab that nearly erased my memory I kinda
remember I was teasing about an email I
wanted to read and I think it's the
email that is here on my iPad screen so
I'm gonna read this email I'm not sure
if this person wants me to say their
name shout out to the person that sent
this to me
I appreciate the email it goes like this
what's happening Rasta Jeff I'm about to
drop in Auto flower
Northern Lights outdoors we will be at
19 to 22 hours of Sun for the next
several months I just listened to your
outdoor growing podcast should I expect
the same sized plant in an auto versus a
fem thank you and then they sign their
name but I'm not gonna say it because I
respect your privacy so let's talk about
your Auto flower Northern Lights
unfortunately no your outdoor Auto
flower plant is not going to do as well
as your outdoor regular photo period
plan that's what it's called as a photo
period plan is what I would call it a
regular or a photo period ah there are
several reasons for that kind of mainly
the reason the way that the auto flower
plant was bred and designed it's not
meant to get large it's meant to grow to
a certain size and then flower most of
them and let me give it a quick
disclaimer ah I don't grow auto flower
plants that's not my thing I really like
regular plants I've gotten away from
feminized seeds I just like regular old
school regular seeds male-female pollen
makes you to grow that that's what I
like to do but so the little that I do
know about Auto flowers they're bred to
grow to a certain height usually they
get about 3 feet 2 to 3 feet depending
on what strain you're [ __ ] with
and I could be completely wrong but from
what I have seen and tried and done the
little experience I've got the plant got
to about three feet and then it started
flowering it took it about eight weeks
to get to that height and then it just
started flowering all by itself I didn't
change the lights I didn't change the
nutrients I didn't do anything and then
it took in about 55 days to finish
flowering and it was done and I wasn't
satisfied with it and I'll never [ __ ]
with an auto flower again but the way
that they're bred there's something in
it that triggers it to flower either
based on its age or its height or
whatever it decides it will start
flowering by itself they are not meant
to stay alive for a long time a regular
plant a photoperiod plant you can grow
it as long as you want the reason a lot
of these plants get real big outdoors is
because we start vegging them indoors
I'm sure you heard Jesse and I talk
about setting up lights in January and
starting your clones in January and
getting them big so that when May comes
you've got a big four-foot tall plant
that's been topped a couple of times
already so that when he put it outside
it's already four feet tall that's
bigger than your auto flower plant is
even going to get so the quick straight
answer is no your Auto flower plant is
not going to get anywhere near the size
of a regular outdoor plant if that's
what you've got that's what you've got
but next year I would recommend working
with regular plants if you can get some
seeds grow them indoors take some clones
off of it find the keeper and then put
that keeper outdoors next year is really
what you should do they kind of got
sidetracked but the reason that the
non-auto flower the regular flowering
photoperiod plant is able to get bigger
is because you control when it flowers
you can veg that thing until it's 22
feet tall if you really want it to and
you had the light in the space to do it
those auto flower plants if you're gonna
run those I recommend planting a whole
bunch of those because they're gonna
grow really quickly they aren't gonna
have time to get real big and take up a
lot of space but if you plant a whole
bunch of them and fill up your square
footage you'll still produce the amount
of cannabis you could produce from a
small personal outdoor grow I'm not
talking like a commercial grow or a big
Humboldt County or outdoor but if you've
got a small personal outdoor and you
just pack in that space with Auto
flowers you could produce as much as you
could produce with one or two big plants
however I have never been impressed or
satisfied with the quality of it
a flower plant I'm going to assume that
your location there in Alaska you're not
gonna get enough dark time to get a
photo period plant so the OTO flowers
are what you've got to do so man good
luck I hope it comes out well for you I
would love an email update maybe some
pictures on the progress so that I can
see how it goes and we'll talk more
about it on the show hey I appreciate
the email thanks a lot I hope to hear
from you again in the future good luck
with your auto flower out there I hope
that goes well all right I've got
another email from a listener and it
goes like this hey Jeff I just picked up
some of your Firefly from the dank team
super pumped on getting a few freebies
and then he goes on to list the names of
those freebies that he got from the dang
team and the best part is I did not name
those that those names are not anything
I ever made up I did not send that to
the dank team that they created those
names I would not have named him what
you said I'm pretty sure what you've got
is a lemon Jeffrey cross to arise and
the other seed pack that you've probably
got is a cookies-and-cream cross to
arise those were some of the freebies
that I sent to the dank team for their
orders I'm pretty sure that's what
you've got if you'd like to know the
names that I decided on or do decide on
send me an email
I'll let you know what those strains are
really called if that's what you've got
I will also contact the dank team and
let them know to quit naming my [ __ ]
because that is not cool that is not
Ross - Jeff approved Yankee don't do
that [ __ ] message me I'll tell you what
the name of you don't get to make up
names I do I bread that [ __ ] my product
all right enough ranting about that the
email goes on like this it says here's a
question that you may have covered in a
previous podcast but I'm a fairly new
listener working my way back through old
episodes ah dude you're gonna love it
because I've been putting out old
episodes iTunes and stitcher only hold
about a hundred episodes in the feed so
I've been putting up the old episodes in
chunks most Thursday's I release long
episodes they're like three or four
hours long and they're usually three or
four episodes from the history the
archives I'm putting them out in order
so hopefully you get to hear a bunch of
those I hope they help you out other
listeners let me know what you think of
those long podcast is that a waste of my
time is it good for you is it doing
anything can I quit doing that should I
keep doing that what do you think well
how do you feel let me know also
I'm putting the all the episodes up on
YouTube so there will be an archive on
you
before too long I've got about 42 of
them made I will not release them until
I've got 50 up there and then you guys
be able to check them out anyway I'm
gonna keep going with this email it says
I'm a fairly new listener working my way
back through all the episodes how often
do you water with nutrients every time
every other time then he goes on to say
the guys that taught me have me water in
nutrients every time I water I'll flush
one day every other week and flush at
the very end and then he explains his
setup so let me talk a little bit about
how much nutrients and how often to use
nutrients most of this is gonna be based
on your medium this guy here who sent me
the email he says he's using botanic air
moisture cocoa I would put some a little
bit of perlite or personal light in that
cocoa to give it a little bit of air
it's a little bit aeration would be nice
there may be some in the botanic air
moisture cocoa I'm not sure but I always
like to add a little bit of perlite to
my cocoa I think it makes it fluffier it
makes it drain a little better the
plants like oxygen it's always helpful
uh if you're using cocoa it is okay to
why it is recommended to water with
nutrients every time the nutrients do
not hang out in the cocoa they basically
fall right out of the bottom of the pot
with the water they don't catch anything
they don't bind there's nothing to stop
it so you need to add nutrients every
time when you're watering with cocoa uh
you're saying you you said use the mills
line with reverse osmosis water your
hand watering and you've got 12 to
gallon plastic pots per 4x4 tray sounds
like you're off to a good start
you got adjust doing double Enders and
co2 enrichment you're pulling one and a
half to two pounds of light depending on
the strain which is good ah you say they
look a little fried toward the end you
might be pushing a little too much
nutrient if they look a little fried
toward the end or you are probably since
you're using cocoa you're probably
flushing a little extra-long it's gonna
be my assumption so let me go back on a
couple of things you said here in the
email how often should I be using
nutrients every other every time every
other time if you're using cocoa I
recommend using nutrients every single
time like I said before the nutrients
don't hang out in the cocoa so you're
gonna need to replenish that every time
if you're growing in soil or a soilless
mix maybe like a peat based mix or
something
I would only I would reduce the
frequency of feedings and water with
just water maybe every other time but
that's for guys they're using soilless
mix or soil or living soil if you're
using living soil you've already got
your [ __ ] in there you don't need to add
nutrients if you're using bottled
nutrients I would say I feed botanic air
bottled nutrients when I feed if I'm
using with tannic air I feed once a week
with the Botanica I mix the fool line up
whatever I'm using it'll probably be
base nutrients cal-mag what else is in
there liquid karma the hydro Plex then I
had a little bit of mammoth PETA that
give you a little OHS of 28 but I will
feed them all of that [ __ ] whatever
they're getting for the week cal-mag
whatever they're getting whatever root
supplement they're getting they'll get
all of that probably Monday then the
next time they get fed they're just
gonna get plain water and then if they
need water again that week I may give
them a tea if it's the middle of flower
but if they get thirsty again they'll
probably just get water to hold them
over till Monday usually my plants get
watered twice a week either in seven
gallon pots most of the time they only
need water twice um also in your email
you said oh let me light up the iPad
screen here again it just black down on
me cuz I haven't touched it in a minute
you said something about flushing that I
want to touch on you said the guys had
taught you have you water in every have
you water nutrients every time you water
that is correct do that since you're in
Cocoa then you say you flush one day
every other week and flush at the end I
would skip the flushing one day every
other week that's not necessary your
plant they are not getting to eat you're
cleaning out the soil and until you feed
with nutrients again they are not eating
you could probably increase your weight
if you did not do that that's my opinion
because that's one more chance they'll
get to eat then you say you flush at the
end how long do you flush at the end
with Coco you can get away with ten days
I would recommend 12 to 14 but with Coco
you can totally get away with ten days
especially if you're watering lightly so
for your situation I would stop that
flush and I would just feed nutrients
every time you water now here are a
couple of things to think about um you
can water with nutrients every time I
would do a base nutrient every time then
your
natives here's something to consider I
until recently
I would add all of my additives like I
talked about on Monday and just pummel
the plant with everything on Monday
somebody has encouraged me to do
different nutrient we call it boosts so
I'll add my base nutrients every time I
water the cocoa but on Monday I'll do my
cal-mag on Tuesday I'll do epsom salts
on Wednesday I'll do plus life on
Thursday I'll add push on Friday I add
something I'm not gonna tell you
everything I had in there but on Friday
I actually had the apatite apatite
apatite from new millennium is what's
been going in there lately so I just add
something different every day of the
week so that that way I feel like I'm
not overloading the plants and that's
something that's been taught to me by
somebody else and I'm just trying it to
see how it works because I'm open to new
stuff and honestly I see great results
with it we do mix several things into
the nutrient mix will do veg bloom base
I will do plus life in there and then
we'll put some fulvic acid and we'll put
some just a couple other things in there
but if we're gonna boost it up like the
cow mag and the epsom salts that stuff
only happens once a week and not all in
the same day so you can think about that
kind of stuff but if you're using cocoa
I would certainly at least add a base
nutrient every single time you're gonna
get a Cal mag deficiency with cocoa but
also in your message you said at the end
they look a little bit fried you might
be flushing too long if they're starting
to yellow up let's just say you're
growing on a nine week cycle you didn't
tell me about your cycle unless just say
you got a nine week flowering cycle
you're probably flushing at the end of
week seven the start of week eight to
give yourself 14 days I'm assuming
around five to six days maybe seven
eight days into that they really started
getting yellow they start to turn kind
of a goldish color maybe a little bit of
red in there and the leaves get a little
grey on the tips and they start
crinkling up you have just cleaned out
all the nutrients that cocoa doesn't
hold anything nothing sticks to the
cocoa like it does in a soilless mix it
just falls right out so that's what's
going on you've probably just flushed
and they're ready what you can do is
give a little more nutrients for a
little bit longer and that way they
won't burn out so quickly and also you
may get a little more weight but there's
nothing wrong with too long
of a flush that's gonna make them taste
really good all right
so I think I covered your question if
you're using cocoa you should use
nutrients every time you water if you're
using soil or a soilless mix I would
recommend nutrients and then water and
then maybe a tea occasionally just
because that will build up and if you're
using bottled nutrients in a soilless
mix the salts will build up quickly and
then that'll start causing lockouts and
problems and everything will go to [ __ ]
so all right I hope I answered your
question he ends the email by saying
killer podcast and then they signed
their name I'm not sure if you want your
name said on the podcast no I actually I
talked to you about it you do not want
your real name on the podcast you said
Kash McCoy is the business aim so big
shout out to Kash McCoy huge thanks for
the email if you have any more questions
please contact me I would love to help
you out if anybody out there has
something they'd like to ask me you can
send me an email and I would love to
hear from you it's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I love making content
based off of listener questions it lets
me know that I'm hitting my target I get
to help somebody out and hopefully a few
other people learn something in the
process so please send me emails I love
answering questions also you can send me
stuff on Twitter at G fyh podcast once
again you can find me on Facebook search
for the girl from a heart podcast I
would love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen this is going to be a 28
minute episode I want to thank you guys
for listening to this podcast let me
remind you again about patreon if you'd
like to contribute to the podcast simply
check out patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information that
you need is right there I would love it
also if you leave me a comment on iTunes
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast go to the ratings and review
section type in a comment let me know we
think about the show I will read it on a
future episode while you're there leave
me some stars so far everybody has left
a five star review leave me what you
feel I deserve and I will appreciate it
I'm gonna wrap up this episode I will
try to get you a Thursday episode but I
make no promises I will be back Monday
with a fresh episode I look forward to
joining you guys I want to thank
everybody for listening to this episode
I want to give a huge shout out to the
person who calls himself the negative
one thanks for the message I appreciate
that and until next time take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]