what's up podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
and it's time for episode number 208 of
the girl from your heart podcast it's
Thursday so I'm posting a throwback
Thursday episode I am posting episodes
39 40 and 41 of what used to be the
agriculture podcast now known as the
girl from your heart podcast before we
get to these old episodes let me make a
couple of updates and disclaimers all of
the social media has changed the new
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com the twitter is at g f YH
podcast and on facebook you can just
search for the grow from your heart
podcast I would love it if you stock me
on all of the social media also there
may be some advertisements and
promotions for old products and old
sponsors all of those have expired I
currently do not have any sponsors I do
not have any advertising so any ads or
anything that may be said in this
episode those expired a long time ago I
do apologize but there will be a lot of
great content in these episodes so
without any more rambles ladies and
gentlemen let's get two episodes 39 40
and 41 of what used to be the
agriculture podcast currently known as
the girl from your heart podcast welcome
to episode number 39 of the Eiger
culture podcast I'm your hostage f sy
guy back at the table guys Jesse's here
how you doing brother hey what's a
podcast lambs do t sound great on that
microphone we made a cup my tech
adjustments something I poured some
super thrive into the mixing gear here
so a couple episodes we talked about
building a grow room and I got Jesse to
come back kind of wrap that up a little
more for us which ironically he might
have been working in a gross space yeah
you learn anything 150 year old houses
or 150 year old houses is it brick or is
it like drywall and [ __ ] it's brick
that's no fun yeah everything's brick
guys that's gonna definitely come in
handy in the talk later because I wrote
some [ __ ] and it's all about building a
room inside of a room and we're gonna
need to do that in Jesse's space it
sounds like but before we get to that
part let's pay some bills this podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
cannabis Grande
Cannabis grand cru aspen will take place
at the sky hotel in downtown aspen
colorado Friday November 14th through
Sunday November 16th 2014
what is cannabis grand cru I'm glad you
asked but it's perfect cannabis Grand
Cru represents cannabis culture
lifestyle business and community in a
premier event setting the event includes
lectures seminars experiencial learning
and entertainment centered around the
cannabis business in the US and around
the world industry professionals and
consumers alike are invited to network
and enjoy this year's beautiful event in
Aspen Colorado while you're there check
out the grand cru village an area
exclusive to ticket holders that will
host Colorado's best dispensaries
including wellspring collective from
Denver and silver peak apothecary in
Aspen located at the sky hotel legendary
pool deck the village will showcase the
latest products from the top
manufacturers and companies in this very
intimate setting there is a disclaimer
this is a Members Only event due to the
current nature of laws in a state of
Colorado attendance at cannabis events
must be by invitation only in order to
protect the event and our guests please
complete the information request at the
bottom of the website for your free
membership members will be sent
information directly on how to purchase
tickets guys hurry up because the hotels
may be sold out by the time this episode
goes up but there are still tickets
available for the event located at the
majestic Aspen no not the majestic in
majestic Aspen and nestled in the Rocky
Mountains the event will take advantage
of the amazing community and provide
networking and fun for folks in the
legal cannabis industry new speakers are
being announced everyday confirmed
speakers include Mason - vert my good
buddy John Hunt and Meg Collins check
out cannabis grand cru calm for full
details big huge shout out to the grimy
Gatsby
all right this podcast is also brought
to you by highly educated titanium I
said who's jaded that's from cottonmouth
and abs a highly educated titanium using
high-grade concentrate you deserve a
high quality titanium nail don't trust
the Chinese nail or an American knockoff
made a crappy metal trust the industry
leader trust highly educated titanium
biggle shout out to task rock if you
guys want to grab a highly-educated nail
check out aqua lab technologies calm if
you want to learn how to seasoned care
for and take care of your highly
educated nail and how to clean it check
out highly educated ti.com one more big
add two more sorry this podcast is
brought to you by our friends at hydro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store
sixty to seventy one Beach Street or
come say hello and Pueblo 618 East 4th
Street Pueblo Colorado check out hydro
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies did I
use botanic air and they just stocked up
on the tannic air it looks sweet in
there I use OGT they just got some OGT
in there they're killing it see I
ordered that once and now they've got it
on the Shelf for me all the time loving
it we also have a big old bag of Route
seven oh seven for twenty-five dollars
this month that's a steal and I might
need to go stock up on that that space
right there along that wall that's empty
we can just fill that right up with soil
and also this month
if you mention agriculture you get
commercial pricing on everything that's
the month of November yeah November go
to hydro indoor growing supplies in
Pueblo when you're paying tell them I
listen to the agriculture podcast you
will get commercial pricing you're gonna
pay what Rasta Jeff pays you can uh you
can get that in Denver too
they may have to make a phone call tell
them a call call Jesse or burnin really
cool if we have a good response we'll
just probably keep it that way
there we go guys go in there and use
that coupon code or that discount code
so that we can keep it going the more of
you that use it they'll see that the
response they'll keep doing it awesome
thank you guys for listening going there
we got one more at Big Love to tree
hugger comm of course the show is
brought to you by our friends at tree
hugger com live music lifestyle magazine
check out tree hugger calm for concert
and festival news and reviews WWWE guru
calm I think I actually uh just
confirmed that I'm gonna check out the
string cheese incident in Denver under
yours it's gonna be kind of cool kinda
random for me I haven't seen the cheese
in years got a friend who needs a cheese
buddy for New Year's and I think I'm
gonna be the cheese buddy quite a cheesy
buddy I think that's enough ads for the
show I think that covered everybody
also check out nature's green remedies
com I didn't do a big ad for them they
are sold out of IRA genetics products
right now but you can get aged green
genetics apply to labs in Sin City
I do not have a coupon code for them
this month once I give them a refill
they'll get a sweet coupon code you guys
will get hooked up so crudely what's
been going on we had an election last
night on the ballots but we did have
number 105 regarding non GMO food this
was the labeling of GMO foods Colorado
dude you failed bro what the hell this
was supposed to pass this was what this
was
we're not gonna get too much into it
because it's already happened this was
we wanted them to have to mark
genetically modified food products with
some sort of indication that it is
genetically modified what the hell is
going on Colorado that's really
disappointing I like Jesse brought a
really good Facebook post he said
something to the effect of that's okay
Colorado I didn't want to share my
organic produce with you anyway Jesse's
tomatoes are delicious I am addicted
there's only one other place I've eaten
recently that's got Tomatoes nearly as
tasty as Jesse's I know where that place
is
do they get so many shout outs on this
podcast I'm addicted to that place I eat
there a lot we went up there with burnt
and first cousins and
they made customers made friends yeah
you like your family when you're they
know my name by now they start writing
down my order when they see it's uh I've
never seen that many madhe uh different
drinks yeah yeah like I was a little
overwhelmed at first it's a little
strange the first time you walk you will
the the vibe there is very unique so
when you walk in you're almost in a new
world turn your cell phone off when you
go in there please
I agree but there are so many people in
there I go I've gone late at night and
midday and if you go during the day it's
like it's 20-somethings with their mac
books and their iPhones all over the
place you're 12 there were some people
playing chess and a couple people who
look like they're on a date or so it's
just real to another guys playing chess
and their look like robots the one guy I
guess where he was playing chess with
the guy in front of them and then he was
also playing it on his iPad I've got a
funny joke that only a few listeners are
gonna get we were at it's we're talking
about a place called the mante factor
and they make your Beaumont a it's a
Brazilian energizing tea they have two
different kinds they have the dark your
Beaumont a which is what I prefer and
then they have got the green your
Beaumont a which I prefer the green iced
and I like the dark ha that's just my
preference so if I need a cool drink
I'll get the green one
the guy was describing the differences
to a customer it's in a really touristy
area so you get a lot of touristy kind
of people that are describing this drink
to a tourist and he said that the dark
roast is the dried leaves that have been
sat out and they've dried and they
crumble it and then they brew it or they
grind it then they brew it together and
he said the green is more the fresh leaf
that hasn't been dried and set out for
as long and I heard him say that and I
looked at the girl that was with me and
I said he's talking about that live red
[Music]
that's exactly the description that
worked perfectly it's all about that
live resin dark roast is the dragon
cured and then fresh green as the live
rays and you can taste the difference
I had only ever had the green before I
went up there and I got the dark I was
like yeah this is gonna happen but if
anybody that listens to this podcast
goes to the monty factor in Manitou
Springs say something about you heard
about say I heard about this place from
the iGrow culture podcast and they told
me to say hi and then maybe they'll
catch on cuz they know who I am I've
said that I'm the host of a show nice
yeah maybe maybe I just want a free
veggie wrap out of the deal I got a free
muffin from them the other night they
were really kind to give me a fresh warm
free muffin that's a lot of talk about
the monta factor the place is so good
bro if you go up there go hike on
Rainbow Falls I never said nothing about
the secret Rainbow Falls that place is
awesome if you can find it go hike it
it's cool graffiti Falls so we're
talking about the the votes that
happened last night Oregon Alaska and
Washington DC have legalized
recreational cannabis welcome to the
cool kid Club yeah for it on the other
hand you're just old people in
Disneyworld still how many people in
Florida do you think could actually
reduce their like their their pain
medication consumption drastically maybe
some of those pain companies the pain
clinics kind of lobbied against all of
this medical cannabis or cannabis no
surely not I mean I would think a big
major corporation would have a lot more
integrity not good honest company yeah
something like that because that would
be kind of cheating and citizens come on
big pharma yeah yeah so if you uh if you
did not go out and vote you can't [ __ ]
about what happened in Florida but if
you voted in Florida and I'm sorry you
did not get your cannabis rights they're
all Alaska and Washington DC however
congratulations like that's awesome
what we're gonna see I kind of cut you
off I was gonna say unless for some
reason they're listening to this and
they voted against it go [ __ ] yourself
so many episodes pay attention that up
for me and we're gonna discontinue that
actually we're gonna stop building
because I haven't said that in quite a
long time on the show so it's kind of
cool somebody let me know what I owe and
I'll pay it I had you on two for one
episode yeah but I don't remember which
one or when or where anything so
dreadful J where are you girl he always
listen to the show and remind me of
funny stuff that I said so gonna say
Washington DC our nation's capital now
has legalized cannabis why doesn't the
rest of the nation
just follow suit with what the Capitol
is done yeah I guess there are
intelligent people in DC change some of
the their habits like while they're up
there doing what they do instead of just
droning on the bill Akhil bro I think
that these GMOs work Rakesh this just
made uh getting a spoken adjoint from
the White House photo up a lot easier
well that's uh there was actually I was
at Garden of the Gods and I think I saw
a sign that remind you reminded you that
that's a state park and you cannot bring
your cannabis there yeah because it's
still federal land so I'm pretty sure
that that White House land is federal
land and you can't have your cannabis
there
good point yeah if you uh if you go to a
state park right now in Colorado people
that are not from Colorado this is a
random did not prepare this part at all
if you're not if you were in a state
park in Colorado like Red Rocks is a
state park most the reservoirs like the
reservoir reservoir hangout you cannot
you can so even if it's gonna be a
little sketchy White House does that
kind of make you feel cold I wasn't
gonna go there I did come across my mind
but all right we've been talking about
Jesse now we're talking about building a
room a couple episodes back and we're
talking about planning your grow room we
talked about selecting your space being
responsible grower on this episode we're
to talk more about building and setting
up your grow we're gonna discuss grow
tents a little bit or those hydro huts
or whatever you want to call and maybe
if we have enough time we're already 15
minutes in if we have enough time I will
try to tackle that $500 grow room
question that's gonna be a challenge but
basically do everything that we're doing
I go much smaller if we don't even get
two pots and soil and stuff on the stuff
that I've got written and we've got five
pages of stuff typed out so this is
gonna be a lot we wrapped up the last
grubka soda with the talk about deciding
how much light to use in your space and
we kind of talked about where you're
gonna hang the lights and where you're
gonna life phone is making noise that's
a poor podcast move right there oh sorry
No yeah it was on silent I don't know
what that was yeah talk about we're
gonna hang glide so you're gonna fit the
humidity was talking a little bit about
bringing fresh air into the room so now
let's kind of talk about building a room
which is kind of helpful because jesse
has a lot of experience in this now you
need to make a clean gross space that
allows you to control the light cycles
the temperature during the day the
temperature during the night and you
need to control the humidity and it's
also ideal to have a lot of control over
the air going in and out of the gross
space if you're using an extra bedroom
or a closet you'll have all the walls
already built but you'll need to work
around the existing room jesse was
talking about working at a brick
building or a brick facility I don't
know where it is I didn't ask I don't
want to know but he was talking about
150 years old that's brick that's gotta
suck because you don't everything to
screw [ __ ] into bricks crumble if you
hit them with a hammer and try to put
nails into him she can go really wrong
if you move one brick now you've got an
unstable wall all right so I'm ranting
about a brick if you've got a garage or
a basement or maybe Jesse's brick area
you're gonna need to build a room you
can't you could just hang lights up in
your garage or in that basement it's
gonna be a lot easier if you build a
room or set up a free prefabricated grow
Hut because I just gives you actually
control over your environment and an
environment simple reflection and
trapping the light and having it reflect
around makes the light up to 30% more
efficient is what I read in a couple of
books one set 21 said 30 how about we'll
settle on 25 percent more efficient and
if you're running a thousand watt light
that's 250 Watts basically of efficiency
that you're going to not lose by having
more reflection so just putting in a
good designed room is already saving you
money and increasing buds because like
we talked about on another show the
light is the main nutrient for your
plants it's not what you pour in it's
not what you feed it it's actually the
light so where are we let's uh let's
actually get into building a room I was
looking at all kinds of stuff and trying
to figure out how to do this I just
decided what's gonna build a four light
room we're gonna act like we're building
it either in a garage that's got plenty
of room or the basement that's got
plenty of room
or maybe in a warehouse sorry about the
cops guys we've been taking dad's so
let's build a room we need for 1,000
watt lights an air conditioner a way to
remove the humidity and a way to draw in
fresh air so let's choose like I said
we're gonna do the basement or a garage
or something like that that we want to
build a floor light room because
two-by-fours come in eight foot sections
right two by three or whatever we
decided to use a 2x4 you can get them
into you can buy a bunch of 8 by 8 bunch
a foot two by fours and I think you
could set up this room in a day you and
I could do it in five hours because
we've done this enough times so you're
gonna use a girl Hut or something or a
pre-made grow lab what do you guys do
you guys know girl huts at the height
over it hydro indoor growing supplies we
have a generic brand is it the grow lab
and we have a girl okay the generic
brand is different than the Chrome apps
I've never seen one but we can get a
really good price on them all right
and they're just basic you know I use
the grow labs that's what I live one 20s
or something like that or the class of
fives yeah those are sweeps same thing
so a thousand watt light in there and
those are awesome they also make it ten
by ten one which would work perfectly
for what we're gonna talk about here
would be we're gonna basically build an
8x8 version of that ten by six ten by
ten feet by ten feet by six eye I think
or seven hi we're just gonna make an 8
by 8 by 8 room one of the best ways to
build a room you know even like a big
huge warehouse what they do is
essentially they build a gigantic grow
out of two by fours and you know try
wall and everything they'll build a room
inside of her groom even in like the
vertical commercial lettuce forms and
stuff like that that's they start with
these cells so I know
um he needs it you know sometimes
looking at a ten-by-ten girl i've got
basic skills but for me buying the ten
by ten Hut and snapping those pieces
together is so much easier for me and if
something were to go wrong in or grow
the thing comes down in an hour you
could have everything down concealed in
one hour put it back up hopefully at
another hour with those girl huts and if
you're like working in a garage or a big
open basement I mean you know it's just
if you want to expand and stuff like
that there there's a lot of good reasons
to have multiple rooms when it comes to
pest control of equipment failure and
all kinds of stuff like that you know
it's good to double up like you said if
the air conditioner fails in this room
it didn't fail in every room it only
failed in one light or four lights worth
of stuff he only murdered 30 plants
instead of 100 I'm glad you said that
part about building a room within a room
comes in handy sometimes because most of
what I wrote was about building a room
inside of a room is gonna say frame out
of 8x8 room that's nice and tall I was
gonna say try to leave as much Headroom
as you can but most of us are gonna be
in a basement or garage so we'll be
limited on space and then I said if you
can use the full eight foot two by fours
you're in good luck so frame out your 8
by 8 by 8 room wherever you're working
and then here's where I kind of start
getting into detail since Jesse kind of
I'm so glad you said build a room inside
of a room even like big like restaurants
and old buildings and stuff like that
that's how they you know it's sanitary
alright so over frame yourself a nice
room alright you're gonna buy a room
just framed you don't need to frame it
like super rigidly secure you just need
a couple of cross beams yeah I'm 24 inch
studs every 24 inches so I stand every
24 inches every 24 inches plan for a
door sometimes you guys forget doors the
hydro shop sell the poly were to talk
about later use a razor you just follow
your razor right along with it and cut a
hole in the poly door do not unzip it
before you stick it on okay we're just
gonna move on because we don't want to
make fun of your customer that did that
to put some beams across the top to hang
your equipment you've got this building
just just a frame studs every 24 inches
maybe a couple across cuz you're gonna
hang some equipment the roof beams well
just any gun if you go all the way to to
the ceiling if you don't go all the way
to the ceiling just stand your don't lay
them down stand your 2x4 stand up on the
skinny edge gives you some metal clamps
and screw them to the top of two walls
and it'll help support the brace
everything you can hang lights from it
all kinds of neat [ __ ] that's why we
brought Jessie it's way easier why
paying the big bucks
everything's framed up you can insulate
the room with the blue insulation boards
if you want to make it more soundproof
and more have more stable temps I don't
find that to be too necessary if you're
in a basement if you're in the garage
maybe is it's gonna get colder in the
winter and hotter in the summer but the
basement like we talked about stays
fairly cool most of the time some people
choose to use plywood or some type of
board on the walls whatever you want is
cool build it how you like at that point
but once you'd be centered on the walls
and insulation that's when we hang we
call it poly or Panda film paulie's
basically plastic sheeting that's white
on one side and black on the other you
hang the white side on the inside of the
room and the black side on the house
the room it´ll the white will keep the
reflection of your light in there and
give you more efficiency you need to
cover up the whole room the walls the
floor and the ceiling and seal it up
with tape seal up any spots where bugs
can get in any spots where light can get
out you want it to be a little fortress
that's its own private little room you
want to seal that [ __ ] up and the more
time you take in the tighter you get all
the plastic and everything there's less
of a spot for bugs to get and stuff like
that yes take your time with this take
your time with it if you can if you have
a little bit of overlap everywhere there
is some kind of gap that's a good idea
when you're putting your staples in put
down a little square of duct tape
yeah because that'll help from the poly
tearing it also keep the stapling a
little bit better you can also go back
and take a little bit of silicone
caulking and stick that right in a
little staple had to make sure I got
that dealt in there like we were talking
about most of what we're gonna talk
about now works in the grow huts and it
translates that kind of translates to if
you're just working with the bedroom
also if you haven't built a room the
main difference is you won't have the
buffer zone around the grow area if
you're in a bedroom you'll need to vent
out of the room or the house without
anybody noticing the room that we've
built inside of the rooms give you more
privacy and I feel like a little bit
more control should we go over a bedroom
how to vent out a window real cheap
snazzy like real quick I think I talked
a little bit about it yeah we can talk
about it and if when I get to it later
on we'll just skip it later okay
so crack your window open half inch it's
kind of depends on how much air flow you
need through it and then screw it shop
there early screw it to where it can't
be opened any further and you do that by
real gently running a nice three inch
screw through the most people have vinyl
windows
through the inside track of where the
window goes up and down that'll hold the
window shut keep someone from wrecking
and open then you take your you went
window blinds get you a nice new set of
mini blinds cheap ones throw that down
close them so that you know no light can
go through maybe leave them open a
quarter-inch at the bottom air will
still suck through a pretty pretty good
and then take pan to film put the white
side to the outside of the window staple
it over that and take you a piece of
plywood screw it up over the wall and
you can cut holes and mount about fans
on there and all your ducting and
everything yeah yeah so you can use one
window as an intake in one window some
exhaust have you ever done the thing
where you Bob
put the blinds up just like you said you
I would close the window or leave it
open just a little bit okay we're gonna
leave it open for what we're doing on
this one sorry too many ideas in my head
you leave the half-inch gap and then you
build basically a box around the window
so you take some plywood and you make
like three inch deep little square
around the like an inch around the
window and then you put a piece of
plywood over that and then you can put
all your ducting in that plywood and it
almost looks like you could put like a
Christmas slide or a candle light or
something in there and it looks like
somebody's home all the time
it look like you got a light can
actually use that as ducting and [ __ ]
too now cuz it's open I did one I
actually stuck a Christmas light in
there yeah a yellow one and it reflected
off the all the plastic and everything
enough to you've got a window open and
it looks like somebody's home you got a
light on in there and it looks like it's
just part of the normal yeah so if
you're I have no idea why we wouldn't
need to be that secretive
you know it's mostly uh I'm not worried
is worried about the police as I am
about the thieves I actually heard a
story about some thieves getting into
somebody's air they went in through
their house through the air conditioning
duct their plants while the people were
home well they found out and I shouldn't
even be talking about this because that
whatever but the people found out their
plants were being stolen because of the
cops knocked on the door and found kids
running out their backyard with pot
plants oh yeah right I don't know how
that story ended I bailed on that
conversation [ __ ] alright so I hope my
story about building the box around the
window makes sense it's I kind of had a
vague idea of how to do that in my head
I was thinking too many thoughts so you
take up just shape the size of the
window you add an inch square so now if
your window is 24 by 24 to make it 25 by
25 square piece of plywood and then you
make a freaking box out of it you know
what I mean like a half box so it's only
you only need it three inches deep make
it a little tray and then put that up
against the window and then you can put
a curtain let's see where was I on all
these papers I hate I hate sloppy
windows I've actually seen a few houses
around town drive around you I can drive
to right now cross yeah right there you
can always see the metal halide in the
Attic so hang that Poli real carefully
like Jesse said take your time with the
poly here this is the building of the
room these are your walls you wouldn't
build your house walls all shitty you
want your plant room nice cover the
whole room seal it up seal any spots
where [ __ ] can get in now he basically
you got that little girl huh we're
talking about a bedroom I think I
already did most of the part I'm talking
about more privacy now you got the room
built and sealed up you're gonna use a
bedroom make sure to clean and dust the
bedroom first
keep on liner oh yeah that's definitely
on my list [ __ ] cover the windows where
the light can get in or get out cover
any cracks if you got cracks in the
walls cover those cover all your walls
in the bedroom with reflective material
the Panda film works in a bedroom also
carpet if you have that option cover the
floor if possible and right here I wrote
I like a pond liner for my floor I like
to get the pond liner about three to
four inches up the wall all the way
around the room so if you do
accidentally flood your rez in that room
or you spill a bucket or something
that's cool you just got a pond liner
there to catch it all and in the doorway
there to help keep the doorway all
filled up just cut you a door two by
four as wide as your doorway stand it up
on the outside and screw it in place and
that's a place to staple your pond liner
to yeah
so terms up a little bedroom into a pond
you know you're gonna have to step up
when you go in and out but you no big
deal I like the way you did that because
I did in kind of a shitty way in my my
newest build it works but I didn't do it
that smooth a nice little air seal if
you put it real tight and everything
little bit about because some of us are
gonna have to use that Trevis underneath
the door to let air in yeah that's
actually a pretty good spot if for some
of us and that's everything I'm talking
about is under ideal conditions yeah
this I mean there's I'm just trying to
throw out because there's so many ways
you could use I mean and so much
different scenarios if you walked into
okay this is a four bedroom house if we
walked into all four bedrooms and tried
to build a grow room in it we'd have to
deal with different obstacles in every
single room each room would have
different [ __ ] to deal with that rooms
only got a window on that side there'd
be some obstacles yeah all right so
wherever you are you're gonna have to
deal with some [ __ ] everything we're
saying is just kind of kind of hopefully
gonna work for what we're doing so now
we've got this clean room basically
we've got a hut that's sealed up we're
gonna add so you get your 8 by 8 by 8
room it's all Panda filmed or you've got
a 10 by 10 grow Hut or whatever some
similar oh now this is where you want to
add an intake and an outtake I talked in
that last episode a lot about how
important it is to vent you the air in
your grow I like those inline style fans
or blowers I like the vortex vortex has
always been reliable
and fan is great a little more expensive
with their adjustable speed and dude
those are reliable those GreenHeart
Hydrofarm blowers those are reliable
they work but they're loud yeah they're
really loved and they're the green
Hydrofarm inline boosters are chunk all
right yeah don't waste your money on
them
Jesse works in a hydro shop and I was
not gonna bash any brand but since he
works there and has to order from them
we'll let him go ahead and talk [ __ ]
yeah I mean it is what it is there's a
reason they sell so many refurbished
ones of those that's a lot of gross
stores we'll get to hydro from
responsible for that I like the room
we're gonna build we need an eighth inch
blower I'm gonna say get a can fan or a
vortex and don't buy one of the green
Hydrofarm ones it if you can afford the
can fan get that the vortex is ideal
next so yeah the Hydrofarm of blowers
are great it's the boosters can fans is
bad but okay it's that's not a primary
fan you know booster on the box okay all
right if you get the right blower you
don't need the booster so add that uh
let's see where were we eight inch
blower attach the blower to the framing
and get it fairly high in the room
depending on where you are some of you
guys might need to do this in the dead
center of the room so may need to do it
off to a corner just try to get it high
I think it's better to get the heat high
it's better to dump it out of the room
high you need to decide if you're gonna
use a fan in hoods or open hoods vinden
hoods are the ones just for the people
that are new with this your light
reflectors and hoods feinted ones mean
they have glass on the bottom and
they're sealed and your ducting will
attach to it and the light will be moved
away from the grow and not dropping down
on your plants if you have open hoods
you're gonna have to have more air
conditioning but you don't have to have
as much ducting so that's when you need
to think about what you got to do you
get more value for
for your light that way but
air-conditioned is expensive right
I like the vintage style yeah that's
pretty much the industry standard it's a
yeah unless you're in I've actually seen
a couple of huge rooms they just dump a
sea-levels stuff you can't be exhausting
yeah
takes a little bit more work time and if
you're really cool kids you got the
kavita's or the nano lux's or something
like that oh yeah those vetoes you can't
duck those so then you're gonna okay so
if you're using kavita's you're gonna
have to use more air conditioning a lot
more all right so if you're using open
hoods and you're trying for the ducting
situation we're doing you can just
attach a carbon filter to your 8-inch
blower and now you've pretty much
finished the extraction but if you're
using it make sure use the carbon filter
also that's what I want to add make sure
using the carbon filter on the
extraction fan sure drop is gonna stink
like all week six you're gonna be able
to smell everything I just hit week five
in the middle of week five in a room and
that uh that gorilla glue number four is
a stinky little [ __ ] you got a rug
ducting running four lights in this
design so I would do it kind of like
this but I'm gonna take a little drink
of this drink first right now taking a
drink that was well deserved all right
so if we're building this room with four
lights I would put a large carbon filter
I like the 39 by eight carbon filter
they have those available right now at
hydro indoor growing supplies then I
would take that 38 by eight inch carb 39
by 8 inch carbon filter I would use an 8
inch wide duct that goes into 2 6 inch
ducts so now my 8 just went to 2 sixes
and I would use the Y to run the ducting
to two lights on each side so I would
have light one a light to a and then
light one B light to be on opposite
sides and then use another Y duct more
ducting and then a wide duct to bring
them back together and then attach that
Y duct and the 8 inch blower
ah I wrote something weird there
attached that why and the 8 inch blower
and the blowers in the air out of the
room something I wrote doesn't make
sense but attach that why duct to that
blower and thence in the air see I
already have something wrong every
because you should have carbon filter
blower is the way it should go
so should be carbon filter blower
ducting or a carbon filter blower why
ducting light light why and then out of
the house is where it should go
I tried something different but I must
have just been I at that time that be a
good spot for a booster fan would be the
perfect spot so in this case we're
running it out of the grow Hut or out of
this 8 by 8 room that we built or if
you're doing the bedroom that's when you
got to build that little wall and run it
out of that duct or that little box that
we made there that was a good burp I'm
glad I got that one off the microphone
in some cases you're gonna need to run
the ducting out of the house or in
another room booster fans come in handy
there try to keep the the ducting as
short and straight as possible you don't
want a lot of bends and your ducting and
you don't want excessive long ducting
also if you can hang your carbon filter
from the ceiling yeah because all of
your heat and steel air is gonna go up
hopefully air moves just like water so
you know if you got a pump it all the
way to the ceiling from the floor you
know that's just stealing energy there
you go and heat rises so put that thing
up there yeah stinks more tooth yes
that's very will work better if you keep
the humidity at a more acceptable level
get it closer to 50 get away from that
70% like I've seen a couple of guys in
their flower rooms at 70% humidity
because they say it makes the butt
sticky don't make your button mouldy is
what you're gonna get bro I've seen
flowers with 0% humidity so much she's
gonna say it's Colorado bro don't look
at me like that and then your carbon
filter pretty much quits working at that
point too
yeah yeah you need some some moisture to
keep that charcoal active alright so
we've got an exhaust setup now you need
air in
depending on the situation I might make
a 4-inch hole six inches from the
corners and six inches off the ground so
imagine there's the corner of the room I
would go six inches in and six inches up
and make a four inch hole and then on
the opposite side of that corner do the
same thing and that'll give you eight
four inch holes for fresh air then I go
and get those HEPA filters from Lowe's
they're just little square sheets and I
staple those over the holes to keep any
dirt bugs freaking dog hair hippie hair
keep all that [ __ ] out of the girl room
with those HIPAA filters they weren't
pretty well I use driver Vince to cover
and prevent light leaks right on the
outside I put those on the outside to
wear or you can put on the inside too if
you need to but I like the outside they
look smoother but into the inside may
work because now the lights come in this
way it's not gonna get in there if
you're using them for an intake don't
forget to take the little flapper out
yeah you could replace the small holes
with one big hole and you can have a
blower in there if you do have something
bringing air in make sure that it is
smaller than the exhaust fan you want to
suck out more than what you're bringing
in you want to create negative pressure
in a grow room you want it to feel if
you have a real door if it's in a
bedroom when you open the door you want
that you want to turn the knob and you
want the door to fly open on its own
that's how you know you got enough
positive pressure so that's negative
second oh I was actually thinking of a
room I was just in so the door would
have been guys what's gonna happen line
up sewed 42 because Jesse just jumped to
the future on me so you can replace all
those holes are the big blower you've
got fresh air being pulled in when the
exhaust fan pulls out still air and
humidity out of the room
out of the house well does that even
mean you tell I was lit when I wrote
some of these notes and it got late so
we got fresher coming in when the
exhaust man pulls the stale air and
humidity out of the room so you can add
an air conditioner to bring in fresh air
also you might be able to bring in
enough air under the bedroom door if
you're doing this in a bedroom I had a
perfect little girl when I first started
off that was in a bedroom and I had to
blow her going over one light I had a
six inch blower go I was going over two
lights and sucking that straight out of
the room and I hung a carbon filter in
the ceiling and I just let the fresh air
come right under the door and I feel
like it was enough air yeah yeah I feel
like it was sufficient in there I didn't
get stifled or anything in there so
that's basin of the door guys that could
be useful you need fresh air coming in
so if you're building this big 8 by 8
room cut some holes in there or add a
blower if you're using an 8 inch blower
out you can use a four or a six inch
blower and I think and you'll be just
fine and even if you're running a sealed
room I hate seeing this this is a little
more advanced stuff but even sealed
rooms need to have the ability to inject
fresh air you know even if you don't use
it but once a week or something like
that but you still need to reset close
your air every now and then
pumpkin co2 into he's talking about a
control a closed environment agriculture
room or everything is sealed up the only
air that goes in the room is co2 that's
supplemented with the co2 tank we'll
talk a little bit about that in the
future because plants actually breathe
co2 and let out oxygen but I think just
pumping all that co2 in there they are
gonna need some oxygen your roots need
oxygen yeah I agree you have to put some
oxygen in that closed room somehow I
just use those hipa filters and filter
your air they also sell the shroom
things the shroom covers I'm a big fan
of those okay I've always thought they
were a little overpriced so I've just
stuck with the HEPA filters I can argue
with ya
we sell a much bigger intake filter
that's similar to a carbon filter and
you know it's not applica all situations
but it's very recently priced for what
it is the lifespan was just touch over
100 and it does some serious filter ink
so you can bring air from outside into
your grow essentially if you filter it
with that okay
sure that's worth a ton of money it
looks like a gigantic KN air K&amp;N air
filter for like a freakin f-22 Raptor or
some [ __ ] imagine you're done with that
thing you go dump it in the I'm just
picturing like some sort of Breaking Bad
desert is where I was watching something
in my mind dump it like throws it down
in the desert and all these bugs and
like imagine all the crazy [ __ ] that's
gonna come out you got a blower attached
to it sucking every bug that flies by is
gonna go and just get sucked into that
and get stuck in your trap now ah gonna
hook it over the fence at the Monsanto
facility there we go we're coming for
you
biological warfare we're coming for you
alright I'm got like three more pages
and stuff typed out I'm gonna have to
edit out the F word so
[Music]
I was just so daydreaming and thinking
about like where would this think like a
boy was a picture in me and you do it in
a picture like some shady grower with
this big gigantic vent cleaner just
rolling it out of the back of his truck
in the desert pretty all kinds of weird
bald danders and pollens yeah one thing
when I was actually a research in it
before we got it I was like oh this
would be great for protection from
outdoor yeah and matured or Anakapalle
and yeah
I've got a male that might blow soon he
just reminded me that I did not move it
earlier I don't want that to happen
premature yeah yeah I don't need him to
go is it a bad spot all right so guys uh
we've been ranting here we're gonna try
to get back on track for a little bit we
got 15 more minutes or so before
everyone's gonna get a DD can already
happen to us since we've got ducting in
place let's hang up some lights guys in
this room we have an 8 by 8 foot print
and four lights that means we can use a
four by four area for each light it's
gonna be bright in here that's what we
want
divide the room into perfect quarters
find the center for each quarter hang
your lights so they're centered in the
corners or the quarters not corners you
want them centered in the quarters so
basically you got a four by four section
with the light perfectly above it and
every four by four space has a light
right above it Jesse's doing math on how
many lumens and how many watts per
square foot that yes it's impressive you
could do 600 watt lights in the setup if
you wanted thousands are the way to go
in here I think
that's my professional opinion if you've
got the electricity and you're building
this room but thousands in there all
right I use those little lab so 64
square feet obviously that's a
[Music]
calculator that's 62 watts per square
foot and what would be a recommendation
mr. hydro shop expert that's a really
healthy look per square foot all right
this is gonna be a healthy room
hey Ryan you've got a room kind of like
this dude it's a good job you might have
taken some advice from me
that's no tiara rojo a hundred and
twenty watts per square foot indoor acre
we're talking about a spot called the
indoor acre is what is that place is
amazing there's like a mile and a half
of plumbing in there just for the hydro
kit all right so we're hanging our
lights there in the corner the core the
the center of the quarters of the room
right there might be a lot of editing on
the show guys we're dabbed out so I like
to use those little hooks I sell at
Lowe's they're just screws with a little
circle at the end of it basically screw
that into the ceiling the ceiling beams
make sure you get a stood yes
well they're only be studs there I mean
or a plastic or a stud for that and it
helps you sooner your lights take to
eight-foot two by fours screw them to
the ceiling then push your lights
anywhere you want you always know he hit
a stone yeah I need to see that one one
area
yeah that I worked at a place where the
lights were I worked for two companies
in the same building ironically and it
the first company I didn't help set
anything up and all the lights were hung
from a floating crit ceiling they go
Raptor hoods with little tiny plastic
hooks it's absolutely like just super
dangerous dumbass move thought out what
I went to work for the other company I
got paid to do by for structure all
through the bit of what could support a
couple gorillas so be safe when you're
building stuff we've talked about not
being that [ __ ] that burns down the
house also don't be the guy that takes
down the bedroom on accident if you're
renting you're gonna have to pay for
whatever you mess up all right I like
those little light hangers take my
lights the ratchet style ones those are
perfect them hang all four lights screw
in your bulbs and wipe off the bulbs
when you're done wipe them off I like to
use like a thing that you should be
cleaning your drums with it's a little
soft it's like a microfiber yeah clean
it off with that sunglasses in that uh
in the bulb or any dust or dirt on there
or any oil from your finger on there any
little thing that close to the bulb is
gonna definitely kill lumens make sure
your bulb is screwed in completely yeah
deck notes and all of your connections
are all pushed inside under ballast as
well so screwing your bulbs wipe it off
make sure it's tight run the ducting
from the blower to the wide dog to each
light back to the other Y out of your
grow room and then secure all of those
ducting 'z with tape there's gonna be a
lot of pressure on the ducts 1/8 inch
blower puts out a lot of pressure that
may be a good idea also to grab a fan
speed controller you plug that in and
then you plug your fan into that and you
can actually your blower your 8-inch
vortex Bowl or you can adjust how much
by percentage of from only works about
50 percent is as low as I think it goes
but then you can go from 50 all the way
to 100 if you're wanting to keep a
little humidity in the room
it down you can get it down to you know
50% humidity turning down to 70% it'll
help you out that's actually how I run
it in one space at about 70% all the
time so many the can fans come with the
little three-speed switch on the core
already adjusted to it yeah so that may
be beneficial and the hyper fan the best
fan on the market might that usually
comes with one built in that's a product
for me when I upgrade it's time for some
of those alright so now we've got
ducting you got lights on its kinda
starting to look like a grow room you
gotta hang a couple fans on the walls I
would put fans right above the expected
height of your plants like if you think
your plants are gonna get five feet tall
put a fan at five and a half feet right
between the fan can't or the light can
it with a damn lot of words right
between the plant canopy and the lights
is kind of where I like a fan yeah keep
the air moving you don't want there to
get stale plants suck up the co2 in the
room quickly they can use the co2 around
them super quickly and you just gotta
move the air so there's more co2 for
them to use up yeah
go ahead we're gonna say would you throw
maybe a box fan on the floor I do like a
box fan on the floor super low speed um
if you're on a budget the box man is
awesome if you have more of a budget I
would recommend a carbon filter with
like a six inch drawer on top of it just
dead sitting in the center of the room
put some ducting off the blower up to
the ceiling and just move that air from
the floor back up to the ceiling and
you're picking up co2 off the ground and
putting it back up to fall back down
onto your plants nice yeah that's just
differences in budgets if you've got a
low but if you've got thirty bucks by a
fan if you got 160 by a blower and a
filter yeah just kind of or I guess it's
gonna be closer to 260 I guess that
blower is gonna be a hundred and twenty
expensive you know I've watched
everything escalate in price since I've
been expanding my grows and since
Colorado has been getting more popular
everything has just gone up in price and
it's not even a competitive raise it's a
gouging raising week I can see it they
know what we're doing I remember buying
a light in like 2002
and keeping your head down at the store
trying not to be noticed man I swear I
paid like five six hundred bucks for my
first light setup and it's just a
magnetic 400 watt like nothing special
whatsoever so but everything else I feel
like has gotten more expensive yeah
lighting is the only only thing and
actually I guess it's just because
there's so many newer options but basic
lighting I Felix gotten cheaper yeah and
more reliable I remember you you buy
[ __ ] and you'll just die on you and I
was the last at least a year or two yeah
if it doesn't you can take it back
alright we've gone 52 minutes my next
part is all about hanging up the
ballasts and electronics and making the
board that I like to hang my stuff on I
think I'm gonna leave everybody hang in
and we're gonna do that part of the next
episode and I got a trick to help you
take better pictures when you're doing
that oh oh he's gonna help us out with
some tricks when can you come back and
do another episode bro probably next
week alright we'll try to get him back
for part three of our growing our
building our grow room episode I don't
have a huge huge super huge shout out to
hi grow and are growing supplies I know
Jesse's here so I'm kissing his ass a
little bit but seriously they helped me
out a lot they sponsor this show and
without them I couldn't do some of the
things that I do have any idea when the
next growers meeting is gonna be yeah
I'm really bad I know one of those guys
who can build you a freakin farm in ten
minutes but if you give him a Thor a
calendar he just gets all this like look
on his face of like great with math I
just can't ever do my work I just got a
new phone so he stepped up into the
future yeah so he's looking through his
phone to find out when the next meeting
is at Highgrove indoor growing supplies
we gather at the back of the shop and we
talk about growing it's gonna be Friday
the 21st Friday the 21st of October yeah
November November because we can't go
back in time No
well it's my favorite movie ever Back to
the Future trilogy alright guys I'm
gonna have to get free that day no
matter what happens because you guys are
all gonna come save the date again
November 21st November 21st it's a
Friday and hydro indoor growing supplies
about 6:00 6:15 yeah well we did it four
to eight last time and kind of decided
the two hours when we were open looks
kind of lame so I don't know it's awful
yeah now we're gonna have barbecue pork
we were thinking about doing turkey but
everyone's got plenty of Turkey I don't
wanna be that [ __ ]
yeah that's few but over have some good
smoked pork from probably my dad will do
it he's been smoking meat for many years
and his dad is a cool son of a [ __ ] and
I am going to get a vegetarian option
too so nice that's much appreciated and
just for people who need to eat their
damn veggies or vegetables guys I've
been a vegetarian for oh my god over 10
years I can't remember exactly when I
know I was a vegetarian in 2002 for sure
can't remember before that when I
started but there was an event that
happened one of my friends I hadn't seen
in a while made fun of me for being a
vegetarian at Bonnaroo and the first
Bonnaroo was 2002 since then since I
started eating better right I try to eat
a little better a better a better all
the time but the more I take care of my
body the better I feel it's so great so
eat your vegetables guys that's a pizza
not don't eat as much meat you know even
if you eat meat America eats way way too
much of it try to eat food quit eating
like food product like processed [ __ ]
that kind of resembles food you don't
want that you want food it's got like 17
ingredients in it that's not food
anymore yeah look for fewer ingredients
and the easier they are to pronounce
yeah all those doses and X doses and the
maintance none of that [ __ ] is good for
you we're gonna ramble it now how about
we wrap up a podcast and we'll look
forward to talking you guys and about
seven days where's the end I've got that
thing I read at the end of the show and
I can't find it guys what am I gonna do
I think there's the paper I need alright
guys don't forget to follow Jesse on
Instagram and Twitter it's at Jesse
grows og on Twitter it's Jesse grows on
Instagram make sure you follow
I read genetics on Instagram make sure
you follow I grow culture on Twitter
Instagram and Facebook that's a lot of
demand just check us out if you can on
Twitter beggin do it do it now yes open
up your butt we need to get some like
really cool tone open up your phone and
follow us hey I want to give a shout-out
to Yeti og that's just awesome strained
my favourite new strain it that I got my
hands on this year cookies Yeti Sour
Diesel grateful dog to gorilla glues and
then to platinum oh geez all in a row so
that's like my stellar row yeah I'm like
ooh let's see what these girls do next
to each other the same thing they're all
under the same two lights we'll see what
they do there in seven gallon pots I'm
getting excited just recently I got to
chuck pollen took a Grateful dog mail
and threw his pollen all over a bunch of
sexy ladies so about January nature's
green remedies will be stocked up
yeah all right now that the show is over
go to iTunes and or stitcher source try
grow culture find the review section
give me a five star rating after that
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the podcast and I will read
your comments on a future episode big
thanks to all the guys that have left
comments I appreciate that the guys and
gals that have left comments they do
appreciate that don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every episode is available on IRA
Genetics Colorado com yes I have been
slacking off on putting videos on
YouTube but I will catch up pretty soon
I've been having too much fun lately
what the Garden of the Gods was my
friend and had a great time just enjoyed
life for a couple of days I'm sorry
I'll get back on track don't worry I
want to give a huge shout out to my
ninja spin so I want to send an extra
special thanks to Jesse for coming to
all these episodes it's really cool
thanks a lot bro problem enjoy guys you
can tell you so much more comfortable
now I'll sit in here like Larry King
with the pen in my hand don't hijack my
dad's closet there we go alright guys
thanks again for listening take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me hey
baby
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome it's time for episode number 40
of the iGrow culture podcast I'm your
host Rasta Jeff joining me at the table
again is our good buddy Jesse how you
doing bro
pretty good how's it going out there
podcast land podcast and internet world
hopefully you guys are listening to us
while you're driving to work or playing
in the garden or doing something fun
whatever you're doing I hope you got a
dab or a fat joint or a bowl of
something super dink we're smoking some
live resin some Bounty Killer no not
Bounty Killer it's oh it is bounty
killer live resin no it's not it's
Capleton live resin sorry I just lied
it's it's in live resin tasty good big
shout out to the dude that grew it
what's up Ryan nice work and an extra
special shout-out to the guy that
blasted extracted it for us this stuff
is super tasty who would imagine that
the IRA genetics guy would have all this
eye region etics tips sitting over there
it's really nice to see you can't even
keep them straight yeah it's really nice
to watch my friends grow my genetics and
then to have one of our good brothers
extract it for us and then he gets his
Ash back and he calls me dude come over
and get some of this hash I just heard
of gold there was grateful dog and there
was Capleton live resin and dude that
was tasty stuff Doria it lefty I keep
saying citronella candles sort of scent
in the room if you're into that that was
a great smell guys I want to take one
quick second give a huge shout out I
always do this at the end of the show
but we got to do a special shout-out
extra special shout-out to my ninja
spence spence has been sick as hell we
found out just recently that his
appendix had ruptured inside of him and
he had to have it removed dude I'm so
glad you're on the way to recovery we
were super worried about you I was
stressing out worrying about my brother
I love you more than you ever will
realize so big shout out to spend
student everybody send your love and
energy to get in spence better get
better buddy come on feller yeah shoot
some hoops you got to make some hash
Spence is gonna win with a secret Cup
finals in Vegas I'm confident
- and appendix
can he fly cheaper he just lost some
weight actually looked it up to them I'm
pretty sure he was pretty bad shape it's
completely worthless somebody asked me
what is your appendix to do and I looked
at him and said I don't know it's full
of a poisoned vial good job creator
[Music]
energy to people that need some help I
want to send a big huge healing vibe to
my good friend Angela she hasn't been
feeling well the past week she's got
some medical things going on that's kind
of private to her so we don't need to
elaborate but dude send a lot of healing
vibes to Angela
big shots Angela care a lot about you I
want you better I want to see you
smiling again hey what's up guys have to
jump in and do a disclaimer I played the
shout out for Angela and when she heard
it she said that I made it sound like
there's something wrong with her vagina
I need to assure you there's absolutely
nothing wrong with Angela's vagina let's
get back to the show and get into a show
I do owe another shout-out to more shout
outs shout out to the man afro man he
played a show in a town near me there's
a little VIP party at a dispensary
called the spot shoutout to the spa
what's up Robert what's up Vegas they
got me to see afro man got a couple of
photos with that man
it's actually Angela's fault she works
there she got me the little VIP hookup
so super shout out I walked in an afro
man was taking pictures with people and
doing a little quick private
meet-and-greet and he saw me he was oh
[ __ ] come here my man with Rasta Jeff
for some reason okay the owners of the
spot said that he could come smoke with
me but he probably would not make it to
his show so he often did not smoke
he was like you look like you might
murder me with some smoke so yeah and
unfortunately after that so we can't
talk about what happened all right a
couple other things to shoutouts are
done shout out to everybody that's
listening to the show this is episode 40
we made it
40 episodes bro this is good I promise
you guys the episodes are getting better
I've been doing more preparation I've
been doing more planning I've got the
next few episode topics already listed
of what I'm gonna do
coming up in a couple episodes we're
gonna do an episode about nutrients
people ask me tell me about nutrients
what is all this NPK 5 3 9 my bottles
what should I be feeding what do I need
so we're gonna cover that and also our
friend Ross Cola King Cola Sean is gonna
come be on the show to be on the show
[ __ ] you he hypes a growing system that
he has labeled organic as [ __ ] I've been
gone for quite a while and he has he has
the approach that I hope to get to I'm
not where he is yet he's got a very
environmentally friendly environmentally
sustainable way of growing and it's kind
of impressive I'm impressed and it takes
a little bit to impress me these
fermentations that look delicious if I
didn't know what was in there some of
that stuff would look tasty yeah yeah no
they really do and it smells good
because of the molasses alright tell you
about his stuff we'll get him on the
show so shout out to Ross Cola King Cola
and organic as [ __ ] pretty soon guys I'm
saying that for but it doesn't cost
money anymore and I'm actually quoting
this guy's brand so you can't charge me
on that one something he can't charge me
for this podcast is Brett
you buy a highly-educated titanium if
you're using high quality concentrate
like these heart of gold live resin you
don't trust those Chinese nails it's not
titanium titanium because it's the most
read you want for your dabs if you want
to buy a nail right now all these
episodes this indoor growing supplies or
the dude can I tell them what they'll
pay for that $17 and change for that bag
usually that's the twenty five dollar
bag of dirt so we saved
I saved eight bucks just by using by
telling them yeah dude it was really
cool is really easy they didn't even you
know when you get a discount some places
they act like you're a dick oh you
pricey yes you do you do give me a deal
so make sure you tell them that you're
listening with agriculture podcast and
also check out their website hi grow
Denver calm pretty sure I didn't write
it down so I thought I remembered and
apparently I got yeah
[Music]
has a facebook on their Facebook on
their Instagram yeah we've got the
[Music]
birthday so happy birthday yeah also
guys this podcast is brought to you by
our friends at Treehugger comm tree
sugar contour no one asked me what is
that it's a cool name it's it's mostly
concert and festival news and reviews is
what it is they talk about all the
concerts that come to Red Rocks if you
listen to stuff like the string cheese
fish galactic the Grateful Dead sound
tribe sector 9 the Disco Biscuits even
if you're into like boom box and
Bassnectar so I'm trying to think of
that's not my thing sorry I'm more of a
fish Grateful Dead reggae kind of a kid
but I check it out because I want to
know when fish is coming and what the
cheese is up to tree thicker calm will
keep you up-to-date with all of your
hippie news I like to say look
the cookout with Treehugger calm every
time you say String Cheese Incident I
think of Richard cheese popular songs in
a lounge style usually I would take this
time to read comments on Facebook or on
stitcher and iTunes but I haven't got
any new comments the people that did
leave comments if you want to leave some
comments on iTunes and stitcher I will
read them also check out the comments on
Facebook all the intro I look at
everything every now and then make sure
there's no you know on the Instagram
yeah oh yeah I try so hard to answer all
of the questions I get since they shut
down Facebook shut down the I read
genetics Facebook page and took it from
an interactive page and made it to just
a business page which I find boring so
I've gotten a lot of spare time to check
[Music]
those Facebook's I do check them down to
your questions but I don't really play
there like I used to they kind of pissed
me off taking my page down like that
without even talking to me dicks we've
been doing grow lessons teaching you
guys or trying to sort of stoner style
teach you guys how to set up a grow room
for yourself so that you can be
self-sufficient we've gotten the room
bill we talked about the best places to
do it we give you a good guide so far
we've got a room built with lights
hanging but we haven't hung our ballasts
yet and our timers so that's kind of
where we are if you guys need to catch
up I'll take a pause and you can go
listen to the two episodes before this
you can catch up or we are pausing
there's another chance Oh anything is
fun I like the flow yeah we built an 8x8
room you've got your poly wraps were
around everything it's all sealed up you
got your lights hanging now what I would
like to do is show you tell you the way
I hang my ballasts and my electronics
and Jesse and I have a lot of different
ideas so this will get fun I use a piece
of plywood to mount all of the
electronics in one area at Lowe's or
whatever hardware store they actually
sell a pre-cut board
I think it's 24 it may be 18 inches by
36 inches you can screw that right under
the wall and you can I can fit four I
can fit five ballasts and my power box
on that so all the bowels are plugged in
to the power box and it's also screwed
to the board I screw the board to the
framing on the outside of the grow room
to keep the heat down Jesse was talking
about if you put it on the inside keep
it close to the door the outside is
ideal because if something goes wrong
you don't have to go in there to turn
everything off yeah also keep a fire
extinguisher near that box that's
something that I recommend you don't
want to have to run into the Grill Room
if keep a smoke alarm in there if there
is a fire you don't want to have to go
half way through the room because we get
into your fire extinguisher you want to
have it outside kick the door open and
start spraying put out fire that's your
that's your biggest fear but we you got
to be prepared for that so you got this
board you got four ballasts you've got I
put a powder box on there cuz that's how
I plug everything in yeah I like those
power boxes they're really reliable they
don't pay me to say that I buy them
later a darker made in America yes I was
gonna ask you here's a random side note
what ballasts are made in America do you
know
you can google that while I read on for
a second it's almost time for me to buy
several more ballasts and I would like
to buy american-made products because I
noticed that the what the hell brand is
that the Quantum's that used to be made
in Germany now they come with the made
in China or a made in Korea sticker on
them really quickly those used to be my
go-to s because they don't sales like a
next gen does next gen will just shoot
out alone it'll try to start up and fail
just before I need to replace my 401
[Music]
actually hard to find you just keep them
flowering you don't need to run all that
much if you're just doing a female hunt
for boys how many people feed all that
for males if you're four meals you're
probably not everything we've said so
far at the table right here if you're
female hunting for males you're invited
send me a message we'll find you
agriculture hotmail.com we're just
strategizing about the very subject
yeah dude can we talk about that yeah go
for it I'm getting really excited about
it me too I read genetics of course I'm
Ross to Jeff from I originates I've been
around and I read genetics for a couple
few years now it's been public seeds
have been available I cannot keep up
with the demand for my product I've got
enough reading space to breed plenty of
seeds but when they go on sale at
nature's drain remedies they sell out in
like 48 hours
yeah so our good buddy Jesse has stepped
up to the plate and now I think Jesse
will I'm gonna run a bunch of his [ __ ]
as soon as it's done and when I see that
his stuff does good we're gonna add him
to our lineup he'll be part of team I
read genetics will be another breeder
he'll be our second breeder tripod farms
[Music]
will be available through the flavor
it's stinky it just doesn't grow with
the vigor that I want it's got good
yield for a plaintiff normally exhibits
[Music]
up with Gorilla Glue my Gorilla Glue has
tripled in size since I started do you
find me an american-made ballast no I'm
not fine I don't suspect the galaxies
are I know some light a lot of their
products are made in America if you guys
have an idea of a good american-made
ballast let me know cuz it's for me I'm
shopping I need a lot of them oh man you
know what actually I think I know of one
it's a really expensive one
no those be made in Holland yes what's
the kavita's competitor the e paps
keep apps that really those are China
China's over the nano Lux TVs I know
those are wonderful ash lights are made
in America or if they're made in China I
would suspect that maybe either
I'd really hope they are yeah Oh so
let's tech made in California okay
yeah very good stuff something to check
out King Z them I suspect that maybe the
hoarder lux makes ballast I think maybe
their stuffs made in America okay I want
to buy american-made ballast guys I
encourage you to also I take this board
that I bought at Lowe's and I put the
board on the floor and I'd mount my bow
I said don't screw it to the floor I set
it on the floor so I can work let me be
clear about that I sent the board on the
floor and then I screw the ballasts to
the board and then I screwed my power
box to the board and now this board is
movable you can hang your ballasts damn
near anywhere you want both that to or
is convenient for you if it's the
outside of the room is what I would
prefer because then you're keeping heat
up those balazar yeah do it outside of
the room and then then you can mess with
your timers and stuff and not be in the
room so that it's just easier so bolt
that wherever you need screw that
wherever you need to the framing then
run that wiring through a small hole
nepali and tape over it to keep the
light from leaking so now you've got air
and air out lights and power if probably
gonna need to cool down the room an air
conditioner is definitely what you're
gonna need you may need a dehumidifier
so take another small board and put your
air conditioner thermostat on there if
you have one that doesn't attach to the
air conditioner you can plug your air
conditioner into a temperature sensor
and hang that on the wall and then when
the temperature gets to a certain thing
up to the certain temperature dream that
you can set the day and night
temperature and then that little leader
will tell the air conditioner when they
come on and want to go off and you can
do that with almost any piece of
equipment in your room you can automate
your your dehumidifier your air
conditioner you can automate your fans
in one room I've got a emergency
shutdown switch if it hits over 9 to 5
degrees in that room everything turns
off every
even the air conditioners because I
don't know what's causing the problems
when everything just shuts off and
Debian tips are only gonna be 70
something in that area anyway there's no
there's no light so automation but all
your automation stuff on one board and
put that where it's visible put a
thermometer a hygrometer on there you
want to be able to see has to be inside
the room so put that in the room if you
have to if you get this it's if you want
that outside of their little be more
expensive trust me that will probably
have to go in the room so just put all
your stuff onto one board and nail it to
one spot up high where you can see it a
random side note when you build the
drill room and you're thinking about
planting your grow room think of water
goes low electrical goes high you want
your water low on the ground if you have
a bucket if you got a reservoir there's
no need to lift that up off the ground
too high keep it low because if it does
topple over you don't want it to spill
on your electronics which should be kept
above waist high I don't run conduit
along the wall lower than about 36
inches that's my waist keep water low
electricity high because you don't want
to pour water into electricity
ever keep your cords organized you guys
I've seen so many messes of fire
detector or you can get in the room of
the fire detector outside of the room
those are little side notes that I wrote
yeah so you're gonna need air
conditioning is what I wrote down next I
follow the general rule of three
thousand BTUs of air-conditioning per
thousand watt light if you want to use
those traditional ACS you can put in the
window you can cuddle that do go in a
window you can cut a hole in the poly
and not the AC to the framing but that's
gonna heat up whatever room you dump the
AC exhaust into if you're in a garage or
unused basement that's cool but you
can't heat up like if you're
Sasa Kido it's gonna go somewhere we're
just gonna continue to heat up yeah you
can run it a lot of people run it
straight through the chimney if you got
one I've seen it going to the Attic if
you need to if you guys are in illegal
states you're gonna have to fly this a
little better because your heat
signature is what they're gonna look for
the bus do I think 2014 almost 15 where
the cops can do just about whatever then
they'll just send a car to go sit in
front your house and then don't notice
some [ __ ] you know the cops are the
worst gang that we have nowadays the
worst criminals on the streets under air
conditioners if it's going to outside a
lot of them or if their conditioners in
your room and it's in an outside window
light shines through yes you can take a
can of spray paint get you remember how
I did it but there's some way you can
give a nozzle on there that you can
stick a little straw in like wd-40 say
the wd-40 Scott yeah perfectly
oh and spray the white foam inside the
vents with black spray paint and it's
all clean and everything let's not be
reflective stops the light from coming
out good idea good idea if you're
putting that in the so cool actually
shut up the sub cool did you so I didn't
brag about this I posted a really sweet
picture to Instagram the other day and
sub cool actually sent me a message that
said we should collab so in the future
there could be some TGA I read genetic
stuff happening but uh right now I'm
gonna focus on what I'm doing with
Jessie because I know that's for real I
had to melt I wanted to say before we
get sidetracked the black spray-paint on
the air-conditioner I like to use the
energy but I like those air conditioners
on wheels they have a little duct you
can just duct it right out of a six-inch
duct it works perfect
those are glorious they take a little
more air a little more electricity yeah
but they're awesome also you need maybe
a fan speed controller if you're those
are always helpful just there's always a
reason to add a fan speed controller I
bought a little thermostat thing to turn
off my air cooled fans when it gets too
cold outside yeah I walked out to the
room the other day and there's 4000 watt
lights burning and normally you know
it's 70 to 68 degrees in there and it
was like 55 degrees yeah I should have
all the fans off everything and it took
most of the life cycle the heat back oh
wow yeah I love it just went I it was
negative six degrees here these are
night where we live very [ __ ] cool
that is cold yeah my my ground my air
conditioners aren't on in any of my rows
right now that's okay I've turned all of
the air conditioners off just let that
receiving some electricity right now a
lot of electricity yeah
yeah I'm that guy that automates as much
as I or everything will go wrong I have
to love this room almost everything else
of course you light cycles your air
conditioning your co2 they want to ban
co2 augmentation things they wrote the
rules so we'll talk about that more in
the future we just mounted the ballasts
right to a board then we put the board
right up on the wall then you got to run
all the cables that's the part I skip to
make sure when you push the cables
together make sure you push them tight
oh all the way tight because when that
shits loose that's electricity that's
why right there just being exposed I
want to design I've made him myself I
just bend them all up but out of wire
but do safety wire - yeah - hold it all
together when I was in bands I learned
to tie cords that are connected together
in that knot or if you pull instead it
tightens that knot stead of em coming
apart I like that move a lot I used to
be a roadie a musician
yeah I talked about a tip on pictures
and since we're talking about running a
course here it is the cord the grunts
from the ballast to the light is what
causes all the bars in your picture so
the shorter those are and the neither
they're hung and everything
the last bars and [ __ ] you'll have
because it's the magnetics it causes
that yeah okay I think that's a good tip
I didn't know that I can't remember I
have it no I didn't really care about my
new room I think if you keep all
accorded away from each other to you
know individually instead of so they
don't try not together on the ceiling
okay make sense
I wrote down so much stuff on so many
different papers I'm looking for them
all we've got this room mostly figured
out we got lights hung we've got all of
our automation set up hopefully we got
air going in we got air going out we've
got an air conditioner now that you got
most everything set up and get your pond
liner on the floor I would add four four
by four tables I use brands but I used
the Hydrofarm four by four white flood
tables because they're perfect yeah
those are perfect I like to raise them
up off the ground I like the white
botanic air trees you can find someone
to make you a stand for them or you can
put them on buckets that are prefab
and cold temperature a little more
airflow to the soil to see what's
happening at the soil or the bottom
foliage cubes disaster what ups were
[Music]
killed everybody
Facebook Winton the Facebook Nazi police
went made everybody use our real names
now when I scroll through I don't even
know anybody
[Music]
here's the trick guys if you are a drag
queen I know that's not the appropriate
word but I don't know the appropriate
word anymore I'm not politically correct
in the drag queen you could email
facebook and say I'm a drag queen and
this is my alter ego and they will allow
you to use your fake name probably won't
work anymore after a couple of days that
this show is out people try it but
that's worked for that's why a lot of
the people that like in the cannabis
community
they're still Richard I know a bunch of
drag queens is like to know that
[Music]
November 21st I grown or growing
supplies to be awesome I will be there
Rasta Jeff will be there also that night
there's a random plug Joe Rogan's new
comedy special comes out on Comedy
Central the night of the 21st at
midnight I'm gonna leave hi girly
drawing supplies and I'm gonna come home
and I'm gonna get super dabbed out and
I'm gonna watch the Joe Rogan special
cuz I was there at Comedy Works when
that [ __ ] was recorded dude it was weird
we're totally off topic guys but have
fun with us
they were seeding us for the Joe Rogan
experience or the recording of his live
show and there were cameras all over
comedy works and they put me and my crew
there was me and my date and one of our
good friends and we all had dreadlocks
and they put us in about row 8 were
known to see us so we're like yeah I get
it
but then they would bring in
normal-looking people and set them in
rows 3 &amp; 4 but then if a guy came in
with a good-looking girl like there was
a girl that came in and I'm not even
being a dick she had her boobies hanging
out she was wearing like a peach colored
shirt
all tan and had her hair all done I
looked at my date may go front-row watch
[Music]
they're just doing it for TV they put me
under a camera because I was the camera
that Joe was looking directly into the
whole recording there was a camera like
20 rows back from the stage they only
did about half the comedy club fool that
night it was awesome yeah way ranting
but I had so much fun seeing Jonah it
was stress will be into taping their
roles they all they asked you for your
phone late Comedy Works wants to take
your phone from you so that it doesn't
ring or go off during the taping they
wanted they wanted me to cover up my
high region etics logo on my shirt but I
didn't do it yeah logos they definitely
put the 3ds probably Monday morning when
it comes out at work what's up I hope
you get to go to work to know is kind of
wrecked everybody's work week right now
so I've been playing nah I'm not gonna
see taxi because I don't mind doing it
but it's been nice helping all my
friends out there stuck her little
boyfriend out the overnight gigantic
trucks so it's not one of those diesel
very functional it's not it's not a
truck it's a working man's truck you can
deliver soil anywhere in Pueblo or
anywhere in Colorado with that trucker
team at the top of Pikes Peak Oh easily
yeah all right wherever I like Inbox
how it is around here right now it's
just slushy just go slow you guys would
be cool seems like nobody's driven in
the snow before done this it's just a
year ago we're kind of ranting here
we've had some dabs I hope you're taking
dabs so you're building a hydro Hut
that's very similar to this setup I'd
run the ducting for the lights there's a
couple way to do the lights but I would
run the lights the ducting straight
through the hut so that the heat never
makes it into the hut there's a hole on
the left side and the right side of the
hut at the top once I'd run the ducting
from the outside over the blower over
the light and out of the other side
[Music]
never actually stays inside the grow
house there's also a little hole the
roof of the hut I had a blower there I
said just the roof that's all the top
fresh air through the hut constantly I
put a carbon filter and a blower inside
the hut and fit it out of the top there
makes the air flow pull air in from the
bottom and the heat goes out the top and
always remember always remember that
your blower can pull more air they're
gonna push then it can push I wrote down
a lot of shitty half-assed notes right
there those notes were full sentences
blowers work better when they're outside
of the room it's the same reason you
never see the first fan in the bathroom
is mounted up in the ceiling easier to
pull air out the end it is to push
definitely easier to pull here's a
question for you do you run a carbon
filter intense when your click the
collecting pollen you know I've I don't
because I don't have a blower at all in
my tent where I'm collecting pollen I
run
dude this is crazy secret with one
flower and one under thousand well I'm
flowering a couple under his house would
walk right now so I think I might be
changing that out to different if I want
to see their fool I don't tell people I
take a brown paper bag and put it right
over the top Cola yeah what I'm sure
that I see him a whole bunch
I just cut that sucker off and then I
have the branch sticking out of the bag
and I'll hold it with my hand around the
branch and pull the branch out of the
bag slowly and as you pull you knock
everything off into the bag I use a
drumhead actually an old drum head flip
it upside down and I'm gonna repurpose
that [ __ ] so if you leave those in the
hut with that bag over there with the
blower on the top it doesn't steal a lot
but it does take a little bit but you're
gonna make enough we'll see you know I'm
also fetal hunting - all right just
collecting yeah and I already know that
means whoo I want some they're just jizz
away and collect it for sure Circle
tricking or [ __ ] and in a bag of not
just Paula choking this times yeah this
meal this is his the same male probably
his dance time pollinating [ __ ] a clone
of his 10th time hitting stuff at least
shoot my one male that are you
already have picked out proving himself
and everything but I took clones up with
the Association I took like 25 nice just
to make sure I will only keep one gonna
have you but you gotta have one yes I
recently took they all cut are they all
rooted most of the seeds I've sprouted
are all germinating and I'm working on
another project I tell everybody this I
am starting to f to black cherry Kim I'm
doing the pheno hunt to find the male on
the female to f2 that I plan to start
the flowering cycle right at the start
of the year so by March first dish I
should have found a good male and a good
female that will be used the clones of
those will be next to be bred to me
don't use two females and one male I'll
use a purple female and a non purple
female let's see what the progeny make
definitely a solid purple mate yeah I
just want to see if I cuz I may it may
make it recessive if I force too much
purple into it may not come out till the
f3 if I do that what's verbals I hope
you guys pay attention to that that's
random [ __ ] right there also another way
that I've been setting up these tents
with just one blower because it seemed
it seems efficient if you're in a small
space I put the five by five hut with I
do the blower right on top there I run
ducting into the hut and then around
into the light fix the light reflector
and then deducting out of the light
reflector to a carbon filter and the
carbon filter is fun really high in the
hut as high as you can get so now you're
filtering the air pulling out humidity
and cooling your light all at one time
and those work great in the garage right
now in Colorado in the winter you need a
heater but if you've got two of those
huts you could run them side-by-side and
you convince that heat into the other
hut from your light if you thought about
how to do
[Music]
sleeping plants emit co2 so if you move
your dark the air from your sleeping
room into your awake room you were
moving co2 to a usable space
that's a definite for people because we
have to travel with tanks but my
argument because I am going to go to
City Council when this comes up I'm
gonna say this is available at the
hydroponic store why can the guy growing
tomatoes or the guy growing orchids or
whatever else he's using there's so many
more dangerous things out there mica we
need you back on the show here in a week
or two because you've been going to
those meetings dude thanks a lot that is
not my thing I'm so glad you're going
but we need you to come update us with
what's going on in our community and
what kind of rules are trying to enforce
on us
[Music]
the weather and the growers yeah this is
like 60 degrees and within an hour it
was [ __ ] damn near freezing minus six
was cold the other night I was driving
home it was nicely cold at minus 6 it's
freaking cold right now man who's coming
up coming down like crazy
once you're prepared the first few winds
I'm from California dude winter killed
me Antarctica to get to school then when
you get to school at 77 in the classroom
[Music]
these generations are getting softer as
we go yeah we're talking about a doctor
our good buddy Spence had his appendix
removed and Jesse was kind enough to
post a meme of a doctor removing his
book that's pretty cute how many people
would just reach down and remove their
own appendix we're too entitled to say
if you got a question
I consider hydro hot like a champ I can
give you a lot of advice on that hung up
there too the other one up there those
are great I think instead of a big wide
reflector a little reflector is better
because you can make a sexual joke out
of this if you want but I want it to go
deeper I don't want it so wide you get
better penetration yeah yeah I want more
penetration I don't need you tearing it
apart so wide go deeper it's still I
mean you got a thousand watts a thousand
watts so if your reflector spreading it
out to a five by five area or you have a
reflector spreading it out to three by
three area which you know reflector
you'll get a better value for that
thousand Watts worth and in my opinion
it's gonna be the three by three every
time absolutely hittin those huts those
huts are very well made with that
reflective material in there they're
great
I feel like I get a lot more lumens out
of those huts than I do the open road
for sure they take better pictures to
background in there alright so most of
this is the same if you're working a
bedroom or a closet just on a smaller
scale if you can't cut holes for ducting
try using a window we kind of talked
about tricking on the windows actually I
use a premade inch flange
[Music]
just be lazy and stomp it out also make
everywhere oh yeah blue when you cut
that blue foam board it's gonna make a
gigantic foamy mess everywhere and it'll
clog up your saws like nothing other
yeah I think it's real hot disguise
you're out ducks if you conduct it out
of the attic or a chimney that's awesome
you don't want your neighbors seeing
it's minus-6 outside right now for my
heat is dumping outside I'm pretty sure
it's making steam even if it's 20
degrees it'll probably make steam
jumping into minus six so they can see
your air coming out of your gross space
I used to run a cycle or to make sure
the lights go off and in the room if you
need to keep in mind my greenhouse I
harvested all the plants right before it
got freezing cold in it but I had a
couple containers with lettuce and
spinach and radish and onions and I'm
super stoked with my little tiny heater
my little greenhouse once everything is
cool then you can put plants in there
and you're gonna have to make a couple
of adjustments if you're just vegging
you're fine you can tweak around with
your rooms while your vegging you're not
gonna piss the plants off too much as
soon as you start flower you have to be
really really careful with your photo
periods that's your light cycle we call
that don't mess with your photo period
keep that solid I didn't like to share
my breeding information cuz I feel like
I'll teach you how to grow but breeding
you gotta get a good grasp on growing
and once you've got that but I kind of
been sharing a little bit of my breeding
secrets so if you guys have a specific
question I'd rather help you than just
watch you fail right when I first got
started
[Music]
you know you know yeah I feel that it
causes problems it's part of what
inspired this show was reading shooting
on the internet going dude I hope nobody
tried that we're actually seeing
somebody ask his friend a question on a
forum that sounds like troll it up but
it's not troll it's very similar but
roll it up somebody asked a question
replied with a totally [ __ ] answer
to his friend and he's like awesome and
I'm gonna try it today I'm like dude
don't your friend just killed your whole
crop over many plants you have they're
dead if you do that there's a thing on
the probiotics farmers alliance a pin
that's the very first post if you ever
join it I can't quote it for verbatim
but by any means but a you know just
says essentially you know don't make
something back just because you believe
okay yeah yeah I can't really uh
recreate it but bs just you know there's
so much [ __ ] out there and people just
type [ __ ] and they believe it in their
full [ __ ] themselves in was just well
work for that may not work for you your
situation could be totally different
yeah I don't think I'm a member of that
group anymore so I will be able to see
it yeah alan taskin see
[Music]
my own f9i
last spring a head of plastic mold and
[Music]
my trimmer buddy Mike it was Mike it's
time we were just kind of new friends
it's time I just always like the whole
thing that's the difference between a
pot farmer and a caregiver for money
yeah there's just so many reasons
I don't like failure
I don't want to keep the Moldy plan
around my house two-spirit mole signal
orange elsewhere he knows this takes
pride in what you do guys you're working
really hard to grow cannabis do it right
don't make people sicker make people
feel better all right I feel like we
went over a whole bunch of information
in kind of a scattered way keep your
plants off the ground yeah keep your
clients upon the ground especially in
this cold weather
keep keep everything off the concrete
floor you can with your nutrients your
water reservoir clone tray supposed to
play oh yeah unless you're running an EZ
cloner and you need that cool water
true-true that's you know but if you
figured that out Dino you're probably
one of those guys that's just gettin
entertainment here so we're gonna we're
gonna definitely get more advanced as we
go we're 40 episodes in you guys are
learning stuff now I'm learning because
I have to read just to make sure it'll
why do you because I made a mistake on
the show one time when I felt really
stupid I don't teach it making sure to
read everything and stay on top I'm
reading more about nutrients because
they know about nutrients you get so
comfortable that's a phosphorus
deficiency yeah I need to do a little
homework I should be doing that anyway
Hayson honestly it's my profession but
yeah yeah those times when you're
sitting there in the store ready to pull
your beard out just grab a book
[Music]
Hydrofarm cygnus of a free book for
employees and stuff
one of our other employees is reading it
right now but I can't wait to go over
it's just about indoor hydroponic
gardening and I said you know I'm not
yeah yeah hydro forms afraid of the
cannabis industry oh yeah I have if you
ever really want to know my view on it
I've talked to several other hydro shop
owners and you guys all seem to agree
everybody feels the same about sunlight
and hydro farms are our customers built
oh I'll say this our customers built him
a hell of a nice [ __ ] living so yeah
yeah all right guys I feel like it's
about time to wrap up the show we've
been going for almost an hour here Jesse
you got anybody to shout out anybody say
thanks to anything like that
burn everyone down with the store
experience we good
they say that was strange okay
I've been digging on on submissive ego
cheese lately big time so when do I get
my cut of that SS vog
no no that's all I had to say because
yeah yeah I think I know where yours
came from and they don't want me to have
it being a breeder dude people don't
want you to have their cuts yeah yeah
kanessa fees made a lot of great strains
I think we're gonna make a couple with
tattoos I guarantee we'll make a couple
I'll make a couple you'll make a couple
yeah yeah all right guys we're gonna
wrap up the show now that show's over
please go to iTunes or stitcher go to
the iTunes Store or the stitcher main
page search Fried real culture find the
review section and give me a five star
rating after that type in a comment and
let me know what you think of the show
and I will really read your comments on
the show
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher and every episode is
archived on ira genetics colorado calm
why aren't you checking out i region
etics colorado calm and joining the
forum right now people ask questions on
the forum a lot of people were at will
answer you I'll answer you my buddy I
will answer you there's a lot of helpful
people on the forum I read you that X
Colorado calm
check out the forum the podcast is there
make sure you follow us on Twitter
Instagram and Facebook just search for I
grow culture follow I read genetics on
Instagram I post a lot of great cannabis
photography on there follow Jesse on
Instagram it's Jesse grows he posts a
lot of great cannabis photography if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like to see us review send me an email
at hydro culture at hotmail.com and I'll
get you all the info you need we still
need our own theme song if anybody wants
to help us out with that what's getting
shout out to my ninjas pants big shout
out to Angela shout out to Jesse for
coming in to another episode much love
to you guys for listening until next
time take a phat dab give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 41 of the iGrow
culture podcast I'm your host Rasta Jeff
thanks for joining me for another
episode excited to be here joining me on
mic tonight a good buddy Mike is back
what's up everybody and our good buddy
Adam is here yo Adam has been here for a
while
tired sick and tired yeah work well it's
about time yeah welcome back to the
working community let's turn that music
down a little bit and get a podcast
going we're gonna talk about some cool
stuff somebody was supposed to come I'm
not blaming anything on Jesse Jesse was
trying to make it he can't make it
tonight
unfortunately so had to kind of replay
in the show trying to get an electrician
to his new girl facility and tonight he
showed up and he called me I was like
dude do that so they know how hard it is
to get an electrician to your facility
and once he's there you're paying him
and it's hard to get him there so just
keep him there and get the work done so
Jesse had to take a rain check if he can
come over later or tomorrow I'll put out
another show in the middle of the week
with Jesse do it yeah Jesse was kind
enough to host another party at hydro
last night we'll talk about that a
little bit I need to before I even
forget before I have a chance to forget
I need to give a huge shout-out to Nano
Lux lighting and hydro indoor growing
supplies just looked over across the
room here there is a brand new pretty
new toy do dual-ended bulb and a ballast
and reflector all attached into one
piece it's the new nano luxe 1,000 watt
it actually has a 1200 watt setting on
it so I'm gonna be cranking 1200 watts
in one section and we're gonna see what
that light does they gave it to me to
run it
I said run a couple cycles let us know
what you think and we'll talk about the
future so if that works out nano looks
maybe a podcast sponsor in the future
here really really cool new toy I can't
wait to see what she does yeah me too
fancy looking light for sure it is it's
one of the the dual ended bulbs and it's
the kind that's got the ballast and it's
got a short reflector and I kind of like
it it's got it all in one piece and it
all hangs from the ceiling it's only
thee is it 240 or 220 it's only the 240
I always get that one confused sorry I'm
not good with my remember that many
goddamn numbers they messed with my
brain but I have a good feeling about
that I've heard a lot of good stuff they
gave it to me because they know I'm
gonna kick ass with it and see what it
does I probably should have asked before
I touch but that's one of the first
things I did when I walked in talked
about we all sat around today like a
bunch of bros and took dads and watched
a movie talk a little bit about that
we're actually going to watch a video on
the show together because some of us
have seen it some have it and I want to
watch it actually I haven't seen it to
tell you the truth and I know I need to
watch it I want to watch it live on the
podcast so that I can give you my
reaction live on the air it'll be fun
but before we get that far we have to do
this stuff right here this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
highly-educated titanium if you're using
high quality concentrates you deserve a
high quality titanium nail made in
America don't trust a Chinese nail or an
American knockoff made of cheap metals
trust the industry leader trust the
innovator trust the king trust highly
educated titanium be a huge shot at the
task rock do task is making these new
dabbers he's learned this new coloring
method so that he can color it he gets
lost in the mics that tone is hard to
record it takes me a minute to get
comfortable to beginning at every show
sorry listeners will get you here dude I
was gonna talk about this in a minute
so I'm gonna finish this edge check out
highly-educated ti.com for more
information if you want to buy some
highly educated products go to Aqualab
technologies comm and search for highly
educated got a bunch of great stuff
they're huge shout out while I'm
thinking about it
Jesse last night dude at the high girl
indoor growing supplies grower meeting
gave a class lecture on taking clones
that dude killed it bro he actually did
a hell of a good job just got this music
guy I don't know what's next on the
playlist I need to give a big shout out
to the mystic roots bandicoot dog and
stay positive sound stay positive
they have given me full permission to
play all of the mystic routes library on
my podcast that's freaking awesome
awesome super awesome the track you just
heard was DJ and a dance the
instrumental version they were kind
enough to send me every track they've
done instrumental so now we got a lot of
fresh music for the show nice so shout
out to Jesse dude he did a hell of a
good job hosting that party last night
yeah we're gonna talk more about that in
a minute but I want to get that shout
out before I get forget because for some
reason I get forgetful everyone was
talking about a pre-show dab and I
wanted to get the heads out of the way
and get those done right before I uh got
super dab down start coughing again this
podcast is always brought to you by
nature's drain remedies comm check out
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics La Plata lab since city
rare dankness mile hike an adventure the
Cali connection MTG I read genetics and
many many more trusted brands guys I
keep saying this but towards the end of
December around Christmas time
nature's green remedies will get a
refill on I read genetics products if
all goes well so far they're looking
like they're going well I will also have
a new coupon code for you this episode
of come out right on Monday it's gonna
be the 20-somethings but on the 1st of
December I will have a new coupon code
for nature's green remedies calm start a
whole browse month with a whole
brand-new pad I'm gonna save this ad
until we talk about some stuff we did
that's good to throw in later
be warned there's a commercial coming up
later guys I've been watching my buddy
Ryan's Instagram and Facebook and I do
is having a good ass time I'm proud of
you Ryan Ryan is actually the guy from
tree hugger com tree hugger com is a big
sponsor of our show they help us out a
lot you guys don't even know what Ryan
does for us so uh spot cast is brought
to you by tree hugger com live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
calm for concert and festival news and
reviews I like to say walk out at the
cookout with tree hugger dot-com Ryan
dude you're doing well I think that's
enough commercials right we paid all the
dues I got this one sitting aside here
we'll cover that one big shout out to
the sponsors I know it sounds weird
having sponsors on a podcast but they
help out a lot it takes a lot of time I
get products
that's that's content I really
appreciate the sponsors Taska you got my
email today read that bro thanks we
don't have any comments to read so guess
what that means guys it's time to take a
quick dab and then we're gonna come back
and we are going to review a couple of
videos that we watched and we'll
actually watch a video on the air guys
stick around we're gonna take a fat Dan
everybody we weren't [ __ ] we were
sitting there waiting for you to pay on
the show since the mics came back on no
we uh I'm gonna give a big shout out
while the heat up the nail Oh somebody
remind me the name of this place gotta
feel like an [ __ ] wasn't with you
higher elevation masterpiece productions
in Colorado Springs I had a broken rig
the joint got broken off it busted right
off but my email pulled the nail off
pulled a joint it right off and busted
that [ __ ] and I took it there and they
charged me a good price and they fixed
it and this sucker looks brand new
beautiful they did it in a timely manner
the price was right and the little chick
that works there is super sweet she's
super friendly I'll go back there when I
need a repair hopefully I don't ever
need to damn repair I'm gonna take a DAB
what do you guys talk about something
chaotic we um we went there and I mean
we were looking he was looking for a rig
but they had tons of little tiny rigs I
mean little tiny miniature cakes like
his Phase two over there that was I mean
maybe this big the smaller shake you
know for only you know not three inches
maybe two and a half but compared to
what we have here locally in town you
know it was it was definitely had more
selection they just had [ __ ] crammed in
cases like it merely had room you know
but there was definitely selection and
anything that you could imagine so it
was definitely a cool place met a
friendly dude in there that was you know
he was talkative and he had some some
golden goat or something was it goat or
was it yeah it's golden goat hash
alright you know we have anything to do
with the store though so don't go
expecting so okay well I didn't know it
we're trying to be social I've never
known any place that can fix a broken
piece before you break a piece it's gone
say goodbye Barry that's not good and
this looks brand new people so a little
bit but the price they charged me I was
blown away at how cheap it was as far as
I'm concerned it's a miracle they made
me drop know this was the thing before
they made me drop a deposit on it which
was cheap but you paid the deposit to
have it repaired they repair it and if
they break it when it's getting repaired
you get 30% off the rig of your choice
of the store oh nice yeah my voice will
come back I sound weird cuz I just took
a DAB I'm all choked up try to get this
dad going for Adam
so it was wider here correct and now
it's thinner right there just like that
yeah it looks like they cut it off right
at the top of because I broke it right
where the new joint the line is I broke
it right the old one broke right there
anyway so they just clean it up and put
a new one on nice and clean like Mike's
gonna caught forever after this so you
guys be prepared yes sorry folks it's
[Music]
two topics dude you guys killed it
Gatsby I shouted you guys out last week
and you got it but we're super Lemon
Haze right now and it's your throat it's
definitely lemon this one's my stash
I've had this set aside for a little
while there's a reason I had some of the
sour grapes
and it was some of the better shatter
that I've tasted here so big shout out
to those guys up there in Springs
rocking it
Jordan enjoys why you don't smoke
tobacco people ya hear Mike over there
trying to die it's like you need to
oxygen scuba gear just to do a podcast
row
we've all been there
except for you who is at the end of the
day of Herson I don't know if you'd add
much at all or with people at all you
see quickly as well you sound like this
on the radio yep you sound like you
should be our radio host for radio sir
all right let's bring this meeting to
order so we talked a little bit about
the meeting Mike was kind enough to show
up to the Gros meeting hosted by hydro
indoor growing supplies last night Engel
then then lesson time yeah but I liked
that it was nice the lesson was I think
I realized about halfway through that
most of us were probably able to do
everything that Jesse was teaching but
I'm glad he took that as his first
teaching opportunity because he was good
now dude he's learning and he's catching
up being on this podcast has really made
him a better speaker so he's able to do
that I think the next couple of lessons
Jesse's gonna really crush it I picked a
bad spot like my if I tried to watch
Jesse while he was talking I would have
been watching his back so I was watching
everyone else watch Jesse and I mean
cloning isn't complicated but he went
over all the steps real quick and at one
point everybody in the room pretty much
went oh yeah and took a second to pull
their phone out or grab a pen and jot
down a little note like I should use
this product or I'm keeping it too wet
or too dry or over underwater inner I
mean just little simple stuff it was
definitely the little talk afterward the
fine-tuning talked about
you're probably over-watering if that's
what you're doing you're probably under
watering that's what was cool that's
what was really valuable after that but
do jessie did a really good job I'm
super proud of him so shout out man good
job you did a really good job we wanted
to say that and also choked up also
you'd shout out to burn she lets us
throw a party back there in the back of
the store that's really cool that's it's
gonna her store it's her baby so thanks
for letting us make our mess in your
place you got like 12 dudes hanging out
back there and thank you for the invite
to to the social gathering there yes
supplies we'll do that every month and
we'll announce the dates on this show we
try to get as many people as we can
Armondo bro i look forward to you being
there i'm sorry you couldn't make it
hopefully we can have another one in
December
December's gonna rough for everybody
there's a lot of holidays there for all
the different religious groups you gotta
have they are talking about doing the
December event they uh they brought it
up at least twice last night I just
don't remember what the date was I don't
think they've have one nailed down yet I
have a little space a big space heater
they thought we decided to do it because
it was a little chilly bro
it's Colorado sometimes chilly is what
happens and in the room is that vapor
[Music]
yes what about you're seeing the larger
towards the outside of town that maybe
you would be able to got at one paw yeah
that's that's in the future we're we're
definitely looking at another social
club it'll be a private party thing that
will be an invite I was just thinking
for that since it was ya know so far at
the store because I talked about a
product and I can run down a hallway a
whole bunch of people left with stuff
which was awesome I left okay I told
this story once but I'm sitting there
the night's pretty much over a whole
bunch of people left with products that
they bought after the bro lesson is what
I was going for but there were a bunch
of people the left with stuff like you
left was given weight big give out gifts
they definitely give out prizes and [ __ ]
for people coming we're gonna start
doing contests and [ __ ] also we're just
we're just getting it started we don't
know we're doing this isn't our Forte we
just decided that it needed to be
Jessie designed taking credit for
nothing
Jessie did all of this he decided that
this needed to happen so he's learning
when I'm helping him learn you know to
say that you to kind of inspire each
other I see is now kind of officially a
part of IRA genetics he's breeding seeds
available as far as I think our plan
goes they'll be in my region etics
packaging and on the Huayra genetics
website we're just gonna add them to
here and I'll give Jessie credit you
know what I mean Jessie is now breeding
it's not all me those strains that
they'll be specific strains it's awesome
yeah so I'm sitting there at the hydro
meeting I'm chillin talking to people
just like we do [ __ ] I'm nice and
dabbed out and Jessie comes up any
slides ain't Nana walks thousand watt
light a full kit right in front of me
and he goes here man run this and let me
know what you think and I was like
shocked I think come up with Christmas
doesn't just appear in front of you like
on a Friday in November
and it did last night for you this one
to watch yeah it was kind of I was
confused right because I'm not used to
guy getting a big that's a big-ass gift
again that's a nice yeah that was huge I
didn't see it coming and what I saw
Jesse give it you know in three months
when you come back to them like do you
do like a trading credit can I take Kiwi
take these five it's nano luxe is the
company analogues and hydro indoor
growing supplies get mad respect from me
check out my on Instagram I post a lot
of stuff as I read genetics that's me
look there that like really honestly
won't get hung until December I've got a
crop that's growing in the room where
that will go
then when that crop finishes that light
will go up and it will start under there
and if it kicks as much as it appears if
it you know as it looks you'll be in the
shop buying three more of them here come
March
I'll buy four more my only concern is
venting those don't match up with my
finding style so I can only run those in
the wind very true but I can you know if
they kick as much asses people have been
saying I can readjust my rooms all I
have to do is change air conditioning
right
I could just go change up a little bit
couldn't you just shorten the pipes and
kind of ducked out from the main room
from top and filter into the bottom you
know cool air in hot air out but the
lights are burning our ducted so the
heat from the lights I'm running now
doesn't ever make it to the room and
those are not ducted it's the only only
downside that I'm seeing right now one
unit which I've never seen before the
ballast and the delight is all usually
separate and this is all one solid
really well built you really see it
looks like it's well bells much lighter
than it looks also it looks like it's
heavy as hell but it's really light nice
yeah alright so let's do this since
we're talking about this podcast is
brought to you by high Gro indoor
growing supplies two locations to serve
Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street or check out the Pueblo location
at 618 East 4th Street Pueblo Colorado
check out high grove for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
to grow supplies hydro gotta catch up
with myself hydro is running a special
for the podcast listeners when you check
out at Highgrove tell them you listen to
the hydro culture podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase
that's so cool that's a sweet deal I was
talking about it the other night I uh I
bought a bag of dirt that bag of dirt
that you see part of it on the ground
there that bag of dirt is a twenty five
dollar bag of dirt I paid about eighteen
seventeen dollars and some jingles some
change in there for that bag of dirt out
the door because I paid commercial
pricing that's a hell of a deal if we
pay what the dispensaries pay is what
our pricing is if you use that that code
if you tell them I listen to the hydro
culture podcast yeah it's helpful for
someone like me yeah I'm saying hey you
could save yourself some money there
it's coupons Cubans
some coupons speaking of couponing shout
out to Maddie what about Maddie you're
the coupon clay it's good to see you
back in action booty looked good last
night dude I saw Spence last night
Spence is back in action back on his
feet
dude weighs a hundred and forty pounds
now he's about six he's somewhere
between 64 and 65 depending on who you
ask
I never run into people taller than me
he's one of the few yeah and he's a
hundred and forty pounds dude so you
guys send him some calories if you can
mentally put calories on my brother
spent just send them right to him
because he needs some help right now I
feel it because you know he's back home
that's the secret look for that maybe
what I'm wishing he knows what I mean
well the secret cup is coming up it's
coming out of the finals and you think
no I don't think about December 15
because that's a brown one he'll be back
I predict you know I'm just guessing
being hypothetical here but the second
week of December may be the beginning of
the third week of December you think
right here in Mike's chair you think
we'll have the secret cup winner garden
of Weeden
lovely lady Madi sitting right next to
us right here if you do can I be in the
chair that's behind the dad stuff
sometimes people sit in and there's no
mic the mic sits right here next to me I
could fire this mic up but it's got a
droopy stand from what I understand it
does but we just that sometimes people
don't want to be heard and they just sit
on the podcast and just watch and then
I've looked them in the eye when I do
the intro and stuff and I have someone
to talk to in the podcast world when
you're doing a microphone and you got
you got a voice going like the energy
sometimes you fail there was a night one
night when Adam and I say her for
probably 45 minutes just going so
welcome to the [ __ ] show we are
failing miserably with a rhythm and a
conversation and a lesson and you should
probably fast-forward through the rest
of this show because tonight is not our
flow episode 12
how it fell we pulled it off eventually
through the magic of editing and a lot
of dabs
[Music]
we'll send you free [ __ ] wait Mike said
that so tweeted Mike and he will send
you free [ __ ] that's what my notes for
so how much wrap that up in quite
quickly and local news for most of what
we're doing here this is fir this is
happening at my town and in my County so
this is very pertinent to me I'm a
grower I've got a home grow I grow my
personal medicine here in my house I do
some small stuff in my home because
that's what we do
it's Colorado everything has to happen
in a large facility I am high Oh Mike's
medical marijuana provider and his
caregiver is happening pertains to Mike
they're trying to enforce rules upon me
and my grow that will it's gonna it's
gonna [ __ ] with Mike's medicine supply
I've been trying to find a classier way
to say that but it's gonna hinder my
production of Mike's quality medicine
and Mike relies on me for medicine so
Mike is going to City Council I'll keep
cutting me off but I'm good Mike is
going to City Council to make sure this
doesn't happen so this is super
important to me
this [ __ ] could happen in your area and
someone's got to stand up and do what
Mike does so if you're doing that I give
you a huge shout out I'm gonna turn it
over to Mike for a couple minutes tell
me what you learned at City Council
recently all right down here in Pueblo
Colorado they're looking at passing home
girl rules in the city and in the county
it's two very separate efforts you have
to go to two very separate meeting
to be involved with this process right
now the Planning and Zoning Department
with the city has finalized their
proposal they're sending that
recommendation on to City Council city
council will receive it I expect that to
happen at their first meeting in
December that's December 8th and then
their final meeting in December on
December 22nd they'll be taking or
they'll likely be taking public comment
and a vote on these proposed home grill
rules that will essentially limit every
caregiver in Pueblo they're really
really ugly rules folks you want to get
down and down to City Council on the
22nd and speak out against these rules
for sure they're also doubt in the
county that meeting is going to be
taking place on December 10th at 9 a.m.
so that meetings a little bit closer
mark your calendars if you can get down
there check that out if you're
interested in local pueblo cannabis law
news check out pablo for sensible
cannabis laws on facebook i'm trying to
post this stuff up as fast as I can but
getting digital copy copies of the
ordinances that I can easily post to
Facebook has been a little tricky but
info about the meetings and what you can
do to help out is that's the best place
to look right now if you're looking for
that kind of info and that's essentially
it folks this is just mainland there's a
whole lot of them they don't make a
whole lot of sense I'm doing a whole
bunch of private lobbying trying to
example of a couple of the stupid rules
they're trying to put out there banning
all co2 usage in any sort of marijuana
grow room but the
they write that rule I mean it's dumb
just on its face but the way it's
written would make it illegal to take
the SodaStream machine I have in my
kitchen into a grow room and use it I
think that's a special new crime now
that's a rule that I find ridiculous
because there are people too he's
talking about co2 for co2 augmentation
we run co2 in grow rooms because the co2
plants would thrive with more co2 than
what's naturally available in the
atmosphere in your natural girlier
probably have about three to five
hundred probably right around four
hundred particles per million of co2 if
you go to the hydro shop they'll set you
up with the system where you can get
about it would be cool if you could get
about 1,200 to 1,800 PPM's of co2 in the
room what that does is your plants
breathe back and they grow much more
vigorously and get bigger bud to get
denser bud to get larger plants and it
makes them grow more quickly so tomato
growers use this all kinds of indoor
plant growers use all of these rules are
written so that they could easily be
applied to anybody doing the same thing
with something that's not cannabis but
it's all cannabis specific so they don't
make a lot of sense hopefully the City
Council will see how much nonsense this
is and kill it on and send the whole
matter back to Planning and Zoning for a
redo but I just think it's done that
they pick out co2 because the tomato
farmer can go to the hydro shop and buy
it and take it to his house and run in
the basement just like just like Adam
would in his basement grow just like
Mike wouldn't his basement grow just
like they heard something that sounded
scary and so they wrote a rule that says
you can't do that and because they don't
know what they're talking about and the
research didn't get done a lot of the
rules don't make sense
I mean I've described it to other people
is like listening to a five-year-old
lecture on calculus it doesn't matter
how much homework they did the night
before but the the lecture will be total
nonsense from start to finish and anyone
not throwing rocks is doing so out of
being polite I think it's just painful
the last time we went to of the council
at least seemed to be I won't say pro
pot but
not against it definitely like I
wouldn't see anyone our council is Pro
pop but there are some that are
interested in what you know you're still
there's still the minority of the vote
it's not flying for sure which is why I
keep bringing it this is mod cast
because people need to show up to these
meetings and start pitching in if
Planning and Zoning z' work on the
marijuana rules is indicative of their
work on other rules that might be an
explanation and the why nothing works
here like it might just be that nobody's
paid attention to government for so long
that note like they don't expect to get
caught just doing nonsense a lot of
people aren't aware that we can just go
to City Council and sign up and sit at
that little cozy chair with a microphone
dude it's cushy it feels they make they
kind of it's intimidating if you're not
that kind of person but the one the
first time you go I feel like I could go
now if I had some real business to go
deal with I could I could go speak there
it's inviting anybody can go you can go
totally under there I can't see his
pants but his shoes are definitely muddy
is so but dude you're invited to go talk
in City Council you can speak and nobody
will judge you they'll listen to what
you have to say they may judge you judge
one person for a few minutes and it was
almost entertaining but you can go speak
and you can say your piece and you get I
think five full solid minutes and these
except during public comment they give
anyone who wants to come and sign up
five four minutes to speak on anything
they'd like to and this happens in every
city if you've got a city hall that has
City Council meetings you can go and you
can even if it's something that one guy
came and talked for six minutes about
the bike lane right and how to use them
yeah I was gonna say it felt like he was
giving the City Council a lesson on how
to use bike lanes but I think he was
asking for more funding to create more
bike lanes was his goal or information
on how to use bike lane in these
meetings or poke at public broadcast
free to the public on like channel 16 or
17 here locally
and so he's trying to show the city how
to use these new bike lanes just he
found out a freeway to get on TV and
give a Pete a little educational spiel
on bike lanes if you guys are against
something that's going or if you need
something that isn't happening to happen
if you if you're not getting some good
recycling in your city go to City
Council be like hey we've done a lot of
trash we should work on some recycling
if that's your pet do whatever your
passion is our passion is cannabis so
we're going to City Council and we're
saying cannabis a lot there's a young
woman who comes down and speaks on
roadside memorials all the time and I
mean half the rooms in tears every time
she speaks 30 seconds - are you for
against roadside memorials I honestly
don't care you don't care well that was
a quick 30 seconds Adam you know me I
don't care are they trash or they to me
it's something that to me no one's been
lost so it's hard for me to really your
every culture has a way they more it's
kind of intense
I don't know driving around and not
being used to roadside memorials cuz
it's not something you see all the time
in Denver even though people have died
on every street corner don't expect to
vote for our president and he's gonna
change cannabis laws your City Council
scary that you has to be cannabis
cannabis pro cannabis and then you work
from your City Council to your mayor and
you try to get that dude in office
that's the way Colorado did it it didn't
start it started in Denver and they
decriminalized it and it worked out
words am i I mean this is just what I
know from looking outside anything
political you definitely start local
that's where you generate your base and
your
and that's what they're talking about
when they say grassroots political
effort is going door-to-door and saying
hey stranger what do you think about
cannabis laws or whatever you're
passionate about and there's tons of
that here I mean a lot of people on a
national level to think of Colorado and
they think they've legalized medical
marijuana years and years ago they
legalized recreational marijuana the
game's over that it's done they want
know it in a very real sense yes I was
in line on January 1st with Jeff and
other people and there was a dance
people were doing on the way out of the
store that they just couldn't help I did
it no one struts and dances and shimmies
through a parking lot on their way out
of Safeway I used to see Mike and I had
Mike was for a few brief days before we
got closed down boss at the only Medical
Marijuana Center in town I sold medical
cannabis over the counter for months and
I'm well-known for that around here the
first time or bliss is just something so
in January first after I was the first
person to buy recreational cannabis at
the greener side dispensary in Pueblo
Colorado there was a camera guy there
hey man we're doing a documentary can
you tell us can you say something good
when you walk out and I was like cool
watch this and I went right back in the
door and I came back out and I threw my
arms up in the air and I yelled just
that I go my name is Rasta Jeff and I
was the first person to buy recreational
cannabis at the greener side dispensary
in Pueblo Colorado and then I screamed
that was [ __ ] amazing film stuff that
they're gonna use every couple of weeks
for the next hundred years that day it's
hilarious all right I just pulled up you
were talking reading so I was leading I
just once Colorado legalized marijuana
the fight quickly became cities and
counties looking for fun ways to ban it
again so yeah in a very real way we won
but in a very real way now we're making
the rules until after you pass forward
you know the whole world's watching
Colorado and Pueblo reports our tax
numbers
so in a very real way our tiny little
town and would you say we get a lot of
press excess traffic because we're like
the first stop we need a lot of every
kind of traffic yeah Plus on the way to
the rest of the us from every place out
there this used to be a stop on the
Santa Fe Trail getting supplies or gas
here for very true dad awesome alright
we're gonna let's do uh I'm gonna see
how long we've been into this holy crap
Mike always bringing the good news but I
just read news from the cannabis this
one's by Ricardo Baca this one's kind of
a neat article this shows to me this
shows that things are evolving and the
America is starting to make changes
that's what I got from it so it's a
positive changes says marijuana
activists are plant are already planning
the 2016 campaign to regulate and
legalize the sale for recreational pot
in Nevada home to Las Vegas one of the
world's biggest tourism destinations but
some tourists won't have to wait that
long to legally buy weed in Las Vegas
thanks to the most legal reciprocity law
in the US I nailed that word alright
well Mike just said it for me so I'm
just gonna point at Mike and he'll say
that word every time it comes up from
now on
awesome medical marijuana card holders
throughout the US will be able to
purchase pot in Nevada starting in 2015
all they'll have to do is show their
medical marijuana license show a
government ID proving they're 21 or
older and sign an affidavit and they'll
have access to that shop but no others
for their stay in Nevada does
that lead me to believe they only get
one stop when they go to Nevada that
sounds like you got a pick it and stick
it homie pick one and stay with it
but how much are you allowed to prevent
smurfing that's an odd way to do that
there you go
well this liberal medical across the
word reciprocity Act as a act as a soft
lead to recreational measures in Nevada
and will Nevada pass full-on
recreational legalization in 2016 of
course it will said Jim Lamoreaux who
handles government relations at Colorado
base pot testing facility can labs which
recently announced its future present in
Nevada's marijuana market
most people are factoring into their
models people discussed it as part of
their model you can consider that Nevada
has fewer than 7,000 medical marijuana
patients it's not a very large base but
when you factor in MMJ patients from
other states who might take advantage of
Nevada system another a hundred and ten
thousand from Colorado five hundred and
seventy thousand from California and a
hundred thousand from Washington
suddenly those numbers are looking a lot
better yeah not to mention if Missouri
goes legal this year which they're
talking about 2016 Michigan trying to do
legalization this year as well what
happened Florida like you thought it I
don't trust Florida's government to like
give them say okay here's here's a full
medical bill you can't do anything with
it nothing can come in nothing can go
out it's got to be all CBD here in
Florida because we just got such bangin
medicine like New Jersey does
you I mean you you were part of that
kind of argument yeah beginning and it I
stuck with it dude and that I'm sorry
man it and slow seven all kinds of
issues they they had CBD only
legislation before this recent medical
marijuana failure and right after the
Medical Marijuana amendment failed the
judge tossed their CBD rules so they're
back to square [ __ ] sorry kids alright
so this article says giving patients the
ability to legal legally access medical
marijuana when they're visiting a legal
medical marijuana state just makes sense
said Taylor West deputy director of the
National cannabis Industry Association a
national trade group for illegal
marijuana businesses and it makes even
more sense when you're talking about a
state that has such a huge number of out
of out-of-state visitors it's safer for
patients and good for and about Nevada
businesses when when if that would
almost be like Florida you know like if
you want medical dispensary right by
Disney World would crush from the
beginning is it's technically illegal
and you can't travel I mean in
Washington you're not good anywhere else
yeah it's good now there's some
reciprocity and that's a beautiful thing
you'll see me in Vegas name and I mean
now look at all the events you know
secret cops gonna be way bigger 2015
that's all I'm saying
now five hundred tickets max keep it
small nice and private
I agree with that but I'd be impressed
if they keep it to five hundred sure
enough Vegas he's roughly forty million
visitors annually that's a lot of people
but how many of those tourists will have
valid medical marijuana cards and how
many of those patients will take the
time to seek legal Nevada weed we're
still talking Reagan rail relatively
small numbers that Joe Hoda's chief
marketing officer at Denver based
marijuana company Eddie uh sorry I read
that way too quickly Dixie elixirs it's
as if the it's not as if the average
tourist or consumer can show up and make
a purchase the red card act won't have
hey that's what they're calling it won't
have huge a huge impact on their tourism
because it's a small number of people
many of whom were probably already going
to Vegas
it might be a convenience but if I have
a red card I can already get my medicine
in my own state have a flying with it
could be sketchy sometimes yeah you can
get it your own stay you just can't take
it with you the Vegas because you've got
to fly there or drive through Utah or
New Mexico that sounds like you're legit
so when you get there because what
happens when it becomes under pressure
it it like explodes or cool okay
everybody else can change your policies
is except for the people that transport
everybody right pretty much okay Nevada
does pass recreational marijuana
measures in 2016 the election in the
2016 election the earliest the state
will see those sales starting is late
2017 the 2018 is more likely until then
companies such as Dixie which hopes to
soon have an agreement allowing the
state the sale of its cannabis infused
edibles drinks and topicals in Nevada
will have time to leave their mark on
the Las Vegas Strip I was gonna ask why
two years but after seeing what just
happened in Washington where they're so
unprepared for recreational I would
almost expect two years to be bright
about right yeah give him time to grow
summer get the rules in place get a
couple things in stock can like cure it
and the next thing is so guys we bragged
about Adam and I bragged recently about
a couple months ago about going to see
Joe Rogan shut up about it
[Music]
Angela myself and Adam went and saw Joe
Rogan live at the Denver Comedy Works
during the taping of his new special
that aired last night
and I DVR'd it Mike came over here and
watched it with Angela and I Adam
watched it is his place with his kind
lady mm-hmm that was a funny damn comedy
special being without a lot we were
there they cut out a walk
last night at I wish I had that quality
of a video camera
the cameras were tiny the camera that
Rogan is staring into the majority of
the time I'm sitting under like a lot of
the time it's a small thing like a LED
screen display basically and that's it
it's cool it was a great comedy show to
end professional comedy works before
they do a professional comedy show like
somebody TV wise big time there were so
many crowd rules they were moving the
crowd around and putting ugly people in
the back and sexy people up front of
course we're under camera so you
couldn't even see us it was sort of
pointless I never saw a real good look
at this it was really dark the only
lights in the building were on the stage
and you couldn't even see the crowd so
all the moving around and all the rules
and the no hats and no logo [ __ ] was
just too much attention we might have
applied if he had a 20 minute bid on
like picking on people in the front row
or some [ __ ] but oh I saw was the
profile of one kid a couple of times and
that's pretty much all the crowd use and
that's where we were three seats off to
the side up on the top and that's where
nice see right next to Jeff Jeff was did
basically at the camera there was a guy
sitting next to us but his they were
still wheelchair accessible so it wasn't
sloped so he was up higher so that every
shot from across the way it basically
blocked us like completely out of there
because we were underneath his shoulders
basically all the way down to his elbow
yeah give you five minutes to talk live
on television Joe Rogan doesn't have to
catch you in the side view great show on
TV for free all right so speaking of Joe
Rogan being on a video shout out to Joe
Rogan that show is great shot it's a
comedy where explain goes big respect to
Melissa if you guys don't know Melissa
comedy works
you don't know what you're missing um
let's see what else am I gonna say we
watched a culture high tonight I invited
these dudes over I rented it from iTunes
which I've never rented anything from
iTunes it feels kind of weird to pay
$4.99 to watch something for 24 hours on
my computer I learned a lot of stuff I
tried to take some notes we came to a
really easy conclusion [ __ ] Nancy Grace
I can't believe I haven't said that yes
that's the only [ __ ] thing I wrote
down the culture hi it's worth watch
your parents down have them watch it
with you watch it as a family watch it
with your friends it's worth it give it
to someone that's maybe not open-minded
but willing to listen that's all who's
one of your favorite speakers in there I
did I forget how it's crazy he gets all
his message is true so it's it's there
who's your favorite doing the show Mike
it's a huge fan of Judge James Graham
I'm a huge fan of dr. Lester Grinspoon
and they're both heavy narrators in the
beginning Ed Burns the guy that did the
wire is dr. Lester Grinspoon life's
life-changing books on cannabis one of
the like the researchers I mean
harvard-trained works at harvard
research and cannabis for the last what
50 years
I mean just incredible incredible
speakers to have gathered for this
documentary I loved it
keep the question how many years do you
think like he worked for he's like XDI
he was a detective for a whole bunch of
years in Baltimore I believe yeah those
dudes always have some stories man like
yeah every time like it's we have more
of them they come over to our side then
they then you know like the druggies
clean up and go to the cops it's made up
fully of ex judges cops detectives DEA
agents that just doesn't do anything but
harm and it might come from an
interesting place of trying to prevent
drug use but it doesn't do that at all
and on top of not being effective at all
at its main goal it's also incredibly
harmful of the society it's great timing
that's right I'm I can agree with that
it also had clips from Joe Rogan we saw
a snoop dizzle who saw Lester Grinspoon
Brian Redman was there a lot of people
might not know who that is but I know
who he isn't shout out to Brian Redman
be roles in there they also look up to a
lot of those people actually sure that
cannabis scientifically they prove that
cannabis does not cause schizophrenia
they remind you talk a lot about that
research in the beginning I love you Dan
cannabis was outlawed in 1937 and they
actually mentioned that alcohol
poisoning causes 250,000 deaths per year
did you catch the tobacco numbers
no I've hundred thousand they compared
it to the Holocaust I mean okay you're
right a Holocaust around the planet
every year due to tobacco consumption
not just the gern or the Jewish people
but also the German soldiers that died I
don't remember how they broken down it's
like five and a half million people
around the globe die every year due to
tobacco consumption in
it's just crazy zero from cannabis the
US has a model around the country around
the world is about place that has pushed
tobacco consumption down to record
levels with education that's really all
we did is we check ID at the point of
sale and we tell every school kid
if you smoke tobacco it will lead to
these health effects and we give them
the legit and legitimate information on
tobacco and that's all we did
and they made cue catchy kind of
teenager commercials smoking ads and
stuff like the really effective stuff is
just sitting the kid down in health
class and being like this is your nice
pink lung this is the black lung videos
I want to do a couple things before we
have to wrap it up for the first time do
you think I can play it with sound and
not get in trouble should I just cut the
sound out of it we might wanna sleep for
legal reasons you might want to hit
pause I think just to I'll watch it and
I'll just keep the volume to where we
can't hear it so it doesn't go to the
recording everybody bring it up real
quick yeah go ahead and type in right
now search for grandma's smoking weed
for the first time I'll give you a
second to search for that pink and
purple the three old ladies wearing pink
and purple they got a purple bong in
front of them that's the video you're
searching for don't give any weird
parody I'm gonna hit play right now and
then I'm gonna talk about it if you guys
need a minute to catch up I'll give you
a second and then I'm gonna play on
three two one
play YouTube's loading I'm sorry I
failed another old lady take they don't
clear it they just fill it and then they
leave it all smoky too much yeah just
it's probably but we'll talk through a
lot of it grab my smokin weed for the
first time it's a very well produced
video they had a nice camera to a tease
of the sound quality so I'm curious
we had our cigarettes and our cocktails
and we were happy you want to listen to
it dude
crank it up and just enjoy it no I'll
watch it when I can one time but I don't
wanna get us in trouble cuz it's the
quotes that are beautiful when the
vaporizer gets dude is about to light
the bong for this nice-looking old lady
she pulled it closer to her face he's
showing her what's about to happen she's
shaking the lighter because it won't
work
she keeps shaking it when she tries to
the lightest and now she's tokin bro
she's pulling a toke she did not carve
it no destructed - as well they were
instructed to do everything till then oh
this one I'd say she's probably the
older of the three she just took a
pretty nice bong rip today start ripping
it here and then she goes back for
seconds the Betty White looking chick is
about to line up for a dab or for a bong
rip I really hope they had some at the
beginning was they gave them snacks and
they gave them drinks and they gave
myself taken off a [ __ ] iTunes but
I'm gonna put some of the volume in from
one minute later so here we want to
listen to this I thought tonight I want
to get myself in trouble but I'm five
minutes later so I'm just gonna let it
play then it's it's a long video so
we'll put some flips amulet now I can go
ahead and tell you basically from memory
they're starting to feel it now playing
with it with their second hand and the
other tricks like no you can't you're
not supposed to she couldn't even do
with two seconds so 15 minutes later
we'll turn it up for a second oh they
pull out a vaporizer
leave it up it kind of looks like a sex
toy and now she's token it she's
actually hitting it so I'm gonna jump in
a couple of minutes because I don't
wanna watch his old lady's blasted 35
minutes later the guy says since you're
cool I'll go ahead and tell you shows
the definition is we should be able to
play it's funny they're high you can
tell they're visibly high but nothing
goes wrong these are all ladies that
one's got like a damn sweater
it's a shawl baby but it looks like a
[ __ ] blanket wrapped around her scarf
these look like lunch ladies like this
they take all the scary consumption
there at the end we're not gonna do the
whole thing on the show because we're
running out of time I don't think you
guys would approve it's funny um what
else did I want to do on the show
your grandma send it to your grandma I
don't know about all that
yeah that'd be weird whatever shows
already sad she's on Facebook it's
creepy
it's creepy all right let's start
wrapping up to show you guys we've gone
just about an hour here I approve of the
movie a culture hi
I think the Joe Rogan show kicked ass I
think this grandma smokin weed video was
pretty awesome if you don't have some
stuff to watch on TV if you're bored
pull up your phone pull up your computer
and watch those things it'll be worth
your time my Instagram on IRA genetics
is getting close to ten thousand
followers the end of this video says no
grandma's were harmed in the making of
this video which i think is clever
that's ten thousand followers if I'm at
nine thousand four hundred and something
if I could get you guys to follow and
get me up to ten thousand that'd be
super awesome it's a tyree genetics on
instagram you guys do a lot of things
that's all I'm asking for today plugs
anything you want people to follow any
shoutouts overgrowth guv Twitter
Instagram things like that big shout out
to bender sitting at home working on the
server while I'm here having fun and
local like mic is fixed and probably
saying I was gonna say check out the
public for sensible cannabis laws
Facebook page if you're interested in
pueblo local cannabis news and check me
out on twitter nemo punk fifteen follow
him guys support if you have an
instrument I doubt I don't agree I don't
take pictures in anything but my dogs
and I feel like people have seen other
people's dogs do they poop in weird
places Oh totally I just thought I'd put
that out there if you want some genetic
seeds pay attention to nature's green
remedies calm in December I'll get them
out there as soon as I can as soon as I
get them packaged up I will get them to
nature's green remedies you get hooked
up I'm gonna start doing that part where
we close out the show if I can find the
proper paper it goes like this guys but
pay attention because there's more to
the end here
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes or stitcher go
iTunes Store or the stitcher main page
in search for agriculture find a review
section give us a five star rating five
stars dude with five stars right oh
absolutely and if and I always try to
give you a five star rating on stitcher
when I listen so nice thank you five
star rating if you give us one yeah no
really do tell us what you really think
but we are high hashtag blame Jesse
don't forget that every episode of this
podcast is available or no this podcast
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every episode is archived on ira
genetics colorado dot-com make sure you
follow us on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook just search for I grow culture
once again fall I read I read genetics
on Instagram if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like us to review send me
an email at I grow culture at
hotmail.com and I'll give you all the
information you need to sponsor or send
me a product we still need our own theme
song I want to give a shout out to coot
dog for the mystic roots he helped us
out with a lot of music but if you want
to make a theme song that says I grow a
culture hosted by Rasta Jeff or
something like that I would really
SuperDuper appreciate that we'd give you
mad credit maybe send you an IRA t-shirt
or whatever I've got laying around that
works for you I want to give a huge
shout out to Angela and her perfect
vagina thanks again for listening guys
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
Wow
all right podcast world that was a
throwback Thursday episode of the girl
from your heart podcast I hope you love
these old throwback Thursday episodes I
would appreciate it if you sent me a
tweet if you send me an email if you
contact me somehow and let me know what
you think of these long as long-ass
episodes I was hard to say are these
episodes hard for you to download am i
messin up your data plan is there a
better way for you to get these old
episodes that's what I want to know I
want to make this podcast easily
accessible for everybody so let me know
how I can make it better for you if
you've got any suggestions on how I can
make this podcast better let me know I
might take you up on your advice I may
just blow you off I'd love to hear from
you you can send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com or you
can tweet me at gfy each podcast if
you're on facebook you can find me at
the grove from your heart podcast on
facebook ladies and gentlemen a smile is
getting really long I appreciate you for
listening I hope to see you on Monday
I'll have a brand new episode out check
it out until next time take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you