[Music]
yeah yeah let's do it again check it
out we used to aim for the sky now we H
at Mars on the rise till we shine like
the fire star son I create you admiring
all by the line for my Rhymes I'm a wire
your jaw check it out lus keeps coming
out with the slamming beats makes the
whole house want to bounce like static
sheets we the track Elite World thought
a and you can't compete cuz your rap is
weak have a seat my num game is
uncontained by a data sheet I run the
game while you drag your feet come on
I'm unashamed with my love for fame cuz
my life was mundane now it's feeling
magnif first place and we moving above
fluing in love under the influence of
drugs you speak hate we could ruin your
mug oh you the boss I can squash you
like a bug
again again yeah what up ladies and
gentlemen welcome to episode number 21
of the Agro culture podcast
I'm your host Rost Jeff thanks for
joining me for another
episode man I've been smoking live resin
today and I'm a little bit dabbed out a
little more dabbed out than usual uh we
were smoking some stuff called uh bare
naked you don't know about the bare
naked yet but when you hear about it
you'll remember that you heard about it
on Agro culture podcast
first I want to give a big shout out to
Spence and the whole garden of Weeden
crew they let me hang out for a couple
hours tonight on the couch take some
dabs talk a little bit be social was fun
thanks for the dabs thanks for the live
resin thanks for the bare
naked much respect appreciate it guys uh
this episode was brought to you by
Nature's green remedies.com visit natur
green remedies.com for gag green
genetics Lata Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Aventure iy
genetics and many more trusted Brands
Nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code podcast for 15% off any
order and you always get free shipping
at Natures green remedies.com
uh that coupon code does expire the 31st
of July there will be a new coupon code
for August so get your stuff while you
can uh seems like the IR genetics
products sell out quite quickly so get
on that need to give a big shout out to
our friends at oil slick oil slick tools
to help you concentrate check at oil
slick pad.com for more information make
sure you follow oil slick on Twitter
find them under oil slick pad send them
a tweet tell them you're listening to
the igro culture podcast the song ended
and it got real quiet that was awkward
it's like when you're at a concert and
you're yelling and then all of a sudden
the song stops and all they can hear is
you
yelling you're always saying a really
stupid word at that time so I had nachos
in my butt or something like that uh
yeah uh oil slick shout out to those
guys send him a tweet tell listening to
the show uh big shout out to our friends
at tree Thugger dcom this episode is
brought to you in part by tree thug.com
live music lifestyle magazine check out
tree Thugger
docomo and
reviews and also this show is brought to
you largely by hyro indoor growing
supplies Hy gr indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 6271 Beach
Street Unit F or stop by the new pbla
location on 618 East 4th Street in PUO
Colorado check out Hy gr for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies don't forget to check out
www.hr denver.com for current store
hours and current store specials
actually I've got an extra added bonus
for you hyro has an awesome sale on
Roots organic soil you can get one toad
of soil for $550 in store pickup or $600
delivered uh this deal is available at
both locations the PUO and inverse store
please contact hyro to verify delivery
uh availability delivery availability
I'm not sure how far those guys are
willing to drive to haul you their that
tote of soil so I'm sure a lot of guys
are saying how much is a toad of soil
rosta Jeff it's a really good question
the answer is a total of soil is 54
cubic feet which is about 350 Gall uh
it's all in one bag also so instead of
buying a whole bunch of separate bags
you got one big bag here a little more
eco-friendly so if you're running three
gallon pots that's 116 3 Gall Pots if
you run 5 Gall pots that's 75 gallon
pots if you run s gallon pots like I
like to do that's 57 galon pots so
that's not a bad deal at all there uh so
go get your dirt at hyro indoor growing
supplies let me read the address to you
one more time that is 6271 Beach Street
Unit f or the Pueblo location uh that
address is in Denver the PUO location is
618 East 4th Street in Pueblo on the
east side so go check out hyro much
respect to all those sponsors they make
the show possible big shout out to you
guys for listening we've made it 21
episodes you guys that's pretty awesome
I've got a couple of things I wrote down
I wanted to talk about where did I put
the paper oh big shout out to Natural
Mystic cannabis caregivers in Colorado
Springs I was running low on
shatter uh natural Mystic cannabis
caregivers came to the rescue I got some
delicious I'm reaching for the container
right now I'm also recording this
podcast in video I don't know if I will
do anything with the video but I am
actually recording it so this is guava
Sky I'm just showing the container from
natural Mystic cannabis caregivers and
this is Mystic is what it's called The
Mystic has torab Bora in there it's a
high CBD mix and the guava sky is the
sativa that they had available uh I got
more of the sativa than I did the CBD
mix that's just my preference but uh
I'll show you the guava sky for the guys
with the camera also take a picture or
with the uh that are seeing the video
I'll take a picture and post this up
online but I'm not watching the video so
I don't know how clear that is I'm going
to stay still for a second so it can
focus so huge shout out to Natural
Mystic cannabis caregivers in Colorado
Springs what's up Joey what's up Shelly
I hope you guys listen much love that's
a great shop if you do need medical
marijuana it does require a red card to
get in there so if you do need your
medical marijuana that's the place in
Colorado Springs I would send you right
now uh they have your back uh chell's a
a uh a cancer survivor uh so she knows
what you're dealing with if you're sick
she definitely knows how to help you out
she's compassionate she's friendly uh
Joey's hard to find he's the uh he's the
boss there so he's always busy working
but Joey's a great dude he's super
friendly he'll shake your hand and spend
a minute with you if he is in the shop
so shout out to those guys I got much
love for you uh here's a little personal
note today is uh as I'm recording it's
4:20 in the morning on July 23rd uh so
it is officially the birthday of his
Imperial Majesty King highly
the first so uh if you know what that is
who that is uh you understand why I'm
giving thanks and praise many thanks and
praise many uh birthday blessings to
King hly salasi the first going to take
a little uh little half a second of
Silence because it's a podcast a moment
of silence would be ridiculous so here's
a half a second of silence for King
Cassi the
first all right we got to keep the show
moving much respect um I am sad to
inform you I'm gonna turn the music way
down for this one also I'm sad to inform
you we had an event scheduled for July
27th at the Brickyard I've been talking
about it quite a bit we're trying to get
that uh hookah bar turned into a dab bar
unfortunately it's not going to happen
the event is cancelled and that place is
not going to get to be turned into a
smoking establishment I apologize for
advertising an event that didn't happen
uh the city is against us every step of
the way they do not want us to get this
place open they do not want us to have
our event I planned on taking live
plants to the event so that we could do
a little bit of education and I could
show a male plant a female plant I had
plants in different stages of flower for
this
event but uh we can't take plants that
they they uh said they would confiscate
the plants we can't risk taking plants
and getting them taken uh I just can't
do that to myself that's medicine for my
patients I'm a caregiver and they're
going to need that medicine so I can't
do that so unfortunately the event that
I had planned that I had talked about
for July 27th at the Brickyard is
cancelled uh we couldn't come to an
agreement with the city they do not want
us to do the event uh I don't want
anybody to get in trouble I don't want
my plans to get taken so we have uh we
have backed out of the event and I do
apologize for
that uh the other day I said something
on the show I don't remember if I said
it on the show or just in uh
conversation with people but I need to
correct something that I said I'm going
to go to a website here this is actually
uh from Ed rosenthals I've just got it
on my computer it's easier to do while
we're doing a show Ed r THS marijuana
growers handbook I'm trying to show it
to the camera I'm not watching the video
I should put the video up on the screen
so I can see the video feed uh here we
go this is the book that uh I'm coming
from so I said something about Red
Spectrum right and I may have gotten it
backwards for what I told you guys so
this is from the book I just showed you
all credit for what I'm saying right now
goes to Ed Rosenthal Ed don't get mad at
me for saying this on the show uh you'd
want people to know this it's called the
critical light period and let me give
you a quick explanation of what the
critical light period is is in uh my
opinion and like a little quick cuz you
need to know that to get to where we are
the critical light period is the amount
of dark time that uh specific cannabis
strain will take to flour so let me
elaborate with Ed's article here got to
take a big breath because I've been
taking
dabs all
right this 12to formula has been
accepted without question by Growers all
over the world
probably probably one of the reasons for
this was my discussion of the technique
in some of my early books the 1212
regimen was selected because my
co-author and I reasoned that no matter
what critical period of variety might
have given 12 hours of Darkness it would
flower however most marijuana varieties
need fewer than 12 hours of Darkness to
flower now what I was talking about with
somebody was they were saying that their
plants are starting to flower and it's
not 12 hours of Darkness outside uh yes
that's because of the sunset and the
sunrise have specific color spectrums
that triggering hormones in your plants
is what I was telling them and I was
calling all of this info from memory so
I think I got it backwards to tell you
the truth so uh if I said that on a
podcast or if I said that to you in
person I need to correct that here's
what Ed Rosenthal has written a little
bit more about it uh if marijuana plants
grown Outdoors required a 12-hour dark
period to flower they would not be
induced to start flowering until
September 21st the first day of autumn
when day and night are equal length they
would ripen 6 to 8 weeks later and in
real life most modern varieties ripen
between early September and late October
budding was triggered 68 weeks earlier
for instance an 8-week variety that
requires 55 days from forcing to
maturity which would normally ripen
October 1st would start flowering August
1st at that day in San Francisco Sunrise
occurs at 5:14 and sunset at 9:18 which
is 7:18 a total of 14 hours and 4
minutes Dawn and dusk add another 15
minutes of red light plants use the
absence of this spectrum to measure the
dark period the total lit period came to
about 14 hours and 20 minutes leaving 9
hours and 40 minutes of Darkness the
critical period for this plant was 9
hours and 40 minutes if it were given
just 10 hours of dark period daily
indoors rather than 12 it would still
flower gardeners growing indoors who
discover the critical time need to
induce flowering uh the critical time
needed to induce flowering can use this
information to get more efficient use of
their indoor Garden currently plants
grown under a 122 cycle spend half their
time in the dark if these plants have a
critical flowering time of for instance
10 hours of Darkness daily they can Prov
be provided 14 rather than 12 hours of
light each day so that they can receive
almost 177% more energy which they use
to produce sugars used for more and
faster
growth so does that make any sense you
guys it's the it's a
it's called the critical period for the
specific strain most of your uh your
like cush strains your indicia stuff
that's going to have a critical period
apparently closer to uh that's going to
have like your 12-hour stuff your more
equatorial stuff you may be able to cut
that down just a little bit actually I
heard DJ Short say that he runs most of
his plants on a uh it's 13 off 11 on and
he said that that shows a little bit
more phenotypical expression is what
that does uh which means that if you're
growing from seed and you're trying to
find that keeper you'll get to see
larger variances in your seed stock if
you've got a little F1 hybrid there I
had another article I got to click back
a couple of steps
here um maybe I've lost it huh I learned
a whole lot of stuff about M here it is
sorry I hate to stumble do that but
looking for stuff on the internet while
I'm talking this guy broke something
down there are things
uh cannabis plants where's this coming
from Let me give credit this is from
marijuana growers hq.com light cycles
and flowering
cannabis uh says cannabis plants are
referred to as long night or short day
plants because they require a long
period of Darkness to trigger the
hormone that tell the plant to switch
from vegetative growth to flowering
these light receptors are color pigments
in the leaves called phytochrome red and
phytochrome far red and they're going to
start abbreviating that so I need to try
to remember which is which these
pigments get their names from the types
of light they absorb phytochrome red
absorbs red light between 600 and 760 it
doesn't give me a definition of what
those are and uh phytochrome far red
absorbs far light between 760 and 800 NM
uh I don't remember what NM is and
that's I should sorry I went blank on
that one just now when they wrote it on
the screen uh these two pigments
chemically react to the light and
Trigger the plant to flower or not uh
this is where it gets a little confusing
and cannabis plants the normal presence
of phytochrome far red switches off the
flowering signal the level of
phytochrome far red is what you can
manipulate to adjust the photo period
phytochrome far red is quickly produced
when plants are exposed to light that
contains far red
wavelengths when there is light the
phytochrome far red and phytochrome red
maintain a balance when the Sun goes
down or the lights go out the darkness
gradually switches the phytochrome far
red to phytochrome Red because of this
the phytochrome red levels gradually
increase and the far red gradually
decreases during the dark period the
presence of red is neutral is a neutral
condition to the plants and essentially
tells them nothing when the light
returns or if a small amount of far red
light interrupts a dark period the red
immediately switches back to far red if
the plant is without light long enough
the far red will decrease past a Tipping
Point this decreased level of
phytochrome far red signals the plants
that fall is approaching and the plants
begin
flowering in short the presence of
phytochrome far red due to long hours of
light and short hours of Darkness keep
the plants in the vegetative phase if
the plant experiences enough hours of
Darkness most of the phytochrome far red
turns to phytochrome red and the low
level of far red signals the plant
hormones to begin flowering that's a
really technical version of what I tried
to say the last time I gave this uh
little rant and I think I got it
completely backwards to tell you the
honest truth so that goes to show you
right there that sometimes you got to do
your research you got to remind yourself
even if you think you know what you're
doing you might [ __ ] up and say
something wrong on a podcast and try to
embarrass yourself but you know what I
don't feel embarrassed I'm glad that I
got to learn with you guys we're going
to go find out what that one little
abbreviation that they wrote there I've
never seen it written like that before
I'm going to find out what that means so
I can share that with you where was
it right there going to Google that and
find out what that
means Googling it right now
NM
light measurement definition pops up as
soon as I start typing that visible
light is usually defined as having a
wavelength okay so that's that is
nanometers what I thought it was they
just wrote it uh small n capital M and I
haven't seen it like that so that's
nanometers as well what I thought it was
there in that that article all right
doing pretty good on that one until
Safari just decided to freeze up there
we go cool all right so uh man this is
going to be a short episode I really
just wanted to come on and uh talk about
having to uh cancel the committee for
the responsible regulation of cannabis
uh party that we were going to have at
the Brickyard I want to say that once
again in case you guys are skimming
through this episode the party the
seminar the educational seminar we
planned to host it has been canceled uh
I was going to take some live plants and
show you guys those we had people that
were going to talk about all kinds of
cool stuff we had a miniature job fair
planned
out the uh city of pelo does not want
that to happen so I apologize it's
beyond our control the police department
have threatened us and scared us and we
don't want police interaction so uh
we're going to back out we're going to
bow down and just uh not do that sorry
it's the best we can do right now for
what we've
got uh all right enough begging for uh
your forgiveness I do apologize if you
were planning to come out uh message me
and we'll find something else to do
how's that so if you're listening on
Twitter or Facebook or whatever message
me and we will uh we'll hang out since I
had that night booked because I thought
I'd be doing stuff anyway so uh yeah
let's wrap up this episode it was kind
of a quick episode I want to give
another uh I want to mention that coupon
or that ad that hyro peblo and hyro
Denver are both doing you can get
yourself a gigantic bag of Roots organic
soil for 550 bucks or $600
uh honestly dude 257 gallon pots or 57
gallon pots worth of soil that's two
runs in a four light room in my opinion
you know so if that tells you anything
with what you could do with that amount
of soil that is awesome big shout out to
all of our sponsors I want to give a
shout out to the Gammy Gatsby the Grammy
Gatsby thanks for hooking us up good
folks over there check out the gamy
gatsby. comom what's up hunt much love
much respect so let's do that end of the
show wrapup thing oh I'm to try to get
Jesse back I was talking to Jesse he's
getting married and he actually texted
me when am I going to be back on the
show so I promise he's coming back soon
we'll get him back on the show do that
outdoor grow lesson for
you um big thanks to King Hy Cassi the
first we used to do that give thanks
portion but I've been cramming so much
stuff into one episode that I haven't
done it so officially give thanks to
King Cassi the first is my give thanks
on this episode I'm not going to go on
about that if you know you know that's
all there is to that one uh check us out
on Instagram
uh at iy genetics is where I post a lot
of good photography there that's at iy
genetics the show has an Instagram it's
at Agro culture of course we do a lot of
Twitter stuff at AGR culture there's a
Facebook you can email me ulture
hotmail.com what I really like is iTunes
comments and iTunes uh fstar ratings so
here's what I where I read the part I
typed now that the show's over please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for igro culture find the review section
give us a festar rating after that type
in a comment and let me know what you
think of the show and I'll read your
comments on the show uh don't forget the
show is available on iTunes Stitcher
swell. and also IR genetics.com every
episode is archived on IR gentics
color.com episodes 1 through 21 uh once
again shout out to my ninja Spence shout
out to the whole garden of Weeden family
uh shout out to Adam Gaskins uh I made
him [ __ ] run around with me all day
we went to Colorado Springs had some
lunch he laughed at me for eating hippie
food dude it was a fun day shout out to
Adam's wife for letting me borrow Adam
all day thanks a lot I appreciate that
that was cool uh we had fun today um
what else what else I guess uh thanks
for listening take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]