yo in a podcast world that you play
Rasta Jeff coming to you with another
throwback Thursday episode this time I'm
doing episodes 40 to 43 and 44 of what
used to be known as the iGrow culture
podcast currently known as The Grove
from your heart podcast before we get
into this block of old episodes let me
make a couple of updates and disclaimers
all of the social media has changed the
new email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com on twitter you can
find us under @gf wih podcast and on
facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast also any
advertisements giveaways our contests
that are mentioned in these old episodes
those all have expired and past so don't
get too excited and also let me say one
more thing a lot of my methods
techniques and ideas have changed in the
past three years and 210 episodes if I
say something in these old episodes that
I contradict in a current episode go
with the most current episode I've
learned a lot in 200 episodes and I hope
you have also so with no further ado
ladies and gentlemen here's episodes 42
43 and 44 of what used to be known as
the agriculture podcast now known as the
grow from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 42 of the iGrow
culture podcast they call me your ass
too Jeff dude joining me at the table
tonight we have a brand new guest who's
never been on the show what's up Tony
how you doing I'm good how are you I am
great bro I'm gonna turn on the music a
little bit we'll talk Tony is the dude
that built my website he built the IRA
genetics website Tony is responsible for
getting the feed up that hosts the iGrow
culture podcast so dude big huge
shout-out you don't get the credit you
deserve thanks a lot excuse me while I
cough out along as usual not usual as
often I guess our good buddy Jesse is
back how you doing bro pretty good oh
yeah oh yeah Tony's got an Italian
family so I could imagine on the 2jz
yeah no headphones for you sometimes
this thing cuts out bro I apologize it's
this headphone jack you gonna come back
yeah just give me that same where the
[ __ ] my headphone signal and we'll
correct it yeah we'll keep going back
cool cool
how was your Thanksgiving but I almost
skipped you it's pretty good good yeah
yeah I have the privilege to go into for
Thanksgiving dinners yeah I had two
Thanksgiving dinners incidentally Lisa
she made a huge Thanksgiving dinner for
the whole family that's really super
cool of you I appreciate it was tasty
I'm a vegetarian so she was really nice
and made some things differently than
she would have she didn't post beef
broth and bacon and some [ __ ] you know
so I had a lot of options to eat Angela
Angela doesn't have any family here in
Colorado so I totally invited her to
come eat dinner with my family and she
had a great time yes she was totally
cool my family loved her so thanks for
coming I really appreciate that Angela I
hope all the listeners had a good
Thanksgiving or if you're not into that
and I hope you had a great Thursday some
people hate Thanksgiving I don't I'm
impartial and I go eat with the family
to be to be social like we should I
think it's one of the better holidays
there's a you know it's just
of course one of the better holidays
about 420 bro oh yeah that's like
Christmas for the potheads
yeah all right so you have any let's get
to some edge real quick so we can get
right down to business on this episode I
do plan on doing a little lesson on
nutrients and stuff and I also have a
good question for my buddy Tony Tony is
a he's an organic chemistry student how
far are you from your degree bro okay I
don't go to college so what does that
mean for humans semester a semester cool
Tony's a new father so he's distracted
from school Congrats on that hasn't been
around as much so I'm sure he's not at
school as much turn down that music
trying to yell over it feels way better
so we'll have Tony talk about a couple
things here in a minute before we can
get that far this podcast is brought to
you by nature's drain remedies dot-com
visit nature's green remedies calm
4-gauge green genetics will apply to
labs sin city rare dankness mile high
can adventure the callee connection MTG
ira genetics and many more trusted
brands you guys will be glad to hear
this nature's green remedies is running
a special for the loyal podcast
listeners type in coupon code frosty for
15% off any order and free priority
shipping at nature's green remedies
dot-com the coupon code is good for any
brand in stock but it does expire at the
end of this month so take advantage of
the coupon code before the 31st
once again the coupon code is frosty
ironically I made up that coupon code
and I texted Yankee from nature's green
remedies I said the new code will be
frosty and he said that's funny brother
that's my dog's name I was just thinking
it's winter and everything's frosty it's
cold our blood should be frosty so that
worked out pretty well
big thanks and much respect to nature's
green remedies and Yankee he's out with
his kids tonight at a slipknot concert
hope you guys had a whole [ __ ] I blow
stuff that's going around everyone's got
a cold around here also this podcast is
brought to you by highly educated
titanium if you're using high quality
concentrates you deserve a high quality
titanium nail made in America don't
trust a cheap Chinese nail or an
American knockoff made of cheap Chinese
metals trust the industry leader trust
highly-educated titanium task is
actually up for all kinds of awards
again for product towards for his stuff
so you know he's killing it he's gonna
win big shout out to task much respect
to what you do those new carb cap
silicon's we I can't wait to get my
hands on a couple if you're listening I
like the ones with stars I've got the
cost to the show you don't have to sit
there all day that's what I think big
love to tree sucker calm this episode is
brought to you in part by our good
friends at tree hugger comm live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
calm for concert and festival news and
reviews look out at the cookout with
tree hugger dot-com big loved all the
sponsors dude we really appreciate you
guys helping us out also a big shout out
to coot dog and Katherine of the mystic
roots band they let me play all of their
music on the podcast how cool is that
can't go much cooler than that I want to
give a big shout out to Spence and Maddy
they came over the other night and help
me do a chore I wish you guys great luck
with the secret cup that you're headed
to I hope you guys bring home a trophy
and a whole bunch of prizes and a new
rig I want to dive out of your new rig
on the podcast next week that'll be
super awesome
and get the respect that you totally
deserve and are worthy of do you hear
that I didn't say that my homie Jesse I
butter him up a lot but uh Jesse just
said you guys deserve respect also a big
shout outs alas I don't know if you
listen to the show but I met a dude
named last recently we finally met in
person we've been online buddies we got
to hang out cool ass dude shoutout also
a shout out for a minute mister Omni Oh
what's up bro
you're finally caught up on episodes
it's like we're hanging out in his
kitchen he was you left a tweet that
says I'm listening while I'm making beef
booyah are hanging out in my kitchen so
did we record this show about ten feet
from my kitchen so that could have been
a reality almost it's kind of you
they're don't cook first no yeah yeah
come cook for us anybody can come cook
for us I'm a strict vegetarian Jessie
will eat almost anything
Tony chef all right I've got a couple
topics written down one of them this
just came up I was kind of rude to
somebody the other day I realized that
they were selling their plants their
crop got powdery mildew and instead of
salvaging it they decided to cut the
drop down and make live resin out of it
and I would not have known about it
unless somebody else told me that they
were doing that and so I called him out
on it and I said you are the difference
between being a caregiver and a cash
crop er you were the person that's gonna
make somebody sick because we shouldn't
be giving tainted medicine to people who
already have a compromised immune system
other people in the room treated me like
I was kind of going overboard but I felt
it was kind of my responsibility to call
this dude out and let him know that he's
really doing it wrong and he's making us
all look bad you know he's not helping
the movement at all and that's not what
I'm working towards so I wanted have a
little bit of backup when I approached
this dude saying this is why so that's
why I brought Tony on the show like I
was saying earlier Tony's an organic
chemistry student and he knows a lot
about this so I guess the simple
question I want to ask once again excuse
my dad's throat if we take these powdery
mildew buds and we blast them with
butane are we gonna get powdery mildew
or what is happening can you tell me a
little about that well you're not gonna
get the powdery mildew itself but you'll
get the mycotoxins or any sort of toxins
that they create which powdery mildew is
fairly toxic to humans now believe it or
not you actually probably be better off
smoking the buds yourself not
distributing them but you'd be less
toxic than blasting it and concentrating
it that's why the column concentrates
because we're concentrating everything
that's in the plant matter into a an oil
that
is far far far more concentrated than
plant matter itself I hadn't even
thought about that route you're making
powdery mildew dabs just like you are
ash yeah
you're taking it mycotoxins and
concentrating it okay when you say
fairly toxic could you put some kind of
comparison on that well it's definitely
not like black mold or anything like
that but um I'm sure you guys remember
the swag days Oh cheap brick weed oh
yeah that stuff had powdery mildew in it
very often and even smoking small
quantities of that you'd end up with
chest congestion bronchitis usually sore
throat for a week and a half so you
could imagine what happens if you
concentrate it 10 to 15 times the dosage
and then you take a big fat dab like I
like to do oh yeah you just probably got
a good percentage of mycotoxins in your
body yeah and the trippy thing about
that is it's not gonna show up
immediately immediately it's probably
gonna show up in a month or two it's a
really weird effects you're probably
gonna go a little nuts from it a little
bit of psychosis in my mind behavior
change yeah but there annoy you that's
if we smoke a lot right that's not like
someone or two dads and p.m. dabs it's
consistent small doses okay
so if you're smoking it use them once a
day for a week or two it's gonna do some
weird stuff to you all right definitely
don't want to do that makes you think
guys wonder why your dads are coming
from this is something that caught my
mind he said it's almost it would be
better if you smoke the buds than it
would be to smoke the hash and I also
like that you said smoke the damn buds
yourself don't give them out to anybody
that's what you should do if you drew
powdery mildew buds and you have to do
something
smoke it yourself that way you know
reflux you so well you're not getting
somebody else sick if you're gonna do it
do it don't give it to someone else to
smoke
alright so mycotoxins you said a little
bit of psychosis do you think a little
bit of headache nausea diarrhea vomiting
stuff that would be described yeah first
mistaken as other things definitely
usually flu-like or cold symptoms and
then as it gets later you'll definitely
get like typical mould poisoning exceeds
and
I'm very very very very bad things will
happen to you a kidney and liver
toxicity from mycotoxins right oh yeah
those those wreak havoc on you and
powdery mildew is its of that type of
organism that's gonna produce those and
it's they don't worry about it for food
crops very often because it's only leafy
parts that get affected but okay most
fruits like tomatoes and stuff won't
show the little patches on them so like
cucumbers are squash that always get
infected the the fruit itself is
probably said um yeah to consume some
turps bro yeah and even then that's not
very strong quantities cuz you have to
have a large amount of leafy matter
infected with the the white patches
that's the fruiting body and then it's
it's a toxin it's systemic that goes
throughout the plant so yeah you'll end
up with it in your cucumbers or squash
or whatever but not much however were
we're smoking a leafy leafy flowers
which accumulate that stuff with
freakishly high concentrations itself so
it's not the same as a food a food issue
because it's it's technically considered
non-toxic for food crops even though
they don't let it ever happen but you
definitely don't want to be smoking that
stuff we've had like you said the leafy
parts of plants but we've never actually
like a gangster rapper what was that
punk rocker okay I've always you know
since powdery mildew Canada came around
last few five six years seems like I've
wondered about those late season crops
that always get affected was that
yeah yeah I've tended to throw a lot of
that stuff in the compost pile that's
probably what you should do well I don't
know is that powdery mildew gonna affect
his compost
yeah you don't want to actually put that
in compost either they say oh yeah it's
it's not a good one to have mycotoxin I
figured you got hot enough and doesn't
kill the spores okay and you don't
actually have to worry about inhaling
the spores it's that literally the
toxins that you're burning are doing
havoc on your uh the mucous membranes at
first and then it's gonna be a little
weird I've been I've seen some big
commercial rooms that I felt like the
the spores actually burn my nose this
dude told me that using a 1 micron
screen would prevent any of the
mycotoxins or spores getting into the
hash that's completely [ __ ] cuz he's
were basically juicing the mycotoxins
right through that screen there in
solution so you can't filter them out as
if they were solid particles just like
that THC is correct correct yeah it's
totally yeah same anything is salt and
water unless you actually have a filter
that's not even that's not even a filter
anymore they call a semi permeable
membrane that's what osmosis uses okay
that's that's yeah that's not even
filter anymore you can't filter a
dissolve solid out of liquid I like the
Tony knows a lot of [ __ ] yeah sorry it's
warm in here today man those tabs got to
me
everyone's a little slow I can tell on
the show all right so basically powdery
mildew is [ __ ] terrible you guys if
you've got powdery mildew on your buds
don't give that to somebody else smoke
that yourself if you're gonna do
anything with it
don't blast it please don't blast it if
you're a medical marijuana provider and
you are giving powdery mildew bud to
sick people you're the devil you were an
Tide the movement you're doing
everything wrong you're making sick
people sicker you're causing more
problems and you're helping your the
difference between the Cache cropper and
a caregiver don't be a cash proper be a
caregiver I'm done with that I'll stop
also Ryan if you listen to the podcast I
kind of went off on you kind of hard
about this the other day I apologize I
tried to be a leader of the movement and
a lot of people will accept that and I
want to speak out about it and make sure
that you know how passionately wrong I
feel that it is might have been rude I
apologize bro we're still friends
we'll still dad all right so I promised
that we would talk about nutrients you
guys all feel good about the powdery
mildew topic oh yeah thanks for your
expertise Tony Tony will be good at this
nutrient part to Tony's I'm not gonna
call him a pro level grower he's got a
couple few crops under his belt he he's
got that chemistry background so it
really helps him out but it also kind of
kills him all right guys we had to take
a quick break but we are back Jesse had
to dip out he uh I wish I had a better
story for you he took a DAB and turned
green so we had to cut out and get Jesse
some water and get him to the couch
right now jesse is uh chilling on the
couch he'll be all right you may come
back to the show but I doubt it he said
go on without him so we're gonna do that
insert your make fun of Jesse comments
right here he is a professional but
sometimes a dad will get you so he's
chilling um let's do him some love by
this way this podcast is brought to you
by our good friends at hydro indoor
growing supplies hi girll indoor growing
supplies has two locations two sort of
Colorado visit the Denver store on 62 71
beach street or check out the beautiful
Pueblo location on 618 East 4th Street
in Pueblo Colorado check out hi girl for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies hydro
is running a special for the podcast
listeners when you check out at hydro
tell them you listen to the hydro
culture podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase Tony you can do that too tell
them I listen to the hydro culture
podcast and they'll give you a
commercial pricing bro sweet that is
pretty sweet
I got a $25 bag of dirt for seven
18 bucks the other day so imagine if I
was buying something big
also huge shout-outs how I grow into our
growing supplies for hooking me up with
a brand new nano luxe light to test big
shout out to Nana na Nana Lux lighting
I can't run it till January because my
rooms are full but I really look forward
to running that light it's one of the
dual ended light bulbs I'm sure it's
gonna put out some lumens it's gonna
make my room bright it's gonna make my
plants happy Jessie was giving him
praise earlier he said he set up one
light with a room that had an uneven
canopy because a lot of times your
middle plants will grow better that's
where all the lighting is he said they
evened out within a week or two so must
be doing something right all right I
said we're gonna talk about doing
nutrients and was also mentioning that
Tony is a chemistry and organic
chemistry major he's a physics nerd he's
a computer nerd but this dude knows a
lot of stuff I think that his knowledge
of science really helps him when he
grows but I also think it almost kills
him when he grows yeah
plants are predictable but plants aren't
science they're nature yeah Tony he's
like I fed them potassium why aren't
they potassium II come on do it and I'm
like you got to go to bed you got to
wait like three days and you got to come
back and check and then maybe you'll see
what you did he's like I want it now he
thinks he should mix it up and see
explosions for the way plants work
sometimes it does but it's funny
watching you be baffled I know how much
you know about science and organics and
to see you look at me like dude how come
and it's just the smallest thing that
you overlooked it's it's great but
sometimes it does sometimes it totally
shoots you in the foot because you don't
believe that the plants will do what I
think they should do on their own yeah
you want everything to be the Incredible
Hulk
all right so we're gonna talk a little
bit about nutrients I was hoping Jessie
would be here because he really has a
lot of cool [ __ ] to contribute but I
will cover I will try to uncle like my
voice really deep I'll turn up the lows
on the microphone maybe I'll turn up my
voice real deep and I'll do Jesse's
parts most of what we're gonna cover
today will be based on bottled nutrients
I think it's a lot easier for a new home
grower to learn what's a good line of
bottled newts next week I'm gonna have a
guy named Sean over you know it may be
two weeks until I have Sean over we got
to see what happens with the secret cup
no I should Sean will be here next week
maybe Spence will be here
week after with the secret Cup victory
that's what I'm hoping for Sean's gonna
teach us about organics and sustainable
horticulture Sean doesn't use to the
best of my knowledge Sean doesn't use
any Hydra store products but for today's
lesson we're gonna focus on basics
bottled nutrients are usually reliable
and consistent our good friend Adam who
he specifically asked me what he needs
to be feeding his plants and he also
asked what the numbers on the front of
the bottles mean so I think the numbers
on the front of the bottle is a good
question and it's a super good spot to
start so we'll talk about that there are
three numbers if you go to the hydro
shop and you pick up almost any
fertilizer bottle there are three
numbers on the front the first number
represents nitrogen the second number
represents phosphorus and the third
number represents potassium that's NPK
those are known as macronutrients so a
bottle of basic grow nutrients like if
you grabbed botanic here botanic air
pure blend Pro or maybe some my advanced
nutrients jungle juice grow the numbers
on they're gonna be like three to five
or two one six or something like that
each brands gonna be different so if it
says two three three to five that's what
we're gonna work with house three to
five it means there's three percent
nitrogen two percent phosphorus and five
percent potassium in that nutrient in
that bottle so the numbers on those
bottles tell us the NPK values of what
the NPK values are of the fertilizers
we're buying but it's up to us to figure
out which bottles to use and when to use
them and how much to use most of the
nutrient companies make a really cool
nutrient calculator that you get the
hydro shop a lot of times it's in a
little insert thing like a coupon right
next to the brand get those those are
always super helpful a lot of times Tony
will be like how much of this nutrient
do I use it since I'm kind of a nerd
I've happened to have a bunch of those
little inserts laying around and I'll
just pull it out and be like it says
this yeah but I definitely recommend
reducing the recommended dosage to about
half of what they say you use sometimes
two-thirds
you can tell we'll talk more about that
I wrote that bark down
so most of the companies make a chart or
also online you can go online to botanic
Ericom or advance nutrients calm I know
they have super great feeding schedule
calculators use a pre developed recipe
from there they'll tell you exactly what
to use every week I suggest you reduce
the dosage like I've seen about half
those companies they want to sell you
more they really want you to buy more
[ __ ] so they tell you to lose a little
bit extra like five or ten milliliters
every week adds up to them and to you
but you don't notice it your plants
won't notice it so they kind of over
feed your plants on purpose so reduce
what they say if you see signs of a
deficiency you can't increase your
fertilizer on the next feed but you
can't if you over tracked it if you over
feed you can't correct that you've got
burnt leaves and angry roots and your
plants look all [ __ ] fried out I
think I've seen a couple of your plants
do that one time oh yeah yeah Tony's not
afraid to mess with some plants Tony is
all about getting in there and torturing
the [ __ ] out of his crop and so usually
pH burns
I was gonna talk a lot about pH burns if
we have time I'm gonna try to go about
45 to an hour here but if we have time
for pH we'll get into it something I
recommend and this is this is part of
what I think Tony shoots himself in the
foot with I recommend that if you're
gonna use a brand of bottled nutrients
you stick with the brand until you
become experienced and you can identify
deficiencies and problems which means a
few things first if you use botanic air
pure blend Pro is a base I totally
recommend using whatever botanic air
pure blend Pro additives you can afford
to add but don't mix enough from other
brands I know that sounds ridiculous
like brand loyalty or a sales pitch but
I think it's rational with any brand and
I'll explain why I don't mix brands
because of Antonio like this chelation
buffers and bonding agents versus
organics a lot of products have
chemicals that make the products last
longer some have chemicals that prevent
certain compounds from bonding inside
the bottle and ruining the solution and
many of those chemicals will ruin all of
the beneficial compounds in an organic
solution Tony may correct me on this I
feel like if I poured some synthetic
nutrient like if I got almost anything
from advanced nutrients if I poured big
bud and do a batch of organic compost
tea I think the Big Bud would kill most
of the bio activity in my compost
is that correct I think Big Bud
especially like overdrive definitely
would wreak havoc okay how about my
mykos is there just gonna destroy my
micro life destroy your mykos and
actually is probably gonna bring things
out of solution like calcium compounds
and those once they're unavailable to
the plant they actually create other
deficiencies it's all about balance
apparently all right you just over
you definitely enforced what I was
trying to say I sound like I know what
I'm talking about now
all right so unless you unless you're
sure the product gets along with other
products you shouldn't be adding two
things from different brands cuz you
could cause problems you could have
everything going for the first six weeks
and then you go and add in some bud
booster that doesn't match up with your
schedule
and it could totally just ruin all the
work you've done for the past
vej time plus six weeks of flower so
another reason I stick with one brand is
because as you learn you need something
to be consistent as many things as you
can need to be consistent it's hard to
adapt to changes and identify problems
with too many variables I feel like if
we minimize the variables we can dial in
our crops to perfection if you're not
truly happy with your nutrients you can
for sure switch them but I recommend
trying the same brand while you learn I
know I keep talking about it but I
personally I like botanic air I've used
advanced nutrients I felt like with
advanced I got huge buds and everything
finished really quickly but I also feel
like everything looked and smelled and
tasted the same I don't think there was
much variation if I ran OG Kush Sour
Diesel strawberry haze they all kind of
have the same advanced nutrients they
all smelled like Nirvana oh yeah and
advanced kind of like junk food it's the
wrong kind of nitrogen but they're not
as healthy as they should be okay I
didn't ever think of that like all I
could tell is that they were taken off
and for what I paid I could tell I was
getting my money's worth I was getting
that extra that they advertised but I
didn't like the flavor and when you're
growing crops for yourself I I want the
flavor I want the flavor I want I'd grew
with psycho I did a couple rounds with
psycho that actually gave me a free box
set and I ran it side by side next to
botanic air you know I
a five-by-five Hut next to a
five-by-five Hut everything is the same
it's in the same room and I did psycho
on one side botanic hair on the other
the psycho side everything turned really
really purple and it was sexy it was
really photogenic bud
once again I didn't like the flavor yeah
it didn't burn as well and I had a funky
flavor
I used sole synthetics from Aurora
excuse me from Aurora innovations and it
has a lot of molasses II type stuff a
lot of humic stuff and that made for
tasty tasty buds but it didn't give me
enough harvest and it didn't get real
resonate it tasted super good but I
didn't get the harvest I wanted Humboldt
nutrients that stuff worked well but
there's a lot of PG RS and things I'm
trying to get away from in there just
like advanced nutrients I don't want to
use a lot of PD yards and things like
that
Humboldt did well but again I prefer
botanic air for the flavor that's what I
like the best yeah now it's turn now
it's getting to be all about the teas
the guy that's coming up next week is
all about making super awesome teas so
for my person he'll always probably go
back to the botanic air pure blend pro
with all the additives recommended I
also use SEAPLEX and from the organic
hair lineup and I'll add some kind of
molasses and yucca extract and maybe
some dehydrated coconut water to my
feeding toward the middle of bloom but
that's our secret so don't ever say that
on a podcast where people could hear you
it's actually good for beginner growers
pile on your error tolerance for
temperatures and a bunch of things yeah
it's very good for you it's kind of like
aloe vera on a sunburn except inside I
know that sounds weird but it definitely
works to moisten things up and keep
things safe a good source of yucca
extract if you don't want to just go
find yucca extract and figure out how to
use that
Humboldt honey is actually packed with
yucca extract and it's a great product
you need something with molasses and
sugars in it anyway laid in bloom so
that's what I would recommend if anybody
from botanic air is listening you can
send me an email and I'll get you my
shipping address and sponsorship info I
region etics on instagram check out my
feed ya Botanica I buy a lot of your
stuff guys talk to me hello I'm another
reason I would stick to one brand is
because doubling up on nutrient brands
you could actually double up on
something you don't want you could have
overlapped there could be too much
magnesium in this one or two
I don't know molybdenum in this one and
you don't realize it because they don't
list all that small stuff on every
bottle so if you use something from the
tannic air or something firm advanced
nutrients you may possibly be overdosing
your plant with something and so botanic
air is not gonna botanic air is not
gonna make a nutrient a with nutrient B
that would overlap they would and they
kind of would they wouldn't do that they
know that that's in there sorry guys my
throats all clogged up from taking those
dabs that killed Jesse no I should say
that most of the nutrient companies make
their own my co products those you can
absolutely for enzymes I always
recommend the hydros I'm and for
Michael's lately all the ogt products
are freaking awesome and I also like
great white shark myself I put those in
almost every plant if you want to go the
advance nutrients route and you want to
spend a lot of money that piranhas and
tarantula and the liquid bottles it's a
hundred and eighty three dollars and
fifty cents per bottle
but like ten or twenty bills will give
you explosive roots put that [ __ ] in
your cloner if you've got an easy cloner
your roots will push the lid off the
cloner your plants will get up and walk
away yeah so once you guys get
comfortable and have a good
understanding of your feeding routine
you can add whatever you feel like you
need just read the bottles adjust your
PPM's accordingly and pay attention to
what you're feeding the plants like if
you're just read the labels like read
them go to the website find out what's
in those products they should be readily
available if a company doesn't want to
tell you what's in their stuff I don't
want to use it as kind of how I feel
anyway yeah I wrote down a side note
talking about PPM's
friend of mine was having problems with
this crop his leaves were curling up
looking like goofy fingers I thought it
was a light leak during the dark cycle
he thought it was the genetics
everybody was real confused sorry I just
burp right into the microphone
everybody was real confused but the room
was correct he had good genetics and
after a few days we realized the problem
his magnetic ballasts were causing
interference with the ppm and pH meter
and everything was way off so he's
thinking he's balancing out the pH
perfectly you know six five seven and
he's actually making it
eleven or lower he's probably going down
is probably like four cuz that low is
probably what made everything curls
getting it real low so what I what I was
gonna say is uh try to get away from
your magnetic ballasts so that when you
take readings your magnetic ballasts
aren't making everything jump up and
down and also take good care of your ppm
and pH meters people overlook those and
they're super important
Jesse recommended making the cords as
short as possible in your grow rooms
yeah and that would definitely help with
stuff like having your ppm meter
fluctuates so heavily it'll take a
couple weeks but his plants will be back
on track he's just a couple of weeks
behind they'll look good alright so
we're talking about nutrients that was a
sight note I wanted to make sure to get
out our main goal here with nutrients is
to have the correct amount of nutrients
at the right time to keep the plants at
peak performance without ever over
feeding them and causing nutrient burn
or lockouts and also I wrote down don't
forget to pay attention to your pH and
also I said when do you see problems it
look like deficiencies they are often
from a pH issue that was overlooked if
you're gonna push your plants to perform
you need to have the proper pH I think
six point five to seven is ideal for
most cannabis drains you're gonna have
to adjust to your room your environment
and your strain the cocoa fiber people
they have a different range and then
regular like deep water culture hydro
people I think they want it down in the
five fires yeah that sounds about right
most of what I talk about is soil sorry
guys I'm a soil soil this kind of guy
most everything I do is in soilless mix
indoors under thousand watt lights so
you'll have to adjust like I'm
everything is about adapting all right
good call right now for reminding those
people or me so drink during the veg
phase your plants are gonna want high
levels of nitrogen as the planets
progress into the flowering stage
they're gonna require much less nitrogen
and they're gonna want more phosphorus
and potassium so we're gonna kind of
shift into explaining the nutrients and
their functions which is cool that
Tony's here for this one because he
knows a lot you hear us talk about NPK
will focus on nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium will go with nitrogen first
you'll almost always hear nitrogen first
most of what you breathe is nitrogen
it's an odorless colorless gas that
constitutes over 75% of the Earth's
atmosphere
despite the overwhelming presence of
atmospheric nitrogen there are only a
few kinds of plants in the legume family
that can make use of it marijuana is not
a legume oh it should say cannabis geez
I couldn't pasted this from the internet
I'll give them credit in a minute I just
don't want to break away from my focus
here where is the website that I stole
this from yeah I don't want to stumble
around and do so many things I'm messing
with the computer and getting distracted
so marijuana is not a legume so nitrogen
must be supplemented synthetically
produced nitrogen fertilizer is made in
the form of anhydrous ammonia from
natural gas yeah that's what I said and
hydrous ammonia from natural gas an
hydrous ammonia is then usually
converted into ammonium nitrate for
storage and ease of application once
granulated the ammonium nitrate is ready
for use as cost-effective and easy to
use plant food natural sources of
nitrogen are numerous and include blood
meal manure bird and bat guano among
many others alright guys Sean will be
here next week I'm gonna jump in for a
minute he'll be here next week to
discuss this all organic method now he
calls it organic as [ __ ] what you hear
about your new tree is being fed being
made with anhydrous ammonia it kind of
makes you start getting more interested
in that sustainable horticultural stuff
it sounds kind of weird and extreme like
some crazy chemistry but it actually
happens in the soil itself there's a
little cycle that nitrates ammonium
nitrates and actually pure nh3 ammonia
are converted back and forth by your
mykos sometimes you'll buy a pack of
mykos that'll say uh nitrogen-fixing
that's what they're talking about they
convert nitrates usually into the
ammonium so it happens in the soil
anyway but that's actually what makes
advanced nutrients junk food it's all
nitrates you want to have some ammonium
ions in there too
Wow and they actually do exist in the
composted organic stuff um they're just
produced usually by bacteria aerobic
decay so Tony's got access to all of the
ingredient lists and studies from the
college's because he's a college kid and
now he's read some great [ __ ] and told
me some great things about nutrients and
it's that's enough right there that's
yeah yeah all right so uh where was I
I'm talking about Sean's coming dude
once I read about this stuff I got kind
of like I want to go more toward a
sustainable way of growing my plants I
think it would be better that's my next
step I can crow I can breed I can select
the phenotypes I can identify problems
like everything my game is strong now I
just got to adjust and get more more eco
friendly quit using so much electricity
and photon hydro shop stuff much love to
my hydro shop sponsor I just got to get
away from some of that stuff you know so
because I was talking about nitrogen
because if it's crucial role in
photosynthesis fertilizers high in
nitrogen are used during the vegetative
phase of growing cannabis nitrogen is
key to both chlorophyll and protein
production and used throughout
photosynthesis for the conversion of
carbon into sugars and other organic
compounds so grow fertilizers are high
in nitrogen they're used for rapid
growth they're used to build chlorophyll
and promote a healthy green color and
they improve the volume and health of
plant foliage you guys if you see your
plants looking pale and yellow that's
your first sign of probably a nitrogen
deficiency over 35 minutes in we'll get
through these nutrients at least this
will be cool I should say that the plant
most plans in general will intake 80% of
all of the nitrogen they use in a
lifetime during the vegetative stage so
that's why all your vegetative cannabis
nutrients have a higher right at the
start of flower stores it up for
metabolic processes okay so just say
it's just chilling in there just save
carbohydrates actually okay it stores it
up as energy and then it releases it
during flower so I usually feed my veg
nutrients until about two two weeks into
flower so that I'm giving them more
nitrogen to have available should I just
switch right away that's what I've been
doing but mine turn yellow way too fast
all right I'll just keep feeding that
next that extra two weeks kind of seems
to keep them green for the time that I
need now there's like veganic sources of
plant nitrogen's usually amino acids
those usually they direct you to use
those
up to flush which I've not figured out
why but it's the good nitrogen lots
vegan annex is way different I've grown
if you get a crop with some veganic
nutrients I was given and it had the
flavor
it definitely cottonseed or soybean meal
those are very high weird organic types
of nitrogen's usually amino acids and
proteins that's why all these organic
guys are getting great results they're
using actually naturally-occurring but
uses a high highly active microsphere
there lots of bacterias and ransoms so
you have to be Shawn to come listen to
the next episode of Shawn you'll love it
you'll love it
alright let's talk a little bit about
phosphorus phosphorus is a volatile
volatile and reactive element which is
why it is probably never found in its
pure elemental form in nature because of
its volatility fertilizer packaging is
actually showing a measure of its oxide
P 2:05 phosphorus is commonly refined
from stone called phosphatidyl islands
comprised of primarily bird and bat
droppings a common bio massive source of
phosphorus is found in the ground bone
also known as bone meal cannabis plants
use the phosphorus throughout their
growing cycles but at elevated levels
when flowering is the plant's nutrient
requirements change the feeding schedule
is adjusted to include bloom foods with
higher levels of phosphorus and lower
levels of nitrogen because plants also
use phosphorus and root formation low
doses of it are often found in cloning
solutions so phosphorus basically bloom
foods are higher in phosphorus
phosphorus improves blood production
phosphorus aids and root development and
it's involved in oil and glucose
production in the end of your blooming
cycle yeah you're actually you want your
highest phosphorus levels
a few weeks before flower and like for
the first third of flower
okay so boost those up just like we did
with the nitrogen yeah the nitrogen
starts to drop down and that's when the
phosphorous goes up and then towards the
middle end of flower you want lots and
lots of K so you want a very very high
last number okay alright let's talk
about K potassium potassium is an alkali
metal that reacts violently with water
and oxidizes quite rapidly when exposed
to air this unstable nature requires
that it be added to fertilizers in the
form of potassium compounds known as
potash not all forms of potash are
suitable for planets like phosphorus
potassium is mined from mineral Laden or
like and in P potassium which is K is a
key component in the mid metabolic
functions of plants and plays a large
role in the production of proteins and
photosynthesis potassium also helps
strengthen the marijuana plants immune
system but it correct that cannabis
plants immune system which help helps
the plants cope with environmental
stresses including insects and diseases
bloom formulated fertilisers often
include increased levels of potassium
because it helps improve flower quality
also potassium is found in both grow and
bloom fertilizers because Tony was
saying that it's good towards the end of
veg it helps the plants immune system
and it increases flower quality you'll
see it in most of your bloom boosters
it'll be real high in potassium so if
you're looking for a bloom booster and a
bud hardener that last number on the
bottle that's the one you're looking at
yeah so would you agree with me that
that's the basics of the NPK yeah you
want to start higher nitrogen and then
end very low and then start mid to low
potassium and end very very high very
high yeah and then the phosphorus kind
of like goes in like a little mountain
hope there's some plants I feel like you
almost can't give them too much
phosphorus it's a timing thing actually
I feed them a bunch of it right as
they're going into flower and then when
I noticed the buds have naturally
stopped
swelling up I do some what's quite a bit
more and then they just they're little
metabolism kicks back on for one more
week
yeah there's yeah if you kick a lot of
potassium in and it keeps it moving it
definitely keeps them from slowing down
and plants don't get as lazy
alright so we'll talk a little more
specifically about when to feed things
to our plants when the plants are young
we kind of covered this but the plants
are young they don't require as much
realization I focus on root building
when the plants are young mykos are your
friend and enzymes are - we've talked
about Michaels and enzymes on the show
before we'll come back to that I want to
get all the basics covered
that's your og T and your hydros I'm if
you guys are looking for products use
them just like they say on the bottle
those are perfect small plants want
nitrogen to grow strong a little bit of
phosphorus will help them build roots
and grow figure it vigorously a little
potassium will keep them healthy your
basic veg nutrients probably have enough
NPK to get you through your veg phase if
you veg for long periods you may need to
add some calcium magnesium ah that's
something that larger plants will start
running out of so let's talk a little
bit about cal-mag while we're here
calcium and magnesium are what are known
as secondary nutrients calcium is a big
part of the cell structure and cellular
growth calcium stimulates enzymes that
build strong roots and cell walls
magnesium is essential to absorb light
energy if your plants are slow and lazy
they may be experiencing a magnesium
deficiency you know certain types of
yellowing between the veins it's
magnesium deficiency magnesium is
actually what makes chlorophyll green a
little bit of Hume egga from organic
hair will speed your plants up when they
start getting lazy like that yeah so in
the beginning you need nitrogen a little
phosphorus and a little potassium if
you're looking for big roots definitely
add some type of mykos or root inoculant
I always brag about the og tea and great
white shark together that [ __ ] works
great for your root to get big fat white
roots if you feed a gteen great white
shark along with your mix your regular
feed schedule in the morning right when
the plants come on if you go in about
two hours later most of your leaves will
be pointing straight up and they're
praying and thanking you they're saying
holy [ __ ] I love that that's what
they're doing they love that
if your plants get a little too big and
fed you're gonna need cow bag once you
into the flower phase totally like we
talked about reduce the nitrogen the
first two weeks of flower will show you
much keep the plants fed and happy I use
micro based nutrient until week three a
flower like I was talking about feel
like it keeps him nicely nitrogen up
until the end of flower I had some cow
bag and put some potassium silicates in
and also some type of kelp in week 3 so
that's cal-mag potassium silicates and
kelp at week three I'll add liquid karma
and sweet at week three also so when he
started week three a flower you can drop
out most of the nitrogen and really
start pumping up the P and K wait for I
do the same thing as week three we
should be low on nitrogen and pumping up
the P and K I'd had some kelp and a
small amount of molasses by now it also
had some enzymes to my mix I'd be
running the whole botanic air feed chart
by week five week four so here we go
week five is where I really pound my
plants with food I think day thirty is
where they're really ready for sugars
and boosters that's when they're really
ready to get hammered with a lot of
stuff so I've dropped the nitrogen by
now and I'm feeding heavy doses of P and
K I'd be adding my bloom boosters and
lots of molasses and sugars
cal-mag will be super important for the
next couple weeks enzymes and kelp would
also be helpful for a big tasty buds I
think kelp I'll use a lot of SEAPLEX
I think all that kelp really adds to the
stink and the density it really adds to
the some flavors if they have that foot
cushy skank skunk smell that stank it
kind of makes them come out a little bit
better if you had a lot of lot of kelp
so you should add some potassium
silicates for thick branches at this
time like week five week 30 ish maybe
you could have put those in at week four
but if you got good healthy plants I
think they're cool on week five you just
need up four to build those branches up
a little bit while the buds grow to
super thick cuz they're gonna start
falling over if you don't have some kind
of tomato cages so a week five is
basically your blue based nutrients lots
of blood bud boosters sugars enzymes
potassium silicates and kelp week six
will basically be the same thing focus
on your bud boosters and sugars and get
that stuff up there as high as you can
without burning the plants put a lot of
molasses in there a lot of P&amp;K products
and some enzymes in there to keep all
that stuff moving if you do the same
thing up to however long you need to go
week seven week eight usually don't feed
after week nine you should start
flushing by week eight most plants are
going to go more than ten weeks off
you're growing a plant that takes more
than ten weeks I hope you're experienced
and I hope all of this stuff already
makes sense to you because that's gonna
be it's gonna be a [ __ ] for you to grow
an 11-week plant without this knowledge
so once you get to week eight and you've
gotten done feeding these plants and
keeping them happy and healthy you need
to flush you we've just talked about how
much stuff we pour it into these plants
now you need to spend at least ten to
fourteen days with nothing but water in
these plants so on Monday however much
if you've got a five gallon pot pour
water through it tell that [ __ ] to run
it through until your tree is almost
full until you're worried about it if
you have a way to get that water out of
the tray that's ideal get that water out
of there and let those plants sit until
they're almost dry and do the same thing
all over again
and do that for the next ten to fourteen
days try to get three or four cycles of
just clean water through there so that
you can push out all the nitrogen the
phosphorus the potassium the calcium the
magnesium the mykos that we just put in
there you need to clean your soil out
you want to get all that stuff out of
there now if you have like really clean
really clean sources like molasses you
could use that your first flush watering
quite a bit of that and sugars displace
salts that's why all the like clear X
that they'll sell you clear X is just a
bunch of different types of sugars just
places salt but it feeds off your mykos
it basically feeds all home boots their
colonization up and they end up eating
any residual food that's lipped they eat
a bunch of it for you little garbage
disposals he just said sugars displace
salts you guys so most of the nutrients
you're feeding are salts and your plants
are filled with salts salts don't taste
so good sugar sounds like it tastes good
right so if you put some sugars in there
when you're flushing it'll push the salt
out of your plants it'll also clean up
the soil it'll break it up kind of goes
in there and stir it around right yeah
feed feeds your hands are hungry mykos
which is always awesome I want to go to
a web
this is where I got a lot of the
information about just a lot of
information from this show it's called
marijuana growers HQ comm is where I got
a lot of it and I also got some guidance
from the Botanic Air website I'm kind of
looking at their feed charts to keep in
mind what I would feed every week
because I don't have my own feed chart
in my hand because it's so it's in the
gross spaces you know I don't carry that
around but yeah so that was a shout-out
to the people that made the charts easy
for me to figure out and they made NPK
easy for everyone to understand I think
we should stop there on the nutrient
lessons because we're 45 minutes in 47
minutes and I think if we go any further
we'll end up running over an hour and
you potheads run out of attention span
at 45 minutes I can tell how long you
listen stitcher tells me Tony can
definitely tell how long you're
listening because he runs all my web
stats we've had about 5,000 lessons on
the past few episodes yeah which is
remarkable I want to thank all 5,000 of
you hope all 5,000 of you continue to
listen it seems like it's about time to
wrap up the show I don't feel like I
have much more to cover or was that page
that I had my topics I think I covered
them all we're gonna say we did because
I can't find the damn paper so we had to
have covered all the topics
oh the cannabis cup was over
Thanksgiving the vault genetics DNA
genetics big shout out shout out to
Crockett I don't remember exactly who
want everything but big shout out to
everybody that took home prizes I hope
everybody has a safe trip home
or the cannabis cup got raided and they
shut it down so they had to move
everything there was no big smoke out
Expo all that they did have was the
concerts that were supposed to happen so
I hope everybody got home I hope nobody
got in any trouble um so now that the
show's over yes the show is over now
that the show is over dude Tony thanks
for coming and no problem is good
finally having you on the show bro you
been a minute yeah you've been working
with me for quite a while we never had
you on a podcast I appreciate you coming
do you want people to follow you on yeah
lxt rvn lxt rvn on instagram follow him
he post a lot of cool pictures of ghosts
og we might kind of be in a personal
friendly comforted competition over a
girl on this ghost og it's kind of fun
so check out his ghost pics and my ghost
pics and then leave some comments
alright guys now that the show is over
please go to iTunes or stitcher also big
shout out to Jesse he's taking a nap on
the couch dude we'll only make a little
bit of funny
it's alright everybody has their first
dab we got to see what happens now the
show's over please go to iTunes or
stitcher go to the iTunes Store or the
stitcher main page there's for the hydro
culture podcast find the review section
please give me a five star rating after
that type in a comment let me know we
think of the show and I will read your
comments on the show don't forget that
the podcast is available on iTunes
stitcher and every single episode is
archived forever on IRA genetics
Colorado comm make sure you follow us on
Twitter Instagram and Facebook just
search for I grow culture follow IRA
genetics on Instagram if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like us to
review send an email to agriculture at
hotmail.com
and I will get you all the info that you
need we still need our own theme song I
want to give a huge shout out to the
mystic roots for let me play their own
music but we'd like something that you
know says agriculture podcast in it big
shout out to my ninja spins guys until
next time thanks for listening
take a phat dad give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 43 of the iGrow
culture podcast the podcast all about
cannabis news education and culture if
you're new grower a professional grower
a longtime cannabis consumer brand new
smoker or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for joining us at the table today is our
[Music]
time out of your busy schedule today
himself he's on his game it's delicious
and when you smoke is good it is amazing
it really is I'd like to steal some of
his turkey turkey Slurpee by the time
this episode airs in my mind I feel like
Spencer will have one the secret cop
he's there now the competition actually
happens Sunday night I think the judging
happens so by the time this episode
comes out he will be the champion of the
secret Cup and I can reveal what was
entered
it was white widow
[Music]
everybody knows now it was White Widow
grown by Rasta jeff of ira genetics he
was the cut spence gave me the cut a
while back I crossed that cut to
Grateful dog and actually made Kabletown
with it I love that white widow dude it
grows like a boss
they kicks out multiple donkey dicks
like menorahs of donkey yeah so I hope
that does well for you good luck brother
I hope you brought home a trophy either
way if he won or not I plan to get him
here on the show he might be the episode
after this his schedule pending it's up
to him he's invited he knows he's
welcome any time
hopefully we can get a shout out Spence
shout out to Big D shout-out to Jeremy
shoutout everyone involved with the
secret cup will do a wrap-up on that one
in the next show let's do an ad real
clip we got to pay some bills before we
get too far this podcast is brought to
you by our good friends at nature's
drain remedies dot-com check out
nature's green remedies calm 4 gauge
green genetics lopata labs Sin City rare
dankness mile hike an adventure the Cali
connection MTG I read genetics and of
course many more trusted brands nature's
bean remedies has a coupon code for you
if you type in coupon code frosty you
will get 15% off any order and you get
free priority shipping at nature's green
remedies calm that coupon code does
expire on the 31st so take advantage of
that while you can Podcast is also
brought to you by my good friend task
rock and highly-educated titanium if
you're using high quality concentrates
if it's solvent lists if it's BHO if
it's live resin if you're taking a DAB
you deserve a high quality titanium nail
don't use some cheap-ass Chinese
knockoff or even some cheap American
knockoff made by some competiting brand
competing brand they're not using the
quality titanium you need trust the
industry leader trust highly educated
titanium highly educated more info if
you want to buy some highly educated
products go to Aqualab technologies
dot-com big shout out to giddy up while
we're at it Jessie's pointing out the
new email that we got my buddy giddy up
in emo tech sent me the sweetest
brand-new Gmail I love it it works like
a boss if you're in the market for a
Gmail an email that stays hot at the
perfect 10 time check out the Gmail also
Mad Love - tree hugger calm this episode
is brought to you in part by tree hugger
calm music and festival no concert and
festival news and reviews look out at
the cook
with tree hugger calm and our last
commercial I promise this is from hydro
indoor growing supplies make sure you
check out hydro into our growing
supplies they have two locations to
serve Colorado is at the Denver store 62
71 Beach Street or of course the
beautiful Pueblo location featuring
Byrne and Jesse on 618 East 4th Street I
check out hydro for a competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies also don't forget if you
mentioned you listen to the hydro
culture podcast you will get commercial
pricing it's gonna save you a lot of
money if you're buying a nano luxe light
you're gonna save quite a few bucks
Jesse just looked to me like we didn't
think of that nice enough to get going
there in the store I just saw you
visualize the Shelf as if the Shelf
would be there he could see it I think
he counted them um I don't know if it's
Tommy's there or if we're gonna get the
order by the time show shows different
numbers go through my head there they
will get your nano Lux lighting needs
taken care of they look to be quality
lights much lived all the sponsors I
appreciate it you guys thanks for
helping us out if you're interested in
sponsoring the show email me it's
Agriculture at hotmail.com and we'll get
it going so I've got a couple of things
I gotta say big shout out to Angela Adam
and Mike dude you guys trimmed for seven
hours last night thank you
Sean just looked over and saw the
trimmed pots and shook his head those
are big pots trim and I could not have
got through it all so uh big huge shout
out to Hankey be Hankey be gave me some
live resin to dab I was hanging out his
house and as I left he was here man take
some of this I just gave me like a
grandma live res make sure you follow
him on Instagram that's hard to say he's
Hankey b11 he told me to make sure I say
that cuz he gave me hash it's a big
shout out to Hank we'll skip some
shoutouts for now that's enough let's
get on to the meat of the show here we
got a guy that does all kinds of
organics and we've been talking about a
lot of grow lessons so I guess the first
question to jump right into it dude if
we just want to get down to it you want
to tell me all
Organic is [ __ ] [ __ ] it's a Jessie
actually started the hashtag of stole it
obvious page but now it's the idea is
that all organic we don't like the idea
of any bottled fertilizers and that ik
nutrients specifically no pesticides
anything with mineral salts map and dap
mono Ematic mono ammonium phosphate
preservatives the idea is to create a
clean product food grade everything half
of the products I use it our local
natural grocers just a really big
emphasis on growing style that's most
growers tend to focus on flower where we
focus on the soil I feel a lot of stuff
is lost when you're just focusing on
weight high vegetative yields you quit
flowering times you're just losing a lot
of I mean money you just lose them so
much in that process quality exactly and
then hurting the environment and a lot
of other people and that's that part is
what's really got me interested I want
to learn a lot from you to maybe shift
my grow toward this style and my
reasoning is the sustainability I've got
a kid and she's 11 now and I keep
thinking about the stuff that I hear I
read about what they're making my
nutrients out of and then I'm thinking
about
I toured a large girl facility that runs
a lot of hydro and they have lots of
water that has to be flushed out as
waste and I thought where does that go
that's going back to our municipal water
supply and being filtered out and when
you get water out of the sink that's
what we're drinking and that really
that's enough the past few years has had
me thinking I want to get more
sustainable and no offense to the hydro
shops but I love them because they help
us out but we don't need to be paying
over March prices for a botanic air
bottle because it says Botanica when
Sean can teach us how to take that
chicken [ __ ] and seabird guano and make
something that we can I do feel
hypocritical sometimes because I use
very few products from our stores well
so it has the option I was pretty blown
away when I first walked in there from a
guy who just absolutely you're doing it
mostly out of the organics with the
clean product for the food grade I'm
interested more for the sustainability I
think that's both a great reason to do
it one thing that got my attention right
off the bat you said you don't use any
pesticides or non-organic pesticides I'm
really curious and I bet the listeners
are too how do you keep bugs out of your
crop without some nuclear attack right
at the beginning of the fall here
everybody I know got three types of bugs
at once three letters I pee em can I
guess what that means
ladies and gentlemen integrated pest
management please write that down that's
important we will talk about that a lot
that's gonna be a glossary term that you
need to mark IPM integrated pest
management prevention is the only
guaranteed form of pest control 100% if
you don't want to deal with pests then
you have to start a program and that
starts with a nice organic base you want
to start out with you know things high
in chitin insect frass crab you know uh
things neem cake all of that into the
soil mix then you want to start off on a
regimen of
you know silica what else
aloe vera you want to build you wanna
strengthen the plant help it build us
cell walls basically you need to build
its immune system so it can take care of
itself so throw away the bottle of
potassium silicates and use the aloe
vera and the one that you said that I
felt would really build the cell walls
the silica silica is just such an
underutilized all the fiber grows
exactly the stronger leaf wall is the
stronger is gonna be able to stay enough
to attack okay what are you used to get
silica organics there's a couple of
different options all no actually
there's thousands of different options
on the market
potassium silica is probably the number
one most common it's really that's a
good one to use most companies from cuts
up the bugs if they try to get through
okay well actually they do high for
spray every it's every girl likes to
spend time in their garden and if you
can find a way to do it yeah they go for
me my ways to spray so you know I do
break it down into regiments shout out
to dragonfly earth medicine with their
natural mystic T's of foliar sprays
their soil inoculates and other herbal
inoculate but that's a big part of my
spray regiment homemade compost teas F
PJs ffj civ fermented fruit juices
fermented plant juices that I make
myself and you're actually spraying that
on your Plus bring that on the plate
into flour and I usually don't go okay
just like a traditional spray sounds
even though it's organic things just
tend to stick around okay yeah Newton
cause problems going past week four or
five I assume exactly especially
everything that I use is very sugary
ya know guys I'm not gonna say that I
was a hater of organics but I feel he
stood up for himself before anybody even
mentioned it he said I brought this to
show you that it's dense and it's
odoriferous and it's covered in
trichomes and it's all of that the
trichomes are actually real they're not
tall they don't stick off the bud that
he showed me real far but they're
compacted they're everywhere all over
that nugget even between where the two
little buds touch on that branch there
between there you got resin everywhere
on that Thanks organics do work I can
see the proof you know I do some
consulting on the side with a couple of
concentrate companies Rocky Mountain a
chiral farming you can check us out on
Instagram following us a lot of these
guys you know they're making pho and
it's funny you you have your little meme
on the internet can only smokes bhu but
I'm pretty sure there's plenty of guys
out there who will back me on this one
say it organics produce better hash
I feel the trichomes more fully develops
you your membranes more intact you're
not gonna get that mush I see it a lot
especially when making the ice why
as you can see this is some stuff that's
locally grown smoke this tonight one of
your buddies had some of this I actually
made it for him okay this is organic
soup it still has a nice smell a lot of
this Ovilus they kind of loses the odor
in my opinion and it's still got that
dank smell I believed it
maybe it's degrading a little quicker so
you check the quality of that one I like
this one a lot this one is tasty who did
you say made this that was made by
trichome heavy extracts shout-out to
jibs and grown by growing cush 1 ma ha
Rob he was just killing the game right
now I walked into the first cannabis cup
nobody knew who I read genetics was I
hadn't put my face on Instagram yet and
I had my shirt on and growing cush 1
mile high spotted me right away and he
goes dude your IV genetics come here and
took a picture with me and posted it to
Instagram and now my face was out that's
what did it that's what put my face on
Instagram that's when I was like well
I'm the tall guy with dreadlocks that's
how it goes
I remember that if you want to get your
genetics off their game a couple of
weeks if everything goes well do you
think the you er I'm gonna kind of back
loop here you said that the trichomes
have a better the trichome heads have a
better casing from organics do you think
that it's because we're using what the
plant actually wants instead of feeding
it junk foods out of a bottle exactly a
few of the synthetic approaches like you
say junk food is just the such an
appropriate term
your buds are gonna get denser if
they're gonna get bigger they're gonna
get fatter does that necessarily mean
they're any better no I mean it's only
better for your wallet exactly and we're
fortunate enough to be in an industry or
at a point in this industry where maybe
that doesn't matter as much anymore
so now the people are all obsessed with
hitting a perfect example one plant
kicked out donkey dicks the size of my
arms and then the Girl Scout cookies
have little popcorn but there was as
much resin on that little popcorn of
Girl Scout cookies as there was spread
amongst that entire other plant it was
so dank that little cookies plan is just
coated I'd rather grow more of those if
I didn't have picky patients if my
patients weren't demanding of the
Grateful dog and other strains I grow
all cookies just cuz the resin it puts
out it's so going to cookies you do you
nesaf eat some grateful dog in there but
I definitely have like a 36 light room
of just cookies cookies cookies I kind
of want to mention things but I don't
want to say too much I am in the process
of possibly taking on a badass position
running 227 lights within the next month
I will be in there growing under 227
kavita's oh yeah I'm a little stoked
it's all hydro tables it's gonna be fun
all right so try better trichome heads
because of organics does the aloe vera
have anything to do with that you think
it makes my skin more supple and doesn't
burn under the grow light yeah I mean
you can really go into the properties of
aloe and yucca and
saponin and all of that stuff that's you
have 30 minutes worth the conversation
but bottom line is it increases the
healthier plant silica aloe coconut
water those are the bases outside of
that preach those products other than
the Basilica I'm always about aloe and
coconut water I teach a lot of people
that myself I feel amazing when I drink
it you know with the gardening that I
use I like the idea that my plants share
the same food you know the more I grow
and the more I evolve into this I think
my plants I was a vegetarian before I
grew I took decent care of myself but I
think learning about the plant biology
has made me take better care of myself
and it's influenced my shopping when I
go to vitamin cottage or whatever
grocery store I hit and jesse has done
it to his own practices have influenced
my shopping am i eating a little bit and
it's which is in turn has affected my
growing because now you're here to teach
me how to be more healthy more
sustainable so I see it going full
circle that's I like it I feel like
people maybe put a little bit too much
emphasis on the switch I mean if you're
running soilless and you're running
betaine a care I've got a grateful dog
run to perfect a few strains but it's a
big jump for me to just go change but I
may do it write down what you do and I
can people have probably disagree with
me on this but I don't think you're
gonna lose yield I have to swear up and
down that this whole organic seals less
is just a misconception in the industry
really is unfortunately you do have
people it's a different approach than
traditional gardening so you've got guys
out there have been doing hydro or
soilless mixes for years switch into
super soils and burn in their plants and
all can extend use anything but it
reflects a lot on the grower also I
think somebody like you could definitely
just take off with it especially with
your experience with the hata dose
that's the key okay is with Oregon I see
you started
face a lot of people like to water never
or water every time I'm sorry they don't
use anything but water and me personally
I like to water never and that's kind of
your style now or you're giving it I
don't know all the product name but
you're eating them silica and yucca and
you're giving them everything that I am
just just in the liquid bottle I'm doing
it the lazy way you know how most of
that stuff is made is it's a compost tea
and then so they make like a compost tea
and then they basically they'll arrest
fermentation so they stop and kill all
the living organisms in there turn it
through a protein skimmer bottle it up
and then sell it to you so just cut out
the middleman
there we go by the summer guys we should
all be making our own newts when it's
warm and we're in Colorado I'm not going
on the backyard doing it this week I got
a garage if I had some space by the
summer we'll get it going will all be
grown organic let's get away we have to
support the hydro shops go buy the
organics there get the stuff that's in
the box the blood meal the bone meal
things if you're doing that get your
worm castings and stuff where we locally
go go to high growth and make sure that
when you're mixing your soil talk to
Jesse about that cuz he can fill you in
on the whole meal and blood meal thing
I'm pretty sure Justin loves to talk to
people he loves to just get paid to talk
it's better than advanced but you know
the meal but no can be improved upon as
well so exactly and this goes back to
the the veganic sweet version to kind of
talking about before the show by no
means do I claim to be a viana grower we
use a hashtag called beyond veganic to
kind of poke fun at it just for the
simple fact vegan growing is kind of
funny
just like vegans are a
you know so it's a vegan don't worry and
that's really how they're using just
bottled nutrients it's just plain and
simple yeah
and if they're not they're really
depriving their plants of you know
certain things they could be using
earthworm castings for example like I
nuclear there's a nice little show Rocky
Mount earthworm castings I know Jessie
uses it I usually belch they're super
high quality he's killing the game right
now dedicated his life to making
castings for people like me and Jessie
I've heard a lot of good things if
you're a customer of my store and use
earthworm castings ask me for him please
do you know is organic grower I've been
in Colorado for about two years now
before then I grooves that all I've
known you bros two years it's only been
two yeah but no so you know I have a
degree in horticulture I'm from North
Carolina obviously but back there I grew
fall so it was organically small-scale
but you know I've been doing teas and
soil mixes for a while
coming out here really opened my eyes to
the fact that you know you think you're
gonna come out to Colorado you think
you're gonna grow organics you think
it's this big popular thing but it's all
about money um yeah but you know Jay I
met Jay um and then he had the high
quality these high quality castings I've
never turned back mayhem probably within
a month of being here I've been using
his castings ever since he does all
testings on his stuff you know it's
super high quality and that's really
posted to them today actually yeah and
that's really the key to basically what
I do is my castings and plain and simple
everybody wants to know how do I do it
it's Jase castings
without a microbial inoculant not
microbial source I couldn't do what I do
a lot of people source
you know wrigglers them castings from
stores you know you can make your own
compost it's probably the best way to do
it your own where I'm castings is
probably the best way to do it but at
the same time a lot of people I call it
green washing they go out and they buy
something because it looks organic or it
looks like it's you know gonna be
all-natural exactly like this
environmental friendly product and these
companies are preying on the consumer
just like they would in any other you
know organic companies aren't any nicer
than synthetic companies there's a
company right now for example that loves
to kick out this they throw numbers at
people and you your average grower
doesn't really understand how these work
but for example like Jesse was saying
Jay actually posted something earlier
about the worm castings I'm sorry I
wanted to bring this up check it out do
your research I like um know for example
so you've got a company out there who's
throwing this number around like 30,000
plus microbe you know living microbes in
your tea and you can use it and multiply
it and you know it sounds amazing it
really does then you read J's test and
it's like six point nine million
protozoa and one gram of material so in
one pound that's through over 3 billion
protozoa that's before you multiply in
your Brewer
so to everybody out there that's using
these these products you know these
sales pitches I'm sorry
[Music]
exactly you know you think you're
getting a leg up but really you're
paying for an overpriced Brewer and
somebody to put stuff in a bag for you
I saw you're paying when to bottled me
it's a lot like clothes we're paying for
the label you're paying for that Nike
symbol hair symbol that advance
nutrients logo
so shout out to Jay he's doing it big in
not only worm castings he can source a
lot of things that you know grow stores
can't get Jesse can probably attend to
that there's a lot of things that you're
just not gonna be able to source he
approaches it a little differently thing
you know that's it's cool once you get
to a certain scale it's time to adjust
from being garage basement attic grower
to actually being a horticulturalist and
setting up a grow and doing horticulture
that's kind of what it sounds like
that's what Jays more aimed for here's a
weird question I'm gonna feed botanic
hair will it kill my neem meal if I put
it in my soil before I mix no you got it
the only reason you really have to be
careful mixing synthetics and organics
is you can really throw off your micro
herd you feed too much of something your
fungus is gonna feed it a faster rate
than your bacteria to kill your bacteria
out and your fungus will actually start
to pull things from the plant if it's
not in the soil so it's a balancing act
there's a couple of people I've seen on
Instagram who are just absolutely
killing the balancing act with the
synthetics and organics I would never
recommend it to anybody that's something
we talked about in the last shows don't
mix just stay away unless you were just
extremely well versed in what you do I
would highly recommend staying away from
running synthetics and organics at the
same time I know a guy that admin's his
cocoa saloon and he's runnin full-blown
- hydroponic smell though yeah these
probiotic guys now I've seen a lot of
I'm running Coco the probiotic farmers
Alliance is getting crazy it's giving
everybody this table knows there's one
grower he runs organics all the way
until about week six and then he starts
just pummeling with like hammer head and
all kinds of ridiculous PG ARS just to
make him explode and he said that gives
it the flavor that's his but you know
I'm just yeah that's his girl he can do
what he wants in there just don't sell
it to me I heard they didn't make that
stuff anymore you know they don't but I
know it's called like bushmasters or
something there are two or three bottles
on the shelf at hydro and supplies if
you use hammer head made my buds larger
I'll say it if you're an advanced
nutrients grower or a hydro farmer and
you want to clean that [ __ ] off the
shelf at Jesse there we go advances on
really good sale culture show
speaking of advanced I had something
written down we've already gone a half
hour guys with this show maybe a little
longer than an hour if nobody minds um
why don't you guys I'm gonna take a DAB
and I'm gonna this is I'm like I'm
starting a fight right now tell me a
little bit about PG ours and how you
feel about them PG R stands for plant
growth regulator you guys and I'm gonna
let Sean tell us about those while I
take a DAB there's a time and place for
everything man um not in my food crops
at least not
synthetically made PG RS there's
obviously plenty of ways to use natural
PG ARS playing hormones gibberellic acid
barley tea over two weeks on my
benchmarks yeah actually alternate
alfalfa and barley for veg and then corn
and barley for flowers just because I
haven't found I mean I know I've been
yeah learning that you know a lot of
cool little additives you don't find it
gross doors although almost art have
sperm ferments for immense ferment like
cold processed extractions that's how
you're gonna get your natural PG RS
fermented plant juices basically you're
gonna collect growing new it's just what
a PG are actually is basically basically
what a PG R is is it controls the
plant's growth um so it contains either
real or synthetic forms of plant
hormones and then it's gonna make the
plant react in a certain way usually by
triggering like apical dominance or
stimulating the plant's SAR there's
different ways that these PG RS can
affect the plants but for the most part
you're just applying it to the plant at
a certain stage in its growth cycle to
make it do what you want
you're just manipulating nature so the
most popular one I think that a lot of
us have used in the past would be
snowstorm snowstorm ultra it's basically
they've taken
I think it's seek help and other plant
proteins and concentrated them why don't
I want to feed that to my plants and I'm
just being I'm just trying to yeah and
the thing is a lot of those
yeah I can't really tell you without
looking at the bottle what exactly is in
it but if you telling me it's the kelp
um me personally my favorite flower
hardener back when I used to use bottled
organics was what is it mindo avalanche
Mendocino avalanche which is basically
two different types of kelp and molasses
so that I've actually kind of adapted
that to my so just replace the trap and
you just make a real deal natural
healthy PG jars versus exactly into the
fermented like plant juices extracts is
the way to go it's basically the same
idea is if you wanna if your human wants
to get ripped
you shouldn't go inject steroids and sit
on the couch you should go to the gym
eat protein eat vegetables get all the
things you need and workout we're not
giving our plants a workout we're
feeding them energy bars and protein
shakes and treating them like [ __ ] and
expecting them to be fully healthy we
need balanced healthy play these doctors
they use these steroid boosted I use PG
ours it's so funny like axiom is one of
the best juice lots of not on my
personal stuff you know you're using
this synthetic to stimulate the plants
SAR which is its systematic automated
response that the first word might be
off some sort of automated response
basically it's the plant's ability to
protect itself its defense mode that's
the reason you know the plant produces
resin is to protect itself basically and
that's kind of axiom does is it
stimulates that chain reaction inside of
the plant so it's going into defense
mode
the plant it's exactly what it's doing
is its chemically stressing the plant
you have to be careful you know just can
probably contended this when you're
messing with you Berlocq acid and stuff
I get a lot of fox tailing yeah when I
can to use it later into flour and
that's usually with any PGR
it wasn't a sherbert like acid at one
point was a choice for people creating
from my seeds too stretchy yeah I found
silver thiosulfate did I make myself is
the best way for reversing I was you're
gonna reverse seeds definitely make your
own silver thiosulfate at home it's
really easy to do make everything at
home kind of apologize also if you live
in an apartment if you're a new grower
if you're not if you're not striving
through what we already don't don't feel
bad use your bottles do what you can if
you're a medical patient and you don't
have the physical ability to mix this
[ __ ] up we're not hating you we're just
recommending we're encouraging there's
no and reach out to us because we
definitely have ways that we could help
you yeah well you know if you live in an
apartment if you are unable to mix your
soil and make your own teas there are
definitely options out there for you see
that stuff community on the podcast
everybody truck and will drive up soil
in your yard for you and pots and will
carry it in and hopefully you can get
your wheelchair between the plants to
water them yeah I think people kind of
over complicate things with organics
basically if you if you want to grow
organics or start growing organic side
recommend going and finding a nice and
organic bottled line of nutrients roots
organic general organic age-old you know
the list goes on and on and
[Music]
fish Hydra slate is very good yeah I
used to use it when I was back in the
dizzy
but anyways I'd recommend picking up a
nice bottled organic nutrient line then
outside of that go and get you some nice
Rocky Mount where I'm casting style worm
castings they the quality is extremely
important I cannot stress that enough
fine high quality worm castings or find
a high quality microbial source and then
molasses
there's your compost tea sean is pretty
much describing the the way I grew they
were supposed to call him something
different that's basically the way I go
inside and I could promise you if you
get stellar results and it's you know
it's the way better than I drove us for
damn sure and you're just replacing you
know synthetics FG lates
and that's kind of the idea of using the
tea with your organic bottled nutrient
is when you feed with your teeth when
you feed with the nutrient you're
putting it in the soil when you're
feeding with UT you're activating that
soil to help me eat those nutrients to
give it back into you it's a really good
way to put that it's a great way to if
you're growing with bottled organic
nutrients and you're not using a tea of
some some sort of microbial source
you're just hurting yourself playing
simple I have a couple of questions
getting down free and stuff will you
give us a quick run through five gallon
bucket on how to make a nice Jessie's
done this for us but we chose how to
make nice microbial tea for her just to
start off with yeah we can use almost
any time okay so yeah without a doubt
worm castings in molasses if you can't
get anything else just those two and
there's your microbial source and
there's a food for it of dependent on
your quality of castings 1/4 the cup per
gallon molasses depending on how often
you're using it one teaspoon to 1
tablespoon for a gallon
outside of that kelp meals always a good
one i coat me all I mean if you're not
familiar with the benefits of kelp you
should really look it up plenty of plant
hormones there's a decent NPK value in
there and then really go crazy just
molasses earthworm castings then you can
go into kelp you can go into alfalfa
depending on you know veg flour that's
how you're gonna kind of deliver more of
an NPK value to your plant
do you agree with the Rebs the Rebs book
true living organics you know either the
Reb sub I grew up learning organics just
like everybody else did and I really
don't agree with his unfort
but I learned everything did I know now
from his book you know it's if I
wouldn't I went through that trial I
wouldn't be where I am today so I can't
be mad at him you just have to work
learn what works for you I know people
who have used to stuff with great
success okay so he's not saying to skip
it no I've seen some people crush it and
have amazing super soil and I've seen
other people have burnt up shitty buds
with super soil so it's kind of it's how
you grow it's people are really funny
about organics we even with my Rocky
Mountain a chiral farming page we kind
of had to take a break with those for a
while we like to put in for informative
posts trying to help the community but
we're not met with a lot of defiance oh
as soon as you put up I quit posting a
lot of stuff on Facebook as soon as you
put up a helpful thing ten people tell
you why you're stupid and you know
teaches and you don't have to agree with
the way I grow right yeah even if I say
something wrong
sure I mean it's a lot easier for you to
focus on one point I got a lot of stuff
I got to remember I've actually made
mistakes on this podcast and I felt
proud to come back and say hey guys last
week I told you the wrong way I'm sorry
like Jesse called me he's like you just
said this [ __ ] I did say that I feel
like people are getting too caught up
this growing style or that growing style
or he grows like this they grow like
that and it just people need to choose
their own information science all three
of us grow different ways you know yes
you know but we all borrow something
from each other exactly you've learned
something from me and I've learned five
things from you and five from yous we're
all still doing the same thing thank you
I love talking to synthetic growers I've
never grown marijuana synthetically my
background is in commercial agriculture
I've been millions and millions of GMO
horrible horrible synthetic plants 30
acres of glass greenhouses before people
get to eat but you know there's a
certain point in time that you've got to
kind of figure out what means more to
you is it your money or your morals yeah
I walked away from making $45,000 to you
which is you know it's a good bit for me
oh no you know walked away from that and
got a part-time job here in town working
at a hydro store and just grew that's
what I wanted to do and I couldn't it's
a lot easier to wake up and look at
yourself in the mirror solutely that's
why I started a seed company because I
got tired well that's kind of what led
to it but that's how I ended up
self-employed I don't want to work for
somebody all day for something I don't
support exact for a minimum wage and
hate myself I'd rather be kind of
struggling and really happy have a cool
job and have a cool job I've got
everything I want cool ass girlfriend I
do what I want I got a seed company if I
and I'm not rich I think if I were rich
I'd just be depressed and confused on
all this money and I wouldn't know if
you guys are my friends because I'm rich
or cuz you guys are cool as [ __ ] smoke
all my live resin because I've got it
out to do too much
I think I've got where we are rich we're
rich this way we make the did we know
that we're not poisoning people happy
drawing a quality product we're
contributing we're moving it forward
we're making the cannabis a good thing
instead of a scary thing I walked away
from a twenty five dollar an hour job
well I walk away they actually told me I
had to quit smoking weed and said no so
but yes and a lot of people tell you
that that's wait half years but you have
to choose the decisions that make ya
happiness over money is way important I
don't drink a fifth of whiskey every
night now oh yeah you can tell one beer
Wow two beers would crush me you told me
earlier what is your average harvest
weight per thousand watt light running
organics you know it varies last round
we ran with the kind of like the style
Jesse was talking about with just a
bottled nutrient kind of her bottled
organic supplemented with teas we were
hitting around I see 1.7 pounds per
light this guy's this last grow um which
is what I brought you today was grown
with no bottle of nutrients absolutely
none I mean this is all fruit juices
plant juices the calcium and I think a
pretty mild soil too compared to like
TLO amending that's really impressed me
about that jar together
[Music]
hold the boat up to the microphone but
it's not loud enough yeah I said we hit
probably 1.2 I'm not done pulling yet
I'll text you with a final wait and you
can throw it up on a later show but yes
right now I'm kind of looking at 1.2 but
that's with no bottled nutrients and
these are new strains that I'm running
this favorite bro you know I'm still I
still feel so like new to the growing
game you know growing back east and kind
of growing what you have to you get out
here and I guess flow probably be my
favorite take good pictures to Rex
I think we were talking about that oh
yeah that win is definitely gonna be in
the garden for a long long time yeah
outside of that I've had a pleasure to
run some of your gear I've grown a
grateful dog the heart of gold is
Jeffrey nice I think the heart of gold
was my personal favorite cool um it was
[Music]
it's not like you wake up in the middle
of the night you accidentally grab that
to put you back to sleep that's the
golden there's definitely sativa heavy
so yeah I think about 10 weeks is
usually what I recommend for the heart
of gold
I took once it's 76 77 days when it's
nice
I think pearly 72 as far as I go so DJ
shorts been preaching this 11:13 light
cycle so I tried it
oh man Sean had a reaction right away
I'm glad I decided to go that route I
had a couple of things written down a
couple of ways to go so I'm glad I went
that way
I'll tell you my experience but what did
you think about it confusion man I just
a little bit of information is a
dangerous thing
that's all I have to say about it I see
I was saying I see more expression the
plants showed more color um a sativa
screen that has never really Fox tailed
on me
kind of made finger e buds um I got a
lot of color I keep saying that the
color was tremendous on this run but I
feel like it lowered my harvest weight
by somewhere between 10 and 20 percent
I'm not I haven't cut everything down
here I've got more to go but I could
tell it diminish my harvest that may
have been from the cold but I really
think it was from that light cycle yeah
we always preach it the most important
nutrient to our plants is the light and
so we took a full hour and that's we
took 63 hours 65 hours away from our
plans honestly yeah and one thing I did
notice they finished quickly I probably
saved two weeks on some of my ten or
eleven weeks drains they're gonna finish
week nine and they'll be done I I'm
worried to let them go too long one made
her mouth I can see it kind of getting
pissy it's like you gotta cut me down
yeah which is cool I'll cut her but I
just wasn't ready it's uh it's a neat
tool and app reading aspect you know if
we were tested across we had made if
you're looking for FINA I think that is
a good point you know that that's
probably the only time I'll use it again
use that you've got growers and advanced
breeders and people talking about this
so just please don't try this at home
yes stick with 12 12 if you want to get
adventurous if you're if you're kind of
advanced do what you want to do I don't
I don't I don't want to hold anybody
back but be responsible because if you
do go and her about that crop you got to
do something with that herm down crop
and don't go tryna you did not just make
a seed company you're not called Calypso
seed does not make a seed company grow
grow them yourself give them to your
friends give free those are free seed
that [ __ ] is free the seed to give to
your friends he warned them and then you
understand hopefully you know all the
breeders are bitching about seven years
or 15 years trained to Kitty's adorable
kitties if your cat guy trained these
kitties to full-on take a [ __ ] in the
toilet
like a human they start tagging that I
region ethics
I don't want to start we're gonna have
shot back because we got more stuff to
talk about I don't wanna start another
long rant because we could I'm going do
you guys have any plugs or shout outs or
anything you want to do people you want
to say thanks to just Rocky Mount worm
company I can't give enough do Rocky
Mount worm company check them out
they've got a Facebook page cool kids
are on these days website Rocky Mount
worm company calm and then they ship all
over the country - yeah I happen to know
a high quality nutrient company that
smog was the stuff into Canada just be
thankful that you year if you live in
Colorado go and get the damn castings
because there's people out there who
just want them so bad and just can't
afford the shipping or they don't have
access to them it's just such an
underutilized thing here in town and it
doesn't sound like you need a whole
bunch you said like a quarter cup yeah I
mean most people are putting in a cup
per gallon these outrageous rates and
you can use 1/4 cup
I mean if five to ten percent cutting
into your soil mixes just more than
enough I use like 80 pounds of it on my
six outdoor plants different grow a
clone grow two clones keep them in cups
for like three weeks you know until
they're starting to get root bound or
they're pissed off root bound feed one
consistently with your microbial tea
with the worm castings in it don't add
that to your other one when you feed it
and pull them out of the cup and watch
you'll have thicker fingery Bank happy
roots on one and the other one you'll
have these thin angel hair pasta wispy
roots if you mulch the one that you're
giving the micro what would it all Steve
Jesus tripped on that word if you put
some mulch on there you see some really
cool [ __ ] happen so nice or just a
plastic cover some fungus among us hey
where do we find you on Instagram Rob's
are like keen Cola
nice king underscore Cola follow him on
there guys
Rocky Mountain natural farming's you can
link through that on my Instagram Jay's
Instagram Rocky Mount worm company do
you have a store opening soon or
something about that well we have a shop
up in Colorado Springs 411 a a 411 a
Tijuana Street and Colorado Springs in
come and check us out see the worm
operation check it out for yourself you
got any questions yeah you're just come
and ask nice nice Jesse any plugs any
shoutouts no Jesse grows Instagram
[Music]
culture podcast I hope you're playing it
in the store play the show in the store
they'd be really cool I keep telling her
to she's like I think we might be
skipping December make it to this one
for sure yeah yeah I know me and Sean
have talked about some cool demos that
he might come and help us with tell
Jesse you want to learn some natural
Farmington yeah hit me up yeah let's
let's get this going I'd love to stock
more of this stuff in they get rid of
one of those things we talked about
earlier I got a whole buncha shelf space
help him help you make your own juice
some synthetic brewery California
wherever you're hitting me up dude oh
I'll show you all that advanced help us
get some organic stuff on the shelf that
you don't care about commercial pricing
[Music]
I need to give a big shout out to Robert
and Vegas and Craig from the spot also
Angela what's up from the spot also just
Angela in general but those kids from
the spot all those guys from the spot
and the spot dispensary in Pueblo West
dude shout out much respect some things
are coming up in the future that's cool
I got a shop opening soon too so I can't
say any names yet though lots of stuff
going on yeah
see all the work that this community has
put in is starting to pay off for all of
us
finally some quality meds we're gonna
wrap up the show make sure you follow me
on instagram it's I read genetics on
Instagram make sure you follow the show
it's I grow culture so we'll read this
part now that the show is over please go
to iTunes or stitcher go to iTunes or
stitcher main page search for the I
agriculture podcast find that review
section give me a 5 star rating
honestly and give me as many stars as
you feel I believe I just want that 5 if
you can move up in the ranks more people
listen to the show the more people who
listen to the show more people that grow
organics more people that grow organics
the more organics you have to smoke more
people that are smoking organics more
people want more people to grow organics
more people start growing weed more
people to Organic weed more we outgrow /
grow the government the more we legalize
cannabis more people listen my podcast
repeat and grow your own food in there -
I want that on a shirt keeps more trees
less [ __ ] someone really famous but
I can't remember their name or what they
did I wonder why they have a cool now
let me congratulate Jesse for making it
all the way through this episode
yeah I took like a whole bunch of devs -
you did you guys didn't even hear it was
cute no guys don't forget that the
podcast is available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is archived on
ira genetics colorado comm make sure you
follow us on Twitter and Instagram and
Facebook search for agriculture if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast I do have a couple of openings
if you have a product you would like us
to review I would like to do that also
send me an email I grow culture at
hotmail.com will get you all the
information you need we do need our own
theme song if you want to make a
cool-ass reggae theme song on the next
episode I hope to have spins here I
can't promise you anything but I really
hope you get spent here just may be here
also and thank you guys for taking time
out of your day to come we're all busy
growers it's great to get all three of
us met here everybody was on time did
you run time like they affect left
coffee stop counts as we're still on
time even after that shout outs went in
just minutes if you listening
[Music]
like reggae till they bands down a
couple times I swear it's [ __ ] [ __ ]
disco music at first it's time number 44
of Viagra culture podcast that's right
number four oh man it's a super special
episode I'm good man I'm on the show
because for some reason we're not gonna
get too far into why but for some reason
we call atom 44 mmm it's a special
number the table from me is our good
buddy Jesse how you doing bro pretty
good and I got to my best friends at the
table I'm doing great
there's nothing to complain about I'm
super happy right now speaking of Monty
I'm gonna reach over and take a sip what
do you guys say pertaining and I'm right
there with you man like it's it's been a
good deal there was a very entertaining
yeah I know it's been a good week words
were coming out that's better than
silence yeah dead air is what you don't
want but we're gonna read a little bit
about some Seth Rogen stuff Seth Rogen
came to Denver recently his idea
backfired we'll talk a little bit about
that I've got an article from President
Obama it's not from him it's about him a
news article I don't remember what I
wrote down where is it it's right here
oh the natives will talk about some
stuff that may happen on Indian
reservations pretty soon been waiting
for that announcement yeah next
reservation I have a special
announcement coming up also some
official [ __ ] here let's quickly do some
advertising guys I know that the
advertising gets old I don't like you to
do this but there's that 30 second
forward on them
let's just hit that if you get tired of
it or hesitate on codes in there and
we'd like to help the people out
speaking of coupon codes as podcast is
brought to you by nature's green
remedies calm dude visit nature's green
remedies calm they've got the best
breeders and the best seeds if you want
your garden to be top-notch you need
top-notch genetics that's not even a
sales pitch that's the truth you can't
grow the dank if you don't have seeds
that are dank get yourself some gauged
rain genetics or plot of labs Sin City
rare dankness mile-high canna venture
Cali connection
MTG or I read genetics will be back in
stock hopefully within the month those
plants are getting cut down here I don't
know if I get bored tonight we can whack
them I'm down yeah there will be some
seeds available friary genetics on
nature's remedies very soon yeah
Christmas time if you are a podcast
listener and you're going to nature's
green remedies calm make sure you use
coupon code frosty for 15% off any brand
and you'll always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies calm that coupon
code frosty is good until the new year
so get in there and get your seeds
before the new year you could start the
new year off with some super dank
genetics the show is also brought to you
by highly educated titanium if you're
smoking high quality concentrates dude
we're smoked and some live resin over
here from the garden of Weeden holy [ __ ]
lay back in our chairs yeah that unicorn
unicorn [ __ ] sparkly glitter have super
unicorn hash you deserve to smoke it off
a high quality nail don't trust a cheap
Chinese nail or some American knockoff
made of cheap crappy metals trust the
industry leader trust highly educated
titanium check out highly educated
ti.com for more info if you're looking
to purchase highly educated products go
to Aqualab technologies dot-com check
them out they got a lot of great stuff
they have everything you need if you're
a dabber podcast is also brought to you
by our friends at tree hugger com tree
hugger comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger comm for
concert and festival news and reviews
tree thugger calm not tree hugger you
guys tree thugger we've stepped it up
wait hugging trees we thug in trees
I just made that up and a super huge
shout out to burn and Jessie this
podcast is brought to you by our great
friends at hydro indoor growing supplies
I grow into our growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store on 62 71 beech tree or
check out the pueblos location at 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check
out high grill for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor grow
supplies hydro is running a special for
the podcast listeners when you're
checking out tell them that you listen
to the agriculture podcast and you will
get commercial pricing on your entire
purchase anything else to cool offer
anything else cool to offer Jessie [ __ ]
we got nanos and stock we got the the
RTE systems for its cloud-based control
Inc no more of power boxes needed timers
were all built in all kinds of neat [ __ ]
they turn them settle something down
while you're on vacation essentially log
into for your temperatures I'm not
really a big computer guy but I didn't
check it from your phone yeah I'm
looking at them like with security
cameras and temperatures I mean you
basically just have another camera on
the you know you don't even need it all
that data to you as long as you can see
into the camera that has all that data
on the wall so yeah there's multiple
ways to do that right supplies guys no
it's just over the bridge in Pueblo
there's a little bit of parking in the
back I've heard that there's nowhere to
park their response in the back you guys
we got the the door all fixed up too so
well
probably by the time this airs it'll be
all fixed up you can just walk in the
back it done nice park in the back if
you drive through the little taco thing
or through the alley
I'm just turn right here you're right
there in the back of high grill it's
that door the door that you wonder is
that the one yes I know
shout out to a handful of people that
[Music]
sorry I got your state wrong if I did
I'm in Colorado in those two states
Arizona Nevada or the big desert down
there hope you guys have time to message
me when you're coming to Colorado to
Pueblo and we'll visit we'll link up
maybe take some dabs if you're into that
that'd be cool all right so big love and
much respect all the sponsors for making
the show possible big shout out to the
mystic roots band coot dog and cat and
the rest of the mystic roots man they
let me play there all of their music
they've given me full permission for
their whole catalog on the show that
helps a guy out trying to run a show and
keep things fresh that's pretty cool
I've been playing a song called the
doggy dub for the intro for the past
couple episodes it's instrumental it's
got a nice flow to it it's kind of got
my vibe so thanks letting me use that
see I have a stitcher comment I like to
read the stitcher or the stitcher and
iTunes comment I have an iTunes comment
from our good friend Fred Garvin what's
up Fred thanks for listening bro he said
great show man thanks thanks
[Music]
me and Jesse were talking about that the
other day that stitching really needs to
get on that that comment section thing
we're just it needs to be linked right
to you or maybe somewhere where somebody
else can see it like just a looker not
maybe a user that has to log in and
teachers aren't comment from a mobile
device on stitcher I can't find any way
to do that so stitcher get on that you
guys I mean that's how I listen every
single podcast this new stitcher so I
mean what I use you guys on stitcher
want to leave a comment I apologize that
you can't but you can go to the iGrow
culture Facebook page and log in and
leave a comment or you can just simply
email me I would love to read your email
I appreciate that just as much if you
want me to read it on the show I
certainly will
the YouTube is another place where you
can go and comment maybe not all the
episodes are up but you know they will
be right you know something down like
episode 35 was there for everybody to
read they don't have to have a youtube
account or anything like that listens a
lot you want to interact if you go to
the Huayra genetics colorado website
join the forum make yourself a a profile
on there go to one of my posts or go
start a new post ask me a question I
will interact with you for sure I do
that usually on Monday or Tuesday nights
when I get all my work done I want to
sit back take some dad's I dab out and
go on the forum and just post pictures I
post a lot of pictures of my roars yeah
there's a lot of stuff on there that
doesn't make it to Instagram I had one
thing that's cool is they can't filter
me that's my website I Tony and I built
that Tony built it I drew it in crayon
this is what the homepage to look like
and then I drew tabs at the top and then
I was like this is what I want the
second page to look like and he kind of
did my vision it's a work in progress
you know but for what I drew he nailed
it got that worked out as well so I also
want to give a huge thanks to everyone
who sent me messages and comments from
episode 43 that was awesome I got more
response off episode 40 35 and 43 have
been our most popular episodes 35 was
drying and curing with Jesse and I and
43 was organics with King Cola
awesome king Cola will definitely
definitely be back big huge thanks to
King Cole a shot if you listen and
thanks a lot dude I've got a couple of
questions for you from a listener
actually he wants me to relay a couple
of questions so we got to get you back
on yeah I got a few too and I had a ton
of response from it as well thank you
everyone
Rock you mad worm company is results for
that get myself I've got some plants
that are gonna transplant into larger
pots here within the next five days and
they will definitely be getting fed
rocky mountain as well you know like you
guys tell them that you're listening to
the podcast home two people are here in
Colorado are supporting them but not as
they've actually commented on the
podcast that they listen we may have a
warming sponsor never heard of it you
know and I'm with these guys most the
time it was kind of their little held
secrets but then they bless it is on the
podcast so you know it's not held secret
but it's no secret to everybody from the
garden of Weeden I mentioned that the
garden of Weeden may be on here to talk
about their secret cup experience they
just got back from Vegas they had a
great time unfortunately they did not
take home the trophy some coastal guys
want some guys from the coast which you
know you can handle that they're not
bitter about it although they were busy
other garden of Weeden was a little bit
busy I was over there hanging out today
was not the day to come on a podcast so
the future will have spins hopefully we
can get Matty over Matt he's never been
on the show I don't think no she hasn't
we got to get Matty over first female
would be the first female on the show to
talk on the show yeah which is
understandable if you're not a podcast
person that's cool but busy is the word
of the week just get everybody to pull
out of their lives for an hour to come
do the podcast but not only that but
let's look at you know like he'd been
sick just there before so he's been
he's good man he's good he looks good
now he's put up Spence was down to like
140 pounds he's six foot four french
toast at some place car bro let's just
go later
huge shout-out to Joey Joey got a hoodie
from me today and I hadn't seen Joey in
a long time so it's kind of nice to hook
up with Joey get him a hoodie
you're gonna look sharp in that hoodie
I'm wrapping up shout out son I got a
lot of them here at the start of the
show it's easier to get him out of the
way much respected much thanks and much
love to Mike Adam and Angela they
trimmed their little fingers off oh my
god well Angela's little fingers might
have normal size she's beastly in it
though Angela is the fastest trimmer I
have ever known
there's one guy I know that might keep
up but he takes adderall compete if
you're enhancing Angela Vegas
Craig everybody over at the spot I gotta
give you a huge shout out to the spot
dispensary in Pueblo West Colorado
they've treated me super kind we've been
at a couple of talks a couple of
meetings and things have happened I
think I'm ready to make the official
announcement today in the mail I
received my Colorado med badge I am now
officially legally licensed to work in a
Colorado Medical Marijuana facility
which means that at this time I can take
the job that I have been offered I am
now the official master grower at the
spot and Pueblo Colorado so within the
next few months there's a little bit of
work to be done on the grow site to get
it up to what I want what we are
expecting there are over 200 lights in
there I'll be the master grower for
those 200 lights which means the and
probably I'm gonna say six months I want
to give myself six months you guys will
see fire coming out of there produced by
Rasta Jeff at all spa in Pueblo Colorado
way cool way cool excited to announce
that what I'm proud to be a part of that
team I was a little picky about where I
wanted to go what I wanted to do a
couple of people have offered me things
I like there grow and I get along with
the people there so it'll be a great
great thing to do my girlfriend is the
budtender I am the master grower my
girlfriend is the trimmer also so it'll
go from it'll have my love in it all the
way from the seed or the clone all the
way up to the time it reaches the
customer and or patience container so
it's gonna have Rasta Jeff love from
beginning to end now so yeah I'm proud
to work with a spot that's my big
announcement that I've been kind of
teasing about on social media and stuff
I want to complement the Colorado Amed
in Springs he made it sound like it was
a big deal to go get your med badge and
it was a pain in the ass I did have a
couple of things I had a tax issue from
my past that I had to clear up and I had
to get a noted paper that my child
support was current and cleaned up but I
already did that because I knew that was
coming and they never asked for it but
they said that they would they never
asked for those papers I went in there I
so in Colorado Springs you're able to
call and make an appointment the hardest
part is getting the appointment call
every day until you get an appointment
because I had to call three times in a
row they called me back after the third
one I said an appointment I got there
early she saw I was early she took me
right when I got there boom she got me
out of there within 30 minutes my full
appointment was 30 minutes giving her
the paper she reviewed the paper and
it's one lady that's there all the time
I wish I could remember her name I was
excited and anxious so I don't even know
what she looks like to tell you the
truth
[ __ ] concert boat lady
yes med lady she was awesome they take
your fingerprints on the digital
fingerprint which is kind of fun and
then they run all your background checks
and then they take a picture of you and
she high-fives you and tells you have a
good day
and that happened Tuesday at 11 o'clock
today when I got my mail it is Thursday
as we record my med badge came in the
mail today
so my bag was check my tax thing all my
child support my fingerprints everything
got done probably within five or six
hours
hands down the fastest turned turnover
rate a furtive I went prepared I went
with everything I needed cuz I called an
ass nose like what am I gonna need I
have like I have a small business
I have child support do I need to choose
like as long as your child support his
current you can prove it as long as your
taxes are good on your small business
they never asked for proof
I guess they probably could tell this
body yeah application was 13 pages I
think 7 of those pages are you signing
writing your name signing and dating
saying this agency can go through all of
my [ __ ]
this agency you can go through all of my
[ __ ] if I missed anything this other
agency can go through all the other [ __ ]
and it's like everything but your
medical records just nice
maybe I cannot say I had that experience
but I got mine right before the first
year last year will tell you if you miss
your appointment it'll be a while before
you can I'm prepared I left early to
45-minute drive my puppy ate my badge
oops
10 bucks I don't think you need an
appointment for that okay they do not
take cash you guys if you ever go into
the Med go get a money order for the
total yeah that's anything pretty much
he really that office and Springs isn't
in a shitty area but parts of Springs
right near like Colorado Springs on one
side of the street is gorgeous the other
side of the street you're like I don't
want to [ __ ] park my car off to the
side areas they could be I wouldn't
recognize a miss they could easily be a
victim of robbery or something not
saying go do it I'm saying they could so
it's why is it they don't keep a lot of
cash yeah and my badge alone was 300
bucks and probably do 20 appointments a
day at 150 years
our appointment price going up for that
50 for the key or 150 for the support
and 300 for the key and if you're
upgrading badge is it still like 253
bucks to go from one to the other like
you should have just paid that in the
beginning so guys if you're curious if
you need to get the big badge or the
little one if you can afford it just get
the big one
yeah it makes you a more valuable asset
to you can actually ask for more pay if
you guys want to apply to be able to
work in the medical marijuana industry
and the marijuana industry you can take
the medical word out if you want to be
employed in any way in the marijuana
industry in Colorado what you need to do
is go to there's a website the
Department of Revenue Department
there will be marijuana documents on
there print out the application for it's
a Med employment application and it's
not the business application it's only
the one for an employment it'll see key
or a support which is how you know if
you're doing the right ones you want
that just go for that key or support if
if you don't want to be like a manager
or something if you just want to trim
her butt and all you need is a support
but if you want to get paid a little
more if you want to have some chance of
climbing up that corporate ladder get
that that big one get that support then
they always have to have a support badge
on premises so if boss needs to go
somewhere maybe you can step up and show
that you can do that [ __ ] that's how
people advance so go on the website
print out that application read it
thoroughly before you even start
printing cuz there's one page that says
if any of this stuff applies to you go
[ __ ] yourself it pretty much says if you
did this you cannot get a badge it's
straight up no like just read your
application now front primarily it's
kind of the same stuff as getting into
the military yeah
no drug felonies no drug felonies is
their main Wanya
I should have had the list here but I
didn't realize we're gonna have this
conversation I mean and it's basically
common sense at that point yeah so if
you can if you're in another state or
one just to clarify like this means like
to work behind a counter selling herb to
people to selling cannabis legally right
doesn't mean you can't live in Colorado
and can't have three plants or six
plants whatever the state this is just
to work in a regulated job become part
of the industry and right right now I
hate saying this but it's what I feel
and what I part of why I'm making the
business decisions I'm making say I
think in the future I region etics will
be able to breed inside of this large
facility that I've just been became
master grower of and right now if I
don't make a move like that the way that
I'm growing in the way that my business
model works I think the industry will
squeeze me right out I either need to
join it or get squeezed out of it and
this is my way to join it and not
disappear I want to be here for the long
haul well I've thought about this I feel
like I'm selling out a little bit but
I'd rather give then not exist at all
what I got to do I totally agree yeah so
all right guys if you get that
application fill it out if you're not in
Colorado you gotta come to Colorado and
you have to show initiative you have to
go to a bunch of dispensaries and apply
in person you have to be kind of
persistent almost be an [ __ ] about it
because so many people apply every day
if you're a hot chick you're gonna get
in don't worry about it you have to know
a little bit about cannabis come with
some knowledge should and be willing to
start at a shitty job be willing to
clean the toilets and trim pot for eight
hours a day because that's what we need
mostly we need trimmers trimmers get
paid decently here and be dependable
please yeah there's such a high turnover
rate in this industry it's ridiculous
bright thing that kind of looks bad
about it don't brag about your trimming
ability don't tell me you can trim a
pound and show up and not be able to
trim it all will fire you while you're
on your phone while you're on your phone
all day there are so many people there
are so many people from around the world
that want in this industry and if you
little performed a top-notch will fire
you they I can't say we I just got
efficient
I moved to your father's you know like
right I can tell you firsthand like if
you don't there's plenty of people that
hit the you know hit the wall every day
and then they get paid and they're just
like I'm mom rich and I you know I'm
around marijuana all day and it's like
nope they just drop out like flies it
may be a cool job but it is still very
much a job it's visit dispensaries here
in town and when I go in there every
week and nobody's there it's different
people in there every week a different
employee ya know customers plenty of
customers especially you know
recreational and stuff like that there's
always lines I've been going to the spot
for a couple of reasons recently mostly
to talk to the owners out there in the
bosses and to see if we can negotiate
and also my favorite person the second
favorite person I have a daughter
sorry girlfriend your second the
daughter comes first just kind of
picking on you but she's out there I go
out there to visit her and go take her
launch or just go see what's up and
doing it's hard for her to get away from
the counter because they've got business
it's you're not gonna go and sit down
behind a counter and be like socializing
with people you would you would think
that you know you still have to have
customer service but it's you have 14
people out in the lobby waiting you know
I told the bosses there that I don't
want a bud tend I said no I'd rather not
be a budtender I just rather stick with
being the grower you know cuz it'll be
downtime for me but I think once in a
while just for fun and I'll announce it
on the podcast I'd be like you guys I
don't mean this right now you guys are
pathetic like a real sense I'll say on
this day I will be bud tuning at the
spot if you guys want to come and buy
some Capleton from Rasta Jeff you
mentioned the Hydra culture podcast will
give you 10% off yeah that's how I got
my foot in the medical industry I was
well I started helping transplant
somebody helping somebody transplant
that had their own shop in too many
plants that couldn't handle it
I saw him struggling I was like you need
help he's like you know how I was like
do this he was older than me so I was
able to work circles around him and he's
like come back tomorrow and I'll pay you
and he gave me way more than I expected
that was for the rest of the week I
guess that's a point go show that you
can do some work don't know it's the
weed industry Wyatt right so you're
gonna think I can show up with my long
hair down I don't need to take a shower
I could put on my Grateful Dead shirt my
[ __ ] up jeans and you can you can't if
you work you still gotta treat it like a
real job interview we want you to be
able to work if I I'm saying we because
I've got my own cannabis business I want
to seed company I guess I can qualify
I'd rather you kind of just show up if
somebody would come in and sit at the
table and not do anything the whole time
and not show any initiative then they
probably wouldn't that's why the
trimmers that were here there were three
trimmers here for like four nights in a
row and that's kinda stressful to have
for all three of those people to take
four nights out of their lives and get a
trim pot for me with me helping them I
could have called two or three other
people but I liked and trusted everybody
here yeah and I could have driven to the
store and came back and nothing would
have gone wrong that's why I keep the
people that I keep that's what it's
about trust
dude be trustworthy you know like and
because you're not if you're working in
the weed industry industry we want some
clean people you're around stuff that
people are consuming and the meed is a
stickler for deenis you guys have some
crazy [ __ ] up rules for this there is
rumor that the podcast will receive a
cease and desist letter we can continue
to podcast but not under the name I grow
culture nobody anything yet a lot of
businesses and podcasts and YouTube and
Facebook and Instagram things have been
being forewarned at that a business
called iGrow which is a college
institution that does college
horticultural stuff is coming after
people using the iGrow moniker I have no
problem changing the name
want to do it slowly if it does happen
and I kind of want to do it preemptively
before I actually get a cease and desist
letter in the mail or email to me or
however it's gonna happen I think it'd
just be responsible and kind I know if
that's their name and they've got it I
don't really feel like I want to rip
them off I just thought it was cute my
buddy Kevin and I came up with it I was
like it's like I wanted to use the eye
because it's the modern I grow eyes and
it's the eye world and it's I grow
you're listening you're learning to grow
from me on your iPhone and it's it's a
play on the word agriculture as what we
thought also
yeah so that's the I grow culture but
we're gonna have to change it I already
know what the name will become if it
haven't decided for sure that I want to
do it I may just do it on December 1st
we'll go agriculture slash this podcast
for a month or two for used to it ya
know but we may have to change your name
you guys it'll still be the same show
nothing's gonna change but the logo and
the title hey bender if you're listening
bro the new title of the show will be
the grow from your heart podcast just
relate that to if you guys listen to now
and the [ __ ] disappears look at the
growth from your heart podcast it's the
same thing it'll be the same feed so
nothing will change I'll yeah you can
type in the title on the feet and change
the feed in my my website stuff
everything will be legit it will all
stay the same other than the words so
bender help me out bro I'll make it up
to you somehow hi if you hook you up
grow from your heart podcast where
there's a girl from your heart podcast
ever you want to do it like a heart with
maybe some herb coming out of it or
whatever do you know red gold and clean
nailed it last time so nailed that last
one just hit gold over there whoever can
do some art if you're in Colorado and
you're an adult and you can find me
face-to-face I'll pay you in seeds or
herb I will gift you seeds and herb in
return for making me this I won't pay
you I can gift you [ __ ] I can totally
give you a gift of kindness
to see and you can also give me a gift
of a sweet-ass logo also you don't even
know if you're not 21 and you're not in
Colorado
I'll get you like a hurry genetics
t-shirt if I have your size in stock
I'll send you something [ __ ] cool
from Colorado to make it up for you up
to you I also need a logo I'm not
begging but I need a logo when it's
community-made nine times out of ten
you'll probably get a flood of songs
girl from your heart podcast that's
gonna I'm gonna have to I'm just gonna
start singing that pretty soon here
that's gonna be company that knows the
name so that was a phrase you told me
one of the first times we like sit down
and I currently talked about growing and
reading yeah pretty hard actually what
she said breathe let's love and go from
here I've been preaching those things
for a long time those have always been
perhaps the truth yeah it makes your
yeah if you're not doing that your dick
if you're gonna grow cannabis and you're
not starting and just like sitting in
that room 24/7 just like on your hands
and knees cross-legged like you need
style like loving on them then that's
you're not getting this part of the
story you know write it down it's
official grow from your heart podcast
how's that third row from your heart I
like it
we just gotta get people out spread the
word that's what we're trying to do
spread the word well most people are
listening most you guys are to listen in
wah wah you already know we were talking
about where I say something dumb one of
my favorite things to do Adam likes to
spurn a rant he'll stare at you as he
doesn't waiting for you to reply it we
know don't reply he just puts his foot
deeper in his mouth yeah just like and
then you look at him like huh huh and it
would be the perfect time right than to
stop but he has three more things that
he really wants to cram in the area
Jesus Christ what is wrong with this
[ __ ] my favorite is when were in the
car and he just starts doing it and he
doesn't know if I'm silent because he's
being a [ __ ] or if I'm just driving
or what it is and he's like yeah that's
why we keep you around bro oh I know I'm
good for a laugh every now and then
working with them either with me or at
me the other night either way it's fun
working with him this last week I've had
some good laughs yeah and thank you man
like for real you put food on the plate
like for the shout-out this week you
brother like straight up new play in the
dirt all day screwing off I can it's the
Denver bug company they're gonna be
wholesalers and thank you you know going
uh or their business plan is to be able
to buy their brand of cannabis and
dispensaries all over the all over the
state so nice Oh but yeah they'll be
opening sometimes you when we're done
building it man I got a few other
hurdles after that oh yeah inspections
yeah
the hardest part in Colorado right now
is getting damn water yeah getting water
rights for ya is a big big big deal yeah
we saw a huge freaking girl today out
south oh they're all around us right now
if you go out highway 96 towards Wetmore
it's just right up against the highway
there chain-link fence you can almost
like flicker your fingers in it when you
drive to the highway the one you guys
saw down south that that thing that
place has a freakin air airstrip on it I
gotta say one of the neatest I have seen
is my boy hanky be over at the greener
side dispensary aha
stewey check still haven't seen a bunch
of LED lights going it's not happening
right now
last season towards the end of the
season they had led LED lights and it
made that whole what is it like a 60 by
a hundred foot greenhouse 60 but no it
was filled with LED lights and so on the
Sun set right at sunset it looks like
aliens were invading for about a mile is
just this big spaceship was so awesome
yeah neat greenhouse it was that forever
flowering yes sir shout out to forever
flowering northern down altitude or
hemispheres the model all of them yeah
yeah that thing sings to you in the
morning alright I do have a couple of
news articles worth 35 minutes in a
great crazy rambling guys I hope you
like these episodes where we just come
and hang out a little bit the past
couple of episodes have been really
intense my friend hooked
she takes notes so I hope you could put
down your pan and just enjoy you know
[Music]
the wire on the what happened my
lightning through the headphones
holy [ __ ] so I have a news article too
yeah first time ever reading a news
article says you know bear with me I'm
not reading it either but I'll just hit
the points so basically the
good old Congress which I believe a
Council of Washington DC one of the
congressmen is thrown in I'm just trying
to gather did you find it on the the dab
is some serious [ __ ] fire Gorilla
Glue yes and they were blasted together
in the obidos dude emo text sent me a
brand new email I've had it running
basically for a week straight without
turning it off I turned it off when I go
to bed and [ __ ] but honestly I walk up
it's like my coffee pot feature for the
[Music]
shut off about 3:00 in the morning
this one's got a [ __ ] USB port that I
turned my phone on and it charges my
iphone so fast
[Music]
yeah it smells garden of Weeden
he just killed or actually Maddy did but
they both did they just
government the Ola mine yes again it had
quite possibly one of the best rounds
I've ever seen of it I haven't got to
grow that strain inside as much as I
would've liked to the stuff they post is
just I mean what's the cross on your
government meal um it is g13 crossed
with Tom Hill's deep chunk everything he
makes is amazing so we've got a little
collaboration happen and Jesse is
actually gonna breed and I'm gonna put
the seeds in I read genetics packages
and we're gonna sell them as I region
etics products because I need some help
involved in that project yeah that x OG
mil I literally don't have a name for it
um and you know I'm not gonna try to
make up some crazy name to for this Mel
I can just say it's it's a really good
mail it's been proven it's made several
crosses for some small-time breeders um
is it the og mail I think of yeah yeah
little one we were talking about the
other yeah cool
so unfortunately you know there's not
gonna be anything fancy on the package
in regards to you know it's just mr.
email or something like that but the
government meals serious fire did to
cross together it's just it's gonna be a
the government meals real deep tone
cleaning he's gotta give your mail a
name like gage calls his mail Joseph so
we just gotta name it it just needs a
cool name what it is that was the name
of the meal that I grew up next to it
was Henry the meal you hear him every
morning
first I want to remind myself oh that's
[ __ ] dangerous you can do that let's
go
[Music]
dude I was like thank you guys all
10,000 of you or at least 150 of you
that like my pictures was going through
and cleaning up spam accounts and taking
off all kinds of [ __ ] so good I got one
form by the way guys that's over grown
your Gov just because somebody I forgot
somebody had taken that that's got like
60 followers and hasn't posted in two
years like I would think if you went
there and it has nothing to do with
cannabis and then nothing to do with
anything slowly say you properly say
you're instantly grow grown you're gov
overgrown you're gov or grown I even
following you I yes you found me I mean
usually people find me it's it's it's
definitely happened but can we see your
real name on the show your flight yeah
Gaskins yeah I call them gas cans what I
call I don't my tell Siri call Adam gas
cans put your phone near Siri on a
British accent with a chick yeah and
it's hot let's read this article Jesse
kind of started to read it Oh bomb
opposes congressional effort to stop DC
pot legalization of human and the
picture it looks like he's clapping but
he's not he's got this like weird facial
expression this article is from it just
says Associated Press nobody gets any
credit here to the AP that's all so
whoever wrote it sorry brother you
didn't nobody cared
President President Barack Obama plans
to sign a 1.1 trillion dollar government
spending bill if it reaches his desk
although he opposed a provision blocking
the District of Columbia from legalizing
marijuana
Jesse's frantically searching his phone
I may be reading a different article I
just want to get that [ __ ] conquer -
congressman's name spokesman Josh
earnest said Thursday that despite
reservations Obama is set to sign less
legislation to fund nearly the entire
government through the end of the budget
year September 30th district voters
approved an initiative November 4th to
allow possession of up to two ounces of
pot or up to three mature plants for
personal use but here we go
language inserted by Republicans in the
spending bill would bar the city from
moving forward with legalization ernest
says the President believes Congress
shouldn't interfere with the will of
City voters on marijuana and other
issues Obama supports statehood for the
district so they wrote a new budget
proposal by they looks like the
Republicans have submitted this right
but in the wording they also try to
block the legalization of cannabis in
the District of Columbia so just in the
city not in the state correct like you
know I know it's a district but e'en on
I'm saying it's like it's the whole
state from what I read it's gonna be the
whole state Washington DC I was down
with DC being legalized he says he's
cool he didn't have to pass that budget
find that [ __ ] name can he go out
can he just he's the president bro why
doesn't he just [ __ ] erase that line
[Music]
he decriminalize the least before he
gets out you know because he was so
I'll leave it alone I'll leave it alone
and then the raids and stuff what he was
here and he's still like there's a war
on drugs still and this then the other
and you know it's it's one of those
things that I feel like if he's gonna do
anything that gives him a like on the
way out it'll be something along that
line if he can just bring it down to a
new substance law
you know he's spokesperson says he
believes Congress shouldn't interfere
with the will of City voters on
marijuana and other issues and he
supports statehood what it does is it
blocks any any congressional or or City
money being used to implement the
program so ultimatum yeah we don't need
your money they'll gladly give it to you
by the droves have you not what happen
what happened to voting and then what
the voters vote for happening like what
happened it's like your parents doing
you go to a house party on Saturday when
they damn well know you'll be in Texas I
hope you guys in DC you get to smoke
your recreational legal cannabis so they
will have a store but they can still you
know I mean fight the good fight guys
you know what they're doing is it sounds
like they're encouraging the gray market
you know a good place to be a Colorado
that gray market is getting squeezed out
I know pot super illegal or expensive
what's not super illegal it's super
[ __ ] expensive at the dispensaries
but it seems like from hanging out in
the shop as much as I have been lately
there are a lot of people that would
rather just go they go to destory shop
from these ARS there are like 12 strains
on this shot on the shelf at the shop
you don't get choice honestly in my
opinion it's too expensive but that's
because I'm a spoiled [ __ ] I grow my
own herb I know what it costs I've been
paying really low prices for several
years now and to go there and
double a little more than double what
I'm used to paying but it's legal but
and it's for anybody sit in a cushy
comfy chair and listen to decent reggae
music they play good reggae there too
that has nothing to do with me
you see these cozy little chairs and
chill out and it's the chill environment
and if you don't want to wait for your
dude to show up if you just want to grab
an eighth on the way home from work if
you don't want it because deals are
sketchy in a parking lot and [ __ ] you
don't want to be doing that anymore
just go to that it's I could see the
black and ivory markets just be and I'm
telling they would be they would be
totally wiped out I feel if it was
accessible in every street corner you
know almost like a damn liquor store
where there's you know 13 of them in
town spread out instead of you know 14
of them out there you guys in states
that are just about to legalize her that
are pushing it you got to get on top of
[ __ ] the day it pops you got to get your
shop open because you have to start
making enough money to comply with the
regulations that are coming because now
that Colorado has set the standard other
places are just kind of adopting that
they're just saying Colorado's doing
this they kind of set it around that
they're not making the same mistakes as
well they already have a template you're
getting what we used to call here was
the wild wild west that I talked about
Jesse knows the Wild West real well good
olders grew the quarter pounds and the
houses rent other houses grow weed in
there take that weed to shops and sell
it to the shop straight up for cash ID
well yeah the backpack full of pounds if
I had a variety if I had five or six
quarter pounds I could sell all of those
quarter pounds for like 700 750 1/4
pound dude and walk out with cash back
in the day yeah it was a handful of
shops here in town and in the area that
really I guess the only one of them
survived but um well too but uh you know
that's they didn't have girl rooms we
helped me date they got stuff from guys
like me and Jeff yeah and it's totally
legal at the time I had a that was all
you know medical and isn't that what
people just went out and got the red
cards and they you know that's that's
what they did yeah but in that kind of
squeezed the grey market here did it not
like in town just because accessible
when we made our dispensary public we
had a participatory that we kept
slightly private we didn't let a lot of
people know about it wasn't a little
kind of thing in private clubs or
nothing but eventually we decided let's
take this to the bigger big room in our
retail store and just kind of show that
this is what we're doing we drop prices
in this town dramatically it was four
hundred bucks an ounce for any kind of
kind but for awhile around here ten or
twelve years ago four hundred bucks an
ounce that Sour Diesel that we smoked
400 bucks out stood for 28 grams no love
you'd sell it for 60 bucks an eighth and
they'd be three point four and then we
got the shop going and when we first did
announce us were 350 just to keep us in
business cuz we were selling out you
know and then we had we had a big
outdoor harvest and we dropped down
bounces down to 320 and then our
patients were paying 280 and then we
were seeing better quality because a lot
of our stuff was outdoor we're growing a
large outdoor and we saw the competitors
the two shops that are still around they
were getting good indoor and stuff I
couldn't grow enough to keep it on our
shelves we had a downtown location we're
banging you so we dropped prices to 200
bucks an ounce at one point and that
[ __ ] up the whole town I was getting
hate mail hate calls death threats like
people were mad at me because I was the
one I was the face of that shop they
thought it was all me kind of was but
yeah we pissed off the town and drop
prices now score a good ounce in this
town for 200 bucks and people still want
to find cheaper houses they're out there
but for the good dank it's a dispensary
price is usually you know depending on
where you go it's about 450 an ounce
right now on the spot I think for a good
day counts
they got some good urban poison though I
would if I had to smoke one that's what
I can go for I mean I've thought about
it one more news article I mentioned the
part about Seth Rogen we may get to that
we may not you guys Seth Rogen wanted to
come to Denver into a smoke out for his
new movie they wouldn't let him smoke
that's kind of the quick version you
can't smoke in a public place anymore he
had to serve tequila shitty alright so
this one is cool Department of Justice
ruling okay we'll try to read that one
we will since you just said that Indian
tribes can legalize pot on their lands
in the sub headline if tribes can
balance all the potential social issues
it could be a really huge opportunity
says Seattle attorney Anthony Broadman
whose firm represents tribal governments
throughout the West so this article was
published on December 11th it's written
by Jeff Bernard and NGO SIA was Nakia
from The Associated Press
it says the US Department of Justice
said Thursday that American Indian
tribes can grow and sell marijuana on
their lands as long as they follow the
same federal conditions laid out for
states that have legalized the drug
Oregon US attorney Amanda Marshall said
Thursday the announcement addresses
questions raised by tribes about how
legalization of pot in states like
Oregon Washington and Colorado would
apply to Indian lands only three tribes
have expressed interest in growing and
selling marijuana said Marshall who
co-chaired a group that developed the
policy one is in California one in
Washington and one state in the Midwest
that she did not name that's been the
primary message tribes are getting to us
as US attorneys Marshall sent from
Portland what will the u.s. as federal
partners do to assist tribes and
protecting our children and families are
tribal businesses our tribal housing how
you help us combat marijuana abuse in
Indian country or Indian County when
states are no longer there to partner
with us
marijuana abuse do you guys see a lot of
that over here yeah for grams the sister
hash I don't need that trash that makes
me laugh because I'm thinking about what
conical does get abused I was gonna ask
you how do you feel about that - you
know since they're allowed to do
everything that they're you know now
they're they're making money in
collecting tax for the state but that
all that land is tax free like I don't
I'm with that you know like we've
[ __ ] stolen the whole West from him
but but if you're gonna sell it to the
public as like Indian grown herb you
should at least pay a tax on the land
that's it's doing that you know I'm
saying like you for your plot this
really approaches that I'm sure that's
the fight they've been fighting for many
years is they won't let them have any
kind of businesses on there that's gonna
prove profitable you know when they open
a casino or something like that it's not
on Indian land it's on you know some
outskirt land that they've had to buy
like separately in Palin tax on that's
that's been one of the large arguments
that I've I've atleast seen over the
past couple years I'm giving you credit
just made a point and maybe 4444 done
episode 44 hop because it sounds like
we're razzing each other we just started
cos were bros sorry don't get mad at us
I'm gonna give a [ __ ] wedgie in a
minute whoa so hard that you can read
Haynes on his forehead you ever have
that kind just pull it up
that's gonna be really weird for you
ladies and gentlemen this is the episode
with too much information
yeah all right I'm gonna try to read
this article with the throw-up that's in
my house
marshal warned warned the announcement
is not a green light to tribal
authorities and that marijuana is still
illegal under federal law the US
government's prosecution priorities
involve pot related gang activity
violence sales to kids and trafficking
will continue she said problems could
arise for tribes with lands in states
that still outlaw marijuana due to the
likelihood that marijuana could be
transported or sold outside tribal
boundaries she added Seattle attorney
Anthony Broadman whose firm represents
tribal governments throughout the West
said the announcement represents a
potential for enormous economic
developer development tool here yeah if
tribes can balance all the potential
social issues it could be a really huge
opportunity I think they'll be able to
handle it
there's want to read this one next
paragraph in the night we can rant on
the part that's the elephant in the room
but those social issues are monumental
Indian tribes have been decimated by
drug abuse Broadman said tribal
regulations of pot are going to have to
dovetail with tribal values making sure
marijuana isn't a scours like alcohol or
tobacco I'm gonna sound racist maybe
generalization we all know that natives
have trouble with alcohol not all of
them but the ones that do really [ __ ]
do alcohols a horrible thing that ruins
tons of lives not just Native Americans
the problem is that you concentrate them
in one area and then you look at them
from afar and then you notice
similarities and stereotypes just as in
any race or okay we've seen that it
works Washington hasn't blown up yet
once I try to replace the alcohol abuse
on the reservation with some cannabis
enjoyment work yeah and maybe they're
the problems that are associated with
alcohol abuse I've got a whole list of
podcast planned we could talk about for
five look at Alaska almost in that same
way I mean
like Alaska Utah Arizona New Mexico
Oklahoma Colorado all those tribes like
I mean really really bad problems or I
mean not to sound like a dick but I mean
I've been around a reservation or two so
um
but yeah no I just I think could be an
awesome development thing for sure and
they're [ __ ] right about these taxes
the tax part here is this tribe selling
marijuana may not be subject to state
and local taxes allowing them to
undercut off reservation sales also
maybe not taxes at twenty five percent
of the price of pot also in Colorado but
Allison Holcomb
yes a primary drafter of Washington
State's legalization measure said most
people in larger states won't want to
drive to far-flung
reservations to buy pot you're crazy
dude imagine that Indian dank weed do
what was it was it here on the podcast
that we had this statistic where we got
thirty million dollars just in
recreational sales that came from out of
state and then every time I go in and
talk to the security guard at any
dispensary taxes [ __ ] taxes I
guarantee you fifty percent of that was
Texas I'm gonna go kind of fast cuz
we're approaching an hour the
combination I said that wrong
combination sorry I apologize in
Washington State recently passed a ban
on marijuana on the reservation and is
trying to halt state regulated pot sales
and grows on lands off the reservation
where it still holds hunting and fishing
rights so they don't want you growing
where they can hunt and fish with
actually a conflict with that or well
yeah no no I just don't know if there's
actually anyone that wants to grow in
their hunting grounds it actually says
Cooper Valley tribe in Northern
California has battled illegal pot
plantations on its reservation where
they caused environmental issues but you
know that's illegal at any rate there
are 566 tribes around the country
recognized I'm gonna go fast and scam
recognized by federal government there's
gonna be a lot of consulting happening
yes for sure
limited resources in a vast amount of
territory to cover federal prosecutors
will not prosecute minor cases
yay tribal policy is based on the so
called Cole memo named after the Deputy
Attorney General who wrote it in which
Justice Department said the federal
government wouldn't intervene as long as
legalization states tightly regulate the
drug and take steps to keep it from
children criminal cartels and federal
property in all the memo said US
Attorney's reserve the right to
prosecute for eight issues sales to kids
marijuana proceeds going to criminal
enterprises shipping marijuana to other
states where it is illegal guys quit
doing that [ __ ] violence drug driving
and other health issues drawing
marijuana on public lands and possession
of marijuana on federal property
so hopefully eventually they're gonna
let the Indians the natives you guys the
natives will be able to grow on their
land and maybe have their own Indian
dispensary I think they grow some date
bro that's what they do
culturals agricultural the people they
would have the dank I'm sure there would
may be ones that would abuse it just
like anywhere else but for the most part
I bet they would be real respectful
about it and I'm saying I mean it's if
you have a not have they not like use
that as ceremony or buy me the perfect
thing that's what the wrost is used for
meditation for a reason the three of us
abused cannabis if we were medical
patients dad we just took was we are the
problems were causing we're loud mouths
with microphones I have to nap on the
couch the other night because I consume
to me dad's like that you know we the
[ __ ] trash free labor cell
yep all right so I'm gonna quickly we're
gonna go over an hour guys I hope you
can stick with us thanks for hanging in
for the random chatter episode which is
might what might be what I named it so
Seth Rogen I've got two articles here
there was an article posted on December
8th and then there's a follow-up article
posted let me click it to read the next
date this one came out December 9th so
the night of the 8th must have been the
event Seth Rogen says he will this is
from Ricardo Baca Baca at the Cannabis
Seth Rogen says he will screen his new
film Monday night in a Denver movie
theater filled with marijuana smoke and
hundreds of his fans but well movie
theater hotbox actually happened while
Rogen has said he thinks it should
happen the City of Denver's executive
director of Marijuana Policy thinks the
screening should obey Colorado law sans
- marijuana smoke so he planned on
debuting his new movie at the oriental
theater and he tweeted about it actually
he said we're gonna all get stoned in
the theater and that was kind of a bad
idea because that can't really happen
because of the rules here in Colorado
they are super strict about that kind of
[ __ ] so first Rogen started tweeting
about getting high inside the Colorado
theater with his fans then the host
venue the SCI Film Center on East Colfax
Avenue contacted Sony to tell them the
audience couldn't line up inside their
space as it would be against Colorado
law then Sony told the film center the
evening was no longer happening the
Kansas cannabis reported that Rogen
responded via Twitter that a Colorado
screening would still happen only at a
different theater the old video is
acting lame so we got a new one Rogen
tweeted so where will Rogen land tonight
and remember this is from a few nights
ago the oriental theater owner Scott
libera who dude we've had some rage and
dab parties in the oriental theater
that's where the first dabs of denver
event was it's worth of seafood cup used
to be home there's a video on the IRA
Genetics YouTube channel of me taking a
fat dab inside the first dab in there as
far as I know I started that party up at
the big old dab
he says tonight's video is private and
closed to the general public and to
promoters who regularly both the North
Denver room for a pot friendly comedy
shows confirmed that Rogen screening is
scheduled to happen there on Monday
night so I set the oriental theater
owner of Denver pot shop Denver relief
and comedy production group sex pot
comedy told the Cannabis we
know if there will be any sort of
consumption or anything I'm gonna skip a
couple of things we're gonna scroll
through so he was planning to come and
watch this new movie which I still
haven't read the name of they have not
advertised the name of his movie in this
article at all it's an interview I think
so I don't watch TV so I don't see the
commercial sorry so there's no provision
in amendment 64 for the on premise
consumption of marijuana Kilroy said
that could have been put in a minute
sixty four but it wasn't so the voters
did not vote for it
so Kilroy said the Denver Police
Department and the city's Department of
excise and license have historically
contacted businesses advertising pot
friendly parties ahead of time to talk
about potential violations we've
educated people on what the wise said
Kilroy and we've gotten compliance
generally but asked if they were aware
of Rogen's event and without even
mentioning the oriental as a possible
location
gilroys office told the cannabis that
Denver police would reach out to the
Oriental theaters owners
sometime Monday so that was the original
article he was gonna come he was gonna
puff right so on the next publishing day
the ninth Jack brown from the cannabis
said his article High Line no weed
plenty of tequila at the interview in
Denver with Seth Rogen so there was one
thing everyone could smell Monday night
at the Denver screening of the interview
tequila so that sucks dude they had to
not puff and they had to serve tequila
what would happen if we replaced every
dab we've taken on the podcast and
before the podcast with a shot of
tequila how do you think our night would
have gone I probably pissed myself by
now and thrown up somewhere because
that's what tequila makes me do now
would have been really mad and violent
right yeah honestly you think you give
me [ __ ] about dabs
dude I'm even more of a [ __ ] when it
comes to liquor beer I can I can deal
with it drink tequila does not mean
you're a [ __ ]
so this guy with my lady pounds the rest
of the bottle yeah yeah so the article
goes on this is when I ran into Rogan on
the top floor of the theater at
Northwest Denver he was adamant that the
show was not how he imagined how he had
imagined at the December 8th event which
had been hyped by Rogen on social media
as a 420 friendly affair the city said
they shut us down if there was any
smoking he said with the bottle of
juarez tequila in hand but I can't
control what you guys do
says Rogan couldn't maybe but a Rogen
couldn't but maybe the what's that Kadri
quatre I've never seen that word the big
ass group of Secret Service asked
security personnel definitely enforce
the Colorado clean indoor air rules
asking several people in my section to
leave during the screening for using
vape pens they're also rumoured to be a
number of undercover police officers in
the crowd in case there was any smoking
taking place as this is the [ __ ] that
happens in Colorado you think you're
gonna go somewhere a puff theater places
it does happen and we keep our mouths
shut about concern like doing it there
that's kind of true you don't see
pictures of people standing around
circles and sidewalks you know like it's
just not something that we take pictures
of if you're here and you're cool and we
know you and stuff we'll grab you and
take you to a place don't be shy well
you'll definitely come with us you know
the cops don't go in the mountains here
spots we found some really cool
adventures so as the duo took stage
Rogen started things off by saying [ __ ]
the police which elicited big cheers
from the pro-pot crowd audience
questions ranged from actual threats by
North Korea over the film because Rogen
having North Korea threatened nuclear
war is not ideal yet we won't even go
into that part so Rogen made sure to
correct a question about smoking bowls
he said first I smoke joints five to
seven a day on a night that was light on
both joints and bowls more were left
simply handing him various pop products
for later the state is famously that
famously legalized it most of the weed
smoking so repetitious so repetitiously
that's a good [ __ ] words took place
in a side alley next to the theater
maybe next year Rogen exclaimed the way
things are trending with pot consumption
enforcement
perhaps next year looks even worse yeah
they're really cracking down we can't
puff here in Colorado you have to be in
a private house they want you at home
smoking your pot it's pretty much the
only place they want you doing it there
are a few hotels sorry do our favorite
hotel that we drive past that we see
that advertising I don't remember the
name it's in Manitou Springs it's right
outside of Manitou as we head back from
the Mont a factor you see the 420
friendly sign they've taken down to 420
friendly part they're probably still 420
friendly but they probably had to just
quit advertising such yeah the micro
tell Micro tell here employment is over
there what's up Dee if you're listening
shut up bro shout out to Big B and
little D yep I think we stayed there
when we first got over this way they
only have a couple rooms that are
actually 420 friendly right if you say
no then there's there's measurements to
take but seven minutes to check out all
of our sponsors guys pretty soon we'll
have Keene Cola back on the show to talk
more about organics we have a couple
questions about map and DAP for him um
we're gonna do eventually we're gonna do
an additives lesson I promise you since
I have taken this new job at the spot
being the master grower I do promise you
that it will not deter or detract from
the podcast we're still gonna do our
best to put out kick-ass podcasts it may
actually help me do some hydro lessons
for you because everything we're doing
there is on large-scale commercial hydro
I get to kind of expand my hydro
knowledge on additives I may have said
that I don't know if I read that line
like what to add to your [ __ ] during
what week so that you know when to boost
it we talked about basic news and we
need to talk about additives we're
working towards episode 50 also 50 is
gonna be fun you just be like a recap
weren't we just like celebrating 25 I
think so
25 weeks ago so if you guys have been
listening for a long time you've got
some favorite moments of the show or
some highlights or something and a
highlight reel
message me and let me know when that was
and we can talk about it we'll kind of
reminisce on episode 50 see who we can't
get to the show maybe I can set up like
22 microphones and get it's ever been on
onto the show all at once or sometimes
have another spot like you you didn't
you know the brickyard a public place
maybe we can do that there is let's give
away something free supplies is gonna
step it up and give away something
awesome like I'm sure you got to make
mine was for you man honestly and you
know like bender of course he's keeping
the servers running yeah hey Fisher cut
faster because he was like I just set
him up with the microphone and just walk
away he's a rapper he's a rapper your
voice on recording yes over and over he
just likes to complain about everything
so when he goes to work his like say my
family friend almost fool construction
talk on you know they'd love to piss
each other the [ __ ] makes it fun makes
work fun oh it does all right don't kill
each other at work you guys what a fish
shut up let me know
[Music]
yeah you know flex Spanish so Ulysses
from Pueblo alright I did most of my
shout outs at the beginning I want to
thank you guys for coming on number 44
bro hey thank you fan like I was sitting
at home eating dinner so I'm always
landing a podcast I really had [ __ ]
planned out it doesn't sound like it he
brought him because at least he had
something going on he messaged me around
6:00 with podcast just gonna let him do
his night but he wanted to so I'm so
glad he came thank you guys for coming
always make sure you listen all the way
up to episode number 50 guys it sounds
like hi grow is gonna have surprises for
us yeah well I'm taking the light setup
so I don't know depends on shipping and
stuff like that we'll figure it out
though so email me some of your favorite
moments and stuff guys what you want to
talk about an episode 50 we'll reminisce
we'll have a lot of fun on number 50
we'll take a lot of dabs will be the one
when I take like because I need to
retire this big-ass dad phase that's
been going on in my life it's it hurts
now to kill me don't we play like fiddle
music or something you know like some
violin soft instrumental [ __ ] to the
body factor I got some loose-leaf
montana bag to take last time super kind
dude the next time I go there I'm a
straight from the Monty I might retch I
may try a chai my buddy that works there
last time I was putting honey in my
bhante and he gave me tips come here and
I went over there he's making himself a
chai like for him and he poured a little
bit of it into a little to go cup for me
he goes try this it's the chai and he
was just like get out of here take this
love it I was on my way out and dude it
was the dankness I may need to pay roots
it's nine o'clock how much how much
crack was in it I'm down I'm gonna call
I don't have
like a milk jug or something they
actually like make sure oh they make
everything everything the Monty factory
Manitou Springs you guys it's my little
secret if you go there tell them hey I
heard about this place from the iGrow
culture podcast and there's a flyer
there's a flyer back there this is how
it's gonna go out - guys there's no
editing in the shows lately I'm kind of
proud of it
[Music]
my tremor friends Mike and Adam here it
still is over Grover please do listen to
this part because it means a lot to me I
like you here till the end iTunes go -
if you can figure it out or email me
send me a message let me know what you
think if you can go to iTunes find the
review section give me a five star
rating type in a comment let me know
what you think of the show big shout out
to our friend Fred Garvin for sending me
a message today or commenting there let
me know what you think I'll read it
on the show I really will I read Fred's
comment today just to prove it I don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is archived at IRA Genetics Colorado
comm make sure you follow us on Twitter
Instagram and Facebook just search for I
grow culture follow I read genetics on
Instagram I am now at 10,000 followers
yeah thank you guys if you're interested
in sponsoring the podcast or if you have
a product you'd like us to review send
me an email and I grow a culture at
hotmail.com I'll get you all the info
you need we still need our own theme
song we're in the middle of a name
change so if you want to wait if you
want to make it the girl from your heart
podcast theme song and/or logo and
appreciate it big shout outs manager
Spence extra big shout out to hydro
indoor growing supplies thanks
good for listening until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me all right podcast world that was
episodes 42 43 and 44 of what used to be
known as the iGrow culture podcast now
known as the girl from your heart
podcast I hope you enjoyed it I would
love it if you reach out to me via email
via Twitter or on Facebook and let me
know what you think of these old
episodes you can find me on Facebook at
the growth from your heart podcast you
can find me on twitter at g f YH podcast
and of course you can send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen I will be back Monday with a
brand new episode I look forward to you
joining me then and it's all next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
it's been for seven weeks
you
beyond description your favorite well
the music
[Music]
you