hey everyone this is Davin brainy and
you're listening to the growth from your
heard podcast
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 211 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right a for your new
grower if you're a professional grower
here at new smoker or a dedicated dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff phone to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
and the mystic roots Ben to let him use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew ladies and gentlemen
across the table from me is white Mike
welcome to the show bro oh man thanks
for coming take some time away from the
new kid yeah how's he doing bro how old
is he this week almost almost two is the
terrible twos kicking in so much wait
till you get to the [ __ ] terrorizing
threes he think two is bad three is when
it kicks in dude right all right we're
not gonna talk about kids a whole
podcast that was it I wanted to get it
out of the way I do respect Mike for
coming to taking time away from his
family he had had to walk away from that
little boy who's a handsome little
[ __ ] I'm sure he's fun to play with it
is it is a lot of fun my kids 13 now and
it's a totally different kind of fun now
she can talk [ __ ] to me like troll each
other a little bit and send each other
emojis of elephants farting in monkeys
faces and stuff nice it's a fun
relationship with my kids shot it's my
kiddo if she ever listens to this damn
podcast she has no reason to listen she
doesn't care about cannabis at all
that's enough kid talk let's talk about
ganja bro you okay after those dabs I'm
good man shout it to my friends at
apothecary extracts and also my friends
at elevations the dispensary in Colorado
Springs on Razorback today I was at work
and I received a text message that there
was a secret drop of some lemon Jeffrey
high cannabinoid full-spectrum extract
and also some high terpene full-spectrum
extract zipped up there after work and I
bought
[ __ ] all of it shot it to my friends
at elevations for they didn't even put
it on the shelf they waited for me to
get there and I scooped it all up just a
moment ago I took a DAB
so I heated the banger quite hot and I
took a dab of THC a I dumped some THC a
crystals on there and then after that I
dumped way too much weight like I come
out dude and then I gave it like a
little nudge and it just just poured out
and I was like fook was the only thing
on my brain but I was like I'm gonna
smoke that with the terpenes I poured a
big fat dollop of Heitor fiend full
spectrum extract onto the nail then on a
dabber I had some high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract also with some
ambrosia and all of it was made from
lemon jeffery except the THC a was made
from another stream but everything else
came from some lemon jeffery the rig
still smells like lemons you can just
pull through the rig and it tastes like
lemon candy without any hash on it I've
been talking about the high cannabinoid
and high terpene full-spectrum ACTRA
extract now that I've got some of this
high terpene full-spectrum extract in my
hand let's talk a little bit about this
let's describe this little vial of stuff
to people it's a half DRAM vials the
unit of measure this size would be if
you don't know what that is how tall is
that mic without the lid it's half to
three quarters of an inch tall and the
lid is almost a third of the size of the
whole bottle and it holds a gram of
terpene high terpene full cannabinoid
full this is hard to say hi to repeat
full spectrum extracts in this one
container I was very well reasonably
priced does it look like really runny
honey possibly yeah or maybe thick
vegetable oil or thin vegetable oil
runny honey is a good description that
hits the color right on the mark and
it's way too runny for for actual honey
but it's got a light motor oil it's like
some 5w30 but real nice and clear it was
funny watching you try to dab it in
motion
well I poured it out of that container
into a banger a quartz banger and it put
in there and when I when the dad here
this is lacrosse yeah yeah there's a lot
of heat and a lot of liquid happening
but when the dad when it hit that it
fell
I think effervescent is the word my face
was filled with the flavors of lemon
Jeffrey there was I reached the maximum
of flavor that your face can take my
face was like that's such a good flavor
and then we go thats way too much of it
yeah I've seen you take huge dabs before
and you don't usually find them like
that yeah I had to keep I wanted to
finish the dad but I had to keep forcing
my lungs to like inhale that and they
were like but dude like it's like if you
put vapor rub on the tip of your nose
and then tried to take a DAB you're like
I'm having a hard time my lungs don't
want to breathe that in real heavily
right it was a great dad then I gave
Mike a similar dab I didn't put as many
things on there because I don't want to
kill Mike we're shooting for a tighter
more succeed show tonight so not getting
super baked was part of the goal
hopefully there aren't as many rambles
hopefully there's a little we're already
off to a rambly start yeah had to
explain these dads these dad's work is
so much fun folks we're so spoiled here
you should come visit Colorado take a
few dabs and then go home don't move
here it's crowded everything sucks it's
traffic you don't want to live here
shout-out to my friends in the mystic
roots band yeah there's a rule now if
you want to move to Colorado you have to
trick someone into moving somewhere else
yes to people and don't don't drive on
i-25 70 promise that you won't go
anywhere near i-25 or i-70 because it's
already packed I had to drive up to
Springs today to go pick up this hash
and it should be a 45-minute Drive
thanks to the the lovely weather and
surprise turns and [ __ ] traffic in
Colorado it took me closer to an hour
and 15 there are rules that you have to
be inside the dispensary by a certain
time you have to be rung up by a certain
time I look like an [ __ ] because I
was pushing the [ __ ] lights like if I
didn't know what I want already they
might have been mad at me for going in
there at that last very second right
they've got to be closed all the way up
by what seven yes they have you last
person's got to be out the door locked
up by 6:55 writings if you're not in the
building by 6:20 you're a dick six 30s
yeah it was 632 ish when I was getting
out of the car and I got off work at
5:00 and just zipped up there so it took
me all that time to get there I didn't
stop for gas at in pee and everything
needed a couple of times
yeah good dab is working it made me
sweaty it made me made me very euphoric
Lehigh and it made me chatting still
taste it it's like lemon starburst like
I ate a whole bunch of lemon starburst
earlier and I've just got that wonderful
little after flavor you know the the
side of the lemon meringue pie where
it's a little more whipped cream and a
little less lemon that's kind of the
flavor they left in my mouth I think
nice
yeah lemon meringue dabs um I couldn't
have gotten my hash today if I did not
get my medical marijuana card renewed
yesterday now my card hasn't expired yet
but everybody in Colorado has been
trained to be very proactive on getting
their cards renewed because in the past
it has taken [ __ ] 10 to 12 weeks to
get your card when you send in the
paperwork it takes 12 weeks to get your
card back the CD Phe the the State
Department that sends them out just got
hammered in the press like a month and a
half two months ago because they were
backed up again and so I'm glad to see
that that backlog is gone yes they're
catching up I think they're about two
weeks behind right now but that's not
too far the problem the problem in that
is so let's say not everybody has a lot
of extra money you're running out of
funds you can't go to the Medical
Marijuana doc that's probably the bottom
of several people's lists you got lights
you got the [ __ ] car payment you got
the rent you got whatever food you're
gonna eat this week maybe somewhere on
there's the weed doctor at the end of
the month there's a lot of telling
information in the order of those items
folks lights blah
sometimes the lights are more expensive
than the rent in some instances I was
that usually people list stuff in order
of personal importance let's just crack
it we you're like man I can have lights
outside I don't need red alright we got
sidetracked already but soaps if you get
your medical marijuana card renewed at
the time that it expires there's going
to be a long time waiting before your
replacement card comes in and you're not
allowed to renew your card 30 days
before it expires so if it takes 32 days
for that card to come in your two days
without your medical marijuana card
which means if you're growing an
elevated count or an increased count
which your doctor can give you if they
do choose to do so
based on your condition you are now
illegal for a few days until your card
comes you cannot shop in a dispensary if
you need medicine until that card comes
it [ __ ] a lot of things up and it was
uncool it was just shitty it wasn't
working it was on it wasn't organized it
wasn't right there was a period of time
where it was on the backlog was almost a
year yeah which in practice meant you
got a free weed card for a year but at
that time you were allowed to use the
temporary pizza shop they had they had
to have different rules then now you
can't shop with temporary paperwork now
they're like bringing a purple card or
get the [ __ ] out well the the new
restrictions on when you can renew in
where like when you can shop if you
don't have your active card with you our
part of the reason that the CD phe took
heat in the press because because lots
of people need these cards to buy their
medicine and if the backlog is longer
than the allowed period to do it you're
screwing people badly absolutely and
people would come into the dispensary
when I was with green and healthy I
would take deliveries or I'd be there
shopping and people would come in with
their paperwork like hey I've been
waiting can I shop and the bud tenders
would have to say sorry he can't come in
here they don't have to turn them away
and that looks like [ __ ] they don't come
back even though it's the state's rule
and a rule that the dispensaries have to
follow to stay in business it pisses off
the consumer because they don't have
their medicine and they have to blame it
on somebody
and so they blame that dispensary that
won't let them shop there and they don't
come back you lose their business
because of their paperwork yep
so the good thing there is a positive
now I went to the medical marijuana
doctor yesterday my appointment was at
1:20 it's the weed doc so around 3
o'clock I finally saw the [ __ ] doctor
that's the bad that's the worst part
about going to the weed doctor is he
make an appointment for I made my
appointment for one they sent me my
reminder saying that it was at 120 I
showed up at 115 and at about 3 o'clock
I finally saw the doc yeah the
appointment took honestly 5 or 10
minutes because I've seen this guy 10
times we have a relationship wheeze a
bonafide we've got a bona fide
relationship he's like yeah yeah
basically the paperwork is way different
now there are way more specific
questions they ask how much cannabis you
use what type you use how you grow it
how much you yield per plant how many
hard
so you get per year.if that's gonna be
turned into edibles or concentrates how
many inch of how much of that you're
gonna use per day per hour they ask a
lot of [ __ ] and then also there is a
caregiver registry that you cannot
become a caregiver now on somebody's
paperwork unless you have a caregiver
registry number so if you're a caregiver
in Colorado you got to get your ass on
the caregiver registry that's easy just
go to the Colorado Department of Public
Health and Environment thing type in
marijuana or just Google Colorado
caregiver registry all that [ __ ] will
pop make it really easy to find so I did
the basic paperwork and the lady behind
the counter goes he got enough of that I
can finish that out for you and because
it's all just a cut and paste she typed
it into the computer from there and then
filled out all the rest of the forms for
me just by cutting and pasting and then
I pulled out my phone and went to a
website that she gave me
I created a username I got an email I
logged in through my email on my phone I
created a template there was a draft
I saw the doc he approved all my stuff I
took my stamped paperwork to a desk with
the lady who took my credit card and ran
it through the Department of Public
Health and public and Health and
Environment website charged me 16
dollars and ten cents for the card
swiping to the state I paid the doc a
fee to get my doc visit plus my plant
count and then she turned in all my
paperwork by clicking a button on the
thing and then today one o'clock I got
an email saying thank you your new card
is activated so I've got a brand new
medical marijuana card two days it took
less than 24-hours to have my card
renewed and activated that's impressive
yeah I can print it off if I need to but
some dispensaries will take it right off
of my phone they say they should not but
some places will take it right off of my
phone I should print that out but my old
one doesn't expire for a month still
I've got three weeks right you were on
when I met the office one day at work
and I think about it I'm just gonna
print that [ __ ] out then I've got my new
card yeah I I made sure that I've got a
reminder setting my phone for a month
before my explains well the the reason
you need a month reminder now is because
the docs are so busy yep it takes a
month just to get into them Medical
Marijuana docum
are trying to receive an extended plant
count or any sort of special treatment
or anything like that a lot of people
ask just because I'm I got asked this
question today
I've got a friend with a child who is
under the age of 18 and is experiencing
some conditions and symptoms that would
be very easily treated by the use of
medical cannabis and I feel that it's
the way to go and they were like we're
ready to do it how do we do this they've
been apprehensive for a while because of
the law but with a card there's no
reason not to do it if you were under
the age of 18 you need to be seen by two
doctors to get your medical marijuana
card so you're gonna have to pay two
Doc's and I don't know of many places
that do two Doc's at one time the place
I go only has one doc on site there are
places send me an email if you really
need the info and I'll help you out but
I'm not gonna give any companies a shout
out on the show like that right now I
think the younger the patient the more
stringent it is if you for the the
really young kids coming to Colorado
it's got to be to specialists which can
be incredibly difficult for a lot of
people there are two people that two
places that I think may do it I just
want to make sure so I'm gonna research
that after the show I'll contact them
tomorrow or something it's not too hard
to just call them to local cable
information we have ones in Springs ones
in Pueblo just ask them if they've got
two Doc's on-site should I just say the
names dude I don't want to advertise but
it's helping people [ __ ] it I'm gonna
say I'm gonna say just to help people I
don't care these people aren't paying me
you can check out relaxed clarity and
Pueblo they may have two doctors on-site
in a place called Medi Val in Colorado
Springs often has two docs on-site I
don't get paid for that I just want to
help you guys out if you need [ __ ] if
trying to get a kid a medical marijuana
card there's no reason to [ __ ] hold
anything back I'll share that info
that's that's worth the [ __ ] one kid
getting their card right one little kid
not having a seizure
it's worth that [ __ ] free shout-out to
those places Tom Ross - Jeff sent you
maybe they'll [ __ ] do something if
not whatever but getting your card is
it's the process with the doc is just as
hard extended plant counts are harder if
you're relying on going to the doc for
an extended plant count you don't have a
bona fide relationship with your medical
marijuana doctor or you're not getting
your medical marijuana card from your
regular physician which is always an
option if you have the balls to ask them
and you don't want to lose your patient
doctor relationship with some people
because some doctor will drop you
just for admitting that you use cannabis
or the idea so make sure you have a good
doc first but if you want to ascend a
plank out you need paperwork you have to
have some sort of proof that you've got
some sort of condition that the use of
medical cannabis would improve the
quality of your life that's got to fall
in the list of qualifying conditions so
but once you get that part done getting
it taken care of like registering with
the state and [ __ ] if you know how to
point and click on a Facebook page you
can register it and get your card done
I'm thrilled this streamlined it it
takes first couple processes we're I
mean it was so painfully slow I remember
the first time I waited in line in the
snow outside of a building in Denver it
took me about three hours to get there
because I drove in the snow and then we
waited outside of the building for about
another three hours saw the doc for
seriously seven seconds he goes what's
your claim to fame was what he asked he
doesn't say what ails you what hurts you
does what's your claim to fame and I
said man my knees are [ __ ] and he goes
sit down and he put a hand under my left
thigh and he said may I touch you and I
said yeah doc he put his hand under my
left thigh and he goes move your leg up
and I moved my leg up oh that's terrible
and he just went to writing that was my
first medical marijuana doctor
experience hears like yes is your money
green yes sir my money's green
I will take your money here is your card
and he handed me my paperwork and he
goes the building right there at the
green door is a dispensary you get a 30
percent discount for shopping here today
thank you have a great day and just send
me out the [ __ ] way and then they
give you a bundle of papers and you have
to figure out which ones to mail which
ones to keep which ones to post on your
garden then you mail off [ __ ] and then
you hope that this little certified mail
thing comes back and then it would
finally come back you a took four
[ __ ] ever for that thing to come back
it would come back and then like [ __ ]
six or eight weeks later you'd get this
crinkled up envelope from the state you
need to open it up and it would either
say oh you wrote your middle initial a
little weird it doesn't look like an M
it looks like a crooked end so you don't
get your card you have to fill out all
this paperwork again take it to another
notary and then send it back and we'll
try again or on the used to wreck people
was use the wrong color ink yeah you can
use black ink
you screw up some more your hand shakes
a little bit so you just slap a line
through it and finish whatever no be
just voided that whole page or whole
application [ __ ] yeah and then you've
got to wait 2 3 months for them to open
it the two months for them to process it
the week for it to get mailed back to
you - no the open oh now you've got
start over yeah or you could get the
card the mail yep or your card shows up
finally and then those cards the ink
wore off of them so a lot of people were
just carrying around red cards but I
have a card
the first batch was [ __ ] flimsy is
how they used to be like a hundred and
twenty dollars a pop yes the original
price now this the purple card that you
got from the state for the past few
years it's purple and it's real thin and
shitty plastic and the numbers just wipe
right off if you get it warm into your
hand is sweaty and you'll just take the
numbers right off I I've been to two
different shops that give you a
protective sleeve yeah how made and
yours is unprotected cuz they know it's
gonna be toast in weeks and the numbers
just stick to that in good shops know
that like if their customers card dies
they can't let them in and out anymore
right it's so yeah it's just protecting
your ability to shop they give you a
free sleeve I keep my medical marijuana
card mostly to shop at three specific
stores like mostly one or two stores but
sometimes it's two or three I like to be
able to stop and shop anywhere I'm at in
Colorado and that helps a lot it is
completely helped the protections it
provides I still really not rely on but
it's helpful it's another house to have
that in my back pocket old Doug gets
really it starts getting like antsy when
his card expires he's like guy we got to
go get my card
I need my card renewed and I'm like bro
it's legal now and he's like I just feel
better with it I feel better I'm like I
guess we'll go get it for you man let's
do that I mean Doug's been around for a
lot of that real crazy parts of the drug
war that we were just kids doing he's
amazed we got to get Doug back on he's
amazed that uh he gets to see this he I
don't know that he believed it would
happen in his lifetime that was the fun
conversation I had all the time when I
was working a sales counter in a
dispensary was people that were my
parents age that were just blown away
that the thing that we're talking about
is teenagers finally really happened I'm
and they got to enjoy it before they
died these kids get to smoke weed and we
didn't even get to do it like it's
totally legal now who'd a thunk it I
knew it was coming I saw it
alright let's move forward a little bit
Mike we're trying to make a tight show
already 20 minutes in we haven't even
gotten really to a topic we love you
good man I feel bad for the recreational
shoppers because the recreational
dispensaries are kind of tourist traps
I've gone in there they're set up
completely different than medical shops
their price points are different it's
all geared differently everything's gear
different system yeah if you're if
you're a Colorado resident just go get
that medical marijuana card and shop
medically he'll help yeah all right I
want to give a big shout out to my
friend big care for the email that they
sent me on the last podcast that I read
and also the follow-up that they sent to
me it's a really long email it's more
personal and to me more than it is to
the listeners so I kept it to myself but
man this person you never know who
you're talking to and you get an email
from somebody and this person knows what
the [ __ ] they're talking about when it
comes to breathing they have earned my
respect I cannot wait to grow some seeds
that this person has bred because they
have goals they started a breeding
project with the goal in mind they've
reached the outcome they were looking
for the very smart person well-spoken
person garum proud to be friends with
you thanks for reaching out to me thanks
for the new email and I'm going to
respond to you through email personally
I just wanted to give you a shout out
here on the show there's so nice when
you run into people that are good at
what they do
he's got pride in heart he's one that
sent me the email about breeding that
we're getting away from breeding like
hardy plants and we're making a bunch of
[ __ ] to put in our grow rooms
dude grows with heart dude breeds with
love dudes doing it all the way properly
much love and respect to that dude for
the way he grows and breeds
also I owe a huge shout out to I'm not
sure if I'm supposed to say your name
the reason I don't do that is because
maybe your wife listens to the show and
you're not supposed to be throwing money
around I don't know I try to respect
people's privacy but somebody
contributed to the patreon account
recently and they also sent me an email
and they said hey I would rather send
you a lump sum instead of just doing a
monthly payment on patreon I don't have
a method of doing that right now
but if that's what I got to do I'm not
going to deny myself of funding and I'm
not gonna leave money on the table so I
may create an account to make that an
option because if people want to throw
money at you you find a way to catch it
right would it be possible to just set
up a larger donation on patreon set it
up for monthly and then just cancel it
after one payment you probably could but
if I just went in like that seems kind
of complicated this they mentioned that
I should have a venmo and they're not
the first person to say that so I should
just go set up a demo account anyway and
then make a girl from your heart a
podcast of n mo page and then people
could help us out that way also don't
man I should also do one of those Amazon
links an affiliate link on Amazon but ah
um I'm busy I'm sitting here smoking
[ __ ] lemon Terps all day you've
already got it how many social media
accounts to manage right and I have a
full-time job everybody
they don't all know that I run the semi
large garden that's a small garden in
Three Rivers organics I don't want to
out you too much but it for a minute in
the recent past it was raining in the
exact space where we record no I talked
about on that pot on the podcast that on
the show yeah this this exact spot where
the MacBook is sitting is where the
puddle of water accumulated on this
table and yeah so every time I get
everyone Mike leaves and we get done
recording the the iPad will get peeled
off the table taken to another area all
this gear gets put away towards in a
waterproof safe place because I don't
trust this roof right now until I get it
fully repaired its patched and it's cool
for a minute but you got lucky none of
the gear got too toasted but all this
travel and rearranging and repacking and
restoring is gonna add to the way it's
been a [ __ ] and I say peel the iPad off
the table you guys because it's got so
much probably stick it to the wall as
much glass around and it's an iPad but
watch I want to try to move it off over
the table and see if it makes a noise
I'm gonna move the mic a little bit
toward it I think you guys probably
heard that that was serious sounded like
that snap was coming through my
headphones - that was the hash sticking
my iPad
to the table so yeah that's my life you
guys where the heck are we we're
thanking patreon contributors on
possibly making a venmo I think that's
where we were thank you that's
contributed it's so nice to have a clean
microphone cover to just you notice that
these are from China they came from from
Amazon and they smell like new shoes and
weirdness I remember like episode 12
where the first microphone covers were
really starting to smell like the locker
room and I was so happy when we started
rotating those out every now and again
but patreon contributors they're helping
mount Mike's sanitary conditions over
here I've been talking about patreon I
want to move on from it but first I have
to tell everybody how to do it just go
to patreon.com/scishow form your heart
if you'd like to sign up to contribute
to the podcast it's really easy you type
in your name you type in some info of
course you put in your credit card
information you type in the amount that
you'd like to contribute and is a
monthly subscription service so whatever
amount you put in every month that will
be contributed to the podcast and it
happens on the first of every month so
put in $1.00 if you'd like put in
however many you're comfortable with I
appreciate it and if you cannot
contribute I still love you and I still
want you to listen to the show there are
people that can contribute they're gonna
cover you I want this podcast to be free
for everybody it's just an option to
contribute if you want to because I do
put time and love into it and it's a way
for people to show some appreciation
other than the cool last [ __ ] tweets
emails Facebook messages high-fives on
the streets hugs it grows stores stuff
like that and that all counts - trust me
I [ __ ] love that if you can't throw
down on patreon like we 100% understand
if you want to throw down in another way
there's a million ways to do it
yeah just high-five me when you see me
and tell me dude great [ __ ] podcast
that makes me smile all day so I want to
talk about growing cannabis for at least
a couple of seconds here this is a
cannabis based podcast I'm gonna talk
about something that I got into a
conversation with some other people
about and then we will talk hopefully
will read the student sent me three
emails I don't know if he thinks I'm
really gonna answer all three of them on
one episode or if I'm gonna stretch a
mountain tease him I don't know what
this dude expected sending me three
emails Chris what are you doing bro come
on anyway
I love it keep Senate up folks I was
taking a quick risk give us a second to
respond to your first Chris slow down
bro what the [ __ ] come on bro everybody
but Chris keep either you drove from
your heart at hotmail.com Chris I got
you blocked no I'm just pleased send me
more messages so I want to talk about
when you're transplanting let's say
you're taking a clone from aa if the
large grow where I work we run clones
and clone domes we put rapid rooters in
a tray we cut a clone into their dip it
in what's the purple [ __ ] clone ax then
stick it into the plug and then we put
the dome over it for like four days five
days and don't even [ __ ] touch it
then we water them lightly as needed
then we start I don't want to go over
the whole clone thing that wasn't the
idea here well then we get roots
eventually we're gonna fast forward to
having reverse board two clones with
just enough to uh man it works
I have transplanted clones and plugs
with just one spaghetti coming out one
noodle yep one white healthy noodle but
if you got like four or five decent
noodles coming out you're ready to go
you can let them go a little longer if
you wanted to get like a little bit of
eggs a little more than that personally
but not like to put them into a bigger
pot and I liked it this is why I like to
do it because at that point I will get
some sort of root inoculate a powder
maybe something like great white shark
something like a zoe's there's cheap
stuff there are like store-brand
products that you can buy that are
probably the same thing
there's mykos there's plus life if
you're gonna use plus life go light that
[ __ ] strong from vegetable ooh read your
labels and know what you use there's
Forge but I believe Forge will be
discontinued we've got about twelve bags
of forage left at the big grow and we're
using them sparingly but what I like to
do with these powdered root inoculants
when you take your clones out of the
clone dome and you're putting them into
soil so you get your pot and I like to
use a six inch net pot or something
maybe a small 1 gallon pot to put my
clones into so that you don't have to
overwater too much dirt for a small
plant
save yourself some space save some water
let that [ __ ] get rooted in there and
get kind of kind of tight in there
before you up pot it but anyway before
it goes in there put in your dirt get it
packed in semi-tight finger it a little
bit to make a hole
for the clone and then I take that
rooting powder and just sprinkle it all
over the roots just rotate the clone a
little bit in your hands and just
sprinkle that powderized us yeah I just
dust them real good and then put that
clone in there and cover it up just like
normal and then when you get them all
done water it like normal like you would
put some fulvic acid in there maybe some
kelp extract of some sort a little bit
of nitrogen if you got any other if you
want to put some plus life or whatever
you used back in the water and do it
again go for it but I really think it's
helpful to inoculate the roots at the
beginning also when you're gonna
transplant from that small pot to a
bigger pot do it all over again fill
your pot put your fist in process just a
bigger yep you see those roots on the
outside and don't transplant until you
see roots on the outside of the smaller
pot when you see them gathering up out
there that's when it's time to go you
want it almost pushing to be like oh
it's been in there too long because
that's when you put it in the next pot
it's gonna explode it's gonna do oh it's
time just don't wait too long
right because you'll piss it off if you
wait too long but right when he gets
tight they take it out and just turn it
in a circle and just sprinkle root
powder whatever you're using those mykos
great white shark plus life Forge
there's a ton of them you guys I bet
there's a ton that I don't even [ __ ]
know about just sprinkle it right on
there and then pot it just like normal
and then feed it with healthy nutrients
put it under a good light put a fan on
it let it get some airflow get a healthy
I think a little dusting of the roots
would really improve your grow that's
one small affordable way just got to go
buy and wear a mask you guys just get
one if nothing else get one of those
cheap eye definer masks the [ __ ]
Asian bird flu mask dust the roots it's
[ __ ] good for your roots and good for
your plants and they will appreciate it
and then feed them stuff like plus life
throughout their veg phase in their
early flower phase happy roots will help
you out we teased Chris's email were 30
minutes in let's give him at least one
email and then we'll see how much time
we've got maybe we'll read his other two
or well maybe we'll just save time for
other listeners to get emails in the
show alright Chris I'm gonna pick on you
till the end of time alright Chris sent
me an email and it goes like this I
don't know if we should have been seeing
his [ __ ] name the whole time since
not what he signed it
maybe I'll just go put a bleep over it
I'm gonna have to do 37 bleep snow
because we said his name that's cool 30
minutes in my can edit the [ __ ] out of
this sorry dude it's not the name I said
I was saying his fake name the whole
time the email goes like this hey Ross -
Jeff I'm hitting you with a few
questions in a row tonight I was hoping
you could talk about your methods for
taking down a plant to keep those Terps
loud do you do a dark cycle pre-chopped
dry trim or wet trim we would love to
hear how you do it big fan of the show
I've been a listener for about a year
and a half now you definitely make my
mind-numbing 50-plus hour work week plus
hour a week day job a lot better sorry
that was hard to read big thanks for
putting out a quality podcast and
helping people learn something and have
a laugh while listening much thanks
sincerely so his question was can we
give him any tips on keeping the Terps
loud at harvest time let me start by
saying most definitely can yes I've got
tips all day the first tip is a little
advice that light destroys terpenoids
quickly so dark is always good for your
Terps keep the lights a little bit away
I loved that part of the question yes we
did the question was do you do a light
sigh a dark cycle before you harvest so
yes if you were going just for loud
Terps yes that will help you out it will
also in my opinion add to density don't
put them in the dark cycle when they're
super wet if you're gonna put them in
the dark let them get not dry but don't
put them in there when they're soggy
because dark and soggy is never a good
thing
that will could lead to problems I'll
let them get a little bit dry before you
put them in the dark yes white does like
I said light does kind of kill the Terps
so they are producing more trips the
Terps are getting louder like you asked
they're getting richer and stronger
they're developing more in the dark face
so if you do cut them down in a dark
phase there will be more true pains
present in your trichomes in your plants
and your flowers and your concentrates
so a dark phase is always good I like to
get it a little bit cold toward the end
that makes them dense up a little bit
also make some purple I think it kind of
makes them panic make sure you flush I
think you say something about that in
another email
so also the less you touch those plants
the better cut them down you ask wet or
dry trim I prefer a dry trim cut him
down hang him upside down touch him very
little okay let me back up a step
flush cut off all the family flush is so
important he's got another email about
that so we're just gonna do that one
next
but flush cut off all the families when
they start getting close to the harvest
time then put them in the dark without
those big fan leaves on there to let
them sit for 24 to 48 hours in the dark
cut them down hang them upside down
until the stems begin to pop and from
there you have to listen to the dry and
cure episodes because now you're drying
and curing more than harvesting but
that's where you get it that's where it
starts then you have to let it dry until
the sticks pop then you cut the buds off
of the sticks into a container and seal
that container and burp it appropriately
until the moisture is gone I like to
make it go really slowly if possible and
Colorado weed dries really quickly it's
hard to go slow here you're trying to
get chlorophyll out and keep terpenoids
in so you want to keep the right
temperatures and you want to keep light
away from it try to keep it semi cool
around 72 degrees 74 degrees is probably
right around where you want it maybe 77
don't go too high heat destroys chirps
light destroys terms so dry and cured it
properly handle it properly don't touch
it
plastic will start causing problems if
you can keep it in glass containers
that's recommended um what else can we
recommend you dry trimming never use a
trim machine I'm gonna get off on a side
rant I [ __ ] hate trim machines the
cannabis industry hates trim machines
the only people that like trim machines
are greedy growers and grow facility
owners that want to make a lot of money
trim machines mangle buds in my opinion
this is all my opinion I could be [ __ ]
alive but I yet to see one that does
what it's supposed to without a serious
detriment to the final product and
another thing that a trim machine will
never do I had a trimmer today find
issues and buds
if those buds got pulled aside they will
never make it to the public that whole
plant got Rhian spected because there
was one small issue in one small area
that part got Secor segregated and
countered his waste and destroyed the
rest of the plant was okay
Dean I would smoke it I would smoke that
myself so it got passed on and trimmed
and taken care of a machine would have
never seen that and that [ __ ] would have
rolled down the line and got put into
either our hash or our pipe or a jar to
get sold and it would have embarrassed
us you cannot put a value on that
quality control that a good well-trained
educated trimmer brings to the table I
mean when you say don't touch it I've
been trimming with people and you look
over and there glove is just solid right
that means your man has half of what I
grew is now on your glove yeah there's a
stick on there just handle that stick
yep yeah find yourself a stick to handle
and don't manhandle the buds um
I think we kind of answered that you're
gonna have I would recommend you
listening to the drying and curing
episode also but for the most part
that's where the harvest Terps come in
you cut it down in the dark you keep it
dark cut it down keep it in the dark dry
it really slowly when the sticks pop
then you cut the buds off the sticks put
them into a glass container and burp
them i spurt I've got OCD I like to burp
it at four hours tumble them around a
little bit get air in there cuz they're
gonna be a little damp you might want to
pull them apart put them back in the jar
close it up burp I'm at eight hours do
it again at sixteen then start doing it
like every 12 hour do it eight for eight
and then twelve so doing every twelve
hours before it when you wake up before
you go to bed every day burp these buds
give them 15 20 maybe 30 minutes open
you're not trying to dry them you're
trying to let moisture escape the bud
but you want so when you close that jar
a reaction happens there's oxygen and
moisture and darkness and those create
the perfect environment for the
chlorophyll to start breaking down you
create an acid in there is it aerobic or
anaerobic acid it's with oxygen okay so
you treat the anaerobic acid and there
that starts eating it how the
chlorophyll I believe you're correct it
starts eating out the chlorophyll and it
turns it into a vapor when you open the
jar the moisture allows that to escape
is how I think it goes I'm just reciting
off the top of my head with no notes and
sounds right so you have to have a
little moisture in there to dry slowly
to pull out that chlorophyll chlorophyll
is what gives you the rough harsh taste
turps are what give you that sweet
delicious taste that burnt grain yeah
yeah that's why uh that's why rosin
always tastes like burnt popcorn if you
overheat it and press it too hard you're
just burning the Terps right there so
there's more to this email I'm opening
up my phone cuz it locked here we go
he goes on to say um my phone is making
noise into the mixing equipment I am
sorry
uh haha big fan of the show I've been a
listener for about a year and a half
dude thank you I make his mind-numbing
50-plus hour a week day job a lot better
that's right dude what do you do that
you're able to listen to that many
podcasts all week and what else are you
listening to send that in your next
email and I'll unblock you
thanks for putting out a quality podcast
and helping people learn and have a
laugh while listening [ __ ] nailing it
if that's what I'm doing because I like
to laugh right that's the mission
statement filthy comedian inside I try
to keep it at bay on the show and I love
to grow cannabis so I'm glad that you
notice that dude thank you for the email
I'm gonna email you right now Mike you
talk for a minute while we're waiting
for response I don't need to wait for a
response right now we got days I was
just I wanted to say thank you to all
the people that sent me messages after
the last show where we got super baked
before we it record I appreciate the
feedback that's always nice thank you
everybody
for his baked as we got people really
enjoyed it it's it got so much feedback
today when we were like let's not get so
baked into a tighter show but my first
thought was like but everybody loved our
super bake show there's one point in the
show when I think I purposefully paused
to edit and when I listen to back
I didn't even edit it was like right
here I need to edit the shows why I
paused at one point I was like and here
we go with the podcast and [ __ ] I
didn't edit that at all I was listening
back and my friend Elijah is like I
don't think you did that right no like
oops we recorded it it like we meant to
hit record it like 9:30 we didn't
actually end up recording until at well
after 10:00 the video was the podcast
was posted at midnight and by 4:00 a.m.
I was getting tweets and messages about
how good the show was nice I think it
was a quick turnaround on that one
that's fun when you post it and people
listen as it goes up you know when the
alert comes up on your phone we've got
an awesome little community you've built
all right do we want to read the next
one from
the message goes like this Gmail I'm
gonna read too because I said his
[ __ ] full name on the show and we may
have to edit a few minutes out anyway so
it goes like this hey Rasta Jeff I had a
question about flushing in Coco do it
that's my advice do you do just plain
water plus a flushing additive or do you
water with a small amount of Cal mag
added in because of your Coco I heard
that was given as advice also wanted to
hear your thoughts on behind unpay CH
water flush or pH in your flush in cocoa
as well as soil like a pro mix alright
there's a couple of things to touch on
there flushing in cocoa do you add just
but before I go that far I want to ask
and I want to address this
are you flushing just at the end of
flour because some people think that
they need to flush their cocoa during
the flowering cycle which I find
unnecessary when I'm watering with cocoa
and I'm growing with cocoa I add
nutrients to every single watering Oh
when I'm growing with cocoa some people
feel the need at the end of week three
to just run so much clean water through
it and flush out the nutrients I don't
feel the need to do that I like to have
it in there cocoa has aloe I don't want
to say this wrong because I'm full of
[ __ ] there's a lot of good people in
exchange [ __ ] doesn't bind to cocoa
stick thank you for the slightly more
scientific term for it doesn't hold the
nutrients as well as dirt right you're
not getting that same salt built it
doesn't live like the dirt does it's
it's real slick and it's oily and the
nutrients and the salts will slide right
off of it essentially it's more like a
sponge that will hold stuff to fall out
of and that's the idea so we're more
able to feed more consistently so when
I'm talking about flushing I am only
talking about the final phase of
flowering when you were trying to get
the nutrients out just before harvest
write a DNA and in soil or cocoa I don't
recommend a mid cycle flush of any type
unless you're seeing a problem and then
if I do that I mix up a very specific
batch of nutrients that I use and I
flush every plant heavily with that
until water is running out and then I
know that most of the old nutrients are
out and what's in there now is this mix
that I trust and I know that's gonna
make my
it's happy that's what I put in there to
fix a problem so now what I'm talking
about flushing I'm gonna go to just the
end of flowering right now is what I'm
talking about Mikey look like you want
to joke I was gonna ask are you do you
recommend just watering the normal
volume of water with clean or clean pH
water or do you like to I think if it is
flooding the plant we're like say you're
gonna start flush today the plant gets
six or eight or ten times its normal
volume of water to kind of just force
everything out it would be ideal to know
exactly how much you can put through and
what it takes but there are several ways
to do it depending on your environment
and your in your situation and your
timeframe um let me write down something
with my pen here which is funny because
I'm writing down the word pen ah let me
write a note to kind of get back to what
you're asking but then I want to kind of
read the email cuz you've got a side
question that's gonna kind of put me
onto that yeah um do you add you flush
with just plain water or a flushing
additive you can do a flushing additive
if you want if you want to speed up the
process if you only have seven days to
flush put a flushing additive in there
in the first day if you've got ten days
of flush consider the flushing additive
if you've got twelve to fourteen days
it's not necessary what a flushing
additive does it sugars when you add the
sugars to the water and pour it through
your grow medium sugars will help
release bonded salts is basically what
happens it's not a hundred percent what
goes on there but the sugars will help
release bonded salt in your rhizosphere
which will help flush your plants and
help speed up the metabolism of your
plants that's the part why you would use
that it's not necessary but it's helpful
and if you've got it go for it um so
just plain water works and then you say
would you water with a small amount of
cal mag added in because of the coco no
i if I'm flushing this is why I wasn't
sure if you meant flushing at the end or
like at the end of week three and five
or something like that know if I'm
flushing I'm flushing I want it gone I
don't want anything in there unless I'm
using veg bloom I will go until the last
five or seven days with some shine but I
never said that out loud
check out a veg bloom tech on Instagram
for all
the details on how to use shine properly
because it's a great product they don't
pay me to say that but it helps umm I
don't put anything in there at the end
of flush I'm flushing I want it all to
go bye-bye um also I want to hear your
thoughts behind unpay chirpy aged water
during your flush if you can pH it if
you've got the ability why not do it if
you are flushing an outdoor plant that
you've got a hundred gallon [ __ ]
smart pot outside just put the hose on
there and let it run do don't even try
to ph that [ __ ] it's gonna take so much
pH down you may not have a reservoir to
do it it's outside you'll be okay
you don't have to pee there done nothing
too bad is gonna happen but if you can
pH it do it why not and some places
that's gonna be crazy important
depending on your water that is true if
your water is completely [ __ ] funky
you are going to need to ph it if you've
got we're very lucky here our water kind
of tastes like [ __ ] it's got a weird
flavor but if you test it it's really
not that bad though the PP ends are low
the pH is all right it's really not that
bad so you can flush with water from
here I don't know where you are a guy
whose name I keep [ __ ] up and
shouldn't say that again I don't I don't
know if you can you if you got well
water I don't know what you're using you
might want to pH that but let me recap
and make sure I got all your stuff
before I go onto the part that Mike made
me write down with my brain plain water
flushing additive if you're in a hurry
but make sure if you use that flushing
additive make sure you get at least one
clean water rinse after that so that
you're flushing additive isn't what you
taste
ah no I don't use cal-mag in my flush
the only thing I would consider using
during my flush would probably be shine
from our friends at veg bloom also known
as hydroponic research um pH if you can
it's not necessary also wanted to know I
may not be necessary sorry I don't want
to mislead you it's not necessary for me
want to know my thoughts behind on pH
water and flush and soil as well
soils much more forgiving if you've got
decent water you're gonna want to run a
lot more water through your soil than
your cocoa to flush that out it's gonna
be a lot harder to get everything out in
the soil than it will to Coco but it
depends on how much you're using
honestly if you want a pH
if you're going if you've got a big
outdoor [ __ ] grow you might just want
to run the hose so I wrote down
something here
flushing either in cocoa or soilless mix
or however you want to grow one thing
you can do elevate your pot off of the
ground
um maybe use or put a trainer if this
would work to put a tray under it just
the little saucer catch the water that's
coming out of it as my point clean your
vessel set the pot on a vessel of some
sort that is going to catch the water
you need like a half inch of water maybe
an inch of water coming out of the
bottom of your pot flush it flush it
flush it until it's draining a lot until
you see a bunch of water coming out go
hard
then catch some of that water and stick
a nice e pin in there stick a ppm pin in
there and see how much it's coming out
of the bottom of your plant
see how low you can get it if you're in
cocoa you can get it really low and soil
it's gonna stay up kind of higher just
because there's stuff in the soil you've
got natural stuff in your soil
let's see hitting it all out so you
rinse out all the soil right see how you
see how low you can get it in that cocoa
uh you should be able to get it fairly
low
maybe maybe test the cocoa when you get
it run some water through it see what it
ec is that before you put nutrients in
it try to get it back to there before
you flush I don't know if you can this
is all one idea but I know what I don't
want to say and I'm trying to think an
arbitrary number but I don't want to
give you a number of what my e sees come
out at the end of the week when we Tet
we test every day when we water it my
girl we catch the water every table gets
wat that gets the EC tested the pH
tested it should be in a certain range
but I don't know what you're feeding I
don't know what you're collecting in I
don't want to give you a fake a false
hope or a fake guideline so see what you
I see how low you can get it in your
cocoa see how much you can flush that
[ __ ] out and see how low you can get so
you gotta go get a p/e C meter or a ppm
pen and see how low you can get it it's
all about the right tools yeah so that's
my advice on flushing in just about any
medium if you're using rock wool or
whatever else type of hydro stuff like
that flush you can flush about ten to
fourteen days seven is maybe enough if
you use some sort of product and you go
really fast and I but I like ten to
fourteen days all right
this next question should be pretty
quick but I want to proofread it um so
he says hey I was just laughing to
myself saying the Dain team was giving
your strains a name that they made up I
definitely don't agree with him doing
that for reasons you stated on the show
but I'd love to hear even in a p.m. what
names they added so it turns out one of
them was called depth charge which was
not my seeds it was another brand and
then the other one that they just put a
label on was they just called it Irie
and it was the lemon Geoffrey to arise
they just slapped the name on it and
called it Irie which if they're gonna
call it anything I guess I read about
their other strains out there called
Irie another breeder I used the name I
Ryoji but yeah I that's all they did
they just called it Irie so answer all
three of your emails since I kept saying
your real name on the podcast hopefully
let me leave that in so that I don't
have to edit too much she's just getting
the habit of saying every email is from
rusty Shackelford yeah if you guys when
you email me which you can do it grow
from your heart at hotmail.com that
should be like instead of hi Ross - Jeff
it should just be bold letters you can
or you cannot use my name on the show
there you go start your email with
what's up Rasta do or do not say my name
on the podcast or just yet cuz that
would help me I apologize if I busted
you out before anybody else sorry dude
keep sending emails that we absolutely
love the questions yes send the emails
to grow from your heart hit a
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I love answering listener emails
because that lets me know that I'm
actually doing something for at least
one person yep and not just rambling
over here - Mike being all hi Mike those
dad's wired off you want to wrap up
podcast and take couple of dabs and get
exactly the same thing we should
high-five wrap this show up and take
another dab a couple more dad dude
couple more dad's alright ladies and
gentlemen please follow myself on
Twitter it's at Rasta Jeff 420 you can
follow the show at G fyh podcast you can
find the show on Facebook search for the
girl from your heart a podcast once
again you can email me grow from your
heart at hotmail.com if you want to
follow mike on social media he is pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
he is also Nemo punk 15 on the Twitter's
are you doing an Instagram stuff lately
very very
I was just every time we do uh social
media shoutouts in the show I smile
because we never talk about my Instagram
account because it barely exists I think
like seven posts nice how many followers
I have no idea less than fifty okay like
48 of them or family go find it on
Instagram you guys a whole bunch of
podcast fans follow me on Instagram and
when I get contacted about the podcast
nine times out of ten it's through
Instagram and ice even though we've
never announced my Instagram on the show
several people follow from Instagram
follow the show on my Instagram wait
follow my Instagram from the show that
was hard to say English is hard you guys
you go for an hour don't say some dumb
[ __ ] occasionally but a lot of people
follow me on Instagram they talk about
the show if you want to follow on
instagram my instagram is Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore GE
and ET ICS I would appreciate a follow
click like check out the cannabis
photography I post I've been posting
photos from some caregiver grows that
I'm involved in those photos of my own
grow I post photos of the grow at Three
Rivers organics I just posted a bunch of
great pictures of this lemon Jeffrey hi
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract posted
a lot of great stuff you might like to
follow it I would appreciate it I'll
also remind you about patreon check out
patreon.com
keep Mike with a fresh microphone cover
so doesn't have to smell his own breath
all the time also if you cannot
contribute to patreon and you want to
help us out you can always go to iTunes
go to the iTunes Store search for the
girl from your heart podcast click on
the little icon
it's got my ugly face on it in the
middle of the screen there's a part that
says ratings and reviews click on there
type in a review let me know what you
think of the show and give me a star
rating that you feel like I deserve I
will read your comments on a future
episode that's always the fun part you
get to hear me read how you feel about
the show let me know what you think I'd
love to hear from you there Mike we're
gonna wrap up this podcast do you have
anything else you would like to say
while you're on the microphone I think
he said it best having whatever time it
is where you heard later and have a good
right the [ __ ] now have a good right now
whoever you're with whatever you're
doing whoever you're doing whatever
you're with have a good time
all right I'm gonna give a huge shout
out to my friend Victor at apothecary
and until next time take a fat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
calm down
[Music]
to change
the same
[Music]
you