[Music]
what's up podcast world it is the first
of the month it is throwback Thursday
and it's time for episode number 212 of
the girlfriend Hart podcast that's right
I'm coming in with a bonus Thursday
episode this week I am NOT doing the
chunk of old episodes this week I am
doing something a little bit differently
we are going to do a garden first of the
month garden checklist I'm gonna list of
things that you should be checking on in
your garden maybe you should check on it
more frequently than you do the first of
the month is always a good time to do a
garden check before we get to the garden
checklist let me do an update on an old
episode on an episode I think was the
last episode with Mike we read an email
about keeping the Terps allowed at
harvest time one thing I didn't mention
was fresh frozen if you really want to
keep those Terps loud chop down the
plants cut the buds off the sticks get
them into a bucket and freeze them
that's right
live resin is made with fresh frozen
material and it is the tur pious [ __ ]
you can get the HC FSC can be made with
fresh frozen or dry material that seems
to come out better with frozen so if you
want to keep the Terps loud freeze that
[ __ ] is your best bet
alright so let me dig into the notes
I've got here I've got a whole bunch of
notes we're just gonna go over some
things that you can do on the first of
the month it would greatly improve your
garden
probably prolong the life of some of
your equipment and maybe give you a few
more grams per watt in your grow so
let's get right to it on the first of
the month something I always like to do
clean my air conditioning filters if
you've got a homegirl with the portable
air conditioner you got that filter that
pops right out of the back just pop that
up take it to a hose take it to a sink
just rinse it off wipe it off real good
put it right back it doesn't take much
effort whatever erican whatever kind of
air conditioner you've got check the
filters see if they need to be replaced
see if they need to be cleaned to see
how often it needs to be done and do it
today it's the first of the month go
check them right now if they're clean
that's cool write it down think about
how long away from now you need to check
them go check them on the first and next
month if they're dirty [ __ ] change
them and keep an eye on how long those
things last without getting super dirty
something we should go over before we
get too far get a calendar get a
notebook start making some notes start
making some check marks if you don't
know when the last time you did some
[ __ ] was how do you know how long things
last how do you know when the next time
you need to change that bulb
that filter house how do you know if you
don't write it down so get a calendar
make a Google document some [ __ ] make
some notes keep things in check so
another thing I would recommend check
your bulbs I would recommend getting a
lumen meter in a lumen meter and a piece
of string or a lumen meter and a ruler
and what you're trying to do is put that
ruler and the lumen meter you're
measuring the distance from the bulb so
that you can be consistent so that every
time you measure the distance from the
bulb you were 12 inches away or 18
inches away whatever you choose then you
know exactly how many lumens you're
getting at that distance I like to use a
just a piece of string and hang the
lumen meter when the string hangs you go
right here you're like oh that's that
many inches and every time you know
you're that far from the bulb so lumen
meter check the bulbs you may be here's
one thing if you are pumping electricity
into a bulb and that bulb is almost dead
it's still receiving all of the
electricity but it's not putting out the
lumens or the par watts so you're
spinning money and you're not doing [ __ ]
to your plants you're just burning money
it's just the boxes outside spinning
your power meter is just of going but
you're not getting [ __ ] out of it so
place that bulb if it's not living up to
your standards and then write a note
mark down how long that bulb has been in
there every time you put in a new bulb
market they should only go from one
maybe two cycles I don't like to let
them go longer than that these double
ended bulbs they just burn out they
don't give you any warning swap them out
after one or two crops that is my
recommendation carbon filter covers you
guys I am guilty of this my carbon
filter cover completely looks like [ __ ]
in my photography it looks black I have
taken it off and I have cleaned it with
oxy clean I don't know what else to do
but I know it's not filled with dust and
dirt it's cleaned up so I mean you guys
need to take that [ __ ] off there and
clean it some of you guys just need to
cut it off of there throw it away and
get a brand new one from the pictures
I've seen on some of your instagrams so
your carbon filter cover may need to be
cleaned your a carbon filter itself may
need to be replaced we're gonna talk
about that and just a few more things
here ah check your ro filters if you're
running RO water check those filters and
membranes they may be getting funky they
may be sludged up you may be wasting
more water than what you're actually
cleaning you might want to check on that
stuff check all of your RO the fittings
the seals everywhere where it reaches or
where it connects check out
stuff make sure it's well sealed and not
leaking odd check clean the glass in
your sealed hoods if you've got those
ducted hoods like a Magnum with glass in
it clean that glass inside and out
debris carbon filter dust [ __ ] flies
around inside of there randomly clean
that let the bulbs cool down before you
get in there and clean it unplug that
[ __ ] wait like 45 to an hour and then
get in there and clean the inside of
that glass clean the outside of that
glass also make sure that all that
ducting is sealed make sure that all of
your from the let's see from the blower
or from the the carbon filter to the
blower to the ducting to the light to
the other side of the light to the
outside make sure that all of that is
sealed make sure you don't have any air
leaks make sure you don't have any light
leaks all right so check the timers for
accuracy and settings I know this sounds
like a no-brainer but sometimes power
goes out sometimes equipment [ __ ] up
go look at all of your timers make sure
they are set for the correct time maybe
daylight savings time happened and you
didn't fix it just go make sure they're
all set at the correct time also make
sure they are set for the correct cycles
maybe you [ __ ] up something maybe you
had an idea maybe you got high one night
and bumped into something just go check
it's always a good idea um let's see
what else check your smoke alarms and
fire extinguishers I know that isn't
something we all think about but if you
were growing cannabis in a home or a
commercial environment you should have
smoke detectors and fire extinguishers
on hand what are you gonna do if you
have a fire and you don't have a fire
extinguisher you're gonna burn down the
[ __ ] house you're gonna be that guy
that burned down the house growing weed
so have a smoke alarm inside the grow
that's my advice and have a smoke fire
extinguisher that word was hard to pull
out of my brain have a fire extinguisher
outside of the gross space if something
does I don't want it to ever please John
no fire but if some fire does happen in
your grow you don't want to run in there
and discover it and have the fire
extinguisher in there where the fire is
you want to be able to kick open the
door with that fire extinguisher in hand
and spray the [ __ ] out of it
it's gonna cost you your plants but you
want a house more than any of those
[ __ ] plants so check on your smoke
alarm and fire extinguisher check the
battery make sure that battery is good
make sure that smoke detector beeps like
it's supposed to make sure that your
your fire extinguisher has a nice heavy
charge on it make sure it's still got
some juice
there's a little gauge on there that'll
tell you and they come with a date they
only last so long till you have to go
get them recharged so check that stuff
out safety is important you guys if you
are using co2 get your Co to set up
inspected um or get it refilled if it
needs to be refilled start refilling it
on the first and fifteenth if it lasts
you two weeks but get check everything
make sure that your meter is working
well run it too high and see if it's got
a safety feature on it test that [ __ ] do
it while you're there so that if it does
[ __ ] up you know it's going to have a
safety turn off when you're gone test it
that is my advice what else can you do
on the first of the month um I said
earlier checking about on like light
leaks and using your checking for carbon
filter problems and needing to replace
your carbon filter here's something a
lot of people don't think about go
outside your grow and walk around go
check for smell go check for light leaks
go check for anything that doesn't look
ordinary go check for odd sounds go
check for anything that would make you
think hey there's a grow in here because
if you walk by go walk your dog go do
something random and just walk around
your house a few extra times go go look
like you're doing something go be
suspicious at your own house you can
walk around but what you're actually
doing is looking to see if you can hear
see or smell anything that is involved
with your grow and if you can hear see
or smell anything you need to correct it
maybe you can feel something maybe you
can feel the ground vibrating from a
blower you've got in the basement I
didn't know what you could have going on
but go check for light leaks go check
for smell leaks go check for any damage
you may have done when you were working
inside and didn't pay attention to the
outside because if you notice it then
somebody else will notice it because
people are [ __ ] nosy there's one
person in your neighborhood that wants
to catch you slipping for some reason
and don't give them the reason okay
they're either gonna smell it they're
gonna see it they're gonna do something
and they're gonna get nosy and they're
gonna get curious and if they can see it
or smell it then law enforcement may get
involved maybe the person that sees it
smells it hears it feels it maybe they
are a thief or a crook just be careful
you don't want to push yourself in any
position you don't need to be in so just
go out there and check it out um I said
earlier get a calendar and make notes of
all of these checks and start doing this
on the first and maybe on the 15th of
every month and I really think that a
few small steps like this
could greatly improve your garden also
it's a good idea to go in the grow room
during your light cycle if it's light oh
it's okay when it's light outside or
light wherever else go in your grow room
and turn off the lights and see if you
are getting any light inside of the room
coming from the outside see if you're
getting a light leak from under your
door
see if there's a hole in your ducting
sometimes the light will travel down
ducting and right back through your
light reflector and the sunshine will
work like your light and you'll be
getting sunshine in your plants during
your night cycle or just depends on how
your shits going but I'm talking about
check for light leaks during your cycles
in your grow if your see my lights are
on at night so the sunshine is on the
sunshine is up on my plants or asleep so
I really have to make sure no Sun gets
into my grow in my personal grow that
that's what I'm talking about I don't
know what you've got setup but make sure
no lights getting in during your dark
cycle also it may be a good idea to put
some green lights in there and just pop
in once or twice and see what the night
cycle feels like how humid is it how
funky is is there anything weird in
there just pay attention to what's going
on in your grow a few things like this
would greatly improve your cannabis you
may spot something that you did not know
about I had a friend that had some huge
problems he couldn't figure out what was
wrong with this plants he called me over
it was during his day cycle I said turn
off all your lights we looked and you
could see light just beaming in through
one window where the board wasn't over
properly and that was what was causing
all of his plants in one section to her
so something small could be something
huge could save you a lot of money could
give you some better product all right
I hope that was a quick rundown on stuff
you should do on the 1st of the month
also I skipped a couple of things
there's a small section here I skipped
calibrate your ppm meters calibrate your
EC meters calibrate all of your [ __ ] now
is a good time to calibrate it it's the
first of the month also do a water test
see what's coming out maybe there's
something in there that you weren't
aware of maybe you need to adjust to the
water that's coming out I like to do a
water test every now and then and write
down the PPM's in the EC and the the TDS
and see what's in my water just so I
know I'm just weird like that
also clean up the first is always a good
time to clean up there's a mess you've
been dodging clean up also it's the
first
pay your electric bill pay your rent pay
all of your bills and don't look
suspicious that will help you keep the
go the grow going alright you guys I
feel like it ran through the checklist
let's see what else did I want to talk
about today
keeping your garden clean and organized
and keeping all of your nutrients and
your pesticides all organized is a huge
part of garden cleanliness and
organization is a huge part to me about
having a successful garden I was talking
about writing everything down I write
down every feed I give my plants I write
down every spray I give my plants I
write down a lot of [ __ ] I have a Google
document where I write some things I
have a notebook where I write some
things my phone is filled with cannabis
Wizardry
what I'm getting at is the garden you
are growing is a reflection of yourself
as a person I think when I walk into
somebody's garden I can see the inside
of their mind I can see the chaos that
is in their mind I can see the order
that is in their mind I can see their
thought processes by the way they
organize their gardens their grow lights
their rows of plants how their nutrients
are taken care of I think a garden is a
reflection of yourself if you are
growing straight for money and for greed
and for [ __ ] purposes your garden will
show it if you're drawing from your
heart and breeding with love your garden
will show it if you were too chaotic and
too [ __ ] up in your life right now
your garden will show it if you are
focused and centered and doing things
correctly your garden will really
probably reflect that as well if you
were a person like me most of the
gardens I've been to I can see this um I
have been to many personal private
gardens for years and years I was a
consultant here in a small town when the
medical marijuana boom took off and I
got to visit I've been in a hundred
private gardens in this town and I I can
see if you lined up ten people and then
let me walk into ten grow rooms and then
put them all like put the guys in a
lineup I hear oh yeah that guy goes to
grow room a that guy goes to grow room
pee I could probably assign the people
with a short interview and a little of
who has which grow because I think the
gardens reflect ourselves that very much
so take care of your garden because it
is a reflection of you the pride you put
in your garden shows it shows in your
finished product it shows in your
pictures I just shows we can see it also
your nutrient decisions strongly show me
what'd you have in mind for this plant
it shows me if you're growing for just
money if you're growing for quality if
you're growing for patience if you're
growing for your nutrient selections
strongly show me where your heart and
mind are in your grow and yes I'm using
veg bloom at a commercial growth because
we are growing on a commercial level I'm
also using veg bloom in my private grow
and I'm also using botanic or I use
botanic air at home and my personal grow
because I think it tastes the best
that's my favorite flavor it gives my
herb something funky it's just that it's
a lot of chicken [ __ ] and seabird guano
and stuff like that and I think that see
product that's in there really makes my
blood taste good that's why I use
botanic carry because I've been using it
for a long time I've tried a lot of
other bottled nutrients in botanic your
gamy the flavor I like I don't spray
with ridiculous stuff I don't feed my
plants ridiculous stuff botanic hair is
mostly on the organic side it's got some
stuff in there that's not but most of
the products do I don't do the fully
organic stuff because I don't feel I
don't want to do that in my home grow
it's just I don't need it it's a bedroom
I don't feel I'm supposed to be doing
that in a bedroom I think bottles are a
little cleaner and safer for this home
that I am in that's just my opinion if I
had a farm we'd be doing no-till all day
we'd have worms we'd have a warm farm
would be scraping up our own chicken
[ __ ] it would be a different story but
like I said I use veg bloom at the big
grow because it's a big grow and veg
bloom is a really clean product the
people are really cool and it burns so
smoothly when you use veggie bloom I
don't think it leaves a whole bunch of
crap behind so your garden is a
reflection of yourself the nutrients you
choose to use our reflection of yourself
and the pest management program that you
use are a reflection of yourself so
think about that when you're playing
with your gardens one more thing I
wanted to talk about I just kind of loop
it all around since I've been taking
care of ganja plants for longer than I
should admit because I've been growing
and [ __ ] with weed since way before
all this medical marijuana [ __ ] the more
I learn about cannabis and nutrients and
a nutria t'v cycle of cannabis plants
the more I'm inspired to take better
care of myself I realize more that what
I put in since you feed cannabis plants
so infrequently and when you feed them
you definitely see results I've noticed
that I
try to pay more attention to what I put
into me I try to take in a wider variety
of nutrients and more specific nutrients
I try to just pay a little bit more
attention since I paid so much attention
to the plants if I'm measuring out this
much nitrogen and this much phosphorous
and this much potassium and then a
little smidge of cal-mag and then put in
some kelp in there and then some
microbes also for my plants why wouldn't
I think about my own body like that why
wouldn't I love my plant like that why
wouldn't I love my branches and my roots
just as well so I think taking better
care of plants has made me take better
care of myself and it's made me learn a
lot more about my health it's made me
care a lot more about my health and it
honestly has made me think a lot more
about my hydration since water is the
only you can just feed these plants
water for their whole lives and they
would grow so it makes me think should I
need a lot more water I drink plenty of
water but I could drink a lot or you
probably could too every time you take a
dab drink a bottle of water three dads
bottle of water I don't know I'm not a
[ __ ] Scientologist but do your own
ratio there every time you take some
dabs drink some water all right you guys
this is gonna be a quick Thursday
episode it's only gonna be about 18
minutes but I hope it was good for you
it was good for me I'll be back Monday
with a full length episode I would love
it if you stalk me on Twitter find me on
Twitter at G fyh podcast you can also
follow me on Facebook simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast I would
love to hear from you if you've got
something to say and you don't want to
meet reach out to me on social media you
can find me and emails that was hard to
say it was all jumbly but I think you
know what the [ __ ] I meant email me grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you also let me remind
you about patreon patreon is a service
where you can contribute to the podcast
financially for more information just go
to patreon.com/scishow to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart I would love
your help also I would love it if you
went to iTunes that left me and high
Tunes rating and review so far everybody
has left me a five star review let me
know what you think of the podcast now
read your review on an upcoming episode
ladies and gentlemen that is all I have
got for you for this short Thursday I'll
be back Monday with a full-length
episode I'll probably be back Thursday
with another chunk of old episodes I
want to give a shout out to my friend
bone Ellis and until next time take a
phat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
we have an wonderful day
[Music]
[Applause]
this guy tonight what about this for
where the Cussler's in a graveyard shift
on the fire
[Music]