it's a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
it's Thursday so that means it's time
for a chunk of old episodes of the girl
from your heart podcast this week I'm
reposting episodes 45 46 47 and 48 of
the girl from your heart podcast before
we get to the episodes let me make a
couple of quick disclaimers the email
address has changed the new email
address has grown from your heart at
hotmail.com the new twitter is at GF wih
podcast and on facebook you need to
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast also any giveaways contests
advertisements or promotions in these
episodes have expired
so don't get too excited ladies and
gentlemen with no further ado I bring
you episodes 45 46 47 and 48 of the girl
from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 45 Daigo
culture podcast the podcast all about
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're a new grower a pro grower a
longtime cannabis consumer a brand new
smoker or just someone who's curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you thanks
for joining me like drywall dust in your
hands no idea like a working man this is
the holiday episode whatever winter
holiday it is did you celebrate this
will be your episode so merry holiday
whichever one you choose to label it as
I'm not gonna I support all of your
holiday decisions whatever religion race
creed you are I hope you have a great
winter holiday you get a lot of gifts if
you're into the gift-giving thing give a
lot of gifts eppie give twice as many
gifts as you receive try to change that
for you we'll give you gifts in the past
couple years but it's always like now I
feel obligated because I'm an adult
then that's the proper thing to do and I
understand that that's not what it was
about the people are able to give out
kind gifts like that to our friends that
we know can't give a gift like that we
do it because we know that you want that
[ __ ] and that you deserve it everybody
bender gave Adam can why save it that's
what it's about he's gonna see you
smiling and all [ __ ] and giggled
playing with it and that's what it's
about it ain't about you givin him back
a gift yeah absolutely and thank you you
know [ __ ] enjoy the holidays with us
roll hold you down and tickle you you
know I try with the kids but it's hot
how's it gonna make you feel when two
grown men hold you down and tickle you
have you been tickled as a grown man not
since I left Florida I'm gonna try to
put it back on track I want to mention
something I mentioned it's a holiday
season iTunes sent me an email and they
say that there will be a delay in
podcast posting between December 22nd
and January 5th which will affect this
episode and possibly another episode I
will post them early I'll try to get
them we're recording on a Thursday the
show comes out on a Monday I'll try to
put it up like Saturday night and
hopefully that'll give iTunes time to do
whatever it is they're doing I'm not
sure why they choose to do that around
Christmas time I don't know what it's
gonna do guys we're gonna change the
name of the podcast eventually I said
December 1st but I was high I meant
January 1st we're gonna start calling it
the grow from your heart podcast because
I grow is actually a horticultural
agricultural educational institution
that does not want me associating their
name with our beloved sacred plant so
before they send me a cease and desist
letter I'm just gonna go ahead and
switch it up it's the responsible thing
to do that's kind I don't want to rip
off anybody else's name
you know if somebody else was called
agriculture I'd be pissed off about that
you know and or if they were called I
read genetics I'd be double pissed so I
move closer to you but you've got that
beautiful that is sexy thank you I
didn't write down any space for you to
ramble about the emerald-cut but do you
want to tell us about your experience
for a second I'd highly recommend
all growers to try to make it out to
that one best cop I've ever seen nice
that's a huge thing to say yeah it's way
different it's not as tongue-in-cheek is
the cannabis cup there's it's not
stereotypical yeah so less of it less of
an RV show and more of the growers
exactly California right yes awesome so
you flew out there yeah he's never
gotten a shadowed on the podcast what's
up James sending you some love bro
hopefully I get to dab some time soon
[Music]
for four days four days for growers can
you just fly over my house come on
always got the worst ideas in your head
and have you been working a lot bro what
you working on man just some grow up
buildings it's uh is it the one that we
talked about last yeah but so far the
whole bug company company you guys are
still put that together yep yep do you
know how many lights are going in there
more a lot I would say 55 to 75 per unit
okay I don't give exact units but it's
still single-digit units
sounds like you're a busy man yeah yeah
it was nothing there and the guy that
was there doing it was there all alone
and I mean I don't know if you've ever
tried to do construction alone but it's
hard you can't really do a lot of
control yourself you're just slow
cutting and doing doing measure twice
cut once nail it up measure twice cut
someone hold the [ __ ] right when he told
me that's great but we you know
that's it's good job I can't I can't
[ __ ] and hopefully it holds out through
the end of the month because I really
needed the stuff for the kids in
Christmas it's good timing right yeah
today myself dude today I'm gonna give a
big shout out to my homie spits Spence
and I have been talking about me
learning how to make dabs because I
smoke a lot of hash and I grow my own
herb
I am sufficient all the way from I can
create my own seeds I can germinate I
can grow the seeds they can harvest in I
can trim it then I've got the product
that is done is flowers and trim and
then I like to smoke dabs so I had to
learn how to turn that into the dabs I
want today's spin
Spence spend about 4 or 5 hours teaching
me how to do that we ran a couple of
batches I got to run some tubes myself
I've got all the way up to the point
when we put it in the back of it I
understand all of that and I understand
the back of and I just don't know the
controls on the oven very well myself
once I get that comfortable I think I
can make pretty good quality shatter
there's a batch of my shatter that I
blasted sitting in the back of and right
now waiting for me to check it out in
about 48 hours Spence is gonna flip it
because it's in his facility but we'll
go from seed to shatter it'll go all the
way from the germination all the way to
my dabber now Congrats yeah I've watched
and tried once out of the comfort zone
I've been really I was comfortable I
realize that was comfortable for a year
like I had go and I haven't done
anything for a year I've got I've
expanded and learned and grown but now
I've got this new girl facility with 227
lights now I'm learning how to make cash
I'm definitely getting out of the
comfort zone just 3 ounces your favorite
lemon Geoffrey and just run it and see
what happens
my forearms are a little there's a lot
of work involved yeah it's not as easy
as you might think gonna be making dabs
this podcast is brought to you by our
good friends at highly educated titanium
if you're using high quality
concentrates made by Rasta Jeff or
garden of Weeden or even this water hash
solvent list what do you call a chunk
full melt hash that Shawn made and
brought over that stuff is tasty and
dank you deserve a high quality titanium
nail that's made right here in America
they're made in Provo Utah by our good
friend task rock don't trust a cheap
Chinese nail don't trust an American
knockoff made of cheap crappy metals
trust the industry leader the innovator
the Kings trust our good friends highly
educated titanium make sure you check
out highly educated ti.com for more
information if you want to buy yourself
a highly educated product or if you want
to buy somebody else a highly educated
titanium gift you should head to Aqualab
technologies calm right now and place
your order and get that Christmas gift
in for your favorite dabber I think
every dabber would like a brand new
titanium nail they've got a nail little
feature 14 and your 18 millimeter rig
they've got one will fit your 10 your 11
in your 12 you can get a carb cap to go
with that I think that would make
anybody at this table pretty happy if
you got a nail and a carb cap in the
mail torch jeez I also want to give a
big thanks to Adams thank you you helped
me out a whole bunch you try to help me
transplant a large number of plants and
it took us hours and I appreciate that
also shout out to Mike Mike helped a lot
we got our fingernails real dirty we got
sweaty I made these guys listen to
reggae and then we got tired and
something really weird happened at the
grow I blasted Pantera
loud as it would freakin go for a good
album worth and that's really out of
character for me but it got us pumped up
we were a little bit getting burned out
that Pantera really got the mosh pit in
the room going where's the rest of the
work and there was no more work so yeah
it worked it went pretty quickly you
guys knocked it out so huge thanks dude
I got it done it took the three of us
most of the night so imagine watching me
try to do that myself as I've said it's
a learning process for me so gonna do a
couple quick ads and then we'll keep
this going trying to keep the momentum
going in the conversation this podcast
is brought to you by our friends at
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics lopata labs rare dankness
mile hike an adventure the cali
connection and a whole bunch of other
sweet sweet breeders nature's green
remedies is running a special for our
loyal podcast listeners type in coupon
code frosty for 15% off any order and
you always get free priority shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com a coupon
code is good for any brand in stock but
it does expire at the end of this month
so take advantage of this offer before
the 31st if you get some Christmas money
or if your girlfriend and or boyfriend
is a pot grower or if you're trying to
get your boyfriend to grow pot go to
nature's green remedies calm and order
them some seeds and give them seeds for
Christmas and that's like inspiration to
get somebody to grow weed I know that a
few of my friends are getting packs of
seeds so that they'll start growing the
weed they keep talking [ __ ] that they're
gonna grow I'm gonna grow weed one day
you're some seeds now you gotta get on
that [ __ ] these are good seed there
don't let them sit around cuz I'm your
friend and I know I gave them to you I'm
gonna ask about them every month how are
they how are they speaking of seeds I've
given people huge shout out to Maddie
she's grown an experimental strain think
I saw that did you see that it's the
Girl Scout cookies frosted a kink in
grape stomp ROG and she killed it bro
Maddie got her own little gross base
over at the garden of Weeden and she put
some of my seeds in there and they look
freakin marvelous so good job Maddie I'm
proud of you they look great I got
dinner weekend then like I said it was
pleasure to meet them
I guess smell finally some of the stuff
that I've been looking at Instagram for
the past three months so you Jesse a
shout-out for absolutely
Jesse you know thank you for letting me
and my wife get out of the house for a
change and
putting me to work so I can pay some
bills for sure but Thanksgiving though
invited you to dinner
yeah they weren't giving anymore
speaking of Jesse this podcast is
brought to you by high Gro indoor
growing supplies I grow indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado check out the Denver store 62
71 beach street or go to the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies you
guys high grow is small they might not
have everything you need when you go
there but they will get it they're still
building their inventory they don't want
to order a bunch of [ __ ] they don't need
and then try to sell you that they'd
rather wait until you go in there and
say you guys don't have this and they'll
go we didn't know you wanted it will
order it for you and we will have it all
the time now I can rely on them once I
say order this I said hi Grizz I'm they
always have hydros I'm we have kind of
ran out the og tea company it's taken a
minute to get OGT in stock but once I
get it they'll have it back what was I
gonna say when you checkout it hi
growing or growing supplies make sure
you tell them you listen to the hydro
culture podcast and you will get
commercial pricing that's good for
everybody just say that all you gotta do
is talk who doesn't talk all day just
say some [ __ ] and you'll get a discount
I'm gonna do one more addicts I got a
lot of cool stuff to say to Shawn and
he's sitting here patiently twiddling
his carb Catholic he wants to hear the
questions I've got brought to you by our
friends at tree hugger com tree hugger
com live music lifestyle magazine check
out tree hugger calm for concert and
festival news and reviews
www.truegreenroofing.com I won't write
it but I know the faction will be up
there because a lot of the hippies like
it bro you can put the rig by the mic
nobody minds here though yeah make them
feel like they're there with us listen
to your torch
um also I'm gonna read part of an email
I want to give a shout outs so that's
all the commercials guys if you're fast
forwarding through commercials you could
stop right now I just listened to this
part I gotta find my phone I have a
couple of notes on my phone did I want
to make sure I read go ahead Adam you
got something for me
I on the forums the other day I was just
looking through there it seems like
you're getting more response in the
forums as well it's not like a dramatic
but when I logged in there was only like
X amount of users and now there's you
know just a little because every one of
those people I'm [ __ ] grateful for 63
I say there are [ __ ] 63 yeah and I'm
making up a number but I'm excited for
each one of them genetics Colorado
website forum so that's I post a lot of
stuff there I haven't been there for
like a week because I got this new job
and I've been kind of scrambling to get
a whole bunch of [ __ ] done before I
start there but trust me I'll be back I
live on that website sometimes I want to
give a shout out to our good friend Jake
Jake sent me an email
i canti can't read the whole thing
because of some of the stuff that he
says he kind of asked me not to say some
stuff that he wrote but he ends this
with congrats on the new job and keep up
the good work you're doing your part in
making my 12-hour shift bearable and for
that I am grateful so big up dude thanks
for the compliments that kind of stuff
right there makes the hours that I put
into this show worth it it makes these
guys come in Sean puts part of his day
aside to come here and hang out Adam has
to break away from his family Jessi's
got a construction company agro-business
a hydro shop these guys have to break
away from their lives so here these
complements really lets us know that
you're loving it makes it worth it
honestly to me do it even if you did but
it really it's like yay someone's
listening so a big shout out to Jake I
appreciate it bro that's pretty awesome
that you did that but I won't say the
rest of your message because you said
some cool stuff that I don't need to say
let's get into the news you guys wanna
talk to the news real quick or do you
want me to ask some questions there's a
lot of cool have an opinion on this I
just want to give Sean some women to
talk he's patient and quiet over there
nice and polite
in local news I hope you guys have an
opinion on this it's not really cannabis
related but the Westboro Baptist Church
is coming to our town to pick it at our
courthouse
and it to local dispensaries they're
coming here because our town supports
gay rights we have a a gay woman who is
one of our representatives and she's a
cool ass lady and I support her in every
way and what Westboro Baptist Church
wants to come here and protest us
because we have gay rights here and then
once they're done protesting at our
courthouse they're gonna go to two
dispensaries and protest over there in
Pueblo West I'm flattered you guys are
coming but [ __ ] off we don't need you we
are our own town we're adults what are
you gonna do to go worry about your own
damn town do that over there in my
opinion no matter what religion you are
no matter what you believe in I think be
kind and love everybody is what you're
supposed to do and they're being very
hypocritical they're not being kind
they're not loving anybody they're
preaching hey they're driving from
another they're driving from Kansas to
come to Colorado to show how angry they
are at us I didn't realize they were
that close
absolutely don't you have some [ __ ] to
do at home I can't be presumptuous do
you think that while mom and dad are
here protesting the little Jimmy's
smoking a joint in Kansas and little
Sara's getting butt-fucked by jimmies
older brother protesting I've seen my
hopes your children that they gay and
smoking weed while they're here
protesting watching duck dynasty
watching duck dynasty watching porn gay
smoking weed drinking 40s mm-hmm wearing
camo saying the n-word but but not in a
racial word coming out calling it home
it's back to the polo shirts and yes
mama but I truly am flattered there are
a lot of places for them to go and they
chose here because we have gay rights
and cannabis I just figured they'd run
it out there
places to go I don't want to be
offensive to a lot of people just just
the West I can't even say the name of
them they bother me so much just this
one group they just pissed me off and I
said a lot of rich I don't want to know
the name of the dispensary side of it
they're going to Marisol is the first
one they listed you know what I think I
took a screenshot of the article here
because that's how I was just saving
news on my phone no I didn't take a
screenshot of the article but another
going to Marisol and one other one odd
and if you said the name of it it may be
Pablo West organics actually but it was
not the spot shout-out to the spot
that's the spot that I would represent
they should go there that's one of the
good weeds gonna be so that's our local
news in bigger news Colorado is being
sued by I'm looking for the article on
my phone Colorado is being sued by the
states of Nebraska and Oklahoma have you
heard about this to join over there he
looks like he's ready for this story
today the states of Nebraska and
Oklahoma announced that they have filed
lawsuits against Colorado alleging that
Colorado's amendment 64 is
unconstitutional Colorado's Attorney
General John Suthers issued the
following statement in response because
neighboring states have expressed
concern about Colorado grown marijuana
coming into their states we are not
entirely surprised by this action
however it appears the plaintiffs
primary grievance stems from a non
enforcement of federal laws regarding
marijuana as opposed to choices made by
the others of Colorado we believe this
suit is without merit and we will
vigorously defend it against it in the
US Supreme Court
so Nebraska and Oklahoma are trying to
sue Colorado because we are not
following federal rule they're gonna try
to force the feds to come in here and
clean up the weeds seem that we've
created they're Giglio that money you
think they're jelly no but those aren't
states that pretty much lock you up
forever for having herb they don't like
it at all there I know it's happening
because I know people we read about him
getting busted all the time people are
definitely driving pounds pounds and
pounds out of this state because we're
able to produce it do you really think
it was any more than before yes
um there there is more cannabis smaller
amount yes and more personal were you
here for the wild wild west revolution
that I talked about when everybody got a
red card there was nobody to care to
regulate it just glue and you could grow
I could walk into your shop at the
backpack full of quarter pounds and
selling me yeah so imagine if you were
getting here it was seven to eight maybe
nine if you could really hustle the shop
for a quarter pound but I know friends
that will maybe send [ __ ] to the East
Coast and they can get 15 for that same
quarter pound to their cousin that lived
or their brother that lives out there
and they just don't give a [ __ ] they're
like why not and they'll just send it or
drive it out there what's - if you're a
20-something year old kid with no kids
the weeds I feel like the weeds just
gonna be moving across those states
anyways regardless of whether they sue
us it'll just go right back to wherever
they be the solution would just be
nationwide legalization you know
medicine without borders we just start a
new a new program medicine without
borders you just make it known and we'll
just drive around you're there talking
about it to converse as well how rich
rich in there get it before the show and
I think that would help yeah yeah
convinced just in jail bro just I think
what you saw was on the onion and I
don't think that that was wrong I don't
know Kirsty pointed it out to me yeah
[Music]
that I spend a little bit of time and we
makes it alright it makes it not so
annoying
oh yeah us in there well that's why we
tears - Brett helps with depression it
makes things it's
oh yeah absolutely that's why people get
they have to work at Taco Bell all day
get [ __ ] blazed written before they go
to Taco Bell all day when you try to
order your food it was way higher than
we were and that's saying something yeah
there's a time and place for that I've
got an article my oh look it's
refreshing we might not have internet
service on computer if that happens then
we're making a 45-minute video on how
about it sucks for medical marijuana
states on a federal level is the next
article here it's from the cannabis and
it's published December 12th and is from
Kyle Potter of The Associated Press and
it says buried deep inside the 1600 page
funding bill Congress is scrambling to
pass to avert a shutdown a few lines can
fall come sorry let me try that again a
few lines comforted Minnesota officials
worried about the federal government
cracking down on the state to mental
medical marijuana program I'm gonna kind
of skim a little bit here because I want
to get to more of this stuff I just
wanted to read this one in its current
form the 1.1 trillion dollar spending
bill includes a section that bans the
Department of Justice from using federal
funds to intervene with states with
medical marijuana laws that's the best
part right there I can almost stop the
whole article right there so what that
says is I'm gonna read it again in its
current form the 1.1 trillion dollar
spending bill the rep your money name
wrap your head around that [ __ ]
number real quick 1.1 trillion dollars
but then it says bans the Department of
Justice from using federal funds to
intervene in states with medical
marijuana laws which means they can't
[ __ ] with us now I mean they can cuz
they'll find a way yeah but they're not
gonna mess with the states they're not
gonna try to come and make us which are
laws back they're not gonna I don't
think they're gonna continue with raids
they're still gonna be illegal grow-ops
they're still gonna be illegal stuff
going on that they're gonna have to
this is 23 states have legalized medical
marijuana but those measures still
conflict with federal law and though the
Obama administration has generally been
friendlier to marijuana than
administration's past Monson regala
wondered what if that changes or a new
president changes court changes course
the US House narrowly passed the funding
bill with the medical marijuana section
Thursday at this Senate was expected to
take it up Friday so he doubts the bill
will markedly change the government's
handling of the issue most attorneys
have indicated they won't go after
medical marijuana businesses so as there
as long as they're following state laws
so the point is I think it gives them a
little more comfort and I wouldn't say
it gives very much more comfort but you
never know he continued the bottom line
is it's still illegal under federal law
so anything could happen but they don't
have funding so what are they gonna do
these cops are gonna go and raid [ __ ] on
their own time are they but I mean then
you're also if the cops gonna go off and
do that on his own time without support
he may be looking for that lucrative
income yeah that's not gonna fly in
Colorado it sounds like to me it's gonna
lead to back to cops all right so we've
done like 25 minutes let's get into some
talk about this organics stuff I want to
make sure that I got through all the
important part paid all the bills yeah
I'm good I'm caught up I'm paying almost
a real show you wouldn't even believe it
episode 50 is coming up and I'm getting
excited starting to think about what we
can give away hey Jesse if you're
listening do remember you guys kind of
volunteered to give some [ __ ] away on
number 50 we got to talk about that so
we've been kind of like trying to figure
out what to give away nice
so he's been bouncing things off me and
I've been bouncing things off him and he
let us know what you want if you guys
wasn't in tweet me at high grow culture
or you email me I grow culture at
hotmail.com let us know what you want
for giveaway prizes and we'll see if we
can't accommodate you so Sean's here the
guy that talked to a whole bunch about
cool organic [ __ ] King Cola you guys
love that show
drying and curing and that organics
episode have been my two most popular
episodes out of 44 episodes
yes people learned a lot of people asked
a lot of questions I can't shout out
everybody that he mailed me texted me
tweeted me because I would spend the
whole show doing it but we got a lot of
response on that I want to talk more
about worm castings mostly because
that's kind of what seemed to be the
base of a lot of your stuff and a lot of
what got the conversation going I'm
gonna jump back we were talking about
worm castings we've got four basic - you
said worm castings in molasses
and you mentioned multiplying the
protozoa is something that you really
stressed so first of all I guess my main
question I should ask is what are
protozoa in Despres it's not just the
protozoa it's everything it's all of the
microbes and fungi so you're just gonna
give them a food source and really give
them a chance to thrive and grow so all
of those things actually fall under the
category of protozoa know the protozoa
are a specific I can't think the term
right off of my head but yeah it's just
a certain microbe I'd seen the word but
I never paid attention until you open my
mind to it actually so since we're on
the subject we have been feeding our
worms
we've been substituting alfalfa with
cannabis yeah we were donated a little
over 3000 pounds of what we call canna
meal which is finely ground material
from a local actually I can open vape
are you familiar with the company they
sell vapor pins and Organa labs they
donated the material by law by state law
all dispensaries have to dispose of
their waste and unfortunately a lot of
people are just mixing it with old dirt
and throwing it in a dumpster it's going
to a landfill we've been feeding it to
our worms kind of as a test trial worms
loved it they really did we just are we
just
our test results back today actually and
the it was off the chart I mean it
really was see what we had a second bear
with him he's digging through the hi
phone always takes a minute I mean the
Rocky Mountain one company has
definitely been the conversation work
for those most of the week anyways
that's good he really takes pride in
what he does and he feeds his worms the
highest quality everything and then it
seems to be the important part it really
is you know he he he makes them produce
what you want yeah everybody's so
focused on cost
everybody wants the cheapest casting out
there and they don't really understand
that you're only hurting yourself yeah
if you want like keep saying if you're
gonna cut costs on the grow then cut the
cost of the sale too and they don't want
to do that they want to cut cost and one
in it's not fair and with these castings
you can take your compost and cut you
know ten to 15% of the compost and then
make your own vermicompost and then cut
that in one part peat moss one part
aeration one part vermicompost there's
your base oil you can add in your
amendments like your crab meal and your
azomite cope and I'll file for whatever
you're gonna add you know there's your
mix oil and it's really that simple but
Jays been feeding his worms cannabis
plant matter and they have been freaking
loving it test results were astronomical
compared ibly to running the alfalfa the
biological life was off the chart I mean
we
gained hundreds of protozoa fungi
bacteria the act of fungi which means
basically the things that are working in
the soil before we had a higher fungal
content but that doesn't really mean
much if they're not active we have a
lower fungal content but more activity
so you want more bio life yeah this
stuff is so freakin bio diverse it's
amazing I'm so excited about it
so feeding a cannabis made it better
you're gonna feed that to your cannabis
those leaves back to those worms self
sustainable system and we all got to get
away from the bottles I've been reading
more about us and Sean kind of talked
about it and we're paying for shipping
and water there's just so much preserve
it they gotta make it stable and it's
got to be elated or buffer or yeah then
it's gotta be shipped and it's gotta be
able to stay in different temperatures
and it's gonna have a shelf life you
could just make it yourself 24 hours
before you yeah you can smell it it's so
much richer yes you're not throwing away
plastic for all the neighbors to see
your freaking botanic air bottles in the
trash can they don't need that so you
talked about multiplying the protozoa
what's the best way to go about that
basically you just need to give them a
food source so when you when you give
like make sure T up so you basically
what you're gonna do is you're gonna add
in your worm castings and then you're
gonna put in your food source and that's
amazing I'm gonna back up just first
time using a five-gallon bucket yeah so
a five-gallon bucket like a nylon or
something to keep all the stuff in I
preach free suspension teas bucket get
your hopefully reverse osmosis water or
at least doc let it bubble for a couple
of days get the air out
and then put all your your worm castings
your molasses and whatever else you
decide to put in there exactly can you
can expand on it as you please you
talked about a lot of cool [ __ ] to put
in there hope you're paying attention
yeah basically yes so you get your
bucket you get your hair stones castings
and molasses you're gonna throw that in
there and you're gonna just want to brew
it from 12 to 24 hours I really wouldn't
recommend taking it anything over that
if you're not familiar with brewing
something you guys it's gonna bubble up
and hopefully it's gonna bubble up huge
[Music]
nice I've seen some of your pictures
yeah all right so we just want to up
feed them and put them in a bucket and
give them some oxygen and they will
multiply
do you know the ratio they multiply are
we gonna give them like 10,000 times or
a thousand times more it's pretty
amazing
check out anybody who's listening that's
interested in this google microbe man
and he's got amazing articles about brew
times and how you can you know take them
longer for more fungal dominated or
times more bacterial domina teas how you
can actually kind of cook your letter
inoculate your ingredients for your
compost tea to make a more fungal
dominant so you can take your earthworm
castings and sprinkle in a little bit of
oatmeal like so let's say that you're
gonna use three cups so I mean for
example I mixed a fifteen gallon tear
there I used 3 and 3/4 cups of worm
castings right and I knew I was gonna
use that much so what I did is I took
that 3 and 3/4 cup of where I'm castings
and put it in a mason jar added some oat
bran spray it with a water bottle and
sealed it up about two days ago and then
today I went down into my basement and
cracked it open and it smells sweet it
was covered in white goodness you know
bacteria and I use that for my tea and
that's a weighted fungal charge the [ __ ]
yeah it sounds like wow that's pretty
sweet and cannabis plants love fungal
dominance and so that's gonna make
instead of those little scraggly shooty
roots you see it's gonna make big thick
white spaghetti for roots right exact
you know with the when you do the free
suspension teas and you kinda get
Messier your drip trays will fill up
with dirt you know how it get to the
engine and I've seen my roots will grow
right into that dirt bottom of the pot
and they just can't get enough of it I'm
definitely I need to go so the stores in
Colorado Springs I live about 45 minutes
away from there I'm going to plan a trip
up there quite soon I hear within the
next week I've got some freshly
transplanted stuff that I want to feed
some Rocky Mountain worm tea you keep
talking about has a bite do I want I've
always thought of as my is something I
wanted to add flour do I want that in my
face as well recommend until your
flowering especially if you're you know
not transplanting really yeah okay all
right
yeah these plants I'm doing a little pop
yeah Haysom I know a lot of people who
will do uh worm castings grow Kashi and
he's in my every two weeks as a top
dress everybody's all grow Kashi is
really cool but I feel like a lot of
people are using it just to use it I
don't know if they really understand
what they're using it for the idea is
that it's lactic acid bacteria it's
photosynthetic bacteria
it's yeast it's a lot of other things
going on in there and you're gonna
introduce that into your root zone into
your plant and the grow cashew actually
help digest old roots
[Music]
see there's something else I'm gonna
learn it's gonna take me a little bit of
time but eventually I'm gonna get away
from all the bottled nutrients it's a
little overwhelming because I taught him
how to grow mostly with full bottled
stuff and he's over there shaking his
head like I have to really I saw the
seed process and I just clicked I
compared it to like cooking you know
like when you when you first start
cooking and you look
recipes online and stuff they're
freaking overwhelming beginners many
things that go into it but once you
acquire once you know your cabinets
filled with all this Rises it's nothing
it takes five minutes to you know whip
up a meal and it's the same thing with
the tea is it's overwhelming at first
but once you have castings and molasses
and kelp and Hydra sleep everything that
you use it's really nothing and then
you're buying all these things in bulk
so you're getting a mid a fraction of
the cost without water weight for
shipping - yeah yeah well you can buy
everything locally for between Jesse and
then there's there's absolutely what's a
good time for me to drop it like that's
about my style Monday through Friday
midday
[Music]
I'll be up there really soon I'll go get
some stuff oh man he spurts so many
questions so many questions I'm not sure
which one to pick I have I'll choose one
from a listener I gotta grab my phone
again I feel like I'm the wrong person
in this damn chair I feel like if Jesse
was here right now he would have been
all in this conversation and I'm just
sitting over here like with my mouth
open so that's great I'm love hearing
about this because I see it around in
all the the growing footage and [ __ ]
part of my show is to bring the growers
on your level and the growers on his
level to get one together because we're
not different I started first you were a
plan guitar or being a skateboarder or
you probably play xbox way better than
me
you might MMA fight as growing while
you're doing that I'll help you grow
some weed hopefully what I want to learn
how to MMA fight or some [ __ ] you're
down to teach me I live back east there
was nobody that was willing to teach you
and you know it's
I watched all the YouTube videos for
many many years so now being able to see
it firsthand and being able to have
different styles when I trim the first
time I thought you had a boner it's like
it got really weird yeah yeah when I
gave him that grateful dog he went nuts
it was so good wow what happened oh I
know what's happening I hope that
doesn't really affect the podcast here
phone call and it's popping up on my
computer because the new iOS know it's
working the new iOS 8 likes to do that
but anyway let's get back on track you
know did I like having you on because
you don't have to be a pro to be here
you you might ask the one question that
the listeners are wondering because
we're Sean and I kind of know what we're
saying and we just we get I've been told
that we're snobs don't we just talk
right over some points because we expect
everyone to know that wears off really
well to like it's it's just I go home
and show how like oh this so someone so
gave us some bud and I'm like I don't I
don't want that yeah I'm good now that
you've seen some things yeah we've kind
of opened Adam sighs but Adam first
moved here he would have smoked anything
I have smoked anything yeah you know
that guy that cleans out your ashtray
yeah and smokes the stuff out of your
ashtray yep so we got a actually there's
a facebook comment from our good buddy
Fred Fred Garvin Fred likes to comment
and I appreciate it dude so this one
says haha shout out Jeff hey episode 44
was rockin dude I caught that tease
about the next episode and map and death
I'm really interested in that I know
nothing about it except Cushman
yammering on about it being bad on a
couple other podcasts but that's it I
would like to know what it is is it bad
is it in my canna a and B cocoa and if
it is bad what synthetic new line should
I should i / we be looking at anyway
keep the shows come in and stay frosty
bro and thanks for what you do so first
of all I say dude thanks for freaking
sending us messages participating and
thanking us for what we do like I said
earlier that means a lot you catch that
something with digital on me that's cool
it's back though yeah thanks for the
question and so that's a question for
Shawn you were talking about mapping
I've been dap is see if I can say this
right it's mono ammonium phosphate in
diode potassium phosphate or something
similar to that I'll give it to you yeah
but basically they're they're chemicals
that are used in basically every single
high I drove product or synthetic
nutrient product on the shelf
they're synthetic salts the big problem
with them in my opinion is they don't
flush out of plants I have you know I
don't think that you can get them out
heavy metals and things like that are
stored in the tricone so once you kind
of get them in there there's no way to
get them out and if you're blasting
you're blasting those heavy metals into
your mix a couple of times - one of the
things that's filled with heavy metals
so you really want to be live you don't
want to use too much of that stuff
glacial rock dust filled with heavy
metals so it's not just our synthetics
you know that are filled with these
things but mono map and dap are probably
the worst of all just in the simple fact
that they're the most common and it's
easy it's something easy to look out for
and I'm not telling you they're like a
runaway from the map and dad but it's if
you're somebody who's interested in a
cleaner product something that's a
little bit more organic you know you
need to become familiar with the terms
that you need to look out for and those
are some of them if you're looking for a
nice organic product looked for
something with like soybean meal or kelp
or alfalfa Brewers Easter whole
synthetic offer stuff like yeah so
synthetics is a killer so good
especially if he's ranked Anna I mean if
you're in Canada then your bio biz is an
organic nutrient line that's very
similar style of growing really high
quality stuff or grain on Instagram yeah
everybody probably follows that guy he
straight crushes it all by a biz
I don't know if you really talked to
that way he uses because he's got
amazing good progress this is a really
good one to use general organics that's
you know that's another one to use
that's really good but I don't use
things like that so it's just printed on
the bottle as mono ammonium phosphate
yes okay so if you're looking for it
that's map and DAP is the dye oh trying
to avoid that that those are the Tula to
stray from and I know I'm just parroting
what Cushman says but Cushman says if
that's often what it gives you when you
smoke good weed and for some reason you
get a headache and you're like that was
good herb why did it give me a headache
it had map and app residuals in it I
can't prove that but that's what Cushman
has led me to believe from everything he
said and I mostly trust Cushman there's
no reason not to trust Cushman in my
opinion names with this began as one a
couple of cups he really knows what the
plant wants yeah I'll take his word for
it yeah do you recycle your soil yes
yeah I don't like to recycle okay I
really don't I really don't if I recycle
my so I like my veggie garden
I just haven't mastered that yet okay um
I always see a loss in yield no matter
I've blamed it on other things and
haven't attributed it to that I always
these worm castings are gonna help me uh
problem I'm having better luck
starting with sterile media's I used to
run like happy frog and roots and stuff
like that switched it up to more of like
a premix base got a lot better results
out of that now I'm running my own like
vermicompost peat moss and buckwheat
hole with amendments and stuff but the
pro mix and stuff I'm getting better
results with reusing the soil it's a lot
easier to amend it at the beginning of
being a sterile media okay I can write
down how much of what I put into it and
basically if my plant doesn't show a
deficiency throughout that cycle I just
remand everything like I would you know
brand new soil mix and grow right back
into it where is running the Fox farm
and the roots organic I feel like with
the guano's and the blood meals and
everything that's already in there plus
me amending it by the end of the cycle
sure the Marten I have been having any
deficiencies but I really don't know
once it's oils yeah yeah okay that's
kind of where I'm at with reusing soil
[Music]
using mixes so this is kind of what I
found to do what I've been doing with my
soil lately so I take it and mix it with
this stuff out of my boo Kashi bucket
like all of the slimy leftover pickle
trash that ends up in your book Hoshi
bucket so I just mix it in with my soil
and it looks like you're making him
hungry
you just dump it out into your you know
into like a Rubbermaid container fill it
up with dirt and then just let it sit
and then basically you know in a couple
of weeks or a month or two or whenever I
get around to going back to those
buckets
it'll be compost and then I'll mix that
with worm castings use that as a
vermicompost for my soil so I use it up
a lot of space aren't you storing
everything any weird experience just
email Jeff yeah there we go and I also
have a friend in California who Walter
bugs yeah yeah if you've got a plant
with bugs he wants you to clip off the
leaf of that or a branch of that plant
and send it to him so that he can play
with the bugs that's his specialty
that's cool yeah a treat John what's up
bro hope you're listening tree town
farmer people are hardcore I'm gonna
find ya yeah that's the truth Adams a
good little transplant and grunt worker
he does some [ __ ] in the gardens just
worked I walked in the room and him and
this other dude had dirt flying three
feet in the air and all of it was
landing in two pots I don't know how I
was working that's right no you
definitely work at a different pace than
what my what should I not use it buy
organic so it's gonna be my last
question for the day yeah it depends on
your level but the first thing that I
would kick out would be blood meal above
meal okay
if you really care about organics
chances are you don't eat GMOs and you
don't eat I'm not gonna say you're
vegetarian if you're you know if you're
into organics and stuff but those things
are byproducts of like the you know
slaughterhouse mystery feather meals a
byproduct of the poultry industry and
they have their place don't get me wrong
because I'd rather than be recycled into
agricultural byproducts for farm and
other agricultural uses but when it
comes to growing medicine for people I
don't believe that feather meal made
from chickens that were fed you know
antibiotics and hormones should be used
to grow a same thing with the blood that
scraped out the slaughterhouse floor to
make the blood meal it's just this
gelatinous goo filled with everything
that there was in that cow so if you're
gonna use things like that I would just
recommend there's other alternatives
like fish blood meal alfalfa kelp
I mean there's a lot of plant baits if
you really want to get into it comfrey
and burdock root nettle and the woods
pick a bunch of sheets am I gonna come
back from the rocky mountain worm
company with a whole backseat full of
brand-new [ __ ] and rethink my whole
growing mint the first time I go in here
probably will and the cool thing is
you're gonna you'll probably see a
couple of things that you've seen if
you're gonna be going up to Jay's check
out the see crop that's a little secret
that I use in my garden but I use it to
basically replace my full power bar if
anybody out there is familiar with full
power or fulvic acid
okay there's scientific studies I hope
you'll be there when I go yeah the
fungal for the girlfriend so I gotta
sneak away while she's at work sneak up
there
one casting firms one more gift for her
gift more self-sufficient come by Rocky
Mountain Company yeah yeah Rocky what
about warm company they listen to the
podcast cuz they said they liked it hey
guys uh I'm gonna come get some worm
castings and we should talk about some
sponsorship sort of stuff because people
seem to be responding to you and I want
to support semi local [ __ ] your Colorado
your Colorado Springs that's not low but
I still love it like to support that
let's see if we can do something I'll
brag about worm castings and you supply
me with worm castings appreciate that
they're doing a great thing I'm excited
to get in there and learn about it oh
man we've done 55 min three minutes
let's start closing up the show dude I
gotta have you back on more I like what
you we get sidetrack as we're potheads
but I like having you on and you have a
lot of useful [ __ ] to share with us
anybody has any questions there we go
we'll have them ready next time the mati
factor also big shout-out to sweet
Angela for getting me addicted to the
yerba Mattei I love you babe but Jesus
Monta I don't know what you've done to
me you've created a monster
Mantes so great the best idea we had
that was buying bags to bring it home
and make it so now we don't have to
drive to our favorite MOT a spot in
Colorado Smyrna and Manitou Springs
every time we want latte because we
would do so I hate to say it I'm more
comfortable in Manitou Springs than I am
here in Pueblo but I feel like I have
more friends that are more open to go
out of the house here because it's it's
weird here there's nothing to really go
have fun enjoy the day I was in
California to take care of something if
you walk in there and go we stick
together over Maddy's good job on
holding down the plants I give a
shout-out to my chick if we're talking
about that my chick knows her way around
the garden bro if I need anything done
she can definitely do it oh here goes my
phone again dude I just mentioned her
she started calling anybody else - so
you know I'm I'm there busting my butt
but it's yeah
thank you Wow phone ringing oh nice got
off work early we might have some food
cool let's wrap up the show I know the
show's over please go to iTunes or
stitcher over the iTunes Store or the
stitcher main page
they're trying real culture find the
review section give us a five star
rating you can give me as many stars as
you feel like honestly but what I want
you to do is type in a comment and let
me know what you think of the podcast
and I will read your comments on the
show don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is archived on ira
genetics colorado comm make sure you
follow us on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook just search for I grow culture
follow
I read genetics on Instagram I had
10,000 followers but then they went did
some cleaning up and I got 9,500 so give
me back up to 10,000 followers that'd be
cool if you're interested in sponsoring
the podcast or if you have a product
you'd like us to review send me an email
at agriculture at hotmail.com and I'll
get you all the information you need we
are gonna change the name it's gonna be
the girl from your heart podcast you'll
still be able to find it I'll advertise
we won't go away it'll just be a
different title we do need a theme song
and a new logo if anybody started
working on that one
big shout out everybody that keeps
listening and be prepared for episode 50
because we're gonna do some giveaways
there'd be some at least stickers Jessi
mentioned some things from the hydro
shop there be an IRA genetics t-shirt in
there maybe a hat maybe some Jennie
Cushman I've had around for a while that
nobody claimed the back in the day I've
got a Jenny cush pin that needs a home
anyway guys keep listening in the show I
really appreciate you for hanging out
big shout out to my ninja Spence he
taught me how to make cash today you
teach a man to fish bro yeah it's on now
game on big shout-out to you guys for
coming out these guys will be back on
the show thanks thank you for listening
you guys until next time take a phat dab
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's up everybody it's time for
another episode of the agriculture
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation welcome to
episode number 46
I'm your host Rasta Jeff I'm coming to
you this week with a solo episode it's
the day after Christmas and all my
friends are hanging out with their
family so I put together a quick show
this week and I'll probably do a short
episode next week also I hope everybody
had a wonderful holiday holiday
whichever holiday you choose to
celebrate hope it was wonderful for you
I owe a huge thank you to my mom for an
amazing Christmas gift I cannot believe
what my mom put together for me
big thanks mom and also a big thanks to
my clean thanks a lot Angela he made
Christmas awesome I'm glad you spent
that with my family and I your family
now also I owe a big Christmas shoutout
to the garden of Weeden they let me be a
part of your Secret Santa that was
really cool I felt blessed to be there
that was a good time I think I'm still
dabbed out from the dab gauntlet we did
and I'm wearing the socks that I scored
at the Secret Santa Exchange right now I
got my hub socks on and my feet are nice
and warm so and it's a cold-ass night
here in Colorado holy [ __ ] it's snowing
out it's windy as [ __ ] so these socks
came in perfectly thank you guys if
you're in Colorado hope you're warm next
week is a New Year's Eve actually so I
will be at the stream Cheese Incident
concerts in Broomfield Colorado with my
lady now we're taking a little mini
vacation so next weekend this week will
be kind of easy shows without a ton of
info but I do promise you guys then I'll
get back to the original format with
tons of info and great guests at the
start of the year the holidays got
everybody in chaos everybody is we're
all growers and we all have jobs and
families so most of the guys just
decided to hang out and not do a show
with me this week which is cool I don't
blame them I hope you guys are having
fun big shout out to everybody who has
been on the show who's taken some time
out of their life to come put in an hour
an hour and a half with the iGrow
culture podcast that's pretty cool I
appreciate it the listeners love you
guys so I got a few people to thank and
a few things to remind you guys of but
before we get into too much of that part
let's pay the bills let's start with
nature's green remedies this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm 4-gauge
green genetics la plata labs Sin City
rare dankness mile-high Kenna venture
the Cali connection
read genetics and many more trusted
brands nature's green remedies is
running a special for all of our loyal
podcast listeners if you type in coupon
code frosty you'll get 15% off your
whole order and you get free priority
shipping and nature's green remedies
calm but this coupon code does expire on
the first so you have until December
31st to get this coupon code in I will
have a new coupon code for you around
the start of the year so big thanks so
much respect to nature's green remedies
dot-com this podcast is also brought to
you by our friends at hydro indoor
growing supplies hydro indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado check out the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado guys if you go to the
4th Street location in Pueblo there's no
parking take a right right at the corner
there's a taco place right there and
then turn into the alley con area and
that first door is actually hydro
there's parking in the back go park back
there it's a lot easier to carry your
stuff out of the back also
so check out hydro for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies don't forget that hydro
runs a special for the podcast listeners
when you check out hydro tell them you
listen to the agriculture podcast and
they will give you commercial pricing on
your entire purchase is they had a whole
bunch of advanced nutrients stuff at the
Pueblo location and they're dying to get
rid of it if you went in there and made
them an offer on a bunch of advanced
nutrients products
I bet Bern and Jesse would hook you up
tell them I listen to the hydro culture
podcast Jeff said to come in here and
get these nutrients and they'll give you
a deal
so this podcast is also brought to you
by our good friends at tree hugger com
tree hugger com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger com4
concert and festival news and reviews
WWE thugger calm
all right much respect all the sponsors
for making the show possible big shout
out to the mystic roots band that's
something that just played was from the
mystic roots band they let me play all
of their music on the show so every
episode I tried to give them a shout out
mystic roots band they're awesome
they're SoCal reggae kind of funk reggae
they got a lot of cool stuff going on
they're probably going to play in your
neighborhood sometime soon those kids
travel around actually they are in
Europe right now the last pictures I saw
they were in Italy man it's good to see
the mystic roots man in Italy I think
they're just out having fun I don't know
if they're playing but all the pictures
I've seen is just them on vacation and
that is well-deserved guys I hope you
guys are having a great vacation
shout out to captain kuda the mystic
roots band check them out they're great
let's see it's got a bunch of comments
and stuff to read what do I want to do
first I've taken a bunch of dads tonight
so I want to remind you guys we're gonna
change the name of the podcast the show
is not going to be the agriculture
podcast for much longer it will be
called the grow from your heart podcast
like I've said before there's an
agricultural educational entity that has
the moniker I grow taken and also I was
told that iTunes doesn't appreciate
people ripping off the eye so we're just
gonna be respectful we're gonna change
it to grow from your heart because
that's what this is all about I've
always said grow from your heart if you
draw your herb
your cannabis your medicine from your
heart you will produce better cannabis
if you don't grow your cannabis from
your wallet or your ego or your camera I
know I take a lot of pictures but I grow
dank herb because I grow from my heart
that's why I'm able to take the dank
pictures I'm not thinking about my
wallet I'm not thinking about the
harvest weight pay attention to that
stuff but I'm in the grow room I'm
thinking about what's gonna happen after
I grow this herb properly that's great
flush it after I chop it down after a
trim it after I cure it after I give it
to my patients that smoke this cannabis
I've got an older friend his initials
are DC I don't really want to call him
out on the show but he's who I think of
when I think of medical cannabis it's a
good friend of mine and I'm his
caregiver what I see him consume the
herb that I put my love into I can see
him get something inside of him feels
better and it's not just a physical
thing it's not just him getting high
there's
emotional thing that happens to that guy
when my medicine makes him feel better
and that emotional thing happens back to
me and it fulfills my heart so I grow
from my heart and you should grow from
your heart as well and I think it'll
improve your outlook on your weed it'll
improve your cannabis overall it will
improve your relationship with your
patients from the scale from your camera
from your heart so the girl from your
heart podcast that's our new motto grow
from your heart requires a new logo I
can't change the name until I have a
sweet-ass new logo so if any of you
artists out there would like to throw me
down a grow from your heart podcast
hosted by Rasta Jeff logo I would
appreciate it I don't have a lot of
money to tell you the truth but I would
compensate you in some way that made you
happy it may take time it may take
payments it may take multiple gifts over
time we will work something out because
uh I like to pay back my community that
helps me out now you like to help your
community out so do me a favor make me a
logo I have this vision actually it's a
seed like if you've ever grown pot when
you germinate seeds they crack open and
the tap root comes out of there
when that cracks open it kind of makes
the shape of a heart so if you can kind
of make that into actually turning into
maybe I don't know you get creative but
I want to see that heart coming out or
just whatever with the heart in it or
grow from your heart of course I like
red yellow and green
I'm a Rastafarian if you do that I've
never said this on a podcast if you're
gonna make a Rastafarian themed logo the
red goes on the bottom you guys it's red
gold and green yes red yellow green but
the red is on the bottom so it's
actually green yellow red
so do that properly if you're gonna make
me a logo because I'm a Rasta and I want
it right because it's almost
disrespectful to put your logo with the
colors upside down if you're bringing it
and a Rasta way I'm not gonna [ __ ]
about it I'm just saying do it the right
way if you're a real Rasta you'll
understand why you want it the right way
so if I put the American flag upside
down it would piss a lot of Americans
off so just imagine you people getting
the Rasta flag backwards it kind of
frustrates some people I don't give too
much of a [ __ ] about it I'm just letting
you know that you're doing it wrong I've
been playing the mystic roots band it
sounds awesome but wouldn't it be a lot
cooler if I had
timaeus theme song that was like
something about drove from your heart I
don't even know how it would go but
maybe some dancehall reggae or something
from your heart that's your job not mine
if somebody's got a song for me I got
the same deal for you as I do the logo
some kind of kick down if you're in
Colorado I'll hand you packs of seed
you'll get I read genetics seeds
feminized or regular or both for
something out I'll give you a t-shirt
I'm gonna get more hoodies made more the
I read genetics hoodies are being
planned out shout out to handmade
apparel thorough we're negotiating had
to kind of hesitate a little bit I'm
gonna do it at the start of the year
just for tax purposes and then we'll get
some more hoodies maybe you'll get a
hoodie out of the deal so I'm begging
I'm just asking for a new logo and a new
theme song for the girl from your heart
podcast because too busy putting
together shows and growing gardens and
teaching people how to grow herb to
actually be able to I've been getting
emails dude holy crap getting so many
emails tweets and Facebook messages
about the podcast it's overwhelming in
such a good way I want to thank
everybody for messaging me the huge
response I've gotten the last few
episodes has really inspired me to push
the show to the next level
I've been putting more time into the
shows and doing more research because I
want to keep bringing the best show that
I can every time you guys message me
that makes me want to try a little bit
harder you know I just want to step it
up
let's see I've got a couple of tweets
that I saved here I've got them in my
phone so do the phone I know I just
don't want to bring you guys better
shows I bring you a half-assed New
Year's Eve show planned but I'm gonna
make it dope for you let's see big shout
out to party McFly
he says Rasta Jeff bro oh yeah you can
tweet me at the hydro culture ri grow
its at agriculture or you can also tweet
me it's a trois to Jeff 420 if you just
want to hit me directly I check them
both quite frequently like once a day
probably this dude says bro I love the
podcast it's the first podcast I've been
into I'm gonna have to start from the
beginning and catch up okay I'm
embarrassed that you're gonna do that
because honestly well let me not say I'm
embarrassed I guess I'm proud now the
first 25 episodes or so I didn't know
what I was doing
I turn on the microphone and just blurt
it out a bunch of [ __ ] whatever came out
of my face is how the show went and then
I started making too many notes and it
got a little weird but I feel like I'm
kind of comfortable with the microphone
now I just turn it on I start I make a
few bullet points and start going and it
all comes out I'm not so so hyper
critical of it now but dude party McFly
and the way you wrote your twitter
handle is pretty cool I can't even I
don't know what how you did that but
it's at frivilous fri vol a yes if you
want to follow a party McFly dude thanks
for the tweet that uh I hope you listen
to every single episode if you want to
listen to them all they're on iTunes I
think the last 10 are on stitcher but
every single episode all the way from
the beginning all the way up to whatever
episode you're on will always be on the
I region etics Colorado com website I'm
gonna have to change the tab on there
we're gonna do a lot of change any guys
don't get lost it's still gonna be in
the same feed so if you're listening on
itunes or stitcher or whatever the feed
will still be the same if you're coming
to the website it'll still be easy to
find don't lose me when I change my name
I just have to do it's super easy a help
so tardy me I'm rambling I took a bunch
of dabs a lot of dabs I made these dabs
even party McFly thanks for messaging me
on Twitter my next tweet came from
Roadrunner it's at Road underscore
Runner 420 he said listening from the UK
still underground here but great to see
you guys leading the way for us great
show keep it up dude thanks a lot those
words of encouragement mean a lot to me
like I was saying everybody wants to
hear that they're doing right
sometimes you just put a bunch of work
in nobody says anything and you're like
killing it so awesome thank you we've
gotten 6,500 listens on some episodes
the episode with King Cola is probably
gonna hit 10,000 episodes eventually
that will be the first one to do it
which is remarkable because it's a newer
episode and there's been a lot of time
on other shows and they haven't been
listening to nearly as much as the
episodes with King Cola so shot out to
King Cola and episode 35 with drying and
curing also has been a huge success if
you guys haven't listened to that one
it's time go back and listen to number
35 if I had a recommendation for you 35
and then
and the ones with keen Cola I don't
remember the numbers I could pause it
look hold on alright I went back and
checked I honestly think that from 35 on
is where if 35 through 45 are some of
our best episodes ever there are a
couple in there 44 is random chatter
because we got chatty and then 41 is
chatty stoners but for the most part the
35 through 45 are some of my favorite
most proud episodes 45 more about
organics with King Kola 43 intro to
organics with King Cola those are some
great episodes number 42 intro to NPK
that got a lot of response ah the
episodes about building your grow 39 and
40 those really crushed it 37 was
planning your gross space that did a lot
and 35 drying and curing definitely has
been listened to a whole bunch so thanks
a lot guys for listening to those it's
good to know that you're paying
attention to liking it I'm so rambley
today I'm glad I turn on the microphone
guys take a DAB I'm gonna take a DAB
right quick I've got some dabs sitting
here this is a mix of stuff that I
recently grew my homie spits taught me
how to make this hash I usually wasn't
making it other people do it but why not
be self-sufficient right this is a white
widow Girl Scout cookies no there's no
cookies in here it's white widow golden
go flow ghost oh gee there's Gorilla
Glue number four in here there's some
lemon Jeffrey in here there's lemon
skunk so this is quite a nice mix I'm
gonna take a big fat dad you guys take a
dab with me please
I only give a big shout-out to giddyup
Annie Motec I'm hitting this G nail I
bet it turned on for about a month now I
haven't turned it off and I'll think oh
that's a big WOW and this G nail has not
given me any trouble it's been awesome I
love it it's got a USB port on the front
that will charge up your phone so you
can plug in if you've only got a limited
spot of plugs you can plug in your email
or the Gmail then you can plug in your
iPhone into bat and charge your phone
while you're taking hot dabs it's
amazing I like it so shout out to giddy
up thanks a lot bro those a good gift
came right before Christmas all right
let's see I did the tweets I want to
thank Jake and Emily while I just yelled
into the microphone I'm sorry I hope the
software fixes that I want to thank Jake
and Emily for the emails they sent I
will be in touch very soon you guys
haven't responded to a bunch of emails
it's been the holidays overwhelmed I'll
get back to you I promise but I'm
interested you guys said some things and
I'm interested I'm paying attention also
I want to give a big thanks to g35 don't
even ask guys that's his name you can be
g35 if he wants Brent em and also Fred
Garvin wanna thank you guys for all your
interaction messages tweets emails
Facebook's all of the above I appreciate
the emails so keep them coming
send them to I grow culture at
hotmail.com [ __ ] I'm gonna have to
change that too we're gonna make another
email address since we're changing
everything I can just keep that and I'll
forward it but we'll make up another one
episode 50 is coming up yeah isn't a
planet a small celebration episode I'm
gonna try to get as many microphones as
I have I'm gonna try to get that many
people my software or my setup here I
could probably put in 20 microphones
with all the inputs and other in lines
I've got but I don't really you know
we'll try to get I'll get Adam and Jesse
and maybe Spence hey Maddie you're
invited I'd like to have Maddie on the
show that'd be great to have the first
chick on the show be you I'm sorry the
first woman I won't say chick that
sexist let's have the first woman on the
show will be Maddie try to correct
myself there I'd like you guys's input
about episode number 50 I've got a few
questions for you so if you want to
email me or tweet me now's a good time I
want to know what were some of your
favorite moments on the podcast so far
let's do it out to
if there's an episode or a moment that
stood out tweet me and tell me what it
was I want to celebrate that on episode
50 what did you guys learn is there
something that you learned that really
stood out that really like have you ever
heard somebody say one thing and you're
like oh my god I've been listening to
this guy ramble for a whole hour and
that's the one thing that made it worth
it if you got one thing that you learned
or something that really stood out let
me know I want to know what you guys
learn from me or us also who's your
favorite guest on my podcast I've had a
lot of people on Spence
Jesse Mike Adam King Cola Edison
tomorrow was on the show via interview
that was one of my most proud because
that was my second episode and I called
up Addison like I had a podcast going on
I didn't know what the hell I was doing
it was kind of funny of me to do should
try that again and see how it goes
also I want to know what would you guys
like to hear next I talk a lot and why
not make it be about something that you
guys actually want to hear you know
because if I'm just gonna talk you can
tell me what you want me to say instead
of me just rambling and rambling and
rambling alright so send me some guys
agriculture at hotmail.com you can tweet
me anti grow culture or you can find me
on Facebook send me a message there to
search for agriculture I've got a
personal Facebook if you guys find that
I don't accept every friend request
right away I kind of i'll troll you a
little bit and see who you are before I
approve your stuff because I'm getting
if Facebook's getting weird I'm sorry I
don't I don't want to be that open
anymore if you want to see I'm
completely open with the Huayra genetic
stuff and the agriculture stuff all of
that is fair game I tweet I Instagram
dude my I read genetics Instagram blows
up and I'm gonna brag a little bit my
mom spoiled the [ __ ] out of me for
Christmas she knows that I've been
looking at this a Nikon camera and so on
Christmas the gifts were all done and
then she slid this other box toward me
and just smiled and had a tear in her
eye and when I opened it I kind of got a
tear in my eye also because she hooked
me up the Nikon d3200 hundred the
package with the extra lens and the bag
and [ __ ] and I've been eyeballing that
thing for quite a while so thanks mom
again that's why I shattered her out at
the start of the show but holy [ __ ]
that's the one of the best gifts I've
ever gotten
not to discredit any other gifts but I
mean holy crap that's the camera I've
been eyeballing for months and mom's
bought it for me so thanks again mom
that means that my Instagram is going to
improve you're gonna see better pictures
you're gonna see more angles you're
gonna see more zoom you're gonna see
better better better just cuz I've got
better here I've been shooting those
Instagram shots you see if you follow me
on IG those shots come from a Panasonic
Lumix point-and-shoot camera it was $199
at Best Buy and that's what I'm pulling
off so now I've upgraded to this
freaking badass camera I think you'll
see some improvement all right I've been
rambling about that holy crap but follow
me on instagram if you want to hydro
culture or I read genetics I've got them
both I post a lot of stuff on I read
genetics I post about every three hours
I try just to keep it moving holy crap
guys I'm dabbed out and I feel like I'm
talking really really quickly I'll take
a big yoga breath together and slow down
a little bit
yeah that's the sound of me calming down
I do that [ __ ] sometimes I need to calm
down for this part this is important
I've got a friend whose name is Deacon
gray beacon gray is a comedian he's from
Oklahoma but he currently resides in the
great city of Denver Colorado if you've
gone to a show at Comedy Works there's a
good chance you've seen deacon gray as
an opening act he's a little white
haired dude that tells wheat jokes he
talked about being from Oklahoma he's
hilarious in my opinion Deacon gray has
made me laugh my ass off multiple times
and recently I'm gonna go to this
website that I've got here I got a
search through it real quick sorry I'm
stumbling because I was trying to be
somber about this let's see I got a back
up one tab doo doo doo doo so Deacon
gray this page is called help Deacon
gray grab cancer by the throat help
Deacon gray grabbed cancer by the throat
Deacon was living his life and slinging
as jokes and doing his duties as a new
talent coordinator at Comedy Works
everything was hunky-dory except that
his friends say hunky-dory when he
noticed he had a lump on his neck better
have that looked at
well he had it looked at and he wanted
to look at it a little closer like take
a tonsil out closer which they did the
bad news it's cancer you guys the good
news
it's a highly curable kind of cancer the
same kind the Nuggets coach George Karl
beat recently his prognosis is excellent
his spirits are good but he's got
several weeks of chemotherapy and
radiation treatments to get through so
let's just click more I'm not gonna read
all this to you guys you get the point
what I'm headed for is Deacon Grey's
made me laugh my ass off several times
he's funny as [ __ ] dude he tells weed
jokes his delivery is amazing and in
return for making me laugh I want to
shout out his website so that we can
raise this guy a little bit of money
he's got throat cancer we got to get him
through it
he can't smoke cannabis right now
because he's got the real cancer but he
can definitely edibles he can do stuff
like that so if you live near Deacon
gray and you see him layin edible on him
a good edible don't give him some
[ __ ]
give him a good clean quality edible and
then after that go to give for word.com
and search for Deacon gray I'm looking
for the lamp it just wants to show me
here we go it's gift for Burt calm slash
fundraiser
there's a whole bunch of stuff so just
go to give forward dot-com and search
for Deacon gray it's DEA Co n then his
last name is great GRA y I've truly
appreciate it
you can donate as little as five dollars
somebody on here donated one of the last
donations that I saw was a thousand
dollars and I thought that was really
generous
I wish I could give somebody a thousand
dollars for their cancer treatment and
health but man I will contribute a
little bit to this and one disclose how
much that's my personal donation but I
will donate to this cause as soon as I'm
leavin the tab open so that I could do
it right after the show here but I'd
appreciate if you guys just went through
a couple of bucks toward Deacon Graham
I'm not trying to beg for him the dude's
got throat cancer he made me laugh
laughter is medicine that [ __ ] means a
lot to me so I want to give forward and
help out Deacon gray so once again I'll
read out his website it's give forward
calm and just search for Deacon gray
he's really close to his goal he's
trying to raise $10,000 he's already got
four thousand one hundred and twenty
dollars
he's almost fifty percent of the way
through thirty-nine donations so he's
getting there that's freaking awesome
Deacon gray shout out brother I hope you
get to hear this somehow I hope somebody
relays this to you much respect he made
me laugh a lot this is the least I can
do for you so I want to go and read a
news article that kind of hit home for
me because well you'll understand why
I'm a seed breeder I am I am Rasta Jeff
I do the Hydra culture podcast but I'm
also the guy that owns I read genetics I
I am I region etics I do the breathing I
do the selection Jesse is actually part
of the team now
none of his stuff is available through
me yet but it will be very soon so Jesse
is part of the team big shot at the
Jesse Jesse grows follow him you'll see
his projects coming through but you'll
understand why this hits home now this
is from the cannabis the article was
written by Jason Blevins it was from the
Denver Post originally was published
December 24th at 5:05 p.m. says pot
growers new quest US patent protection
for cannabis seeds then Holmes jelly
lowers the turntable needle onto the
album and traffic's medicated goo begins
to play Steve Winwood's
wistful tenor sweeps through the
Centennial seeds laboratory my own
homegrown recipe you'll see it through
everyone stole from Steve Winwood home
says his foot tapping as he injects a
syringe of dark syrupy liquid into his
gas
from chromatograph no one is stealing
from homes a self-taught scientist
engineer farmer and cannabis seed geek
who next month will take a rare step to
apply for a patent on a laboriously
created cannabis superstring if it is
awarded the US patent on homes medical
grade Auto two strain will be the first
to protect a cannabis plant and a first
step in establishing plant breeder
rights for growers who only a few years
ago were considered criminals I said the
the strain is called Auto - it's spelled
OTT oh and then the Roman numeral - it's
not Auto like Auto flower so I just want
to clear that up it's the same word
essentially I'm saying Auto and I would
say Auto if it were spelled the other
way so if you guys are haters of Auto
flowers that's not what it is it's just
Auto like the dude from The Simpsons
it's probably got some Canadian
influence I would assume right anyway
this industry came up in stealth born in
basements and crawlspaces Holmes said
but now with companies forming and
making larger investments the desire to
protect intellectual property is
becoming paramount bleeding-edge stuff
right here this is kind of hits home to
me because I breed seeds and I create
strains and I see people I don't wanna
say ripping them off because I don't
know if they thought of it before me if
they just happen to post it to Instagram
after me but people we like to borrow
names in this industry four strains we
we think we're coming up with something
original you guys are gonna hear a
thumping noise I'm moving this
microphone it's sliding sorry here we go
sorry if that sounds like [ __ ] the
recording I'm not gonna censor that her
edit that out at all so making stuff my
strains get stolen often and I can't
complain about it because I'm actually
using other people's strains to make
mine somebody had to make the seeds for
me to breed with but just give credit I
guess but now people are gonna be able
to patent stuff so what I'm worried
about mainly are people with more money
going to Punk me and patent my [ __ ] and
squeeze me right out are you gonna see
other people claiming that they own
Kabletown that's what I'm worried about
and I don't I don't know the legal parts
of this enough to know but I do know
that I don't have any money compared to
a lot of these people I am small time
compared a lot of these people compared
to green house compared to the callee
connection compared to DNA I am nobody
and those guys could squeeze me out
tomorrow
if they wanted to but luckily we're a
friendly industry big business doesn't
give a [ __ ] about friendly industry
they'll squeeze us all out by doing this
kind of stuff because they've got the
money that's what I fear but I'm a
paranoid hippie I've been on too many
fish parking lots to have a clear head
about that kind of [ __ ] I just always
think that more of the article it says
indeed gone are the days when pie-eyed
long hairs haphazardly hurled fallen
into jungles of pot plants hoping to
meld two strains and that's such a great
cliche in one [ __ ] sentence I love
that pie-eyed long hairs so you can see
those guys early fallen they're just got
this male plant there's beaten into the
room in the jungles of pot plants so no
strain selection here let's just put a
bunch of females in here sorry I'm just
talking [ __ ] about the sentence it was
great
hoping to meld two strains today's top
readers are geneticists taking years to
weed through carefully engineered
generations of cannabis to elevate the
most desired traits that's a pretty
accurate statement I will agree with
that some of the new super strains are
high in cannabidiol or CBD one of
several dozen cannabinoid chemical
compounds in cannabis and the plant's
major non psychoactive ingredient
compound but then he said ingredient and
then that ruined him
I'm so critical these guys articles and
I bet I say some really dumb [ __ ] on the
podcast cuz I'm high so these guys have
editors and proofreaders and [ __ ] I'm
just you're spouting it out I've taken
dabs and drank monta and can't be held
accountable for anything I say after
that epic seizures prompting widespread
calls for additional research other more
utilitarian super strains are resistant
to mites or the crop killing powdery
mildew that plagues grow operations
across Colorado crop killing powdery
across Colorado
sounds like we only have that here
powdery mildew all over the place bro I
don't know why you're single in Colorado
it does happen here all right I'll quit
ranting about that part let's get more
into the article here oh where was it
some super strains are suit
superstone ii with sky high levels of
tetrahydrocannabinol or THC the
psychoactive compound in cannabis s real
way down there's like seven answer here
we go the gas chromatograph is homes key
in shaping Auto to a high CBD low THC
strain he hopes can feel medical
therapies the 50 year old gizmo
separates molecules and converts them
into an electrical impulse a green line
tracking across screen reveals the THC
level in the substance that line will be
the baseline for a measurement of auto
two homes produces a well-worn label
tablet laden with acronyms and millivolt
values from the gas chromatograph those
figures reveal his painstaking progress
toward breeding the THC out and the CBD
into his treasured varietal it is in
many ways the result of a lifelong
career dedicated to breeding growing
cloning engineering and charting the
most useful cannabis plants as Winwood
seems the oft covered dear mr. fantasy
Holmes shares his plans to protect Auto
two but ranks among the most valuable of
his collection of 400 varieties of
cannabis seeds both marijuana and him
most of which are stored in additional
freezer in his lafayette lab in addition
to the patent he hopes to be the first
cannabis breeder to secure protection
under the plant variety Protection Act
the seminal plant breeders rights
legislation from 1970 the value of that
seed long term could be very very
valuable an annuity said Holmes a father
of two who serves on the state's
industrial hemp Advisory Committee and
is collaborate collaborating on the
University of Colorado's groundbreaking
cannabis genomic research initiative and
if you guys haven't checked that out you
should I'll say it again it's the
cannabis genomic research initiative
there's a link to it in this article on
the cannabis so if you can find this
article on the cannabis it's the article
about pot growers new quest US patent
patent protection this link is in that
article
so everyone who does this wants to
produce something with durability he
said a seed with good utility that
produces well can have longitude II for
generations which is very true I've read
a few strains that I can keep those
seeds around and that Capleton the
Bounty Killer will be good forever I'm
gonna get back into the article here
that was kind of a rant
right God says Holmes is sort of a
modern-day Luther Luther Burbank who you
should read about guys the pirate
pioneering American botanist and
horticulturist who developed more than
eight hundred varieties and strains of
plants in the late 1800s and early 1900s
his name was Luther Burbank if you want
to google him wikipedia that guy
Burbank faced intellectual property
challenges in his career as he created
still Harold peaches plums daisies and
the world dominant Burbank russet potato
Holmes follows Burbank lead offering a
few types of seeds to a single large
distributor who can flood the market in
the first year before anyone can take it
as their own by cloning the young
seedlings this guy's idea that's a good
idea he's gonna put out so many seeds so
quickly that everybody will know it's
his because it'll be flooded but nobody
will be able to claim it before they can
cut a clone because he'll be so well
known for putting it out that's pretty
smart it puts out so many they're like
oh it's got to be him because everyone's
got the seeds yeah that makes sense
I like that's a good idea hoarding
certain strains when I make seeds no I'm
just make a whole bunch of them until I
can do that I wouldn't do that I'm just
joking sorry guys
by the time copycats have cloned
holmes's strains he's already he already
has made his money he also licenses the
use of his heirloom seeds but not the
extra-special seeds he doesn't want
copied really the focus - any patent
protection is non licensing and careful
selection of distributors homestead
state trademark protection can safeguard
the name of an innovation within a
state's borders but protecting
intellectual property through state law
is a bandage patents are exclusively
federal marijuana is illegal under
federal law and federal law trumps state
law so this guy could get completely
denied for his attempt at patenting his
cannabis strain but if he does he's
going to open the floodgates for a lot
of [ __ ] and people will start
panting their own strains I bet you that
means I don't have to get on the game
get lawyer it up a little bit harder for
a lawyer that knows about patent laws -
vast you have to have your hands in
everything now to be able to keep up in
this kind of a business if you just want
to move to Colorado and get in the
cannabis industry I recommend you do
like a year of research before you get
into it maybe come here and talk to
somebody who's in the end
Street I can help you out a little bit I
don't know a lot about getting into the
industry
I don't like into if you want a
dispensary or something and I don't know
how to get you into there that's gonna
be hard so be careful let's see in this
episode I wanted to talk about the new
year is coming up and the new year is
always a good time everybody says they
want to do New Year's resolutions and
stuff I think it's a good time to start
a new grow calendar or a schedule I kind
of make a game plan
clean up your grow room get everything
started fresh again and then instead of
just cutting a bunch of clones and
having a bunch of plants and veg and
having some [ __ ] over here and some more
[ __ ] over here think about what you're
gonna do think about how many lights you
have in each space how many flowering
lights do you have how many plants fit
under each of those lights how long do
they take to flower
okay so you got about 65 days underneath
this light right well in about 65 days
you need more plants to go under there
but you need a couple days to clean that
you got a trim you got to sweep up you
gotta wipe the walls down you gotta
clean all the dirt out you got to repot
you got to get [ __ ] back in there
remember that in like nine weeks you
need more plants in there so you got to
cut clones about three to four maybe
five weeks before that depending on how
much space you have you gotta get your
[ __ ] ready so start planning I think
it's a good time for you guys to start
working on an advanced grow calendar I
don't know how you want to do it there
are a lot of ways to go about it do it
your way is what I recommend maybe we'll
make an episode out of that but it's the
start of the year coming up and just
make a calendar because if you pop a
bunch of seeds you cut a bunch of clones
and you got a vet roomful and a
flowering roomful and you don't have a
full plan of where those plants are
going you're gonna run into some
problems overcrowding causes problems
overcrowding promotes problems you can't
see that plan on the bottom you can't
tell there was a spider mite infestation
there you got spider mites everywhere
you got way too many plants it's out of
control just be diligent think in
advance think ahead of yourself be like
five steps ahead that's how you be a
good grower kind of try to predict
what's gonna happen in your plants don't
just watch and see what happens be like
oh this is going to happen because I've
grown weed a million times and I've paid
attention at least ten of them all right
I'm ranting again but it's really
important I think and it's a start of
year so it's time for that to happen it
would be a good time for all of that
include
[ __ ] right at the start of the year if
it's if your carbon filters are all
mucky buy some new carbon filters if
your bulbs are all shitty get some new
bulbs it's the start of the year spoil
your Gardens they spoil you back that's
my advice that's my personal advice from
the from the heart of Rasta Jeff I must
be dad doubt you're saying from the
heart of Rasta Jeff grow from your heart
right that's what I say all right this
episode you guys I hope you join me next
week it's gonna be another quick episode
I'm gonna go see the string cheese on
the 29th 30th and 31st the string cheese
incident at the Broomfield it's the
first Bank Centre in Broomfield what's
up don't be shy I'm the tall white guy
with dreadlocks I'm probably wearing a
pirate genetics hoodie that if I'm a
tall white guy with dreadlocks and
there's a little short chick with
dreadlocks next to me and she's sweet
looking it's probably me there's gonna
be a lot of people to match that
description but I'm probably wearing the
ivory hoodie and she's probably got the
Huayra hoodie I might have I'll try to
remember to take some stickers or
something with me and throw them in my
back pocket so that if you say what's up
shake my hand give me a hug I'll give
you a sticker it'll be really funny when
you hug the wrong hippie because there's
gonna be a bunch of tall white guys with
dreadlocks there so say what's up to me
at the String Cheese Incident if you see
me I hope to see you there
maybe we'll smoke down or something I'll
have some dabs with me if we're not on
the show I don't know how I'm gonna
sneak my rig into the show but all I
definitely have a spliff all right let's
wrap this up you guys you guys might be
what are you listening to this you might
hear this on New Year's so let me look
at the calendar ones this come out when
does this come out bro go into the
calendar I'm not gonna press pause and
record I'm just gonna do it or and try
not to do any editing anymore what do
you think do you like it when I just
talk a lot and don't uh feel like when I
talk about my life and my stuff and I
don't just keep talking about weed and
have it all scripted or do you do you
want me to keep it tight owner don't you
think so this episode will come out on
the 29th oh [ __ ] you guys probably I
hope you're listening to this on your
way Drive into the cheese show wherever
you are so if you see me a stream cheese
give me a hug the next Happy New Year
also because Wednesday is the new year
so happy new year hope you guys are safe
dude don't drink and drive be safe take
care of one another
keep an eye out for each other I don't I
want everybody to be able to see all
your friends again
tomorrow so have a Happy New Year you
guys I love you guys thanks for
listening
there's nothing cooler than having
people that email you and tweet you
until your list they're listening so now
the show's over please go to iTunes or
stitcher and find the iTunes or stitcher
main page there's for agriculture find
the review section
give me a five star rating type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on the show don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode will always be
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
find us on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook search for agriculture I'm
gonna have to change all of that stuff
to grow from your heart podcast I hope
all of those services will let me change
my name at least once not sure how it's
gonna work but I'll do it I'm more
focused on the string cheese concert so
I'll be gone for three days I'd be gone
for like four days so I'm more worried
about that right now than I am getting
the show stuff done because I don't have
a logo yet and all that but once I get
the logo going we'll get it happening at
the start of the year you guys would all
be rockin stay with me please don't
abandon me right around episode 50 I'd
be weird also follow I read genetics on
Instagram that's not going anywhere
well unless I read Instagram [ __ ] me
like Facebook did if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like me to
review send me an email at agriculture
at hotmail.com and I'll get you all the
info you need we do need a theme song
and a logo a big super huge shout as my
ninja Spence also big shout out to Matty
big shout out to my mom's for the super
cool camera and other cool gifts big
shout out to Angela love you babe thanks
again for listening you guys until next
time take your fat dab give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
yeah what's up guys it's time for
another episode of the Grove from your
heart podcast that's right I made the
switch it is now the official growth
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
welcome to episode number 47 I'm your
host Rasta Jeff and I'm coming to you
again with another solo episode today is
Saturday it's the Saturday after the new
year it's the first Saturday of the new
year everybody had a great safe joyous
new year I have a few people to thank
and a few things to talk about but
before we get that far let's pay a
couple of bills this podcast is brought
to you by our good friends at nature's
green remedies dot-com is it nature's
green remedies calm for gage Green
genetics La Plata labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can adventure the
cali connection ira genetics and many
more trusted brands nature's green
remedies is running a coupon actually
running a special for our loyal podcast
listeners type in coupon code Irie 2015
and you'll get 15% off any order and you
always get free priority shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com that's
Irie 2015 I have to write that down cuz
I actually have to tell them the coupon
code that I use that might be helpful
I read 2 0 1 5 PI R ie 2 0 1 5 all one
word
so that's your coupon code for nature's
drain remedies con you'll get 15% off
any order and free priority shipping
this coupon code let's see will make you
good for the entire month of January
this expires January 31st so get in
there and get some seeds while you can
big thanks and much respect to nature's
green remedies
what's up Yankee I hope you're doing
good brother
this podcast is also brought to you by
our good friends at high Gro indoor
growing supplies hydro indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado check out the Denver store at
62 71 beach street or visit my favorite
location the Pueblo store on 618 East
4th Street in beautiful Pueblo Colorado
check out high grow for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies hydro is always running a
special for the podcast listeners when
you check out tell them you listen to
the iGrow culture podcast well that's
gonna get confusing because now you have
to say you listen to the Grove from your
heart podcast but let those guys know
you listen to the podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire order so much respect to hydro
indoor growing supplies the Denver and
Pueblo location that's a sweet hookup
for the podcast
Jessi and I have been talking a little
Jessi's been kind of a busy dude but we
are working on putting together some
prizes for episode 50 that's so we're
gonna hang out in a day or two and
that's gonna be our priority of the
conversation excuse my sniffles we'll
talk a little bit about my sniffles here
in a little bit I saw the String Cheese
Incident for three nights in Denver
gotten a little bit sniffily during that
up - 16 night this podcast is also
brought to you by our good friends at
tree hugger comm this episode is brought
to you I just read that part huh tree
secure comm live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree hugger comm for
concert and festival news and reviews
look out at the cookout with tree hugger
dot-com that's all the ads were gonna do
today big shout out much love to both
those are all three of the sponsors I'm
high and stumbling I gotta get my rhythm
in this episode alright so a big shout
out to the mystic roots band the song
you heard at the opening of the show was
called the doggy dub from our good
friends the mystic roots shout out to
cat and COO hope you guys had a great
new year hope everybody had a great was
talking about going to see the string
cheese incident so uh we'll talk about
that a little bit I got to go see if you
don't know about the stream cheese
they're a jam band from Colorado they're
from the boulder Estes Park area they're
from all over the place out there so you
can't pick one split place to say but
that's where they're from is that kind
of area they started off as kind of a
blue grassy jam band now they're kind of
a more of a psychedelic dubstep you jam
band they've got two drummers or they've
got a drummer a guy that plays
percussion they've got a keyboard player
that tears it
they've got an electric guitar player
who plays fiddle and electric guitar and
mandolin like a champ builder she plays
acoustic guitar and then their bass
player is uh he's solid dude he doesn't
like stand out he's not super flashy but
he never missed a note in three nights
so the screen she's incident they play
uh the only way I can describe to do
this carnival music it's calypso music
it's Mambo music it's Samba it's rock
its funk its reggae but it's like one
giant carnival the whole party the whole
concert was one giant carnival was a
great time so we saw String Cheese
Incident they did three nights at the
First Bank Center in Broomfield so we
drove up to was actually Westminster's
where our hotel was so we drove up to
the hotel we stayed in the hotel we went
and saw the first show and after the
first set they do you three nights and
the first night they played for about an
hour and fifteen took a break and then
came out for about another hour and a
half and toured that night up after the
first set of the first night I said
where are they gonna go from here
because they came out and they just tore
it up right off the bat they didn't
start like let's start slow and build it
up no they started like let's come out
on fire and just [ __ ] this all up and
they did it was amazing so big thanks to
the stream cheese incident that was
awesome so day two or we finished your
show night one away back to the hotel
where he pretty much slept day two we
kind of just hung out in the hotel and
we're lazy it was cold it was uh
-16° that day and there was no real
reason to leave the hotel other than to
get food we had dabs and drinks and
everything we need it so we just hung
out in the hotel until time for the show
the second night was amazing we'd pretty
much we ditched the shows at the end and
head right back to the hotel we're not
real party animals anymore I don't need
to eat a bunch of drugs and get spun out
I wanted to go home and get prepared for
the next day because New Year's was a
big party they started a little bit
early and they played until about 1:45
if I remember correctly they started at
8:45 and went till 1:45 with a couple of
breaks ah
String Cheese Incident on New Year's
I've never seen so much confetti so many
balloons I can't even begin to describe
what it was like we were me and my
girlfriend Angela were in the front
three rows right in front of Bill nur
she and kind of off to the side from
Kyle so there's a huge party right there
after the first or second night
everybody knew who we were so everyone
has treated us like friends and family
so big shout out to all the new friends
and family that I made from the string
cheese incident but man they had these
giant bill clay cocoons hang it from the
ceiling when we walked in that night and
you couldn't identify what they were but
as the midnight countdown began these
cocoons opened up and there were they
became giant flowers that were lit up
and it was pretty amazing I posted video
on my facebook if you guys want to check
that out you'll have to find my personal
Facebook I shouldn't have said that but
there are a lot of cool videos I would
check it out
it was amazing I was covered in confetti
there are so many balloons so a big
thanks to Angela for letting me go
inviting me to be your New Year's buddy
and also further thanks for that sweet
New Year's kiss baby we needed that I
meant a lot to me um let's see big
thanks to all the cheese kids and fans
that I made I made a list here I'm gonna
try to get some of these people in here
I'm gonna skip a bunch though a big
thanks to Pam and Jessica um I met Pam
for the first time angela speaks very
highly of you and now i see why
jessica i just met that night had never
heard of her she's a big ball of smiling
energy it was great to meet you and hang
out with you a big thanks to Mama Cass
was great Mama Cass had a lot of great
energy had a lot of good things to say
amazing candy I cannot remember your
name this dude next to me offered me a
lemon candy and I said is it just candy
and he said yeah man my thing is to just
bring weird candies to the show and
they're delicious and so I took this
lemon candy from him and it was amazing
later on in the show he offered me
something and when he pulled it out of
his pocket the guy next to him patted me
on the shoulder and said eat one of
those man and when I tried it it was
amazing it was something I all the
packaging was in another language it's
like Chinese or Korean or something I'm
sorry if that's offensive I don't know
the [ __ ] language it is it looks
Chinese to me and it was mango flavored
and whatever it was amazing today they
did not have drugs in it so I was pretty
relieved about an hour later when I
wasn't flipping my face off so a big
shot to the candy guy also big shout-out
to Dan Caron Rowland and Riley there's a
pleasure meeting all of my new friends
you guys are great great little family
you guys have there also shout out to
the girl that we named titty girl
I never met her we never met her but her
boobs and her vibes were amazing and fun
to watch
she was so exposed that my girlfriend
told me to look because it resident
ridiculous she said look to your left
that girl's boobs are out of her shirt
and I looked and it was it wasn't even
like I was looking to be a pervy I was
more looking like is she really having
her tits out of her shirt that much at
the show it was kind of entertaining
kind of ridiculous so big shout out the
titty girl she's a good dancer she had a
lot of good energy she brought a little
crew a chicks with her that twirled
around and brought a nice little vibe so
that was neat did some of the girls at
the show they wear this eye makeup with
beads in it dude and I don't understand
how you ladies do that stuff like
seriously right in the corner your eye
where you wake up with high Krusty's on
the outside nose but the other side it's
got little beads and [ __ ] there ladies
tolerate that [ __ ] all night on your
face but I do however think it's cute
and I totally appreciate the effort but
it does make me be extra glad to be the
guy with dreadlocks I wake up sometimes
I take a shower occasionally that mostly
wake up put on some clothes throw on a
t-shirt shake my head put on a hat now
I'm ready to rock you can't tell if I
just woke up or if I've been working all
day so it makes me actually grateful to
be a guy that can be lazy but also thank
you ladies for looking great at the
cheese show Angela thank you for looking
wonderful thank you for letting have a
good time I did mention I got a little
cold I guess I got some sniffles brides
sniffle wrecking the mic to do that no
it's rude but I was -16° one night and
you gotta go from the car into the
concert venue and the minus 16 and then
in the concert I just I took off all my
jackets and I had my t-shirt and my
pants on and my shoes on my hat and I
was sweating my ass off so you got to
try to negotiate the cold and then the
super hot heat and then back to the car
again and then let the car warm up and
get to the hotel so I think all the
climate changes I may have caught a
little cold here and also I smoked like
45 joints over three nights at these
concerts but I rolled a bunch of joints
it's more like 45 joints with strangers
and I'm wondering if maybe I got a
little bit of string cheese incident
look flu but whatever I'll live got some
emergency and some yerba maté a I'm
gonna be just fine
I was fun meeting a lot of Instagram
followers I met a lot of people they
walked up to me and they said hey are
you I read genetics or are you Ross to
Jeff that's always kind of nice when
just now randomly somewhere that there's
a band playing and you're not like it
wasn't a weedy van
I shouldn't have been getting any
attention but people knew who I was it
was kind of neat so big shout-out to all
those folks that said hi
I really appreciate that I'm digging
through notes here Oh huge shout out to
Aaron Brooks on the very last night we
were walking out of the venue and if my
girlfriend didn't have to pee we would
not have bumped into each other so I'm
so glad she had to pee and I bumped into
Aaron Brooks and got a big old hug Aaron
Brooks is an artist if you're not
following him you should be ah let's see
what else do I need to talk about I
wrote down a lot of stuff I feel like
I'm rambling we're already 11 minutes in
cuz this is gonna be another one of
those short quick episodes with just me
um I put a lot of work into this podcast
but this week I was obviously busy
seeing the string cheese incident I've
been out of town has gone for four days
it took me a whole day to get my Gardens
back to where I felt they should be they
missed me and then I needed a day to get
myself back together I tried to record
yesterday but there's chaotic so here I
am I'm recording this quick short
episode because I love you guys and I
don't want to leave you hanging for a
whole week but I do promise that the
next episodes are gonna be back to what
you expect 48 49 and 50 are gonna be
stellar episodes hopefully get Spencer
on pretty soon but I never never teased
you about that well let's see sorry I'm
Chokin let me take a quick drink here
take a dab while I take a drink
I'll shout out to water and root beer
and those things keep me alive so remind
you guys of the name change that's my
next note I'm sure you noticed at the
beginning of the show that I said
welcome to the hydro culture podcast I'm
doing my best to roll out the new name
I'm doing it slowly so I don't lose
people so if it looks confusing for a
little bit I'm sure you guys are aware
of what's going on if you're listening
but we are in the process of changing
the name from agriculture to grow from
your heart bear with me I still could
use more logos somebody sent me one logo
but I asked for a couple of adjustments
it just they didn't fit the way I needed
it to fit to make squares that but I
need a square logo so if you can send me
a 1400 by 1400 pixel image with the girl
from your heart podcast I would love
that
I also need a song if you guys want to
if anybody out there is an artist and
you want to make a girl from your heart
podcast theme song I will compensate you
in the future
that'd be really cool so I'm starting to
change the title in social media places
also I'm waiting on a couple artists to
submit some logos that I've commissioned
once I've got all the artwork I can
fully roll out the new title and start
switching everything over I'm hoping by
episode 50 that we can actually just
call this the girl from your heart
podcast and everything will be switched
right over let's see also there's
something that I've been considering
this is just a personal thing for myself
that I'm considering doing I may cancel
the Instagram for the podcast there is
an agriculture podcast Instagram that I
haven't posted anything to in several
weeks honestly it kind of it's just a
distraction there's not a lot it's a
podcast and some of my guests don't want
me to take their picture Jesse doesn't
want his face on Adam is cool with it
Mike is cool with it but some people do
not want to be seen and I feel like I'm
just going to over do my Instagram
presence by having the I read genetics
and the I grow culture or the girl from
your heart podcast so I'm thinking about
just combining the two into one entity
and maybe I'll start posting a few
things from the girl from your heart
podcast on the IRA genetics Instagram so
if you're not already following IRA
genetics on Instagram go there and
follow that
because I'm really considering taking
down the Instagram for the podcast it's
just a distraction it's one more thing
to worry about um I'm also considering
and I'm not committing to this but it's
highly likely somebody had a talk with
me and it got me thinking but I'm
considering cancelling my YouTube
account for the iGrow culture girl from
your heart podcast you'd say why would
you do that people are listening they
are but not as many and I'm not
appreciate the people that are listening
but it takes me a long time to get those
episodes up there I feel if I cancel
that until I can focus more on the show
and if I didn't have to create as many
different types of media I could make
better content just for the audio
podcast I'd rather spend the time
creating content editing video and
setting up a camera and lighting and
editing the video again and then
rendering the video for YouTube
it takes a few it's just a few more
steps but all those steps matter I could
spend that much time preparing for this
show and making the show that much
better having that many more details
being that much more prepared getting
that much better of a guest on so the
Instagram and the YouTube may go away
and that's just personal things I'm
trying to free it more time to take what
I'm really passionate about to the next
level I don't want to drag my feet on
things that are not fulfilling me
honestly so I may eliminate those and I
do appreciate the guys that watch me on
YouTube I've only gotten like 17 or 18
maybe 20 videos up on YouTube because
like I said it takes me an hour to make
each one and I feel like I could I'm
repeating myself I could just spend that
time doing stuff so I may take them down
I don't I don't want to abandon people
but if you are watching on YouTube you
should be able to find it on the high
grow culture or the IRA genetics website
every podcast is there and if you've got
a browser it works the same and there's
nothing you're not missing anything
visually really so those are mostly
distractions I feel like I'm gonna stop
contributing to those just so that I can
improve the audio part of this show so
like I'm talking about that for a long
time I need to move on let's see I
appreciate all the emails I've gotten
holy crap you guys we're gonna continue
to use the iGrow culture at hotmail.com
email address for now bye episode 50 I
will have created the new email address
and
are talking about it you can email me
there but from now on or for now keep
using the iGrow culture at hotmail calm
email address i did change the twitter
it's still at hydro culture but if you
look at it the name is grow from your
heart podcast it won't let me change my
hat name only my display name so that's
something you can pay attention to let's
see I wrote a bunch of notes and I have
them in my computer and I'm scrolling
through the computer and looking at a
piece of paper trying to read two things
at once and it's honestly not working so
episode 50 is coming up you guys have
been talking about that I'm planning a
small celebration episode but I would
like your input I asked for this on the
last episode but I wanna know who your
favorite guests were what were some of
your favorite moments and what did you
learn and what would you like to hear
next so like I said send me some input
it's agriculture at hotmail.com you
could tweet me or you can find me on
Facebook um it looks like I need to
change the Facebook also you guys so
it's still agriculture but pretty soon
it's gonna be the grow from your heart
podcast on Facebook crap sorry I feel
like I got you guys caught up on all of
the stuff I had to remind you of and
talk about so now I think it's time to
read a couple of news articles that I
picked out for the day ah this one says
Colorado seeks federal okay for state
colleges to grow pot a lot of people
from out of state are going what but
it'll make sense this article is from
the Denver Post it's written by John
Ingold it says Colorado has made an
unusual plea to federal authorities let
our colleges grow pot in a letter sent
last month the state Attorney General's
Office asks federal health and education
officials for permission on Colorado's
colleges and universities to obtain
marijuana from non federal government
resources for research purposes the
letter isn't more specific on how the
state's higher education institutions
might score weed but it was sent
pursuant to a law passed in 2014
requiring state officials to ask that
Colorado colleges and universities be
allowed to cultivate marijuana and its
component parts
current research is riddled with bias or
insufficiencies and often conflict and
often conflict with one another reads a
letter written by Deputy Attorney
General David Blake it is critical that
we be allowed to fill the void of
scientific research and this may only be
done with your assistance and
cooperation on the request is Lana not a
longshot while marijuana is with
qualifications legal in Colorado it
remains illegal under federal law and
getting permission to conduct research
on cannabis requires clearing a set of
high hurdles approval from multiple
federal agencies and strict requirements
on how marijuana must be handled and
stored researchers that work without the
federal government's blessing risk
losing crucial federal funding for their
institutions not to mention possible in
prison
an intern an international treaty that
the United States sign in/sign D signed
on to sorry I'm stumbling um hi signed
on to requires the federal government to
designate only one place in the country
that can legally grow marijuana for
research since 1968 that place has been
the University of Mississippi's national
care for natural products research which
cultivates cannabis on a 12 acre plot
and sends it to approved researchers as
that a 12 acre plot is rumoured to be
where the g13 came from many years ago
out of a University of Mississippi so if
you know anything about that send me
some info I'd like to know about it
alright the article goes on to say
coincidentally the National
the National Institute on Drug Abuse
recently put the government's pot farm
contract up for rebid applicants need to
have 12 acres of secured and video
monitored outdoor space and 1,000 feet
of indoor space to grow marijuana to be
able to make marijuana extractions test
for potency and prepare preferably by
hand rolling a small batch of marijuana
cigarettes of according to the official
solicitation the contracts winner is
expected to be announced in the next
couple of months a spokeswoman for the
National Institute of drug abuse would
not say how many institutions applied
for the contract or where they are were
sorry spokesman for the University of
Colorado and Colorado State University
said their schools did not apply the
Drug Enforcement Administration in 2014
massively increased the amount of pot
the government's official supplier can
grow from 21 kilos to six hundred and
fifty kilos the increase was the result
of a boom in marijuana research interest
and the University of Mississippi has
pledged to grow new strains of marijuana
to give research more options for their
studies is a long time ago there was a
video out a movie I cannot recall the
name of the movie I mean it was
something like the Union it may have
been in the Union I may have been how
though how we'd won the West maybe I
can't remember the name of which movie
it was but they actually showed us
inside of this facility in Mississippi
where they grow this cannabis and it was
terrible
they weren't growing high-grade cannabis
I [ __ ] about the weed at the
dispensaries and I would rather smoke
the weed at the dispensaries than the
[ __ ] that I saw being grown at
University of Mississippi that stuff was
terrible so it's not really cool that
they're doing the research with that I
hope they get I hope since then they've
gotten a real grower and they've gotten
some genetics and they've learned a few
things is what I saw was [ __ ] all
continue with article it says still the
Colorado Attorney General's letter says
the federal government falls short of
being able to supply researchers with
the kinds of products available in
Colorado's commercial America commercial
marijuana market state health officials
have just approved up to eight point
four million dollars in grants for
marijuana studies some of which will
examine Colorado specific products but
the Attorney General's Office says more
needs to be done we need to support
but we need the support of our federal
partners to overcome the inertia that
continues to complicate state state
efforts in this area at the letter
states so it seems like they caught on
they know that we've got the dank here
in Colorado they need they know that
they need to contest excuse me they know
they need to examine Colorado specific
products so maybe they are catching on
maybe they know that that stuff that
they're drilling out there that
University is a bunch of mids
speaking of mid shout out to my buddy
bigger lover hope you're doing well bro
so what this says this article talked
about this a minute we are actually
asking the federal government to let the
state of this state colleges or higher
educational centers in Colorado to grow
cannabis they want to grow pot that
means there will be courses or a class
that is accredited to a college where
somebody is growing weed it's probably
going to be a chemistry class or a
biology class it probably won't be a
horticulture class because they're not
worried about growing it they're more
worried about the effects and science
and they know how to grow it that's
horticulture that's already done these
guys are gonna probably have some
students doing making extracts testing
the extracts I'm not even sure what
they're gonna do but I'm impressed and
I'm excited I hope this works because I
would love to see cannabis grown in a
university and tested here in Colorado
where we're not scared and trying to lie
about all of the results and to see
possibly some of my friends that are
college students able to study cannabis
in this way in a college and actually
get college credit and build a future
for themselves I really like this I
really love that cannabis has kind of
opened doors and gone from us hiding to
letting us kind of make a living for
ourselves this demographic this age
group of 25 to 40 year old males and
there are females in there too but I'm
honestly the majority is males we were
struggling we were broke and now the 25
to 40 year old demographic has something
to do with ourselves we can grow great
cannabis and get in the industry it's
great
so here's another news article guys I
feel like I'm going really fast sorry
I'm talking so fast I've had some ear
but Montay and I'm drinking a root beer
maybe I just need to slow down a little
bit we're 25 minutes and it's gonna be a
short episode but I promised you that
anyway so it's okay I found this article
on the cannabis tazewell and I found it
entertaining it says it's actually a
long article I only want to read one
piece of it to you guys says cannabis
cue a naming strains and federal
rescheduling riddle rescheduling riddle
the part I want to read about his naming
strains this is from it's by Susan squib
on the cannabis staff and the header is
welcome to our cannabis column Oh
welcome to our ask the cannabis column
clearly you have questions about
marijuana be it a legal concern a health
curiosity a Colorado centric inquiry or
something more far-reaching check out
our expansive 100 question colorado
marijuana frequently asked questions
first and if you're still curious email
your questions to the cannabis and then
there's ask the cannabis at gmail.com so
if you want to participate in that feel
free I get a lot of my news stuff from
these guys so participate with them if
you want
the first question got my attention it
says hey cannabis why would someone name
a strain of weed after a bio weapon that
killed thousands of people and they
signed the letter put off pot so this
guy's asking why would somebody name a
strain a weed after a bio weapon to kill
thousands of people and the cannabis
replies you must be talking about Agent
Orange huh I hear your concern strain
names can mean one thing to a potential
customer and something else to a plant
breeder naming the strain while Agent
Orange is not a peaceful happy or your
phoric name if you view it in historical
context there is the other view that the
name suggests an orange scent and the
potency is the bomb the article says I
chatted with Adam Dunn host of the Adam
Dunn show shout out to the Adam Dunn
show what's up Mitch what's up Adam
what's up everybody on the show crunch
each bike you guys are all doing well
but Adam is the founder of the
amsterdam-based seed company th seeds
and he says having owned a seed company
myself for 21 years I can attest that
many cannabis seed companies are run by
people who have a bit more of a juvenile
attitude especially when it comes to
name - the names game Dunn says names
like Agent Orange
47 Green crack and wheelchair weed
though quite distasteful conjure up
images of something really strong and
devastating I doubt the people who named
Agent Orange really considered this was
a bio weapon that killed thousands of
people and destroyed lives have
countless more often stray names are
creative often strange or creative
combinations of the names that make up
the genetic lineage or other plant
attributes annum Dunn says having been
there at the naming of ak-47 and my own
MKULTRA I am guilty of joining the hype
Dunn says I was dead wrong back in 1993
when I said ak-47 was a terrible name it
was named for flowering on 47 days an
ak-47 went on to become one of the most
famous strains and history at the start
of the legal adult use market this year
the reactions of consumers to strain
names is a recent development in
marijuana marketing Dunn points out Dunn
points out that the cannabis industry is
very young and will go through many
changes so I am guilty of this this is
why it got me attention I've got a
string called Bounty Killer and I had a
friend named Nancy tell me that she
didn't really like the name and she was
reluctant to grow it because it was
called Bounty Killer I called it Bounty
Killer honestly it's named after one of
my favorite reggae artist his name
Bounty Killer uh he I like the way he
does things and I wanted to kind of
honor him I've got the Capleton which is
also named after a reggae artist and
I've got the Kalonji Kush which is also
named after a reggae artist and the
night nurse is named after a reggae song
so the reason I called Bounty Killer
Bounty Killer after the reggae artist is
because it grows killer weed it is
killer it'll kick your ass and it grows
huge colas and huge harvests so that's
the bounty there and it's the Bounty
Killer so if you don't know about reggae
it sounds like you're reaping the bounty
you're killing that huge harvest or if
you know reggae you know that it's the
Bounty Killer and it's kind of
aggressive and kind of loud and it's got
a groovy beat to it that's why I call it
the Bounty Killer I wanted to talk about
why I named sting things the way I named
them and why strains I've treated have
the names they have
I'm a Grateful Dead fan I'm a Deadhead
I'm kind of a and it like the whole
spiritual side of life I'm definitely a
Rastafarian that's why my company is
called IRA genetics I try to honor the
parents the parent plants that I'm using
when I create a new strain but sometimes
that just gets redundant and you can't
be creative so I like to draw from Rasta
culture Grateful Dead culture and like
positive loving hippie culture that's
why I've got a string called heart of
gold it's the golden goat cross to the
Grateful dog it almost got called horn
dog but that didn't sound as good for
the vibe I'm trying to promote a heart
of gold when he smoked that weed and you
meditate your heart is calm your heart
is filled with love well it's better
than a heart of gold right you got a big
heart of gold that's just pump and love
and positive energy and it's got golden
goat in it so it's heart of gold
lemon Geoffrey is golden goat crossed to
the lemon skunk
so there's lemon obviously the lemon
right and my name is Geoff and I wanted
something like you got Orient haze and
there's Neville's haze why not have a
lemon Geoffrey that's named after me the
guy that made it that was kind of my
little stingy move on the kiss world
there these guys were talking about
Agent Orange that was so cool it's
orange velvet it's an orange velvet to
Jack the Ripper cross and I think Agent
Orange is a perfect name then I just did
another name Jack the Ripper
it's Jack Herer crossed to other stuff
basically and sub-cooled didn't want to
use the name Jack Herer so it's Jack the
Ripper just that's how these names come
up I've got a strain that I wanted to
call it the Golden Road it's a golden go
across and of course that's a Grateful
Dead song so my names come from trying
to honor the parents trains and so I did
get creative I crime gonna say this name
here on the show that it's not out yet
but I've this is my cross ah
gorilla glue number four crossed to the
Grateful dog is called griptape and
that's for my skateboard friends you
know what grip tape is on your
skateboard it's that [ __ ] that makes
your feet stick to the board a little
bit
I call it drip tape because it is sticky
it would be called fly paper but fly
paper has already taken and grip tape
kind of honors my skateboard friends
so that's where the names come from
we're not just spouting out random [ __ ]
some guys are
one of my best sellers lately has
actually been a strain that's called
Blue Heeler that was named by our good
buddy Spence from the garden of Weeden
it's actually blue dream cross to the
Grateful dog so grateful dog gives you a
dog named the blue blue heeler it's
named after a dog to keep the Grateful
dog reference and it's also got the word
healer in there because it's gonna make
you feel better so it's just me trying
to be silly and trying to be creative
and honor the parents and you have to
name it something you know you can't
just call it X 5 maybe you can but that
would be boring right that's not good
marketing all right so that's enough of
that article I just wanted to talk about
how I named strains and why I named them
what I named them if you gave me like
anything that I crossed a ghost oh gee
it's gonna be called ghost whatever I
crossed it too you know what I mean
ghost dog goes to goat the golden ghost
you know [ __ ] like that it just oh if I
cross golden goat to stuff it probably
got the word gold to put in there that's
just how I do it all right
I've only been gone for 32 minutes you
guys but I don't have a lot else to say
I honestly didn't have time to prepare
for this episode I don't I didn't want
to stress out over this one I wanted to
hang out with you guys take a couple
dabs let's do that let's do that it's
good add add together all right you guys
take a second I'm gonna ramble here
while you guys get a DAB together to dab
with me I am proud because I'm gonna dab
cheddar that I made myself yeah did that
I made hash and then spent vac purged it
for me
I got it in there got a gone but I had
to leave so he finished it for me the
stuff got purged for 35 hours it's
pretty damn dank I hope you got a DAB
ready by now let's take a DAB together
and then we'll start wrapping up the
show
I'm gonna hit D I've got the Hitman
eseries sidecar with a highly-educated
infinity nail on it attached to the
highly-educated infinity nail is the emo
tech on G nail as always on I've got
mine set to 850 right now which people
say is kind of high but honestly if I
put it any lower I don't get a big
chunky dab on my carb cap it so here we
go shout-out to emote a shot at the hit
man shout-out to highly educated
titanium and shout out to garden of
Weeden and Angela too since I'm going
shoutouts here we go let's do it dad
[Music]
yeah
you
I like those big ol chunky
sure if you're gonna try or a call for
die alright so this will be fun I'm
gonna try to do the to show closing
without coffin after pretty good-sized a
bond to thank you guys for listening I
promise you the next episode is gonna be
better I hope Spence will be here but I
can't promise you he'll be here before
episode 50 if not on episode 50 make
sure you listen episode 50 they're gonna
be prizes oh here we go now that the
show is over please go to iTunes
stitcher go to the iTunes or stitcher
main page I told you hi search for I
grow culture / grow from your heart
right now I've got both titles in there
it's I grow culture / grow from your
heart hopefully by the time episode 50
comes out everyone will be caught on to
grow from your heart podcast so we'll
find the review section give me a 5 star
rating
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the podcast and I will read
your comments on the show excuse me
don't forget that every episode is
available on ira genetics colorado calm
make sure you follow us on twitter
follow follow us on facebook and follow
I read genetics on Instagram it's at I
read genetics on Instagram I'm a cancel
that face bar that Instagram and YouTube
so for the show so don't be sad if they
disappear it's nothing personal I just
want to focus on more important stuff so
if you guys are interested in sponsoring
the podcast or if you have a product
that you like us review send me an email
to agriculture at hotmail.com or I wrote
the other one down I made it and it is
growth from your heart at hotmail.com so
email me it agriculture at hotmail.com
or grow from your heart at hotmail.com
both of those will work I need a new
logo you guys the growth from your heart
logo would be really nice so that I can
get everything in place and make the
show new title official I'm really high
I'm like talking in a circle we do need
a song if you guys wanna help sounds
like I should just end this show sign
off for now so I look forward to seeing
you in seven days until next time
[Music]
yeah what's up guys it's time for
another episode of the Grove from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation welcome
it's episode number 48 we're creeping up
on number 50 I'm host Rasta Jeff and I'm
dad the [ __ ] out but I've got good
reason we were joined today by Spence
and Maddie from the garden of Weeden how
you guys doing over there I apologize
for yelling at everybody holy [ __ ] push
the mic right in your face that's
tradition over here but I think we did
it the first thing Maddie said when she
walked into the house was I need a dad
welcome if you need another one do
there's dad's over here there's a hot I
got the email on shout out to giddy up
an email tag for the Gmail we keep it on
most of the time
isn't that dope charge the phone all the
time while you're taking dabs and on
Instagram and on Instagram the phone
take Babs and be on instagrams over
there this headphone [ __ ] don't ever
buy the live wire solutions hero4 don't
ever buy one of those it's a piece of
[ __ ] a lot so we were saying that maddie
was gonna be the first female on the
show actually that's inaccurate because
I took the podcast to the Brickyard one
time and we had you're gonna be special
in just a second okay
I'm gonna skip bragging on the other
people that were there were other
females but you're the first female to
be here on the show we went somewhere
else and there were females there that
were on the show but you're the first
lady to come be in the iris to do
damn the first black person on the
potters probably I'm always the first
black person in anything Jeff does black
person in my house true there's been a
lot of white people a lot of Mexicans
visit my best friend's here quick that's
tradition the first nature's green
remedies calm check out we're gonna do
the quick version check out nature's
green remedies calm for gage Green
genetics a lot of labs Sin City rare
dankness mile hike an adventure use
coupon code it's Irie 2015 for 15% off
your whole order free shipping at
nature's comm magazine news and reviews
indoor growing supplies and it's great
to have my friends working hydro shops
[Music]
actually if you listen to the I grow
culture or the girl from your heart
podcasts we're changing the name you
guys I'm gonna stutter and say the wrong
name a few times I'll remind you about
that later on on the show if you go in
there and you tell me listen to this
podcast you will get commercial pricing
on everything you buy Maddie didn't know
how to do that she's gone
[Music]
all right music stuff alright dude we
just took some dabs only give spins a
huge shutter on the show Spence taught
me how to make my own dabs that's
freakin awesome I appreciate it I am
self-sufficient it's great to learn from
one of who I consider the masters and
also a brother so means a lot thanks a
lot bro no problem it's about time you
have great product so in turn that's
gonna make great oil I appreciate that
I want to brag on Maddie oh and it's all
a story about Maddie introduce you guys
so one time Spence made Earl and pyrex
dish that had a little bit of vho left
in the bottom that we didn't feel like
scraping out and she decided to heat it
up and make brownies in that pan with
the BHO mix in there and she's laughing
because Spence and I are on the six-four
six-five level of life close to 200
pounds each and there was another guy
and another guy in the room that's about
same same weight class and she [ __ ]
wrecked 4 dudes maybe 5 or 6 dude I
didn't even know that that it was gonna
be that potent oh my god the whole outer
layer of the brownie was literally
covered in a layer of shatter almost and
it coated inside of the brownie but it
worked itself in perfectly to where it
got us all so fun it was like a
pineapple upside-down cake layer of hash
on the outside of the brownies illis so
it was tasty but God I was
leave about 30 minutes after I left the
Irate that [ __ ] I felt my arms drooping
and that was the only way I could really
utilize a pyrex dish without wasting it
so you sit back in the Damned and ask a
tech question now what do you do now
definitely do not blast into a pyrex
dish or use a pyrex dish in our process
anymore at all everything's closed loop
and use parchment when we process it to
go through the back of it so there's no
pirate station needed now nice yeah you
guys stopped me a way to do it there's
no pyrex dish involved in how I was
taught which is kind of neat these guys
are [ __ ] badass at what they do let's
do a urine review and I thought that
would be kind of cool the one thing that
stood out to me too is you got super
[ __ ] sick at the end of the year in
2014 one of the most important things is
really sorry where should happen on the
computer but it's alright we're
recording take care of our bodies is
really important and with him getting so
sick now we're trying to get them back
together and get them healthy and
gaining some more weight eating properly
is one thing we've kind of clicked into
doing or seeking great care of
yourselves going to the gym - now this
will be Spencer's first time going to
the gym today exercise in front anybody
so and it's in our location there are a
lot of large people so I'm sure you guys
don't even look that silly they're like
an Olympic athlete out there
[Music]
if you go by the college but black
blotter black folk you should wear your
grill to the gym Maddie grew my girl's
kink in grapes topper G cross and it
looked beautiful yeah I had two
different nose I had four plants all
together to fiy nose of the same thing
and one got huge and the nodes were
really far away totally different color
the smaller plant the other Fino turned
purple at the end of flower but was
super frosty the other one wasn't as
frosty though did a good job I'm not
sure if that thing is ever gonna get to
market I think that might just be
something that the crew around here gets
to grow but you did a good job all right
so for a year in review both you guys
are involved in these questions you can
both have an answer you can take turns
huh what were some of your favorite
strains to grow since we're all growers
in the room and I might answer on some
of these questions too and since we'll
do a year interview let's see I think at
the beginning of the stuff on the whole
Girl Scout cookie thing I was kind of
running through I still currently still
have a lot of different you know just
different unique cookie stuff but I do
that yet EOG and that kind of put me
onto the OG side of you know kind of
trekking and trying to find different
strains like I picked up triangle the
other day so that's another one to have
around but I'd probably say yetis are as
my favorite planet that's one Jessie
found for us
what am i follow-up questions was gonna
be do you prefer to grow different stuff
for oil - if you're gonna smoke it for
flour do you grow up for yourself do you
grow a different strain and then grow
different for Earl um a lot of times oil
is just depending on what we have
available at the time so if we have
certain strains that we know that are
better and oil than they are flour will
make oil and it seem like we have Kanna
tonic right now which we're gonna you
know split and do some oil and then some
like capsules so there's a little bit of
mix of oh yeah that's why I feel real
high they also gave me too two of those
hash capsules right before we started
the show why am I getting heavy and then
you said that
so Kanna tonic is that the super high
CBD strain mom it's not a crazy high
it's good ratio so three two one THC or
CBD THC ratio so it's nice and great
medicine great medicine yeah yeah great
medicine for people are you gonna take
it - do you have a specific patient in
mind or a type of patient like an
epileptic or someone else or something I
have a couple of people have a couple of
people who are also like cancer patients
that I want to try to get some stuff -
and see if you know just it's not gonna
hurt to give it a try especially when
it's you know cancer that's cool that
you guys help people out guys came from
North Carolina and set up shop in
Colorado and they give away a lot of
medicine and for people to be able to
move at it from out of state and do that
is really cool because there are a lot
of people that are really stingy with
what they grow with other people and
show people what we do yeah that's why
you guys are so well-known cuz you share
and you're super kind I think why we
moved from North Carolina's because
North wanted to tell everybody I grew we
but he was illegal but I was like yo
come look at this room like I'd crack
the door open there's so many people
that you know like you do the same thing
so it's like let me see your weed just
you know everything's common I one thing
I do wish I do wish the barter system
was
a little bit better because it would
take money out of the equation yeah if I
could just go to the restaurant and pay
for it to grow this we don't know who
it's from but there was a New York City
diesel fee no we had and it tastes like
it smells like red wine and we had put
it in this big circle chart all of our
friends including me would just
literally stick their faces in it for it
was insane and then the oil from it was
even crazier it just had such a potent
flavor it was almost it mix it with
something else to kind of dial it down a
little bit then definitely at the end of
the year one of my last favorites is a
tangerine haze times the white yeah I
just found out that I have two packages
of that in my little vault and that [ __ ]
is going to be ran well you're looking
at me like well let's you run it and
give me clones at the keeper
unfortunately in the middle of a process
where we didn't know what we were doing
with our garden or if we were relocating
so I decided not to take clones of it
which was a huge mistake because I had a
fee no that was heavier in the white and
had a really good flavor to it the oil
of course is amazing tangerine oil
tastes crazy yeah she gave me a couple
dabs of this tangerine oil so I'll give
you I've got to pack two seeds I'll give
you a pack maybe both of them you run
them and you find that tangerine Fino
and and then that'll be a good trade
I'll take a keeper out of that [ __ ] okay
nice tangerine flavored one and then
maybe I'll breed two that tangerine
flavoured female I'm so glad you said
that because that was definitely one of
my favorite strains that's from down
with dirt seeds shado Riley that's a
great strain bro good selection usually
if you breed to the white it either
comes out nothing like you don't get any
flavor or you get all that dank
yeah I had one Fino that came out a
really strong white flavor and the
tangerine was still there but it was
definitely a back note to it which was
nice
whatever you were giving me dabs of was
delicious for sure I was like y'all got
some more of those dabs Felicia
at all inside the good dads go away
quickly I've been trying to conserve
what I made and it's hard my dad's all
day we're gonna take a beer we keep
saying the D word so many times I've got
a little bit I got from my good friend
Spence a while back it's the gorilla
haze imagine the size of parchment that
it takes to make that sound you guys
yeah that's a nice piece educated my
next question that I want to talk about
for the year I might mention a couple of
strains I don't even want to talk about
my own strains I should but did you
anything that you there's a few strains
you grew this year that you know that
white widow was pretty unique there's
some of it over there in a jar curing
still and I took a bunch of that to the
string cheese show so what I would light
it the people around me would be like
[Music]
again I took cuts to grow it again a
couple more times cuz I definitely want
to put it in a bigger pot to give it
more love more training more nitrogen
guys if you grow the Gorilla Glue feed
the [ __ ] out of that like yeah it's
hungry it wants a little bit of
everything just over feed it if you
think you're gonna [ __ ] it up in week
four feed it more just feed it more it
should be okay I'm gonna take a dab
somebody's got to say something so I'll
ask a question what are some of your
biggest growing evolutions and one of my
favorites is lemon Jeffrey the white
widow and the Gorilla Glue I guess will
settle on those and the Yeti of course
what are some of your favorite a biggest
growing evolutions that you guys made at
the garden of Weeden this year and I
kind of know what you're gonna say and
I'm gonna give a shout out to somebody
after you do it the cage thing yeah we
kind of changed but with you know stuff
changing and like regulation and laws
and stuff like that you kind of got a
change with the game so now we're kind
of
instead of doing a roomful of multiple
plants were doing less plants same space
but just bigger Longer veg plants so we
really get to take care of a lot of you
know get to spend more time with each
plant management plan for their grow and
a lot of people are catching on to what
they're doing because with the plant now
we have to do something but the spot to
the spot some breeding in there I've
been talking about the light that Jesse
gave me I might not even be able to run
it you guys my grow rooms got like a 7
foot ceiling I grow my plants to usually
five and a half feet tall and I've been
told that you got to keep the plants 3
feet from those lights you'll burn them
because there's probably cover strains
that could go closer than 3 feet but I
just think they it would definitely
stresses a mouse just too much spectrum
and too much just I mean that does if
you've never been on a design
they just hired me at the spot there's a
[Music]
follow those guys inspired it is green
underscore works under yeah and make
sure you follow garden of Weeden don't
follow one of the fake garden of Weeden
look for pictures of these folks I don't
want to be a hater so just ignore it but
make sure that you find a picture of
dispenses a six foot six foot four six
foot five black guy with the beard and
dreadlocks I mean if there's not
pictures of that dude on there don't
follow that one and then Maddie's a
pretty lady they're standing together so
I mean it's easy to spot them I probably
hit them expensive rigger
in the picture so we have at least we
know we worked hard for it yes I'm just
saying you guys are always at this not
just your own all the cool events and
[ __ ] yeah we're so lucky we have so many
friends with awesome toys that we get to
play with all the time yeah this
industry is so great when you make
friends in this community slash industry
that's a good competition there Master
Shake against the rig that Spence
brought over who made that rig you
brought I don't know the name but it's
BC class with a wave yeah that thing
kicks you right in the dick and smiles
it looks at you like Elson is that the
guy from The Simpsons is that his name
they should name it Nelson just kicks
you right in the dick and laughs it's a
great rig but I'm kind of offended by
the way it hit me so we talked about
growing evolutions I didn't change too
much I'm learning more about breeding
and I learned that one of the methods I
try to overdid it and I don't need to
apply so damn much cuz it [ __ ] up my
plants I tried to I make my own silver
thiosulfate and I applied way too many
applications and I learned that if you
overdo it it just pisses the plants off
and you don't get enough pollen and it
sucks so that's what I learned
that's my growing evolution noticed this
other thing Green Works who stood out in
the weed community you can talk about
good and or bad stuff cuz you covered
your face like you [ __ ] or like man
let's see I'll give a shout-out to like
all the people that are you know not
necessarily going away from bottle
nutrients but people who are you know
expanding their grow game into
biologicals um I was actually just
endeavour on Monday and I got to meet up
with the microfusion guys I got some
bags in microfusion for you nice
um and then shout-out to the mills cause
um always hooking me up when I say you
know bills pays the bills yes never used
mills never have an Instagram I think I
used to follow somebody that talked
about mills basophils
[Music]
she raved about it for outdoor her
plants were beautiful too and she is all
about mills so when he started talking
about it well microfusion
then they're doing something together
now their line is now teamed up so they
have their whole feeding chart with the
soon we're gonna make a field trip it's
gonna be Spence and Jesse and myself and
Maddie you can come too if you want
we're gonna go to the worm company in
Springs the rocky mountain worm company
and go visit jay and stock up on some
organic probiotics farmers alliance
those types of guys one time on accident
bought a beer rig across the table and I
had my shirt on and she complimented it
I was like you want to hit and she's
like yeah and that she goes here you're
that guy and as I can because she
recognized me from Instagram so
everybody at the secret cup a lot of
people had ran her
yeah the size of my arms yeah I know
[Music]
so I don't do my own thing all right so
I guess since we're talking about
[ __ ] the talent and stuff that we see
here's a great question after seeing
it's been a full year of legalization
like a year in five days now since we've
legalized recreational adult use
cannabis in the state of Colorado I
remember the moment that you could buy a
weed at a store in Colorado but after
this full year how do you feel about it
and what have you seen make a difference
yes you guys are from a whole other
states it's legal so they have to
regulate it you know and some of the
regulations are shady
yeah but it's stuff that has to be done
if the whole you know the country wants
to use Colorado or Washington as an
example to go legal across the board
they're gonna have to be it's gonna have
to be regulated like if it wants to be
everywhere so eventually like it's gonna
happen it sucks first small people like
myself who are small business mom and
pop trying to be small business yeah
always remember go to the mom
Pop's yeah you always find better stuff
there and you will the big store for
sure yeah check the spot first all right
what did you notice over the last year
so many people from out of state are
flooding into Colorado a lot of people
are from North Carolina its North
Carolina and Texas that have moved here
[Music]
we are all from yeah yeah you brought
the town of Dixie with you yeah and all
of our friends though learned how to
grow amazing weed this year all of our
friends are really caught on quickly and
learned a lot from from us and also
yourself and Instagram it's not only
social network a great media to learn a
lot your table at the should the new and
the old house as part of what started me
thinking about I should do something
because I would go to your place and
guys it's Vincent Maddie's old place and
the new place but people would fly from
North Carolina and come visit these guys
and just hang out for the weekend
and when I would show up to come dab
them out and kind of maybe give them
some Irish seeds and a t-shirt and some
stickers for visiting and maybe a hatpin
they would start asking weed questions
and no [ __ ] ten guys came and nine of
them asked the same exact first three
questions I was like I should just
record this somewhere and play it back
at him like here is my answer like an
automated weed service or some [ __ ] but
I got good at talking to people at the
table and talking about growing weed
like that and so you guys this table
kind of open this up a little bit George
I know you're here so that's kind of
silly our table is because we're always
just taking dabs and talking about
different growing subjects and there's
always so many different people there
it's always a different conversation
there's always something to learn such a
crazy mix of people black guy
why at that part of the map and I missed
figure out where I was aiming for
there's an Asian guy from his Vietnamese
dude a couple of white dudes when
there's legal weed why wouldn't you we
come from a place where you can't have
more than a gram on you well you get a
citation like if it's under 1/8 or happy
but if it's more you have the
possibility of going to jail that's
still that's still real in places I'm so
free we're going home at the end of the
month and so most nerve-racking because
we can't be ourselves there we're so
used to Colorado everything's so
easygoing and free here I'm staying yeah
yeah that's smart that's smart here I
forget that we're still supposed to
people forget that there's an open
container law that applies to cannabis
here you're supposed to have your weed
in a container that's sealed up and out
of your reach like in probably supposed
to be in the trunk
honestly I put mine I've got an SUV so
my trunk I can reach the trunk in my car
I can reach everything I'm [ __ ] 65
and have an SUV
ya know what no matter where I put it so
I put it in the backpack in a container
and my dad's are always out of reach and
in the backseat I mean that's how I roll
sometimes there may have been card abs I
wanted to be a smartass and ask why he
had know what time it was but none of my
jokes are gonna be appropriate Oh guys
get blazed don't work too
[Music]
when everybody got sick everybody came
back strong so that's good Congrats on
that completely different once you get
your what are your full palate back I
still haven't gotten mine full one back
I don't think a whole bunch of crime all
bunch of murder a whole bunch of rape a
whole bunch of little kids running
around smoking spliffs people walking in
the park just getting high yeah yeah
yeah what is there to fight over when
it's legal it is it's like the
no-brainer I just don't understand why
other states don't follow hear that
Maddie's boy guys if you're in another
state [ __ ] legalize weed there what
the hell and have less people in jail
for pointless crimes and make some money
off of cannabis taxes because the state
of Colorado makes a [ __ ] ton I could
google it but that'll give me give me
sidetracked if they make a hole yes I'll
probably try to do that on episode 49 or
50 we'll talk about those numbers look
at Mike here Mike's good with numbers
what's up Mike you've been working hard
bro what's up Adam Jesse that whole true
Tony they all been working their asses
off proud of them they're getting some
[ __ ] done what am I supposed to say fish
cut faster I think that's what I'm
supposed to say yeah they listen to the
podcast at the worksite fish do
something bro [ __ ] do something
man you play xbox later brother alright
so full year of legalization and
nobody's been [ __ ] raped and killed
no kids with joints what's my next
question you guys won a bunch of awards
this year what are some of your proudest
achievements
sorry I just got deep on you we had to
go through a lot of hardships this year
so definitely getting our win first
secret cut melon was awesome for us
pulling everything together and getting
our entry right and perfecting live
resin or not I don't know if you'd
consider it perfecting but working on we
just got really good part of the
pioneering process of trying to perfect
we were with all of our friends and it
was an awesome competition it's pretty
fair in my opinion because you have fur
if anybody doesn't know you have a box
with I think there were 32 maybe 30 you
get to compete with especially Colorado
Colorado's like the first place to do
weed stuff yeah so like now you got it's
supposed to be like the mecca of oil
makers so it's cool to try to win that
you know we're waiting for Colorado and
competing against people you know who
push you can't adjust one the Amsterdam
Cup yeah with the comb when I was
standing there I was standing next to my
girl and they're like when Big D
announced egos like you all know who won
first place you already know who it is I
was like I don't know I don't like I was
like well then that made me think well
obviously it's not spins cuz it's
something that would be it's like gonna
be one of those popular guys it's got
stickers everywhere and [ __ ] everyone
knows him and they were all high-fiving
him as he walked in and I was like I
didn't [ __ ] see bomb anywhere but
[ __ ] garden of Weeden and us all I
could say was holy [ __ ] I just looked at
my girl like dude do we know you guys
walked up to the front she's like
shouldn't you go up
like let my homie have his minute for a
minute like let him do his thing and
then everyone the crowds are gonna be
like they moved out of my way so that I
could walk up towards you guys all like
[ __ ] and then second place was his
speech was great though perfect yeah
from here so this is [ __ ] cool the
best part about it is we had all of our
friends pretty much from North Carolina
we're at the event with us so the best
thing is to win with the people beside
you that you started with a lot of
people thought that I drew that material
because what's up Jerry boy are you
listening where was I oh yeah proudest
achievements so yeah when in that secret
copy that was fun I was there with you
what's the other stuff you guys keep
winning on Thursday top-shelf Thursday
there's multiple social clubs in Denver
too so if you're ever bored and you want
to go smoke somewhere just drive a
Denver and Google social smoke Club
7:10 social lounge okay but you can pay
like a member price they pay like 25
bucks and you can go in there for last
month they did last time they did a 16
person bracket just all the way down to
the finals and I won the finals now it's
32 people so it's a bigger bracket focus
more focus on making sure my tweets
where it should be at before I even make
oil
see that's why I wasn't even making oil
before I wanted to breed and make sure
that [ __ ] was on boy like do that let
you hash makers from go ahead oh one
thing with all these competitions this
year also we met a lot of amazing people
in Denver specifically because we used
to go to Denver we used to not really
know that many people and then we
started going to the social club we kind
of connected with a lot other people so
if you are new to Colorado that's a good
opportunity to meet a lot of other
fellow divers even if you're just
somebody that's in the 7 10 or 20
community from Colorado and you want
other people for sure find it like the
cannabis cup for sure I don't really rep
the high times events but I'll be there
it's the High Times Cannabis Cup it's
April 19 three days this year a lot of
dope-ass events planned out I'll be
there I will not have a booth I was
offered a booth I declined
I'd rather roam around and do a task
rock style just take my backpack and do
what I can
ah yeah it'll go quickly I'm sure it's
more fun that way I don't feel tied down
when I have a booth I can walk around
and go see who I want to and then get
the [ __ ] out when I'm ready and then
I'll get a booth in a couple years I'm
just not ready for that I don't want to
invest into that and be tied down I need
to have some employees that will run the
booth the whole time for me that's what
I want before I measure yeah I'm not
ready for that
so if you're looking forward to me
having a booth at the cup I apologize
but I'm really tall and really white I
got really long dreadlocks and I'm worn
a hydrogen etics t-shirt and or hoody
we're easy to find alright so what's
next for the garden of Weeden you guys
you know 2015 back to the basics and
really work particularly lately been
working on our veg just getting our veg
absolutely perfect and just making sure
all of our stuff is top of the line
getting all of our equipment in check
[Music]
pay attention to the veg you guys don't
pay enough attention to veg I'm not
scolding any of you I'm saying a lot of
people don't pay enough attention
specifically not you sorry you could you
could pay more I'm sure bedroom as much
as you love the flower room because
that's where it all starts healthy
children make healthy adults you have a
shitty bed and sometimes even us we
sometimes start to get so caught up in
our flour room that like I said our veg
started falling behind a little bit so
we're gonna work on just making sure all
of our garden is in check in/check you
guys have a nice team bigger mic call me
Big Mike nine one nine on Instagram
check him out that's one of our good
homies okay Rocco ganja that's him
that's him
it's a rockin Nonna's bodyguard what's
up Mikey come be on the podcast remember
you want bro but we're gonna give you
big dabs Mike isn't into the giant dab
thing like we are over here
because I'm nice so this is just random
side talk when we're talking about
strains a lot of times people and I
tried to avoid it also but so many
people said it that I got sucked into it
a lot of people will say the [ __ ] the
length of times the grateful dog and I
like to say crossed too but so what do
you guys think tweet me that I grow
culture which I wish I could change that
but I can't think about it we'll see
what we can do just make a new one and
then add the link to that one in that I
might have to do new Twitter but tell me
what you think how should we say that is
that what does that X mean because it's
not math it doesn't mean x times two
would make the four you know if you'd
have to bone two it would have four was
what would come out it's all still
though I just don't I mean technically
could be right me personally I just
think when it comes out of my mouth it
just does not sound right because we're
not doing math all right so let's start
something new
yeah what's new what you I'll give you
the opportunity if you can think of
something
[Music]
can I get like phone friend or something
I mean you can take it out alive I'll
try to get this dabble live resin for
you man what's up man have you come on
the show until the whole process I can't
afford that
[Music]
[ __ ] the grateful dog I can say that
when I talk like it the cannabis cup to
people they were gonna be offended some
people might like it yes and f is for
[Music]
alright you guys hear that let's turn
the letter takes big dad's dude Matty
takes bigger dads than we did alright
now that you're pulling out of fat dad
and starting off into the sky what's the
new word protesting you should find a
solution you don't me to pause unless
you take a drink and fly for a minute
[Music]
okay hey do you guys want to be on
episode number 50 you too and Adam and
Jesse and Mike I think I can do that
many people buy some mics and they're
returning [ __ ]
[Music]
yeah all right we're gonna start
wrapping up the show before we go I do
want to say a couple of things first one
thank you guys for coming to is an
awesome podcast that was fun woman on
the show at your location it's awesome
thank you thank you
fist bump Vince is looking at the weed
there's some lemon Jeffery over there in
a jar that I drew there's some platinum
og some girls got cookies some Grateful
dog and some lemon Jeff
grown by me take a peach I can't told
her this from that angle
that's grateful dog I think I think so
crack it open cracking nugs I'm gonna
talk while he does that yeah thanks for
coming let me remind you guys a couple
things I'm changing the name it's not
agriculture it's the girl from your
heart podcast now I don't want to get
sued by that other company as I could
use a new logo by the way well it's my
fault you won't know it's I stole
somebody's name on accident girl from
your heart sounds good that's what it's
all about
could use a logo keep asking for a new
song you know I'm like you playing that
song from the mystic roots man and other
mystic roots band songs cuz they said I
could they're free and I like it grab
for the podcast
there won't be an I drew a culture of
podcast Instagram but the I read
genetics one will exist what are you
gonna take pictures whatever links I'll
just start posting those pictures to the
IRA Genetics Instagram and have one feed
instead of having to fees I'm trying to
keep up with it's just a lot of [ __ ] I
know that sounds like a bunch of
bitching but it is and I'll probably
cancel the YouTube for the podcast also
and just keep the and start doing
something with the IRA genetics YouTube
or something just so much goddamn media
I can't keep up and I want to focus on
doing a good podcast is really what I'm
gonna want to do if you guys want to
email me you can use agriculture
hotmail.com
or grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
check them both episode 50 is coming up
I think Spence will make it I think
Maddie will make it we'll have Jesse
hopefully yeah there we go
Jesse Adam Mike Matty spins myself that
might fill this little space we guys
might have to [ __ ] go yeah so episode
50 will be a small celebration Jesse
teased that he would have some prizes I
definitely have at least an IV genetics
t-shirt or three to give away like a hat
pan
baby's got any prizes or something I got
some tea okay random prize run
downstairs and check the little box that
I've been to a pile you know I don't
want to dedicate too much but when
episode 50 comes Jesse promised some
stuff so what's up Jesse if you listenin
sub 50 is in like a week and a half if
you listen I want you to message me let
me know what you learned on the podcast
is we want to talk about that on episode
50 and recap for you like we did the
urine review I kind of want to know your
which you learned from the show I wanna
know who your favorite guests were I
think I just listed them right it was
[ __ ] Spencer Jesse Mike Adam guest
Shawn dude [ __ ] I think Shawn got the
most listens if you want to come be on
episode 50 you can bro but it's gonna be
a party I'd kind of rather reserve your
knowledge for when it's just you and I
face to face cuz you [ __ ] school me
that's awesome
if there's somebody around here you'd
like to have on the podcast let me know
it's hard for me to reach out to people
if you have something you want me to ask
other people and you have some ideas if
you like get this person on back that up
with a like and ask them this girl from
accom or you could tweet me agriculture
I might make a new one since been said
that idea it's kind of smart I probably
will grow from your heart will have a
new Twitter page I'm sure there's
something that's good for my heart
somewhere else that's gonna [ __ ] try
to sue me for that too but yeah well
stand up for this one I've had that on
my website for a long time so I think I
own that one
cool big fist bumps everybody at the
table I'm gonna read this part it goes
now this the show is over please go to
iTunes or stitcher go to the iTunes or
stitcher main page and search for the
iGrow culture podcast search for the
girl from your heart podcast or one of
the two search for both find the review
section give us a five star rating after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comments on the podcast guys don't
forget that the shows available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode will always be archived and I
read genetics Colorado calm you can
leave comments there as well make sure
you follow everyone on Twitter Instagram
and Facebook its garden of Weeden all
one word with an end at the garden of
weed and make sure you follow those guys
make sure you follow Greenworks the
bunch of great dabs ridiculous that rig
dude broke my face
they made a whole challenge to do a
podcast at the beginning just kind of
mean make sure you follow I read
genetics on Instagram please do that
we're it like 10,000 and some change now
so that's kind of cool if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcaster
she's got a product you'd like us to
review send me an email to Agriculture
hotmail.com or grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and i will give you all the
information you need
I do need a logo keep saying that big
shout out to my ninja Spence shout out
to Angela thanks again for listening you
guys until next time take your fat dab
give your mom a hug for me we're gonna
end the show with a song by our boy
sloppy song it takes a second for it to
roll in so we might just ramble for a
second I'm actually gonna fire up a big
dab of this live resin and then we'll
turn the mics down and let the song kick
on and the garden weed and get weeded
Kapaa bye y'all everyone's why you gotta
make it up any boxes
[Music]
you know what it is holding it down for
North Carolina in Colorado all right
podcast Rona thank you guys once again
for listening to episodes 45 46 47 and
48 of the girl from your heart podcast
I'll be back Monday with the brand new
full-length episode I wanna remind
everybody once again to follow me on
twitter it's @g fyh podcast also check
us out on facebook look for the girl
from your heart a podcast and if you'd
like to send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
i would love to hear from you that's all
I've got for you for this long episode
thanks again for listening and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
you