[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 215 of the
girl from Earhart podcast you're a
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat ku and the entire mystic
roots crew
I hope everybody's having a good week
hope you had a good weekend I hope
you're listening to this on Monday when
it comes out fresh no matter what day of
the week it is what time it is wherever
you are hope you're having a good time
over here smoking a Fed joint maybe
taking a DAB with me I've been smoking
on the I've got some Three Rivers
distillate I've got some Three Rivers
organics dub wise distillate it was
grown by me it was actually extracted by
the folks at pure distilled I'm really
enjoying the Three Rivers dub wise
distillate it's pretty nice I've been
talking a lot about the HCF SC and the
HTF SE the high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract and the high
terpene full-spectrum extract and all
those extracts I'm not sure if I prefer
the distillate or the hdfs II to tell
you the truth to treat my most of you
folks that listen to the podcast know
I've got a little traumatic brain injury
and sometimes it [ __ ] with me and I
think smoking a fat dab of distillate is
the quickest way to make my head noise
go away but sometimes I really enjoy the
effects of the high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract crystals and a
nice chunky dab I'm not sure which I
prefer so they're in competition they're
both trying to win my heart we will see
which one wins where do we start
let's talk about this thermal banger
I've had an evil week I hope you guys
have had as good of a week as I have on
Wednesday I had a an adventurous day I
started off by heading to elevate
elevate glass 517 South Tejon I picked
up in Colorado Springs I picked up a
brand new thermal banger let me explain
this thermal banger a little bit let me
explain to normal banger and then we
will kind of describe the thermal banger
so a normal banger a banger fits on a
hash pipe a bubbler a small bong I
prefer a very small dab rig so this is
the part that you actually will put the
dab into this part fits on your hash
pipe your bubble or your small bong your
little dab rig a hitman sidecar or a
little mad Rob or a little Toro piece
this piece fits on there this is the
part you heat up you put the dab into
here it kind of looks like it could be
just a normal bowl it's got a stem that
comes up and then it's got a 90-degree
angle and then there is a quartz just a
dish I just looks like just don't you
keep that up and then you put your dab
in there and then you put a carve cap on
it and you take a dab
it's just a normal dish it just looks
like you took a dish like it maybe a
thimble and then attached it to a way to
put it onto the bong or onto your rig
so and the idea is you heat that up and
they let it cool a little bit you put
the dab in there and cover with a carb
cap in the carp cap Stokes the heat and
then you get a nice healthy dab with the
thermal banger this is a little bit
different it's like they took the
original idea of the banger and then on
the inside they put another piece of
glass which is where the dab will
actually go so it's hard to explain it's
like a it's like a thimble with another
thimble inside of it basically and
they're both made out of glass it's all
made out of glass it's supposed to be
quartz these are glass so um you heat
the outside of this thermal Boehner and
the House earlier of the glass gets
really hot the glass on the inside does
not get hot you drop your dab into the
glass on the inside and you cap it now
this does a few things first of all the
dab you just drop down there doesn't
come in contact with the heated surface
so it doesn't cool the nail down super
quickly when you're taking large dabs
sometimes the hash will cool the nail
and it will steal your heat so you don't
get all the dab so that can't happen
with this because you're not actually
putting the the dab on the heated
surface also I gives it low tip we say
low temps for taste you gotta taste
wasted to taste it
lower temps for better turps I have
realized that is not how I want to dab I
like hot dabs I like my sheet a little
bit too hot I am in the glow squad I
want to burn myself I don't like wasting
hash I like going at it too hot and
making sure I get it all I do not feel
like the thermal banger is something
that I'm going to enjoy I'm gonna keep
giving it a few tries I might test it I
liked watching the hdfs II burn in it it
seemed to melt a little bit differently
a puddle differently but it is not my
style you guys the the thermal Boehner
is not Rasta Jeff approved I may have to
get a different carb cap I may have bare
foot come over and show me how to use it
a little differently but so far from
what I've played with and what I've seen
my friends do with it that is not my
style it's for low temp dabbing I like
these hot hot and hurty long burnin dabs
so I don't know that the thermal banger
is for me and I turn a basher
actually I want you to go by one and try
it see what you think let me know what
you think about the thermal banger I got
mine at elevate glass at 5:17 South Bay
hone in beautiful downtown Colorado
Springs Colorado go there get one see
what you think about it shot my friends
at elevate so I was talking about my
amazing day on Wednesday let's talk a
little bit more about that other than
getting the thermal Bangor we headed up
to Denver and I started my evening with
a Metallica concert it's right we headed
up to Denver and there were two opening
acts
I think the first band was called
volbeat and then after that it was
Avenged Sevenfold no offense to anybody
that's into either of those bands or
those bands I purposefully missed them I
was not into those bands at all I went
to see Metallica I'm not really into the
hard rock metal thing honestly but I
grew up on Metallica Metallica was my
first favorite band I think there may
have been bands before that when I was a
little kid and didn't know any better
but I think when I was becoming in a
rebellious teenager I think Metallica is
what helped me do that I used to wear a
Metallica shirt every day my closet was
just filled with black Metallica shirts
I had all of them if they put out a
Metallica shirt in that era I had it
I've been a Metallica fan for a long
time I'm a drummer
I've played drums I think I got drums
for my 14th or 15th birthday uh and the
drummer from Metallica was the dude that
inspired me so I was about probably 13
or 14 years old and my uncles they're
bad influences on me but they're really
cool dudes they decided to take me to a
concert in California I'd never been to
a big Stadium concert I'd been to like
little shitty gigs and stuff but I'd
never been to a real concert so my
uncle's Ron and Eric shout out dudes
ah they took me to see some shitty bands
they took me to see Jackyl and the Damn
Yankees it's not the coolest bands on
the planet but when you're a 14 year old
kid or a 13 year old kid bucking drums
and guitars and loud and lots of people
and we're looking freaks and boobs
everywhere it was a great time so how
does Metallica tie into that my uncle's
my uncle Eric had a Chevy El Camino it's
like a super [ __ ] white trash
Rockstar ride that's like a truck it's
kind of lowered but it had a camper
shell on it so my uncles were in the
front and I was in the back part where
the camper shell is and
was no window between us and them are
between myself in them and they smoked
the joint and put on the black album I'd
been smoking a little bit of weed with a
friend of mine but not regularly I
hadn't I hadn't become a pothead yet
they put on the black album
it starts with inner sandman and then
it's sad but true and I think it's
through than ever maybe you're holier
than now but enter sandman' and sad but
true we're all you [ __ ] me that
starts the whole album off it starts the
whole day off perfectly ah they smoked
the joint
I'm pretty sure I got a little stone
from the joint that they smoked in the
front of the car cuz they just hotbox
that [ __ ] they rolled up the windows
and smoked on the highway so all the
smoke came to the back of the car where
I was I got good and stoned that day I
decided I was going to be a drummer I
knew that I had to play the drums and
that joint that my uncle smoked and
Metallica and that adventure that day
changed me and that told me that day hey
you're gonna be a drummer this is part
of your [ __ ] life this is what you're
gonna do so I've been in Metallica a
huge Metallica fans since then I was
already a Metallica fan but that's what
sold me getting stoned with my older
uncles on accident I don't even think
they realize they were getting me high
in the car they were just doing their
own thing but I got stoned with them saw
a great concert and then they just
changed my life now I'm sure that the
next day I was obnoxious air-drumming on
everything
drumming on the desk at school actually
got kicked out of several classes in
school it continued all the way through
my high school career ah I got kicked
out of all my classes for drumming on
the desk and eventually my last year of
high school I only had band classes
that's not a joke alright so I drove it
and saw metallica metallica was [ __ ]
awesome you guys Sports Authority Field
is huge [ __ ] trying to park at that
place it took me no joke 30 maybe 45
maybe an hour to find a parking place
eventually I ended up paying $25 for a
parking space ended up paying 20 more
dollars for a pedal cab to get me from
that parking space to the venue it was
worth the ride it was worth paying a
little dude to pedal me around he was
pretty cool he knew a lot of stuff about
Denver knew about the area that was
helpful so man [ __ ] parking but once we
got there it was cool once we got into
the video was cool I timed it
beautifully we got some food on the way
we stopped at elevate of course we hit
some traffic there was a little bit of
rain we had to drive around and find
parking once we got into the venue we
had time to find we got some snacks we
got
slice of pizza we got some drinks just
just cokes you guys no beer nothing I
don't go crazy I don't drink at all um
and so we found our seats and we looked
around and I talked to the guy next
music what's up bro it's going man and
apparently the guy in front of me was
super drunk and being an [ __ ] trying
to talk to everybody he did not want to
talk to me so that was cool
Metallica came out shortly after that
and did quite a few cool songs they did
mostly new stuff they did the Atlas rise
and they did uh there's another one that
I can't [ __ ] hardwired to
self-destruct they did those I'm not a
huge fan of the new stuff it's really
cool I just like everybody says everyone
that's a fan of music they all like the
old stuff better everybody just says I
want to hear the old stuff and that's
kind of how I felt about it I'm looking
at my phones I made a note really a list
of songs that they play but I cannot
find it here I know I have it in my
phone anyway um they were jamming
they're rocking out they did for Whom
the Bell Tolls and they did another song
and then after that the band looked kind
of confused they were like I'm not sure
what's happening here and then they all
walked off the stage and a dude came on
the microphone over the PA system and he
said hey guys we're not canceling the
show but there's a major lightning storm
over Denver right now and he could see
it people have been watching it they're
like there's a major lightning storm we
need everybody to exit the grandstand
which this is the football stadium in
Denver we need everyone to exit the
grandstand and please make your way
safely to the concourse so we all had to
get up out of our seats and go find
shelter basically from the rain and from
the lightning in the concourse at Sports
Authority Field it was crowded it was
obnoxious people were smoking and
blowing [ __ ] cigarette smoke in my
face half the people were drunk and
ridiculous but I knew that if I waited
there was more Metallica so I'm
scrolling through my phone so Lee here
because I made a couple of notes on
songs that they played and can't find
the note which is weird
but anyway Metallica did come back on we
made it back to our seats Metallica came
back on ah
they played I think they played
motorbreath at that point and then they
talked for a couple of seconds James
Hetfield actually gave a little bit of a
speech he's like hey uh I forgot exactly
how he said it but he talked about I
don't care if you voted for this guy I
don't care if you voted for that guy I
don't care if you drink this I don't
care if you smoke that I don't care if
you believe in a God won't care for you
don't believe in a god he's basically
said we're here to [ __ ] party and
listened to Metallica so we're all
[ __ ] friends [ __ ] all that [ __ ]
which I thought was kind of cool then
they played then James asked do you guys
want some hard stuff and of course the
crowd was like yeah and James Austin
James Hetfield from Metallica is kind of
funny he tries to be a comedian on stage
he's pretty good front dude things like
you guys want to hear some hard stuff
and of course the crowd was like [ __ ]
yeah so that's when I really feel like
Metallica started firing it up they did
sad but true then they did one followed
by master of puppets followed by
creeping death then they brought out
they brought out another drum set and
set it at the very front edge of the
stage you guys this was at Sports
Authority Field I was a mile away it was
a mile high plus I was a mile away from
the [ __ ] stage everybody looked like
they were about 1/4 inch tall from where
I could see him the drumset was just a
blur the backdrop was amazing the blood
the backdrop was so cool they had 50
foot tall video screens they would play
videos on the pyrotechnics were pretty
cool
it was pretty bitchin ah so then they
did seek-and-destroy on the front of the
stage like that then they did fight fire
with fire
I've been there a couple more songs that
I did not make a note of they shredded
for a little while longer
I remember hearing creeping death in
there fade to black was in there then
they on court of course with [ __ ]
Enter Sandman everybody's saying enter
sandman' it was a great show lots of
great pyrotechnics I like I said I was a
mile away I was in the back section of
the Sports Authority Field and when some
of the pyrotechnics would go off I could
feel the heat I could tell that my date
was cold because it was getting chilly
and it was raining I could tell that she
would feel relieved when some of the
pyrotechnics would go off she'd be like
Oh warm then she would reach to it like
a little heater so Metallica was [ __ ]
awesome
Metallica shredded all night
it the show ended it took us a little
bit to get out of there because humans
are [ __ ] cattle and they're half
[ __ ] but once we got out of there we
made it to the car and then we headed to
servantes other side at Five Points in
Denver because one of my favorite reggae
artists Capleton was playing at
servantes other side when we walked in
he was already playing I feel like you'd
only been going for a few songs because
he went for a good 45 minutes to an hour
or so after we got there ah man Capleton
is a reggae artist who is known for
playing really high-energy set at reggae
Sunsplash and roto tom
reggae music festivals i check him out
you guys if you were into reggae music
if you're into high-energy music check
out Capleton Kabletown put on a great
show shout out to everybody
I had servantes other side man I had a
good time there she's not a lot to talk
about about the Capleton show the
Metallica show was huge so many people
so much pyrotechnics the Capleton show
was a small club shows a small I'm gonna
say maybe three maybe five hundred
people there there couldn't have been
five hundred people in that club but
every single person was paying attention
to every single moment of that Capleton
concert he speaks the way he speaks you
just have to listen you cannot turn your
head when Capleton speaks he really gets
your attention so I had a huge weekend
seeing some music
tomorrow night actually I will be seeing
dead end Co at Folsom Field in Boulder
Colorado so I look forward to that and
then I've got a whole bunch more cool
stuff coming up fish I'm super excited
to see fish I'm gonna do all three
nights of fish at Dick's Sporting Goods
then I've got some comedy shows coming
up it's gonna be a great summer hey let
me know if you're going to any shows if
you're gonna go see some reggae music if
you're gonna go see whatever kind of
music you're gonna go see whatever
you're doing for summer fun let me know
what you're gonna do I want to hear
about it I just got to brag for like a
good 15 minutes about all the cool [ __ ]
that I do send me an email let me know
what you're doing this summer let me
know how you were involving cannabis in
your summer fun plans I would love to
hear from you send me an email grow from
your heart at hotmail.com or you can
tweet me at g f YH podcast let me know
what you're doing so let's move this
podcast forward just a little bit you
guys there are over
the YouTube videos posted I think I've
got video number 52 or 53 is up now by
the time you listen to this 53 should be
posted I want to thank everybody who's
been subscribing I've been getting a lot
of video views and a lot of subscribers
already I've only got 50 something
videos I've got another 160 to put up so
I appreciate everyone who has subscribed
thank you guys I appreciate it
if you want to check out the videos of
the first 50 episodes I'll go to youtube
and just search for the girl from your
heart podcast click subscribe on there
honestly you guys the first 50 videos
are a mess there's not a lot of effort
put into them because I'm just trying to
get them out there and get caught up
once I get caught up the videos will get
better I know what I'm doing now I've
played with iMovie enough to kind of
have a little clue on it so I just need
to take some time
make some effort and get caught up it
takes however long the podcast is it
takes about 2 or 3 times that amount of
time to make the video for it plus it
takes like another 2 hours for it to
upload and while it's uploading I can't
make another I can't work on the
computer very much because the way that
iMovie works it just if you change
anything it [ __ ] everything up so I
kind of kind of ties up my computer for
2 or 3 hours so I try to make the videos
at night and then launch one up before I
go to bed and then I'll make another one
early in the morning and start launching
it to YouTube before I go to work so
that way it's loading while I'm busy
anyway the videos are happening that's
the point and I would appreciate it if
you subscribe that's a way for you to
listen to old episodes so also I want to
know what you think of the Thursday
episodes I've been putting out I've been
putting out old old episodes blocks of
old episodes on Thursdays I'm calling it
throwback Thursday let me know what you
think of that a few people have emailed
me and said that they'd appreciate it
one person asked me to put the titles of
the old episodes in there so they know
what they're listening for I will try to
remember to do that but honestly it's a
lot of work and sometimes I don't even
listen to the old episodes I just have
to make the chunks of shows and put them
out and get them to you because I am a
little bit overwhelmed with all of my
commitments and priorities to tell you
the damn truth but I love getting the
podcast out to you guys so it's always
gonna happen I haven't missed a single
Monday in 3 years
215 episodes I haven't missed a show you
guys I'm dedicated I promise
right I want to keep them in the podcast
world I am going to talk about cannabis
in the show I promise I've just got a
whole bunch of other [ __ ] on my mind I
have this pie if this episode doesn't
keep you entertained there will be
another podcast coming out Thursday and
there will be another one Monday so I
hope I don't lose you let's talk about
patreon right quickly I know I haven't
talked about ganja at all but we're
going to patreon I owe a few people some
thank-yous I'm not sure if people want
me to say their real names on the
podcast so I'm just gonna cover
everybody in one gigantic thank you
listen if you've contributed on patreon
thank you for your contribution I truly
appreciate it it does not go unnoticed
every contribution is appreciated I see
it I get an alert and this is my thank
you to you I'm not sure if I'm supposed
to say your name because I don't know if
you're supposed to be known that you're
donating your money to a podcast or if
you're even supposed to be known that
you're listening to a ganja podcast or
if it's even supposed to be know that
you're growing cannabis or supporting
cannabis so I don't say people's names
I'm trying to be better about that but
thank you I appreciate it if you don't
know what patreon is let me explain it
really quickly patreon is a service that
allows you as a listener to financially
contribute to the podcast if you feel
like the podcast was worth a couple of
bucks of your time all you have to go
all you have to do is go to
patreon.com/scishow all from your heart
you put it a little bit of information
your name address phone number all that
and then it will ask for your credit
card number once it asks for that you
get to decide how much you want to
contribute you can sign up for a monthly
contribution which is known as the
subscription or you can sign up for a
one-time contribution it's up to you if
you sign up for a monthly your credit
card will be billed on the first of
every month for the amount that you
decide to contribute now that will be
taken from your credit card and put
directly into my PayPal account on the
third of the month now what I am going
to do with those funds is I will use
those funds to pay for my website Irie
genetics Colorado com that is where I
host this podcast that's my way of
keeping the podcast free for the general
public everybody can listen to this
podcast for free 100 episodes of this
podcast are always kept in the feed for
free plus I'm updating all of the old
episodes on YouTube so you've got the
entire archive to listen to for free
forever I do not need everybody to pay I
want you to listen to the show for free
and I want you to appreciate it I want
you to enjoy it I want you to learn how
to grow better
Cannabis I want you to teach people the
right ways about cannabis and break the
myths and break the truths support
cannabis legalized cannabis and get
everybody healing themselves with proper
cannabis I want it to happen for free
there are people out there however who
do want to contribute and who are able
to contribute to the show and those
folks can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart if you can't
contribute I still love you I still want
you to listen and I still want you on my
team this podcast is still for you
alright I feel like an evangelist for a
minute so I'm gonna hold off on all this
patreon talk let's talk about some ganja
related madness all right here's
something I've wanted to talk about
because it's something I've been
experiencing you guys ever go through
phases where sometimes you can smoke all
of the hash or all of the weed and
nothing happens like I've got days where
I feel like I could just open up my
shatter and just take half gram dabs all
day and I don't get high properly like
I'll get a little bit of a boo for a
couple of seconds but then I'm just like
that that was fun
and it'll last for days like that and
I'll feel like I just smoked all of my
hash and all of my weed and I just keep
smoking and nothing happens and then one
day it'll flip to where I can think
about smoke and some hash and I just
feel high as [ __ ] like I'm super high or
some days you just open up the parchment
and before you even get the dabber on
the nail you're like wow it's so high
already
are there some days I can take just a
little dab and get super rekt and it's
really odd I've been noticing that I go
through phases where I can smoke all of
the hash and then it'll flip on me and
then I could just barely smoke and get
rekt I've been trying to pay attention
to a few things and see what causes this
and what is related to this the first
thing I would say is it's directly
related to my hydration if I have not
been drinking enough water my lungs hurt
when I take a DAB I can feel it my lungs
are like dude that's hot that's dry [ __ ]
you hydrate yourself and how much food I
have consumed and what kind of food have
I've had a lot of sugary stuff I can't
get high properly sometimes if I've had
too much caffeine and too many sugary
snacks and I take a DAB instead of
getting high properly I just get jittery
and anxious and it'll feel good and I
have to wait like through the initial
high of the dab to feel okay like a good
fifteen or twenty minutes later once the
blood
and the [ __ ] Mountain Dew or the dr.
pepper sugar and the cookies and the dab
all stop fighting each other so it's
directly related to my hydration and my
food consumption and my blood sugar I
and they all those three together are
the main components and it's mostly
hydration because I can take huge dabs
if I'm well hydrated if I wake up and
just hydrate heavily and then start
taking big globs I can smoke heavy all
day and my lungs are okay with it if I
don't drink plenty of water and I start
taking big dabs my lungs burn and then
by the late part of the day I don't want
to dab hard anymore and I'm tired and
worn out so I think a lot of my thing is
directly related to hydration which is
directly related to my blood sugar I
feel like when I don't have the right
food I get high and I get lazy and I get
rekt but if I eat right I get high and I
get uplifted and I feel much better I
also think that a lot of my being able
to get really rekt and not being able to
get high properly has stuff to do with
the weather when it's really hot outside
I don't even like to get real high I
missed an O I skipped an opportunity to
go smoke with some friends baby because
it was 90 degrees outside there wasn't
anywhere cool to go smoke it was just
too hot and just being in the car if we
would have gone to the car to smoke if
we would have gone somewhere else to
smoke just being outside back in the
heat I'm just gonna [ __ ] ruin my day
and give me a headache and make me lazy
so sometimes the weather has stuff to do
with it I don't like to get too blazed
in the too hot when it's cold let's
smoke I can smoke like I said I can
smoke all of the hash when it's cold
there's just something about it that I
really enjoy being wherever out in the
car out in the backyard camping whatever
alysha's smoke when it's cold I can
handle that my body likes it and it's
probably because I'm not getting so
dehydrated and I'm not just trying to
survive and my hydration isn't suffering
another thing that affects my ability to
medicate or get high properly is my
stress and anxiety level if I'm stressed
if you guys ever experienced this have
you been
maybe you got high and you went for a
drive or maybe you got high and you had
an experience that some adrenaline
kicked in and you can't be high anymore
have you noticed your high just [ __ ]
goes away at those points or have you
ever had just something scare you and
just blow your whole high like maybe you
get pulled over and
as soon as you see those red and blues
and miraculously I am not even high
anymore
I think stress kind of blocks my ability
to get blazed properly if I'm too
worried about work or podcasting or
whatever it is that people worry about
nowadays half the time it's dumb [ __ ]
that we [ __ ] invented anyway because
this is just a fake world that we live
in we should be doing totally different
[ __ ] than what we do with our lives but
see that that that that stress right
there is what I think [ __ ] with my high
sometimes it just doesn't let me get
where I want to be some to stress with
the [ __ ] world and with stupid [ __ ]
also environment I feel like when I
smoke at this table at this spot right
here
I could I could never get too high at
this spot because I'm in my comfort zone
I've got a bottle of dr. pepper right
here I got a bottle of water right here
I got all my apothecary jars right here
my eye pads right here my bones right
here my computers right here my bed is
like 30 steps from here there's a
refrigerator full of goodies right there
I got a TV over there there's not a lot
could go wrong in this environment so I
feel like when I smoke right here I get
I allow myself to get pretty high but I
get in a bubble I get in this productive
bubble I want to clean this area up on
organize all this [ __ ] and I want to
start writing podcasts I want to start
just this is my creative zone of my
space right here so when I smoke right
here certain things happen but if I were
to go I know I keep talking about the
car sorry Mike sometimes I medicate in
my car the vibe is completely different
I feel like I get much more medicated
when I smoke in the car because I'm not
in my comfort zone if I'm a passenger or
a driver if I'm out smoking in the car I
get way more blazed because my mind is
more stimulated and I can't just be here
in my bubble when I'm here in my bubble
I don't have to worry about anything my
my sense is no you're safe you could
turn off when I'm out in public
I'm like a [ __ ] deer out in the
danger and everything is just blinking
at me and I got to pay attention to it
so I get blazed I see that even more and
I get even higher from it so also I
think when I go to places like the can
of Canyon my high is way different
because it's a social high I've got to
stay I can't get blackout blazed or
silent blaze because sometimes I like to
smoke myself into a silent stupor that's
what I enjoy when I'm alone then it
makes my mind go and gets me creative
and I just start flowing but I can't do
that at places like the canna Canyon
because people want to talk to
so I think my environment has a huge
part about how my high plays out on how
I'm able to get and how much just how
much I noticed maybe I don't notice that
I'm super high when I'm sitting at this
table because nothing can go wrong and
maybe you do notice that you're super
blazed after to DAB's when you're out at
the mall just because you feel like
everyone's looking at you just cause
you're aware so I think environment
plays a huge part in how high I am and
am not able to get one thing I really
don't like to do but a lot of my friends
love to do they like to smoke and then
eat and I am the exact opposite I like
to eat and then when I'm done eating and
I don't need anymore food that's when I
toke down and get blazed because I feel
like if I eat right after I smoke I
pretty much just wasted the food and I
wasted those dads because they're both
just gonna balance each other out
there's gonna dig 8 each other I won't
notice either one so eat a big fat meal
get nice and nourished get comfy then I
chug up a little bit of water then right
after that the dad time are you guys
I've been rambling for like 30 minutes
I'm gonna press pause for a minute I'm
gonna take one of those dabs I've been
talking about I'm also gonna take a
couple of drinks and then I'll be right
back and we are going to read an email
from a listener
all right podcast world I am back I got
hydrated it definitely took way too many
dabs
I was dabbing this lemon Jeffrey high
cannabinoid full-spectrum x-ray with a
little bit of Heitor beam full-spectrum
extract poured into it with a little bit
of dub wise distillate dropped on top of
that then I rolled that sticky dab into
a little bit of this THC a powder and
then I got way too lit mic off for about
seven minutes
I blew about a gallon of snot out of my
nose now I think I've got my [ __ ]
together and we're gonna try to do a
podcast all right so I got an email from
somebody I'm not sure if I'm supposed to
use their name I'm not going to we're
just gonna skip that this email comes
from a listener and if you'd like to
email me you can send me an email it
grow from your heart at a hotmail.com
maybe I'll read your email on a future
episode this email goes like this hey
brother did I hear that correctly and
then he says half asleep on a throwback
episode I can't remember where did you
say that you switch back to 1864 late
flush do you still do that back in the
Hydra days I would sometimes put them
back into total blackout for the last
two or three days I've never
her going back to more light would you
mind giving your thoughts behind that uh
to tell you the truth bro I don't think
I said that I hope I did not say that I
do remember one instance where that may
be useful I have talked about Reeve
edging your plants the only reason that
I would recommend going to more light at
the end of flower would be to revert
your plant back to the veg stage that's
the only time it's useful do not go back
to 18 6 at the end of flowering if
you're going to change your time at the
end of your flower period I would go
with more darkness and less light so
maybe go from 12 12 to 14 hours of
darkness and 10 hours of light or maybe
increase your dark period but do not add
light to the end of your flowering
period that'll [ __ ] your plants up it
will confuse them it will make them
think that it's time to revenge they
will start reef edging if you want to
revenge that is something you can do but
if you don't want to revenge the plant
don't do that
you must have been half asleep you might
have been high and it's [ __ ] weird
that you're dreaming about me but please
don't do that and thanks for the email
there's more to this email I'm gonna
keep reading it says I really like your
show incidentally only recently
discovered it keep up the good work keep
up the good hard work ethic the fun and
I appreciate the rallying content which
is always solid I learned stuff I think
new thoughts
I respect the point of view - I'm good
with using the content of this email in
any ups in any episodes or not as you
prefer but no name please as I'm not as
I'm in not land so I think he meant to
type I'm in prohibition land or not
legal and he skipped the word there but
then he says thanks man and he signs his
name dude thank you for the great email
I hope you did not try to put this 18:6
into practice at the end of your
flowering phase because that would have
caused you problems and then I would
have felt like a dick for messing up
your crop um let's talk about the only
reason that would be useful because this
is where I'm sure you got this idea
the only time they going to 18-6 at the
end of your flowering phase would be
useful is if you plan to revenge that
plan the only time that that's useful is
if you do not have a clone let's say you
got a clone from your friend you grew it
you thought your buddy had more clones
he doesn't that weed that you grew about
week six week seven you realized this is
the best [ __ ] weed I have ever grown
I want to grow this more there are no
clones there are no other options that's
the only plant of that strain left so
here's what you could do 14 days before
harvest you can turn your light timer
back to eighteen six or you can put it
on 24 hours that will make the plant
start thinking it's time to go back into
veg but that 14 days will not be enough
time for the plant to actually return to
veg if you cut it down as predicted in
14 days so you're gonna cut down most of
the plant and you will leave about four
maybe five or six shoots at the very
bottom of the plant just small little
buds with just just enough to keep the
plant alive and if you put that back
into the 24 or 18 six after you harvest
the rest of the plant the remaining
plant will eventually turn itself back
to veg and you were speeding it up and
buying yourself time by putting it under
the veg flowering cycle while you're in
flower that's just gonna save you time
to revert your plant also if you're
trying to revert it feed it a high
nitrogen diet and also add some sea kelp
to there there are tricks that you can
do with gibberellic acid I don't have
enough experience to talk about it on
here if you want to research Reve edging
your plant by using gibberellic acid it
is very possible I know somebody who
does it that information is very easily
available online I have not enough
experience with it to talk about it
myself but I encourage you to try it if
you don't have a clone of your favorite
plant you can revenge it but that's the
only time that I think of it increasing
your light cycle at the end of a
flowering phase would be useful so
please like I said earlier don't do that
to your normal flowering plants if
you're trying to speed them up if you're
trying to make them Hardy R if you're
trying to make things change reduce the
light because
these plants are photosensitive the
light does 90% of the [ __ ] to these
plants it gives it all the signals it
tells it what's going on so if you start
adding more it thinks the days are
getting longer which means it thinks it
needs to veg if you reduce time it
thinks days are getting shorter which
makes it think it needs to finish here's
a tip that I gave somebody online just
recently this tip was about a very
specific strain there is a strain that
goes around Colorado right now that
produces very delicious oil the hash
that comes from this plant is [ __ ]
delicious the Terps that come out of
this are amazing top-shelf Terps it's
what everybody wants the flowers are
ugly as [ __ ] this plant doesn't finish
up it would take you could probably let
this plant go 12 to 14 weeks and it
would finish up nicely most people don't
have that much time and they're
impatient and they don't understand
what's going on I had the opportunity to
play with this plant several times in
what I learned and this was just
thinking and trying to figure out how to
speed up the plant and thinking what I
could do I simply reduce the time I go
from 12 12 when I'm in flower about the
end of week 7 or 8 I drop it from 12 12
to 10 on and 14 off now I'm giving it 10
hours of daylight and 14 hours of
darkness it thinks the days are getting
shorter
I'll let it go for about a week like
that then I'll take two more hours off
now I'm only running that light for
eight hours a day on and 16 hours a day
off now this plant is thinking that
winter is coming and it says what the
[ __ ] am I gonna do I must reproduce so
it starts making fatter and fatter buds
the trichomes start riping up I make it
a little colder in the room drop it just
three or four more degrees get it nice
and chilly in there at night those
plants will finish up much more quickly
you can cut 2 to 3 weeks off of these
plants instead of 14 weeks you can
finish these plants at 10 or 11 weeks
I've cut them down at the end of week 10
and I've considered them to be done but
you've got to speed them up by reducing
the timer late in Flour if you do it at
week six you're kind of cutting yourself
off of optimal growth if you do it week
seven at the end of week seven you can
really start speeding up the finishing
time of longer flowering plants
all right you guys I want to thank
everybody for listening to this semi
short episode I know I didn't talk a
whole lot about cannabis and I did not
give a whole lot of useful information
but I hope you had fun hanging out with
me anyway I had a long productive week I
had a lot of fun I did not have as much
time for the podcast as I would like to
have had but I will bring you a better
episode next week I need to get myself
ready to go see the Grateful Dead
tomorrow and Boulder it's not the
Grateful Dead but it's close enough it's
dead and Coe it is most of the remaining
Grateful Dead members that are alive -
Phil Lesh Phil's taking it easy he's
staying in California he's the original
bass player right now they've got Oteil
Burbridge on bass and also they have got
John Mayer on lead guitar if you haven't
seen dead and Coe with John Mayer on
guitar you're probably going what the
[ __ ] John Mayer plays guitar for The
Grateful Dead he does and at first I
wanted to hate it when I heard about
this years ago I was like they put bad
dude on guitar with a Grateful Dead what
are they doing then I went and saw it
and I have no complaints I'm satisfied
it's [ __ ] perfect I am amazed at how
perfect it is he is one of us I've
listened to him talk about it I've seen
him play it no doubt in my mind John
Mayer is one of us so big shout at John
Mayer for making the dead and Coe
magical I can't wait to go tomorrow
shout to everybody that I got to dance
with in Boulder because this is gonna
come out on Monday the show will already
have happened I hope we all had a good
time together ladies and gentlemen I
would love it if you go to iTunes if you
go to the iTunes Store search for the
girl from your heart podcast find the
ratings and review section type in a
little review let me know what you think
about the show and then give me a star
review or a star rating so far everybody
has given me a five star review let me
know what you think give me what you
feel like I deserve also I would
appreciate it if you follow me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart a podcast I would love it if
you follow me on twitter at g f YH
podcast and if you've got something to
say and you don't want to find me on
social media I invite you to email me
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
once again don't forget about patreon
patreon.com / grow from your heart I
would appreciate your support also I
want to thank everybody for listening I
love each and every one of my listeners
my followers my Frant my fans you guys
are all my friends if you see me out
somewhere don't be shy stop me shake my
hand tell me what you think I like
making new friends I'm
as shy as you are I'm just a normal dude
say what's up you never know I may have
a damn I may have a sticker I may have a
[ __ ] seed back on me
say hi don't be shy don't email me later
and be like hey bro I saw you at this
event I didn't want to say hi dude just
[ __ ] walk up and say hello
fist bump me I'm cool the people with me
are cool you might change both of our
day you never know I want to meet you
you want to meet me let's hang out to be
friends take some dabs all right you
guys I feel like I'm really rambley
after the dads I took and all the dr.
pepper I drank so it's time to wrap up
this show I want to give you a huge
shout out to my friend Brett also known
as Mary's motivation on instagram and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
Magnus
by
[Music]
[Applause]