what's a podcast world it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode of
the girl from your heart podcast this
time I'm putting out episodes 49 50 and
51 of the girl from your heart podcast
let me make a couple of disclaimers
before we get to the show if I said any
advertising if I had any contest going
on anything like that that's all expired
doesn't count anymore don't get too
excited also all the social media needs
to be updated on Twitter its @g fyh
podcast on Facebook it's the girl from
your heart a podcast and if you'd like
to send me an email it's a girl from
your heart at hotmail.com of course I
would love to hear from you all right
let me keep this file nice and short
ladies and gentlemen here's 49 50 and 51
of the girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
you know what's up cannabis community
it's time for another episode of The
Grove from your heart podcast welcome to
episode number 49 oh I apologize in
advance I can already tell that my voice
sounds all terrible gives I've got a
cold but as a professional podcaster
this show must go on so I'm gonna skip
that long intro that I do and we're
gonna introduce everybody that's here to
my left we got Adam what's up brother yo
what's up man to the left of him is
white Mike how you guys doing over here
is everybody how you doing pretty good
actually messaged me today they were
like podcast around seven-30 long
Christmas season podcast yeah I want to
apologize I could tell that I'm gonna
sound stuffy there may be a pod for me
to take care of this I got a broken pipe
in my brain and my nose is just dripping
dude oh my god from the mystic roots man
for let me play their music on the show
that's awesome thanks guys we allowed to
talk about that yeah look dude all of
them look like they have just been
through the freakin wringer yeah I run
I'm pretty hurt couple weeks with a good
couple weeks yeah so jesse is apparently
the boss yeah I'm a full-blown
consultant let me tell you what I'll do
anything you need to get your place
accidentally start a construction
company build your grow out and then
he'll supply it with grow supplies and
then him and I will teach you how to
grow and then we've got a grow team on
hand if you need employees will show you
genetics with oil producers [ __ ]
found his niche for a while now and we
for sure founded how long you been here
now bro it'll be fill in pretty quickly
yeah I'm happy here man I was thinking
about that today Colorado has changed me
for the better you know I used to be a
hermit and stuff like that and just
getting out you know we all fell today
you know you know the other podcast just
[Music]
to ramble and you know I felt an
evolution in myself because if my voice
changed I honestly just stuck a wad of
toilet paper in my nose to keep my nose
from freakin running because it's that's
why it's not puberty it was me on the
mic by myself it felt like I was reading
it like this podcast is brought to you
by nature's green remedies calm is what
it felt like I flipped the papers over
that I had on the desk and just started
talking this is what I want to say and
it's fun it's fun kind of it was I did
too much at the beginning know how to
put nobody cared about me like I didn't
want to come this is me and my podcast I
feel like I made friends with all my
listeners if you're sure
kind of care yeah so we're saying that
Adams found his wheelhouse this kid's a
framer he swings a hammer and frames
like a champ
kinda who would have known
[Music]
I have problems you know a lot of these
people kind of understand those problems
so you know we're you know seems to
rotate we're doing construction and
unheated sometimes poorly or unlit
warehouses I mean tempers can flare
quickly but Lord we've got the team
pretty chilled out in like okay go take
your 20
show yourself outbreak is nice we've
learned to just swing it correctly no
tools go flying at each other don't do
construction I'd rather just be a lone
wolf growing so I kind of sometimes I'm
like man these guys are having fun all
day I want to go to work somewhere with
them and then I'm like I'm gonna get
some money set up before I can it's
Tuesday night as we record actually have
another meeting tomorrow in the morning
at the spot so things are starting to
definitely come together I was in there
checking out the grow a few days ago
it's kind of a mess they're getting a
lot of [ __ ] done the floors the walls
and the ceiling are all the same
material and it looks like one sheet of
everything I can't find the seams in
this material and these rooms are bigger
than my house I'll be growing in there
but I'm going tomorrow there's actually
talking about sending me to there's a
company that built our grow they're
talking about sending me to their
flagship grow so let me go check it out
and see what happens and learn from
there grow a little bit that'll be neat
it's yeah it's cool I think it's by I
don't want to say the wrong name I'm
pretty sure no I was told that I was
wrong about who made that there there
was a company that made it and then
another guy kind of he was part of that
company he separated from them and
proved on it and sold them the
impression ideas yeah you see it no
scenic it built
oh yeah is also different you know
perspective they like to you know we're
not lights or anything like that but
just you know preparation for that yeah
yeah they're gonna hire like a grouse
specific company to come in there do
that are you guys doing it all the way
to the end we're gonna do it nice with
the advice from you know I have reps
phone numbers in my you know there you
go HVAC guys yeah yeah well we're having
a HVAC company come in and put in
specific units specifically set up so if
you're building a personal drone get a
real electrician just haven't been spend
everything there's so many electricians
on Craigslist Craigslist and [ __ ] that
are there legit they're not gonna snitch
on you for going herb if you're in
Colorado get an electrician don't be
that [ __ ] that burned down your house
by trying to grow too many lights in one
room there was a story in the paper
today some idiot brewing hooch blew his
house I saw the photo and explosion in
Pueblo County oh I don't want to give
them the idea but I strongly suspect
they were making pho in there I don't I
don't see how alcohol would have
prohibition with this why you can't make
I don't know about here I know a couple
guys from my house
[Music]
all right [ __ ] to blow some [ __ ] up
guys if you're making I've got a news
article that we're actually gonna read a
little later about making pho let's see
I want to do an ad really quickly just
because we've got to sneak these in this
podcast is brought to you by nature's
green remedies dot-com check out
nature's green remedies calm for all
your favorite seed readers people I
trust people I respect they're on there
and go buy stuff he's good code what is
it frosty no it's I read 2015 I read two
zero one five for 15% off any order and
free prior to shipping in nature's green
remedies calm that coupon code is good
through the month of January once again
the coupon code is Irie I RIE
two zero one five go check them out Tom
Rasta Jeff sent you Jesse's here so
let's kiss his ass a little bit this
podcast is brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies everybody loves
hydro indoor garlic supplies there's two
locations to serve Pablo or deserve
Colorado visit the better store at 62 71
beach street or check out the pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street and
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies
hydro is running a special for the
podcast listeners when you check out
hydro Tom you listen to the growth from
your heart podcast and they will give
you commercial pricing on your entire
purchase just by saying that you're
gonna pay the same exact price that I
pay that's pretty cool yep I wrote all
these ads it works that's great people
are local people are listening to the
show people from other states are
calling the store in place in orders -
we got a girl Kashi in two days ago
Brokaw she need to go to hydro for a
couple of things in the near future
maybe I'll pick up a bag we'll talk
about it on the show a little bit
speaking of Gro Kashi
I'm gonna kind of branch off here I saw
a box of prizes being donated to the
show from high-growth webelo yeah there
might be some crow Kashi there might be
some OGT another doji t's not gonna be
I'm gonna Jack
there's there's there's actually a bag
to grow kocchi there's some OGT and
there are some other nutrients in there
there's some really cool things in there
grab bagger swag bags yeah our good
friend task rocks and does a
highly-educated t-shirt in size large
there are a couple few ira genetics
t-shirts there are a couple of hat pins
in there there's an irish sticker pack
nice yeah from the garden of Weeden may
possibly have some prizes for us I know
there's a couple of garden of Weeden
stickers cuz I've got those I'm hoping
to get a shirt from him but the man is
busy episode 50 I'm hoping to have all
three of these guys back plus Maddie and
Spence which means it's gonna be crowded
as I'm looking at the table I felt like
crap today I didn't prepare and I just
wanted to have these guys over we're
gonna kind of [ __ ] and read a news
article before I do that researcher calm
this episode is brought to you in part
by tree huggers calm live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree hugger
calm for concert in festival news and
reviews WWWE I'm also supposed to say
that if you're interested in sponsoring
the show send me an email it girl from
your heart at hotmail.com and I'll get
you all the info that you need about
that I think that's all the show opening
important part I'm supposed to make sure
I cover a whole bunch of times
this articles from the cannabis you know
what's cool about the cannabis when I
open up the cannabis thwack right on the
top there is an an advertisement for the
spot so then Colorado's largest
dispensary no long waits friendly bud
tenders and new strains weekly visit us
today at the spot the spot did not pay
for that ad but uh I endorsed the spot
there's a cute little button derp with
dreadlocks over there go visit her say
what's up she'll tell you something
curbs
yeah visit the spot so the cannabis this
article is by Ricardo Baca the headline
is that weed infused sex lube for ladies
it'll be on Colorado shelves this month
that's what I said everybody in the room
just looked at me like some satires over
the last yeah yeah it's been in Cali for
a while I think it has I think the same
product so says remember when wow we
first wrote about THC infused sex lube
Floria and it's quite sink quite
singular user instructions in June 2014
I remember it says apply four to eight
sprays directly on to the clitoris so
it's not by yourself
this chicks on the couch or you do four
and wait and see if you feel anything
dude three or four more later I'm all
for the product just the number of Los
angeles-based forea founder Mathew
Gerson helps introduce the unique
product to the masses and now Gerson who
originally hails from Boulder is
debuting his special non-psychoactive
loop outside of California for the very
first time Floria will make its Colorado
debut at the native roots location in
Aspen during the winter x-games on
January 21st through 25th that's confuse
sex with the ex totally just heard all
those words in the creek I don't know if
I want to cross the line of words I want
to say on this show
[ __ ] got all beat up at the x-games
[Music]
okay from Colorado and I've been trying
to get back ever since Gerson told the
Canada super excited to be bringing it
to Colorado and native roots is a good
alignment for us so it'll be available
at native roots on what Floria is per
Gerson for my June interview with him
it's a sensual enhancement oil designed
for female pleasure a therapeutic
aphrodisiac women have described it as
relaxing and they've said it's
heightened to their sensations
they've associated it with warming and
tingling localized in the sexual region
well that's where you're spraying it
you're gonna feel it on your arm for
native roots native roots his new Aspen
location at 308 South Hunter Street
throughout the x-games and all other
native roots locations after the big
event native roots is floria's partner
in colorado and how have the last six
months been for Floria in california a
says we never could have imagined the
impact it's having on the patient
community in California and how it
spanned the spectrum of users from
younger women who are looking to deepen
looking to deepen the level of intimacy
of their own bodies to older women who
are experiencing a reawakening of their
own sexuality Gerson said there are a
large number of women who could benefit
from cannabis but who are interested in
the psychoactive component the products
expansion into Colorado is only the
beginning
Persson estimates Floria will be
available in Washington state pot stores
in the next few months I know a guy that
claims he made a lube using coconut oil
and cannabis and he says when he uses it
on chicks that they definitely enjoy it
a lot more than when he doesn't use it
I just wanted I thought it'd be fun to
read this with four dudes at the table
an abyss a lot more when I use it right
then when I don't use it the article is
awesome it's just [ __ ] I've heard of
puns and shoot a lot of placebo warnings
about this you know whereas she's
spraying it on her [ __ ] in outer labia
it's working it's already moisten and
[ __ ] up and that's waking it up a little
so even if it doesn't work but have you
ever eaten like tincture or I guess who
just teams for the desert you get warm
inside like you feel warm and fuzzy I
can just imagine spending some tincture
on my junk though let me get all sticky
and gross that's what I felt that night
from that uh mountain bar you know
that's that's the whole feeling
[Music]
definitely does work that apotheca I was
skeptical about it because I'm a pothead
if you smoke weed or consume cannabis
somehow to get high right but my
girlfriend actually the granny Gatsby
gave me a bottle of that Apothic Hannah
and I rub my girlfriend down with it for
like an hour and a half one night and my
to quote Pink Floyd my hands felt just
like two balloons they felt I feel like
that Mickey Mouse gloves on I was like
well my hands are big like fluffy and
bigger than they were
yeah I'd go to like scratch my face and
punch myself in the head a little bit
because my fingers were
it's like a boxing gloves on my mom used
that and she said she got high as [ __ ]
from it she I don't know about getting
higher [ __ ] from it but I definitely
felt my mom's a very small it definitely
helps I start off the massage with just
coconut oil to kind of start a massage
you get to loosen up and get her I use
that app off the counter right away it
absorbs in too quickly and I don't think
it spreads enough so I get her coconut
oil and then I put the Apothecary in
there definitely I can tell it she can I
can see that she loosens up as soon as
that apothecary starts getting in there
so I have to use that word there's
nothing else to do but sometimes you
gotta take that job you say words that
you're trying to avoid a lot of people
don't like the word moist I've noticed
moist moist moist let go properly all
right this is written by John Engel and
Jordan Stefan from the Denver Post the
headline is hash oil legality now
question for Colorado courts and then
the sub headline is by the end of
Wednesday hearing Denver District Court
Judge a Bruce Jones had concluded both
sides were wrong though it was still
unclear how he would ultimately rule
side note students name is a Bruce Jones
bad [ __ ] if your first name is
just an initial graphical error let let
me be call her led to me being called B
for like that's frustrating
yeah this dude chose to do it he's a
Bruce Jones you chose to do it his
parents just tagged so I guess if I
wanted to be a poet or something my
middle name is Scott so I beat Jay Scott
and then my last name I almost said in
the show by hanging
[Music]
just like as like five and I mean you
know you know in the corner but we got
in the car and I'm sitting there and I'm
like you know yeah that doesn't work so
I trying it's shattering everywhere and
I'm spilling it I probably lost half a
gram that way and I was like you know
what I'll do I'll pick it up I'll hold
the torch and I'll just you know laughed
it and I'll use my thumb is like a guard
to protect the heat and that worked fine
that was great we were attempting to
blowtorch is a hash lightly the kind of
melted aluminum or horribly in between
two pieces of parchment paper all right
this is some high-quality concentrate
see stuff yeah and this is Colorado
[Music]
around you know town and stuff so I
[ __ ] it up I was like this is working
I'll just set it down and do the same
thing listen to me people don't do that
yeah I burned a bunch of money that day
for nothing they just went up in flame
it was way too late by that part you
know like yeah it's like a match book I
felt bad for you know nobody else did
they all laughed I learned something
so I laughed later I was done with no
because that was an expensive [ __ ]
damn I've got some unicorn Hashem's I
actually dabbed up all my unicorn hash
last night container for Friday's I
forget what we saw the day but we saw a
unicorn I it was it was just rarity it
was on the way to work I can't I don't
remember what it was now I'll ask in the
morning what we saw of it was definitely
unicorn status [ __ ] it was no rare you
know that's that's weird my third dab of
the day when it's 9:15 usually I start
off the day with a couple of fat dad
anything about how I felt today been
trying to get hydrated dude it's so hard
to get hydrated once you're dehydrated
don't drink that pick up the rig thanks
for being a friend that would have been
miserable there's probably like a good
gram of reclaim just floating on top of
that [ __ ] the worst drink ever
anybody out there would definitely pay
money to just like scrape your your
pipes you know and your reclaim their
yeah I was on tiny chat last night and
they showed somebody my hash no and he's
like is that your dad and I was like no
he goes just dab it and so I weighed it
and it was 0.5 I was like well okay and
so I typed it's 0.5 and he just nodded
like uh-huh
then I was like God knows me and so I
did a half gram dad last night on tiny
chat it was fun yeah sometimes I am on
bonk TV life guys that is me if you
wondered my favorite cruising through
bong TV live and you see that white guy
with the dreadlocks and a fiery shirt
I've always got my sunglasses and a hat
on taking dad's that's me bruh that is
me I'm Ross to Jeff on there say what's
up if you want to great somebody talk
will I take a DAB we were talking
earlier today that 50 is gonna be
jam-packed full of chaos and that's good
great I'm so pumped for 50 like to give
away and all that stuff I'm sure
everybody's pumped for but I'm just
pumped to get everybody it's already
been 50 episodes man like I was just
talking about that with him today like
when you really keep track of them and
put a number to them it hurts you
realize how far it goes it goes so
quickly every week I do an episode I've
done a couple of episodes weeks where
I've done multiple episodes too but I
feel like I bore the people I don't have
enough content it's just me rambling
when I do two episodes it's kind of a
big dad for you bro Mike we need to get
you some of that Floria after this all
right thank you for the crowd I like all
these people gatherings it's usually two
people you enjoy and thirteen people
they like cellar eight and if if the
guest list for 50 shows up and
everyone's here it's gonna be sick
well they set the date so hopefully yeah
spits and Maddie were the ones that said
when we're doing this what the hell is
that okay
I heard that noise there's a light
coating of drywall and above your head
all day the new girl at the spa there's
no like carryin their carts I got one of
those for all my [ __ ] like just push it
around my mom's and now I've got yeah
that's my carrying over to the bathtub
and just rinse them out a little bit
coming out of the carp cap honestly I
probably is the carb cap dirty you think
dirt yeah a cleaner monkey that just
walks around behind me and cleans up
after me all day let me tell you people
if you think you smoked a lot of dabs
like there are present I mean there's
[ __ ] reclaim coming off then a torch
here
[Music]
yeah I had someone ask before the
reclaim in my work rig the other day and
you know it's pretty substantial that's
just a cheap little break and as long as
I can suck through it it's cool but yeah
I'd never even consider was like I'm
just like mix that [ __ ] was [ __ ] with
the 420 formula for 20 or whatever all
right all this BHO talk leads me right
into this news article that i was
attempting to read so that's perfect
you're gonna hear a couple of weird
breasts for me I can feel my nose trying
to run to determine the legal status of
marijuana hash oil in post legislation
Colorado resulted in the judge turning
up his hands and shrugging his shoulders
in exasperation Mike's pulling out his
phone to take a picture of me because I
got this big wad of toilet paper stuffed
in my nose while I'm doing a podcast for
district court was to decide whether a
man named Paul man EOD man eonni
many-many if this guy Paul who was one
of the three people charged after an
explosion at a Southwest Denver
warehouse can be prosecuted for the
crime of manufacturing marijuana
concentrate the man's attorney Rob Corey
who helped write Colorado's marijuana
legalization law said Manny Oni can't be
charged because of Colorado's
Constitution now protects the personal
possession of marijuana and the
processing of marijuana plants the court
system is not to be used for marijuana
regulation anymore Corey said I wish you
would have said cannabis it would have
made it a lot better
the Colorado Attorney General argues
Manny Oni can be charged because by
virtue of a curiously placed comma in
amendment 64 the legalization measure
the protection for marijuana does not
cover cannabis oil like hash oil
now the measure says its definition for
marijuana does not include industrial
nor does it include fiber produced from
the stocks oil or a cake made from the
seeds of the plant the Attorney
General's Office which weighed in on
Manny oneis case even though it is not
prosecuting the case has made a similar
argument in a case in Mesa County by the
end of Wednesday's hearing Denver
District Judge a Bruce Jones it
concluded both sides were wrong though
it was still unclear how he would
ultimately rule Jones said he plans to
deny Corey's motion to drop the charge
meaning the case against Manny Oni can
proceed and here's kind of getting into
the part where it's all technical hash
oil is a potent goop left over after
marijuana's active chemicals are
dissolved from the underlying plant
material I tried real hard
II tried hard everyone involved in this
story in this article is it best trying
the cannabis often tries really hard but
they need somebody they need a guy like
you Mike except the wording hash Ville
is the potent goop leftover oil in the
pill is about hemp seed oil if you take
have a seed and you gather it up and you
press it sort of like you do grapes to
make wine you get in oil that you can
make everything you can make with oil
oil like Texans haul out of the ground
oil and that's what they're referencing
in that part of the bill hash oil isn't
oil oil or cannabis oil we just call it
oil because it kind of looks like honey
oil when it comes descriptive slang term
the judge isn't gonna drop the case
because I'm pretty sure this [ __ ] out
blow up this house yeah there's more to
the story let me read part
blowing up your house is long been a
crime in Colorado that something Rob
quarry mentions and I'm gonna have an
argument later on in the story no I like
it I like forward-thinking people it's
awesome we don't have to sit in the
backseat of our minds and [ __ ] let
everybody else drive us think forward so
hash oil they describe it wrong and this
is a popular amateur production method
uses compressed butane gas which can
lead to dangerous explosions like the
one that rocked the 1200 block of South
lemon Street last April mani Oni is also
charged with arson in connection with
that blast during Wednesday's hearing
Cory argued that home hash oil
explosions our mistakes but not illegal
I compare it to frying a turkey Cory
said accidents don't mean a crime has
occurred Jones didn't seem impressed
calling some of Cory's arguments
circular but Jones also criticized an
Attorney General's position I'm going to
tell him he's wrong I'm going to tell
him he's way wrong Jones said so he
compared it to if I'm cooking a chicken
and I burn the apartment building down
or a turkey then I made a mistake but I
think I'm still recklessly endangering
people and I think charges are gonna be
pressed on me even if I do burn down my
apartment building right if you're
frying a turkey in the living room of
your apartment you're cooking dinner in
the kitchen and I'm just cooking normal
food I got veggie burgers and some
[ __ ] vegetables and some rice and
some macaroni or whatever and I [ __ ]
I take a DAB and I come back in the
kitchens on fire Boosh
am I gonna mi gonna face charges for
something now no as long as you were
just it was innocent you might you might
be legally liable for life damages okay
I don't know it depends a lot of that
depends on where you are at the time and
Mike's not a lawyer he just stayed at a
Holiday Inn Express last night that part
of Cory's are giving
but the part does that doesn't apply to
butane hash oil it's your venting cans
of flammable gas into an enclosed space
which is actually an OSHA crime I think
thing in the fire code for sure when now
when I asked the fire chief down here
because pueblos outlawed the making of
BHO a while ago and when the vote passed
I right after the pad passed I stood up
and walked back to the fire chief it
jokingly asked venting cans of butane
into your living room and lighting a
match has been illegal for how long and
he chuckled and went longer than I've
been on the job because that's a thing
you can't don't gasoline around your
apartment and light a match and if
you're venting cans of butane inside
your venting gas on your article almost
on the sidelines was the Denver District
Attorney's Office which is actually
prosecuting the case a deputy district
attorney said the hash oil qualifies as
pot but he said there's a difference
between amendment 64's protection for
processing marijuana and the state laws
for criminalizing of manufacturing
concentrated marijuana Jones is expected
to issue is ruling in the coming weeks
so they're saying that there's a major
difference between processing which is
properly doing that [ __ ] in a facility
in a tested authorized emedia proved lab
that's also been state regulated by the
Health Department and like there's like
seven different agencies that want to
come in and inspect your [ __ ] if you're
growing and making concentrates and then
manufacturing concentrated marijuana he
was doing that at his house open
blasting so that I think that's where
the or the change happens yeah so I
guess the point is don't [ __ ] blast
in doors don't open blast if you're
gonna blast get a closed loop and you
can still [ __ ] up do that safely
there's
to be a news story about someone hurting
themselves making pho outside those news
stories don't happen because people
don't get hurt that way that's kind of a
good point just taking your backyard
numbnuts
everyone I know that's never blown
themselves up my extracts outdoors it's
pretty much I knew that already but
they're like you always do this outside
was the first thing step one check the
weather I don't think there's any other
news that we should talk about someone
blew up a house with alcohol here in
Pueblo the other day that's funny this
is one of the largest alcohol we were on
one of the routes for the Prohibition
this was a huge prohibition town we have
tunnels under this town where people
used to move alcohol from private houses
where it was made to clubs downstairs
death why is it scares you bro my kids
are gonna grow up here my kids are while
they're gonna find that [ __ ] I lived in
a house in an area I don't even know if
I should talk about this oh there's a
part of town called go hill many years
ago I don't remember the exact year so I
don't want to be wrong and try to see I
have an idea in my head but many years
ago this town flooded up to like the
third storey window of a lot of
buildings downtown 1916 I think it could
have been all agree with you a long time
ago when the pictures were yellow 44
that's about it could've been so but
this town flooded there's a hill near it
used to be First Street now it's [ __ ]
Center Center City Drive or some city
center drive that's so dumb it's first
Street [ __ ] why'd you change that so
right up there there was a hill and it
was called go hill and that's where
allegedly all of the Italians that lived
here went and moved to that top of the
hill and took all their lives
there they had goats up there and that
part of town became known as goat hill
in my house I had a hatch that lifted up
in my bedroom like and he could lift up
that and you'd end up in a hidden
basement part and then there was
definitely a hole that had been bricked
over and I'm pretty sure that that hole
was part of those tunnels and then I was
in a band that did a show at the Damon
Runyon theater downtown which used to be
the chief and if you go to one of the
little back areas by the kitchen there's
a tunnel that's blocked off and the
security guard wouldn't let me go past
that area because I was just in the
opening band and he's like you can't go
back here unless I come in the band he's
like oh you can't go back here it's like
all right I tried so those tunnels used
to be used I bet that tunnel on the
tunnel I found connect somewhere somehow
probably this and the hooch was made at
the top of the hill up on go hill and
then it was ran and money probably like
if you want to know why Pablo has people
in it you can watch the two
documentaries on Netflix one of them's
Prohibition and the other ones the great
Dust Bowl Ken Burns is amazing Ken Burns
is the [ __ ] if you watch both of those
perfect there's a lot of stuff here
where people that move here like what's
with that it's you know a question they
ask a bunch of their first year and the
answer is either prohibition or the Dust
Bowl yeah this is old school this was a
stop on the Santa Fe Trail this was used
to be called little Chicago relax
rehearse meet here go on all different
directions between here in the counties
two major highways meet here now you
know a lot of weird [ __ ] here highway 50
go to east and west all the way across
the country and i-25 goes north and
south almost all the way around I think
yeah so I don't know might stop
somewhere
what even got us on that weird grant
[Music]
shut up to the garden thanks for coming
over and making me snap out of my funk
I've been moping around all day I did
get a little bit of work done I put uh
I've been talking about the black cherry
Kim phyno hunt that I'm doing I don't
know how much you've talked about it on
the show I sprouted I spent 40 seeds and
35 of them made it to the flour room
which is actually pretty impressive when
that many of them making all the way to
flour that means that there were five
like maybe I don't I don't remember
exactly but some didn't germinate some
were runts and then some I just didn't
feel like if they were worth the space
so 35 of them made it to flour today I
moved 11 of them into another room
because they are males my goal is to
find a purple male and a green male
hopefully the light went off I gotta go
check that it's supposed to go off at
9:00 they're in a new room that got
started tonight we'll see how that works
yeah hopefully I find a purple male on a
green male and hopefully I find a purple
female and a green female and I'm going
to kinda collect pollen and sort of cube
things and see if I can't make f two's
that come out consistently purple and I
want to work them to f5 honestly it
sounds ridiculous but I want to work
into f5 to where they're purple clones
of each other when they could have a
problem we're having with that one I
want the same thing so happens I can't I
can't get it back that's what I want
dude strong [ __ ] I'm not sure what any
of that meant but that's why we bring
out I know that's why I just ran right
nobody else did either they're all
brought to you by force now we're
working together and he turns around and
glares at me thirty seconds later he
turns around and glares again way across
the room perfectly into the trash can
yeah I do
I don't resemble the practice break this
is a three-pointer for sure you are yeah
there's no filter no it's fun there's no
filter it's fun the tape measure and a
stack of aluminum framing studs and just
let him go to work yeah there's like
more than five ingredients on something
[Music]
Jota Mac eco and you're not getting
hammered like we forget he's not from
[Music]
McDonald's and all that we haven't you
know we get subway every night just
because it's right there but you know
can I have a little GMO in your life
else oh I guarantee the the food at the
Mexican places they weren't eighty cents
I'm gonna tell you much right now they
were
speak English
[Music]
we'll see there's different kinds of
Mexican food racism there's three tops
on that street like Pueblo style Mexican
which is like Taco Casa and taco stop
man for burritos biddies and that's
where you get green chili and stuff like
that then you got like the actual
Mexicano my street tacos street tacos
yeah em and if you tell them you want
green chili you get green chiles diced
[Music]
yeah when I worked at our Center there
was a little lady that used to come in
all the time
those guys would buy the burritos in
about 30 minutes later then I'll have to
go take a fat dump you couldn't find the
there's one chick and her son every time
I see her I'm like I've been buying them
since I work construction 12 years ago
yeah what do you go they always have a
little fried stuff yeah I'll tell you
later
actually kind of old the Nana looks love
is they're taking the [ __ ] oh man oh man
a lot of cool prizes on episode 50 I'm
excited about that I'm hoping I was just
listening to the banter that was
happening on the show with four of us
and with six people out
it's gonna be a mess I really got to
come up with some contest if you guys
got any our deals some contests yeah way
to give away all the cool prizes that
we've got I think we've got a couple of
cool ideas we're gonna number the prize
packs so that this is like the biggest
one will be number one and we'll work
our way down to the smaller prizes will
be number five and then we'll do some
sort of contest and whoever does better
at the contest will win a place in the
prising maybe we'll let you ask which
for which prize you want so that you're
not you don't want a t-shirt or you want
a t-shirt you win a [ __ ] ballast you
know grow and all you wanted was an
Irish shirt and we send you feed
nutrients to the ornamental plants and
the apartment complex
definitely gonna have to get together
right before the show a little bit talk
about what we're giving away and I'd
never win but if I wasn't you know one
of the dudes that you're not I know but
I'm just saying like I'd never win it
but if I'm telling you now if I was I
try it's good stuff it's gonna have to
be some rules on there's some stuff in
that box that I would fully be like oh
yeah and I'd go home and play like
create new username
[Music]
I'm also doing a lemon Jeffrey cross to
the Grateful dog Fino huh those look
amazing
I've got five of them in there and
there's two of us in the room they just
yeah I got somebody else grow many
projects so many seeds to so many people
yeah guys I was promising more seeds
nature's green remedies up all the seeds
that I made and honestly I'm gonna get
my crew around here seeds before I mail
a lot of [ __ ] out to a distributor it
just seems like growth from the heart is
my my name of my show it's been my motto
for years and I feel like my community
is right here and I don't need to go
sending stuff out to somewhere else it
helps you produce a better product it
does because I get to see clones I get
to go to these people's gardens I get to
see what's happening guys you'll get
seeds from me I promise I'm always
making more we're working on the team
now he's making more I've got breeding
space somewhere else now I promise I'm
always making more just hard to keep up
dude you guys are hungry for the seeds
thank you and I apologize yeah yeah I've
been one seed since I've been here I
just never had money at the time so
which one do you want oh my god the ones
that you're throwing away over there
would be cool getting your mail started
and then if I put three or four or four
or five females in the room with that
mail sometimes they have to go into
flour four or five six or seven eight or
ten days apart from each other to time
up when the females are ovulating to
take that pollen for sure and different
males don't pit different times yeah
honestly what I did I'll admit this I
make my own silver thiosulfate and I
tried a new method and I over applied
and my male plants turned male super
quick quicker than I've ever seen but at
the same time they didn't make any
pollen they made some but not nearly as
much as I had anticipated not what I'm
used to so I got about a quarter amount
of the seeds mistakes a high-level
mistake too so yeah if you're making
that you know times
[Music]
don't spray your hash with the torch
learn if you don't [ __ ] up you don't
learn that's what I think I taught you
that but I [ __ ] up on a big scale like
I was going big and I kind of ruined
some [ __ ] by doing it but we all do a
lot of good those plants that did not
get seated everybody tickets the Denver
cannabis cup is coming I am not endorsed
by high times I'm not paid to say this I
just want to see you guys there I will
not have a booth but I will be cruising
around having fun saying what's up to
people I plan on being there all three
days most likely should we all just rent
a van and a house
house would be cool but yeah
well I've got my tickets maybe in two
people I'd go to a motel with my wife
right yeah I'll help on the couch I
don't care I usually do a pretty good
hotel for those kind of events if I'm
there for three days I want some luxury
you know how we do it somewhere with the
balcony see we can open that balcony
with the door there the sliding glass
door and chill out sucks this sounds
like I'm gonna be working a booth first
one so yeah we'll be able to trade out
for another very interested before the
cannabis coop before the cannabis cup
there's something coming up do I need to
grow a fat crop or something no no no
April oh you tree Cannabis Cup tickets
so that we can all hang out have fun
there don't be a [ __ ] like wristbands
from the vendors the tickets right now
what I bought was a three-day early bird
special for like 85 bucks plus a five
dollar and fifty cent service [ __ ]
stick it in your butt fee it does not
include any concert tickets because I
actually plan on seeing Doug Benson I've
got a ticket to see Doug Benson on 420
at Comedy Works at nine o'clock so I'm
not going to the Snoop Dogg concert and
stuff I know that sounds weak but Doug
Benson is actually a friend of mine and
it's a comedy taping one of my favorite
comedians taping their new comedy
special at my favorite comedy club in
the country even say that I'm sorry the
High Times concerts aren't cool concerts
like it's great like you look outdoors
in April and Colorado and you don't know
take shorts and the parka we saw yeah
exactly
we saw shorts all day cuz at the cup
it's nice you know what I mean you're
rockin shorts and a t-shirt and then you
get in the car and you go eat dinner and
you go to the hotel you got to change
into like pants and long sleeves and a
hoodie and put some chapstick on your
lips cuz we went out to Red Rocks for
Slightly Stoopid
shows you guys we went out to Red Rocks
and it was so windy ghosting Slightly
Stoopid at Red Rocks just not on 4/20
yeah I've never heard anyone say doc
yeah I wouldn't go see them at Red Rocks
anytime anybody seen anybody at Red Rock
oh yeah
January 30th at Red Rocks is Damian
Marley and a couple it's probably
coinciding with each other just to make
money and they make it seem like it's
just a nice casual treacherous yeah
could you imagine all the [ __ ] ice
d-mail true [ __ ] there got to spray all
the concrete surface and the muddy
parking one slip at the top and it all
away
Ari Shaffir Comedy Works I haven't
talked to my buddy about that we've been
kind of he's working nights now and I'm
on this weird random podcast life
schedule so I might be going to that
what's up bro if you're listening to
this message me will see a file we're
doing that we'll see if there's room for
one more in the car or whatever if not
that's cool I didn't I didn't have
anything going on at the time but yeah
for sure I would I'm just told him the
other day that he should come with us
tonight Benson but he's like don't know
you know it's cool he's got his wife
there you know spending the weekend and
[ __ ]
that would be cool but uh now she can
she'd stay at home with the kids I'm
talking my wife not yours my wife my
wife totally lost my train of thought
with that earlier I was trying to talk
to somebody I was like just it stopped
it's like I'm sorry I had to say good
yeah yeah got any plugs to do any
shoutouts or anything I haven't been
present on the job site for a few days
for some family reasons yeah baby
laying it for me and taking care of
business family things for sure yeah all
those [ __ ] there Maddie's Maddie's been
killing it at the at the store for us
filling in there - good day thank you
very much Maddie this also killing it's
like slaying it try not to sneeze wreck
the show closing I made it almost all
the way through the show and I'm getting
that watery eye thing like I'm about to
sneeze I wanna give a shout out to my
girl Angela What's Up babe want to give
a shout out to the spot dispensary all
the sponsors that have sponsored the
show and tasks and the mystical roots
task rock and the mystical roots bands
separately that's not in the show's over
please go to iTunes or stitcher go to
the iTunes Store or this deter main page
and search for agriculture slash girl
from your heart find the review section
give us a five star rating after that
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on an upcoming show maybe I'll
even read your comment on episode number
50 you never know don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes stitcher in
every episode of the archived on I read
genetics Colorado com make sure you
follow us on Twitter and Facebook just
search for grow from your heart please
follow I read genetics on Instagram I
post so many sweet sweet cannabis
pictures on there you got to check that
out [ __ ] don't forget we're in the
process of changing the name it was
I'm trying to work on making it grow
from your heart
I need the logo somebody's I haven't
heard from them free time and he said I
talk to you about this you just built a
picture in my head you gotta make do
all right don't lose us it's a
transition that will happen slowly
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like me to
review send me an email and grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and I will get
you all the info you need I wanna give
you huge shout out to these boys for
showing up today making a great podcast
we do any preparations and we sleep this
show bro lady awesome rawr we've crushed
it we totally like nerd it up and she
has happened some snowboarder talk
little bit I guess so wicked gnarly brah
hit some pow pow we're gonna end this
before this gets out of control I want
to give a big shout-out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening until
next time take fat dad
[Music]
Yeah right as the show starts I look
over and Spencers just giggling number
50 of the girl from your heart podcast
your source for cannabis news education
and conversation dude I'm excited I
can't even talk I'm so excited everybody
made it on time everybody is here
welcome to episode number 50 guys we're
just gonna introduce everybody to the
last we got we're gonna attempt to share
the mic I think that every time it's
Maddie's turn to talk she's gonna get
punched in the head with microphone but
it's really cute the way it's happening
it's not it's not violent it's cute over
here to my right at the three o'clock
position we got mr. Adam Gaskins how you
doing bro what's up man number 44 in the
house absolutely number 50 men 50 thanks
for coming everybody made it I'm excited
[Music]
so everybody brought everybody
Jesse brought some great prizes from
hydro indoor growing supplies who's
gonna do this weird we're gonna do it
just like this we'll jump and do
speaking of hydro indoor growing
supplies this podcast is brought to you
by hydro indoor growing supplies super
huge shout out to hydro they have two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store 62 71 Beach Street or of
course our favorite though I can't even
speak today our favorite Pueblo location
at 618 East 4th Street in Pueblo
Colorado don't forget if you're
listening to the Grove from your heart
podcast all you have to do is tell them
you listen to the show and you will get
commercial pricing when you check out at
hydro
dude support them if you listen to the
show you will hear about some kickass
prizes they brought today it took two
men two boxes of [ __ ] to carry it into
the house and then I added more to it
when they got here so huge shout out
Jesse thanks a lot bro for sure I tried
to save that for the show so thank you
miss really cool of you
[Music]
listen do you remember their name I
don't remember his name but I will see
you at the store they'll go buy a bunch
of [ __ ] thank you to the mystic roots
band filete muse their music on the show
thanks to Kat ku and the entire mystic
roots crew the stay positive productions
crew that's really awesome they let me
use their song on the show I appreciate
that that was the most important paper I
had to get through Mike wrote up a
really interesting topic we were gonna
do some giveaways and [ __ ] but I got a
couple things to talk about before we
get into they're my crowd up a really
interesting topic I saw it you guys
might have seen this this morning
Ralphie may came to Colorado right
before a performance apparently the
police had to be called to quiet there
of the pissed crowd when Ralphie was way
to zonked to even finish his sentence he
should video of Ralphie May being
escorted out of the back of the comedy
club by the police because the crowd was
so pissed off at him they were demanding
their money back and he was just smiling
and like I love you guys I don't know
what happened you wouldn't let me do my
bits and he was waving like he was a
princess or some [ __ ]
it was really [ __ ] funny
hyah [ __ ] before and I've never seen
Ralphie made that high he talked about
doing a lot of drugs you gotta read the
labels people read the label you know
it's Ralphie May he probably ate
something too went down this is
delicious and just started eating all of
them probably 5,000 milligrams a [ __ ]
for me Alfie made this episode won't be
out for like two weeks so that'll be old
news by then but we read it today we
thought it was freaking hilarious
Ralphie May you're the new Maury no
doubt I hope you work that into your
next bit I hope that's funny at some
point that's good yeah tonight it'll be
too late but the new re shoot for your
comedy special is on at midnight tonight
to catch that yeah paid regular with re
one of my favorite comedians last time
we talked about the best [ __ ] of the
year 2014 we left out something super
duper freakin important oh we didn't
even mention live resin oh there's some
[ __ ] to a competition and it's like
[Music]
definitely really came about yeah live
resin did a lot for you of course it is
a lot for emo and giddy did a lot for
Hankey be in the greener side kinda as a
residual it actually your win and the
secret cub boosted up my Instagram
following made me more known so yeah why
present kind of boosted us all up in the
seen a little bit for sure I can't
believe we forgot about live on the here
review episode yeah I can't believe this
was such a big part of the end of our
year especially with the secret cups oh
and it was awesome to win the secret Cup
regionals that was awesome we met a lot
of people in Denver through that yeah
people still talk to me like I'm part of
your crew like do you agree that well
and I'm like I didn't grow it do that's
they grow it they [ __ ] pop the seeds
they shatter it they blasted it's all
fam so I have to correct people a night
I let them know that you drew that I
never take credit for your guys's grow I
didn't grow that snuff you guys it was
them soil to oil yeah actually the stuff
for I may have grown a couple of theirs
but I've taken credit for those so this
is kind of a random note a lady messaged
me on Instagram and kind of called me
out she said that and I'm sure I said
this but I don't remember the exact
words in an older episode I kind of
tried to cover my ass legally with the
disclaimer like if you live in an
illegal state don't grow weed follow the
rules and all that [ __ ] I gotta say that
kind of [ __ ] to cover my ass I don't
know technically if I come on the air
and I say hey if you live in Florida
[ __ ] all the rules girl all the weed you
can I don't know if I'm gonna get in
trouble for that to cover my own ass I
just say follow the follow rules you
guys but I think that you should grow
your own cannabis if you're smoking
cannabis if you're consuming cannabis if
you like it recreationally if you like
it medically grow the [ __ ] out of it
everywhere
that's my new stance on it over grow the
government they can't arrest us all they
might arrest me for saying that but if
they do somebody else make a badass
podcast and keep these going for me and
I mean if you are gonna do it illegally
you know if you do it somewhat
responsibly and you're willing to go to
court for that then so be it I mean you
may be the change that your state or
your
yeah your communities needed to plant
more seeds you guys grow more weed I
can't be a hypocrite I grow a lot of
cannabis I think you should too but also
know the risks if you've got kids in the
house you could lose the kids when they
come in the door think about that kind
of [ __ ] it's gonna be traumatizing it's
gonna [ __ ] up your life if you're
prepared for that if you can handle that
if you're a man and or woman enough if
you're transgender enough I'm not trying
to exclude anybody I'm trying to include
all of you can handle that [ __ ] grow
cannabis do your thing just know what
the risks are there we go I'm not being
a hypocrite
yeah she also called me out for dabbing
in the car and telling people not to I'm
a professional lady I could dab in the
car if you find yourself to be a
professional dab in the car the people I
was talking [ __ ] to we're not profession
I'm a professional card ever it's always
parked in very certain locations where
it's like this is dab approved places
between here and like Boulder Fort
Collins that I know to pull off like I
could pull off right here there's a
little gas station with a car wash I
love to go in the car wash at the gas
station and get my car washed
nobody can see cars covered at all
angles in there damn the Master Shake -
that's a perfect little car rig it's
hard for the car Master Shake is a
little ten mill rig it there's no way to
hold it up in the car there's nowhere to
put it it just falls over when you drive
so this is mostly the hit man take more
than one he Nelson the cars always
driving with the Pelley nail in the car
you see that dude a bit in strip clubs
on an airplane did he really take the
dad or did he just show off the rig I
didn't see the real I might have been
hypocritical but just trying to cover my
own ass is all I'm try not to go to jail
and trying to keep this podcast go and I
can't tell people in [ __ ] Texas to
grow weed not think that I'm gonna get
in trouble but guess what if you're in
Texas grow some [ __ ] weed dude you
wanna put the correct information out
there for ya yeah well she called me out
and I I guess she was right cuz I did
say don't do this and I guess it can't
be a [ __ ] about it I just want a man up
to that one was I gonna go from there do
we want to start this big ole list a
shout out something like eleven minutes
into the show I do have one more thing I
have to do I just look down this podcast
is brought to you by nature's dream
remedies calm check out our friends
nature's drain remedies calm for good
deals on gage green genetics lopata lab
sin city rare dankness mile high Kenna
venture the Cali connection IRA genetics
and a whole bunch more trusted brands
use coupon code re 2015 for 15% off any
order and he always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com I don't
know when that coupon code will end
we'll just keep it going probably all
the way through Valentine's Day so check
those guys also check out tree hugger
comm if you want to read about dude you
guys probably don't care but the
Grateful Dead is playing at Soldier
Field in Chicago with Trey Anastasio on
guitar I'm sure there will be articles
about that on tree sucker coms check out
tree hugger comm live music music
lifestyle magazine yeah sorry for
stumbling through the ads I just want to
get them done I promise I'll do those
for people to do also if you're
interested in sponsoring the show send
me an email from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all that info
that's all the technical stuff for now
we're not gonna do any more that
um alright let's read this big ol list
of shoutouts I'll let you guys go first
if you guys mic if you got anybody you
want to shout out or say anything to
because this is episode 50 it's kind of
time for like a celebration before we
start giving away prizes and [ __ ]
everyone's looking at their phones like
but 50s huge right well thank you guys
for coming all of you guys are Clinton
Sean should be here but there aren't
enough chairs dude if I had two more
chairs Sean and Clint would have been my
next options to have here for when you
keep us updated with our local politics
in the local [ __ ] that we need to be
aware of and I think that they can
participate on that it's not gonna go
the way you want it to and you're
looking at local bands like Colorado
Springs I'm impressed with how friendly
you have become with some City Council
members you'll be hanging out taking
dabs in the phone or ring oh that's this
City Council member excuse me for a
minute and I'm like bro you're in my
house taking dad's listening to reggae
and you're gonna excuse yourself to go
talk to the City Council manager okay
they they they're people too bro like if
you call them they call you back their
job is to keep the constituents happy
and it doesn't matter how often you dad
you're a constituent it's pretty killer
I like that you've developed that
relationship for us because I know it's
not my spot it's it's fully my cross to
bear I can see why it's like my
wheelhouse and honestly I don't see
myself knowing what you know about
growing or knowing what Spence knows
about blast
I know about but that was kind of fun
full-on dad barcia's never Mike but most
you guys probably caught that from the
ecto in the room I had someone ask me to
plan their reception for me
[Music]
all right Maddie just grab the mic from
spin so it looks like she's prepared
you got any shadow shout out to our crew
from NC in Colorado they really stepped
up their game this year and learned how
to grow some killer weed granted they
have some you know good friends to help
them learn but our friends really
stepped up and started growing some
amazing cannabis this year they deserve
a big shout-out for that good genetics
go a long way also I've seen a lot I was
gonna brag on that yeah shoutouts all
those guys cuz a lot of them you guys
have passed on eye region that exceeds
to a lot of that crew and they are
freakin killing it on instagrams
[Music]
genetics it's a great place to get
reliable reliable genetics from well
thank you yeah no problem yeah I wish I
could give unfortunately you guys there
aren't any seeds in the prize packages
because of legal reasons these prizes
are available to almost anybody in the
United States unless you're here at the
table or you're too closely affiliated
with the show by the way I make the
[ __ ] rules they can change any time I
decided I'm sorry we'll make a Colorado
contest where I can put some ira seeds
in there eventually I just got to figure
out how to do that it'll just be a local
thing those guys dude Matty you
something great on a microphone you were
you need to be podcasting all the time
thank you yeah we have a discussion
table every night when we take jabs we
usually just have a session sit down and
talk for an hour - and just [ __ ] and
honestly it could be on a podcast that's
why I've said it before on the show that
your table is part of what inspired this
podcast you guys his friend I won't say
his name he used to come and pick my
brain for two hours at a time at your
table and I thought I should record all
this to write it down and just refer him
to my recordings I wish I could just
bring thoughts back that I have like I
remember something we were talking about
but I don't remember the specifics one
time on an older podcast that I used to
do
December lanai on the blocks on that
podcast we had a recording issue and our
whole recording got lost and we decided
let's just try to redo it and mimic it
about ten minutes in we're like this
feels so fake there's no way to bring
back those thoughts in that conversation
so remaking a talk is and it's not the
most legit thing yeah I just I wasn't
feeling it like it was time to record
and I just wasn't in the mood and now
I'm way more comfortable at it so did 50
episodes in on this show and then I did
about 50 with another show also so then
that's some time to get company yeah
yeah I've only been a host for 50
episodes I feel like you've only been a
host for about 30 episodes to tell you
the truth yeah yeah I'm thinking about
doing more frequent episodes cuz we get
more to listens when they're more
frequent but I don't want to bore people
also I don't want to be that podcast
just appears for three months and then
comes out with the show and then comes
out but I also don't want you to have to
listen to me four times a week like Joe
Rogan because I don't even have time to
hear all the Joe Rogan stuff yeah yeah
alright just grab the mic from Adi he
smacked her with it violently it's when
they do it how about you Spence you got
any shoutouts for the year shoutouts all
the people who breathe seeds and give me
free seeds to grow and the people that
hooking up with California Seattle so
shout out to all the people out there
the past on genetics you know it's kind
of
now it's kind of something that should
be done now is you know kind of share
the genetics for people there's always
gonna be cuts people are gonna hold
that's just how it works
but you could still share at the same
time yeah try not to be a clone hoarder
I know that's hypocritical because I'm a
breeder and I'm kind of a clone hoarder
but everybody's got this couple that if
you got something to tie and CBD or is
really good medicine cuts are one thing
seeds or another yeah yes I think should
be given out that's why you guys are
frustrated with me there's not a lot of
stuff at nature's green remedies calm
it's because all my locals are getting
it there is obviously a markup when you
go through a dealer a distributor and
I'm skipping that markup and getting the
seeds to my locals at wholesale prices
cuz it feels good doing that sorry that
you guys didn't get a lot on nature's
green remedies who get the next the
whole batch will probably go to you
because my locals are served up
everybody's fed yeah and all my friends
like where the seeds and I'm like you
have to go online like everyone else and
it feels rule it was kind of our
Christmas this year yeah yeah we're all
gonna take turns joking circle shoutouts
you concluded what the sharers the
people to share yeah you look your eyes
are is ready
everybody in this room is quite so we
took a little pre preparing session Adam
how about yourself bro you got any
shoutouts passes you brother like you've
I've only been here a year and I mean I
met you quickly man you know like
without you I wouldn't be in the scene
that I'm in Jesse you know he fed my
family brother like straight up Mike
thanks for doing the work man next year
[Music]
next year I got your back I know what
you're capable of brother thank you so
[Music]
everything you guys moved from another
state pick on you bro but I'm proud of
you for quitting that job because that
[ __ ] was treating you like she walks
kids to school every morning and snow
you know she's never dealt with snow at
all so you know props to her everything
that she does yeah that's all the moms
out there shout out to all the moms
what's up mom - mom oh yeah pretty good
all right I've got a big list got a big
list of shoutouts on the cube here dude
thanks all the people that set thanks to
me thanks it makes me blush it makes me
feel honored you can be somebody taught
me that you are the some of the five
people that you surround yourself the
most on purpose five people sitting at
this table is Ben cliff ravenscraft is
where I heard it but somebody else
taught him it might have been my client
it doesn't matter but yeah that's the
five people that you surround yourself
with the most on purpose are who you
become and there are five people sitting
around me that I I'm inspired by all of
you every day just a little bit Mattie's
look at me like you're inspired by me
[Music]
and I completely agree with that same
statement I've never really thought
about it like that before so I was
staring and of course Angela would be if
there was another person to be here to
contribute to who I have been lately
Angela would be I've YouTube madyun
spins were a person I've got a huge huge
freaking list of shoutouts and I want to
give here I'm looking to see how much
time I'm into this episodes I don't want
to take like four minutes doing
shoutouts what I'm yeah right that's
probably the next part here so let's see
I said it first
Angela keeps me smiling and inspired
Maddie dude you're the first woman on
the show that's awesome thank you thanks
for coming again Spence dude you keep me
supplied with the dankest ads I could
ever imagine smoking I smoke a lot of
hash you guys and Spence keeps me going
he's actually in the process of teaching
you how to make my own hopefully
tomorrow we'll get on that again big
shout out to Big Mike what's up bro
you're like family
Michael you like family white Mike sit
next to me family sloppy what's up my
ninja slop dizzle big shout out big
shout out to Phil
silly don't get to hang out enough
Britta kind of quiet but know that I
think about you that you're part of the
crew over here Adam what's up dude he
already know I said what's up Jesse dude
you're quiet in your shot but I love
having you on the show man you're loosen
it up you're becoming a great [ __ ]
podcast guest for sure a hell of a dude
I know that if some [ __ ] goes wrong I
can always call you Jesse can build a
house with his hands superpower can call
a shout out bro Clint shout out super
big shout out to hunt granny gets me in
the turf axe crew seven one nine hugs
big shout out there extra large shout
out to hydro tree thugger nature's green
remedies oil slick big super warmed up
to the perfect temperature shout-out to
highly educated and tasks rock how about
this one a shout out to Robert
Craig Vegas Matt and Matt from the spa
Twitter listeners frivolous Roadrunner
mister Omni o L Roache Oh from Facebook
how about Fred Garvin how about my good
Logo Designer bender what's up buddy
people that let me use their music cat
and COO from the mystic roots bed DJ
nicotine task list muse his music to to
shout out for that the guy that taught
me so much about podcasting and has no
idea that I even have a podcast and it's
never listened to my show will not hear
this shout out but huge shout out to mr.
cliff ravenscraft the podcast Answer Man
Funes are trying to make a podcast do
totally Google the podcast Answer Man
check his [ __ ] out he will teach you so
much if you're looking for some
high-grade no wait if you're looking for
some mid grade cannabis big shout out to
my friend figure lover
[Music]
super dude shoutout to giddy up an emo
tech a shout out to Hank EB and a super
special shout out to my good friend Doug
Benson and also Joey cocoa Diaz
everybody to made it here the show
[Music]
the little Filipino girl in between them
and he's just like oh yeah sweet little
peeps a little Filipino girl who is that
Emily Cooper's Margaret Cho I want to
thank all the listeners from from my
heart I grow from my heart and I thank
you from my heart thanks for listening
to 50 episodes we get like 6000 listens
on a huge episode when Sean comes on we
get 6,000 people to hear this yeah I had
no idea if you knew what my guess was it
was nothing maybe like 1500 that's what
I was thinking but I did I mean I don't
think about the fact that it's the it's
the web I said print ads to nature's
green remedies and so everybody that
bought seeds for like three months got
my ad in the mail with their seeds
around the world as soon as I get the
new logo figured out and everything I
plan on printing up a new logo and
bombing the world with new newsletter I
[Music]
could probably tell you by looking at
the the logistics on my website it tells
me where yeah I can see where
everybody's IP addresses but the problem
is if people cheat on their IP addresses
they can't be looking at certain [ __ ]
where they're from so they got to go in
somewhere else and then come back to
your site yeah but like we're listened
to in like Prague and Russia TV we've
been arguing but it's a friendly
argument shout out the dough trip I
can't list them all I forget people all
of them what's up guys with the
dreadlocks
dread dread 4:20 the other guy I think
that's general dread okay I think I did
with the other dreadlocks yeah all right
so what I was getting at is that I love
all the listeners and to show that
appreciation we've got some killer prize
packages and we want to give them away
we sat around here for a few minutes
trying to think about ways to give them
away so I think this is what we're gonna
do I will post pictures and I'll read
the price packs in a minute but I want
until you first keep you excited I will
post pictures of the prize packages on
Instagram and Facebook the prize
packages there won't be Derby individual
prizes the prices that are on Facebook
or only there on Facebook the prizes
that are on Instagram are only available
on Instagram so the people that are on
different social medias have options to
get in on this
I'll post pictures on whichever sign I'm
posting it on what you have to do is
follow on Instagram you have to follow
where is it you have to follow I read
genetics you have to follow hydro Pueblo
and you have to follow garden of Weeden
on Instagram if you want to be in the
Instagram contest you have to follow
those people then you have to comment on
a photo of the prize package that you
want because I don't want you if you
want a t-shirt don't like comment on the
nutrient packages because there's a
nutrient packages and shoot that I want
those to go to people that are gonna
grow if you want a nutrient package
comment on that if you want a t-shirt
comment on that if you want this sweet a
spinet the Madi and Spence bra comment
on that so that we can give these prizes
to people that want them so comment on
the prize that you want using hashtag
grow from your heart giveaway on
Instagram and then comment on that
picture and tell me why you think you
should win that prize so it's pretty
easy you got three things to do you got
to follow three people you got a comment
using a hashtag using hashtag girl from
your heart giveaway and then you've got
to put in a little message there and
tell me why you think you should win
that specific prize
you can enter once on each picture and
that includes Facebook and Instagram you
can do all of the contests once
don't enter don't leave two comments on
the same picture I'll probably delete
both of your comments at that point I'm
just trying to keep it fair you know I
just don't want a bunch of people
spamming the [ __ ] out of my stuff
the rules yeah yeah I make all the rules
as they're going I'm gonna try to be as
fair as possible but I do have the right
to change the rules if I feel like you
cheated or you're being a douche I can
just [ __ ] block you that's my thing I
hold that heavy banhammer they brought
four killer bags all right let me read
you what's in this bag here's the bit
I'll go from the bottom um the smaller
prizes are from our good friends at
highly-educated titanium there will be
one highly-educated t-shirt it's a size
extra large and there is one I read
genetics sticker pack in there which is
a license plate sticker a regular logo
sticker and an I heart dab sticker so
that's the highly-educated prize pack
there are four I read genetics t-shirts
and sticker packs available right now
and sticker pack on there cuz I didn't
put that part on the start so before I
read genetics t-shirts and sticker packs
available there's a variety of sizes
there are three black and one white I'll
list them all on social media sites
they'll be probably to land on Facebook
to on Instagram will list those up there
so you got four options I'm gonna go
ahead and add there are two hat pins two
IRA happens one for Ag and one for
Facebook and there's a lot of cool ass
prizes now let's go nuts
yeah I'm only shipping the [ __ ] to the
United States you guys in the United
States of America if you win these
prizes and you want to pay for the
shipping and you're in France or
wherever else out of the country you can
pay for the shipping and I'll mail it to
you but it's already gonna be expensive
enough there are for that grand prize
it's gonna be like 40 bucks yeah if it
goes like yeah yeah that's coming out of
my pocket so shout out to I mean
everybody threw down sweet prize
[Music]
what you brought way outshines my
shipping cost garden of Weeden there is
a prize package from the lovely folks at
garden of Weeden there's a t-shirt what
size was it extra large yep extra large
t-shirt there is a sticker a garden of
Weeden sticker and a cool-ass pindy it's
like a honeycomb I think it's a
honeycomb it's made by the real ghost
cat glass artist and it's pretty sweet I
told him that it wasn't making it to the
prize pack and they looked at me like I
was a dick and told me I had to give it
away so those are kind of the smaller
prizes which aren't even that small we
got t-shirts we got t-shirts and sticker
packs we got a ping
we got hat pins so here's where we're
getting fancy there are three of these
available there are it's a big one of
those sweet tote bags like you get at
all the events there's a bunch of heavy
sixteen nutrients like a heavy 16
nutrient packed shadow it's a heavy 16
good [ __ ] you'll grow some heavy herb
with that there's a bottle of plant
catalyst there's a bottle of tap root
there are some stickers and then there's
probably a Humboldt hemp wick and maybe
some random [ __ ] in there just a little
bit of swag in that bag so there are
three of those looks oh yeah a green
flashlight for your grow room the green
light won't love your plants yeah those
have been a favorite around the people
the grand-prize again I got a mention
hydro indoor growing supplies in pueblo
and denver check them out
mention the show you'll get sweet deals
hydro indoor growing supplies has
donated a bag of grow Kashi a bag of OGT
a big bunch of heavy 16 nutrients a big
bottle of plant catalyst a bottle of tap
root there's a wider some stickers
there's a probiotic farmers Alliance
button there's a gauge dream genetics
button there's a Bronco t-shirt with
some other stuff on it
I don't think that Bronco logo is used
with light okay and then there's
probably stickers and there's gonna be
other random stuff in that one that is
our big super number one bonus prize
pack that gro kashi is gonna improve
your grow by a whole bunch that ho GT is
going to improve your growth that will
make you into a damn near great gardener
yeah yeah all you need now is a good
pack of seeds and some soil and a good
light yes crushing it decent good living
soil yeah yeah yeah I I actually got a
sample pack of that heavy 16 and I will
use it on something really soon I've got
so many projects coming up that I've
sorted another perpetual cycle instead
of doing large rooms all at once I've
got a perpetual that gives me more
options to run different notes so I
really like the perpetual better it just
keeps me going yeah keeps me I don't
know seems like I get stagnant when I
just have a long long grow all right so
guys get in on these prized packages
here are the rules again I'm going to
take pictures of every prize package and
I will try to show everything that's in
the package and a nice little pile it's
gonna take me a minute to get all these
up I will post the pictures to Facebook
I will post some of the pictures to
Instagram well you've got to do is go
and follow oh yeah I didn't say he had
to follow on Facebook you have to follow
the girl from your heart podcast you
have to follow hydro indoor growing
supplies and you have to follow the
garden of Weeden on Facebook and then
it's the same thing you have to comment
using hashtag girl from your heart and
you have to tell me why you should win
the prizes so I will post the pictures
on the at I read genetics on Instagram
and the girl from your heart podcast on
Facebook is where you'll find these
pictures right I said that right
everyone I just want everybody to be on
the same page as me so my notes are
really scattered I would imagine all
this information will be in the post for
the shirts folks we made sure to get a
selection so check the folder that
you're looking at don't comment on the
extras
sir when you want the extra large yeah
the extra medium medium tall and skinny
yeah do you look funny english-medium
they'd be like a little mini halter top
on you this is like six for 65 I
remember one time I went to was it big
and tall was just regular tall but no
you got to be like size 42 Greenworks
big shout out to green works they
changed the game this year a little bit
for a few people just shout out
I got indoor/outdoor tree trunks growing
inside pictures check outs his Instagram
make sure you do if you're trying to win
some prizes you're gonna have to like
some stuff on these follows listen to
episode 50 I think that needs to be a
row all the rules they probably listen
to number city yeah please just listen
to the podcast guys tell your friends
we're getting yeah we're definitely
hitting 4,000 listens on almost every
episode which is pretty cool too better
episodes get 6,000 the standouts are
getting 5,000 lessons there are some
that are still like episodes with just
me we know nobody listens and I can see
on the website if you listen like for 40
minutes of the episode or 40 percent of
the episode it shows me how far you drop
out and people just get tired of me
rambling by myself but tell your friends
about the show if all 5,000 of my
listeners told one / told two people
about the show because one person's
gonna ignore you and one person might
listen then probably get me at least
another thousand listeners
what's a podcast people when more people
listen it moves my show up in the ranks
in stitcher and iTunes and then that
shows it makes it available
that's my goal all over the world we had
Christmas episode we are gonna get back
onto the track of doing those great
episodes where there's a lot of grow
lessons and a lot of great casts you
guys gonna learn more [ __ ] it's not just
gonna be my high ass rambling I've
actually got the next like ten episodes
kind of outlined I know what the topics
are gonna be I could scroll through my
phone and read offf gonna do it for me
miss Maddie what screen did you just
give me you you are close to that mic
all right somebody's got to talk while I
take a DAB yeah go for it Adam you
always have a good have a good ramble
well we learned today that getting hit
in the face with the ball
[Music]
shut up fish you know Micah Jesse pretty
damn face was clearly I think taken out
of that job site as fast as you can with
all will spin towards that very very sin
and steel frame gate is like you guys
have fun at work zero fun is allowed at
work dad just made my face today was
t-ball that do weird kind of fun of
today you know I've been made fun of a
couple times these guys didn't work
together until recently I think it's
partly my fault that these guys all kind
of built a construction company together
on and it's fun to see all my bros just
hanging out talking about what they did
cuz before they were all off doing their
own separate [ __ ] they all have a good
story together so Adam said the 2015 is
the year of learning does anybody else
have something that 2015 is for them the
year of what
I'm cashing in hopefully it will fo sho
yeah I was thinking the 2014 is the year
like getting the construction and the
foundation in 2015 is actually seeing
some [ __ ] succeed and get finished
sounds nice
I finally got hired on at a large
facility so I've got over 200 lights to
work with now that's kind of what my
ears gonna be about you're gonna have
fun with that buddy blowing it up bro
blowing it up get more shirts made get
them on the shelves at the spot get more
hoodies made get them on the shelves at
the spot dude I'm glad you said it
because Robert if you listen in to this
episode bro some hats are necessary we
need spot hats and we need I read
genetics money I don't have grass roots
Colorado Crest roots California arooga
Ryan if you're listening to this show
brother
I would love a sponsorship I'll do ads
for a year in exchange for IRA genetics
ads that's a lot it's 52 episodes a year
at least with 5000 people here in your
ads spot gas is brought to you by our
good friends at grassroots California if
you're looking for a dope-ass something
Larimer and pick yourself up grassroots
[Music]
yeah yeah come on down bro
so I can take care of himself
actually kind of love this place people
like why do you still live there I'm
like I didn't grow up here but I became
Who I am here and I feel like I kind of
owe it to this town to stay here and be
Who I am supports a movement here and be
part of this scene here all right almost
50 minutes we should put about another
ten minutes into the show anybody got
anything smartass are great to say what
are some your favorite moments we've had
on this podcast so far I know remember
that night we sit here we talked about
it earlier we sat here you said across
the table from me and we tried to do a
show for like three hours and I don't
know if it was the dabs or if it was
just the focus of the group walks up in
the room I had a recording her tour I
didn't delete one of the pre-recorded
tracks from another recording session
and when he came around to that that
recording dropped into while we were
talking perfect hey it's me man what's
going on it just starts talking
[Music]
for traction
I don't need edibles be careful please
luckily that's a medical only but yeah I
think they can only sell hundred gram
edibles incredible yeah I mean yeah like
it's read the [ __ ] life like that's
what that was the big lesson of 2014 is
why happens if you legalize weed oh as
it turns out people don't read labels
for [ __ ] anything ever we just take
pot all remember the chips that gave you
anal leakage like they were looking for
fat free and a major [ __ ] drip on the
front of the bag and they still sold
everywhere and it's because people don't
relate those in with edibles that leaves
you the whole hugging a pair of weird
jeans in a hotel room and then writing
about it for the New York Times we may
try not to shoot himself with a little
black kid that always says you mean to
tell me that yeah but you mean to tell
me there was some [ __ ] chips that
caused anal leakage and people were
still buying it yeah
[Music]
seriously give it two or three hours
give it some time to kick it it's are
you gonna enter any contest in 2015
hopefully I'd like to I'd like to travel
to organ and maybe California but maybe
what next when is that next November I'd
like to get out the best thing about
going to cups is it's like vacation but
[Music]
you're gonna buy tickets or go
the vending route oh yeah okay I got my
three-day pass I'm just working on a
book in a hotel room
I've actually got a ticket to see Doug
Benson on full house nine o'clock house
it's just me I just roll solo and do the
back get in the car and leave when I
want door I wha I'm just gonna be me
doing the backpack in the car yeah extra
money I've gone with the crew of people
and I've gone by myself and it's easier
for me just going I like going I don't
like going with the crew but I like to
especially me when I'm trying to like
talk to people with kind of it's kind of
hard having 15 people when you're trying
to even trying to be people walk up and
want to talk to me they know who I am
so if you're hanging out with me you're
just hanging out by yourself pretty much
so I roll solo so crowded so well
attended
[Music]
there's no more playing games and I'm
trying to come out and take some cake
there you go I'll be trying to talk to
somebody like hanging out with Mila and
then the people with me there's
something I don't understand right now
it'll probably explain later with this
guy even lunch can be a mild adventure
where famous people just appear
you just gotta accept it it's bizarre
you just got to know how to put yourself
in the position and line yourself up to
meet the people you want to meet without
being creepy and realize they're just
[ __ ] people - and if they open with
the right lines they're just humans -
and they realize that you're not a
stalker they want I did I have nobody
perfect and I'm sure I kind of got a
nice dude that it tells the truth most
the time I thought maybe when DNA
genetics walked up to me and shook my
hand because they recognized me and my
logo from Instagram like hey I know who
you are man and they said what's up to
me he gave me props for my work that
kind of put a smile on my face I got a
hot nail somebody talk while I dad I
mean you get a great set up form from
you know shout out for that we use that
thing every day we used it right before
the show shout-out to the G now I
thought that earlier that I forgot oh
yeah I'm sorry
Oh G Gmail is a beautiful invention
these dabs are available that are on the
table anybody came out of that I'm not
trying to be standing out - all right
big shout out to dabs
[Music]
I'm so much more comfortable on a mic
night is swing the mic in front of me I
don't do that edit the shows anymore I'm
just like podcast time I feel better
putting some of me into the show instead
just being all information I feel like
I've made a lot of friends now and from
listening to I listen to The Nerdist and
I listened to Doug Benson and now when I
see those guys like I saw Nerdist Chris
Hardwick at Red Rocks it was like
watching one of my friends achieve a
goal so I feel like maybe my listeners
feel like I'm one of their buddies
especially the people to interact with
me on Twitter and [ __ ] I know I'm their
friends like if I met mr. Romney oh he
lives in the UK if he showed up he'd
bring the doorbell he'd come in to take
dad's and hang out dude I'd make a cup
of yerba mate and we chill on he'd be my
bro and just because I have a podcast so
that guy's my friend now from that Fred
Garvin would probably show up and come
take dabs we just killed Mike with the
dab Big D hunt all the Denver crew
nicotine shout out oh don't do that
that would be the most horrific thing
ever I know he's been beating up the
microphone daddy's about to blast the
dough torch to the dome
somebody should hold on I'm gonna yell
you guys so it'd be cool Mike is alive
you guys we did not kill him very
borderline all right does anybody else
have anything to say we're down to two
minutes I'm gonna down to a minute try
to keep this about an hour
do your stuff couple times I sincerely
want to thank all you guys for coming to
the show you guys are Adams made jokes
about a team and B team and [ __ ] but
this is my crew right here this would be
the first five people I could call to
help me out I really appreciate
everything you guys and all together
from North Carolina from Colorado thank
you I didn't realize I taught you so
much and in realize you absorb so much
of what I taught you I learned from you
guys - it's not just me teaching you
guys I come and pair it a lot of [ __ ]
that Spence says just in my own language
you know what I mean I learned [ __ ] from
you guys every day yes even Clint and
Mike Mike stop me gross [ __ ] on accident
just not just refreshing your mind think
about growing is about growing there's
simple [ __ ] in your grow room that Mike
may go why is that turned alley if you
turn that way you'd get better air flow
and I'm just giving random examples
there's like physics and [ __ ] to be done
in the grow room shot a Tony also sorry
he keeps the website going he keeps the
feed going and he's one of them when I
sent physics I thought it was about air
flow and a lot of that [ __ ] so good even
if your friends aren't the best growers
you can learn accidentally about HVAC
you can learn plumbing like all that
[ __ ] comes in handy so don't ever take
anybody for granted octave on ya and
Scott and Scott don't ever listen to
this probably but they at least deserve
[Music]
to learn and we'll get you four places
all right yo fish I'm sorry I was
dissing you on the other show bro I'm
sorry
also shot at the dreadful J version
somehow every single in the day I used
to play like Marlon Asher and popular
reggae and they never flagged any of my
shows but I only have like 100 listens
[Music]
guys I promise they're gonna get better
I promise the guests are gonna stay high
caliber whatever they like to be back I
promise I'll have everybody here again
it's harder to get ladies on the show
there aren't as many ladies guys have
more [ __ ] to talk about cuz we're kind
of egoists you know what I mean
you hang out with a bunch of badass
dudes that picture you posted like all
these dudes protect me hell yeah we all
there's other growers like in the scene
and Instagram and all that stuff but
you're the only one here locally that's
at least known for producing killer
stuff so lady ladies want to be on the
podcast and have something to contribute
about cannabis
please step up come be on the show if
you want we are in Colorado on the south
side me male you call me you can
Facebook me
it's download the show everyone they
contribute a also a little bit I added
we added Tony technically added at the
request of myself a donate button on the
IRA genetics website if you go to higher
genetics com find the growth from your
heart podcast tab there is a donate
button at the top if you feel like this
show was worth a couple of bucks and you
want to make a slight contribution you
can make a donation to the show I will
thank you on the show if you'd like me
to or you can tell me not to say your
name I'm not begging for money but a
couple of people said that if I had the
donation button they would throw
donations in there and why not your time
and effort into this you deserve it
only that but you can put it back into
the podcast for necessary you can also
put it as an anonymous so you don't even
need to know you know it's just 30 bucks
that came from nowhere something else
that I may try to do in the future it's
called a Money bomb is what this guy
called it if you listen to a lot of
podcasts you may already know about it I
don't want to tell you two more the
radio I haven't paid too much attention
to how to do it but it sounds like a
great idea to where it will give me
money to give away to my listeners and
also help fund the podcast a little and
like Maddy said I do put some time into
this they everybody here spent about an
hour with me before we even recorded
putting the show together
I was thinking what we were talking what
it would cost to get all of us in a room
huh say for like a two hour consultation
with the business and it's expensive for
that kind of if you think it is upfront
and honest as we are at the podcast I'm
sitting thinking about the content over
the last 50 episodes and if you go back
and cherry-pick say like the outdoors or
and they're growing and caring and
harvesting episodes
that's like job training if you pay
attention to take notes you can fully
have a career based on that information
if you put a couple of years of practice
into it and do your own independent
research that's the found it that's like
a bachelor's degree lessons this year me
through my outdoor this year you know
there was a wheat dried and cured
absolutely and then Shawn came and
talked to you about organics and taught
you how to not go buy bottled nutrients
anymore and I mean just yesterday I
mixed up a girl Kashi you know I'm
saying like right here that will teach
us how to make cash but at the same time
that's risky because we can't teach you
how to open blast because that's not
legit and then nobody wants to give will
get Fred Morris or somebody to come
teach you how to make water hash please
I want you to come on and teach us how
to make water hash you know cross the
table there doesn't know knows quite a
bit about water house as well
[Music]
you know if you made an hour and 10
minutes into this podcast I love you
every day
before Maddy has to walk home please go
to iTunes and or stitcher go to the
iTunes Store to the stitcher main page
and search for I grow culture / grow
from your heart by the time this comes
out it better be fully switched to grow
from your heart I'm gonna get that low
go speed rush made I've got to work with
but don't worry bender I appreciate your
logo and I need it all so keep it coming
but I've got another idea that I want to
use I've been home to doctor he doesn't
reply to my emails either so it's cool
for the show the review section give me
a five star rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on the show if you think I completely
suck at podcasting you can say that if
you think I've got a shitty voice or an
awesome voice you can say that - just
tell me what you think and I will try to
improve and make you happy
or I might just ignore you and block you
and every episode will always be
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm and don't forget about that
donation button yeah it goes right to my
PayPal my daughters trying to go on this
adventure in Hawaii an educational
adventure and most of the money will
probably go to that to tell you the
truth not trying to kiss your ass but
that's probably what I'm gonna do with
it truth make sure you follow us on
Twitter and Facebook just search for
girl from your heart please follow I
read genetics on Instagram if you want
to win those prizes you know what you
got to do follow eye region etics if you
are interested in sponsoring the podcast
or if you have a product you'd like us
to review send me an email it's go for
me hard at hotmail.com and I'll get you
all the info you need big shout out to
my ninja spits who is higher than
giraffe [ __ ] in the corner walking
around my house over there
[Music]
microphone cover with bacon please
thanks for coming hope ya got some food
somewhere it closed before we die
everybody thanks for good for listening
check us out on episode 51 to tell then
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
so if you all away now because you wanna
be
[Music]
yeah what's up cannabis community it's
time for another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're a new grower a professional
grower a longtime cannabis consumer a
brand new smoker a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you thanks
for joining us I'm your host Rasta Jeff
I'm excited because across the table
from me is one of my favorite people on
this planet she said she did not want to
be on the podcast and then I talked her
into it and Miss Angela is here thanks
for coming I'm gonna get her talking
she's a talkative chick she's not
feeling super well today so I rescued
her from work we're gonna give her some
medicine she's gonna smoke some CBD herb
on the show and we're gonna kind of see
if it makes her feel better while she's
here I think she took one hit off that
bowl and she started to smile a little
bit so thanks for coming Angela I really
appreciate that over here to my left is
this obnoxious dude we got Clint Stewart
all playa's back dude thanks for coming
bro you know it's great everything but
Clint people people like you because not
everybody is a cannabis expert you're
the new guy you remind me to quit doing
wheelies and to just ride with both
wheels on the ground and teach you guys
how to get your balance and go straight
you can do like a one hander try to
catch up to where you're at cuz you're
at a level what 50 and I'm at a level
negative one I did last night and for a
whole car ride home you were higher than
her I want to say a big thanks to coot
dog cat and the mystic roots band
because they allow me to play all their
music on the show I just got to say
thanks to that all the time I'm gonna do
two quick ads before we get into the
show cuz I can tell there's always gonna
already gonna be a lot of conversation
here this podcast is brought to you some
of my best friends hydro indoor growing
supplies hi
you're drawing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado check out
the Denver snore at 62 71 beach street
or visit the pueblo location on 618 East
4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
hydro is running a special for the
podcast listeners what do you check out
at hydro tell that you listen to the
growth from your heart podcast and they
will give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase so you'll save money
just by saying you listen to the show
this podcast is also brought to you by
my good buddies at nature's green
remedies comm check out nature's green
remedies doc no is it yeah nature screen
remedies calm for gauge rain genetics
the plot of lab since city rare dankness
there's one of these I can't read
anymore
I read genetics and many more trusted
brands one of these two I had to cross
out and forgot which one it was
they don't cast listeners coupon code re
2015 for 15% off any order and you
always get free priority shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com the
coupon code will be valid through the
month of February and I'll change it up
in March it'll be different March first
so through the month of February the
28th or 29th I don't know if it's leap
year or not but it's good until my
birthday March first so shop now while
you can
big thanks and much respect to nature's
green remedies for the promotion and the
continued support if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the show send
me an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com i'll get you all the
information that you need I think that's
all the ads and the important stuff for
now let's talk about some [ __ ] we're
gonna talk about the Ari Shaffir show a
little bit you want to talk about CBD
medicine first introduced everybody last
night my buddy Clint about a month ago
my buddy Clint sent me a text message
said Ari Shaffir comedy works January
30th that's right and I was like [ __ ]
yes yeah and barely had time to even
talk to each other over the past month
it's been four or five text messages
Merry Christmas and so I'm so glad when
he's like [ __ ] ya bro and I was like
alright be at my house at 4 and we'll do
this yeah my problem is it's it's not
Jeff it's me cuz I'm I just work too
of us Geoff's busy too but you know it's
just I'm on a steelworker I'm there all
the time all the time yeah and do you
work a week days a week of days and then
a week of nights and yeah that would
just drive my body insane yeah we do
12-hour shifts Monday through Friday I
would kill her
7:00 to 7:00 and then so you're doing
a.m. 2 p.m. and then the next week a new
p.m. 2 a.m. and then back and back and
back it's you know so you just
constantly trying to catch up on sleep
so I apologize for not coming and
hanging out with your brother man it's
understood you're here now and we got to
have tons of fun
yeah adds a fun so last night Clint
Clint actually bought me a ticket to go
see Ari Shaffir
if you don't know Ari Shaffir he's on at
midnight quite often you gotta watch at
midnight if you're in the funny [ __ ]
he's got a show called this is not
happening on Comedy Central
he's got a Thursday night he's got a
podcast podcast called the skeptic tank
it's great and then he just put a
special out on Comedy Central regular
about his experience
coming up at the Comedy Store in Los
Angeles where most of our favorite
comedians seem to have gotten their
start at least at least went through
there for a time yeah I really enjoyed
his comedy last night man he tore it up
so I have never seen or paid attention
to Steve Simone on the way up
Clint told me that Steve Simone was the
opening act dude Steve Simone was
amazingly funny he's a mostly clean
comic he didn't I don't think he ever
said [ __ ] he might have but I mean it
was in passing I think it was something
where it was it was so fun he just he's
a ball of energy and he's still in sixth
or fifth grade yeah thirty-five-year-old
sixth grader yeah yeah it's kind of cute
it's adorable man watching him wiggle
around all uncomfortable but comfortable
you know like like he's got all that
attention that he wanted but now he's
like oh [ __ ] I've got the attention and
he starts wiggling but he tore it up he
crushed it was real fun and then
shout-out to Chris Charpentier for
hosting that show too great he was
hilarious yeah I like that the openers
get that short little set because then
they just do that highlight set yeah get
out of there I think that's kind of
smooth you
know yourself off and Charpentier is a
Denver guy so we're trying to get him to
come down to Pueblo that's sweet
we're trying to do stuff down here too
we're trying I'm still I'm still an open
mic rebutted on shows every once in a
while it's just you know I'm busy with
work so everybody's trying but uh made
some new friends last night it was real
fun at the Denver Comedy Works which is
our favorite Club my favorite Club yeah
definitely my favorite comedy club on
the planet yeah so we get to make a
whole bunch of friends and it was it was
a lot of fun yeah people gravitate
toward my boy Jeff here it's it's funny
dreadlocks and a big cheesy smile
because I was high well they probably
also wanted to be sitting front row like
we were you know that's my Buddy Baker
hooked us up with the preferred seating
passes and actually got a text message
from him today saying whatever we want
that just let him know and those are our
seats
we're like a b-level regular yeah
whatever we want to sit there those are
our seats bakery oh my boy ah dude ari
we want to give a huge shout out to Ari
and Steve Simone those guys tore it the
[ __ ] up I laughed my ass off I've needed
laughter is therapy my life is stress
will be in a pot grower having so many
friends having an Internet life my shirt
is stressful I balance my stress pretty
well but comedy is my medicine dude
cannabis is my medicine comedy is my my
soulful release and music yeah but going
to see comedy and laughing like that I
feel like I got refreshed with you of
course bro that might have been part of
the therapy you know you don't a good
conversation yeah with I mean that's the
thing with us is we don't even there's
what no time for music or anything all
the way up because now parts about not
seeing somebody for a month flow is like
everything's brand new
yeah so I could agree it was great it
was a great show I would recommend
everybody go check out Ari Shaffir yeah
check out Ari Shaffir support that guy
his t-shirts are 3d and they are awesome
yeah I'm wearing one right now
they're sweet the sweetest t-shirt I've
ever seen on a tour
super quick shout out to our buddy
Deacon gray Deacon gray is experiencing
throat cancer he's been through all of
his chemo therapies he looks good his
spirits are up but I still want to send
you a big hug
lots of comedic love Deacon is a Denver
comedian support Deacon gray I know you
don't know who he is but just sent him a
big fat jaw hug or whatever you believe
in sent him some vibes because he needs
your energy to get better over this
cancer yeah laughs and I think since
laughter is medicine we need to return
the favor to him he's come down to
pueblo down spring we did a free show
here yeah that's super cool not super
popular town that has a bad reputation
and did a show for free yeah that's
that's awesome
he's a Denver guy why did he come here
because he's awesome all right so Ari
thank you dude thank you thank you for
the ticket thanks for driving that was
like [ __ ] you I 2525 can suck it
sometimes yeah
hit a little rush hour but it wasn't too
bad not too bad so I know my way right
to Comedy Works blindfold me my car just
goes there it feels like that was so
great that was pretty great all right so
Ari Shaffir was awesome that was well
that's our point here dude if you guys
get the chance go check it out check out
paid regular re wouldn't mind me saying
this it's on the Torrance go find the
extended version on a torrent site
please get the Xtend first don't check
out the broadcast version all right the
name change is official you guys this
show is now called the girl from your
heart podcast I'm gonna start trying to
remember that all the time it's not
agriculture anymore there's a new logo
the new art is posted but facebook and
Stitch are slow to update they won't
change stitcher won't change probably
until I put up this episode it's been at
the wrong artwork the wrong show
description for a week and I've emailed
them and they're like we'll fix it but
it's free so don't give a [ __ ] they're
not gonna fix it Facebook will change my
name February 4th they have to verify
that I am Who I am because I'm a
business and [ __ ] they don't want me
just change in something and yeah so
they're like you get 14 days and that
comes up February 4th so that's all
coming up that's all official [ __ ] that
I needed to say the website I read
genetics Colorado calm we have got
shirts and happens and stickers on there
they're a bunch of black t-shirts in
sizes small through extra extra-large
and white and I think there are only
about ten I read genetics hat pins on
there those are going quickly so grab
those while you can while you're there
join the forum on the website and also
not trying to be a mooch but there's a
donate button on that [ __ ] right
on if you go to the podcast page there's
a donate button if you donate you can
donate $1 up to however many you feel
like if you feel like this podcast was
worth a couple of bucks of yours for my
time in my effort I would appreciate
your donation but somebody said they
would donate if I put that there so it's
there feel free to use it you donate it
goes directly to my PayPal account
that's kind of it helps me pay for the
show because I do put in a lot of work
to the show yeah still a free podcast
though yeah I'm never gonna charge you
I'm never gonna make you pay for
anything I'm just saying if you feel
like it was worth something and it's
like a tip if you felt like you got good
service put in the tip yeah all the
information this guy's giving you a buck
I would definitely buy new microphones
microphones for sure and then my
daughter's trying to go on an adventure
in Hawaii an educational program and
until that happens all the money that
goes into that donate button will go to
her eldest treat send that to her
GoFundMe for her her adventure in Hawaii
her educational adventure so that's
gonna ya guys I know I did a bunch of
giveaways on episode 50 I'm still giving
you time if you haven't listened to 50
go listen to it learn how to win a bunch
of bad ass prizes from the garden of
Weeden prizes from hydro indoor growing
supplies hype prizes from IRA genetics
there's a highly-educated t-shirt I plan
on deciding my the winners around
episode 52 or 53 like I said I make the
rules I'll decide what I did what I
don't even want to tell you how to win
the prizes but when I see the right one
the winner I'll go that guy wins it'll
be by episode 53 I won't drag it out too
long all right so Angela sitting across
the table looking all sweet you look all
right I'd over there can atonic do you
remember the numbers on that I know it's
0.5%
see in like almost 15 okay so I'm gonna
kind of rewind and shut up to natural
mystic cannabis caregivers in Colorado
Springs that's where we got this high
CBD medicine Angelou is one of my best
friends I know a lot about it I'm gonna
try not to talk too much about her world
so if you feel like you need to slow me
down and tell me not to say that or
whatever feel free to cut me off I'm
gonna try to be completely respectful
about this conversation but it's your
health and I'm talking about it's your
private [ __ ] so interrupt me whatever
you feel necessary and chime in when you
want Angela used to dab with me like a
[ __ ] champion do Angela used to smoke
fat joints she would roll joints the
size of my middle finger and I've got a
big middle finger and her and I would
smoke them just to the dome and then
she'd roll another one and smoke weed
smoke half of that and then put it out
and smoke it later so she was a heavy
smoker one day she had a mean headache
and somebody did the hippy pressure
point where they squeeze between your
forefinger and your thumb there's a
little spot in there that all your old
hippy friends will tell you if you
squeeze that and rub that a little bit
your headache will go away so one of our
silly hippy friends did that and she
completely blacked out I did a little
fluttering and she hit the floor and
when she came to she was really
disoriented and kind of groggy and it's
been labeled a seizure is what everybody
any medical person has called it and so
she went home she got home from work and
what's the first thing you want to do
after that you want to go [ __ ] smoke
a joint after you just had some
traumatic [ __ ] like that happened to you
she tried that and she told me that she
felt like she was tripping she's like
I'm hallucinating I'm seeing [ __ ] and
she put a blanket over her head and laid
down on the couch in the fetal position
and wouldn't talk to me for like an hour
yeah she was hating life and this is a
girl that I've seen take half gram dabs
and laugh at me she just make fun of
Adam we would smoke and Adam what a POW
and want to go home and she'd be like
come on [ __ ] smoke a joint
she said that she used to smoke two
grams of wax a day by herself and her
and I hanging out together we kill and
hate the hash and a day just on a normal
day just her and I smoking yeah
yeah so she went home and smoked one
joint or one dab or whatever and was
freaking out and she thought maybe it's
just today you know she gave it some
time and what about her life but she
still had a headache and didn't feel
right and so she smoked more weed and
every time she would smoke weed she
would just get ridiculously high it was
like hanging out with a high fifth
grader like it's really what was
happening to her she went from a pro to
Clint yeah just we had to babysit her
when she would get high and she'd get
super-anxious a lot of anxiety from
smoking weed so we found a few strains
that would work better the Platinum og
was working well and the Girl Scout
cookies was getting her to high but it
was the kind of a more comfortable high
floor it seemed like so she didn't feel
he was it's been about a month and she
really did not feel good a few days ago
it's been about a week right yeah and
she felt like [ __ ] yeah and not being
able to obviously you kind of Jones for
some smoke because it's ritualistic it's
not just wanting to get high her and I
used to pass a joint back and forth and
lay around and smoke a joint together it
was like you just feel good feels good
to get stoned and smoke and like being
sick and not being able to smoke the
medicine that she relied on it's driving
her crazy I can [ __ ] see it it's
making her kind of grouchy so we going
we call my friend Joey at natural mystic
cannabis caregivers about a week ago and
I'm like hey bro do you have any high
CBD and he said I sure do come on up to
the shop we'll get you set up I wish I
could remember the bud tenders name she
was beautiful she was super helpful and
I would hire her if I owned a shop any
day that girl knew about cannabis she
had great skills I wish I remembered her
name cuz she was awesome I don't know
that she'll ever listen to this but she
deserves a shot
so we go through we get the CBD medicine
and we got canna tonic can ASSU and Tora
Bora and they're all super high CBD
strains and we okay okay thank you but
we get we get to the car I'm trying to
be discrete but we go to the [ __ ] car
and she wasn't gonna wait she rolled up
the joint and she started smoking it and
she got about halfway through the joint
and I looked over like you're smoking
like a lot of weed over there for
someone that has panic attacks or
smoking weed and she looked at me and
she goes I'm high and smiled okay it was
definitely so for myself I've smoked a
lot of CBD cannabis and I've written it
off because it didn't seem to really do
anything for me it didn't do I want to
get high when I smoke I want to feel
that cycle or that psychedelic it's
slightly I don't even know what to call
that head change and CBD doesn't do that
so I've written it off if they're like
this is a high CBD strain I'm like well
I'm not gonna smoke at all that you
smoked it cuz you have pain and enjoy it
because I'm just wasting that dab or
that joint and so I know it's helpful
for patients but watching her it changed
our entire day just she smoked that
joint and half of another one and then I
smoked half of one with her and I had
taken a couple dabs we stopped a smoke
on the drive and I we pulled over and
got out and did a little hike and she
and I took a couple dabs but then after
I smoked that joint it felt like my dad
hi was kind of diminished it was like
now you're not as high as you used to be
I was like why am I getting
Mellott but it made me higher for a
really long time and we got giggly we
both got Connie and I don't get giggly
from smoking weed but CBD after a couple
of dabs changed dabs don't give me an
eye high when I smoked weed back in the
day my eyes would get all droopy my
dad's don't do that to me
but the CBD weed totally put that back
it did that so I think I'm missing
something when I'm dabbing I think I
need to smoke more flowers and I think I
also need to incorporate more CBD excuse
me and get clogged up yeah do you feel
like CBD is like a like a
No not to call marijuana like a hard
drug or anything but do you feel like
CBD is a drug unto itself like THC is
what drug and then see CBD is a drug
calm like you you like when you get your
tolerance going for THC maybe that's not
the same tall and she would have 4c be
right it's a different compound it's
affecting a cv d receptor instead of a
THC receptor which is also a cannabinoid
receptor but it's gonna affect you
differently yeah well that sounds like
something that that people should be
aware of like no it's not just marijuana
it's like no you need to kind of know
what's in that like or what style
completely because now we're gonna focus
on finding her a lot of CBD medicine
because she's been a different person
from when you got here yeah you were
laying on the couch in the dark now you
doing all right yeah so it's helping you
it's making a headache go away you're
you look better you don't look like
you're trying to hide from the world you
know when you don't feel good
you just wanna hide you put your hoodie
on yeah but your kids always find you
and it sucks man you must be stoned as
[ __ ] today oh yeah Angela's the
budtender over at the spot dispensary
shout out to the spot dispensary in
Pueblo West Colorado the spot for high
society stop in and say what's up to
this cute little dreadlock girl she's
beautiful store that I've been to
because normally I have other context
where I can get marijuana from riots
anyways a very nice store I like the the
people in there they were all super
helpful had no problem finding what I
needed to find I liked it has a nice
store it's a cute little shop check it
out it's under construction in the grow
area and as soon as it's ready there
will be some Rasta Jeff grow it happen
in there that's what I'm excited about
yeah I get in the whole world excited
about that how much of that have you
talked about so far
on the show yeah I'm not much because we
haven't super it's not my business yet
if that makes any sense all your
headphones cut out some time to be
talking about really talk about what I
can say yeah I can say that there are
over 200 lights and that it's hydro and
that the rooms are [ __ ] awesome like
I've been in a water grows a lot of big
grows and when I walked in there I win
damn you guys did this [ __ ] right yeah
like there's a showroom you open these
two swinging doors I dunno if it's
double doors or one door it's a huge
[ __ ] door you open it you walk in and
there's a showroom
that's the grounds are glass so that you
can see into two rooms ocean the water
room yeah so there will be they plan to
do like visual tours and [ __ ] haha I'm
down yeah get me on that that's just
cool yeah it is yeah I'm hoping to do a
lot of things with there I've got ideas
they've got ideas we just need to agree
yeah so she's backing up another bowl
over there about of that CBD has it been
other than today has it been helping you
I know today was an extra stressful
shitty day for you for sure I'm pretty
sure if I smoke this before work that I
would have felt better than to bail out
halfway through so why would you do that
I don't work she works with the person
that did the hippy [ __ ] hand
technique and he's kind of sympathetic
still so you should play that card
[Music]
that's basically what it is I'm gonna
take a dabble you want to hit that bowl
while I take a DAB clips not smoking
this evening Clint saw I got a drive
here pretty soon and I'm not uh I'm not
capable
it's a Saturday night and there's a UFC
fight and there will be police
everywhere where you're headed yeah so
I'm just gonna chill out and hang out
with the listeners maybe you guys are
smoking maybe you're not I think that's
the best part about this podcast is it's
just information you know and then
Jeff's doing a good job of trying to
make it a fun and educational I know
you're making educational finding that
borderline that's that's the tough part
is because you guys can ramble on about
a lot of stuff but that's like you said
earlier as maybe I'm the guy that
because I don't know a lot about this
stuff even the questions between CBD and
THC I just don't know I guess I should
talk more about CBD I don't have a book
or website I'm just kind of spat out on
my head
CBD is a cannabinoid I think it's
pronounced canna Biddy all it works more
as an analgesic and anti-inflammatory
it's known to have antibacterial
properties it's really well known for
and this is a good segue it's really
well known for stopping people who have
tremors and seizure type disorders or
conditions I won't even call it a
disorder that's a condition calling it a
disorder makes it sound like you're
[ __ ] condemned or something yeah this
people with seizure conditions so I was
telling a random story that I will tell
on the show in a second I was telling a
story to a friend who is a paramedic and
she said that CBD stops an electrical
firing in your brain that causes
seizures so that's awesome yeah and so
it that's gonna be really helpful for
anybody with seizures CBD definitely
makes me hungry that's why I'm not
smoking that ball it's like my first or
second hit off a CBD my stomach does so
if you got some cancer and you're not
eating from the chemotherapy
dude smoke some canna tonic that stuff
makes me starve like we would do it
watch and then smoked
after lunch and I was like we got to go
back in there yeah that stuff just makes
you want to eat um it made my I can play
guitar longer I've noticed that I got a
new guitar for Christmas and I've
noticed if I play too long my wrists in
my forearm yeah yeah I don't I just keep
going now really and I may just be
building up endurance but I don't feel
any pain from it I would [ __ ] up after
a while I know I'm not so this stuff is
instead of like the head high that I
normally get where I'm just flying
through the cosmos
now it's more of a body high is that
what you're saying like you would
probably experience a body high yeah
because you're really low tolerance to
any first but people that have smoked a
little bit it just goes straight to pain
I feel like it knows where the pain is
it's like Oh your arm hurts I'm gonna
drive right up to your arm I'm gonna
park here let out my little CBD
paramedics oh we're gonna work on your
arm or your head or your neck and
shoulders cuz she's had a lot of weird
symptoms lately sorry I cut off my
description of what kind of video all is
but it's it cannabinoid it's the
opposite of THC it's the the one that
goes down and stead of up and it's I
think it tastes like cherries I
definitely think that a water herb that
has CBD in it and extracts made with CBD
they often have a cherry like a cherry
hall's cough drop or a Luden's kind of a
taste to it that's what I've always
thought of CBD I'm high in random I've
talked about how it affects me it makes
me hungry it made me really mellow it
made me kind of smiley like put a grin
on my face like a giggle and then
there's a really a random story you
ready for this one over there so we had
a long day we went to Springs and bought
some cannabis which is an hour drive
away we went to lunch and then we came
home and like two beautiful people do we
uh we're both loving what we were doing
and after about an hour of us giving it
to each other I kind of looked at her
like um I love what you're doing but I'm
never going to finish like this is
perfect you've done everything I love
and this is not gonna happen like
nothing's Ryan she kind of looked at me
like me too and I'm gonna
you but it usually doesn't take much for
her to be done like she gets three to my
one cuz she's a girl yeah I'm not
complaining but I mean I didn't even see
one is she's obvious when it happens I
didn't see one and I was like well she's
not either so she goes I think that CBD
and I was thinking it right as she said
it she was I think that CBD weed killed
it and it was the whole time it was
happening it was like I was almost there
so it was [ __ ] amazing the entire
time but he just wouldn't
there was no grand finale there I was
like it's not you and she's like it's
not you so we so I talked to my
paramedic friend and she said that that
same electrical firing in your brain
that causes a seizure is the same one
that causes you to orgasm oh Sh
and by smoking CBD you pretty much just
turned that sucker off and she said
we'll do it turns off that electrical
firing mechanism honest part of the
reason I don't smoke is because we
bought a limited supply I don't need to
waste it it doesn't do much for me other
than make me hungry and not make me nuts
so what's the price comparison on you
know that dispensary is very completely
fair and it's they have three different
price points of that herb and it
averages at $200 an ounce but it's a
medical only shop oh yeah so you have to
have a medical card to get in there but
$200 an ounce is a very good price yeah
because she works at a dispensary and
did you sell an ounce today
no we barely ever because it's like 560
out the doors after taxes everything a
little white bag that walks to even
carry your ounce out in it's like the
first accessory you didn't even like
you're gonna because you have to have
that to leave the dispensary because
that's childproof that's how the
dispensary watches their ass Wow yeah
that's that's weird I didn't know that
that's so they actually have to sell you
that bag or they that's kind of like
given with the 560 that's what the 560
but they could some dispensaries charge
you for that is that what the 560 we had
the childproof bottles we are supposed
to charge for the bags because they're
buying a lot of stuff yeah they stock up
at that shop that people really like to
stock up when they come it's fun
watching them shop people are mesmerised
guys come to a dispensary if you're from
another state drive out to Colorado
go to the spot dispensary if you're
coming from the south go to the spot if
you're up north dude go to like I don't
even know how to tell you to up north
I'll find a good spot and I'll recommend
them soon but come to the spot in Pueblo
West Colorado check it out they've got
such cool [ __ ] in there they've got like
25 strains of herb on the shelf if
you've never been in a dispensary and
somebody shows you 25 jars full of
cannabis you're gonna smell every single
one of them the bud tender is gonna
start tapping their foot they've seen
them all but just just just just look at
every one of them and enjoy them I'm
sorry I'm doing that to you I know
you're the bud tender and I'm telling
them to do that but enjoy spoil yourself
the first time yeah look it is so
freaking me like I remember the first
time I went into a weed store it's
amazing and I'm from here yeah save
yourself some money start growing your
own hair I'll make up for telling him to
take all day the bud tenders do accept
tips there's a tip jar on the couch yeah
make sure you toss some [ __ ] in there
big tips 600 bucks for an ounce out the
they drove all the way here yeah just I
mean that's I'm uh I'm an open mic
comedian
I'm sure if anybody's heard me before
they they know how unfunny I am most the
time but not trying to say I'm a
comedian just saying I'm an open mic er
but that's like one of my big things is
just how cool Colorado is compared to
everybody else around us yeah god it
must suck being from Utah oh yeah yeah
yeah I hear I hate Texas at probably 50%
of the customers seem like they're from
are all from Texas yeah so they hate
they hate Texas because they have to
drive from there just to get legal weed
that's ridiculous
yeah yeah guys do what you can where you
are to get cannabis legalized in your
area so that you don't have to drive all
the way to Pueblo Colorado to come by
and eat for like 70 bucks speaking of uh
like people making changes I want to be
able to shout out to our buddy Mike for
holding it down at the City Council
stuff appreciate it
Neil Punk you really kick an ass man
yeah appreciate it he does 12-hour days
13 14 hour days just so that he's able
to get to the City Council meetings I
think you got to work at 6:00 the other
day and finally got home from City
Council at 10:30 so however many hours
that is Mike's putting a man for us so
that we can grow so that we can smoke so
that we can do what we do here and not
feel like criminals again in our in our
local area that's Mike that's a good
thanks for reminding me of that well
weren't you saying something we were
driving up yesterday we got talking I
asked how's Mike he said well we they
got this kind of thing going on and they
were talking about like your backyard
stuff do you want Mike in here to talk
about that better or like how City
Council's trying to make it to where we
can have less plants in our backyard or
something like that yeah well we've
gotta talk to about a little bit of that
on the show City Council is trying to
limit us to like 6 plants per household
and you have to grow it in an
outbuilding not attached to your house
and Mike and I Mike mostly but since I
know a lot about drawing I was able to
contribute a lot but Mike wrote pages
and pages and pages on why that's
ridiculous and he's been going to every
he goes to the Planning and Zoning the
City Council city commissioners any
meeting that he can sit in and go this
is why that shit's [ __ ] yeah he
shows up and puts it and he's working a
like a 45 hour a week job doing
construction - so he's blended and he's
doing he's actually building grows for
the Denver bud company that is so cool
all day long he's cannabis in some way
or another but just thanks Mike we
appreciate it
if you're on Twitter follow Mike woodsy
neo-punk on Nemo punk and then there's
numbers after it can we talk about the
wheat brain I got on the way up there my
goldfish goldfish memory cuz I have such
a low tolerance we smoked before we I
smoked here I smoked one hit and this is
the funniest thing to me because I know
it's gonna happen and I want to hold a
conversation with people but I I smoked
one hit off of my little pipe and I am
like thirty seconds so I'm like what was
it's every 30 seconds it's hilarious -
it is hilarious
I know what's happening so I tell Jeff
like yeah I just don't remember what we
were talking about he's like dude it was
four seconds ago and I'm like I just
don't remember I'm sorry we could off on
these tangents I get excited there was a
pause at one point when we were driving
I don't remember who was talking but
there was a pause and we looked at each
other and I just go
[Music]
so if you're trying to hold a
conversation or if you're trying to be
the cool guy
maybe marijuana like for the first time
isn't the right thing to do and I wasn't
even planning on smoking at the show I
was just like yeah we'll get back to the
car I'll smoke in the car and we'll head
back but then when Ari Shaffir passes
the joint too it's like wow you know I
probably should yeah yeah you were
silent until we got to the gas station
to get gas the window just enjoy and
just thinking of like oh man it was so
pretty out - and then what I think I
said one thing I could Denver so pretty
yeah that was beautiful other than those
damn horses Jeff my boy Jeff here has
had nightmares and he's uh he's afraid
of horse-drawn carriages that's true
yeah that's true he let me know this so
every time a horse-drawn carriage was
coming our way I just punched that horse
boundaries drawn then the punch would
come you never had to drop [ __ ] horse
[Music]
I don't know any horse names like
Secretariat I got nothing man okay I
hope Rican tucky Derby of dropping
horses over here the honest truth I
lived in Santa Fe New Mexico for a short
period of my time of my life and I had a
dream a nightmare that on the plot well
this actually happened on the plaza in
Santa Fe there are horse-drawn carriages
cariann yuppie folk around all the time
just on dates and [ __ ] and they got
white Christmas lights and candles on
him and [ __ ] they're all snazzy I had a
dream one night that I was in my car and
I could see this horse-drawn carriage up
the road crossing the street and I just
could not stop I was only going like
normal speed I wasn't going over 45
my dream but my car and I stop the
horse-drawn carriage with people in the
carriage it was chaos I'll be back when
you're not around carriages crazy yeah
thanks guys
yeah do those a great trip thanks for uh
thanks for making that happen that was
your fault
hey you drove man I appreciate you
driving there's no way I can get
high-end Drive I'm not seasoned drive
yeah
don't drive high please like that's
that's it drive yeah know your limits
well we got talking about why Jeff
doesn't drive when he's like cashed
that's because Jeff's kind of an
ambassador for as I see it like with
this podcast and stuff like that you're
trying to make weed as acceptable as
possible
yeah and you know yes you look like a
hippie I mean you've both got dreads but
you don't need to be making the classic
mistakes at every stoner movie like
showcases like oh he's so stoned that he
can't get off the couch or always see in
six shades of grey or something like
that because he smoked himself
colorblind or some [ __ ] I don't know
it's just yeah it's the dude where's my
car effect where everybody's an idiot
what kind of brought it up was there was
traffic was going crazy up ahead of us
and I wasn't sure what happened
and I said pay attention to which which
way the turn signals go and Clint found
that to be some sort of genius [ __ ]
observation yeah because that the mile
ahead I can see the turn signals flicker
in and I know if I need to start going
left or right now cuz I'm just gonna
copy the turn signals and I'll be in the
proper lane instead of fighting for it
when I get up there yeah getting cut off
by two Priuses was cool turn signals are
going on up ahead now is just stoned
enough to go that was like extra
attention and be more a little more on
top of it because I've got dreadlocks to
my ass a morning I read genetics
Colorado cannabis t-shirt the car reeks
of dank even though the herb is in the
back of the car in the backpack in a bag
it is reeks I look like a pirate and I
don't want to be pulled over on the side
of the road and a rack and there goes a
stupid pothead hiya [ __ ] did something
dumb I don't want that cuz I will scar
the community I feel like and this is
what kind of brought this up I feel like
I kind of represent I have chosen to
represent the community not just myself
there are a lot of us that do it but I'm
one of the people that have chosen to
speak out and put myself in the
spotlight for cannabis and they need to
be not a malnourished to skinny dude I
need to not be the cliche on the couch
guy and be [ __ ] the red eyed in every
picture that you see that way maybe some
of our friends who are taking the
red-eye pictures maybe they'll be like
oh you know what maybe the maybe the
cliches donor isn't really what we want
to be showcasing to middle America white
America who doesn't I mean I'm all
cracker it's just you know and for the
longest time it was it was it was
something where weed was dangerous
because we're indoctrinated with that
through dare and all this stuff yeah
well back in the day and the they taught
us that the Mexicans and the black jazz
musicians would smoke weed and rape
white [ __ ]
yeah always you turn into a demon and
rape the white women yeah for madness
it's what we were taught propaganda and
people my grandparents like they they
were smart enough to go away that's
[ __ ] but their dad friends that were
like your kids are smoking weed and
whenever I even gonna be your friends
again because like my grandparents
raised cool ass kids we're all pockets
like three uncles and two aunts and my
mom and they were all pot heads until
their adulthood life and some of them
still smoked just because my mom can't
smoke anymore she gets so [ __ ] stupid
when she think that's the thing with
weed is there isn't that me and my buddy
Paul Paul Rosales he said Paul what's up
bro
what's up buddy he's present yeah wild
cousins check out wild cousins um no we
uh we were talking about it the other
day and there's no like with heroin you
get sick if you try to quit with math
and all these terrible drugs and and but
marijuana for the longest time was in
that same category like everybody
thought that that's oh it's it's all the
same you know but nobody talks about
like oh I can go into a 7-eleven at any
time before 2:00 a.m. and go buy as much
alcohol as I can fit in my car
yep and and no that's okay because this
is Clarke and drink it on your boat
mm-hmm yeah yeah yeah you're completely
allowed to I mean you could I
I've been sober from alcohol for eight
years then I had to quit I had to quit
because I had a real problem with it
fortunately I didn't get withdrawals
when I decided to quit but I do know
people that did you get shakes at all
I don't remain it's been sold so you're
just over it but I was forget that but I
was literally 22 years old when I quit
drinking Wow
yeah I mean when you started it like 14
but that was the things you could get
alcohol alcohol was you could get it
it's just like cigarettes were back in
the day which is illegal you could get
weed yeah ever gonna stop you from
getting what you want yeah but I don't
remember the DARE officer being like
dude alcohol is the one you gotta be
watching oh they put [ __ ] if you look
at alcohol commercials they make you
think that if you drink dose icky
you are the most interesting man in the
world I don't always drink though
sadiki's but what I do but I don't
always drink alcohol but when I do I get
two chicks I got a boat I get a cool
acid dog someone throws a party balloons
happen [ __ ] I'm beautiful like [ __ ]
just cuz I drink some dose at keys yeah
but but on the opposite hand like
anytime that you're smoking weed you're
the stoner that sits on the couch and
you're just so typecast as that and I
think that's such [ __ ] yeah so I
wanted to give you a shout out Jeff for
being a good representation of cannabis
culture thank you bro that's good
hopefully some people on the on the
other end of this podcast will agree
with me I'm absolutely positive they do
because after I posted episode 50 my
email and social media feeds have
exploded with people saying thank you
for this show dude you guys you
overwhelmed me you made me like I don't
even know there's a feeling in my heart
I don't even know what to call it but
there's this big bright white light that
goes around my chest area when I think
about it and my friends in this room can
see it in me when I'm talking about it
right now it's unblocked Waveland have
that many people email me and go dude or
[ __ ] proud of you and your show is
awesome like I'm overwhelmed and super
excited to be on the podcast I wanted
you to be here when I told the story
about us not being able to finish our
sexual escapades because I wanted to be
respectful about it and I would have to
play the episode for you and let you
edit out anything you didn't like anyway
so you kept us on track and kept it nice
so I'm glad you came for that part how's
the store treatin you do you like
working there
so it's taking a hit yeah I like it
she can't see she [ __ ] hates the
novelty like definitely wears off kind
of quickly when people come in for the
first time and they're really excited
that like makes it all worth it can't
really complain I sell weed all day
previous meals or the drink I just took
but yeah we shouldn't found that I'll
show up with food or sometimes the
boss'll just have random questions and
I'll pop in and I don't want to leave
when I get there cuz it's fun it's
everyone's just hanging out and having a
good time
nice place they're sweeping and cleaning
and [ __ ] but I mean you can [ __ ]
with me while you're sweeping and
cleaning and there's it's fun there it's
a good atmosphere
yeah the crews all like family to a
little too well I hope everyone's
listening I look forward to getting in
there yeah yeah I totally took over your
answer but I look forward to getting in
there because it looks so much fun do
you have a favorite product from there
is there something that you would
recommend as the Apothecary lotion i
make Jeff rub me with that all the time
because my shoulders are always killing
me the extra stream I was I didn't
believe it would work and then one time
I rubbed her down with it and it made my
hands all fluffy shout out to Apothic
Anna the Grammy Gatsby so that's
something that's C that's just stuff
that it's like it's so it's a lotion
doesn't get you high but definitely is
really relaxing muscles and everything I
definitely deal with a lot of neck and
back pain and that helps a lot right on
I put it on my knee
it helps my bum knee a little bit makes
it not hurt when he gets cold my knee
hurts and I hope some of that on there
no more anymore I said no mo can you
pick that up on the recreational side as
well as the medicinal side yes you can
see these are the questions that need
answers is why we brought Clint yeah
awesome good question we're just
chatting I'm not even paying attention
forty nine minutes
yeah okay I had some news articles I
think that'll be episode 52 will just
save those there's no need to get into
the bunch of news my news is that uh
February 21st we're doing a benefit show
at the downtown bar in Pueblo Colorado
I'm not sure if there's a cover I'm sure
there is a cover but I don't remember
what it is but I'm on early I'm on it
like three o'clock in the afternoon we
do comedy first and then they're gonna
do bands after that so you pay maybe
five bucks it's a benefit show February
21st
who are we benefiting that is for pops
for pops yeah cool what's up pops
benefit you bro will uh the Brooklyn
Heart podcast we'll try to figure out
some way to contribute to that yeah
genetics and team IRA will have to do
something fizzy pop PSA's I used to grow
specific CBD medicine for pops back in
the day note in there or something he's
got some notes so February 21st in
Pueblo Colorado at the downtown bar
there are gonna be a lot of comedians I
think I've seen something about this but
I see so many things on Facebook that I
my brain doesn't absorb all of them
downtown bar there's gonna be a lot of
good music there be a lot of good
comedians get down there support pops
pops has been a staple of the Pueblo
community for a long time if you're from
Pueblo and you've ever been to any
drinking establishment and you've had to
deal with that old guy outside with a
gravelly voice the checks your ID let me
see your ID
that's pops that's pops you know pops
and he's helped somebody to not get your
to not kick your ass at one point in
your life if you've been to the bar pops
has been the bouncer in the security
guard and there's always that one
[ __ ] in the bar that wants to fight
and pops will protect you so shout out
to pops he's uh he had lung cancer so he
needs we need some Clint get to your
notes I'm rambling about pops for a long
time now yeah sorry all right
is uh February 21st at the downtown bar
music and comedy and show starts at like
2 2 p.m. and I'm gonna be on maybe like
3 o'clock but it's the comedians I'm
just gonna talk about the comedian's
because there's so many guys coming down
let's hear him Dan Rainey myself that
was but that's that's like a really good
group that is a very funny guys and I'll
be on so I mean that means that you're
actually funny quality comedians every
one of those guys as funny [ __ ] yeah
none of those guys are hacks Facebook
about a local comedian being a hack and
every comedian in Puebla thought I was
talking about them not the hacks know
those people tell jokes they wrote no no
that's that's the thing that's they all
heard that southern Colorado comedy is
is really pushing forward with our own
sense of humor he might not like me but
you're gonna like one of the guys on
that or you're gonna like one of the
people on that we've got a lot of
friends we're all friends and that's my
favorite thing about the comedy the
culture is it is it is kind of like a
weed culture I mean they go hand in hand
almost it's because everybody knows
everybody yeah we went up to that show
you knew people that knew people there
was people our waitress was like do you
know this person now I kind of know this
person though but and they know that
person it was it's just a community and
yes and so it was great of that Chris
Charpentier I told him I was like dude
we need to get you down to Pueblo
because he had been scheduled down once
but he couldn't make it that night but
that was one of my favorite shows that
was David Bowie came down with Sam
talents and it was great and Byron
Graham so shout out to everybody that
comes down to Pueblo we're really trying
to work hard every second and fourth
Thursday we're at the rainbow bar on
Santa Fe doing an open mic trying to
promote that we did one this last week
and it was it's so fun it's such a great
place for comedy so I hope everybody can
come out and check it out
support local comedy you guys even if
you're not in Pueblo there's comedy
where you are and if you're an aspiring
comedian start the scene do it that's
right all it takes is you to go Stan's
more and tell some jokes and invite some
friends to come listen get four or five
people make a little comedy showcase at
the bar every night Wednesday nights are
good for it Thursdays I mean we're on
Thursdays because we don't want to
compete with the downtown bar every
Wednesday yeah but you know we do the
second and third or the second and
fourth Thursday we're gonna be at the
rainbow bar and I just I'm hoping people
come out it's a free show free super fun
and are so funny it's ridiculous super
free fun comedy night it just became
[Music]
without that for comedians that's not
bad you know you said how comedians or
friends it felt like once we hung out
with Ari for just a couple of seconds it
just seemed like just some other dude oh
yeah and it didn't even seem like we're
smoking with the celebrity he just
smoked weed he's like alright guys I
gotta go
it had some phone texting going on I
think he had some booty call to go tend
to and he was out yeah he was just a
nice guy I mean there was literally a
couple of minutes there were nobody was
talking and everybody gets so amped
around like celebrities but I really do
feel like Ari Shaffir is a celebrity
he's put in so much work to get to where
he's at and his special was so good and
his special just came out so you know
you would have thought like all these
guys that listen to his podcast would
have been all upon us nuts but
everybody's just kind of like yeah we're
just it you're just a guy and that's how
he acts he has sweet sweater I didn't
like hearing about I listen your show
man it's great episode whatever was
awesome is like cool thanks let's talk
about weed yeah just [ __ ] I don't
want to talk about me anymore like it
was kind of neat like he didn't care
dude man well yeah and then you I did
too because I told him all that if you
get a chance we're gonna listen that
skeptic tank was it 202 with the alleys
yeah I think if you're gonna listen to
the Ari Shaffir skeptic tank listen to
the episode that is titled paid regular
let's start with that one I think that's
one of the best
I think that's episode 201 sweet maybe
200 but don't wander it was a couple of
his comedies yeah that was really funny
to other people in the world before we
wrap up the show here an extravagant
message of peace and love for everybody
insert and stretch a piece of love here
try to insert anything don't smoke too
much CBD minute let me embarrass you on
the show thanks a lot for coming the
show's over please go to iTunes or
stitcher go to the iTunes Store or the
stitcher main page search for The
Gruffalo heart podcast find the review
section give me a five star rating after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is archived on ira genetics colorado
calm make sure you follow us on Twitter
and Facebook search for grow from your
heart oh yeah there's a new girl from
your heart podcast Twitter that has
never shot out a tweet maybe by the time
this airs I'll post a tweet from it but
there's a new Twitter I'm gonna switch
it over I just committed to it it's at g
f YH podcast is what I think it is it's
perfect well I heard weird music was
that you over there that was weird
[Music]
joke last night too though
maybe that's what's going on make sure
you guys follow
I read genetics on Instagram I will be
posting podcast stuff on the Huayra
genetics Instagram it's at I read
genetics if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like me to review send me
an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I'll get you all the
info you need
Clint thanks for coming on the show bro
it's really awesome to have you thanks
for having me thanks for let me plug
those dates to other [ __ ]
that's part of being on a podcast it's
how you got paid yeah Facebook and
Twitter and Twitter and I'm on Instagram
and every social media has at tall Clint
it's Clint CL int it's not to you in the
middle there Clint there isn't n jerks
it does look weird so yeah big shot too
many just Vince thanks again for
listening until next time take a phat
dab and give you a mama hug for me
[Music]
she confused me I don't know what you
think what you do to me first you treat
me like a king and linji through with me
but truly I get for loving every day cuz
it's my duty even if she kind of moody
bride to make you a key
[Music]
all right podcast rolling I want to
thank you guys again for listening to
another long chunk of episodes I'll be
back Monday with the fresh new show and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me