welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 217 of the Grove
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
but right up here zoo grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated davor if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank-you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roof man who let him use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to cat poo and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen I hope you were
smoking something delicious with me
right now I just took a fat dab of some
bear dance butter from our friends at
apothecary extracts this stuff is
delicious I cannot even describe the
flavor of this it's I'm gonna smell it
again just to see if it makes me think
of something
you know sometimes some herb has a dryer
sheet sort of a smell this stuff has a
dryer sheet kind of a smell happening
something smooth something silky but
then there's a sweet berry taste at the
end of it that I'm really diggin I'm not
usually a fan of the berry weed but this
uh that dryer sheet smell on the high
from this bear dance batter is amazing
it's got kind of a a cheesecake sort of
a texture it looks like some cheesecake
batter or some cake batter the dad let
me take add add a little tiny dab goes a
lot further than you would expect it
gives a lot of smoke a lot of vapor so
shot it's my friends and apothecary
extracts for the amazing bear dance
batter you probably hear that it made me
coffee little bit for some reason the
day I took made me sneeze you'll hear
that in my throat for a couple of
seconds but I promise it will I can't
promise you I'm not positive but I'm
fairly certain that will fade away as
time goes on hopefully the high fades a
little more slowly than the chest
congestion anyway ah bear dance let's
see let's talk about the bear dance and
why I bought it I picked this up at
apothecary on Saturday the reason I
chose to buy the bear dance is because I
was going to see the remaining members
of the Grateful Dead which are now known
as dead and Coe I thought it would only
be appropriate to smoke a bear dance
hash at the Dead and company concert so
uh let's talk a little bit about dead
encode before we get to some cannabis
talk here and we are going to talk about
cannabis on this episode I promise you
ah
Saturday I got to see dead and Coe at
Folsom Field in Boulder Colorado it was
a beautiful day it was a beautiful Drive
Jenny Beth looked super beautiful people
could not quit staring at her all night
all day it was a little bit ridiculous
she bought a dress that I showed her
features very well and she looked
[ __ ] great
so that was fun we got up there it was
super sunshiny it was kind of warm it's
actually really nice the riffle dead
came on I keep calling the Grateful Dead
it wasn't the Grateful Dead it's the
dead and Coe it's
from The Grateful Dead the remaining
it's through original two drummers
Mickey Hart and Billy kruseman and then
you got Bobby where original member of
the Grateful Dead and then over there on
bass they've got a dude by the name of
Oteil Burbridge you may have heard of
him dude plays a mean bass then they've
got a dude named Jeff committee on
keyboards and then there's this young
guy that you might have heard of him
before his name is John Mayer he plays
guitar because I've talked about this on
the podcast before a long time ago when
I heard that John Mayer was playing in
Jerry's spa and the Grateful Dead I was
I don't know what the feeling was but I
doubted it and I wanted to be a hater I
was skeptical I had skeptical hippo eyes
right at the very beginning but I've
gone and seen it a few times now I've
actually caught a few shows of the
newest version of the Grateful Dead and
John Mayer nails it you guys if you want
to be a critic if you want to be a hater
go see a show and you will be blown away
at the way John Mayer fits in with the
Grateful Dead I made a couple of jokes
though Mayer does bring a younger crowd
and you can tell who's there to see
Mayer because they don't put their
phones down and they don't shut the [ __ ]
up during the concert when I'm seeing
the Grateful Dead or a Grateful Dead
style band their jammy they do
psychedelic long extended songs I want
to be able to get in my head into this
little bubble that happens when you're
watching that and not be interrupted and
all these younger kids that are going to
the shows now they want to [ __ ] talk
over the jams they want to ask you what
song they're playing and [ __ ] I'm a
bigot shut the [ __ ] up on Jerry's plan
I'm gonna go see fish in a couple of
weeks and I might get a shirt made this
has shut up when fish is playing this
because that's how I feel about it I
don't mean to be a [ __ ] about it just
sucks you pay a lot of money to go see
your favorite band and then some kids
are right behind you just talking
through the whole show you'll turn out
to be like a broken even maybe not talk
during this song and then they think
you're a dick because you want to hear
whatever song you're trying to hear
anyway overall it was a great time there
were enough cool ass people there to
override all the young kids John Mayer
played the [ __ ] out of the show early in
the show there was a great version of
ramble on Rose
they played a really long version of
Dark Star one more Saturday night was
awesome there were tons of great songs
honestly you guys I can't remember all
the songs I haven't been a list here but
unless you're a deadhead you probably
don't care and if you aren't a deadhead
you probably already know what they
played that night so we saw the show
they tore it up one thing I do want to
talk about there their current bass
players named Oteil Burbridge he's
played with bands that you've heard of
before he probably I'm trying not to go
too much into the music talking nerd out
because music is one of my my top three
favorite things cannabis and music are
soo my top three favorite things take a
guess what the third one is Oteil saying
china doll this band has been together
for this version of this band has been
together for a couple maybe three years
now um I don't remember exactly when
they started but they've been together
for around two or three years and Oteil
has not sang and a few nights ago in
California he's saying China Doll and I
heard a couple of notes I when the band
stops and they start tuning their
guitars and everybody starts hitting the
effects pedals on their guitar to get to
the effects they need and the keyboard
guy warms up by playing a couple of
notes of the next song I'm really good
at guessing what song it's about to be
just the music nerd to me can spot it
and I looked at Jenny and I was like
they are going to play china doll and I
knew that she was gonna love it because
she loves when they play slow mellow
songs and she's been wanting to hear OTO
sing so I put my arm around her and they
smile I was like she is gonna love this
and we danced together for a couple
seconds then I just kind of stepped
aside and let her just have her moment
she did that thing you know when girls
are super happy and they're not sure if
they want to smile or cry and they put
their hands and kind of like a pray
thing and they just touch their mouth
with it I'm doing it right now for some
reason she did that for the entire
duration of the song it was about six or
eight minutes she just smiled and Bob
back and forth great moment anyway yeah
saw the dead it was awesome they did
china doll one of my favorite parts of
the show they did china cat into i know
you ride her and there's a part in the
song the lion is I wish I were a
headlight on a northbound train I'd sign
my light through that cool Colorado rain
and when they they sing the Colorado
rain part that whole that whole field
erupted with cheer it was [ __ ]
awesome I knew it was coming because I
know the song so I was just looking
around I think this is gonna be [ __ ]
rad and it was pretty damn cool to hear
the whole crowd just go yeah so that was
pretty awesome
ah so the grave lit they tore it up I
will go next year I had a good ass time
I look forward to seeing fish here in
just a couple of weeks if you guys gonna
see fish I would love to see you there
let me know I may have some seed packs
in my pocket when I go to shows I put a
couple of packs in my pockets and I just
carry him around and if you
seemi high-five me you hit me up maybe I
got some seeds for you yet never know
it's Colorado I can do that [ __ ] ah
let's move forward I bought a new
printer why is that significant that is
significant because now I am able to
print off the emails that you guys send
me and I can bring them to the podcast a
little better than fumbling through my
phone trying to find the appropriate
emails instead of doing that right here
these are the messages I'm gonna read I
don't have to go dig through my phone
there's no [ __ ]
makes me look sound and feel a little
bit more professional so I've got a
printer I'm able to just wirelessly
shoot the messages from my phone right
to the printer they come out and read
them we can do some [ __ ] I like it so
why throw tis still [ __ ] up from that
dad that I took so I am going to I'm
gonna take a drink and then honestly
I'll probably take another dab and just
chill out for a second till my throat
quits then we'll come back and we will
read some of these emails we were gonna
start off with an email from a guy who
calls himself Saint skinny and then
we're gonna work our way through to
godfather cush and then you never know
where we might go after that so ladies
and gentlemen you heat up a nail and
take a DAB and then drink some water or
something natural maybe some kombucha
and I'm going to do the same thing and
with the power of recording magic I will
be back in half a second all right
podcast world I hope you took a couple
of fat dabs during my quick break I know
it was really brief let's see before we
get too far into the show I need to do
something special I need to wish
somebody very special a very special
happy birthday I need to wish two people
a happy birthday one of them probably
does not listen to the show one of them
definitely does just a couple of days
ago it was my beautiful daughter in
Mayas birthday happy 14th birthday I'm
sure she doesn't listen to the show but
still I got to do it I love you kiddo
happy birthday also somebody that I know
is listening she's probably smoking a
big old dad right now and listening to
the podcast the dad and granny had a
birthday today today is 619 and it is a
davon granny's birthday she is 62 years
old today I don't mind announcing how
old she is because she did 0.62 gram dab
on Instagram for her 62nd birthday happy
birthday granny we need to get you back
on the show real soon granny so whenever
you have time
drive down to pueblos or I will drive up
to Colorado Springs maybe we can go to
the candy Canyon or somewhere and hang
out for an hour or two do some we can do
some Facebook live maybe some Instagram
live maybe some periscope videos and we
certainly need to record it grow from
your heart podcast together shout out
huge happy birthday blessings to you I
love you every day and I miss hanging
out with you all so big high-five -
Kevin the grumpy grandpa that's right
you guys the dad and granny as a partner
in crime known as the grumpy grandpa
they're a great couple
high-five to both you guys look forward
to seeing you all right let's move
forward with this podcast I did tease
that we were gonna read some emails I've
got them in my hand you hear it here I
feel all professional I feel like Dave
Letterman or Jimmy Fallon
or somebody popular and famous and on TV
I don't watch a lot of TV so I was
trying to fake some names Jimmy Kimmel
is who I was [ __ ] thinking of but it
took me a lot of time to come up with
that but I feel like Jimmy Kimmel or
something I feel like Dave Letterman I'm
flicking my pencil up in the air and let
it do flips and then catching it like a
pimp and then marking down on the paper
what I need
I'm gonna quit rambling and I'll read
emails you guys I took dabs they're
[ __ ] working all right this first
email and by the way if you'd like to
email me it's really easy send me an
email and grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you
I'll read your emails on the show and
then I've got a printer I assume I
imagine I predict I'll be reading a lot
more emails and I'll get a lot more
organized with a lot more [ __ ] also
hashtag they like it when we ramble
anyway this message goes like this hey
Jeff and then this dude put in
parentheses you can use my name st.
skinny or st. or skinny to refer to me
I'm not a picky dude and he goes on to
say I thought I'd share some of the
music I like to listen to
after getting nice and toasty if you
guys remember I'm the 4:20 episode I
asked people to email me to tweet me to
message me in some way and let me know
what kind of music they listen to after
they smoke it the messages are still
coming in the podcast never goes away
sold people will reply for a long time
and here is what my friend st. skinny
said he said Kottonmouth Kings and
potluck are two of my main jams but I
also like things on the other end of the
spectrum the clashes London's calling is
one of my all-time favorite albums right
up there with Marty Robbins gunfighter
ballads and Johnny Hortons greatest hits
if you don't know Marty Robbins El Paso
is not a great son
type is not a great song but I think he
probably meant ah if you don't know
Marty Robbins El Paso is a great song
with some gorgeous guitar if you don't
know Johnny Horton
I'd suggest the Battle of New Orleans
where they used a gator as a cannon
guess where the powder wait so that
makes more sense the way yeah I think
you just got ahead of himself with it
not in there so uh we've got to check
out some Johnny Horton and some Marty
Robbins you guys had stuff we've got to
listen to Saints Kenny recommended it
give it a listen let me know what you
think I'll give it a listen we'll have
like a Rasta Jeff's music club sort of
thing going on here you never know maybe
we'll discover one of our new favorite
bands by finding out what our friends
are listening to through the podcast
dude thanks for the email it goes on to
say keep doing your thing Jeff and
thanks for the shout out to my mom and I
she heard it coming home from the
hospital and about had her in tears
little things like that mean a lot mama
Saint is in the hospital again getting
her bone marrow transplant to fight off
the leukemia so well wishes prayers and
positive vibes are appreciated if you've
been listening to the show for a while
you guys probably have heard me read the
emails from Saint skinny before and he
was telling us about his mom being in
the hospital and I gave her a shout-out
on an episode and she happened to be in
the car when Saint skinny was playing
the episode she heard it and so I've
been corresponding a little bit through
emails with Saint skinny uh and you guys
he said that she is in the hospital
again getting her a bone marrow
transplant to fight off leukemia it's
got to be a horrible experience I know
that I have never experienced anything
that horrible and I hope I never have to
I'm grateful that I am healthy I had a
traumatic brain injury that [ __ ] me up
but that just happened and then it was
over is like I got hit and then I woke
up all [ __ ] up I feel like getting
bone marrow transplant is a long slow
battle and it's got to be horrible so
whatever you believe in I'm not I'm not
gonna ask what you believe in you could
believe in Jesus you could believe in
Jah Rastafari you could believe in
Buddha you could believe in rocks and
trees you could believe in nothing but
what I want you to do is think about
Saints Ginny's mom just imagine a
nice-looking lady a mom she nice-looking
lady you know you got whatever you think
my mom looks like in your head imagine
her and then imagine this one being
Saint skinny's mom and she need
it's bone-marrow transplant and she
feels like [ __ ] and I want you guys just
to send her some love from your heart
because no matter what you believe in
what your religion you got love in your
heart so send a little bit of that to
Saint skinny's mom just to get her
through this look this bone marrow
transplant cuz that's got a [ __ ] suck
you guys if you're well enough to be at
work or in your car or whatever you got
a second to send some love to this nice
lady so just do it right now
all together right now doing only gonna
take half a second here we go
did you feel it I did it I hope you did
too all right
since Guinea I hope it works I hope that
all that love lands on your mom I hope
she starts feeling a little better uh
what do I call her do I call her mama
Saint yes we're gonna call her mama
Saint how things go well for you um let
us know how you're using cannabis to
deal with this because I've never dealt
with leukemia and a bone marrow
transplant sounds like you could teach
me things and if you don't mind I'll
share it with the listeners and we can
kind of turn a positive out of a shitty
negative thing it's the best we could do
best I can do I hope you guys are well
st. and mama skinny Saint Saint skinny
and mama st. I kind of want to know how
Saint skinny came up also to tell you
the truth we've been corresponding for a
while so share that with me he ends the
email with stay red-eyed smiley and live
life Irie you know I will do that my
life is great
I run a cannabis grow I've got a
beautiful healthy daughter I'm fairly
healthy I'm getting older I'm falling
apart a little bit here and there but
I'm fairly healthy for the most part I'm
grateful for that I'm thankful for that
so I'm living life Irie and I hope that
you and your family are doing well with
what you guys are dealing with much love
you guys's direction everybody sent a
little love tour do it again all right
I'm gonna move forward with another
email skinny thanks for the email dude I
appreciate it much love much respect
shout out to your mom also all right
let's move on to another email this one
is from a guy who calls himself
Godfather cush and he says good day to
you sir I hope you were fully medicated
and loving life right now no doubt you
are sorry sorry in advance for this long
email hey don't be sorry for long emails
sometimes it takes a lot of words to say
how you feel uh if anybody understands
that I do it takes a lot of words
sometimes I'm rambling a [ __ ] right now
ah but let's get on with this email he
says I'm a new listener and I dig the
show for sure I've listened to all
episodes available on iTunes it must
have been meant to be because as soon as
I ran out and caught up on the current
episodes you posted your first few shows
oh you guys if you listen on Thursdays
I post old episodes I've been going and
making you it's usually three episodes
sometimes I can fit four or five and a
three-hour file but I've been going and
getting old episodes and just
sequentially putting them back out in
order and chunks of three because iTunes
and stitcher feet only hold 100 episodes
so ever
I put out a new show something falls out
so I'm putting them up in chunks of
three hoping I can get old episodes up
so you can relist it I'm making videos
for the older episode than putting those
on YouTube because eventually the
reposts are gonna fall out of the feet
also and I'm gonna have a lot of content
is what's gonna happen and a lot of the
archives will end up on YouTube and the
most recent 100 ish episodes will be on
iTunes and stitcher
boy what I'm doing is putting out the
old stuff because there's a lot of
valuable content in there a lot of my
really written and thought out episodes
weren't about fifty five to a hundred or
some of the most educational stuff that
I put out so they'll be back they'll be
back in the feed they'll be up on
YouTube I'm really rambling so I'm gonna
get back to the email here he said I
want you to know that your message and
vibe really come across any positive and
uplifting way your character and
attitude really makes it known that you
were coming from such a real place in
your heart and are a true caregiver I
really like the fact you breathe strains
with patience in mind and you don't just
cross attractive street names for fun I
can only imagine how many people you
were able to bring to enlightenment when
it comes to cannabis breaking stoner
stereotypes is what this world needs and
you were doing a great job hey thank you
uh the past like four sentences you said
really mean a lot to me I'm not trying
to be an [ __ ] I'm really high and I
really mean it like my character and
attitude make it known that I'm coming
from a real place yes I'm not joking I
love cannabis I've done 217 episodes
I've put them episode out every Monday
for three years because I'm dedicated
and I love cannabis I'm coming from a
true place thank you for noticing ah and
I am a true caregiver yes I sometimes I
just sit and listen to my friends talk
and we smoke and I think sometimes just
listening to a guy talk and nodding your
head sometimes it's all somebody needs
somebody just wants to be heard
occasionally and if you can provide that
and just also provide a little medical
relief at the same time you're really
doing a lot so being a caregiver yes I
am doing that thank you for noticing
it's not that hard you guys just take a
minute
I just [ __ ] sit down with somebody
you're doing it already you're just
sitting there smoking people anyway go
find somebody that needs some help and
smoke with them and just talk for an
hour you'll feel better you'll feel
like oh man I just sucked up all their
problems but then you might realize like
I don't have those problems and then
you'll be able to help them and everyone
will feel a little bit better so I'm
gonna keep moving he says he likes the
fact that I breathe strains with my
patients in mine and I don't just across
don't just cross for attractive strain
names that is true I like to breed with
a goal I know what I'm looking for when
I start breeding and I will scrap a
project if it sucks trust me I'm not
sure how many people I am able to bring
to enlightenment about cannabis but uh I
hope just a few people would make me
happy I hope I'm reaching a large
audience but just a few would make me
happy as long as I'm changing one person
a day that that would make me happy if
one person everyday listens and goes you
know what this pothead guy isn't that
bad we might learn some [ __ ] that would
make me happy so breaking stoner
stereotypes is what the world needs yes
it is that's partly why I do this I know
I've always been well-spoken and kind of
a speech kind of a guy I've been that
dude and I felt like it was kind of my
responsibility to do this so thank you
for noticing that I'm you're telling me
that I'm doing a great job thank you um
I know I've been at it for a long time
and I have pride but still being told
you're doing a good job always feels
good even no matter who it's from so
thank you man I appreciate that and then
you go on to say I'm done blowing all
that smoke your way I just had to let
you know that you have a new fan hey
Thank You Man I appreciate that I will
promise to give you quality content as
long as I can then you keep going and
you say I went to the bank team to get
my hands on some of your art they have a
couple available but not much and not
really what I was looking for I did
however get a freebie with an order and
I'm pumped on it I'm down here in New
Mexico and I've heard you shout out
organic ax and how they have a 30% plus
a rise so I'm hoping it comes through on
your crosses
he's got my cookie cross and he says
definitely looking for a short and
potent definitely looking for short and
potent and we'll let you know what I get
everything really does happen for a
reason because even as I type this I'm
listening to the latest episode and UT
some upcoming seed and strain talk and
I'm looking forward to it long story
short I'm a new fan of you and what you
were doing I wouldn't mind hearing more
about what you were breeding and when
you will replenish the Dane team with
your fine craftsmanship brag more on
your are
I don't mind it one bit and I'm sure
other people like it too
Grover's love and mom says what the
hell's a Rasta Jeff and she got a hug
anyway that's funny
this dude said take a fat dad and give
your mom a hug for me and he told her
she'd know what the hell of Rasta Jeff
was it's just me Mom I'm cool I'm
harmless
there's so much to talk about here in
this email let's back up Oh God he's got
his hands on some of my art from the
dank team you guys I read genetics seeds
are available at the dank team.com you
can get a few things there they had a
deal for a little while if you spent so
much money you would get some freebies
of cookies and creams cross to arise
which has been named to the cream I'm
not sure that they have that anymore I
can announce that I am in talks with a
new vendor and I will soon announce that
vendor on the podcast and if you are
looking for a new avenue to acquire eye
region that exceeds I have a new vendor
we're working on it they'll get a shout
out in the next episode or the next two
episodes depends on how things go I want
to make any promises we're gonna get
that worked out we should have another
avenue for you to get those beans and
they will have the cream available they
will have a rise they will have cascade
they'll have morning dew there'll be
several great things there if we can
work that out you're down there in New
Mexico where organic ax is shout out to
my friends Tim and Charlie Charlie jr.
and everybody over at organic oh there's
a bunch of great folks over there I
don't want to miss anybody so I'm just
gonna stop with those three they've got
the 30% arise and you're hoping it comes
through on the cookie cross it will it
will come through on the cookie cross
I've got some cream growing in another
room and it is frosty as hell
also you may be able to pick up some
seeds and organic ax in the very near
future and they will have a rise and
they will have the cream and they will
have morning dew and they will have
Firefly ah so keep your eyes out for
that coming up at organic ax also
sometimes organic uh sells clones so you
may be able to go down there and get a
clone of the arise that is testing at
over 30 percent THC it's tested at 35
percent THC before the last couple tests
have been closer to 32 they test every
batch and they're getting it dialed and
they'll get those 35 s consistently but
go down there and check for a clone or
call them maybe they've
a clone for you down at org antica if
you're going to get clones at org antica
try to get yourself a Zack Hayes clone
that plant was bred in honor of our
friend Zack who passed away from cystic
fibrosis and that plant grows like a
champ smokes like a champ and the
medicine that he creates is potent and
amazing anyway I want to keep moving
with the email sorry I'm rambling today
you said everything really does happen
for a reason yes you're right it truly
does everything does happen for a reason
then you kind of asked me to talk a
little bit about my breeding which is
perfect timing everything does happen
for a reason I got this at just the
right time because I'm on Father's Day I
will be doing a little pollination in a
room right now I have got to arise males
that's the same plant I've got two
clones of it because I want to make sure
to have enough pollen I want to sprinkle
a ton of pollen in that room and I also
want to collect a little bit of pollen
to keep in a jar which we will talk
about in a future episode but I've got a
rise a male in flower he is dumping
pollen right now he is dripping
also I have got let's count there are
approximately 20 females in in the
flowering room they will be ready to
receive pollen on the 18th of this month
around the 18th would be ideal a couple
days before a couple days after would
not hurt but I think the 18th was the
day that I chose I wanted to do it and
that is Father's Day so it's going to
work out very well the girls that will
be in that room the female plants that
are in there there's grateful dog in
there the arised a grateful dog makes
morning dew there's lemon skunk in there
arise - lemon skunk makes Firefly then
stuff I've never done there is a Kalonji
cush so we will have Kalonji cush cross
to arise there's Capleton so you'll have
Capleton cross to arise let me tell you
what those are Kalonji cush is tahoe OG
cross to the grateful dog the Capleton
is white widow cross to the grateful dog
so I'm gonna cross those to the arize I
see a lot of great things happening
there they'll put out some really cushy
stinky phenotypes I'm hoping that the
arize male puts a little more weight on
both of them
the Kabletown already puts out huge buds
I'm curious to see how big those buds
are gonna get and what that might do
also in that same
there's a redheaded stranger I like the
way the redheaded stranger grows it
branches out a little more than they
arise which I like it would kind of
improve the structure of your eyes so
arise and red headed stranger I plan to
call that red rocket there's a flow
plant in there that will take pollen
there's also a platinum tangi a very
small platinum tangi plant I just want
to make a few seeds to play with it see
if I can find a very orange phenotype
there are a lot of great plants in there
so I do have a breeding project
happening right now the pollination
should happen around the 18th you know
what I could do
I've been trying to think of a good name
for flow crossed to the arize I would
like to think of a word that means like
the upward flow of energy or uprising
energy I know I just said the word
uprising that may work um something so
you guys if you have any suggestions to
help me name flow to arise flows the
girl arises the male ah send me your
suggestions you can tweet me at G fyh
podcasts you can send me an e mail it to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
or on Facebook it is the girl from your
heart podcast I kind of want to hear
your opinion since I'm talking about it
white widow times the rise needs a name
also there's a white widow girl in that
room so white widow to arise needs a
name I've already done that before I've
got seeds of that I've just never
bothered to name it I haven't grown the
seeds because I haven't had room there
are only a few of them sometimes I just
run little tiny plants for my first
breeding project then I'll grow them and
see if they're worth a [ __ ] then I'll
make a whole bunch more in the same room
for the breeding there is a female Pro
dad Jim is how I think you say it that
was bred by Colin Gordon of the ethos
collective uh it is a very orange e it's
got like a like an orange cleaner kind
of a smell to it with a little bit of
you know how a car tire shop or any
where you get your car worked on has
like a hint of like an oil sort of a
smell it's got that smell to it it's
oranges and oil I like it in a sick way
it's got a really great aroma to it so
there's a proton geom in there there's a
Jeff Shoji in there so we're gonna need
a name for Jeff Shoji to arise and also
there's a hell's og in there so there
will be hell's og cross to arise and I
think I have a name for that
not certain yet but I want to grow it
and see what it looks like but I'm
pretty sure I've got a cool name for
that so those will take pollen on the
18th ish I like to hit the plants with
pollen sometime around day 25 there's a
little window between like the 23 and a
32 ish that they can take pollen it's
usually about day 25 that most of them
really like it I like to do it when the
pistols are nice and fat some people
will put the females different females
in the room at different times to time
them some people just throw them all in
there at the same time these plants are
kind of small they are not huge plants
I'm not trying to make a whole bunch of
seed I just want to see what some new
crosses do and while I'm at it I'm just
repeating some old crosses to make it a
little bit more seed stock for myself um
so I'm gonna hit all the plants at the
same time on the 18th and then I'll let
them grow for about five or six weeks
and I'll start pulling out one seed from
the bottom of each plant seeing how hard
it is how dark it is looking to see if
it's getting tiger-striped if it's still
white and soft it's obviously not done
when they start getting hard that's when
they're done I'll flush them cut down
the plants let them dry pull the seeds
out and then I will test most of them
myself is how I usually do the first
batch I just run them myself it takes me
a little while but then I find what I
like and I make more and more and more
of those and as I make more I usually
throw a couple of new things in the room
so say I'm trying to make a whole bunch
of Firefly I'll do a whole light of
lemon skunk females but then I'll put
one of something new in there that's
never been pollinated by the arize just
so that I can treat something new while
I'm at it that way I make production
plus a new personal cross to play with
just try to keep things new as a breeder
as a grower you gotta keep it new keeps
your mind excited keeps your heart into
it keeps it passionate so that's what
I'm doing with my breeding project I
hope I answered your question their
Godfather cush that was a lot of
rambling year long email was met with
their long reply I really appreciate it
alright I feel like I've got time for
one more email this one is gonna set me
off on a long rant so I'm gonna press
pause I'm gonna take a drink I'm gonna
take a DAB and then I will be back with
an email about traumatic brain injuries
and cannabis use hang tight
all right podcast world I am back I I
took way too big of a dab I'm all sweaty
I feel like I am red and uh I am
sweating behind my knees I've never
split felt this sweat behind my knee
before but right now I can notice that I
don't know if I have never done that or
if I've just never noticed it or if I'm
finally just high enough to notice that
but uh yeah there's sweat back there
I've never done that before I'm wearing
shorts I'm still sweating on my legs
that's a good dab anyway before the
break I promised that I would read an
email about traumatic brain injuries
because if you've been a longtime
podcast listener you know that in April
of 2015 I experienced a traumatic brain
injury I simply hit my head I hit my
head real hard I hit him just the right
spot and I knocked myself clean the [ __ ]
out I gave myself a subdural hematoma
which is just a big word for I had a
bruise on my brain there is pot there's
your brain and there's a pocket of fluid
and then there's your skull and then
there's your skin and I had like a
bubble between the brain and that layer
of fluid it was kind of acting funny and
was putting pressure on parts of my
brain that were making me say and think
weird [ __ ] I really [ __ ] me up I am
NOT suicidal at this time I've never
really wanted to kill myself but during
that brain injury there were times when
my brain was telling me that I should
hurt myself and I knew better but it was
all related to a brain injury
I was I was slowed I couldn't speak as
well as normal if you listen to the
podcast from that time period April of
May of 2015 June 2015 I was goofy I
smacked the [ __ ] out of myself I
couldn't do math properly I couldn't
drive right I couldn't write podcasts
properly I was [ __ ] up
and it was making my attitude bad and
not being able to perform properly and
remember a sentence and remember what
was happening was making me have weird
thoughts of doing weird [ __ ] to myself
so a traumatic brain injury can [ __ ]
your life up um I felt like [ __ ] for
days it felt like so at first I didn't I
couldn't
even tell what was wrong with me I was
so [ __ ] up I was just broken I didn't
know which way was up which way was down
I wasn't hungry I wasn't thirsty I
wasn't hot I wasn't cold my friends
would have to tell me to drink water
because my my gums would just be stuck
to my teeth like fire marshal bill
remember fire marshal bill had that dumb
expression where his teeth were just
paste it or his gums were pasted to his
teeth I looked like that and didn't even
know it because of a brain injury my my
little signals in my brain that would
say hey dude you're thirsty that signal
never went off my net my my would sound
like this on the show and it would just
be my mouth so dry then my lips and
teeth and my tongue were just all stuck
is one piece I couldn't even tell
because I was broken in my brain ah I
would go outside and it was cold as [ __ ]
and I wouldn't even have shoes on
everybody else would be shivering and
cold with a jacket oh that's fine out
here they'd like you're [ __ ] crazy
and I didn't get a cold I didn't get
sick from it that was tremendous ahh
there would be times I would just be
sitting here at this table and I would
forget where the [ __ ] I was at what I
was saying better been points on the
podcast when I was recording at that
time were had to stop and rewind and
listen to what I was saying and tried to
figure out what the hell I was even
talking about so I was broken from the
traumatic brain injury you guys I have
recovered quite well there are still
problems in my body from that there are
still problems in my brain from it I get
the normal forgetful [ __ ] that people
get I get the normal problems that
people have but her like what was that
but but I also have other things that I
can tell are from the brain injury
because they're new and they didn't
happen before that I went through weird
attitude changes I was very impulsive
for a little while I was quite angry for
a little while I was I was honoring is
the only word that I could use to
describe it I was just [ __ ] with
people and just being a smartass and
it's trolling people and it was all just
from a brain injury just triggering me
to do weird [ __ ] and I read books and
talked to doctors and I did all the
right things and the books and the
internet experiences told me that there
are phases you go through from a brain
injury and I was going through them
properly if I didn't have support from
my friends and the internet telling me
that [ __ ] was gone right I would have
been really scared because not knowing
there
parts of my life that are missing
there's from from the month after that I
probably only know I can put together
one full week of [ __ ] and I don't know
the rest of it and that is I I may be
slightly a control freak I'm the boss at
my job I own my own business I host my
own show I've got some control freak
[ __ ] going on I did not have that after
my brain injury and it really [ __ ] me
up so I want to get to this person's
email I was just trying to to let
everybody know I did have a serious
brain injury so when I talk about this
I'm not talking out my ass what I was
getting to it just loop back around I
know I started saying something it felt
like somebody had put I first I couldn't
it [ __ ] sucked that was cloudy I
couldn't think then the pain set in on
day two when I hit my head it didn't
hurt it was just like what the [ __ ]
happened I was out I was confused my
body and my brain weren't connecting the
next day it [ __ ] hurt it literally
felt like I smacked my head on the wall
and I did and I took a couple dabs and
it made it hurt worse because it
increased my blood pressure and with
that increased blood pressure I could
just feel the head wound just going and
I could [ __ ] hear it one thing I did
not mention about my brain injury and I
don't like to talk about it it kind of
bothers me and it embarrasses me but I
love you guys and I think you love me
back
so if you hear my voice get weird it's
cuz I'm nervous about this I hear noise
in my head I'm not crazy doctors say
it's okay they know it's their
psychologist notes there
I'm not [ __ ] hiding it there is noise
in my head it sounds like when you go to
Guitar Center and that kid doesn't know
how to play the guitars and he plugs it
in and turns on the app and it goes Kane
that's what it sounds like in my head
sometimes not always but sometimes
sometimes it sounds like you know the
air conditioners just real loud and
you're trying to hear your friend talk
but the air conditioners just going too
loud or maybe the torch in the
background like this
I just hear sound like that let's just
do my head just like that just
constantly in my head and it comes and
goes it's not constant but when it
starts it could last for days
so there's [ __ ] like that there are
effects like that that are still
happening in my head I'm dealing with it
and I'm getting a lot better it gets
better every day I think
but sometimes [ __ ] pops up so sativa
dads were making my head throb and it
was making that noise really loud
Spencer garden of Weeden Spencer and
Maddy shout out to Spence and Maddy I
went to their house and they're like bro
you need some CBD in your life and I was
like give me CBD if that's what you
think I need I will do it and they gave
me a couple dabs of CBD and with the
first dab so I described the pain it
felt like I had a belt around my head or
a vise around my head right around my
temple region and when I took the dabs
of CBD it felt like the belt loosened up
a little it just like ah it just felt so
the CBD was slowly making it loosen up
so I'm gonna read this email then I'm
gonna talk a lot more about my
experience with cannabis and a brain
injury and what I can recommend it for
you but let's get to the email it goes
like this hey Jeff I hope all is well
know Gro talk today a more serious note
I'm hoping you can provide me with some
info or links as to the benefits of
cannabis and TBI TBI is traumatic brain
injury a close friend of mine was in a
motorcycle accident it has a serious TBI
and is being treated at Craig hospital
he would like to start using cannabis
medically for the TBI when he gets
released
I would like to grow some cannabis for
him to use but have no idea what strains
are beneficial for TBI or what method of
ingestion is best thank you for the info
very much appreciated and he signs his
name which I'm not sure if he wants me
to say I'm gonna call you Eminem right
now I just see you have a name for the
podcast Eminem thanks for the great
email thanks for the opportunity to talk
about something close to my heart
through my traumatic brain injury
recovery things changed frequently and
without warning um when I first had the
injury CBD was what I needed
CBD got me through the recovery and back
to my normal self it made it made the
swelling in my brain
calm down and if the swelling didn't go
down organically there was going to have
to be a medical procedure done they
would have changed my life they would
have [ __ ] me up forever that I would
have been angry about I would not be the
same person right now had that had to
happen to me it would have pissed me off
so much it would I would I I don't want
to talk about it
but so it really reduced the swelling it
reduced the inflammation in my brain the
CBD did that for me um once that went
away also let me add that while I was
doing this CB a-- the CBD I was smoking
CBD dabs that's how it was working for
me also let me make a disclaimer just to
cover my ass I'm not a doctor I have no
medical training this is what I have
done myself and it worked
please don't take me as a doctor consult
a doctor if your friend has a traumatic
brain injury go to all of the
neurologist appointments that are
required share with your doctor that you
were using cannabis along with whatever
medicines they give you I am NOT a
doctor please be responsible with your
medical treatment especially with the
brain injury there's not a lot that can
be done but go get checked out because
you can have a stroke from [ __ ] there's
other things that can lead that can come
from this and you need to be paid
attention to by somebody that knows the
long term side effects of a brain injury
so there's one I want to put that out
there I'm not a doctor that's probably
[ __ ] obvious but I have to say that
please be completely respectful to the
medical professionals that are treating
you for this brain injury if you're
gonna do that I just have to say that I
believe it and also I have to say it to
cover my ass so what worked for me to
start with CBD I also added a product
and I don't work for this company I'm
not pitching them I was taking a product
called alpha brain from on it which Joe
Rogan pitches all the time Joe Rogan
eats alpha brain like their candy
I was having problems recalling
information I was having
word-association problems
I was with my mom and there was a banana
on the counter and I wanted the banana
but I kept calling it a burrito and I
said mom will you pass me that burrito
and she looked on the counter and there
was no burrito so she told me there's no
burrito there and I was like offended I
was like I can [ __ ] see the burrito
why are you doing that
give me that burrito and I pointed to it
and then she looked at me a little bit
concerned and she said Jeff do you mean
this banana and I was like [ __ ] I do
mean banana and I was seriously saying
burrito like I meant it like I was mad
at my mom for like treating me like a
fool and that's when she realized you're
broken like you're not kidding cuz she
she thought I was exaggerating she I
told her I hit my head like knocked
myself clean out I don't remember [ __ ]
and she's like whatever boys will be
boys and she I she didn't she didn't
take it as seriously she should have
until that moment and then she turned a
little pale and she realized like my
kids [ __ ] broken that's when people
kind of started taking me a little more
seriously about my broken [ __ ] but I was
having word-association problems I
started taking alpha brain they
recommend two a day I was taking four a
day
because I'm like that first of all if
you say take two it'll fix it I'll take
[ __ ] four I'll be way better that's
just the school I'm from I've won one
rapid duct tape to fix it the whole damn
roll ought to fix it real good is the
way I think so I was taking for alpha
brain and honestly I don't work for that
company this is serious testimony I feel
like it sped me up because of the time
without it and the time with it when I
started taking it [ __ ] started coming
back like routines and patterns and my
daily what I do like I've got dreadlocks
that hang to my butt and I tie them in a
knot on my head in a very particular way
that I've been doing for I've had these
dreads for 13 years I've been tying them
like that since they could reach I
couldn't figure out how to do it after I
hit my head imagine that imagine not
knowing how did whatever basically
something you do every day probably tie
your shoes a lot of us kind of our shoes
[ __ ] lazy tied all mine or lazy
tights or I could slip them on now I'm
trying to think of [ __ ] that you do
every day brush your teeth imagine if
you woke up tomorrow morning and you
just looked at your toothbrush in your
toothpaste and you're like
but sort of it and you're stuck in your
mouth and poked your cheek a couple
times you're like nope that's not what I
do with this you got to think about it
and figure it out I couldn't figure out
how to tie up my own dreadlocks and I've
been doing it twice a day for the past
ten years I couldn't figure out how to
[ __ ] do it the Alpha brain made stuff
like that sort of flowing back into my
brain like I missed an appointment uh
burned from the gross store called me
she's like hey there's somebody here
that says you promised you would meet
them here what's going on I was like
dude I hit my head I don't even remember
making an appointment and then once I
started taking the Alpha brain that
phone call where I made that appointment
and booked that that came back I was
like oh I remember that
so CBD and alpha brain are what put me
on the path to recovery
eventually the CBD stopped working and
it made me lethargic and lazy and I know
that sounds weird
but I'm an energetic peppy guy you could
tell by how much I [ __ ] talk I'm not
lazy I'm usually up first and I'm up
last also I go to bed last and I wake up
first and I've smoked more dabs and I
crush I do a lot of [ __ ] work in a
day but the CBD was making me lazy
so I started shifting myself to high THC
dabs and then the distillate started
coming around this is when like the 98
and 97 and 99 percent THC distillates
started coming around so I started
dabbing that and I found that super high
doses of THC through a DAB would make
the noise in my head stop and it would
make the the uncomfortable out-of-focus
feeling it would make that go away and I
would be able to and I know this sounds
really weird but I would be able to
focus and function a little better when
I smoked a super high THC dad now I can
tell that my brain is getting much
better and much more healthy my thought
patterns are much longer they're like
they used to be again my paragraphs when
I write a podcast or when I write an
email my paragraphs are actually [ __ ]
paragraphs again I have a beginning a
middle and an end when I'm telling a
story now back in the day I would just
ramble but what I'm noticing is now that
my brain is not injured so much I'm gay
really high when I smoke good THC hash
there are days when I can tell my brain
is a little funky and I think you guys
can tell when I record also when I have
a funky brain day people around me can
tell but the people that know me they
know and they know that I'm staying away
from them because I'm having a funky
brain day but on the funky brain days if
I dip high THC shatter into really
limonene dominant Terps my head troubles
just chill the [ __ ] out and I'm really
lucky that I figured that out and it
took talking to a few people with head
injuries and it took a lot of buying and
smoking of a lot of [ __ ] to figure it
out but that's what works for me so I
don't know exactly what's gonna work for
your friend CBD should work in the
beginning to help reduce the
inflammation and sometimes when you've
got a brain injury or any kind of
swelling on the body too much THC will
make your heart race and that'll just
make that bruised area that injured area
it'll just make it throb and swell a
little bit more and it'll make it hurt
make it uncomfortable and that just that
then that gets to your head and then it
makes it hurt more and then it gets to
your head again and it makes it hurt
more and it's a [ __ ] up hour and a
half of being high and an unnecessary
pain so if you're gonna smoke CBD if he
is gonna smoke CBD I would recommend go
really our THC let me restart that whole
[ __ ] statement if your friend with a
traumatic brain injury is going to
choose to smoke THC go light in the
beginning because it may increase the
pain I highly recommend starting off
with CBD if he's been smoking if he's
already a cannabis user if he's already
a medical patient a pothead whatever go
heavy with the CBD treatments and he'll
be just fine see how that does if it's
working
do it go harder if you want to I don't
know how he feels about edibles the
edibles are gonna come on a lot stronger
they're gonna last a lot longer so smoke
a little CBD see how you like it then if
it's working
start doing edibles Oh like I'm saying
eventually maybe that CBD is gonna wear
off as the brain injury progresses this
is what worked for me then shifted THC
when that THC isn't working smoke CBD
again just balance it out you're gonna
have to experiment he's gonna be a
guinea pig because
his motherboard is broken you know what
I mean like he so the computer doesn't
work the way it should anymore so maybe
the things that should work for him
aren't going to and the things that you
would never think would work might
because the computer has been a little
bit reprogrammed so be patient with him
as a friend just be there for him he's
gonna say some weird [ __ ] uh
just listen and just don't scare him
don't point it out cuz it used to [ __ ]
with me when my friends would be like
dude you're actin [ __ ] it would make
me feel weird so just treat him right
make sure the dude is not suicidal is
after a brain injury suicidal thoughts
creep into your head because you have I
try to fight is this the appropriate
word of [ __ ] you feel [ __ ]
because you are [ __ ] your thought
process has been [ __ ] so you feel
[ __ ] and you lose confidence in
yourself and your life isn't what it
used to be and it's hard to deal with
so it puts the thought on the back of
your head if I'm gonna feel like this
every day and be [ __ ] I might just
not have to do this anymore so make sure
your friend doesn't get in that space
I'm lucky that I've got great friends my
friends love me my mom loves me
everybody kept a good eye on me so that
was not even a [ __ ] option for me but
it does happen with a lot of people we
see it in football players uh sports
folks athletes who get traumatic brain
injuries they kill themselves a lot and
it's because your brain is so [ __ ] up
you can't think right the motherboard is
[ __ ] up the CD is skipping you got to
find a way to stop the CD from skipping
and unfortunately some suicide is a way
to do it so that's something you could
really do is just be there for him uh he
said he was in a motorcycle accident
there's probably going to be some PTSD
involved in an accident involved in a
motorcycle involved in the sounds of a
motorcycle so be gentle with that my
traumatic brain injury was caused by a
[ __ ] doorway I was I'm six and a half
feet tall and this old part of town it
was built by old people from different
descent I only know the we have a
derogatory word for them that everybody
just uses here like it's [ __ ] normal
even them they made it up I think people
of slavic descent built small houses in
this old part of town so the doorways
are low and i tried to go through a
slovenian doorway and I'm a german boy
and it didn't [ __ ] fit kapow was
knocked out now when I am at
work in the grow and I'm standing up if
I kneel down to pick something up when I
stand up I stand up really slowly and
after about my fourth day there one of
my co-workers is like bro why do you
stand up like that when you kneel down
and I was like I have a traumatic brain
injury and I'm afraid and he's like oh
[ __ ] yeah it only takes one and they all
realized why now they watch me like they
notice that I'm keeping my head safe cuz
after one I don't I don't want to do it
again and I don't know if my brain could
take it again I might not survive that
[ __ ] also uh when I was younger
I was I've been trained in karate I've
got doesn't matter I've got some karate
experience they've done some tournaments
it was an exhibition team I've kicked
people in the head you guys in
tournaments not in tournaments oh god I
never want to do that again and if I've
ever kicked you in the head I'm [ __ ]
sorry that sucks I can only imagine what
I did to your brain my eggs are
scrambled and I hope I didn't do that to
anybody in a fight in a tournament in
the street protecting myself whatever
it's [ __ ] horrible
you guys don't ever kick anybody in the
head if you have to get in a fight if I
could put them on the ground make them
tap out or something don't hit anybody
in the head that [ __ ] sucks cover your
head wear a helmet
alright I am really rambling I want to
thank everybody that sent me emails I
want to thank God Father cush I want to
give a shout out to Saint skinny and
skinny mom or Saint mom it's clay skinny
mom it's probably a [ __ ] good
compliment for anybody's mom skinny mom
send some love and energy to that whole
family if they need some support also it
sounds like our friend Eminem's buddy
could use a little bit of support so
send some love and light that direction
yeah protect your head you guys [ __ ]
reading this about the traumatic brain
injury really got me riled up and got me
ranting but uh you say you want to grow
some cannabis for him if you need
something with high CBD I can probably
recommend Tora Bora from DNA genetics
Pennywise from TGA sub cool seeds there
are probably tons of other high CBD
strains out there you may be able to
reach out to somebody on the Facebook
community and the Instagram community
and you may be able to find free seeds
that are high in CBD if that's your goal
it may be possible reach out to me if
you can't do it maybe I'll help you out
I'll do it we can also you said what
strains are beneficial and what method
of ingestion is best I would start with
smoking if your friend has been a smoker
before roll in the joint load i'ma ball
if they are if he's been a heavy smoker
before I keep saying he it could be a
sheet let's see a friend of mine was in
an accident and had you said he all
right I just want to make sure I don't
wanna be sexist on accident I'm trying
to be more sensitive ah if they've been
if he's a smoker before give him a DAB
because I think a DAB is good because
you see immediate results like there's
so much it's concentrated so when you
take a dab of it you're gonna get the
results immediately you'll know if it
works you'll know if it doesn't and then
you can go from there quickly with
flowers it's gonna take a few more
inhales depending on the person's
tolerance but I would start with flowers
find out how those work find out what
you need excuse me I've been switch to
concentrates or edibles just to be able
to deliver the medicine more properly
they do make a patch if you are in a
medicinal state it's not you said
treated at a Craig Hospital possibly
Craig Colorado the patches are great the
transdermal patches the CBD patches you
can put those wherever it hurts so that
is very useful I don't know if you could
put them on your head if you've got hair
but maybe on your lower neck something
like that would work for you but you got
to start out with smoking smoking works
right away and also it's the easiest to
shake off if you eat edibles it's gonna
last a long time if you get it if you
take a DAB it's gonna last a while if
you take one or two puffs off a pipe and
it goes the wrong way it's not gonna
take a long time to get that out of you
a couple of peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches maybe something to drink you
should be
fine pretty soon wouldn't be too
uncomfortable for most people all right
Eminem I hope I was able to help you out
I hope you're able to get started
growing for your friend like I said if
you need help finding CBD seeds let me
know I know a few people that may be
able to donate a 10 pack of seeds to you
just to get you started
sounds like ah your friend needs some
help hey I want to give you a shout-out
for reaching out to me to help your
friend that's some good French [ __ ] so
what we need more friends like that I
hope everything goes well with your
friend I hope you recover as well from
the traumatic brain injury if you want
more interaction about this TBI if you'd
like to talk to me more about it just
because I've been there I guess I'm not
a doctor but I've done it so if you or
your friend mm-hmm
excuse me if your friend would like to
reach out talk to me about it I'm here I
like sharing my story I'm passionate
about it so don't be shy
so shots everybody who sent me an email
I got super rambling on this episode so
I want to thank everybody for listening
if you'd like to send me an email to be
read on a future episode its grow from
your heart at hotmail.com you can also
find me on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast
you can also find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast you guys I'm gonna wrap up this
podcast I would love it if you would go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the girl from your heart podcast
click on the podcast there's a little
section that says ratings and reviews I
would like it if you type in a review
let me know what you think about the
podcast I will reveal read that's hard
as [ __ ] to say I will read your review
there we go I will read your review on a
future episode also everybody has given
me a five star review so far click on
the amount of stars you feel I deserve
and I would appreciate it that's all
I've got free this week ladies and
gentlemen don't forget to check out
patreon.com/crashcourse
[Music]
Oh
looking for a sharpening some de rich
[Music]
don't know where just don't you know
they made
[Music]
true
around some
[Music]
but you know each arts this place beside
you can say that you need
[Music]
it's true you can see that is true you
can see
[Music]
you