[Music]
yeah y'all check it
out10 a big disaster in July bombs are
going off we whip the batter till it's
dry I love my butter on another matter
cuz the tip the da tends to chip the
shatter in my eye mic I'm set to Scorch
get the Dome as well cuz I'm a vector
torch and the microphones a nail I'm the
truth all you Liars go to hell every
time I grab the mic it's like a giant
showing tell we've been doing this since
way back I used to a until I blaz them
my great slack went to college and
acknowledged that I hated that route so
I backed out and I doubt I'll ever make
it back I see the way you act jealous
crap something's fishy here I think I
smell a rap this is our house but we
ain't got to tell him that let's leave
him at the front door yelling at the
welcome come on everybody get another da
same R slightly different from the last
track a million songs about we but where
the Dabs at you don't like my dabbing
songs you can kiss my ass crack come on
everybody drop another huge bomb 420
game 710 it's time to move on upgrade
your tolerance downside your new bomb
favorite way to
[Music]
medicate what's up ladies and gentlemen
what's up ladies and gentlemen big shout
out to task Rock for letting me play
some uh music you're listening to task
Rock tnl lus no task and Linus tnl the
movement sorry I'm a little distracted
I'm sitting here trying to open this
edible that I bought I'm trying to eat a
mountain medicine 350 Mig
active cannabis delightful chocolate
peanut butter bar Mountain medicine get
your goat on medical marijuana edible uh
the new rules say that these packages
have to be childproof and God
damn on the microphone with me is my
buddy Adam Gaskins he's hanging out
we're uh we're going to do just kind of
a fun episode today I got a couple
things to talk about nothing super uh
super planned out say what's up bro
what's up uh thanks for coming man
thanks for coming hey no problem so I'm
sitting here watching him struggle with
this packaging and he's he's bit at it
it he's starting to grab instruments and
trying to like cut it open he's got a
pair of scissors probably 20 are there
scissors over there right over there
behind you yeah yeah well that thanks
dude that reminds me part of our uh talk
we may talk if I even get into it I'm
going to eat this edible this is 350
milligrams welcome to episode number 22
of the igro culture podcast of course
I'm Rost Jeff you're joining us on
another episode uh we'll do sponsors in
just a second uh big shout out to Adam
for coming big shout out to my friend
that helped me trim tonight if you're
listening to the podcast uh short person
with dreadlocks you helped out a lot Sav
me a lot of time so I just dropped a
bunch of weed into this edible I just
picked up scissors that we were using to
trim to open this package uh they're
package compliant dude uh this company
uh there's an expiration date on here
there's a barcode on here there's a ma
on date couldn't get into that and
inside yeah inside of here uh this is
like bulletproof Kevlar fireproof
bombproof plastic the it took uh Fisker
scissors to get through this [ __ ] and
they struggled a little bit
fiskers are your lawn scissors just to
let you know now fiskers are the [ __ ]
Diamond tip DM scissors bro so uh I'm
going to do a read an ad for a sponsor
while I struggle to get this open right
quick uh this podcast is brought to you
by Nature's green remedies.com visit our
friends Nature's green remedies.com for
Gage green genetics L Plato lab Sin City
uh rare dankness smile high can Aventure
iy genetics and many many more trusted
Brands those guys were at the Cannabis
Cup this weekend I hope they had fun I
saw a whole bunch of rain I hope you're
safe drop that music town just a little
bit that's some task Rock in the
background uh yeah make sure you check
out natur's green remedies.com if you
buy uh they change their special often
right now they have a special running if
you buy a certain amount of IE genetics
you will get a certain amount for free I
don't remember exactly what the special
is it changes so frequently I'm not
going to quoted on the show the code
word we gave out uh does expire the 31st
of this month it will put out a new one
at the next podcast the start of August
so pay attention for that we got a
really special deal coming up for the
podcast listeners on episode number 25
so so you actually may have to listen to
episodes 22 23 24 and 25 to put stuff
together to have an answer to kind of a
puzzle and if you have that answer to
the puzzle there will be prizes and
special offers for those so keep
listening to the podcast when episode 25
comes up we'll let you know what's going
on and uh it may work out for you um I'm
strugg struggling with this [ __ ]
package I got it mostly open and now I'm
struggling with not shoving it into my
face in the middle of a commercial I
want to get these done and then we'll go
for it uh this podcast is also brought
to you by hyro indoor growing supplies
high gr indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 8271 Beach Street Unit F
or stop by the new PUO location on 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado check
out H grow for competitive pricing and a
great selection on indoor growing
supplies make sure you check out www.hr
denver.com
hro denver.com for current store hours
and special sales also they're running a
special I don't have the paper in front
of me it is
$550 for for one tote of soil I talked
about this last week a tote of soil
that's if you pick it up at the store
it's
$550 it comes in one bag it's Roots
organic soil it's good [ __ ] uh how much
is a tote that is approximately in my
measurements I think that is about 28 or
uh is about 48 to 50 7 gallon pots so
you can run an eight light setup pretty
decently with this one package of soil
if you need it delivered it is $600 it
comes on a FedEx truck to your house
so it's not like the hydro shop is
showing up with a truck or anything it's
actually FedEx it looks like you got a
package that's [ __ ] huge uh that's
going to be a lot of weight so hopefully
they can haul it right into your garden
area or something you're not going to
have to deal with moving that so check
out our good friends at hyro uh I want
to give a huge shout out to Jesse uh and
Bernadet uh they got married this
weekend burn actually works at hygro so
that's what made me think about it they
got married they threw an awesome party
just want to give them a quick shout out
of congratulations at the start of the
show we're going to talk a little more
about that in a few minutes here you
look like you got something to say bro
no I was just going to say
congratulations yeah do their wedding
was awesome so uh uh oil slick is next
shout out to oil slick oil Slick's a
loyal sponsor they've been a longtime
sponsor uh I use an oil slick product
every day every day there's almost one
in every room of my house I think one of
the most used products in this house uh
carb caps uh dabbers oil slick pads uh
and a rig and a torch I need a torch
sponsor vector Vector torches come hit
me up or somebody's got another email
for me because this one's starting to
lose its luster email company wants to
sponsor us let me know let's review your
product and [ __ ] and we'll shout you out
on the show all the time enough
pandering uh oil slake shout out to our
friends at oil slake Oil sck Tools to
help you concentrate check out oilslick
pad.com for more information uh dude go
find our friends oil slick on Twitter
seriously I say that every time but go
find them uh they're at oil slick pad uh
send them a tweet and let them know that
you're listening to the igro culture
podcast let them know you heard this ad
and that my ad advertising is effective
let them know that you're paying
attention and that it's working for them
I know right now you're probably in the
garden you could be driving in the car
maybe you're on a treadmill uh what do
you do when you're listening to the
podcast uh usually game I mean while
you're playing video games slow game
okay so then you don't have your hands
available to go and tweet me something
right no try to remember it later guys
just just tweet us I I know I ask for a
lot but that's all I want is a simple
tweet come on man just pay attention I'm
kidding well oil slick just I mean dude
they're they're constantly coming up
with good Twitter pictures just alone I
mean I follow them and if you're dabbing
uh the reason I have them as a sponsor
is because I use their stuff because
it's necessity it's useful if you're
dabbing you need some oil s products you
need something to keep your hash in it
if you're smoking the live resin that
we've got now you don't want to carry it
around in parchment paper you want your
live resin to be kept in like a nice
smooth looking oil slick container my
red golden green rosta colored oil slick
container on the table with my oil slick
pads it just looks classic they got they
got these things here with like the
magnetic sides too where you can just
put your slab in I'm going to have to
[ __ ] Google that cuz I'm not sure if
that's actually their product or if
somebody's making that uh modified
version cuz I can't find it on their
website but hey oil if you're listening
no no no we're going to have to find out
cuz that's a good idea you guys if you
have a miniature size slab you can take
two of these uh oil slick uh uh mini
pads slick pad Minis and you can rubber
band them together with your slab in the
middle or you can find other ways to
stick them together and just have your
slab right in the middle make it easily
accessible uh they're great things I
actually use it almost as a uh I wipe my
Dabber off on it that's why it's all
sticky on this Edge near me uh so I take
another dab wipe it off on there my next
dab doesn't have residue of my last dab
on there every dab is fresh and not only
that but I've I've you know I've seen
you use them to set pipes down on Just
for I usually try to have it like a
coaster because the table's wood and I
think it's just a little better than
[ __ ] dropping my glass onto the table
have that little pad underneath it not
all the glass is heavy and thick right
and my domes for my D rigs I know I
don't there's one D rig on the table now
that the Dome sits on there because you
leave uh I I made an ad that said stop
leaving sticky rings on your mom's table
because everybody's table got those
little Rings you can tell who's a Dabber
and who tries to hide it yeah yeah so
that's a huge shout out to our friends
at oil slick uh man oil Slick's been a
huge sponsor I totally represent that
[ __ ] all day long so thanks guys thanks
for sponsoring us uh seriously go to
their website uh did I say it already
where is it written it's on here um
oilslick pad.com there we go yeah go
there uh I also have to give one more ad
shout out to tree Thugger dcom this
episode is brought to you in part by
tree Thugger dcom uh live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree
thug.com for concert Festival news and
reviews www.re Thugger
docomo this is the revolution this is
the revolution well I just got seven
Facebook messages in a
row I guess the internet's back huh I
think uh your phone was not working
earlier because the internet was down I
think that's what the problem was
correct yes the internet is back on yay
we might be able to read some news since
the internet's back I wasn't able to
research much news Because the Internet
Was crooked but uh so we got the ads out
of the way much respect to all those
sponsors I do want to give a big shout
out to our friends at natural Mystic
cannabis caregivers and Colorado Springs
uh Shelly you're awesome uh big digital
hug to you I'm not sure if you get to
listen to the show but either way I'm
sending you out a big digital thoughtful
hug also Joey what's up bro thanks for
uh that clone I don't know if I should
say that on the show he didn't give me a
clone uh but man thanks for that clone I
really needed that that helps me out in
a big big way huge Shout to Natural
Mystic cannabis caregivers uh I think
that's all the ads I'm responsible for
this week uh I've got this thing open uh
let's eat an edible this is where we all
started 10 minutes
ago uh this is 6 o 168 gram of chocolate
and peanut butter is what it looks like
to me 350 milligram active cannabis
medicinal product Keep Out Of Reach of
children uh the packaging is quite fancy
I'm going to read you the back just cuz
this is a really they did a hell of a
good job on the packaging this is the
outer box uh this product is infused
with medical marijuana and was provided
without regul regulatory oversight for
health safety or efficacy and there may
be health risks associated with the
consumption of the product keep out of
the reach of children processed in a
facility that make may contain nuts I
hope so there's peanut butter in it uh
there may be additional health risks
associated with the consumption of this
product for women who are pregnant
breastfeeding or planning on becoming
pregnant it's pretty much anyone at
Pueblo this product is unlawful outside
the state of Colorado the intoxicating
effects of this product may be delayed
by two or more hours do not drive a
motor vehicle or operate heavy machinery
while using medical marijuana uh it's
got a phone number and an OPC license
like it should uh the ingredients uh
caught my attention eggs flour baking
soda salt cocoa powder I'm reading all
the whole [ __ ] rapper I now but I've
got a point uh peanut butter butter
powdered sugar chocolate hash butter uh
0.5 G cannabis weight .5 gram dosage 50
milligram so this is supposed to be a s
dose uh edible here is what they're they
have intended I'm going to eat the whole
damn thing is what I have planned right
now I've got a napkin I got a drink I
think this is going to go down well
what's got my attention is it lists
other ingredients it has p uh 51.9% k
38.1% n uh 11 point Sorry I should back
up nitrogen phosphorus uh I did them in
the wrong order but that's you know what
I mean now those are theut used in the
plant uh phosphorus potassium and
nitrogen uh calcium magnesium sulfur I
don't know what that one means I should
but I'm I don't know the table of
el yeah you can't do it either the table
of elements I the periodic table of
elements I couldn't say it I was reading
these F sugar malti extract so they list
also what what it was grown with and on
the bottom here organic neem oil uh so
they also list some of the stuff that
was used to treat the
plants that's pretty interesting that
they list that on there so I know almost
everything that went into this product
that I'm going to eat which is kind of
kind of nice to know so let's get down
to the [ __ ] point I'm going to put
the edible in my mouth I'm going to turn
up some task Rock so you don't have to
hear me chewing it stinks like it uh I
bit it open and as soon as my mouth my
teeth broke the seal it smelled like uh
old school pot food it really smells
like cannabis like it's in a smellproof
vacuum sealed wrapper I can't tear this
wrapper I'm trying to open it up a
little more to slide this out easily and
[ __ ] won't rip it's bullet you can
make parachutes out of this [ __ ]
Greenhouse
material all right I'm almost to the
first bite oh man it's it's
green holy
crap
so 350 it's going to have 350 milligram
I can taste all 350 it's delicious yeah
it's uh chocolatey and peanut buttery so
is it is it almost like an ice cream
type of
bar or does it have a softer it's like
texture you know it's not like hard the
top layer is straight creamy peanut
butter the bottom layer is soft it's
like a almost a soggy brownie but better
all righty I don't know what that
texture is it's almost a fudge like a
nougat no it's harder than that okay I
want to give you some but I want to eat
the whole thing no no no no you you eat
it I want to [ __ ] experience this as
I said I think they have these down here
at the shop and speaking of
uh it's a peanut butter bar so whatever
they make a peanut Mystic is dude p is a
step their game up because you know
their Bud down
there I feel like driving to Springs
yeah we went to Natural Mystic cannabis
caregivers to uh pick up some shatter
because we were low on shatter and we
were just waiting for things to happen
and I took Adam Adam doesn't get to go
to a lot of dispensaries I took Adam
with me uh he's been shopping at pelo
shops uh so natural myy cannabis
caregivers ble your mind huh it's yeah
uh their Bud quality they were big hard
nuggets of joy you know like they love
those plants there it wasn't oh let's
see how quickly we can turn this out uh
for number one I think it was still only
medical right yes that shop is only
medical okay so that's that's one of the
you know one of the reasons but then
again there's still medical shops that
don't give a damn this is a lot of
chocolate and peanut butter if you're
like uh if you're actually sick and have
like cancer or something I don't know
that this I'm not knocking the product
it's [ __ ] delicious I get acne from
chocolate so this would would break out
in it like while you're eating it you
get zits it's Rich this is I had a bag
of M&amp;M the other day it's supposed to be
seven Doses and if that's supposed to be
seven doses I'm a good four doses in by
now yeah yeah and see uh that last drink
that I bought that's what I thought too
you know I was like I was like I marked
lines on it and I was like and then I
was down to here and I was like oh well
you know here you go so you're talking
about the chai High uh it wasn't a chai
High it may have been that chai high was
that what it was called you showed me
the bottle in a picture yeah I don't
even remember it was so worthless to me
our little trimmer friend that was here
earlier uhhuh uh who used to work at a
shop she said she used to drink those
and sometimes uh it would wreck her and
sometimes it wouldn't do anything to her
she said and it may have been that's
what she was saying the lady at the shop
she said next time try a a fruit flavor
and that's what I wanted I wanted they
had like an apple cider type oh and I
was yeah I was like yeah that's me dude
all day um Southern boy and
they went all they had was some
cappuccino and like I said it was like
water down Yoo dude there was no
cannabis at all like I just when he said
water down Yoo did anybody else think of
the Beasty Boys song uh Professor booty
is a song yeah if anybody else knows
what I'm talking about tweet me about it
that'd be really cool just tweet me hash
Professor booty at ulture I'll send you
stickers yeah I'll send you an i genetic
sticker or two yeah uh I just like the
interaction I'm begging for
attention um this thing's delicious it
reminds me of remember the Little Debbie
nutty bars oh yeah it tastes like or a
peanut butter
bar I buy those for the kids dude I'm
I'm with you one remember those we had
week it's better a hippie made this I
would bet a hippie made this this is one
of those snacks uh so I was going to buy
another brand because they're delicious
um I'm reluctant to say the brand I was
opting to buy that I chose this over I
was going I asked for a monkey bar
because the monkey bars I love a monkey
bar dude I love from Incredibles so
shout out Incredibles the monkey bar is
delicious I was going to buy one of
those and the girl that works at the
lady that works at the dispensary is a
friend of mine and also a patient she's
a cancer survivor and she uses these
products and she said I know you like
The Incredibles they're 100 Mig they're
$10 this mountain medicine peanut butter
bar is
$11 and it's got 350 milligram so it's
like three and a half of those for a
dollar more and uh you know the
businessman in me didn't take a lot of
convincing to say it's three for one I'm
going to do that and I just handed her
money and thanked her for being such a
great person yeah uh the flavor so far I
am happy with my decision that's cool uh
I I know that I'm going to be wrecked
yeah so we better get anything out of
the way that we need to handle you sure
you want to eat all of it I'm going to
eat all of it all right all right be a
man that's what I'm yeah that's what I'm
saying because you don't know high five
and everything we don't know if it got
melted in all 350 brand to this bite and
all 350 Brandy here as you're saying
there's it's it's almost like a
different kind of chocolate I would
almost kind of imagine that it's you see
how right there there's like a big
splatch of like that's like uh a
chocolate chip or something inside of
some peanut butter batter stuff it's got
the works dude it's a layer of uh semi
dark chocolate over peanut butter with
this peanut butter chocolate uh it's a
thick mousse a light fudge sort of a
texture all right it's uh I can eat it
quickly enough it does it's not so
peanut buttery that I'm stuck while I'm
trying to talk but it does take a little
effort to clean up the face while you're
grubbing it and in the summer time eat
this in the air conditioner don't try to
take this out anywhere she told you to
kind of put it in the fridge like for 5
or 10 minutes beforehand or she said
actually put it in the microwave or warm
it up first oh yeah she did no this
would have been uh that I don't know
that i' recomend this would just be a
puddle she didn't say long she said like
1 second two seconds you know but I'm
take a couple more bites out I think
maybe uh just putting in the
refrigerator would be even better just
was there a strain natural Mystic
cannabis caregivers that got your
attention cuz they had some great
looking herbs I smelled a couple of them
uh there was only one of them that I
really knew what the smell was so you
know that was my only com comparison uh
they had Harlequin there that was I I
haven't smelled that yet and it was wow
it was really potent uh what was the
what was the other one that we got uh or
that you got that day that they had the
strain there the torab Bora no no not
the Tor Bora the was it the Super Lemon
Haze no I can't remember which was they
had one that just stunk to high hell and
it was great yeah yeah yeah that's
that's the one I'm talking about the one
where it's that's what we got some of
the Shadow oh the guava yeah the guava
guava that really impressed me dude that
she opened the jar and it was like a
punch in the face before she handed it
to me and I mean like I said there was
no small nugs in the jar and everything
was Frosty everything was right to that
point where I feel like I could have
brought it home and kept it in my jar
for a couple days and it would have been
like you know I could have judged where
how dry
we tend to like Adam tends to like his
weed a little crispier than most folk
Adam likes it a little drier we like uh
so we'll cure it perfectly and then give
it to Adam to destroy for us yeah
exactly but still it's it's nice to have
that option instead of where I'm from
It's Always dry so you know you get
something wet you're like what is this
I'm all in now I just put the rest of
this thing in my mouth up I wasn't
[ __ ] about that final thing filled
with butter cuz that last bite tastes
like butter not even like chocolate or
pie no like butter oh just butter huh
Pauline made that huh yeah um so I've
never had a chance to say this on like a
public platform but [ __ ] Paul
aine hey here here um now [ __ ] her
before her racism but extra [ __ ] her for
her
racism Sor I'm trying to get this
chocolate peanut butter my mouth kind
of one time uh so I had an Italian
girlfriend and we would watch Jada de
laus and Paul Adine back toback and I
think Alton Brown was on in the mix uh
sorry I'm wiping my face I got CH
[ __ ] chocolate peanut butter butter
all over the place chocolate peanut
butter butter it's got I could feel the
butter on my lips they're like it tastes
like movie theater popcorn in that last
bite so Pauline one day she's making a
meal and she's like this meal got a
little something for everybody well
except the vegetarians but screw them
they can go outside and eat
grass uh [ __ ] you Pauline I'm going to
go outside and eat grass while your
show's on and never watch your [ __ ]
show again I would go outside eat no I'm
not going to go down that road in your
podcast what I do all right I'm going to
go outside and smoke grass until
paladine's over I've never really done a
[ __ ] you on the show I feel almost a
little bad now but [ __ ] you badine you
suck you're racist you're [ __ ] rude
to vegetarians um so I do I I I sent her
a letter I was like I will go outside
and eat grass until J deenus comes back
on yeah didn't you um have a correction
or something that you need okay if you
want to get to the point the fun banter
I didn't no that's cool whatever Adam
you can drive the podcast today bro hey
I wasn't trying to drive the podcast I
correction you're right you're totally
right uh I in edible and you're going to
have to keep me on track you're going to
have to do that guys we've been smoking
live resin yeah uh and unicorn
hash uh and butt naked also known as
bare naked depends on where you are uh
if you don't know about the Unicorn hash
the live resin or the butt naked you
don't even know bro the love resin the
love resin that's it you heard all that
[ __ ] here first on the Agro culture
podcast remember it you're going to ask
questions later yep we've got answers a
correction I did an episode about veg
growth it's at some point in the episode
I said keep your veg plants on 1212
don't [ __ ] do that I [ __ ] up I said
something wrong this is me being a man
and telling you I [ __ ] said that
wrong I'm correcting myself right now on
the air where I have the chance I
apologize I am the captain of this ship
and I almost drove it into the wall I
and see now I feel kind of like an
[ __ ] because I forgot it was about
that I thought it was something else
because I thought you corrected about
that last week or the last podcast
episode you did so uh no that was
correcting my now you're pointing out
that I [ __ ] up twice dude oh my god
dude
just edit this [ __ ] out no I'm Le we're
awesome we're awesome uh no uh I did I
that's why I said I'm being a man about
it I could just be all no [ __ ] that
we'll just keep talking like that didn't
happen no we got to correct it because
we're I'm the captain of this [ __ ]
pirate ship right here yeah this is my
ship that I'm driving and I got to guide
you guys into the right way or we're all
going to fail together and I want you to
win is why I'm doing a show I'm trying
to improve your growing no [ __ ] it up
sorry I'm trying to adjust the music
task got a little loud for me but I want
to make her growing better so yeah my
first mistake was I don't even know if I
said it on the podcast or in a personal
conversation but I mentioned the red
light spectrum and I got it totally
backwards and then my second mistake was
saying to keep your vegging plants on
1212 do not do this keep your vegging
plants on at least 18 hours of at least
16 hours of light uh 18 would be better
24 is what I
do to be perfectly fair you didn't say
it like uh by the way put your plants no
it was at the end of your sentence at
the end of your lesson at the end of
your ramble of
how lights work so it's probably high
yeah yeah you were definitely back from
probably been doing it doing a show for
an hour so excuse me I apologize but I
admit it I [ __ ] up and I'm driving
this boat I'm just telling you from a
listener's point of view tighten your
[ __ ] up I'll be buying more of these
Edibles all right that's so good dude
I've got this chocolate peanut chocolate
peanut butter is a potheads treat in my
mind and I've got it in my mouth and it
tastes so good I'm a peanut butter fudge
dude from Sonic the song that's popping
up right now is called hashtag and you
can't get enough though it's perfect cuz
is chocolate peanut butter and you can't
get enough though yeah let me know
because I like I said I would have
definitely been like yo 11 bucks you'll
be over yeah I know you'll see what
happens all right so we did a
correction I ate the edible God damn
it's good we should talk about Jesse's
wedding reception I want to give a big
shout out to uh Jesse and burn of course
uh Mr wit I got to meet Jesse's father
that's a character there yeah that guy
is awesome
he can party harder than you and me and
then if we cloned each of us and set
them next to
us he would win the [ __ ] out he would
out dab us he would out whisky us and
then he would look at us and be like why
are you guys so [ __ ] up yeah yeah he
is a professional and he's a man to the
man's man World he's a champ so shout
out dud was great meeting you I think he
listens to the show so big handshake Mr
wit that wedding reception was great the
bride looked beautiful the groom uh well
he was pretty awesome until about
halfway through the night he decided to
wear a young lady's wife beater for the
rest of the evening uh each nipple stuck
out just a little bit and he's quite a
hairy man so it looked great in the
beard uh you looked great through the uh
the start of the night bro and then once
you Dawn to the wife beater I threw up
in my mouth a little bit I think I just
did just hearing about it uh shout out
to the Garden of Weeden crew Everybody
showed up looking classy as a
[ __ ] and I think if you say
classy as [ __ ] that describes him
perfectly Spence looked sharp as [ __ ]
Maddie has always looked beautiful big
Mike was [ __ ] dressed to the nines uh
Joe even brought a skateboard to skate
in this cool place and then of course my
my homie sloppy look sharp as hell Fong
we wish you were there bro I don't know
if you listen to the podcast Fong is out
of town we miss you Fong that's a somber
note right there but at the wedding
reception I didn't go to the actual
wedding uh the pothead crew as I was
calling us wasn't uh we chose to just go
to the after there was like a wedding
and then a reception and then kind of an
after party that started about 8:30 uh
once the kids bailed out uh we set up a
dab bar and uh Spence from the garden of
Weeden and myself with also the help of
Maddie and if I missed anybody The
Garden of Weeden list and people I'm
sorry I'm trying to do a podcast I got
like 9,000 thoughts in my head at once I
don't mean to miss anybody I love all
you guys at the Garden of Weeden sarakin
Nana included and even honey uh so
Spence and uh Maddie and I were pretty
much giving out dabs to the entire
wedding party that was over 21 and stuck
around after the uh the old folks and
the children left [ __ ] some of the old
folks got down better than the
youngsters but uh D we had an enail we
had a regular rig and we couldn't keep
up with the dabs that people were
wanting because uh Jesse handed me his
live resin uh he gave me a nice chunk of
live resin to dab out the wedding party
and he said guard this with your life so
uh it was my job I volunteered to go
there and be the dab tender so we set up
a little dab bar and I needed help
better yeah yeah right yeah and he's
like I know you'll [ __ ] give out good
dabs and I know you how to know how to
manage dabs so dishing out dabs I'm
getting buzzed I think from that my had
just swirled that was pretty awesome
we'll take a dab here in just a minute
too we'll slowly Watch Jeff degrade I'll
start melting here if anybody's got that
weed if you've seen that commercial that
that girl smoked and she [ __ ] melts
into the couch and becomes like Play-Doh
if you have any of that weed Andor hash
hit me up at I gr culture on Twitter
they're lying to you dude they've been
lying to you that was photosho they
don't have she photoshopped that chick
yeah yeah it was all photo I want some
of that weed dude that looks like some
great [ __ ] it's that pink stuff in that
in
that so I think we dished out probably 7
to 10 g a live resin last night to the
wedding party some people kept coming
back and coming back we uh we probably
broke the dab record for peblo County in
one building at one time with a certain
amount of people I don't know what the
[ __ ] the logistics were but dude we
we won I'm guessing go team uh on an
average day and people are going to [ __ ]
their pants I take 25 dabs no problem on
an average day uh maybe 30 or 40 on a
heavy dab day uh I've gone to secret
cups and we've had the judge 42 samples
and I've done those all in one day and
was okay and went back for seconds on a
couple so I'm I'm in the 25 to 50 dabs
per day range which I don't know if
that's sounds like a lot um and when you
see the size of dabs he does it is a lot
so and what's odd is I'll uh I'll wake
up and I'll rock for a few hours before
I take a dab I try to do a couple things
like I try to get food and water in my
body and [ __ ] check my EMA get too
dabed 7:00 at night and you yeah I
haven't taken a dab yet because well if
you take that if you get up a reasonable
time somewhere between 800 and 10 you
know do your day get some food in you
get functional get your blood moving and
don't take a dab till 710 in the
afternoon or in the evening you get
[ __ ] higher than you would so yeah
but what I was going to say is I wait
until like 6 or s or 4:20 lately it's
been too hot to get dabbed out all day
so you got to wait until [ __ ] 6:00
and the Sun starts going down and by 9:
you get dabbed the [ __ ] out then I'll
take [ __ ] seven dabs per hour I'll
sit down and take six dabs in succession
you know in 20 or 30 minutes yeah you're
shaking your head because I ruin you
doing it right yeah I just uh I feel bad
for you you know I feel bad for your
lungs that's all you know I'm sitting
here shaking my head think imagine if I
was doing bong hits of flower that much
though and see that but that's what I'm
thinking though is you know I smoke
flour most of the time so it's not
sitting there smoking you know 10 bong
hits of flour where if I'm just sitting
there smoking by myself it's two then
another four or five hours later two
more you know know uh so I get what
you're saying I I go slower with the
dabs than I do with the flower
so less uh your lungs probably uh your
lungs are like any anything I think I'm
a smoker too so they've got a certain
amount of inhales and exhales your lungs
are going to give you before they start
to burn out just like any sort of
equipment or [ __ ] device or moving
anything that moves is going to break
eventually MH and uh if I've only got 72
billion ins and outs I'd rather spend
half of those on a dab than 34s of them
trying to smoke herb maybe I should just
get half of those on oxygen at least
half but you know what I mean I'm trying
to hey no I get what you're saying and
and you know it it's understandable my
vapor to smoke ratio hey tonight would
have been the night that we would have
done that event at the uh the Mary Janes
and at the hook bar I want to give an
apology to everybody that was excited
about that I myself was excited me too
there were some uh bureaucracy
discrepancies and some stuff that
happened and I'm no longer a member of
the uh citizens for the responsible
regulation of cannabis I don't know if
that even exists anymore to tell you the
truth backed out of that uh just going
to stick with being a breeder and a
podcast host and doing what I know I'm
good at um I don't like the I used to go
to City Council meetings and stuff when
I was with another dispensary group I
don't like being in that realm that's a
little uncomfortable to me uh I don't
know I'd rather just kind of it's one
thing going there when you have to you
know uh but when you know you're just
voluntar you voluntarily going there and
it still feels like Court yeah you what
I mean once you've been to court in the
courtroom type building it still feels
like court and I don't just they're
judging you oh completely yeah and they
don't I don't feel I backed out of going
to those meetings because I felt like I
was a hindrance to the group because I'm
just a cliche looking pod and I didn't
speak anyway we had spokespeople for the
group so I just quit going and you want
to know the worst thing that I think
about courtrooms is can't wear the hat
no hat yeah so you know your long hair
you can't hide it from anyone oh I can't
hide I can't hide my dreadlocks anyway
um there's no hiding these dreads you
know what yeah I was talking about the
wedding reception and uh we got way
sidetracked but that's cool we're just
having a fun episode this time Sid track
dab track we're just having a fun
episode we're not going to try to do a
whole bunch of stuff I may tell you how
I dry trimmed some of this weed maybe uh
I'm just going to tease about that uh
the wedding was awesome uh I saw a lot
of people that I haven't seen in a long
time uh shout out to bullheaded shout
out to uh KH KH performed without booger
I don't know why booger didn't show up
but he still killed it by
himself um uh despicable dialects
wrapped who else performed I know I'm
going to miss somebody uh Jesse wit
grabbed a microphone and wrapped that
was pretty
entertaining uh yeah a lot of people did
a lot of cool things and it was a great
time I'm going to put in the request for
next growth lesson then going down
freestyle uh oh the music's fading out
get the music back let's get it going
again all right yeah uh there it is see
yeah the wedding was awesome it went off
that a hitch everything was fun
everybody got home safely we made sure
everybody got home safe cuz they got
kind of silly some people got a little
bit goofy just want to make sure to give
shout outs to the Garden of Weeden crew
for running the dab bar like a champ
shout outs to those guys for getting
married we'll get off the topic of them
getting married cuz I don't have a lot
more left to say about it live resin I
keep talking about live resin
everybody's tweeting me messaging me
what is it WTF live resin what the [ __ ]
it tastes great it tastes great right
less feeling uh it's like a a very
light like love resin I'm going to take
a dab love resin it's funny uh I told I
text I sent Adam a text M message saying
hey bro I got some love resin what I
actually meant to say was live resin and
so he's been laughing at that ever since
that's what it is uh I'm going to claim
take a pretty chunky dab of some live
resin right now I've got some friends
that were kind enough to gift me a
little bit of live resin super
awesome uh I heat the torch or heat the
nail a little bit less heat and make
sure to use the carb cap with a live
resin I don't want to burn it up because
it's a lot more turpy it's more
terpenoids if you know about tpps that's
what mostly gives you the flavor they're
flavonoids and paleet that uh contribute
to that but mostly uh it's the
terpenoids that you want to taste and
it's very
clean yeah you can see the cleanliness
and the clarity in the hash I think I
might have talked about it a little on
the show here we go doing a
dab
yeah that was a dab of live resin here
take that part
take the
torch oh my goodness shout out to task
Rock for making super awesome nails and
carb caps uh Highly Educated is not a
sponsor of the show but they should be
one day they will be I just got to uh
tasing I've been talking uh shout out to
uh Highly Educated sorry I just took a
mean dab so words are complicated right
now I'm trying to say that you can pick
up Highly Educated products he did a
little more bro sorry I don't even have
your daad ready I'm over here rambling
uh you can pick up Highly Educated
products at aqualab technologies.com I
recommend uh if you've got a rig with an
18 or 14 mm mail joint sticking out of
it I recommend the Dual Tha nail that's
probably the way to go uh there it's
going to fit if you've got a 10 mm there
is a 10 mm domeless that works perfectly
as well I'm catching my breath get
yourself a carb cap carb caps are the
new [ __ ] and they're
awesome uh you you don't have to heat
your nail as hot you start you drop your
dab in there you let it puddle up a
little bit you cover it with the carb
cap and it requires less heat so you
choke less and your dab tastes a little
bit better you'll need a little more
Heat next time bro that wasn't too bad
you got to dab but a little more heat
will be better for you try not to heat
it up because of what you just said yeah
there's that you'll find it I usually
heat it I counted the T I usually heat
it for you when you're here but uh once
your nail gets a little bit older you'll
need to give it a little bit more heat
is something that you guys will learn
once it starts getting too uh too out
it's time to replace it by to tell you
the
truth shout out to task I'm giving him a
big old ad he doesn't even sponsor the
show he's just task is a badass he's a
he's a Pioneer for the community he's
done a lot of [ __ ] he's a hell of a
rapper who we're listening to in the
background also so multitasker
multifaceted ingenius man entrepreneur
live resin you ready for this live resin
uh pretty
much uh take a plant that is growing
shop it down at Harvest time it's been
flushed you know you've been flushing
for 10 or 14 days chop it down it's
harvest time uh maybe a couple of days
ago you went through and pull off all
the big fan leaves all right uh if not
uh hang the plant upside down and take
off all the fan leaves right now let it
dry for like and you know some guys are
leaving the fan leaves on I should
mention that some guys leave the fan
leaves on especially Frosty strands uh
let it dry up for like 3 to four hours
then chop it up into Buds and other guys
are this is one method I've seen and it
varies a little bit but this is
basically it chop the buds off the
sticks so you just have the buds and
leaves you don't have all the stems so
now you got like a [ __ ] 5 gallon
bucket or so whatever uh put that in a
freezer if you need to use bags put them
in bags and put them in your normal
freezer we've got a fancy freezer we'd
be using uh so freeze your buds get them
nice and Frozen uh they've been putting
them in a deep freeze is what I've been
seeing then it's ran through a closed
loop system uh I'm not there for that
part most of the time not I'm not a hash
maker dried and cured no fresh you cut
down the plants okay good question I'll
emphasize that again you cut them down
you let them hang for like three to four
hours and take off the leaves and then
freeze them okay that's all they hang to
dry right boom Frozen chop down Frozen
and then blasted in the uh closed loop
system taken out of the closed loop
system and vacuum purge really really
gently and I'm not the hash maker this
is the process I've observed and
gathered from hanging out with all of my
friends that are extract artists all
right all right that's that's the basics
you know don't don't rush out
and you most people and I sound like an
[ __ ] most people don't have access to
the machine you need to do this right on
you're not going to have the machine
there are a couple of specific machines
that you need to do this there are only
a couple Brands and I don't know exactly
which two everybody would recommend to
fight over if one of them wants to uh
sponsor the show hit me up we'll start
talking about your machine on the show
so maybe someone close to us maybe where
would they even start to look once this
this develops where would they look for
it Denver uh yeah Denver is the only
place I know if you can get live resin
right now uh there was and it's gone now
so I'm sorry you guys but it was there
it went [ __ ] quickly there was Tangi
live resin at the clinic it was 250
bucks for three grams for one of our
friends that bought some I think that's
$85 a gram is roughly what that comes to
but it's you got to than you're paying
for the
machine well and it's kind of the hype
uh that's part of I mean how many people
have you seen on Facebook or anywhere
yeah right and it's our crew pretty much
the Denver crew has got it figured out
the Denver crew is smoking the live
resin I'm not sure who came up with it I
don't have any of I think uh I think it
was gidy up is one of the first people
that I ever saw smoking live
resin I've seen it online but it didn't
look anything I'm going give giddy up
and
uh do I even want to say the other
people so it's like Giddy Up Garden of
Weeden maybe some Greener Side Empire
that crew I'm going to give them credit
for inventing the bare naked and the
butt naked right here on the show pretty
sure those guys invented that [ __ ] that
was their idea gidy up was definitely
one of the pioneers of that [ __ ] and now
that I've recovered from my dab let me
tell you wow isn't that smooth so the
live resin uh people are arguing that
it's not cured so it can't be as good
that the [ __ ] weed isn't as good cuz
it's not cured before it's blasted is
the Taste not incredible it is more
flavorful than anything if that any any
shatter that I've had here if an apple
tasted like uh some dank weed this is
Girl Scout cookies weed we're dabbing if
you had a Girl Scout cookies flavored
apple and you bid into it you know how
apples take a second for that juice to
come out of the fiber of the apple and
then drip into your mouth is that what
like a Weedle if you had a Weedle a weed
apple is that what it would taste like
that's what that is where compared to
shatter would be like buying slices from
a bag you know what I'm saying like it's
it's already preut it's got that air on
the on the it's not as we're not
downgrade we're not meaning to downgrade
shatter we're just upgrading yeah
upgrading the live resin that's all
upgrade we got the upgrade that's two
D's two upgraded yeah yeah for a double
dose you're from the South if you got
two D's and upgrade buddy you've never
seen that movie somebody will'll get it
out there and tweet it to you I'm not
even going to let you know I hope they
do uh you want to shout out your Twitter
address
uh that's overgrow the gov at overgrow
the gov that's my buddy Adam over here
he's from the south so excus for the
[ __ ] that he says yeah it should be
changed to like Adam with no filter it
may you know it's it's pretty good
that's Adam with no filter over there
yeah but who cares we're just rambling
guys I hope you're having fun on the
podcast this time um I've been talking
about maybe talking about talking about
may be talking about I know I was
waiting for you to catch that that's why
I paused oh dude one more thing one more
thing uh I'm going toot some horns so
live resin guys I hope we explained that
enough we're blasting fresh frozen
plants don't dry them blast them fresh
frozen boom that's it vacuum purge it
really lightly because the vacuum purge
[ __ ] up your terpenoids and it
collapses a lot of things uh if you're
doing this process you should know what
I'm talking about all the vacuum purge
lighter and a little longer uh just go
lighter and longer less heat don't
expect to get shatter through the same
process no no you kind of it's it's not
supposed to won come out like that some
of it came out shatter some it is what
we're calling sugary and it looks like
we [ __ ] up it looks like old school
hash that we [ __ ] up but it's almost
clear it tastes so [ __ ] good oh my
gosh dude it is and that's and I'm
higher from it yeah it's uh it's a
cleaner I don't cough I don't cough from
he doesn't I I do cuz I smoke cigarettes
so well if I take you know I don't know
if I could I don't know if I could do a
half gr dab of live resin that why would
you want to though well because I like
dropping half gr dabs of [ __ ] regular
shatter I like that that like kick in
the dick kind of feeling that it gives
you and I guess On My Level sometimes it
takes a half gr dab YouTube video in the
making how much live resin is on this
little sheet right here I don't know you
should I that's not even big enough to
be impressive all right you get yeah
that's a lot of live it's [ __ ] dude
$85 a gram at the clinic yeah no you
want me to drop a $45 gram or $45 dab
this coming from the man who has burned
quite a few things that I don't even
want to talk about uh I'll post that
picture up I'll post a picture somewhere
he's talking about me burning things it
was a $100 bill it was the 4th of July
uh I'll post that picture one day
somewhere if that's not a crime I I res
I was afraid to post it up because I
thought that may I may get in trouble
for that it's not it's not a crime it's
a it's an actual form of protest that's
acceptable it's a political protest yeah
isn't that random you guys I burned a
$100 bill there's a story behind that uh
one there's well there were two $100
bills but there's a story behind it so
it's a really good story behind it it is
maybe next year I might have to edit
that part out but you never know uh and
we also said Somebody's last name that I
may have to edit out uh I'm not going to
repeat it yeah uh if you guys didn't
catch it the first time then you didn't
catched it uh so I'm going to toot my
own horn but also I'm going to recommend
that you guys go and check out Cannabis
sativa the essential Guide to the
world's finest marijuana strains edited
by St owner his name is Stoner this is
volume three released by Green candy
press uh this book is
$20 uh it should be released very soon
I'm going to go to amazon.com I'm not
sure that it's even out yet but when it
comes out you got get this [ __ ] book
dude because on page I think it's 45 or
54 I suffer from it's 54 page 54 there
are some glorious photos of Golden Goat
those photos are by myself uh took those
pictures yeah thanks a lot I'm just
Jing I actually took those pictures with
a an
Olympus uh what's it called now I can't
remember the [ __ ] of course you can
it's a little Olympus camera it's not
even anything fancy it's uh it's a digal
it's a Panasonic Olympus it's just a
little uh 16 uh [ __ ] it's got a real
good zoom it's got a 16x zoom on it is
what's real nice about it and that thing
took uh all the pictures in this were
taken with that cheap uh is a $200
camera from Best Buy yeah so it's
published in a book guys uh that should
be uh so thanks I want to give a shout
out to them thanks for putting me in the
book I also want you guys to look at the
book support these guys they put out
great uh strain guides the
description uh I wrote some of it and
then it was uh given some Liberty I
think is what I'm trying to say I didn't
write that the way that it's written
there so and I also am not taking credit
for creating Golden Goat I did not
create Golden Goat guy named uh Mr dank
from Kansas created the Golden Goat and
uh that was not me I simply put it into
seed form it's in feminized seed
unfortunately right now it's sold out
but there will be more made it went so
fast dude you see you got Golden Goat
seeds I made a test batch and they went
pretty quickly to all my test crew and
they showed [ __ ] huge potential and
they looked like Golden Goat Mommy so
then I made more and I put them online
bang they were gone dude that's awesome
yeah shout out to Nature's green
remedies uh those boys know how to
hustle uh so I was in the book yeah it's
Cannabis sativa buy that book check it
out guys it will be available on Amazon
if it's not
already uh they do great work over there
The Strain guides are important now that
we're getting into the medical marijuana
stuff and it's getting to be legal where
people are going to want to know about
these strains and they're going to be
growing all this crazy [ __ ] and now
we've actually got a book to kind of
document it dud the picture from subcool
on page 72 of Jack the Ripper
gorgeous excuse me bless you I've never
sneezed on a podcast before it's the
first time excuse me sorry guys I didn't
mean to do
that dude my eyes got so heavy when I
sneezed that that edible is [ __ ]
working woo I forgot all about it
honestly I can't forget about it I still
have the taste of chocolate and peanut
butter in my mouth this is a cool book
look at that picture of East Coast Sour
Diesel trust me damn dude whoever grew
that let's see uh Illuminati seeds huh
they uh hey it's also got some uh some
of your other guys in there the llata
labs picture oh llata is in here do you
remember which strain it was um no I
don't remember their picture will be
easy to spot because they take amazing
photography shout out to L Plata Labs
it's Josh and Jeff um I'm going for it
I'm going them
looking uh their their photos are
great I think it was that if you
remember the name of the Strand it' be a
lot
easier wow the picture of white diesel
is glorious you guys are going to want
this book somebody did a good job this
is uh a lot of these are better than my
Instagram
feed NOP close though close it's that
style yeah la has a loton stuff very
blackground lemon alien yeah there you
go oh L got to go to it's all
alphabetical so they try to help out the
bhe heads that was an amazing picture
too they had a lot of color and stuff
yeah there we go shout out to L Plato
Labs on page
86 amazing picture uh Greenhouse Super
Lemon Haze times alien Bubba tested at
16% THC check out lbs.com uh those are
friends of mine so I definitely do
support them they are available actually
at Nature's green remedies.com so if you
need to get your hands on some llata
Labs products natur's green remedies.com
um the coupons that I give out are good
for every brand somebody asked me if
that's only good for I genetics products
uh shout out to iy genetics I know
that's weird right but a lot of people
don't realize that I am I genetics as
well so iy genetics is the largest
sponsor of this podcast they never get a
promotion or anything so first time I've
ever done that big shout out to IR
genetics Colorado check out iire gentics
color.com for great cannabis photography
some information on uh myself I haven't
updated the website in a while there's a
forum there if you want to join the
Forum it's kind of a fun little thing to
do but uh yeah Nature's green remedies
those coupons expire uh I was gonna say
that the [ __ ] e I'm high those coupons
expire this month but I'll give you
another code but they're good for any
brand not just mine so if you want to
get some La Plata Labs if you want to
get uh there's so many good brands on
there I think alphac chronic is on there
uh Gage green is definitely on there I
recom highly recommend Gage green highly
recommend Gage green I use gauge Green
in my breeding projects all the time y
uh daybreaker F2 uh breaker F2 time uh
plushberry is actually black cherry cam
I'm high dude can you see that on my
face I could definitely see you're
getting fidgety yeah I'm totally fidgety
let's take a dab try to calm me down a
little bit you're like let's go for a
walk you want to go for a walk I don't
know if I yeah you wouldn't make it far
we'd get out and you'd be like wow that
grass is really wet no I got you brother
you're good uh so I said I was going to
talk about trim stuff we better do that
cuz we're 49 minutes in holy crap guys I
dry trim you need a long episode you
know I understand I get it but you've
needed one you need I like to do them
structured but this was fun this was a
good this was a good idea I'm high as
giraffe [ __ ] I bet you are and that's
to Joe Rogan quote but I am
there you you said hey usually hey is
followed by I don't know a statement
ending a statement guys if you're
wondering what Adam looks like all you
got to do is watch this cartoon called
King of the Hill and there's a character
named Lucky oh my God in about 10 years
Adam's going to look just like
lucky in the truck L that's
fine you want to give a shout out to
anybody while I do a dab no I don't I
don't really want to give a shout out to
anybody uh all I know is that this stuff
that you're dabbing is is 100% And I
want one of these next time uh because
you do yeah you want one of those yeah I
do and I damn sure don't want to split
it with her no just eat the whole thing
the whole abely and make her extremely
jealous there we go that who I'll give a
shout out to I'll give a shout out to my
wife because IDE she's sitting at home
while I'm sitting here D
so good
night you know not you guys just his
wife yeah good night Christie I just
dropped the torch Oh I thought that was
a rig dude that was a torch my heart
dropped I had it at the edge of the
table cuz it was hot I just had it face
down right
there it scared me though I thought one
of these that fat dab alive resin after
how high I was from that
edible this is going to be a fun end of
a show section if it ends oh if it ends
can we just podcast indefinitely I think
we got everything yeah we could do a
live feed couldn't you you ever uh
Google hang out and just then release it
you ever eatting LSD where you got into
that bubble where you don't want to
leave where you are because you're just
like I'm here and I'm safe yeah
absolutely so that's how the podcast has
me right now I'm secure I've got my
little station right here I got some
dabs I got a drink I got a book to read
if something goes wrong I got the
internet I got my little station I'm and
the internet's back oh the internet is
back the internet was down here uh
Comcast come on dude you're you're
expensive I wasn't even going to say the
CW you know what I'm saying tcast yeah
they're so expensive they should work
come on guys get it together it's not
that they should work they should work
past 12:00 to 4:00 because unlike them
other people do things at those hours
and it's
like you know I'm not going to say what
people do I'm just going to say that
people need to do that yeah on the
internet all right guys after I finish
this
cough here we go with the miniature grow
lesson on dry trimming and bear in mind
I ate a 350 migr edible that is highly
effective I'll get him to slow down a
little bit it's [ __ ] working yeah
Adam will help us out so I'll even turn
down the music CU it's highly
distracting because I love these songs
task Rock's awesome in my
opinion uh dry
trim wear rubber gloves for almost all
of everything that I'm talking
about uh get the uh the blue nitr gloves
those are those are great they're cheap
they got them at like Walmart and
Walgreens they're affordable woo I'm
high here we go uh
so uh pull the plant out of the room I
guess and just chop it down to the base
and then hang it upside down I use uh
that bottom Branch the very bottom
Branch where the first [ __ ] set of
buds are I hang that over uh sometimes
you could string up a line across the
room or maybe use like a coat hanger
depending on how many you have going on
but wherever you're hanging it that's
your new little hanger that little y
that first intersection and then I'll
grab like a uh a fuzzy stick pack of
fuzzy sticks from Walmart it's kind of
like a pipe cleaner
uh anything like that uh [ __ ] the the
thing around your bread bag they got a
bunch of those kind of things little
twisty tie sort of thing wrap out around
the stock and just kind of secure it
onto whatever you're hanging it to a
little bit because sometimes that Branch
will break if you got a heavy plant if
you want to go to the second Branch go
for that uh secure it on there a little
bit I like to secure it either way just
cuz I'm [ __ ] OCD I don't want my
plants falling in the floor after
they've been growing for [ __ ] 125
days or something you going to be all
right princess you're turning colors hey
don't call me Princess you'll be lucky
to talk BR yeah yeah this uh this edible
works if you guys want to buy an edible
uh I recommend the mountain medicine but
know your tolerance yeah dude eat half
of it dude don't even do that eat a
quarter if you were I'm high yeah I'm
I'm a professional working for you I
know it's going to work for me I I like
to say I'm a professional and this is
[ __ ] me up in such a good way when I
bought that 3155 milligram drink I
thought that it was going to [ __ ] me up
I mean you literally told me I want I
wish we could play some Grateful Dead
music without getting the show in
trouble right now that's where I am high
I want to listen to Jack straw if
anybody's a dead head out there you know
where I am if I say I just need to hear
Jack straw man somebody knows where you
are somebody knows where I am somebody
wearing a [ __ ] tiedyed shirt is out
there going yeah man and they're GNA
play Jack straw for me all right so we
got the plant it's hanging upside down
right uh you need to get off the fan
leaves uh now is a good time to do that
maybe you did that some Growers do that
a few days before Harvest maybe I should
have recommended that uh maybe a few
days before Harvest go in there and take
off all your big fan leaves uh or you
can do that right as you harvest or you
can do it as it's hanging up just get
those big fan leaves
off now your plants are hanging upside
down in a room uh you want that room at
like uh [ __ ] I should have wrote this
down because I'm getting really high uh
you don't want a lot of humidity in
there maybe like 25 to 30% Max maximum
humidity and then uh and you want to
have some air moving but not like your
fans blowing directly on the plants
that'll crisp them up a little too
quickly you want them to dry a little
bit slowly while they're hanging upside
down so you got a whole plants hanging
upside down minus fan leaves just
hanging upside down the humidity is kind
of low uh keep your
temperatures uh you don't want to go
cold uh but you don't want to go hot
either so like 70 75 is like right you
know right the same that's a good area
for like what they like yeah yeah where
you are is where they're cool um yeah
might hang kind of like in a work area
where it's a little dark keep it dark in
there uh and I could I would imagine it
could go to possibly 80 you know like it
80 would probably be up a little faster
than you want but you know closet if you
have to you know like that type of thing
just make sure you're getting air to
them if you are doing like closet or
something air because uh moving air
prevents mold just remember that in
every grow situation moving more air
prevents mold that's like one of the and
growing is humid you may not even
realize how much water is involved in
growing but every gallon you pour in is
coming back out somewhere and you got to
move that you got to get rid of it or
utilize it somehow so you got these
plant are upside down they're in the
room with the right humidity they're in
the room with the right temperature
hopefully it's dark right uh as dark as
you can get it uh you got to dedicate
space you got a lot of air moving so you
don't get moldy now just let them dry up
for uh [ __ ] I've got some that have been
hanging uh the plants we trim tonight
were cut down uh on a Monday so they've
almost been going for two weeks hanging
up there and it's been a little uh a
little humid because we've had a swamp
cooler going in that area uh not in that
area but in a room like three a hallway
down I guess there's a swamp cooler in
there just because that's what that room
came equipped with so we gotta run that
enclosed area yeah but uh it's still
getting it's still it still makes a
little humidity in the rest of the the
grow environment so whe they're sitting
there hanging for about uh 14 days is
where they've been and they don't have
any fan leaves on them you might want to
check them every other day uh every day
like start checking about four days 5
days six days give them a little squeeze
and when those fan leaves or the little
sugar leaves start crisping right off
just by hitting them with your finger
grab those plants and just take like
I've have these long bins and I just
take branches off the I have the plants
hanging I cut branches off and lay them
into the bins and once my bins are full
I go to a seated area cuz you got to sit
down to trim dude oh man it'll drive you
nuts trying to stand up I'm getting old
that's how I know I'm old I can't stand
the trim anymore so you got to sit down
and I just kind of hold I cut one butt
off at a time and just knock the leaves
off of it with my thumbs because now
that it's dry those leaves are pretty
much just going to fall off and you can
see what your finished product is as
you're going so trim it to your liking
at this point if you're selling it to
[ __ ] for stupid cheap a pound and
just hustle and wait to get it out don't
trim it worth of [ __ ] that's why cheap
wheed is cheap if you want kosur Grade
weed take your time and trim it and wear
rubber gloves that's yeah yeah yeah
please I don't want to smoke all your
skin your we if your weed's that sticky
then definitely wear rubber gloves and
then uh have something to be proud of
Adam loves the finger hash uh if you're
wearing good rubber gloves you can like
rub you'll learn how to don't scrape the
[ __ ] latex right out of that [ __ ] but
you'll learn how to rub the the hash off
of your fingers and make like little
hash ball or a little hash watch a watch
a video on making uh what was it called
you know what I'm talking about no I
don't cuz you're saying it the oh the
hand hash when AR Go makes chus chus
there you go watch a video on how to
make chus and it you'll figure out real
quick yeah so the buds are pretty much
dry right uh we've got them in the room
they hung they're crispy now we're hand
trimming them so cut off like you got a
bunch of sticks in a band you take that
[ __ ] stick you cut off little
individual Buds and you just knock the
leaves off with your thumbs you can use
scissors now if you want but it's kind
of pointless I am faster just thumbing
it it looks like you're playing Nintendo
with the butt in your hand you're like
just going up it should just take you a
couple seconds to get each bud and you
can see like I said you can see the
finished result and what's really cool
is if you wet trim uh you got to trim it
and you're all sticky and it [ __ ] up
your scissors and it takes so long and
every time you set a butt down or touch
a butt it [ __ ] sticky there and
stickier and sticky here uh dry trimming
is way cleaner uh and this may sound
weird but as soon as you're done
trimming you can weigh your [ __ ]
like and this is how much I have yay and
it's done at that the leaves not pull
out moisture anyways I mean they're
essentially yeah it's ideal to leave
them you know like they're they're ducks
to for the the place they're they're
what's struggling to suck up the
moisture not the the bud really I would
imagine that's yeah that's mostly right
but also it helps slow it down because
you want the water to leave more slowly
okay because that let the the
chlorophyll evaporates with the water so
once the water's gone you can't take
away any more chlorophyll but if you let
the water come out slowly then that
chlorophyll dissolves with the water and
goes away oh okay yeah and then it
happens in The Cure process also you
start uh the gases start convert we're
getting into cure that's different we'll
go yeah yeah we'll go there later I yeah
it's just um I can tell you now like
most of the videos that I've seen I made
it an hour and I'm high as [ __ ] on that
edible it only took like 45 minutes to
kick in I'm a little better now I've
calmed down but for a minute there I was
really high your hands are still like on
your chair like you're holding yourself
to your seat right
now you'll tell me you're a little
better guys seriously if you are not an
experienced and don't try to be cool
because I smoke a lot of dabs you'll be
that lady from NBC or whatever yeah dude
you'll be writing a story about freaking
out in you'll piss your pants don't eat
350 milligrams unless you're experienced
because you will piss your pants I'm
being a bad example on my own podcast
I'm sorry no like you said you you an
experienced dude you're in the
comfortable ability of your own home you
got a homie here you're good like you're
you're in the perfect spot to do this to
be like I'm going to this is no
different than drinking a bottle of
tequila I'm not going to drive I'm not
going to go anywhere nope I may uh I may
troll the internet a little bit
yeah until your spelling goes and then
it's going to be like who the hell is
this [ __ ]
yeah that's that's about the the most
trouble I'm going to be tonight yep yep
you're good holy crap so did we get
through triming weed cuz I'm high yeah
you did think I always say are we done
trimming weed that's that's your worst
part you can tell how many times a
grower or a person in the trim Circle
has been around pot by how [ __ ] eager
they are to trim if you're like are we
going to trim tonight I'm just so
excited let's trim it's like your second
third maybe fourth time if you're like
he I got to [ __ ] trim a bunch of weed
tonight you're an experienced grower
you've had a couple of crops down yeah I
still love it I love it and hate it I
love it because I get to finally check
out my babies I get to see like oh here
we go get to [ __ ] take those pretty
flowers and blast them into shatter no
I'm just kidding I get to take all that
trim and make shatter and that's one
cool thing about dry trim as soon as
you're done dry trimming you can haul
that trim off over to your extract
artist guy and he can do his thing with
it uh I've cured trim before and blasted
it uh it was very very unnoticeably
different yeah you couldn't tell the
difference between batches some people
say that's not the if your weed's good
you yeah you know yeah I cut down crops
early if I'm making hash out of the
whole plant uh sometimes we'll run we'll
run girl Scot cookies whole plants and
just make dabs out of it and I'll cut it
down a little bit early just a little
bit early I like to take it 63 days
usually I'll cut it down to like 55 56
right at the end of 8 weeks like a
mocha Frappuccino it's got that Dirt
Coffee chocolate taste in there so good
Girl Scout cookies hashy guys man let's
put some music in the background again I
turned it down to give that girl lesson
and talk and it disappeared forever guys
if you got more questions about dry trim
and weed please let me know cuz I
seriously am [ __ ] high as [ __ ] off
that edible what are you looking around
for bro I'm just making sure we covered
everything I'm just helping you help you
I like you helping me thank you for
helping me help myself cuz all right I
think we you make a good co-pilot
tonight at this point we have shout out
to the little trim girl that came over I
wrote that down I might have said that
earlier you did but it's all good yeah
she helped trim dude she saved hours of
the night y lots of them this a good
song this song makes me think of uh
Addison Deora [ __ ] singing it one
time he knew like every at the one point
where it was he like you're running
video of this right no I'm not running
video it's a shame no no yeah it's
definitely a shame I'm a little lit yeah
a little it's fun I've never been this
high on the podcast before do you do you
feel like you could derail at any moment
no no I'm not Lo not I'm not going to
freak out or nothing no I'm just high
and you feel like you've died and nobody
will tell you no but I do want to like
take my mic off the stand and stand up
and dance around and [ __ ] that's what
you look like you really if there was a
concert right now I would be front row
and my hands would be up in the air like
yeah I'd be screaming yeah I'm ready bro
too bad it's dark time and if everyone's
in bed and [ __ ] I'm sorry that
everybody's so disappointing this will
be coming out on a Monday morning and
everyone's going to be like what's wrong
with him he's all [ __ ] sloppy today
shout out shout out to sloppy yeah there
you go uh it's been an hour dude what
else do you want to cover like I said
guys if I [ __ ] up the grow tip please
uh please let me know correct me cuz
I've said wrong [ __ ] before and like I
said I'll fix it I'll try to tell you
the right stuff it's not about
correcting you it's just about I want to
get people not getting the wrong
information that's exactly it that's and
yeah I want you guys to do it right cuz
I'm like I said I'm the captain of this
pirate
ship uh pirate people that know you in
real life they oh they know they just
laugh that [ __ ] off yeah we know he's
hot yeah he ate 350 milligrams and took
like 72 dabs today yeah with an IH heart
dab shirt on making my I'm wearing the
IH heart dab shirt boom love it I'm
dabbed out uh not yet not yet you're
going to take some more dabs dude I'm
I'm not you're probably [ __ ] you can
let's take another dab there's probably
just enough for two dabs of live resin
on this little piece of parchment right
here I I feel bad for we're smoking up
all your live oh no that's what it's for
to take dabs of it doesn't do any good
sitting on a piece of parchment paper I
just want to as a somebody else sitting
here at the table I want to share the
wealth and like goodness man you
contributed to a hell of podcast your
close friends definitely deserved so
anybody out there listening that is one
of you
folks you know um no let's skip this
song I watch it's just a little skit we
don't need to listen to a skit on the
podcast that's awkward oh yeah uh torch
here it is there it is we're running out
of butane we're going to have to switch
to the enil pretty soon you came
prepared though I came I got the eail
sitting on the table right here with the
Highly Educated Infinity nail rigged up
ready to
go it
um uhhuh it's impressive to say the
least like yeah yeah it's only the
second time I've seen it but um from the
south we don't have no fancy [ __ ] like
that you know like I had the bong you
mean electricity yeah uh
no disrespect to the South only Adam
yeah yeah completely me just Adam and
his trailer park that small town yeah I
got it enough for everybody the railroad
tracks behind his trailer park no this
is the power plant oh man yeah is that
why you're kind of
mutated it's it's debilitating is what
it is do you get any government grants
from any of that [ __ ] no you don't
Unfortunately they just want to like do
a bunch of studies and uh research you
know but uh we no I like I said I've had
the bong for the past 10 years or so you
know everybody would come around to
smoke my dual chamber water ice cooled
bong they it was amazing I've never seen
it how much did you pay for that
$400 no man a lot of the people that are
coming here to buy the wreck weed are
straight up from the south they drive
all the way out here on a weekend Texas
or Florida the same damn thing I'm
telling you right now imagine driving to
from [ __ ] Florida to Colorado no
there's
States um yeah but you can't go there
and get it as easily you know what I'm
saying like you have to prove residency
you know um that yo if you're in sorry
I'm totally interrupting you I'm high
rude if you're in poblo Colorado and
you're on the very south end of poblo at
uh mile marker exit 91 uh hit that exit
and then as you come off the exit you
need to go north just a little bit from
the exit uh and there is The Greener
Side dispensary and there's a certain
time period
uh in the early evening right as the sun
sets the LED UFO lights come on in the
greenhouse to keep the plants from
flowering early into the bloom season uh
from about a mile and a half away this
[ __ ] 120 by 30t Greenhouse I think it
is illuminates this purple blue spectrum
and if you don't know what it is it is
the craziest looking [ __ ] thing ever
dude it was all lit up last night when I
was out there that's crazy I was just
driving past but I was on I25 as you
look over you're like what the [ __ ] it
looks like aliens are landing bro that
would be a cool thing to like [ __ ]
really [ __ ] wreck her and take her
out there be like what the [ __ ] is that
so just go to The Greener Side
dispensary and buy yourself some [ __ ]
recreational Cannabis it's on they open
like 11:00 so you can go out there
around 7 7:30 and buy I don't recommend
that but yeah you could probably call
them and ask them what time the UFO
lights come on and tell them that you
want to come check out the purple
greenhouse and they'll probably tell you
what time those turn off cuz I they CH
they you know they it's a greenhouse so
the schedule is going to change they're
just trying to do it to keep the plants
uh going into flower early we're fun
people there's tons of fun stuff to do
here we got a frisbee golf park look out
disc golf disc golf are you any good no
I've never played never mind I miss I
miss a lot I went out there and got got
really high that's pretty much the point
that's pretty much the point chase the
Frisbee and [ __ ] smokes and bowls in
the they were like dude if you just
bring a couple joints I'm sure and I
went out there and I was like I got
joints and they're like no dude we don't
we don't want your weed and I'm like I
don't blame
you they had a lot better weed than I
did so yeah definitely who were these
guys I'm I'm just back in [ __ ]
Tennessee I don't know some Tennessee
Stoners yeah sounds like everybody had
better weed than you in Tennesse
everybody had better weed than me in
Tennessee welcome to shout out to
Loke and you're shitty weed for years
and years in Tennessee yeah there's like
50 guys in Tennessee going yeah he just
gave me a shout out no no no all
right huh so that's that did you take a
dab or did I just take one to be stingy
I don't [ __ ] know if there's some
left here that means I didn't share it
yeah there's a little left here I didn't
even see you take one yeah I took it
dude that's you you put it down like it
was nothing yeah I took a dab cuz it's
the Dabber is clean I must
have you sure you didn't just like you
sure you didn't just like drop off the
side of your computer I'm like 137% sure
which is that's all right that's a big
percent yeah I don't know if that exists
there's some accountant out there
pulling his hair out right now going
[ __ ] you you can't have
137% then again they don't come to the
Agri culture podcast for statistics they
haven't they haven't seen how many grams
per W pool
oh hey keep listening to the podcast and
you'll you might grow yourself and find
out oh oh yeah yeah grams per wat I
heard this girl say uh she can pull two
plus pounds of Kong per thousand watt
light she was using uh 4x8 uh [ __ ]
botanic hair trays on tables like
elevated uh [ __ ] lights every five
thousand watt lights every 5et and rows
of Five
Lights yeah that's a lot of details for
this chick's room but she was claiming
that she pull I'm not doubting her but
she was saying that she pulls [ __ ]
two plus pounds of Kong per [ __ ]
cycle just to be funny a lot of details
would have been like
address when she's going to be there you
know that would a [ __ ] that's a fat
pool if she's doing that props yeah hey
but then
again coming from East and just watching
videos the only place you can watch
videos of that nature forums and YouTube
and stuff like that a lot of people
sometimes
exaggerate and I'm not saying she is
I've seen some pictures that may that
may do her juic this I want to see
pictures she may have just ice I need
she needs to send me the dick pics you
mean of the dick plants not like
actually dick because this is the
internet age and if you go on a podcast
saying someone needs to send me some
dick like within [ __ ] 44 seconds of
this being released your Twitter is
going to go and you're going to get
dickpics hey you know what you'll ask
for you'll ask for support for your
family with cancer and people will
ignore you you ask for a dickpick on a
podcast [ __ ] everybody in America is
going to flash you a dickpick real
fast you let you let me ask for what I
want to ask for
okay as long as you can clearly give
your Fu I'm retweeting everything to
you oh man guys uh if you're checking
out the Agro culture podcast Twitter
please uh yeah refra refrain from the
cockp picks yeah yeah refrain I like
pictures of fat buds I'll go home and
I'll make my wife's a Twitter account
and you can send her
cockpits she likes the
penis pretty sure that's the first she
likes the penis reference on the podcast
there it is I'm surprised it wasn't from
Wade
hey it's pretty dope task rock song it
bumps it gets going is it time to end
the podcast we've been going at it for
an hour and 13 minutes you got anything
cool to say it's your podcast you wanted
to hang out and do a random episode so I
wanted to [ __ ] kind of roll with that
I want to know if we got enough random
in it feels random I feel like I [ __ ]
up a grow L and people count on me and
I'm super high so well ask for details
so what do we do after we got the leaves
bucked off you throw them in a bucket
and let them sit there for a couple days
crisp up and then after that you put
them in a jar and start curing that's
from there is curing and uh I don't know
if I want to get into curing yet that's
I want to talk about that when I'm not
wrecked so I'm going to write that down
and [ __ ] in two or three episodes
from now guess what we'll do curing cure
some weed that's right I mean that's a I
know we went way out of order because
we're only in veg and that actual
lessons but I was trimming weed tonight
so it's crispy in my bra a lot of people
don't even know you know what I'm saying
they literally think you dry it and
that's it no it's got to get cured a
little bit from now I mean you could I
understand that you could if you're
sending it out of town you just [ __ ]
do it but you're going to smoke yourself
or with your homies or use it for
medical purposes we got to cure right
now you want to be proud of
it you know holy crap that edible is uh
bubbling up in my stomach it made me
burp all kinds and it tastes like
[ __ ] weed and [ __ ] peanut
butter yeah all right let's end this
podcast up while we're uh still all
saying by the way uh I ate 350 milligram
of cannabis Edibles and I'm okay but I
don't recommend that you do that I can't
Advocate that type of use I recommend uh
this package says 50 Mig uh I'm going to
say start with 25 or 50 Mig
technical I dared you to do it so it was
a dare you had to do it I [ __ ] would
have done it without your dare I'm pry
sure I like to eat a lot of Edibles uh
this thing got me high good uh it comes
in waves is it worth
$11 to me yes um it depends see that's
hard to say because some people like
their spending habits are different like
where you choose to put your money I
could understand that and this is a
weird rant but my mom will say
everything is expensive how much is it
it's two pennies God that's so expensive
because she's from back in the day when
that was a quarter of a penny so now
it's a [ __ ] she just sees it oh my
God so yeah it's just so it's going to
your but for me that well worth 11 bucks
is is my [ __ ] really short answer of
a lot of long
words um I'm just saying usually things
on that level are a lot more if you well
an edible yeah an edible is 10 to 15
bucks maybe 20 bucks or something really
potent if you're going to a concert or
something and you want to get [ __ ]
high as [ __ ] and not have to worry about
smoking through it cuz that's why I like
Edibles I go to a comedy show and you
can't smoke at The Comedy Works they
will throw you the [ __ ] out and you're
highly visible in there that place is
Tiny yeah uh so eat a fat edible and
just sit in there and grin like a [ __ ]
the whole night [ __ ] this would be
beautiful for that someone likes to say
pregame yeah eat it about uh [ __ ] uh
North End of Denver if you're driving up
from poblo [ __ ] eat that [ __ ] stop
and get gas at that one gas station
there you go gas or whatever eat that
[ __ ] in the parking lot and then get
back on the road and by the time you get
to Comedy Works you'll have a smile on
your face m
wherever you're going in Denver you know
that's just mine um but this was yeah it
was worth 11 bucks so if you're going I
was I was going to go at least I want to
go up there and get some weed and then
and you know what that $11 includeed tax
their dispensary includes tax so 11
bucks flat out the door that is great uh
if you're uh like [ __ ] vegan or
something I don't know what their option
is for you because that's super chocy
and if you're diabetic you're going to
have to be careful with that but of
course you're not supposed to eat 7
doses all at once like I did that's got
me
rambling everything in
moderation I guess go bigger go home on
the igro culture podcast that's right
all right guys I really want to thank
you guys for listening to me ramble uh I
ain't that [ __ ] edible so I'm going
to go uh find something super
entertaining to do with myself now once
again thanks to all the sponsors thanks
to Natural Mystic cannabis caregivers
big high five across the table to Adam
for coming and doing a [ __ ] hour and
a half long podcast with me it's quite
entertaining sorry for dragging it on
dude it's awesome [ __ ] if you're
having fun they're having fun right on
I'm having fun I got task Rock in my
right ear quite loud it's not as loud as
everybody else hears it I got a bumped
up a little more on my headphones all
good I got it going on over here yeah
but uh guys go leave some comments uh
you know that I love [ __ ] comments on
Facebook uh on iTunes on Twitter on
Instagram on Stitcher uh I didn't read
any comments this time I didn't even
check to see if they were there we were
just trying to have fun um yeah so now
the show is over go to iTunes oh yeah I
already said part of that search FR gr
culture find the review section give us
a festar rating after that type in a
comment and let me know what you think
about the show I will read those
comments I won't be as high when I read
your comments so that they will make
sense don't forget that the show is
available still available and always
will be on iTunes Stitcher swell. i.
each episode is archived on iy genetics
colorado.com you should be checking that
out anyway shout out to Jesse Wht and
burn um shout out to my ninja Spence
thanks for listening everybody take a
fat d dab give your mom a hug for
me woo we did it bro and I'm dabbed the
[ __ ] out and that edible was
[Music]
awesome like a nuclear war gu me on your
settling I'm a new to your tell me no
I'mma do it some more do with the floor
yeah hey Phil let's go get in a fight on
the internet hell yeah man I love
talking
[ __ ] I got some
the no I'm [ __ ] pretty sure I could
walk straight up that wall right now if
I try dude
watch