hey what's up podcast world it's Rasta
Jeff and it's Thursday so that means
it's time for a throwback Thursday
episode of The Grove from your heart
podcast this time I'm doing episodes 55
56 57 and 58 before we get into the
episodes let me do a quick disclaimer if
I advertise any products any contest any
giveaways they've all expired these
episodes are very old so none of that
stuff counts anymore also all the social
media has been updated if you want to
follow me on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast on facebook search for the girl
from your heart podcast on Instagram its
Irie underscore genetics and if you want
to send me an email its grow from your
heart at hotmail.com now with no further
ado I bring to you episodes 55 56 57 and
58 of the girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 55 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you thank you for joining me
I'm your host Rasta Jeff as always I
want to send a big huge thank you shout
out to the mystic roots band to let me
use their music on the show
big thanks to Kat coot and the whole
mystic roots crew right now you're
listening to a song called the doggy dub
check that out it's on their album the
constant struggle before we get too far
this podcast is brought to you by hi Gro
indoor growing supplies hydro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or check out the
Pueblo location 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies get
your favorite nutrients at Highgrove
indoor growing supplies a gross store
ran by folks who grow always running a
special for the podcast listeners when
you check out high grow tell me you
listen to the girl from your heart
podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase also the organic portions of
this episode were sponsored by my
friends at the rocky mountain warm
company visit the rocky mountain worm
company in Colorado Springs for fresh
worm castings African nightcrawlers red
wigglers and all of your organic soil
amendments the Rocky Mountain worm
company has dragonfly earth medicine
products in stock right now Rocky
Mountain worm company will ship to your
door you can get the same worm castings
that I use and many of the same
amendments that I use through
www.rockymountainatvmc.com estreet in
Colorado Springs Colorado and make sure
you tell them you're listening to the
grow from your heart podcast
big shout out to J and Howlin and Sean
and Nick and everybody involved down
there the Rocky Mountain worm company
really appreciate you sponsoring the
show and huge things for the gift
package you sent me homeless we'll talk
about that in a minute this podcast is
also brought to you by my good friends
at nature's green remedies calm visit
nature's green remedies calm for Gabe's
green genetics the plot of labs Sin City
Magnus mile-high Kenna venture the
callee connection MTG
I read genetics and many more trusted
brands patreon remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners use
coupon code spring 15 for 15% off any
order and you always get free priority
shipping at nature's green remedies calm
the coupon code spring 15 is good for
any brand in stock but it does expire at
the end of this month so take advantage
of that offer before the 31st big thanks
and much respect to nature's green
remedies for the promotion and the
continued support big thanks to all the
sponsors if you guys are interested in
sponsoring the show send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
and I'll get you all of the information
you need to sponsor the podcast I want
to take a quick second and read and
iTunes comment we got a 5 star rating
again it says thanks from fat ankle-foot
the comment was left on February 26th it
says love to listen getting better with
every episode as someone whose influence
is mainly from sohma's book it's nice to
see things turning to more organic based
been using worms for years please keep
doing what you're doing and keep up the
great work well thanks a lot for the
sweet comment fat ankle-foot I
appreciate that I'm glad that soma
inspired you and started a lot of your
teachings because I was hanging out with
a friend who grew weed for several years
and we were talking about my crops and
he said dude you know who you really
remind me of was a guy named soma never
heard of so I went home and of course I
googled soma
and someone I have a lot of the same
philosophies a lot of the same practices
we agree a lot so I've learned a lot
from soma I kind of used some sohmas
methods but mostly his ideals he almost
treats plants is like a religion sort of
you know he's his religion is growing
pop and I took that spiritual aspect of
growing pot I had that before I ever
knew about soma so I kind of I
multiplied on it or expanded on it once
I found so much so I'm glad you knew
soma and glad your soma fan and dude
thanks for using worms in your garden
and thanks for trying to go organic and
thanks for listening and super thanks
for the comment and the five stars if
you're part of the crew now so welcome
to the true fat ankle-foot we appreciate
it
I think I read this this comment on the
last episode but this one is from buzzer
I read that it says thanks for making
this for us again dude you're super
welcome thanks for listening so if you
guys want to send us a comment I'd love
to read your comments on a future
episode thanks for the comment for
everyone that sent a comment for the new
comments and the old ones thanks to
everybody if you want to leave a comment
on iTunes or stitcher or if you don't
want to leave a comment on iTunes or
stitcher just send me a tweet it's a
girl from your heart so it's actually
@gf wih podcast send me a tweet there or
find me on Facebook and I'll respond to
you if you want to say something
anonymously you can send me a personal
message and I will keep your name
private you can also send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
you can let me know if you want your
name said or not I try to be respectful
I know how it is you can't always tell
everybody that you grow cannabis if you
don't live in Colorado it feels like
intro stuff a little bit about the Rocky
Mountain worm company the Rocky Mountain
worm company was kind enough to give me
a tour of the worm farm I'm also gonna
talk a little bit about my company IRA
genetics and I'll also talk a little bit
about feminized seeds I've gotten a lot
of emails about feminized seeds I'll
explain my method of making those a
little later in the show now let's start
with the Rocky Mountain worm company
last week I was invited to go visit the
Rocky Mountain Worrell company and they
gave me a little tour of the building
and I got to see where the worm castings
are made they don't have a giant
facility but what they do have is super
clean and super organized and I was
pretty impressed I got to hang out with
J and Sean and Alan for a few minutes
and they taught me a lot about worms and
worm castings and why they use specific
worms that they use to make the worm
castings some worms you guys only eat
the top layer of if you put them in a
big thing of dirt like if it's a field
of dirt or if it's just a bucket full of
dirt they will only eat the top layer
and they don't dig down these guys
actually know which worms eat the top
which worms eat the bottom they know
that some worms will eat every layer
some worms will travel through all of
the dirt or whatever you're putting them
in and they will eat and digest all of
that these guys these guys knew a lot
about their worms they showed me worms
in every single stage of growth every
single stage of life they have
kind of keep the worms in five-gallon
buckets and they let me open the buckets
with the warm farms and them I get to
feel the texture of the medium in which
the worms live in it's kind of Airy its
kind of fluffy it feels a lot like the
soil that I mix for my plants one thing
that I thought was really cool is what
they're feeding the worms this is really
cool in my opinion
parts of the worm diet is dried and
ground herb from a company called
o.penvape open vape makes vapor pen
cartridges so they're using their
extracting the CBD or THC from a plant
and making oil out of it and then they
send all the leftover material to the
worm company to feed the worms so the
worm company is using ground-up plant
stocks and leaves and whatever else was
left for over the plants after harvest
after the making oil part happened and
they're feeding the ground-up plant
matter back to the worms and then the
worms are making castings at VAT and
those castings are being used to grow my
cannabis and probably those worm
castings hopefully make it back to
o.penvape and go back into their
cannabis so we're kind of doing like an
in-house recycling sort of thing it goes
full circle without us creating more
stuff without something being tossed
into a dumpster for the trash guy to
find imagine when you harvest you have
every plant has a stalk and stems and
leaves imagine if you let that dry grind
it up and had some worms to feed that to
you wouldn't have to throw all that away
and you wouldn't have to make so many
trips to the dump or wherever that's
just super efficient I was completely
impressed so let's see I want to give
you huge shout out to Jay and Sean and
Alan and Nick I really like hanging out
with those guys the worm Factory is a
cool place I'll definitely be back there
soon
those guys through a handful of products
my way and I'm kind of starting to
implement them in my grow I have to
slowly adjust from the organic or from
the non-organic bottled stuff to the
organics because I don't want to ruin
the organic stuff so I'm learning what I
can switch out and what I can use
together and these guys are definitely
definitely definitely moving me along
quickly I've been feeding my plants worm
castings for about a month now and I can
definitely see an improvement in my
crops the first thing I noticed I would
say that after introducing worm castings
and grow Kashi is that my plants are
just simply
more active they look more vigorous they
look happier they're greener I see more
growth and they also seem to want more
water which tells me they're growing and
taking nutrients more than before so I
definitely encourage the use of grow
Kashi and worm castings as a nice way to
just start leaning toward the organics
yeah so I feel like I've been talking
about them for a little bit let's see if
you want to learn more about the worm
company I definitely recommend you check
out their online presence is wwr Aki
mountain worm company comm they're also
on instagram at Rocky Mountain worm
company dude you will learn a lot from
them if you can stop by their store
check it out tell him I sent you
I said that at the beginning but go
there check it out it's a great place so
big huge shout out to the Rocky Mountain
worm company love you guys can't get
enough of that place the other thing I
wanted to talk about is Irie genetics
I've got I get a couple of emails every
week about I read genetics with
questions about hydrogen etic stuff and
somebody just asked me why I don't talk
about IRA genetics on the podcast show
isn't really about IRA genetics the show
is about Candice cannabis in general so
I not try not to focus too much on my
own company but it seems like you guys
are interested so I guess it seems fair
that I talk about it a little bit I
turned out to toot my own horn I'm gonna
take a sip here sorry hold on
um so let's talk about IRA genetics I
guess let's jump into this um I read
genetics is of course my seed company I
breed regular and feminized cannabis
seeds right now I read genetics is
pretty much sold out of seeds for the
most part nature's green remedies is my
main distributor and they got most of
what I had left over after I hooked up
most of my local friends with my latest
harvest I really like to get the locals
uh all my friends all my Colorado I mean
my company is called IRA genetics
Colorado Colorado is what allowed me to
become this breeder I feel like the
local people should get the IRA genetics
products first and that way I get to see
what they grow and I get to take
pictures of it I can take clones of it
so I'm not trying to be rude about it
but the locals always get served up
first
after I feel like everybody's gotten
their seeds make sure nature's green
remedies gets what they can what they
can do so I really can't make enough
seeds to meet the demand lately honestly
I'm gonna make more golden goat let me
Jeffery seeds here really soon the boys
for that project are actually in flower
when you make em seeds or seeds in
general you got to start the boys off a
little bit ahead of the females so the
males are in flower now the girls will
go on flower and a couple few days those
should be ready in about ninety days
from now I think this episode will come
out March 1st or 2nd and ninety days
from then I should have lemon Jeffery
and golden goat seeds available I
actually wrote down the wrong screen and
I'm gonna set the wrong strain and teach
you guys but yes I'm making more lemon
Jeffery and I'm making more gold and go
right now they should be ready in about
ninety days the locals will get them
first there is no waiting list there's
not a way to get on a waiting list right
now after my locals get served up they
will be dished out to nature's drain
remedies and nature's drain remedies com
will sell out quickly I promise you that
I'll make an announcement on this show
before they go there so when I make
those lemon Jeffrey and the golden goats
I'm also gonna put a new cut called
Kalonji cush in their Kalonji pushes The
Grateful dog pollinated the Tahoe og and
I call it Kalonji Kush after a reggae
artist named Sizzla Kalonji if you're
wondering where my weird names come from
Kalonji is a reggae artist sizzle of
Kalonji
so I'm gonna cross the golden goat to
the sizzle of Kalonji
and I want to call that sunshine girl
which I is actually a sizzler song so I
think that's gonna be pretty cute
I have a couple more ideas that I'm
gonna put in that room I have two more
females that are going in there for sure
but I don't want to talk too much about
them until I've got some seeds in my
hands from those because man we tell you
weird side story one time I reversed the
golden go plant a female golden go
planet I treated it I turned it into a
male and I'll talk more about that later
in the show how I do that but I turned
this female plant into a male right and
it created pollen and I put that pollen
on a roomful of plants and that's how I
created the lemon Jeffrey that's how I
made golden goat seeds there was another
cross in the room that's never been
released or shown to anybody because it
only made a few seeds and those are mine
but I also sprinkled that pollen on
another plant um
the screen was headband it was a
headband cut that I got from my good
buddy hanky B he gave me that headband
cut I sprinkled pollen on it and when
that plant took the pollen the plant
died within 24 hours that plant was dead
every other plant in the room was
healthy and happy took the pollen it
showed signs of being pollinated just
like it should have I don't know what
went wrong but that headband plant died
was in 24 hours of taking feminized
pollen I've never seen that from a plant
I have never heard of that from a plant
I've talked to other breeders nobody has
an explanation for that the plant was
healthy everything was cool I don't know
what the hell happened so I'm gonna put
another headband in there and I'm gonna
hit it with golden goat pollen again and
I've got a name for it but I'm hesitant
to say it on the show because people are
gonna rip me off
but if I say it that no one can steal it
from me Rex I'm saying it the golden
goat is going to pollinate the headband
plant and I will call it as a halo you
know right you see you got a headband
and now it's gold it's above your head
that's the halo bro so that's what I
think I'm gonna call it a headband to
the golden goat the halo Kalonji cush to
the golden goat will be the sunshine
girl those are coming up you guys about
90 days so pay attention I'll need some
testers but I didn't say that on the
show let's see more about IRA genetics I
recently started my work on making black
cherry Kim f2 seeds f2 is finial
generation so I made the f1 right that's
plush Barry was pollinated by a
Daybreaker plant and the seeds that came
out of there were called f1
the first finial generation of that
cross so now I grew a bunch of them out
and I found the mail that I want and
I've recently found three females that
are good candidates for breeding so I'm
waiting for these plants to finish
before I commit to which females I'm
gonna use to continue the line into f2
but once I choose one I'm going to I'm
gonna choose two of them actually and
I'm going to hit both of them with the
male pollen and then I will keep all of
the seeds separate so that it's
phenotype number seven and eight are the
two that I'm really eyeball and for my
females so I'll keep black cherry chem
seven and black cherry chem eight
separate and pull all the seeds out and
I'll grow a hundred of each one of those
and see which one shows me what I like
and it will keep that one to continue
working with so I'll wait for these
plants to finish I got a smoked them I
got a dry them they're gonna turn some
of it into ABS I gotta smoke some of it
as flour I got to see which one I really
like the best and then that will be used
to make the f3 and I'm really trying to
stabilize the purple tree and that
strain is what I'm trying to do so I
really want right now I'm getting about
a little more than 50% purple when I run
a pack of 50
I'll have 25 purple plants I want to
make it up to closer I want to get like
75% purple plants out of this and then
by the time I'm done I'd like to see
that purple plant come out almost every
time is what I'm aiming for I plan to
take it to f5 over the next few years
I'll breed the f2 s this summer one
thing I've seen out of it that's really
cool is some of the phenotypes look done
and there are only 55 days into flower
so I have made a purple strain with a
chem flavor that finishes in about 55 to
65 days which is pretty cool so that's
my black cherry chem project that's
going right now you can check out
pictures of those I put them on
Instagram and I also put them on my
forum on my website if you go to I read
genetics Colorado comm go to the forum
it would be really cool if you join the
forum sign up and join the forum it
doesn't cost anything nothing weird is
gonna happen you're just a member now
and you can communicate with us and
participate but every week I go and post
a weekly grow journal of my own gardens
up there and the black cherry cam has
been highlighted quite a bit so you can
see a lot of great pictures of black
cherry cam on my website right now
for him I'll go there to check it out if
you can and all if you ask me questions
there and you talk to me I really that's
my favorite place to go to communicate
with people because they can't censor me
because I own that Facebook can't shut
that down or anything so do what you
want to do there if I think you're a
dick I might tell you to quit being a
dick but then grow weed and post your
weed pictures there I'd love it alright
um one thing I can talk about is I'm
looking for an a rise male a rise is
golden goat that was pollinated by
Daybreaker
and I really love that strain it makes a
great smell it makes great flavor the
high is amazing the plants put on super
resin they grow in a good amount of time
they're real stout plants you don't need
a lot of staking on it if you find the
right phenotypes so I'm looking for an
arise male I want to use a rise in a
long term breeding project he will be my
long-term breeding male I see some
beautiful things from the strain and I'm
sure the a good male will make some more
amazing crosses the resin production
from that plant is so impressive but
it'll be a few months before I select in
a rise male I've got the feminized
golden goat lemon Jeffery project ahead
of that I've got the black cherry Kim
ahead of that and then after that will
be the arise male selection I want to
find a good arise male for my permanent
breeding stud but I plan to make like 15
to 20 f1 hybrids with the rise to see
what works when I do find that one then
I want to see what can be improved on or
what I need to abandon um guys when you
if you breed if you take a male plant
and you hit six or seven female plants
with it don't be afraid to throw away a
bunch of seeds when you you have to grow
those so you take male plant in a room
with like however many females you're
gonna put in there five six maybe 20
females you're gonna make that many new
crosses you have to grow some of each
batch of seeds yourself before you can
do anything else with them unless you
give them to like your friend and you
say these are untested dude because you
don't want to put out seeds with it you
don't know what they're gonna do so get
the seeds and grow at least ten I would
say a hundred if you can I know you're
limited on space and things I like a
Fino hunt of a hundred plants it really
shows you the what's gonna happen
but grow some of those and if they
totally suck throw them away I know that
sounds crazy but there are enough
strains on the planet to where if you
just made some [ __ ] that doesn't
improve the genetic line throw it away
why do we need that
don't be so attached to your new
creation that oh it's a great strain it
does this it know it sucks throw it away
I have thrown away more screens than I
have kept we all talk about the lemon
cush everybody had high hopes threw the
lemon cush that I worked with that
strain sucked it tasted amazing and it
drew big fat donkey dicks for buds but
you couldn't get high off of it it would
not make resin none of the phenotypes on
that planet made resin and I don't know
why it's just that cross did not work so
all of the seeds are gone all of the
clones are gone that project has been
abandoned I realized that's a failed
project it wasted some time but I don't
want to waste more time or more people's
time with the same project by sending
out shitty seeds so that's a rant on a
not being too attachment that's an a
lesson an attachment if you're too
attached to that strain then you're
wasting your time growing something that
sucks and you could have been grown
something way better you could have been
breeding something that was way better
just let it go
sometimes you gotta learn to let things
go remember that lesson I talked about
my rig that I dropped you just got to
sweep it up and move on sometimes
alright so when I do get all these new
strains made I will need help testing
these like I said I like to run a
hundred myself but I will also send out
a bunch of seeds to reliable testers the
way that I know you're reliable tester
is you've joined my web forum and you
have posted pictures of your previous
grows on my forum and you stay in
contact with me
and you show that you're serious about
it that's a lot of how I find my testers
is off of my own website so in the
future if you're interested in testing
eye region etic seeds it would help you
a lot to join the forum I do play
favorites that way it's my choice
let's see I'm not sure what else to say
about IRA genetics I'm the head breeder
I make 99% of the decisions with help
from my friends I do let the people
around me kind of give their input
because their cannabis consumers growers
smokers they have a lot to say but
that's me I read genetics is all Rasta
Jeff I have trim friends that help me
shout out to everybody that's ever came
and help me trim some IRA genetic stuff
or shout out to all the people that have
helped me package seeds or whatever so
in the future I am going to get away
from the feminized seed as much because
feminized seeds are a pain in the ass to
make and I think that we should all
eventually step up our game and learn to
just grow regular seeds if we didn't
have male plants we wouldn't have more
plants anyway so it's my responsibility
to put out more regular seeds I think
than I do feminized seeds and I see um I
see better [ __ ] come from the regular
crosses then I do the FEM seeds honestly
feminized seeds are stuck you can't
improve on them too much the trust that
you make that's what you got like I see
when I cross like if it's feminized if I
cross plant a and plant B they come out
a little bit better than a and B were
but you can't make them super better if
I take a regular male plant and a female
plant and cross that I see much better
stuff come out of that much more
improved plants transgressive
segregation my offspring will outperform
each parent and that only happens when
I'm using regular pollen I can't make
that happen with my feminized pollen so
there are a couple reasons why I will
eventually abandon the feminized seeds
that's eventually I'm not saying soon
but one of these days I will stop making
FEM seeds I don't know what else to say
about IRA genetics that's uh there's so
much I could say but I feel like I'm
just stroking my own ego over here
talking about I rely um support I read
genetic student it's a Rastafarian seed
company by her Asda man so instead of
having mass-produced commercial seeds
you've got seeds every seed was touched
by me every plant was touched by me by
my Rastafarian hands so it's got a
little bit of Rasta love in there I
think that means something to me I'd
rather buy products from a small company
that cares about their products than the
Walmart of whatever industry you're in
alright
let's get on to another topic here I
mentioned that I want to talk about
feminized seeds a little bit um a lot of
people seem to have misconceptions on
what feminized seeds are on how they're
made on where they come from and on what
they will do people think that feminized
seeds are straight-up hermaphrodite
seeds which I've got a pretty popular
seed company that only sold feminized
seeds for two years and we came up
pretty good and I don't know how I
region etics would be popular and/or
reliable if we just sold a bunch of damn
Herms so let's start with some basics
here what does it mean to have feminized
seeds I took a few random notes
feminized seeds mean that the seeds will
produce all female plants I can only see
99% of female plants because this is
science and nature and [ __ ] happens but
there'll be 99% females this is helpful
because new growers don't know how to
identify male plants in their gardens so
if you're growing feminized seeds you
don't have to watch for the boys it also
makes things easier for growers with
limited space because the grower knows
that every seed planted will be a usable
female and none of their space soil
nutrients water electricity none of
that's gonna be wasted on growing a male
plant that had to be chopped down ten
days in the flower so feminized seeds
mean that all the seeds will produce
female plants now here is where some
people are confused how were feminized
seeds made pay close attention because
honestly you guys I am I'm amazed with
myself that I'm giving out this
information this is one of my biggest
secrets and I don't usually share with
anyone I want to take a dab in a drink
before I share this but I'm gonna take a
quick to happen a quick drink and then I
will teach you guys how I make reliable
feminized seeds on a semi large scale
for nature's drain remedies and patience
throughout Colorado give me a quick
second I'm gonna take a DAB in a drink I
want to tell you how I make my feminized
seeds first of all I gotta warn you the
the chemicals that I will describe here
are a little bit dangerous and you need
to follow the safety rules for these I
am NOT responsible for you hurting
yourself or making yourself sick with
these chemicals okay I'm simply telling
you how I do this if you do this follow
the instructions wear gloves wearing
goggles do everything safely
so the way I start is I order silver
nitrate and sodium thiosulfate from a
scientific supply company um I get
powdered versions of silver nitrate and
sodium thiosulfate and I mix I'm not
gonna tell you the delusions or the
rates but I mix the silver nitrate into
an amount of water and I mix an amount
of the thiosulfate into an amount of
water and then I mix those two in
another container into another container
and now I've got a hundred percent
silver thiosulfate in that third
container and I will dilute that to a
certain dilution now some plants will
take will need stronger delusions of the
silver thiosulfate and some plants will
need lighter delusions of the silver
thiosulfate what I've learned as some
plants I can treat some plants one time
with the silver thiosulfate at a high
dilution just before flower the day
before flower and that will work for
that plant some of them I have to make
the dilution much weaker and spray it
multiple times and some plants I have to
make it stronger and only spray at once
and the only way you'll learn this is
through experimentation by trying plants
by trying different delusions so I put
the silver nitrate into one container of
water and put the thiosulfate into
another container of water I shake them
up to where it dissolves I mix equal
amounts into another container and then
I take that container and dilute it to
the proper dilution for the plant that
I'm working with
then I will I'm gonna use golden goat
because I'm I just did this the golden
goat about seven days ago I took three
golden goat plants and I put them in a
small space where there aren't any other
plants around there's no wind
to where my spray is not going to
randomly land on other plants because I
don't want to reverse other plants on
accident in this process so I took my
three golden goat plants I put them in a
small confined space and I sprayed them
with my silver thiosulfate mix at the
proper dilution and I sprayed these
plants to the point where they are
dripping from top to bottom these plants
were covered in the silver thiosulfate
solution be careful because if you use
the silver thiosulfate at a strong
dilution
it may turn things purple like the floor
or the spray lands on the wall behind it
may turn I may leave little purple marks
so be careful or a little shiny purple
mark like shiny iridescent looking marks
I think is the word it's gonna need the
way it looks but it'll screw some stuff
up if you don't want your things purple
be careful so spray the plants didn't I
let them sit and dry because I want them
dry before they go in a flower room so I
let the plants dry then they carry those
plants to the flower room where they
will go into flower and I try to spray
them right before the lights off for the
flowering cycle so they get sprayed they
dry they go into the flower room and the
lights go off and they have now just
gone into flower and with the golden
goat I can spray it one time the day of
flower and in about 10 days that plant
will show me male flowers now people are
saying how does that work I gotta
explain this to you kind of slowly so
pay attention because I'm trying to
explain it to myself I don't have any
notes on this I'm just freestyling right
now so bear with me what happens is when
we spray a female plant with silver
thiosulfate solution the thiosulfate
acts as a carrier for the silver the
silver isn't really absorbed by the
leaves easily but the thiosulfate makes
it get in there a little bit better so
we're tricking the plants into taking
the silver by absorbing the thiosulfate
now when the silver reaches the plants
the silver disrupts the copper movement
in the plant system there is copper in
your plants yes the silver will disrupt
that when that copper movement is
disrupted in the plant system it
responds by triggering an ethylene
production or I'm sorry ethylene it
triggers an ethylene response it's not
an ethylene production it's an ethylene
response and that ethylene response
tells the plant that something is
seriously wrong and it's time to go into
survival mode so that plant survival
method is to create male flowers that
will create pollen because now all that
plant wants to do is shoot pollen and
reproduce to keep the species alive
so I've disrupted the copper the plants
freaking out
the panic causes ethylene to move
through the plant in a weird way that
ethylene triggers the plant to throw out
flowers that are male flowers that
produce pollen now since those plants
that female plant is all female it does
not have any male chromosomes the only
reason it is showing male sex parts is
because I've stressed it and manipulated
it so it will now throw out male parts
that contain pollen and though that
pollen will be all female excuse me my
throat's clogging up here from the dabs
let me take another drink of water so
now we've got female plants that are
spitting out all female pollen and we're
taking that pollen and of course putting
it on female plants you know we've never
introduced any male pollen here so like
I said before 99% of those plants should
come out female and the only reason I
can see 99% is because like I said it's
science in nature and [ __ ] does happen
and also your grow room can cause issues
as well your gross style can I'm not
blaming it on you I'm just saying that
environmental factors and all that stuff
plus science and nature will lead to
some screw-ups
and I'll take credit for part of those
screw-ups because I'm the one that made
the seeds but when this is done right we
get quality reliable feminized seeds so
I hope that makes a little bit of sense
I make the cytosol fate and I spray the
plants with it and magically that makes
the plants turn into transsexuals
they're not male plants they're reversed
females is what we call it and that
basically is how I am making feminized
seeds so these are not hermaphrodite
seeds I'm not taking hermaphroditic
plants and using hermaphrodite pollen
I'm not doing anything crazy ridiculous
this is reliable science the reason a
lot of people are afraid of feminized
seeds is because when it was started
there were other less reliable practices
used to make phem seeds soma does
another method since we talked about
soma earlier in the show soma does not
use the silver thiosulfate method as
often as I do
what soma does is he lets his plants
grow too long so if he's got a 10-week
flowering plant he'll let it grow about
12 weeks and when a plant goes that long
it kind of stresses itself and then it
firms out and creates pollen that way
and that's what soma is using I've also
heard of soma taking a mature plant and
this sounds completely crazy to a lot of
growers but it'll make sense
he takes a completely mature plant and
then he will light a small fire and he
will put his plant too close to the fire
door the plant panics and the plant
feels like it's a forest fire coming so
that plant starts to create male flowers
and it's a female plant it's freaking
out it's triggering that survival
instinct so it makes those male flowers
which make pollen and then soma collects
that pollen and sprinkles it on to other
plants and maybe this explains why
feminized seeds are so damn expensive
because there are more steps into making
feminized seeds than there are to making
regular true breeding male female seeds
that's why it's hard for me to keep up
because I have to reverse plants and I
don't get as much pollen from reversing
these plants as I do from a normal male
and it takes a little longer
alright I feel like I told you enough
about reversing plants I think you
should have caught on by now like I said
you're gonna have to experiment with the
delusions and the application rates um
in edie Rosenthal's book I don't have it
next me the Oaksterdam chorus guide
they had wrote the most not even sure
that it's the most current but ed
Rosenthal wrote an Oaksterdam course
guide and in that book there is a recipe
to make your own silver thiosulfate that
recipe does work although for some
plants it will need some adjusting
that's just my advice alright I am going
to take a phat dab and take a drink and
try to get this frog out of my throat so
that I can sound like an actual
podcaster give me one second I'll be
right back guys and we will give some
shoutouts and wrap up the show alright
guys I'm back I won't apologize for
taking so many breaks on you this
episode usually I have some guests that
can cover me while in coffin and taking
a drink or whatever but today was just
me and so you had to bear with me I
apologize I hope you enjoyed the show
I just took a big old fat dab of some
Jack the Ripper shatter made by my good
friends at Terp X I picked that up at
the green and healthy wellness in
Colorado Springs I don't shop at a lot
of dispensaries because I'm
self-sufficient but I was low on chatter
i i'm just between harvests right now so
i had to pick up a few grams of shatter
dude dream and healthy wellness on to 12
South 21st Street Colorado Springs has
hookups on Terp x shatter if you have to
be a medical patient so if you have a
medical card and you were in the
Colorado Springs area [ __ ] if you're in
Pueblo or Denver it's worth the our
drive to head to green and healthy
cannabis and pick up your terp acts
shatter it's a great price I can't tell
you how much it is because it's member
pricing we have non-member pricing and
they have quite a few tiers of pricing I
don't want to get you pumped up because
sometimes they run out of the low
pricing stuff but dude go to green and
healthy wellness in Colorado Springs and
get some turf backs big shout out to
John and John and Jordan and Jordan
nothing like a dispensary with two
John's and two Jordans in it alright
also I want to give a big shout-out to
my friend Claude the Candyman
Claude if you're listening to this show
bro big thanks much respect guys support
sweet stone candy if you were in
California you can get your sweet stone
candy I don't think it's available here
in Colorado anymore but much love much
respect to Claude the candy man
big shout at the sweets no candy also a
big hug to Melissa and a little scratch
on the head too sticky the dog shoutout
I'm also big huge shout out to my buddy
hunt i always owe you a big shout out
bro you need to come on the show grimy
gatsby on the podcast that's what I'm
saying um we are having a growers
meeting you guys we do these growers
meetings in the back of hydro indoor
growing supplies Jesse gets a topic
started and then I will jump in and help
him give a little girl lesson I think
we're gonna talk about I don't even know
what the topic is this week I should
text him and find out but we are going
to have a meeting the meeting is on
March 6th at 6 p.m. at hydro indoor
growing supplies grabbing the paper with
the address right now because I don't
remember the address I do remember but I
don't want to say it wrong it is 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado you
were invited that's right you were
invited if you're listening to this
podcast I think you have to be 21 and
over it's a 21 and over even if you're
listening to the show and you're 21 and
up you can come to this e van it's a
hydro indoor growing supplies March 6th
at 6 p.m. I will be there Jesse will be
there there's a good chance Shaun King
Cola will be there sometimes mints shows
up garden of Weeden comes there will be
a lot of cool people there sometimes we
give away prizes they give away prizes
it's not my event I just help out but
big shout out to hi drone or growing
supplies for that so
come to start coughing again I feel like
I have a big coughing fit coming so I'm
gonna try to wrap up the show pretty
quickly just a short episode you guys
seem to pay more attention when the
episodes are shorter I honestly get more
lessons more completed lessons under 45
minutes so we might start doing that if
you have a show idea message me I'd love
to hear your show ideas this show came
out of emails that I received from
listeners I made this show just for you
because of your questions so if you want
to hear something let me know don't feel
shy don't feel like you're begging I
will do a show based on what you want to
hear because this show is for another
week hey I said dragon fly to earth
medicine people were coming it turns out
our schedules kind of missed each other
they are in Washington up near Canada
right now I may set up a Skype interview
but I never went podcast do Skype and
phone interviews I usually don't listen
cuz it sounds like [ __ ] so unless I can
get a really quality recording out of it
I won't do it to tell you the truth I'll
wait for them to come to Colorado and I
will interview them in person so I hype
you guys up at the dragonfly with
medicine people are coming there was a
miscommunication they are currently in
Washington I am in Colorado yeah you
heard me if I can make it happen through
a good phone interview I will if it's
not quality I will never play it cuz I
hate to hear a crappy phone interview on
a podcast but I'm gonna try to get Sean
and Jessi back for a soil recycling
episode really soon I've got a lot of
cool stuff lined up the cannabis cup is
coming up here pretty soon actually it's
my birthday right now so I got a lot of
fun [ __ ] happening this week um if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like us to review send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com and
I'll get you all the information that
you need also don't forget to check out
our sponsors the rocky mountain warm
company and Highgrove indoor growing
supplies don't forget about the new
coupon code at nature's green remedies
calm that coupon code is spring of 15
Wow as I was saying that Yankee from
nature's green remedies just messaged me
to confirm that he got the new coupon
code I gave him that is pretty neat so
that coupon code is up and active you
guys spring 15 at nature's drain
remedies dot-com now this show's over
please go to iTunes or stitcher
go to the iTunes Store or
yeah go to the iTunes store search for
girl from your heart or on stitcher you
got to find the review section do it on
the individual episodes I guess cuz
sister sucks for leaving reviews give me
a five star rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode
like I said stitcher keeps changing the
way the comments are done on there just
leave a comment and I will do my best to
find it if you have something to say
you're not into the social media thing
you can always email me girl from your
heart at hotmail.com don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is archived on
I read genetics Colorado comm we did add
a donation to the podcast page on the
website if you feel like the show is
worth a few bucks you can go to my
website I read genetics Colorado com
click on the girl for my heart podcast
tab at the top right there's a donation
button that goes directly to my personal
PayPal account
I'll never charged anybody anything for
this podcast this podcast will always be
free this comes from my heart for you
I'm not asking for anything but if you
feel like you want to make a donation
don't be shy just click on there you can
throw in $1.00 there's no limit on what
you can throw in one listener emailed me
excuse me one email one listener emailed
me and told me that he would actually
donate to it if I put the button up
there and I had my web guy put the
button up and he has not contributed yet
so I'm hoping that he hears this cuz my
web guy spent a few minutes I'm just
being a smartass you guys find me on
Facebook search for gruffly heart follow
me on Twitter search for its GF yeh
podcast fall I regen etics on Instagram
let me give you a huge huge shout-out to
my ninja Spence also big shout outs my
friends that were in town visiting from
Mississippi this week what's up Jeff
what's up John
hope you guys listened to the podcast
had a great time with you this week had
a great dinner last night
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 56 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're a pro grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or if you're just
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host Rasta Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always
before we get started I have to send a
big huge thank-you shout out to cuckoo
cat for the mystic roots band thanks a
lot for letting me use your music
joining me today again is one of our
heroes welcome back dude we got king
Cola to the left are you bro good man
I'll do thanks for coming we're excited
about this sean is going to drop some
knowledge on you guys today that is
going to [ __ ] up your whole thought
process that Mike has impotency problems
it likes to droop after a while I'm not
my word is not law by any means but this
is just my how I grew this is what I
have discovered through my personal
studies but I just want to say stop
using molasses in your teas and yeah I
mean completely and the main reason is
is a lot of people are using molasses on
a regular basis typically when you ask
somebody what they're using in your
compost tea and the same for me um I
think probably on the first episode I
probably even recommended certain rates
to use molasses at I think to not you
know sue I mean you just this is an
evolving industry everything changes we
learn as we go but uh so I cut more I
heard a while ago basically you need to
quit use them somebody told me you need
to quit using molasses I said why and
they order you know I'll get back to you
I never heard from him again
but it's stuck in my head so I quit
using molasses just cut it out and
I didn't see a difference you know I
mean it's not like things quit working
so it's not acting like the but hardener
and the sweeter like we think it is
maybe yeah you know I didn't I didn't
see it I'm doing my thing and then I get
back in touch with this person and we
kind of discussed a little more and a
lot of people like I was saying for a
basic compost tea what I used to
recommend and what a lot of people are
using her earthworm castings or Alaskan
houmous or some sort of humic acid
they're using molasses and then they're
using like a kelp meal or something well
the reason that you use that molasses
and the tea is actually not for the
reason that you had mentioned early when
you use excuse me when you use the
molasses and a tea it's not for not so
much as a bud hardener for the airplane
it's not so much a carbohydrate for the
plant as it is a food source for the
microbes and the tea right okay and the
thing with molasses is it's a simple
carbohydrate and simple carbohydrates
feed simple organisms and that's the
simplest way to say it so molasses is an
extremely strong bacterial food you've
probably heard before that marijuana is
a fungal Dom in a plant they like fungal
dominant ease especially in flour so by
using molasses you're gonna be
encouraging bacterial growth well the
molasses not only feeds the bacteria but
it feeds it an enormous rate bacteria is
naturally occurring it's everywhere it's
already in the soil it's on our skin
it's everywhere and in between so it's
already gonna be there in your teeth
it's gonna be in your water it's gonna
be in your soil you know probably some
of it's already gonna be in molasses so
there's plenty of bacteria out there as
you add this molasses you start to feed
this bacteria and the bacteria starts to
eat the food and they start to digest
and what happens is the growth of the
bacteria happens too fast and the
organisms will actually use up all of
the available food and oxygen resources
so you actually drop the dissolved
oxygen levels in your tea so putting
molasses in your AACT
will take out one of those days it will
make it go anaerobic and you will no
longer be having an aerated compost tea
despite you having bubblers running
you're still gonna take out the oxygen
you lower the dissolved oxygen levels
then you're just harvesting anaerobic
bacteria basically killing off
everything we're working to create
exactly by adding the thing that we
thought was fueling our fire exactly
okay by adding molasses you're just
taking out everything that you just put
all of your money and time into you're
just growing the bacteria to phenomenal
rate they're out competing everything
else and that's eventually what you put
on your plant I just googled fungal
dominance we can do an entire episode on
that just by what I'm reading yes if you
want to catch up google fungal dominance
I can't even begin to explain it there
is so much going on and fungal dominance
Wow that'll change your thinking but
right there yeah definitely so with the
teas like I was saying it so when you
add the molasses it can drop the
dissolved oxygen levels for anybody
who's listening here wants to know
specifically above eight parts per
million of dissolved oxygen is where you
want your teas that's when you're
brewing aerobic organisms between six
parts per million and aist parts per
million you are facilitating anaerobic
zones these organisms out-compete the
aerobic organisms at a rate of two to
one these facilitate anaerobic zones
this is where some really nasty things
live
these things are in your compost you
were like these bad organisms are in
your compost such as you know really
anaerobic or e.coli or these other
things just nasties they're gonna
multiply at an alarming rate once you
start and creating this anaerobic
environment and if you use that as a
foliar spray you just sprayed eco light
under your plants right yeah and that's
the thing is they actually like when you
your tea starts to do that the organisms
are produce acids that kill anaerobic
organisms and high enough qualities
these acids can stress and kill your
plant you know growing environment
anywhere is there a shortage of bacteria
so there's no need to just feed more of
them and stress your plants out and
there's other options instead of
molasses so right off the bat just cut
it out so if you want to do a tea what I
would recommend would be okay but yeah
so if you're gonna start a tea I would
just go with worm castings I would go
with kelp meal and that's just about it
castings and kelp meal yeah I'm sorry
I'm trying to any I've got everything
right now so yeah there you go he's got
a whole computer and further than you
guys had to come prepared
he came well-prepared I kind of peeked
at his notes a minute ago he's got a lot
of info yes so we've got so basically
for a really basic compost tea I'm gonna
roll with dr. Alaine Ingram's compost
tea so her teas are basically compost or
you know worm castings or whatever you
can source kelp meal and then you can
add in instead of molasses you can add
in a humic source so you can add in like
a humic acid derived from peat like a
dragon fire with medicines brilliant
black there's a lot actually yeah
there's a lot of different options out
there but you can add in a few
acid or in that place you could add
enough fish hide really so for your bass
T's every time I would just go with worm
castings in water outside of that you
can add in kelp meal or alfalfa meal or
anything like that specific to your
stage your plant stage in life and then
if you want to start adding foods for
the fungi basically if you're in veg
fish hydro slate also for vegetative
growth instead of using molasses replace
it with fish Hydra sleep now fish hide
really it can it can go the same way as
molasses it can turn your tea anaerobic
really fast and I know you're probably
thinking anaerobic well you know you
I've personally talked about anaerobic
teas and do Kashi and all of these
things which is you know they're
actually integrate with fermentation
sinaner it in terrific compost that's
completely different that's because we
want anaerobic environments we don't
want anaerobic bacteria in our aerobic
teas okay you know so they're separate
but equal that you are exactly
fermenting don't let oxygen get into it
and when you're reading don't let it go
stagnant so as far as food for your teas
like I was saying if you need to improve
your fungal count which everybody wants
to everybody wants a fungal Domenic
you can add a steel-cut oat bran or
steel-cut oat bran Crowder shrimp pills
I mean there's any sort of really any
sort of like high protein we can just
pick that up at the health food store
you can pick all of that alright
actually there's a lot of like it seen a
lot of stuff on people or people are
starting to consume like fish Hydra
slaves and stuff I mean I wouldn't be
surprised if you can pick that up at the
health food store soon eventually right
but yes so just molasses I mean take it
how you want it you know take it or
leave it I recommend cutting it out I
think I've learned from very reputable
sources and you know they're these
aren't people just you know talking [ __ ]
these are real scientists these guys are
sitting there in front of their
microscopes and they're strain in their
minds in their eyes so we don't have to
know I don't think you need to try to
give yourself any sort of credit or your
sources you've been on here enough and I
think people have realized that you are
definitely not full of [ __ ] well thank
you we respect your opinion well thank
you I've been at this for years and you
teach me stuff every time you come I
really appreciate it yes I mean just cut
cut the molasses out of your teas I used
to use it every [ __ ] day and like
every time my last batch of tea you know
I didn't see much of a difference I used
I used used to use your recommendation
or the Rebs recommendation of molasses
MIT and I made a tea just a few days ago
with some focus bucket leachate in there
and I actually got way more foam without
the molasses on that bucket than I've
ever made
that's the best you have ever made was
my most recent without the molasses yeah
I mean love yeah you're gonna get better
results using beneficial microorganisms
using things like cold processed fish hi
drew Slade like the Browns fish hide
really you grab from Rocky Mount worm
company or you can make your own fish
hide really but those food sources work
way better they're way more natural but
just like us if we eat natural food our
body absorbs it much more naturally pull
out the nutrients and poop out the crap
instead you're able to absorb what
you're eating it should be so you can
eaten a pop-tart or an apple yeah
you know how does your body run off of
it but uh yeah the so forties just keep
it simpler the better
you know just run your castings run you
know your kelp if you want to add a food
source you can I like I really like fish
hide really during veg you see
tremendous vegetative growth and then
that's how you really step away from
bottled nutrients you know that way if
you are using bottled nutrients the only
one you're using is a fish product what
are we using what are we using to feed
vt in bloom you keep saying surfer if
you're gonna feed your tea and bloom
soft rock phosphate there we go yeah
that's a lot in your GT so sorry
phosphate but that goes right back in
till you need to know what you're using
how much you're using where you're
sourcing it from you go and you dump
astronomical amount of stuff rock
phosphate on your plant you're gonna you
know like I said that goes right back to
you can be organic and you can be worse
than all your synthetic buddies out
there right I actually I think I
overused some OGT because I wasn't I was
thinking oh so GT let's [ __ ] it up so I
fed it instead of every two weeks I was
doing it every week because I wasn't
paying attention and I think the plants
sped up too much like you said because
they were burnt they were showing
nitrogen deficiencies in like week five
yeah and I think they're just going to
fix like the trichoderma the experience
that they have in there but he has soft
rock phosphate also in there which works
as a food for the microbes you know it's
a fungal food but you can also get your
phosphates obviously from introducing
that into the tea so it's a great that's
a great source of if you need a blue tea
for say theoretically you should have
all of that a minute in your soil and
it'll just kind of take up what it wants
which kind of rolls into what we were
yeah that was our original idea today
was to talk about building a little bit
of soil so I believe you I like you guys
molasses is unnecessary those are
old-school farmer tricks we were taught
that uh try it yourself make us do a
test run set one set of plants on one
side of the room one set on the other
add molasses to one say
tea or however you're feeding ad Milan
don't add molasses together see the
difference for yourself it's you're not
gonna see enough difference to like
break the bank or anything so give it a
try yeah and I mean keep your molasses
around I use it for plenty of stuff f
PJ's a lot of the yeah a lot of the
Korean farming techniques that I do
a lot of the homemade fertilizers I use
molasses and like I said if you're gonna
use it for your sweetener purposes or
your hardener purposes or your foliar
sprays or if you use it for stuff but
don't use it for the teas food source
and don't use it every time don't use it
for your teas food source guys we're
over or like over amping the tea
basically we're making hyper little tea
is all little kids just like sugar yeah
they're all competing everybody yeah all
right so you have four soil mixes for
this one I know that everybody has their
own mix everybody has their way of doing
things they're super soils and there's
layers and there's no till there's a
million ways to do everything so I just
I figured maybe the best way to go about
it would be to kind of just discuss you
know what what they are so okay that
sounds great yes a super soil super
soils are a term for a nutrient charged
soil a sub cool is the father of super
so yeah cool made it really famous and
basically the idea is you're gonna
create this nutrient rich mixture soil
and you're gonna layer the bottom if
your pot with it and then you're gonna
plant your plant actually into a less
hot medium like so you would use a
bagged soil and you would take your five
gallon container and you fill the bottom
so many inches up with your super soil
mix and then add in your bag soil and
then actually transplant you're playing
into it theoretically you water your
plant the roots grow through the bagged
soil medium into the super soil
then you never have to fertilize your
plant you can just always feed a water
you know every times everything
everything's already mixed cannabis oil
bottle so that's one method of mixing
another method for a lot of people is
just like a complete through-and-through
mix so like a dragon fire if medicine
just does it really really awesome mix
where they do it's similar to the super
soil but it's actually incorporated
throughout the entire mix okay so you
don't like the whole thing exactly so
there is no like layering and you don't
pad it with you know other soil what
they'll do is they they make their soil
and then they do what's a term called
cooking which is just composting so they
let their soil sit for a couple of weeks
or a month you know the longer the
bedroom and by doing that you can really
encourage natural processes and if you
go to Dragonfly with medicines feed
they've got some really cool things
about how they'll you know if the soil
that's cooking they'll treat with
[ __ ] and lactic acid bacteria and
they pour all their excess compost teas
on it and you can do these things too
while your soil cooks but they do them
like really it's more of a botanical
mixture they use like a kelp meal
alfalfa nettle you can go to their
website to their feats and kind of find
out I don't want to give away all their
got some check out dragon flavors
medicine will get them on the show
they're in Canada they said they were
gonna come here and then they had to go
back to Canada or Washington there right
bike in Pacific Northwest they're just
holding it down up there actually
they're in Europe right now if they went
to like Prague do an interview with me
and they're gonna tell me about all the
things they've seen around the world
that'll be great yeah but they've been
protecting the soil mix for a while and
you know I mention them cuz they do like
a completely botanical base you know
everything's plant-based with their
mixes I know a lot of other people are
traditionally doing especially like with
the Rev and some other people moonshine
man and there's a lot other mixes out
there which you're all bone meal blood
meal phosphates it's real similar to sub
cools mix but it's the same idea that
you mix it throughout the whole batch
and you let it cook for a period of time
and then you go into it and we gotta get
away from the blood meal the bone yeah
yeah there's an alternative to mania
bone meal a soft rock phosphate comfrey
metal yarrow
fishbone meal there's other options
blood meal which is your nitrogen source
yeah there's I don't even need to like
get in there there's so many other
nitrogen alfalfa yeah there's there's so
many other nitrogen sources I don't even
need to cover that but uh I mean
definitely source where your products
are coming from me personally I go with
a very simple mix I use typically I like
to mix my own soil base the best mixture
I've ever used personally was it's a
product called Malibu compost it's a
biodynamic compost blend it's [ __ ]
awesome it's only available in
California it's really hard to get here
I was fortunate enough to come across a
couple of bags and it was probably some
of the best properties but it takes
compost it's not a soil mix whose in
California that can send us a couple of
bags of that hook me up please
here we need that Malibu compost I'll
give you my p.o box number just took me
up yeah but it's a biodynamic blintz
they have like yarrow and nettle and up
dandy lines and all sorts of cool stuff
mixed in there but uh so I used so I'll
use a compost and then cut it in with
perlite I'm not sorry not perfectly I
use a compost I think I cut it in with
worm castings so I make my own like
vermicompost
so use the
yeah the Malibu's compost Rocky Mount
worm castings and then I'll add in an
aerator which is typically a lot of
people use perlite
I don't like perlite so much so I use a
Diana might because I've got a huge bag
of it I've had for like years I'm still
working through it but you can use like
Pumas or lava rock I'd like to recommend
people use things that don't go away as
fast you know
perlite floats to the top and it grinds
up really fine and it just kind of goes
away to nothing but I always recommend
people to do like 50 percent like lava
rock or Pumas or Diana my something that
doesn't break down as quick and then do
another 50 the other half do like a rice
whole or buckwheat whole okay or some
more of a carbon-based aerator alright
so yeah we put in our aerator and then
after your compost in your aerator then
you make the decision of whether or not
you're gonna want to use coco coir or
peat moss I like peat moss but I like
the environment to all comes from like
one swamp in Canada or something
organics it seems like it's always
awesome but it's not always the best you
just kind of got to pick what you want
I've actually found best result I like a
mixture of cocoa and peat moss there's
something about the oils that come from
the cocoa fibers that the plant really
likes yeah I have really like a mix of
I've been plenty to take a DAB so you
better keep talking oh you again yeah
I've been playing around with different
ratios 50 50 75 25 of cocoa 2 peat moss
but I kind of like a half-and-half
mixture with it and then outside of that
will go in and then add a kelp meal
crustacean neem oyster shell powder
glacial rock dust jimson if we really
want to get into it we'll add your
biochar mukashi and a lot of other
natural farming inputs but that's
personally for like my home growth I can
give into it with that stuff but you
guys can't - listen to this episode hit
pause and rewind all that stuff and
listen back and make a list and if you
can't afford to buy a bunch of [ __ ] by
the first - yeah and the next time buy
the buy three of them and then you'll
make a better soil every every time and
we'll start you'll start seeing good you
should get great results right often I
usually if you think if you if you play
it back and you think it's too
overwhelming I see what I do work with
the dispensaries a lot you know I run a
consultation company so if any of you
guys out there know anybody who I hate
the word column i interesting i'm we do
consultations but if anybody out there
wants to switch you know any facilities
that want to switch we're all licensed
over here natural farming and you know
we've got our cards we can go in and
help your favorite grow convert to
organics but I work with a couple of
different shops and they always seem a
little overwhelmed when I come in there
and I started running my mouth about
mixing soils and you're gonna get this
and this and you're gonna mix it
together and it's overwhelming they like
that when you can walk in there and you
can be like yep buy a pallet of this you
want a pallet of that so I've actually
got a mixture for everybody out there
who wants to go and just buy a pallet of
soil or you want to go buy a bale of
pro-mix or some sunshine for so just go
and grab your sunshine for your Pro mix
I recommend cutting in worm castings 10%
for your microbial source
then I would just add in depending on
what you're going with so if you go with
like a sunshine for Advance they've got
like a nutrient starter pack which is I
think there's some like minerals in
there other things like that yeah that
one's a really good one to go with and
then just add in your worm castings kelp
meal mmm cake and crustacean meal or
oyster shell powder just kind of
depending on how you want to grow
personally okay but that's it that's
that's a good start right there I've
I've tried them out like right now if
you go to the king underscore Cola feed
on Instagram you can look at the there's
pictures of worms just all over the
containers and your top soils move in
and that's actually all done in sunshine
for with kelp mean crustacean an oyster
shell fabric nice I really simple I mean
I feel like I'm getting some of the best
results that I've ever had with this
super the between this mix and then the
mix I'd mentioned earlier with Malibu
compost are probably the two best
results I've gotten since I've started
okay it's so hard to source a solid like
place to get compost so if you can't do
that and you can't make your own compost
[Music]
over the past three or four weeks I
don't know how long I've been talking
about the [ __ ] bucket but I see it
turning into funk inside that bucket and
I will have that's a five-gallon bucket
essentially I'll have five gallons of
compost to add to a whole bunch of dirt
and then a month or two I will have my
own amazing compost started from May
exactly and I mean even they even buying
soil from the store using the nicest
castings that money can buy like Rocky
Mount warm castings and it's still crazy
and then after amending the soil soil
it's amazing how cheap this stuff comes
out I'm not gonna say the name of this
thick shot that I'm working for but
I will say that they're running 488 20
gallons and when we priced him out at $1
20 per gallon of soil wow that's amazing
so suckle now and synthetics and that's
for a dispensary so they have to rely on
quality products I hate to sneak in a
commercial but I have to do them and
this is a great time because a lot of
what we're talking about the organic
portion this portions I'm gonna try this
commercial again the organic portions of
this episode Chris sponsored by my
friends at the rocky mountain worm
company visit the rocky mountain one
company in Colorado Springs for fresh
worm castings African nightcrawlers red
wigglers and all of your soil amendments
the rock you met worm company has
dragonfly earth medicine products in
stock right now we've been talking about
that a lot they have the fish hydro
slates there they've got brilliant black
humic from dragon fire earth medicine
they have a lot of the stuff we talked
about you can grab right there
it's a Rocky Mountain worm company so go
there you can actually get their
products if you're listening far away
you get the product shipped to your door
and get the same worm casting shot and I
use in our Gardens many of the same
amendments check out WWWE need calm or
if you're in Colorado Springs Denver or
Pueblo drive to 4:11 Tijuana Street in
Colorado Springs Colorado and make sure
you tell them you heard the about them
on the girl from your art podcast that'd
be really cool I know there are two more
quick ads just cuz I have to get them
done these guys pay for this and I feel
bad if I don't do them he's got so much
good [ __ ] to say of course this podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
hi girl indoor growing supplies hi grow
undergroung supplies has two locations
to serve Colorado check out the Denver
store 618 no Denver store sixty to
seventy one Beach Street the Pueblo
location 618 East 4th Street and
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor girl supplies
all the stuff I'm not able to get at the
rocky mountain worm company I pick it
all up at hydro indoor growing supplies
my lights my bulbs my neoprene for Mike
Lohner
nutrients for Mike Lohner all that stuff
comes from hydro you guys so when you're
shopping there tell them you listen to
the girl from your heart podcast you'll
get commercial pricing you'll save a few
bucks on everything you buy it really
helps out it makes it worth going there
if they don't have what you want let
them know they will order it for you
they're sweet shout out to Bern shout it
to Jessie and also share it to LaDonna
growers meeting there last night big
huge shout out to everybody that showed
up dude that place was packed it was
cloudy in there that was a good ass time
blast dad I promise
podcast is brought to you by nature's
green remedies dot-com if you need some
new beans and a new seed some high-grade
genetics go to nature's green remedies
com they've got gage green lopata lab
sin city rare dankness mile hike an
adventure the cali connection
I read genetics and many more leading
brands right now they have a coupon code
type in coupon code it is spring 15 for
15% off any order and free shipping at
nature's green remedies dot-com all
right I didn't want to interrupt the
show if those guys paid me money for
that so what else you got on making your
own soil or do you want to talk about
something different no I think that's it
this is a good point to go back to high
gray oh I do want to mention because I
feel like we've been taught I don't want
to know be other people we're talking
about no I mean because I was telling
people to go and grab soil mix you know
yeah yeah I work with Jesse a little bit
and we'll try to get we'll call it a
Rocky Mountain natural farming mix up
there for you at the stores I mean they
already carry in the soil they've
already got the castings up there
they've got grow Kashi up there yeah
yeah you talked to Jesse we can get you
fixed with the Rocky Mountain a chiral
farming mix which is like I said it's
mean pro-mix sunshine for kelp
crustacean mean get to rockin well
pretty good hey guys here's my idea I
want you to set up one little section
just a shelf so we can just walk right
there and get this stuff like it'll be
the girl from your heart rocky mountain
worm castings Highgrove indoor growing
supplies little bonus section and just
go right there be some girl Kashi there
for you to be so awesome let's do this
guy's that's my proposal to you guys if
you can't if you can't source compost
and all of that jazz then go to your
local hydro store high-growth and grab
your bagged soil get you some basic
amendments and the the trick is is to
figure out what works for you I don't
like this the one-size-fits-all idea of
growing
because it doesn't you know I mean you
probably water completely different like
that if I used your soil mixing method I
would probably slaughter those plans
I guarantee I'd kill every single one of
them and then you do the same thing in
my style does that mean that you're a
better grower than me or vice versa no
it doesn't exactly it's just a matter of
you've got to dial it in you know I
would recommend starting out with the
pro mix or a sunshine for once you get a
grower to down with that and your really
basic soil amendments then all sunshine
for in pro mixes is peat moss and an
aerator and you know those products last
one was done it with sunshine for
products yeah and you know yeah I think
people get overwhelmed when you start
talking about the conversion to organics
but if they only knew how close they
already were so many synthetic growers
are using sunshine for and they're using
pro mix it's like well next time you do
that just add in on microbial source
like earthworm castings add in some kelp
meal you know to help prevent against
you know fungus gnats and white flies
and spider mites add in some name cake
or crustacean meal yeah I mean easy
stuff like that right at you're mixing
soil anyway you should be yeah oh you
shouldn't I don't think you should open
the bag and start pulling out of the bag
you should dump it into something kind
of spread it out I was surprised to
learn the sin that like I said I've
always grown organically so I always I
see a lot of the commercial synthetic
growers and kind of how they're doing
stuff and I was really surprised to see
even name in the [ __ ] out of their soil
I mean they're growing you know in Pro
mix and that it would pour and the end
they're still ready to drink until it
all yeah
it was something we were trying to talk
to a friend about last night is finding
that balance between the worm castings
and the advanced nutrients he's like can
I do this and we were trying to tell him
gently that your advanced is just gonna
kill all that stuff bro throw away those
advanced bottles yeah if you're wanna
make the if you want to make the switch
then you need to not get advanced
nutrients go get something like a
general organics or roots organic yeah I
mean even if you were to go age-old is a
really old-school product it really is
so cheap and I know so many people who
crush it with I've got a friend who
grows nothing but I regen etics with
nothing but a jolt and it's so cheap I
mean you wanna talk about low cost of
production who cares if I mean you know
yo yields good but even if you did it's
so [ __ ] cheap you're only paying for
power right yeah that's the truth and
it's the beauty of organics organics I'm
making a switch and I love it I've
really seen a difference in my plants
they perform better
they don't seem and I do cannabis for a
long time the plants always seemed like
they were thriving to me and now that
I'm using the organics I can see that I
was missing something they look they
just look they're waxy err they don't
have they have more the cuticles on the
leaves are thicker the stems are more
robust and I was feeding I've fed all
the commercial brands of nutrients
before and I'm definitely noticing a
difference with just basic and just
small jumps to organics it's not even
anything major and then you told me you
since you come from
listen thetic growth is it easier I hear
a lot of people tell me it's more
complicated but I am NOT the move I mean
I do a lot of other stuff I'm not in my
grill like I used to be at my plants are
fine the way I think this seems to make
more sense to me than mixing up bottles
like a scientist
yeah and I've read all of my bottles
anyway so I know what that's coming from
like I know that that's chicken [ __ ]
seabird guano why don't I just use
chicken [ __ ] seabird guano yeah and I
think I didn't trust myself to make
those mixtures I thought I'd burn
something or whatever but there are so
many guides between you the red
and every forum on the internet I can
find the correct mixture for everything
the podcast now this is a good you're
gonna be way more forgiving to you
putting the guan i wanted then to you
putting a bottled nutrient that's got
guano in it on it
very true that's more concentrated and i
can definitely add too much of that way
easily exactly yeah I don't even like
using guano I'm gonna stay away from any
kind of [ __ ] guano is actually extremely
unsustainable to harvest and then it's
really bad for you to breathe in but I
know a lot of people are diehard about
it and personally I think like produces
really awesome outdoor waters pretty
banging for outdoor there's other
options but hey if we're dissing your
growing methods I'm sorry we're not
dissing it we're just trying to
encourage you to do more sustainable
healthier things do what you want do
actually you're gonna get it if you if
you're okay with it go for it yeah I
don't eat meat you know I don't eat GMO
foods I live my life a certain lifestyle
that I try to live by and I incorporate
that all the way into the medicine and
the plants that I grow so yeah I don't
force it I hang out with people who we
meet they hang out with people who are
synthetics like it's no big like to each
his own you don't have to I really I get
attacked a lot on Instagram and a lot of
these like other places when I feel like
when I try to put information out there
I feel like it get met with a lot of
resistance but I'm not telling p.m. not
trying to tell people how to do things
I'm just trying to give it put
information out there so please don't
argue with me if you like it take it in
you know if you don't I'm following me
there's other Instagram pages to troll
but that being said if you if you ever
have questions and you're serious and
you want to know something just direct
message me email me email Jeff yeah I
got your back you will get you know
we'll get you the knowledge he needs
yeah we know we've got resources for all
kinds of knowledge I was funny because
we were at a growers meeting last night
in Sean and I were both stumped on
something and people looked at us like
well what the [ __ ] if you guys don't
know then what is the answer we're never
seen that so I don't know give me three
days to research it we'll find out but
right now you might have to call Jim
Ferrer people have this like they've got
this idea that we can just look at one
picture on your phone are you gonna send
me one direct message and I'm gonna know
what you fed him for the past three
weeks yeah we'll try yeah we'll try
sometimes yeah that one last night was a
weird challenge I don't know what it was
as powdery something they'll do wish
that was a case of all - it's all too
familiar like I know him person I was
actually working with him on that before
the meeting he was introduced to me
through a friend of mine but uh yeah I
thought it was powdery mildew originally
and then we thought it was a pH problem
and he thought it was new law and it's
all too familiar of a problem he
actually you know wasn't too familiar
with growin I went to the local hydro
store not high grow because if you you
know Jesse would have helped him the guy
would have been killing it but he goes
to these horrible competitors here in
town and they set him up only he thinks
his cocoa they give him a cocoa nutrient
he's running it turns out it's peat moss
it happens and he's learned so much and
he's his plants are still alive even
after all of that you know like I mean
is we so [ __ ] up pictures of them but
hey they're still kicking yeah he makes
it to harvest that's what counts you
know but uh
press reverance you know you just gotta
keep stay committed to it don't if you
think that I grew beautiful plants every
time you're out of your mind that I've
done
I'll admit one time I had and this was
years ago the first time it was the
first time I said I was in a new house
growing in a brand new basement in the
middle of winter and I'd never grown in
there before and you got a dial in a
room but I had a White Rhino plant in a
seven gallon pot there probably weighed
between five and six ounces and I went
to cut it down and I noticed powdery
mildew all up the one side that was near
the exterior wall corner so that wall
was colder than the whole rest of the
room and he got powdery mildew it was
ugly [ __ ] my buddy Mike was there
helping me trim I say Mike watch this
I'm gonna chop the plant and usually
he's got a hand on it when I cut it so
that it doesn't timber you know and I
just cut that son of a [ __ ] right to
the ground just timber and he hit the
floor he looked me like what the hell
man I was like there's powdery mildew on
it we're throwing the whole plant away
it happens I mean people ask me all the
time how do you know if it works that's
how thousands and thousands of dollars
worth of juice just do but if you're
gonna try something crazy trying on one
plant if you have the option yeah don't
do something ridiculous
I've been trying extreme defoliation on
one planet I won't do it to it more than
one I see a difference and I like it
honestly guys I doubted it and I learned
this the hard way every scientific
experiment for God's sake make sure you
have a control we forget a lot of [ __ ]
six-month trial notes we should go for
about five more minutes guys the last
episode was short and you listen to
every minute of it I can see the stats I
can tell how long you listen
holy crap thanks for listening to the
whole thing that was cool I appreciate
that I hope you like that solo episode
that's hard to do solo shows I feel like
we cover to do the molasses thing is
gonna be the ground breaker for the
episode I like that we've covered soil
pretty well you have any wrap-up notes
for soil keep it simple there you go
keep it simple stoner all right huge
thanks for coming 45 minutes before we
even
which is awesome so awesome people like
how long does it take and I'm like a lot
of two or three hours when you get here
because [ __ ] today is a special day
you guys I might get teary-eyed for this
I had to save it to the end happy
birthday Jenny Kush we love you today
this episode is being recorded on the on
Jimmy cushions birthday should be 36 I
can't talk too much about it because
it'll make me cry happy birthday Jenny
we love you we miss you wish we wish you
were still here with us guys Jenny
Google Ginnie cush if you can check her
out you must support Jenny cushion the
movement um green and healthy cannabis
and Terp ex love you guys big shout out
on the next episode I was told that
Spence in the garden of Weeden are
coming so hopefully we can get Spence
over here he says he's coming tomorrow
night to record I hope he brings Maddie
Big Mike's invited this will be a good
time also I am going to record what the
grimy gatsby enter pecks next week so we
got an episode coming up with those guys
I'm taking the recording equipment up to
Colorado Springs gonna go hang out at
the turkey boy house and hit the mother
ship whatup guys I cannot wait to come
I've been talking about golden goat and
lemon Geoffrey seeds they're right on
schedule so I'm saying like 85 80 days
from now we should have some new seeds
ready on the next episode I'm gonna talk
to ya I think the next episode I'm gonna
talk to Spence about [ __ ] rosin dude
rosin soil grown in the rosin thing man
I had a whole bunch of food grade good
cooking grade or whatever you want to
call it from my last wash my last
harvest
I mean jars full of it sitting in the
cupboard with some new things called
rosin tech if you guys are gonna try
making rosin tech don't burn yourselves
that's all I've got to say because
that's gonna hurt we've seen rosin tech
happened then we've seen people follow
suit and now I'm waiting for the rosin
tech burns that's what's gonna be next
also if you're on Instagram check out
dragon fighters medicine
holy [ __ ] you'll learn a lot of great
things something I want to talk about
more in the future is the Bokashi bucket
it's something I'm experimenting with
right now great results cannot believe I
didn't do this earlier thanks a lot to
Rocky Mount one company and Shawn for
hooking me up with that that's really
cool no problem game changer dude I
added the the liquid that came out of
there too
worm tea and it's the best warranty I've
ever made and I saw results within 24
hours on my plants and then everybody up
there check out the Bokashi bucket on
Instagram they actually have their own
page they're a super awesome group of
guys down in Hawaii actually I gave one
of the guys one of their first dabs here
it was actually the Emerald cup but I
was daven him out on some fool melt yeah
shout out to the Bokashi bucket guys
they're great guys yeah or your if the
rocky mountain world company does have
them but if you're not near us you can
get them the Bokashi bucket guys have a
website or also Whole Foods sells them
so there's a Whole Foods in your area go
check out the chicks and the yoga pants
and ugg boots and pick yourself up a bow
Kashi bucket I don't think there's much
left to say we've done a lot of work
people have probably took four pages of
notes because I took a page and a half
myself I know you write down a bunch of
notes I hope you went through seven or
eight pages on this episode she really
listens yeah you're changing growing for
a lot of people I'll be back another
news episode or something I'll post it
up in the midweek I want to start doing
that I just I get overwhelmed with time
I don't forget to check out our sponsors
the rocky mountain warm company hydro
indoor growing supplies and make sure
you visit nature's green remedies calm
for your seeds and use coupon code
spring 15 for 15% off if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like me to
review send me an email it's girl from
your heart at hotmail.com and I'll get
you all the information you need please
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for girl from your heart find the
review section give me a five star
rating because we're badass right if
you're that type in a comment let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode stitcher keeps messing with the
way the comments are displayed and
handled so I'll leave the comment
wherever you can there and I will find
it don't read it you're not into social
media you can't email me it's girlfriend
calm don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm my papers got hash all over it's
all sticky that was great a donation
button to the page on the website if you
liked the show and you think it's worth
a few bucks you go to the website I read
genetics Colorado calm click on the girl
from your heart podcast tab at the top
right is a donation button that goes
directly to my PayPal account
I'll never charge you guys anything for
the podcast every episode will always be
free all this information that Shawn
brought today was free I should pay him
for it cuz it was so awesome I'm gonna
give him a couple dabs
but I'll never charge you anything for
the show if you feel like this show was
worth something you can make a
contribution and it'll go to my PayPal
account and I will say thank you want a
show if you'd like
I truly appreciate it we're on all the
social media sites just search for us
whatever you use make sure you follow us
on Twitter
it's G f YH podcast big wall shout outs
went in just minutes thanks again for
listening until next time take a big fat
dad let's give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world the star
episode number 57 of the girl from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation if
you're new grower a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a veteran
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host Rasta Jeff thanks again for joining
me as always I want to send a big huge
thank-you shout out to the mystic roots
band for letting me use their music on
the show big huge thanks to cat and coot
and the whole mystic roots crew myself
picked up at nugs with screen and
healthy cannabis and Colorado Springs
this is some delicious I really like
this we're gonna turn down the music
and we're gonna read some news I've got
in iTunes comment to read but before we
get that far this episode were sponsored
by my good friends at the rocky mountain
worm company visit the rocky mountain
worm company in Colorado Springs for
fresh worm castings African night
crawlers red wigglers and all of your
organic soil amendments rocky mountain
worm company has dragonfly earth
medicine products in stock right now
Rocky Mountain worm company will ship to
your door
that's right they'll ship Rocky Mountain
worm castings the same worm castings
that I use and many of the same
amendments that I use will get shipped
straight to your door just check out
www.sceeto.com Rado Springs Colorado
area the store is located at 4:11
Tijuana Street in Colorado Springs
Colorado and make sure you tell them
that you heard about them through the
grow from your heart podcast also
portions of this show are brought to you
by my good friends at high grow indoor
growing supplies hi girll indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store at 62 71
beach street or check out the pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street and
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out high
grill for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor growing
supplies high grow a gross store ran by
folks who actually grow hi girls running
a special for the podcast listeners
hydro tell them you listen to the girl
from your heart podcast
and they will give you commercial
pricing on your entire purchase that's
right also the show is brought to you by
my good friends at nature's green
remedies dot-com what's up Yankee I hope
you're doing well my friend visit
nature's green remedies calm for gauge
green genetics lot of labs city rare
dankness mile high
MTG trusted brands for the podcast
listeners any order free priority
shipping in nature since the very
beginning the problem support all of our
sponsors if you're interested in
sponsoring the show send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
and I'll get you all of the information
that you need I'm gonna turn on the
music here it's a little loud in my ear
I turn that down and let's go to iTunes
and let's read in iTunes comment here it
is this comment is from white trike the
comment is this show is great keep it up
well thanks a lot for the comment white
trike I appreciate that I like hearing
that the show is great and I like the
encouragement so I definitely definitely
will keep it up thanks everybody that's
left a comment in the past let's go to
Twitter I've actually got a couple of
Twitter comments I want to read I feel
like I'm doing a Doug Benson kimete
stand-up comedy show because Doug Benson
just stands there and reads tweets the
whole time and that's kind of what I'm
doing to you guys but I like supporting
the listeners there wouldn't be a
podcast if there weren't listeners there
just be me talking into a mic for no
reason so I appreciate you guys a lot
scrolling through looking for this
notification here
where is it mr. Romney oh he says
sitting in the garden in the Sun while
listening to Rasta Jeff on the
girlfriend heart podcast explain warmth
Sting's benefits and see genetics
hashtag good life mr. Romney oh dude
thanks for listening to me while you're
gardening
that's what I'm hoping for I hope you
guys are in the garden learning stuff
while you're playing with the plant
maybe you're on the drive to or from
work maybe you're at work
hopefully I'm in you're here
entertaining you and teaching you
something about cannabis um also let's
see Adrian ghee the amazing Adrian he
said that girl uh could be here or she
let me check on your stuff I don't want
to call you he if you're a female I'm
sorry Adrian is kind of a unisex name no
that is a dude in that picture it's
definitely a dude so he Adrian says just
started listening to your podcast it's
great lots of good info and of course I
replied I said thanks for listening on
Twitter dude thanks for listening to
show that's what I'm here for I'm trying
to teach you guys trying to educate a
little bit trying to move cannabis
forward I think if we talk more
positively about this plant people will
be less afraid so all we got to do is
open the door to talk about it so again
big thanks and big shout out to white
write for the iTunes comment there if
you leave a comment on iTunes or
stitcher I will read it on the show you
guys and if you don't want to leave a
comment on iTunes or stitcher send me a
tweet it's at g f YH podcast or find me
on Facebook and I'll respond to you
there if you want to say something
anonymously you can send me a personal
or a private message and I will keep
your name private you can also email me
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I know that's a lot of contact
information but if you want to be in
touch I'd love to hear from you so I
said at the beginning of the show that I
had a bunch of news and stuff to talk
about so let's click on some stuff here
we go clicking away click click click
and I'm finding the first news article
the first news article is um it kind of
hits home here because I actually am a
medical marijuana caregiver the way you
become a caregiver all you really have
to do is have um so I'm a there's a
patient there's that's what we call the
person that smokes the medical marijuana
there's a patient that person goes to
the doctor they get their medical
marijuana recommendation and then when
you send that into the state of Colorado
you can assign a caregiver and that's
where my name goes on to that paper my
name and my address and a copy of my
idea
and to the state and I become a
caregiver which means I am now
responsible for growing medical cannabis
for my friend who signed me up and there
is a limit of five people that you're
allowed to be a caregiver for so you can
be you can have yourself plus five other
people and you can grow cannabis for
them um that's kind of how it was and
before you were allowed to have six
plants per person but then there are
doctors that are willing to write you an
extended plant count so if you say my
back hurts a lot or I've got
fibromyalgia and I don't smoke cannabis
I actually make oils out of all of this
and I need a lot more plants the doctors
will be a little compassionate and they
will write you what's called an extended
plant count and sometimes that cost you
more money but in the long run that's
worth it because you need your medicine
and I just allows you to grow more
plants and possess more cannabis so the
state is kind of caught on that some of
some people are going to the doctor and
there are some doctors in Colorado that
it just cost money if you want the
original six plants it's cheap you go in
there and pay a cheap like 45 50 dollar
visit if you want 12 plants they double
it if you want 25 plants they pretty
much quadruple your price if you're
wanting 50 plants you're paying five
times what you did before there are some
doctors that will write a 99 plant
recommendation for five hundred dollars
flat so you can grow 99 plants in your
house for five hundred dollars for one
here that's how it was but now they're
making all kinds of rules because they
have seen that what happens is a lot of
people sign up for 99 plants and if you
grow 99 seven gallon pots hopefully
you're pulling a whole bunch of weight
and then that's hitting the black market
and they're kind of aware of that and
they don't want that happening in the
state of Colorado anymore if they're
really trying to crack down and tax
every gram of pot that's produced I'm
gonna take a sip here and then I'll read
you this news article I've got
got some your Belmonte here it's nice
and hot be careful with that all right
so the this news article comes from a
website called the cannabis shout-out to
the cannabis I pull a lot of news
articles from this site this was
actually published February 26th so I'm
a little bit behind but this is still
relevant the article was by Joey bunch
of the Denver Post the headline is
Colorado MMJ caregiver bill clears
Senate Committee the article says a
state Senate Committee on Thursday
unanimously approved a bill that would
require medical marijuana caregivers to
register and allow state agencies to
share enough information to ensure pot
grown for medicine isn't sold illegally
while pot sold for recreational use has
been subject to a battery of tests and
regulations since it became legal last
year medical marijuana has gone
relatively unregulated requiring only
that caregivers be at least 18 years old
and have some significant responsibility
for the care of a licensed medical
marijuana user there's actually a spot
on the application that asks what
services you provide for your patient
I write spiritual counseling I write
that I drive them to and from their
doctor's appointments because a lot of
that is true I prepare meals for some of
my patients they ask for what you do so
you got to fill that in and actually
they have denied one of my care giver
requests I had to refill out to pay for
and put better reasoning because they
did not like my reasons why I was part
of their significant responsibility so
they are paying a little bit of
attention I'll get back to the article
it says the regulatory bill was
characterized by the state agency and
law enforcement officials as a benefit
to caregivers because those registered
would not have to face arrest or cost or
a costly legal proceedings if they're
registered with the state the bill is
supported by the Colorado cannabis
Chamber of Commerce the medical
marijuana supporters testified they were
concerned about cost from regulations
patient privacy and the risk risks of
untested medical marijuana this bill is
written really about assessing law
enforcement but it's doing so at the
expense of the rights of patients and
caregivers said Colorado marijuana
activist Robert chase who opposed to the
legislation legislation I'm sorry in
2009 when the US attorney general's
office advised federal agents not to
intervene in cases the
compliant with state laws medical
marijuana license have exploded in
Colorado in 2008 there were 4800 19
licensed medical marijuana patients in
Colorado said senator Irene Aguilar
as of last December there were a hundred
and fifteen thousand four hundred and
sixty-seven license loser users said
Aguilar at the bill Senate sponsor but
to keep federal regulators out of
Colorado's pot business the state must
regulate it adequately she said the
federal expectation is that states that
have allowed marijuana to be legal and
local governments will be implementing
strong and effective regulatory and
enforcement systems that will protect
Public Safety Public Health and law
enforcement interests she said while the
average age of Colorado medical
marijuana user
is 42 years old the number of children
has increased in the past two years on
indication spot helps children with
seizures and other illnesses in March
2013 Colorado had 35 patients younger
than 18 by last December the number of
minors had grown to 462 Aguilar said
Sierra riddle of Colorado Springs said
she moved from Utah in 2013 because her
son has cancer and needs medical
marijuana big shout at the team Landon
what's up I didn't even know Sierra was
gonna be mentioned in this article those
are people that we support in Colorado
Springs so support team Landon and
Sierra riddle if you can pick shadow the
amount of children that are increasing
on the medical marijuana registry needs
to be considered because it's only going
to increase more she said these rules
and laws need to be put in place to
protect our children to protect their
planet count and to protect our rights
to grow their plants now this article
kind of hits home because I'm a
caregiver myself and the local rules are
changing here to where we are we're
being reduced on the number of patients
we are allowed to have which will also
reduce the number of plants we are
allowed to have
and they have also reduced the amount of
space we are allowed to use so that
means the five people that I am
responsible for providing medical
marijuana to somebody is going to have
to find somebody else to grow their
medicine for them and the state doesn't
give a [ __ ] that I have been responsible
for them for the past seven or eight
years it has been my responsibility and
my duty to take care of these people I
have established a relationship with
them and I have a significant role in
caring for these people but the state
does not care they need to end that and
find a new caregiver to grow their
medical cannabis for them I think that's
[ __ ] because I know these people
I know what strains they like I have
bred strains for my patients yes that's
what I do I have people that smoke
medical cannabis and I will breed
strains for them the night nurse was
inspired by my friend Doug he's an older
cat and his body hurts and he has a hard
time sleeping when he smoked the Tora
Bora
he said holy [ __ ] when he smoked The
Grateful dog he said holy [ __ ] those
were two of his favorite strains ever so
I felt like it was my job to make a
hybrid of the two
and then find the right phenotype that
worked for Doug and when I grew those he
loved it and now guess what sorry Doug I
don't get to be your caregiver anymore
because the state doesn't give a [ __ ]
about our bona fide relationship that
we've developed over years not really
Doug I'm keeping it but that's my
example team Landon there are little
kids out there with brain tumors cancers
seizures lymphoma kids have all kinds of
bad things that adults have and now we
need to let these kids have their
caregivers have plant counts this is
messed up this is why I'm fired up
because this is what medical this is
what started the cannabis movement in
Colorado was medical cannabis and
caregivers caregivers are what started
it the patients and the caregivers are
Ground Zero and now guess who's being
screwed right out of this deal the
patients and the caregivers because they
want us to be forced to shop at
recreational dispensaries where taxes
are [ __ ] ridiculous and we cannot
afford it how are we gonna medicate
ourselves that way the reason we are
medicating ourselves with cannabis is so
that we don't have to jump through
somebody else's hoops so that we don't
have to go stand in line to pay
ridiculous prices for medicine you're
[ __ ] us over guys sorry in the rant
I'm passionate about this it pisses me
because the patients that started
medical cannabis are now the people that
nobody I can't say nobody the people
that most of this industry is looking
over right now we've forgotten them it's
all about the patient patients first
without the patients there have been no
medical marijuana movement they've not
been caregivers they would have not been
homegrown we would not have gotten as
far as we've gotten today we'd be years
behind if we did not start this with
medical marijuana
all right so think about the patients
you guys I'm gonna do the best I can I'm
gonna have to register my grows with my
city and with my state they're going to
come to my private grow and they're
going to look through my grows and make
sure that I'm following all of the laws
and that everything is done up to code
I'm gonna sign up to do that because I'm
well known around here
and if I don't do it I know they will
come here and they will try to press
some kind of legal charges on me um
there are paperwork papers that I can
fill out to have an excuse or an
exception to have more patients but I
don't see I'm gonna really have to pull
a lot of reasons out of the air because
they're they're paperwork they don't
have any compassion they have checkmarks
you know what I mean does this this and
this happen then no and it's just like
talking to a computer instead of a
person with compassion it sucks alright
that's enough on that article give me a
second all right guys I'm back I took a
couple dab to calm down I'm not so
pissed off about that last article
anymore but we have a whole new article
coming up in this could this could do a
lot of things to us the sub headline is
another lawsuit has been filed in
federal court over Colorado's marijuana
legalization amendment the headline is
new lawsuit sheriff's from Colorado and
elsewhere challenged amendment 64 what
makes the new suit unique is that it is
also asking for a federal judge to
overturn amendment 64 s protections for
marijuana use and a pro possession this
articles written by Kirk Mitchell and
John Engel of the Denver Post let's get
right into it
six Colorado sheriff's sued their own
governor in federal court on Thursday
arguing that state laws legalizing
marijuana require them to violate
federal law during the sheriff's in the
lawsuit the fourth to be filed against
Colorado over marijuana legalization are
the sheriffs and prosecutors from
Nebraska and Kansas the suit argues that
federal law supremacy means Colorado
cannot allow people to possess or use
marijuana for recreational purposes and
it cannot license stores to sell it the
law does not challenge Colorado's
medical marijuana laws or stores the
suit is about one thing the rule of the
law Larimer County Sheriff Justin Smith
said in a news release release I said
released J's the Colorado Constitution
mandates that all elected officials
including sheriffs swear an oath of
office to uphold both the United States
as well as the Colorado constitutions
the suit names governor john
hickenlooper
as the lone defendant Colorado's
Attorney General cynthia coffman will
defend the state against the lawsuit a
spokesman for her said
lawsuit excuse me the lawsuit has the
backing of national anti illegal ization
groups and its nationwide ambitions were
apparent in the choice of where to
announce the suit in a news conference
Thursday morning at the National Press
Club in Washington DC Smith told
reporters that Colorado's passage of
amendment 64 created a constitutional
shutdown in the state the amendment
which voters approved in 2012 made it
legal for people over 21 in Colorado to
possess a limited amounts of marijuana
and for licensed stores to sell
marijuana this we think they call we
think that what Colorado has done is
illegal we think it's unconstitutional
Scottsbluff County Nebraska sheriff mark
Overman who is also a plaintiff in the
suit said at the news conference
I believe my fellow plaintiffs believe
that this case is going to have national
ramifications and if we win then we can
reverse what looks like a surrender to a
pro marijuana crowd the lawsuit follows
another legal challenge filed in
December by Nebraska and Oklahoma which
asked the US Supreme Court to strike
down the history-making law two lawsuits
filed earlier this year by the anti
legalization group safe streets Alliance
on behalf of several Colorado residents
are also pending against the state over
a minim at 64 similar to the previous
lawsuits the new suit seeks to close all
of Colorado's recreational marijuana
stores but it also asks federal a
federal judge to overturn amendment 64 s
protections for marijuana use and
possession the law enforcement officials
suit claim that local officers are
breaking federal law and international
treaties when they find marijuana but
they do not seize it at Thursday's news
conference Yuma County Sheriff Chad day
said Colorado's marijuana laws now
prohibit officers from seizing marijuana
and serving certain circumstances
putting officers he said in an
inevitable position that's kind of funny
by supporting and upholding one were
violating the other he said I'm excited
to very least to get an answer from the
courts
these cops are not robots they are
people and they know they're they know
what they're supposed to do these guys
are acting like we've got droids out
there acting as police officers and
we're gonna flip their switch and make
their computers crash this is
ridiculous dude Sam came in I'm probably
saying that wrong Sam Kay a law
professor at the University of Denver
was skeptical of the sheriff's argument
he said no law requires local officers
to act as de facto federal drug agents
of the four lawsuits this is the one
with the least merit came and said they
have targeted not just the marijuana
store regulation piece but they're also
essentially saying Colorado can't
legalize marijuana no one has ever gone
that far
Colorado plaintiffs in the latest
lawsuit include Smith de Elbert County
Sheriff Shane Heep hensdale County
Sheriff Ronald Bruce Kiowa County
Sheriff Casey Sheridan and Delta County
Sheriff Frederick McKee of the six
Colorado sheriff's involved in the
lawsuit only Smith is from the county
that approved amendment 64 with 55% of
eight thousand or eighty six thousand
four hundred and ten voters approving
the measure the measure was approved in
33 of 64 Colorado counties by a fifty
five percent margin also named as
plaintiffs are three Nebraska sheriffs
Adam Hayward of dual county mark Overman
of Scott's bluff County and John Jensen
of Cheyenne County Jan County attorney
Paul Schaub of Nebraska and sheriff
Charles Mosier of Sherman Wallace and
Greeley counties in Kansas also signed
at the document sorry I kind of
snowballed in that last part there but
those a lot of names is really all
excuse me as in the lawsuit filed in
Nebraska and Oklahoma the law
enforcement officials from Nebraska and
Kansas are are arguing in the new
lawsuit that marijuana flowing out of
Colorado post legalization has led to
more arrests and strain their budgets
I'm gonna jump in here and say so
legalize pot in your states just
legalize weed in Nebraska and Oklahoma
in Kansas and you won't have to worry
about arresting more people and
straining your budget you'll be able to
sell cannabis like we do here in
Colorado and you'll be able to fill up
your cash registers at the stores and
you'll be able to fix your stupid-ass
roads that you guys have think about it
come on let's use our [ __ ] brains
people alright it's actually taking
money out of Sherman County taxpayers
pockets
Burton Pianalto the sheriff in Sherman
County Kansas said at Thursday's news
conference in January 9 out of the 46
people booked into Sherman
jail were suspected of possessing or
distributing hallucinogen hallucinogenic
drugs the category under which marijuana
is classified in Kansas criminal law
according to an online booking log 2 out
of the 15 inmates listed on Thursday as
being currently housed in the County
Jail face charges related to
hallucinogenic drugs so more [ __ ]
they call cannabis a hallucinogenic drug
which is right in the same category as
probably LSD mushrooms ecstasy um this
is some cannabis you guys this is
medical marijuana it's funny to think
that over an invisible line that this is
now a hallucinogenic drug and you cross
this invisible line and now it's
recreational cannabis and then you can
cross another line and it's medical
marijuana this is so good I love the
time and place that we live in this is
so amazing to me all right
where was I Colorado officials have not
yet responded to any of the pending
lawsuits previously state attorneys have
argued that Colorado's more permissive
marijuana laws both from medical and
recreational use and sales do not amount
to legalization of marijuana instead
they contend that marijuana remains
illegal in Colorado aside from the
specific exemptions allowed under the
medical and recreational marijuana laws
when Nebraska and Oklahoma filed their
lawsuit against Colorado last year in
Colorado Attorney General John John
Suthers said in a statement that it
appears the plaintiffs primary grievance
stems from a non enforcement of federal
laws regarding marijuana as opposed to
choices made by the voters of Colorado
basin to virt one of the lead proponents
of amendment 64 said if the lawsuits are
successful in striking down the measure
it would lead to a system of marijuana
chaos which I would love to see what
happened I don't want it to happen but
it'd be really neat to see how it's
dealt with because there are
dispensaries on every other corner in
Denver every other corner in Colorado
Springs Bob Lowe West has 12 or 15
dispensaries now in that small community
they are everywhere it'll be hard to
complain they'd have to go to California
they'd have to go to every state that's
got medical cannabis they couldn't just
come here cuz then that would be they'd
be signaling us out says this is just
another case of the arrest and
prosecution industry teaming up with
marijuana prohibition groups to roll
the progress that has been made in
Colorado he said in a statement Thursday
a US Rep jared Polis said in a statement
that the US Department of Justice and
President Obama have made clear that
they will not interfere with the states
whose citizens voted for recreational
marijuana use this lawsuit is a silly
attempt to circumvent the will of
Colorado voters and is a waste of time
Bullough statement says unfortunately
these frivolous lawsuits will likely
continue until we pass by bar bipartisan
regulate marijuana like alcohol Act and
finally end the outdated federal
prohibition of marijuana so these states
have filed a suit they're trying to sue
us to shut down our recreational
marijuana program because they can't get
cannabis to stop coming into their
states I think I said it the first time
stop [ __ ] with us and do what you can
to make respectable responsible cannabis
laws in Nebraska and Kansas in Oklahoma
and then the state's bordering those
will have to follow suit and then
eventually it'll just be a whole dream
mat stead of having a red and blue map
we'll start having all green states this
will be great all right so here's
another article that I keep seeing pop
up on social media I'm finding this
article on the cannabis they get a lot
of my articles from there this was
written by Christopher Ingraham from the
Washington Post there's a cute little
headline article headline picture of a
little bunny rabbit sitting on a digital
scale and the bunny weighs ninety three
point two grams it's kind of cute um the
headline says Utah DEA warns of stoned
rabbits if state passes medical
marijuana bill I'll say it again DEA
warns of stone rabbits if state passes
medical marijuana bill well let's take
that in now I'll read the article
Utah's considering a bill that would
allow patients with certain debilitating
conditions to be treated with edible
forms of marijuana if the bill passes
the state's wildlife may cultivate a
taste for the plant lose their fear of
humans and basically be high all the
time
that's according to testimony presented
to a Utah State panel last week by an
agent of the Drug Enforcement
Administration I deal in facts I deal in
science at Special Agent Matt Fairbanks
who's been working in the state for a
decade he is a member of the marijuana
eradication team in Utah some of his
colleagues in Georgia recently achieved
notoriety by raiding a retirees garden
and seizing a number of okra plants
Fairbanks spoke of his time eliminating
backcountry marijuana grows and the Utah
mountains specifically the environmental
cost associated with large-scale weed
cultivation on public land personally
I've seen an entire mountainside
subjected to pesticides harmful
chemicals deforestation and erosion he
said the ramifications to the flora the
animal life the contaminated water are
still unknown at some illegal marijuana
grow sites he saw rabbits that had
cultivated taste for the marijuana it
continued one of them refused to leave
us as we took all the marijuana around
him his natural instincts to run or
somehow gone it's true that illegal pot
farming can have harmful environmental
consequences of course nothing about
these consequences is unique to
marijuana if corn were outlawed the
cartels would start growing it on
national forests the per plant
environmental toll would be about the
same which is kind of a neat fact but
back County marijuana grows are a direct
result of marijuana's illegal status if
you're concerned about the environmental
impact of the grows an alternative is to
legalize and regulate the plants so that
people can grow it on farms and in their
gardens rather than on remote mountain
sides now regarding stone rabbits some
wild animals apparently do develop a
taste for bud
but I don't know that the occasional
high rabbit constitutes four grounds for
keeping marijuana prohibition in place
any more than drunk squirrels are an
argument for outlawing alcohol and let's
not even get started on the nationwide
epidemic of catnip abuse
there was a time not too long ago when
drug warriors terrified a nation with
images of The Devil's weed and reefer
madness now it seems that enforcers of
marijuana law conjuring up a stoned
bunny not scary enough for the Utah
State it seems the panel approved the
bill and sent it to the full Senate
where it will be debated this week well
good luck to you Utah I hope that this
bill passes I hope that you're allowed
to consume an edible form of marijuana
outlying cannabis in your state because
the rabbits are gonna get stoned
would be a lot like outlined roads
because dogs and squirrels are going to
get ran over it's kind of a stupid-ass
argument come up with something better
we aren't buying that [ __ ] anymore
because I've got one more news article
that I want to read and then we're gonna
wrap up the show this one is from the
toke of the town actually and this will
be the final news article that I am ever
going to read from the toke of the town
and I will tell you why this article
comes from the toke of the town and it
says after five years toke of the town
says goodbye since 2009 toke of the town
has brought you the biggest marijuana
news and the loudest pot views from
across the country and around the world
along the way we've covered the huge
progress many states have made toward
legalization and wondered why others are
so far behind this country still has a
long way to go but things are looking up
and we have our fingers crossed that
2015 will be another big year for
legalization but the toke won't be
around to see it at least not in its
present form this is the toks
total the town's final day of
publication and this was actually
written at the end of the year don't
worry we're not quitting the movement
we're just returning the focus of our
marijuana coverage to our local voice
media group papers you can still read
William breeds weekly pot reviews and
ask a STONER to call him at Westward com
or they started and you can continue to
follow him on Twitter and on Facebook
and you can keep following Tok on
Facebook and Twitter too for the latest
marijuana news from all of our papers
many thanks for reading and supporting
us for the past five years we couldn't
have covered the marijuana community
without such a strong one reading us
though the community itself is a strong
one I was thrown off by the way they
worded that and all of our archives will
remain online because we wouldn't want
you to lose access to our serious
reporting on issues of Medicine and our
light-hearted coverage
stoner movies light went up for us won't
you so this is a little outdated because
this was put out at the end of the year
at the start of this year at the end of
last year the toke of the town is not
posting any more news I used to pull a
lot of news articles from there but I
will not have them as a resource anymore
so we will miss you talk of the town you
were a great resource my little podcast
here you provided a lot of news articles
I'll do a DAB for you later I'll miss
the joke of the town
that's enough news for one episode I'm
gonna wrap up the show here it's been
about 30 minutes let's see how far we've
been going one minutes I don't even know
what I'm good all right let's see let's
do some things I think the garden of
Weeden will be here on the next episode
I have a phone interview planned with a
cat known as soil grown on Instagram
soil grown is doing something he calls
rosin tech about that a little bit on
the next episode we'll be here we're
gonna talk about canopy management big
shout-out to our friends Green Works who
got us started on this canopy management
product a project in an upcoming episode
we will have tour pecks and hunt from
the Graeme Gatsby to come talk about
some things I'm actually going to
Colorado Springs to interview those guys
also big dude you asked me a couple of
questions today on Instagram and then
you asked me if you were bothering me no
dude you're not bothering me at all I
love the questions I'd love that you
listen to the podcast I love that you
support all of the IRA genetic stuff on
Instagram I love that you listen to the
girl from your heart podcast you're
never bothering me dude ask me more
questions I will use your questions as
material for the show you'll hear your
stuff broadcasted to the whole world so
dude you're never bothering me and that
goes for everybody if you sent me an
email if you send me a tweet you send me
a Facebook message whatever however you
hit me up you're not bothering me I will
answer you sometimes it'll take a minute
because you wouldn't believe how many
emails and messages I get but I will
respond to you the best way to contact
me would be to join my forum on I read
genetics Colorado calm go to the forum
create an account and go somewhere and
ask me a question there there's an ask
the breeder part ask a question there
and I will answer you because that's my
forum I'm fully responsible for that and
I check that
I try to get on there every Monday uh I
can't do it every Monday because life
goes certain ways but ask a question
I'll answer it on the forum and then if
I ever need new testers for new seeds
that's the first place I go to look for
testers I look for your grow photos I
check out your profile on my form
because that shows me that you're
interested in my brand and you're kind
of loyal so join the forum I would
appreciate that a big shout out to my
friend Judy also big shout out to hippy
nurse and a big shout-out to dreadful
Jay look forward to seeing everybody at
the Cannabis Cup alright let's wrap up
this show let's get to that last paper
where I read all that stuff don't forget
to check out our sponsors the rocky
mountain one company and hydro indoor
growing supplies make sure you visit
nature's green remedies com make sure
use that coupon code spring 15 for 15
percent off your entire order if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like me to
review send me an email girl from your
heart at hotmail.com I'll get you all
the information that you need is now
that the show is over please go to the
iTunes Store search for girl from your
heart find the review section give me a
5 star rating
after that type in a comment and let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comment on a future
episode uh stitcher keeps changing the
way the comments are handled so leave a
comment wherever you can on there and I
will find it and I will read that if you
have something saying you're into the
social media thing you can email me it's
girl for me hard at hotmail.com
don't forget every show is available on
iTunes stitcher and also I read genetics
Colorado com don't forget we added that
donation button to the podcast page if
you feel like the show is worth a couple
bucks you can go to the website I read
genetics Colorado com click on the drove
from your heart podcast tab at the top
of the write the top right there's a
donation button that goes directly to my
PayPal account you guys will never
charge you anything for the podcast I
keep saying that because I mean it this
is going to be a free podcast but if you
feel like making a donation or a
contribution for the amount of time that
I spent on this show for the amount of
time that I spent putting together the
show together
I buy water bottles for everybody that
comes on the show I smoke everybody out
it takes a couple hours of my day
if you want to throw down something I
would appreciate it I'll give you a
shout out on the show we are on all the
social media sites search for us grow
from your heart on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast
there's a Facebook if you're gonna look
for us on Instagram it's at I read
genetics I just combined everything it's
one Instagram page I think that's the
end of the show guys are covered
everything I wanted to say thanks a lot
for listening big huge shout out to late
intra spins until next time
[Music]
turn on the mic son I might help geez
what's up everybody
sniper episode the girlfriend heart
podcast time for episode number 58
intro thanks for joining me everybody I
do have to give a big shout-out to Kat
coot from the mystic roots band we are
high as [ __ ]
speaking of weed what's up Spence
joining me across the table as my buddy
garden of Weeden he showed up with the
mothership rig in a pelican case any
we're gonna get rekt as soon as you
walked in let's do one quick and then
we're gonna get to this show there's
organic portions of this podcast were
brought to you by my good friends at the
rocky mountain worm company visit the
rocky mountain one company and Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments now you can
get the same warm castings that I use
Sam casting the spence uses same casting
that Sean and Jesse use I can get them
all through www.rockymountainatvmc.com
[Music]
into the growers meeting the other night
aboard I'm gonna prepare something next
time so that it's not just a bunch of
let's do a question box so at the end
there you go everybody has to do come to
the growers meetings all you gotta do is
email me or tweet me and I will base my
next lesson for the growers meeting
around some of your questions also we'll
do that so shadow tide Road or growing
supplies they have a Denver location 62
71 Beach Street also 618 East 4th Street
beautiful Pueblo Colorado the next time
you shop at hydro indoor growing
supplies tell them you listen to the
growth from your heart podcast and you
will get commercial pricing on your
entire order that's [ __ ] super sweet
super phat deal everybody wants to save
some money go for it bro so I just try
to take a selfie this at
[Music]
what's up with you taking selfies on the
show that's og right there Spence is
here and we're hi and I just want to get
to the conversation I don't want to
ramble about commercials you guys don't
want to hear a lot of commercials but if
you guys are interested in sponsoring
the show sent me an email it's grow for
me hard at hotmail.com I'll get you all
of that info so and he said management
so we're gonna jump right into it that's
good [ __ ] so canopy management I've
been watching Spence follow a guy named
green works on Instagram so a lot of
this will be inspired by our buddy green
[Music]
works he kind of inspired Spence to set
up some really killer Cage like not
really cages the keys only on top do you
want me to keep rambling for it alright
so it's essentially a single plant scrub
to where you have these bigger pots uses
27 I'm pretty sure something like that I
use around 2020 the pots are two foot
tall but it's just it's it works for
what it is it's all about you know
working surface area you're giving
especially like in areas where they
limit plant counts do a lot of things
for people I'm writing down the word
surface area because that's a good thing
to think about we're gonna go back to
that so yeah for people with limited
plant counts in Colorado well in our
location
definitely messing with plant counts and
we're not gonna be able to grow as many
plants as we used to
so what's Vince has done he's taking
these giant pots and he takes a plant
and he build a PVC sort of a frame
around it so it's he's got a square
frame now above the plant
how big is that square anywhere it's a
four by four square
cage basically you've got a cage out of
your PVC and you do layers of trellis
for support you know if some people do
there's a lot of people because it works
I mean it's it's more bang for your buck
if you have you know especially it's in
my opinion strain dependent strains that
are built for that system Gorilla Glue
loves it loves it killers I'm saying so
like those moonshine Hays that lobsters
grow all inside that net so things like
that works and cookies will do decent
but not like essentially it's a four by
four cage with you know multiple
trellises and then you lollipop from the
soil to the first trellis you know so
everything from that first trellis up
will be just knows okay yeah all right
so you go get your frame you got a
square then you put a net over you just
got a bud going through each part of the
screen it's out of control because it's
more about you know canopy management
like making sure while it's you know
especially through the stretch face from
they want a flower till date 21:22 which
when it's growing like crazy you'll want
to get in there and really like tie them
down make sure they're not growing out
of
what they didn't need to so it's you
know with those trellis nets are like
3x3 squares or 4x4 squares you know you
want to try to essentially get a node or
a coal to hit every single one of those
squares I mean there's if there's 60 of
them on a plant so just you know the
surface area works okay how early in the
veg do you start manipulating the screen
so typically what I do is I'll go from a
one gallon pot or a clone to three and
I'll let that three kind of get bulky in
that three gallon and then straight into
the final pots and then give them you
know five six weeks but it's really not
as long as people think it is especially
when it's strain dependant and strain to
grow you know faster than other strains
yeah it's gonna be worth it so once you
you know find your strain that you want
to use you know you basically are
training it through the net so you know
so if it's getting too tall
make it go back under the trellis what I
like to do is I like to just kind of on
your first screen you kind of spread it
open and then you let all the insides
grow up and everything on the outsides
gonna grow okay around in the case all
those little shoots that would just be
cut off your normal you're gonna grow
into actual bridge yeah they're gonna go
straight to branches so the bottom of
the stalk that shoot clear up to the top
canopy management okay I read an article
a long time ago they kind of introduced
me to this idea the article was actually
called growing on the grid is what I
think it was called and author was Eric
Pizza I'm gonna Google that just to make
sure but he was used to be a writer for
High Times and he wrote an article about
this I'm searching his name while I talk
it's called growing on the grid with
Eric pizza it'll kind of if you guys
want to read more about it this is kind
of we're gonna give you the the in
action in practice sort of talk Eric
pizza is he writes a lot so he's gonna
give you a really technical explanation
on it
I'm not sure how many times he's done it
Spence here has done it message and
Greenworks
we're gonna try to get Greenworks to
call in one day and we'll talk to him
we've got I just actually learned how to
record quality phone interviews using
FaceTime I probably can do it with Skype
also I just haven't experimented with
that yet I opened a FaceTime and played
around and I'll be able to record so
beyond the show you're far away
FaceTime is now the way to do it it'll
be great Greenworks I'm inviting you
call us
speaking of FaceTime I'm gonna get up I
want to talk about this guy in a couple
of minutes but I'll talk more about
Canon canopy management but I have a
phone interview plan into the three goes
into the 20 do top before you transplant
into the 20 at all it's a plan to me
some people do top it but I'm more of
just kind of you know working it through
the net so I'll take one branch and take
it all the way to the left side and take
this branch and take it to the right
side and eventually in that system it's
gonna fill itself back up if I took my
whole arm and just it over its gonna
just make little shoots horizontal you
know your colas grow your nodes stack
vertically they grow together so if you
were to bend that branch all the way
down you're taking each one of those bud
sites turning them up which creates more
bud sites on that plant then you would
get stacking it together okay for the
plant all right that makes pretty good
sense so you don't talk at all that's
see I would have topped them some
strains I do
girl Guzman the ones I kind of gross
[Music]
there's there's some things I would do a
couple two weeks worth of aiming and
your training and stuff like that and
then know what to do because they are
know which ways up still alright and I
have like seven questions in my head if
it's not gorilla glue what other strain
do you like to sprog and it's I'm still
learning like the curve I'm still
picking up the curve which is you know
going from you know seven and tens up to
20s and to plants that are two to three
times the size you know maintenance on
those plants like you always have to be
cleaning up the bottoms and stuff cuz
imagine you know six-foot plant that's
four and a half feet wide underneath
there so the things like the leaves and
stuff died off just because they don't
get light to survive so you have to
constantly be in there picking them off
and things like that it's a good thing
to think about
I like that you said that would have
been a six-foot-tall plan that you've
gotten it down to four feet tall that
kind of puts it into a lot of
perspective for me I'm running in a
nine-foot ceiling but it's all about can
you keep him down the light.the kavita's
will work for you it's just all about
like in my opinion when you when plants
get tall and get close up to the
kavita's and then they kind of feel how
powerful they are all the way down you
know it's all about surface area oh do
you have a prediction on how much weight
you're gonna pull per thousand watt
light with this new system
well right now per thousand watt I'll
probably pull all my first go probably
six seven hundred grams per gorilla
booth that's not bad at all that's over
a pound and a quarter yeah comes back
right okay
and that'll be pound and a half with
it's only in a 4k I'm running a 4k
kavita's and for a six week that's not
the plants really grow like when you put
them from a three gallon pot into a
plant a pot that's I've seen stocks of
your plants and their figure around in
these microphones for sure Wow yeah it's
impressive your rooms look great I've
been in there well I've been in there a
few days or so but I've been there
recently and they look pretty darn good
shut it's a big Mike Madi Michael
everybody that keeps the gardens on
track who else helps over there
he wraps so wraps the show boys if you
listen to this Michael
Big Mike's lop fill daddy always welcome
whatever you want to do a podcast just
text me we couldn't do it like live
broadcasting but we have a house and all
that so I talked about taking my
recording equipment to the cup and just
taking it to my hotel bring it to my
house this is not snow but he's gonna be
in the Denver area during the Cannabis
Cup and you're down with Spitz and you
want to take a dad with Rasta Jeff in
the garden of Weeden true there's a good
chance I will bring some maybe not this
big ol set up but I might bring some
small recording gear I just have a lot
going on I don't want this to disappear
while I'm at the cup or something for
sure from the car or some [ __ ] I get
prayer this is my livelihood so I'd be
crushed with
but uh this gear some kind of recording
gear may end up at the got my phone if
nothing else that works well let's at
least hang out a few guys and take some
dabs this show won't come out for
probably a week front it's tomorrow but
you'll have plenty of time it's just the
middle of March when this comes out
let's meet up the cannabis cup you guys
let's take some dabs I should have some
Geoff's OG dad's if spence's down to
blast it for me do that if you're not
gonna do this grogs you can lollipop
really heavily that's another good way
to make space for what you've got kind
of pay attention get down on your knees
and see how far the light is getting
into your plants and when you don't see
any light hitting those leaves just
clean that [ __ ] off from the bottom
there because there's no like it's gonna
be a waste of space there's you can do
shaking I like the system but I still
like the old-school look going in a room
and being a hundred stakes deep in there
and I like some stakes I grow some
plants I use the seven gallon requires
either a tomato cage or some staking
yeah I like this because I can pull it
apart and I can break I can support do
what you do just train it to like this
this coal has got this section this coal
has got this section you want to kind of
fill as many sections as you can yeah
you're using the golden go or the whole
bunch of heads doesn't really like to do
it so maybe grow a whole bunch of small
cookies plants like just if you can do a
bunch of two-foot tall three foot tall
cookies - flour it yeah that's the way
to go G cush just do a bunch of small
ones instead of one
yeah they couldn't figure out how to
[Music]
light a flower to help you know early or
the first couple weeks of fire do you
keep them lowered you keep them further
away you know my lights don't move I
sometimes put my plants on a five-gallon
bucket to get them higher but for the
duration of the girl my plant my lights
don't move on in the rooms one thing I
do is I don't change out from the
halides to the sodium's for the first
two weeks of flower they keep some I
feel like they don't stretch as far when
I do the switch I start to bulk up right
away at the two weeks I really probably
that change from blue to HBS kind of
gives them a time span they gotta get
used to that [ __ ] I do dark periods
before flower under 24 hours and then I
would veg for 24 and then go dark for 24
[Music]
so I go 18 to 6 when they sleep they're
ugly and then when they you know
eventually when the lights come back on
their get into the swing of things and
then you know before the cutoff start
going back down and then I usually hit
that 48 hours dark even when it's dark
they're already praying and ready I feel
like they're just preparing themselves
for the time change yeah excited for it
yeah it's crazy how like you the plants
will be the veg looking and then that
dark period you go in there like oh [ __ ]
they're ready plant these plants tell us
what they want that's for sure I like it
he'll be afraid to try a different light
cycled my mother plants run on a 19-5
cycle recommended by dieter Knight is in
1950 a 19-5 recommended by DJ short and
that's the best performance I've ever
had from the mother plant so don't be
afraid to experiment with some stuff now
I do the I do 18 6 in my veg areas and
then my flower I just ever grown was
actually grown under a high pressure
sodium in a 400 watt metal halide in the
same bulb and that grow syllable that
Hydrofarm a yeah that was great great
bud it had great flavor it looked great
some of my best pictures came from that
run a flower
there's definitely quality buds my best
girl of that headband cut ever
[Music]
so what's his name there's going on
there's some new [ __ ] it's called I saw
it first on Instagram from a dude named
soil called this dude what do you think
cuz we're gonna have me on the show
pretty soon I will gladly support
somebody trying something new for sure
like no doubts I was listening to church
today don't like don't freak out on me
cuz I say this cuz people argue about it
all the time but it's the first
non-solvent actual not enough there's
not like water as much as you do you
don't believe it it's a solvent then the
butane and propane those are all
solvents but he's just using pure heat
to extract oils there's no you can't use
heat as a solvent heat and pressure
see the pictures like the whole slab
rolled up in a worm around the car he's
been going in lately yeah I've got a
scheduled phone interview with him he
said Tuesday or Wednesday he hasn't
confirmed a specific time but we're
gonna talk to him I'll probably just
piece that right into this episode you
guys if I can get him to call me on time
that's all I need I'll throw that into
this show probably right here so here's
an interview maybe hopefully what so how
you doing bro great cool man thanks for
uh pulling some time away from your work
to join us I'm just gonna I know you're
a busy man I'm just gonna get right to
it and start asking a couple of quick
questions first of all can you explain
to me a little bit about what rasen tech
is and how you got the idea
hash you take your hash no no you can
turn it into now all the resin out of
the no no you know with the double
boiler a ball and your no notes so if I
did this different method rosin I guess
what rosin is technically it's just a
form of resin obtained from my plant you
know that's where like I don't I don't
know why it's called rising I mean it's
similar like rosin what I know Roz was
like you know for both strings for
friction together but I don't know where
the term actually stuck in cannabis but
that's where I know it's from and it's
really kind of related to Residence you
know in a way basically I know so I
decide something out I have all this no
no but I remember back then collecting
his teeth but something on on the IG
about taking like a flat iron just
suppressing you know I'm just
by your hash much simpler than heating
up a wand or you know doing something
like that you can set the right town
just to press it out you have a proper
track down well I used to take my wife's
hair curler and I would uh sometimes I
get too hot you know by accident and I
would notice better with separate is the
oil and then the hash
I wasn't thinking this is like you know
this is uh this was a while back so I
didn't think anything of it I would just
focus on backup and yeah I have a pest
catty that was over but uh anything that
I would try to try to increase the
quality on it so we'll give you the idea
to just start pressing straight buds
without trying passion there we just
took I don't know we're just sitting
here smoking no I'm not I smoked flour
but my thing is yeah me too definitely
yeah so so we're just sitting here
bullshitting with my father-in-law and
like hey let's try this I grab now he's
like what are you doing I put it in
between the parchment just like I would
a you know a rolled-up ball and hash and
my surprise resin squeeze out the button
we were both in shock like no way
so I scooped up the oil did it again
scooped it up there was a little there
was enough on the hand look like a gap
so we tried it out
and uh and to my subscribers even good
ba Jolie for Reza do sometimes
so that's impressive yeah yeah exactly
very sweet you got lucky figuring that
one out do what I do every day and I was
so much into the to the extracts as much
as you do to find that for us because it
seems to be the thing now bro you're
blowing up on Instagram yeah just kind
of a brief oh I know it's just a pretty
simple process can you tell me kind of
briefly how you do it process and
extraction I would say if you want to do
it the most basic way to do it for
anybody at home ladies flat iron your
hair straighter get the widest one you
can digital settings would be optimum
that's not I mean when I first did it I
had it up to 420 degrees yeah I mean it
seems worried about you know so to my
surprise I was pulling out that and now
that I'm fine tuned it a little bit and
there's gonna be a lot more involved
it's just those Turks out of it but so
you just get the straightening comb with
a flat iron and then just baseball game
yeah so you put it between the parchment
and then put it between the firon you
want to do it in a quick fast as
possible put it between my flat iron and
then press it as hard
you know as far as you can for about I'd
say one or two to three seconds
depending like how hot you got your iron
but usually you hear you come out it
mostly it comes down to trial and error
and hearing that that sound of knowing
when to pull up and you know knowing
when you have it to Heidi really all
right so I'm just gonna practice and
waste a couple of buds doesn't look like
you're doing a lot of buds at one time
so that's not too big of a deal to waste
a couple nuggets I get a more efficient
process but right now this seems to work
it's if I can fine-tune this to make it
workable do whatever goes on after it's
gonna be better there you go keep
improving everyday that's the way this
industry is working so are you doing
anything special to prepare the buds do
you like them a little more so you like
i'm dr you like them crispy
do you like I'm cured too much moister
it probably will work too much like
fresh nuts and I haven't had too many
results with it nothing under static is
gonna affect whether we see it or not
you know moisture just wrapping in there
some not properly dried ìwe you know
you're trapping moisture so I don't see
that being the same for this process all
right do I do certain strains work
better
do you like into Custer sativas work
better or do you have a favorite strain
that works the best for making rosin I
mean I've even had some real frosty
tequila's but not like it
9% but I have some indicas fall around
anywhere spun like 9 to 22% you know wow
that's impressive
yeah all right that's good to know how
does the flavor of a rosin dab compared
to like a Pho dab result unless tab are
you still getting good flavors my next
question I was gonna ask if you've had
anything tested or if anybody that you
know is how to test it yet yeah actually
foundation extracts I think somebody
else um actually seemed like it was
pretty high in CBD my page with the
results of combination extract I think I
was like eighty-three percent THC and
eight percent
Wow have you seen any hatred from all
the BHO people you guys have spent
thousands of dollars on equipment and
now you're just doing it with the shirt
[Music]
a lot of people are just like just not
giving it a chance but then you know
like I'll see them I'll see some of
these people like changing their minds
about it they're trying it out once they
try it like you can't knock it till you
try it
right you know this industry they make
decisions right away yeah you're right
you're right just how the way the world
it's the way the world works but they're
gonna be the one in this
right that's true guys if you ever get a
chance anybody that's listening if you
get a chance take a dab of some rosin
before you dissin try the rosin check
yourself don't be a hater there you go
how's the hi is it similar to a normal
dab do you get feeling like you do
sometimes from a water dab or most
likely being challenged this year all
right well if you were at the Denver Cup
you better find me a little white guy
with dreadlocks for sure do you think
you're gonna enter any contests or any
concert we're gonna enter a shower for
setting up before we're starting to
prepare for it nice you gonna put rosin
tech in there yeah um
and then I'm hoping to have some actual
action as well very cool I can't wait to
see what the rosin tech does up next to
swags and also you're gonna be competing
bro you'll be right up there with those
guys I have faith in it from what I've
seen people are loving it Thirteen's
whether it went through heat the process
that I went just can't forget that it's
thought of this I'm not big on [ __ ]
saw that with solvent extracts that's
sometimes in my mind I have four years
against it you know there's some very
enjoyable extracts actually solvents but
I just thanks for uh supporting the
clean madmen bro we need more people
like yourself that are aware of what
we're doing for the community and to our
bodies and with our medicine that's cool
I appreciate it yeah for sure
then I'm gonna wrap up this phone
interview I told you I'd only take about
15 minutes of your time we're getting
pretty close to that how can people find
you on Instagram
I'm soil girl so uh so that's on
Instagram I don't really do too much of
the hashtag for the so don't check but
uh you know you're fine you'll see this
fella groans there you go search for
rosin tech on Instagram you'll
definitely find this guy but do you have
anything you want to give or anything
you want us to look at since you've got
a lot of people listening to you
something you want to say to the world
and you know a lot of you know I would
say I would call it a connoisseurs xpect
nice I like that I brew only truly
appreciate you calling it for the
showman if you ever have anything else
you want to say on the show you've got
my phone number
stay in touch with me if you're in
Denver I look forward to meeting you at
the cop man Rosen Tech for me and I'll
take a DAB with some turned back to Pho
for you this dude you just heard what he
said hopefully one of these bounty
killer resin tabs off the mothership I
might not be able to talk for a couple
seconds with spin Sikes direct me hold
on to the rig for a little bit because I
like to take ABS it are too hot which we
call glowy's in this crew they're not
even like super bows but it's just hot
it's a little too high I'll agree but I
like the way I like the way I get the
dad when it's that way clone just
smacking his mother ship bring on the
table like it's nothing
the sound of my brain is better it's
like job bubble wrapping fireworks pop
rocks pop rocks yeah what do you uh what
do you think of the row I'm blown away
by it
he's using equipment that everybody has
her I've seen people use a flat iron or
I think bright black people call that a
pressing calm don't they I'm one show
that you're on I said you the only black
person that's been in my house I'm in
Colorado I grew up in Southern
California where I had like she had she
called it a flat iron or a straightening
comb I thought was the same [ __ ] but
[Music]
these guys are using [ __ ] that's around
the house and handmade Adam had from
handmade apparel
he showed me his what he posted his slab
because of course he had a t-shirt press
already and just kind of around the
house actually I think it has something
to do with the moisture content of how
your wheat is dried like you down here
is really dry so it's just maybe I
needed to do more we've got his piece
and you actually know is that rosin tech
is great and if just talk about it
because maybe we won't get his interview
this dude's taking a t-shirt press and
he's modified it and he puts a layer of
parchment paper a little layer of buds
and another parchment paper and squishes
it for about force
it's lifted up pulls apartment-house
he's got pretty much Earl's into the
floor and stomps on it all day has a tea
jar just once he's done with it he makes
tea in the morning with big shout out to
my hat's oil grown if he if he called it
and did that interview extra super huge
shout out if he didn't still check him
out on Instagram it's at soil grown
check out the rosin tech it's really
really really cool since I'm going
through my notes here I have to give a
big shout out to Judy what's up Judy
hope you listen into the show I
appreciate it one more thing to talk
about that I have to remind you guys the
prizes have been shipped remember we did
prizes for episode 50 those have been
shipped to people never gave me their
addresses both of those prize winners
were from Facebook you guys go on
Facebook and give me your address if you
want your prize you have until the next
episode airs to claim your prize if
those prizes are not claimed they will
be sacrificed to the cannabis gods and
recycled for future episode prizes what
else you got on your brain bro things
bit man curling your ass off
[Music]
so it differs our first one then we're
gonna do organ possibly Michigan Wow
Michigan that's stretching out far it's
it's one of the smaller ones and they
accept out-of-state cards and then
[Music]
travel in two more of these cups I'm
just a solo grower so if I don't have
anybody backing up my girl when I go so
it's hard to uh pretty get away for
three or four days check on the plants
and then I'll fly back yeah everything's
alive one time tweet me guys what do you
do when you go out of town and you grow
paw how do you keep your plants alive
when you go out of town I'm just curious
I know what to do I just wanna know how
you do it tweet me it's at G fyh podcast
curious I want to know tell me what you
do how's that so right before you came
over tonight I was at the gross base
taking pictures of like 20 different
phenotypes of black cherry Kim and I
have narrowed it down there's one that
is definitely a breeder it's purple it's
got the great bud structure it smells
like purple laughy pack you can smell it
far away it's got a weird
oh it's a dictum but I don't like very
sorry wasn't going to smell that one all
the time
nice structure it's a little lighter
purple but has more of a chem dog sort
of a smell so that one's gonna be an
option and there's one with no purple
also are no purple at all but tons of
trichomes tons or trikes and a great
Kimi kind of funky cherry resin kind of
smell so those three or four females are
gonna get put in the room with the black
cherry I got some great string ideas I
want to see what they do there will be
some new black cherry crosses coming up
[Music]
some things
right now I've got golden go go a
reversed golden go man it's a female
that's now a male in a room with some
lemon scones
so there's more lemon Geoffrey be invade
there's more golden to have seen to be
it made and I'm treating sunshine girl
and I've also put Gorilla Glue in there
so we'll have
[Music]
there's the whole thing that was like
the length of my arm like reptiles when
you say his name he'll turn and look at
you like you can here's name like my
snake she she kicks is definitely one of
the funnest places to hang out you never
know let's see a club will be doing a
boost
the cup gardener weed smokers club booth
look for me there I'll be hanging out a
little bit yeah
it'll be it's gonna be a good time so
enjoy 4/20 and come hang out with us
everyone's gonna be mad at me because
I'm gonna be out of seeds by the end of
the first day they get to Denver I'll be
there Friday okay the end of Friday
night I could be out of seeds all over
guess what's in there I do a big huge
shout out to green and healthy cannabis
and Colorado Springs Colorado you're
looking for the turf X on the low-low
cheap and they got the Durbin poison wax
good stuff so every few days they get
new drops of great great medicine over
it green and healthy cannabis 212 21st
Street I think it's south 21st I'm gonna
pull up the track yesterday yeah 212
21st Street if you're in Pueblo if you
are if you're in what's to the east
that's uh that's just and get yourself
some turf bags medicine on the cheap
it's I don't rep other dispensaries very
often
[Music]
I'm ahead of myself because an episode
came out today and then I've got one
pre-recorded and then I've got this one
and then I'll have hunt it's gonna get
[ __ ] awesome here I live shows coming
out maybe think the show I did last week
I'll put out on a Wednesday gonna have a
Wednesday show this week yeah I watch
this
have you seen like the Colbert Report
[Music]
I want to say cuz they're Jo Jo koy does
a character called I think I got
confused Buddha on YouTube type in
Russell phone pranks shut the phone to
fungus fungus were originally on my
Asian voices
all right so what's going there oh come
on ownage pranks that's what it's called
ownage pranks yeah pretty good if you're
bored you got some time to kill
check out youtube check out own it
Frank's [ __ ] hilarious it's all one
guy doing all those voices he calls
people and harasses them but he does
call and apologize so he's not a total
dick but that's my recommendation for
the week I've never done a
recommendation for the week I guess now
that I've said that I'm gonna have to
recommend something every [ __ ] we've
done favorite oops I recommend a mother
till next week
vector torches we're gonna go with the
gmail from emo tech that's plenty of
recommendations actually shoutout to emo
too should be enough for you to forget
hey what's up giddy thanks for the email
anyone for my car bro do you have one
with like a power converter that plugs
yeah or something some velcro so we can
velcro that [ __ ] to the - you got a
radio attachment yeah I'm about to do it
we're gonna wrap up the show I'm gonna
try to do the closing part of the show
right after this dog here we go say
something interesting Spence oh I'm not
really an interesting person
but nice with a car cat though that's
what I need
this guy likes to give me big fat nasty
bad you know I don't even like Big Daddy
I think that's why I do it cuz I don't
like oh yeah pop rocks in the brain
there we go see I remembered all my
brain is sticky now alright guys we're
gonna wrap it up because I'm super duper
high like level 11 don't worry I'm gonna
be alright I ain't gonna fall over
nothing I'm already in a chair Oh what
do you recommend you play have you
played destiny it seems to be what
everybody's hooked on it's not Monty you
like those sports games don't you I like
basketball football but recently I've
been playing Grand Theft Auto 5 stars
cruisin Tony if you have my grand theft
auto 5 I got an Xbox
[Music]
I think good care of my plants has
taught me to take better care I'll be
back in a few more days the next episode
should be hunting the freakin turf X
boys that should be awesome
don't forget sponsors documenting
supplies if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you like this review send me an
email
[Music]
please go to the iTunes Store search for
girl free heart find the review section
give me a five star rating after that
type in the comment let me know you
think of the show and I will read your
comment on a future episode stitcher
keeps [ __ ] with the way comments are
posted so post it wherever you can and
I'll find it on stitcher social media
thing you can find me at girl for me
hard at hotmail.com I don't forget the
shows available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode will always be
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
click on the grocery cart podcast tab
stop right there's that donation button
but if you wanna throw something in
there definitely appreciate it will give
you a shattered on the show for free
Heart Twitter its @g fyh podcast dude
thanks for coming Spence
for sure for sure we'll have Spence back
on in a few episodes we'll talk about
healthy stuff we'll talk about can I
tell them that you were about to embark
on a breeding project yeah I just did so
I hope I could say that on the show talk
about yeah we'll talk about that in the
future so until next time you guys take
a fat dab give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
alright cannabis community I want to
thank you guys again for listening to
another throwback Thursday episode of
the growth from your heart podcast I'll
be back Monday with the fresh show make
sure you follow me on twitter at g f YH
podcast if you'd like to send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
that's all i've got for you this week
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
you