welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 221 M to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower here at new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic boots ban who let
me use their music on my podcast big
shout out to Kat ku and the entire
mystic brew crew
ladies and gentlemen I'm recording on
Tuesday June 27 and it was a hundred
degrees outside today in Colorado I hope
you survived I hope you stay your air
conditioning situation figured out open
nothing went too hot in your grow room I
hope you were staying hydrated it was
hard to dad today you guys I felt like
when I took dabs my brain was just
cooking there's a long hot day happy
summer everybody happy summer welcome to
the summer it's gonna be a long hot
summer I hope you're prepared to get
some air conditioning fans aren't gonna
cut it you need to replace that hot air
with fresh cool air you need to cool
down the hot air a fan is just gonna
blow that heat around and piss your
plants off so figure out some air
conditioning for your grow room soon
ladies and gentlemen cuz it's only going
to get hotter also speaking of heat if
you hear a little rattle noise in the
background a little fluttering sound
that of course is the air conditioner
that is the only thing keeping me sane
right now I apologize if that is
interrupting the podcast without that I
I may go crazy and smash some [ __ ] to
tell you the truth it's too [ __ ] hot
I hate the heat I'm not a fan of the
heat which sucks because when it gets
cold I'm gonna [ __ ] and complain about
the cold also I wish we could just have
a nice even climate make everything
higher II that's what I wish ladies a
John welcome to the podcast thanks for
joining me thanks for listening to me
ramble on for a couple of minutes
already I do have a podcast planned for
you before we get their own TV huge
thanks to some people on the last
episode or two episodes ago actually I
mentioned that I have bred a new strain
and then I was growing the seeds and
that that new project needs a name I got
a lot of responses through Instagram
through Twitter through email a lot of
people responded the cross that I'm
looking for a name for is Flo from DJ
short that's right I've got a clone of
DJ shorts Flo and I pollinated that with
my male arise and I need a name for Flo
cross to arise a lot of people have sent
suggestions there's some good stuff in
there I have a good idea I actually came
up with a good idea on my own I've it
may get used but I haven't decided yet
so if you've got a name that you'd like
to submit for consideration for this or
maybe if you've got a word that you just
like to put out there to be a stray name
send it to me let me know somehow
contact me via email it's a girl from
your heart at hotmail.com you consider
it's me on twitter at g f YH podcast or
if we happen to be instagram friends if
you follow me on instagram you can send
it to me on instagram my instagram
account
I understood genetics that's right I
read genetics that's me on Instagram so
if you've got an idea for flow cross to
the arize flows the female arrives was
the male something that means like
upward flowing energy is kind of what
I'm looking for
I've got a word in mind but I'm not
certain it's not like a real easy to say
word or real popular word so I don't
know if I want to put that label on
there but you never know I might do that
I do weird [ __ ] with my strain names I
like one word names I like cool stuff
reggae related Grateful Dead related
positive moving words stuff like that
it's kind of where I'm going with it
anyway send me your suggestions grow
from your heart at hotmail.com @gf wih
podcast on twitter or irie underscore
genetics on instagram or of course
there's the Facebook simply grow from
your heart a podcast on Facebook I want
to know so your suggestions also on the
last episode I talked about the screen
of green technique that episode went up
Monday and this morning Tuesday when I
woke up and checked my email and this
isn't my email it says hey thanks for
the podcast man you answer my questions
spot-on I'm going to use the trellis on
my next grow thanks for explaining in a
simple way I'm gonna skip the next
couple of lines because it reveals too
much about you and I'm not sure that you
want people to know who you are and
that's a little personal something to
skip that and then you say and we'll
probably bug you in the future with a
question if you got time thanks again
man your show has been a life saver love
being able to listen B love being able
to learn from a good source thanks for
the hard work you put in it man ah dude
bug me with more questions please you
were not bugging me at all I love
listener generated content that lets me
know that I am hitting my target
audience I was able to answer a question
and put out a great podcast at the same
time I'm sure I helped you with your Dro
hopefully I helped a whole bunch of
other people now that information is out
there without your inspiration that
episode would not have happened so it
works perfectly for both of us I got
some content you got to learn something
so thanks a lot for your help please ask
me more questions you say you'll
probably bug me in the future
you're never bugging me that's what I'm
here for I want to help you grow better
herb then you say thanks I've been a
lifesaver that's pretty awesome to know
I like saving lives hopefully saving the
lives of lots of cannabis plants
improving the lives of lots of ganja
plants and then you said thanks for the
hard work dude you're very
thanks for noticing thanks for reaching
out if you ever have more questions
please please please email me you know
how to do it you just sent me this email
girl from your heart at hotmail.com
thanks again for the email I think I
just called you G on the last episode
because I don't know if you want me to
say your name or not but G big up G
thanks for that message perfect time is
righteous song ends also I do have
another email that I want to get in so
we're just gonna read a couple of emails
on this episode why not I like all this
listen or generated content like I said
that lets me know that I'm helping
somebody out if you ask me this question
you obviously need the answer so I'm
trying to get through as many of these
emails as I can and give them solid
answers so let's get right into this one
this one starts off in big bold capital
letters please try not to use my real
name in my email address if you do this
in the podcast then he says if you do
it's cool I'm not super worried thanks
homie then he goes on to say and don't
worry bro I'm not gonna say your name
I'll keep you undercover
you could be incognito with me he goes
on to say sort of longtime listener here
I love listening to you in the gang get
high as [ __ ] and do your throwback
podcast they've been great for real
istening while I set up a new grow I've
been growing underground in Illinois
until the last couple of years then took
a break so things have changed for sure
I just to kind of explain what this
guy's talking about he said I do like
your throwback podcasts on Thursdays
I've been putting out what I call
throwback Thursday episodes where I take
chunks of old episodes usually three
four maybe five episodes and I put them
into one chunk of of one file and then I
post that up to iTunes and stitcher and
wherever else it goes my website I regen
attics Colorado calm which that website
sucks you guys I apologize the website
is kind of a piece of [ __ ] it needs some
love I don't have time or motivation to
work on that the podcast works that's
what we need so that's there but uh I
put up the episodes and they're old
episodes iTunes and stitcher and my
website only hold 100 episodes in the
feed we are currently at episode number
221 is what I think this is so that
means there are a hundred and twenty-one
episodes not available to you anywhere I
that are not in that feed so I'm putting
them out in old chunks I am also putting
them up on YouTube but that's taking me
a little while I do have the first 60
videos up on YouTube but I've been
putting out the old throwback there
the episode so that people can go back
and listen to that because there are
some great episodes in there from about
episode 50 to about a hundred there are
some really golden episodes like
scheduling a perpetual harvest and just
stuff along those lines
lots of improving harvest and harvest
weights stuff like that
I absolutely is one of my favorite
episodes personally but those those
aren't in the feed anymore
so I've been throwing those old episodes
back in chunks so that if I put that way
when I put three episodes out I'm only
losing one episode and there are three
freshies for somebody to listen to I'm
trying to keep content fresh for you
guys and as I'm going I'm making videos
for YouTube I'm just simply putting the
girl from your heart podcast logo up on
the screen and then running the audio in
the background I'm doing very little to
the videos I just want to get them out
there so that they're listenable I will
catch up thanks for being patient with
me on that holy crap that's a lot of
ranting let me slap myself in the face
and get back focused you do like to
throwbackthursday podcast thank you
because they're kind of a lot of work it
takes my computer a long time to process
that big of a file putting it together
kind of takes me a minute so I'm glad
you appreciate that they're great for
listening while setting up a new grow
yes I love listening to podcasts while
setting up a new grow just helps me get
in the zone and get in the flow I'm glad
you're listening to my show I appreciate
that
wow you've been growing underground in
Illinois until the last couple years so
things have certainly changed yes they
have I hope you get some cool [ __ ] going
out there stay safe be careful follow
the rules and then let me know how it
goes for you then you do have some
questions let me get to the first
question it says just a couple of
questions what are your thoughts on LED
setups I can't recall you talking much
about them or was I too stoned and
missed it but I'm curious my thoughts on
LED setups honestly I don't have enough
personal experience growing under LEDs I
have grown under go Vitas I've grown
under T fives I have grown under high
pressure sodium zai have grown under
metal halides ah but I do not have any
personal experience with LED lighting I
have seen some amazing crops grown under
LED lights my friend Nancy Budd well is
a was I'm not sure if she still is I
don't want to speak out of line but
Nancy Budd well was a rep for lush
lighting for quite a while
and her lush lights were putting out
very beautiful crops she's growing some
Firefly right now under lush lights and
it looks very beautiful she took some
amazing pictures of Bounty Killer that
were grown under her lush lights and
they were gorgeous so I don't know
enough about any specific brands to love
or hate them what I do know is that if
you're getting a quality light that's
putting out the right lighting the right
colors the right spectrum and it's wired
properly and it's safe I have seen some
good [ __ ] happen I've also seen people
buy cheap shitty lights and it just
makes their plants look like [ __ ] so I
don't know what brands to recommend but
if you can do some research and
eliminate the crap brands you could
probably grow a decent crop with an LED
light is my opinion I don't have any
first-hand experience so this is not my
area of expertise but I've seen it done
and I've seen Nancy grow some great herb
I've seen a few other people grow a
great herb under LED lighting I just
haven't done it so if you're looking to
save money on electricity on cooling and
if you're just growing for yourself in
like a closet or a spare bedroom or
something and you're not trying to do a
big production crop to like pay the rent
or something if you're just a medical
patient trying to grow your own medicine
and LED should be perfect for you to
LEDs one for vegging one for flowering
you should be right where he need to be
so that's that's pretty much all I know
about LEDs is they're better for smaller
setups I saw some cool do a side-by-side
he ran his normal white his thousand
watt high pressure sodium and then he
put an LED in one section of the room
and he said that he had to feed the
plants differently they were underneath
the LED which I would believe because
they will photosynthesize differently
because they are getting completely
different spectrums of light so you may
have to change your feeding and he may
have to change your flowering times in
your veg times but it could be
beneficial and that's I wish I had more
info for you but I've never done it and
I don't want to talk out of my ass
any more than I just did so question
number two I came across the idea of
having a grow that works as a small
scale assembly line for lack of better
term the general idea is to have 12 to
16 plants total one for every week a
plant is alive so you want to have your
plants alive for 12 to 16 weeks total
which makes sense you got about a nine
week flower time
I've been probably four or five weeks of
veg onto that that's putting you have 14
weeks and then two more weeks of as a
clone is 16 weeks so you can shave off
whatever you need to Mitch you're 12 but
that's a 16 week plant life which is
acceptable then you go on to say
planting one every week harvesting one
every week moving one two veg every week
etc other than not being able to
deep-clean do repairs between cycles are
there any problems with this way of
growing should I even try something like
this then you wrap it up by saying I
hope the second question is clear enough
I'm based in Durango so I hope I can
meet you and dab you out sometime I have
way more questions but I feel bad you
have to read my rambles this far so
until next time the rain grow during
grow great question dude there's a
question number two right here I love
this this is this is a great question
and this is clear you are very well
spoke and you wouldn't believe some of
the emails I get dude you wouldn't
believe some of the people I speak to
send me more [ __ ] I like the way you
write I can tolerate you I want more
send me more questions I want to hear
them now let me answer your question yes
this is a great [ __ ] idea this is
kind of I run a giant computer not a
giant I run a medium-sized commercial
grow and this is the idea we don't do
things every day we do things in about
three weeks cycles because we cut down a
lot of herb it takes us an entire week
to finish a harvest we have a whole trim
crew come on Friday they cut down every
plant in the room it's usually one room
is a hundred and twenty six plants the
bigger room is a hundred and sixty-eight
plants or somewhere around there so
between 125 and 170 ish plants is what
we cut down at a time they cut it all
down on one day it hangs upside down
they do that on Friday then they come
back Monday usually ish or they'll cut
down on Monday come back Friday depends
on their schedule we have an outside
trim crew that comes I shout out to the
trim crew if you're listening thanks for
helping us out ah they come and they
chop it down on Monday hangs upside down
then on Friday they come and buck all
the buds off of the sticks into buckets
and then the next Monday they come and
start trimming it all up and it usually
it takes them until Friday to finish
sometimes on Friday they get off early
but usually on Friday it's a scramble to
get that last bit of blood trimmed up so
it's a 40-hour workweek trimming
trimming our weed so we only cut down
we have three flowering rooms so we cut
down about every three weeks is our
cycle so yes this is what you want you
want to always have things running odd
why I want to know why do you want to do
one plant constantly instead of having
the room come down all at once that's a
thought that I would put into this and I
know why because I'm a grower and I'm
experienced but I want you to think to
yourself why you want to do this instead
of taking down twelve or sixteen plants
at once and then having a pound of herb
as opposed to having an ounce every week
yeah and I get why because you want to
smoke an ounce a week and it's easier to
trim an ounce every week instead but
you're gonna have this is gonna create
constant work which is not a bad thing
but if you [ __ ] up then your rhythm is
[ __ ] up if you if one clone dies or if
one plant goes wrong or if you can't do
something right then you're really
screwed also this locks you into a cycle
it's where you can only grow one strain
that fits this program so this is a good
idea yes this is kind of the goal for
production two one in one out constantly
but the way I would recommend you say 16
plants here I would do four plants at a
time just to keep it that way you have
then you can put some weeks a week of
space four weeks of space or something
in there two weeks of space instead of
every Monday cut in a clone cut in a
plant down and it sounds awesome yes but
it's gonna get tedious and it's gonna
get overwhelming and when it gets
tedious and overwhelming that's when the
love comes out of it and it starts
becoming a production line and you want
to keep as much love into growing
cannabis as you can that's something
that we overlook we often see it on
baked goods and they printed on a lot of
packaging in the end the dispensaries
that this product was made with love and
the ingredients we have to remember to
put that into cannabis if you're smoking
cannabis recreationally if you're
smoking cannabis medically loved is a
required ingredient this is a plant this
is something that's growing from a seed
from Earth this has got some earth life
energy no matter what you believe in
this has got some connection to you
somehow and you got to put love into it
anything that you put love into grows
better anything you nourished properly
grows better and then I think it's
better to if you're smoking
recreationally you're medicating because
you feel better and it's even if it's
just to make your mind smile and make
your bits
that's a medical treatment too because
it's a relief in some way you you're
you're it's it's relief in my opinion so
it needs to be nourished as a medical
product or as a real product that we're
going to put into our bodies and it will
medicate us better so you need to treat
your plants with love and I think if you
have too much of a production the love
kind of falls out and I may be a [ __ ]
hippie for thinking that and that's cool
maybe you don't believe that there needs
to be loving your plants I'm not single
India I'm not saying I'm maybe other
people don't believe there needs to be
love maybe aa kind of a good friend who
I'll see him tomorrow afternoon he
doesn't love the plants he knows that
that's a production line this is a
product and he's going to grow this
product it's a commodity we will cut it
down we will sell it we will do more he
doesn't love the plants I love the
plants I feel like it's something you
should do sorry I get sad treks I love
the plants but yes so your your idea is
perfect but I would do instead of doing
16 plants and doing one every week I
would kind of break it down into four in
four out that way you can get three
weeks of not having to trim because if
you're gonna have to trim one plant
every week and then you're gonna have
one plant curing it's been in the jar
for a little bit you're gonna have to
birth that jar and I don't know how big
your plants are gonna be but it's gonna
be a lot of work it's gonna be a lot of
excess work if you chop the harvesting
things in larger batches is just easier
for burping and stuff like that but I'm
not trying to shoot down your idea if
you are dedicated and you think you want
to do that if you don't have another job
and if you don't have a busy life this
would be [ __ ] awesome for you this
would not work for me I am way too busy
to chop down a plant every week cut a
clone every week it just seems tedious
to me but that is the idea what you're
getting at is ultimately the idea there
are large grows in Colorado that work on
basically this plan they put but if they
do it every week every Monday plants go
in and plants come down every Monday
plants go in plants come down and that's
there's just crude you are right the
only downside to it is not being able to
deep clean and do repairs but there's
nothing stopping you from pulling every
plant out of that room or over to one
side of the room and cleaning the [ __ ]
out of where you can and move the plants
the other side of the room clean the
[ __ ] out of where you can
or you've got 12 hours during a
flowering cycle you should be able to do
just about any kind of repairs you need
to do during a 12 hour cycle that's my
opinion I don't know I don't know how
physically able you are or what kind of
work skills you've got but most stuff
that needs to be done in there cleaning
wise you can take down I have taken down
an entire room Mike and I have taken
down every bit of ducting every light
pulled out the flooring redid the
flooring in the room we actually painted
the whole room with kills redid all the
ducting we did it all in 12 hours those
plants didn't skip a day they didn't
miss a minute of their night cycle they
were all back on the right cycle so I
think it can be done just about however
big the room is you may need a friend
it's got a dedicate and if you're down
to do this [ __ ] 16 plants every 16
weeks idea you got to be down to clean
and do stuff like that it sounds like
you're a savage during grow whenever
you're up in the Pueblo area or if
you're in Denver or Colorado Springs hit
me up I'd love to dab with you I go to a
lot of comedy shows and stuff like that
so if you're going to comedy shows if
you're going to the any of the the fish
shows Brella it sounds like you might be
going to fish a lot of folks from
Durango come up to see fish look for me
hit me up we'll take some dabs together
ladies and gentlemen sure you can hear
my throat doing that thing where it's
getting dry I'm gonna press pause for uh
well I'm gonna pause for several minutes
I'm gonna take a couple of dabs I'm
gonna drink some water and then I'll be
right back and we will read some more
emails
[Music]
yeah I am back Podcast world guess what
my head is vibrating ooh yeah I just
took a big old gigantic dad of lemons
skunk dunked in lemon Geoffrey hi
terpene full spectrum extracts and it
tastes like I just ate an entire so if
you took the powdered sugar stuff off of
a lemon head just the lemon candy flavor
and just concentrated that into one bite
like the the whole the powder from one
bag it tastes like I just ate that much
of that flavor it's strong on my tongue
like it tastes as lemons and there's
like this real smooth flavor I really
enjoy that but yeah that is intense holy
crap there's talking to the friend it in
I have we all agree that lemon and
limonene stuff and lemon flavored Terps
are really good for your head injuries
so if you got a head injury you guys we
can all recommend the limonene and
lemony Terps that just makes my head
feel better I talked about that on a
recent episode but somebody else agreed
with me all right I'm gonna get my [ __ ]
together I was just talking about the
email from our friend to rein grow
thanks for the email if you guys want to
email me send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I want to answer
your grow questions but I want to remind
you that I think it was episode number
73 was all about scheduling a perpetual
grow and it was basically what you were
talking about but it was using a 5x5
flowering space and another 5x5 space to
feed that to pull down one plant every
four weeks is what I think I was doing
unfortunately that episode is not in the
feed because like I rambled about
earlier iTunes and stitcher only hold of
100 episodes but I am very close to
getting back up on iTunes so bear with
me and within the next few weeks here
we'll get that up on iTunes and everyone
can listen to these scheduling a
perpetual grow episode alright I've got
another email here on my phone this one
I found very interesting a few episodes
ago I spoke of my head injury I don't
want to ramble on about it right now for
too long but about two and a half years
ago I suffered a traumatic brain injury
ie
I'm 6 foot 5 and I walked through a
doorway that apparently was 6 foot 2 and
it knocked me the [ __ ] out I don't
remember hitting I remember thinking I
need to go get a chair it's at the
bottom of those stairs
and then I remember uh kind of sound
like a cymbal crash maybe a little bit
of lightning maybe a tailgate of a truck
slamming and I remember being at the
bottom of the stairs and all my friends
saying my name and I was like what the
[ __ ] you keep saying my name it was like
why am I on the floor I [ __ ] myself up
I knocked myself clean the [ __ ] out I
was not right for a long time I spoke
about it on a recent podcast I don't
need to go too far into it right here
but I'm much better now much better I
feel like I'm Way better now I ramble a
lot now but I feel like I'm Way better
anyway
a listener wanted to email me and I
found this to be a very great email it
goes like this
rhasta Jeff I heard your podcast on TBI
and what happened to you much love bro I
suffer from chronic PTSD and my doctor
suggested I try THC it has changed my
life and my outlook on it your podcast
puts a positive note to the change we
all want to see so far so good right you
guys this guy suffers from chronic PTSD
I've got a little bit of PTSD from I had
a friend who discovered they had a
seizure disorder she wasn't my friend
she's my girlfriend I lived with her and
we discovered that she had a seizure
disorder and her seizures were [ __ ]
horrible and I wasn't prepared to live
with that at that time in my life and I
watched that person have some serious
medical problems and it [ __ ] me up I
don't think I've ever talked about that
on a podcast but I've got some PTSD from
watching a girlfriend from my past have
grand mal seizures and nearly died
multiple times so I've got some PTSD and
I believe that the THC kind of it
doesn't allow those shitty thoughts to
come up when they do you could be and I
know that's a shitty way to cover your
problems but it does kind of the PTSD
triggers weird [ __ ] and it makes other
emotions start going and it gives you
more things and it stops at that so I
agree that it does work it does change
your life I'm glad that it changed your
outlook on it and dude I am glad that my
podcast puts a positive note because
that's what that's what I try to do I
try to be a good ambassador for this
point so that means a lot to me here's
the part of the email that everybody is
gonna go Wow because I really did this
listener says I am
former law enforcement officer and never
thought I would be using THC so sad to
know how ignorant I was for all those
years thank God I found cannabis and
added it to my daily life
dude I am very grateful that you have
found cannabis and added it to your
daily life it's helping with your PTSD I
had helped me with my head injury it
helped a couple of guys I was talking to
today with their head injuries it is
helping a lot of people take care of
their heads and manage their head
problems so I'm glad you found it what I
want to know is are you sharing any
information with your fellow law
enforcement friends I it says that you
are a former law enforcement officer so
if you've got people that are still in
law enforcement still active are you
doing anything to kind of educate them a
little bit are you doing it are you
sharing is your cannabis use your THC
use is this public knowledge with
anybody as your family knows your do
your loved ones know do your colleagues
know I kind of want to know and if this
is too much I won't share on the podcast
or anything send me an email and let me
know how are you using the THC to
control your PTSD is one thing I'd like
to know not control but help and then
how public and/or private are you about
your cannabis use and would you maybe
share my podcast with some of your law
enforcement colleagues so that we could
show them that we aren't all just pot
heads trying to smoke to get high to
giggle and watch teach and cheong that a
lot of us have medical conditions that
without cannabis we wouldn't be able to
function and have a daily life and I
don't say that lightly I am a caregiver
I provide medical cannabis for a couple
of people that I don't know if one guy
would still be here if he didn't smoke I
don't know how I would be able to handle
my brain injury if I didn't have
cannabis available to me I don't know
how your PTSD would treat your life if
you didn't find THC things may be
drastically different if we didn't have
a little THC in our lives so maybe you
could share my show with your law
enforcement friends or I don't know if
you want to do that because you don't
want to out yourself but you've already
you were no longer a law enforcement
officer so I mean you know they're gonna
fire you I'm just trying to do it maybe
you can share this for us and spread the
word
and you're on our team now so so help us
out if you can I appreciate it
it's always great to hear people change
and come to the green side from the dark
side I just made that up anyway I hope
THC keeps your PTSD under control and I
look forward to hearing more from you
thanks for the email
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure I've
scented a lot of times if you want to
email me it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you all right I've got one more thing on
a rant about just for a couple of
seconds before I start wrapping up the
podcast um if there's something in your
grow room that you can do today do it
today if there's some cleaning up that
can be done if there's some improving
that can be done some straightening if
there's a small mess that you need to
wipe up if you can do it today do it
today don't push some stuff off for
tomorrow that can be done today because
there's gonna be some other [ __ ]
tomorrow to handle one thing I teach the
guys when I hire new people or when I
train people at a commercial grow I
always teach them that the first thing
you get to do when you walk in is play a
game called find the surprise commercial
grows cost millions of dollars but for
some reason there's always a little
[ __ ] it doesn't seem to matter how
much money you spend how much you
prepare something goes wrong randomly
overnight when you're gone it always
happens when you're gone if you watch
the cameras it always happens right when
you leave you lock the door and then
click something goes [ __ ] wrong and
you don't notice it until you get there
twelve hours later you walk in at 7:00
or 8:00 in the morning and there's 50
gallons of water in the floor or
something weird happened that you never
would have foreseen you never could have
predicted but now you've got to deal
with it so always keep in mind that
there's gonna be [ __ ] popping up
tomorrow that you're not prepared to
deal with so clean up do whatever you
can today if you're gonna do foliate
defoliates a day if you could trellis
trellis today don't wait until tomorrow
because tomorrow is going to have its
own [ __ ] up surprises knock [ __ ] out
get it out of the way do what you need
to do early and then you can just kick
back and relax if you let [ __ ] wait
until tomorrow that means you're
probably gonna let something else wait
until tomorrow which means you got
tomorrow's work plus that [ __ ] you
waited for and then you're not gonna get
it all done so now that shit's gonna
fall onto Wednesday and now Wednesday is
gonna [ __ ] suck because you've got
Monday's work fell onto Tuesday
Tuesday's work fell into Wednesday
you're doubled up on Wednesday now I'm
simply getting off at 5:00 we're not
gonna get off till 6:00 and then [ __ ]
Thursday already sucks so just do the
[ __ ] you can do get it done have it done
and then when Friday and Saturday come
it's kicking it time you don't have to
worry so much that's my advice if you
can get it done today get in there and
get it done today because tomorrow
tomorrow you never know I'm the manager
the facility manager that grow the
cultivation manager the cult leader at
my grow and if a contractor shows up I
have to follow them around and talk to
them if the meed shows up I'm the one
that has to follow them around and talk
to them when the consultants come when
the investors come when the owners come
that's right I follow them around and
talk to them so if I've got some work
planned for tomorrow and I stacked up
too much [ __ ] for myself and one ring of
the doorbell happens my whole day can be
jumbled and I'm not gonna have time to
do what I want to do and if I save
something from yesterday for today I'm
certainly not gonna have time to do it
all right I feel like I reiterated and
reiterated that rambley point just get
[ __ ] done don't hesitate don't wait the
plants aren't gonna wait for you don't
[ __ ] wait don't be lazy you're
growing herb man it's one of the best
jobs you can have you're growing
cannabis get in there and do your best
every day sure I should just drop the
mic at that right get in there do your
best every day thud mic drop gone home
see you next episode
all right ladies I really am gonna wrap
up the podcast I want to thank you guys
for listening to another episode make
sure you check out patreon.com
patreon is a service that allows you as
a listener to contribute to the show
what that does is helps me pay for my
web hosting help so we pay for these
little foam covers they go over my
microphone helps me pay for my
high-speed Internet connection so that I
can upload these giant files of podcasts
patreon.com slash girl from your heart
if you were able to help out even if you
can't help out I still love you thank
you for listening to the podcast also I
would love it if you stock me on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast you can find me on
Facebook search for the girl from your
heart podcast and I've set it one
hundred and twenty-two times in this
episode send me an email it's a girl
from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you also there
is a YouTube channel the first 60
episodes are up on YouTube now that's
right if you search for the girl from
your heart podcast on you too
you will find it go check it out good
leave some comments get the comments
start it only takes one or two comments
and then everybody wants to speak their
opinion we get a bunch of trolls in
there the more trolls the more comments
the more views it'll just get the page
moving that's what we need for right now
get some people notice in the podcast up
there on YouTube that will inspire me to
get more videos out and then hopefully
I'll get caught up before too long
alright ladies and gentlemen if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast or if you've
got a product you'd like me to review
live on the show send me an email
once again it's ignore from your heart
at hotmail.com i would love to check out
your product ladies and gentlemen that
is all i've got for you this week I'll
be back Thursday with another throwback
Thursday episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend fast berry and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
for you for you and me
cause I see how the
[Music]
for you and for you
you