what's that podcast world it's Thursday
that means it's time for another
throwback Thursday episode of the girl
from your heart podcast today we're
doing episodes 59 60 and 61 I talk a lot
and I start making mistakes so let's get
right to the chase
here's the old episodes
[Music]
I need it so much it's so god damn blame
when I price of mash and that [ __ ] don't
melt it just turns into a black biscuit
on the neck
well Nebraska
[Music]
got the gnome and oppressed guys yeah
you know we got so much
[ __ ] in Nebraska no Mount abrasca
we got the normal Nebraska yeah we've
got that [ __ ] big Braska Braska
Nebraska I've got to [ __ ] get all of
this it just makes me sick I just want
to get rid of all of it somebody please
take mine Oh Malcolm
Nebraska
[Music]
Nebraska is Jordan from turf X how about
turf X you got to find out I have been
dabbing mad torpex for the past two
three weeks and turf X's put a smile on
my face I just dab some chem dog nectar
all right here I'm gonna turn it back
over to Jordan no bro no melt Nebraska
let's hear it again okay so no Mountain
Nebraska is basically any
in Nebraska had someone come down we
lived in Northern California came down
from Mendocino miss talking for weeks
about this awesome amazing granddaddy
[Music]
light brown you don't really get any
smoke in the face I'm making does not
convey on radio at all but I'm making
this faint like if you've ever smelled
burnt hair I'm making the face that
happens when you smell burnt hair buddy
[Music]
or mostly meltdown
kind of everybody you know if you don't
understand all of the verbage
nomenclatures going on today definitely
right in to the grill from your heart
podcast and ask for a definition well my
name is Richard and I don't understand
what that nomenclature word is that you
I'm frankly I'm offended no not
everybody can be on the level I'm pretty
sure it's to my mostly left over here
I'm gonna say what's that like 11
o'clock you bet the 11:30 position
because that's for 20 plus 710 there we
go that is my buddy hunt that's the
crime again how you doing brother I am
ecstatic to finally be on the potty
once the [ __ ] talking about it and
getting called out by my boy Irie for
not listening and they're trying to
listen and playing it at our shop and
doing everything I finally [ __ ] hear
spittin grammar on the mic I am the turf
man I'm in the turf mansion I guess the
trippy Trap House been to my house I've
invaded their dining area I stepped on
their dog walked in kick the dog grab
the email and set up a mic and the dog
is asking for a kickin dude that dog
came right back and tried to hump your
ass
he probably smelled moose knuckle ninja
foot for a reason that's the not act my
age this is your fault that all this
chaos I'm also gonna give a huge
shameless plug to green and healthy
cannabis on to 12 South 21st Street and
Colorado Springs how much love I know I
do work for but I come up to in between
and we're always there waiting for your
name you just these guys just merged out
of the video game rule a few minutes ago
[ __ ] you got a real podcast join the
show GG fam is thick and thorough barely
smoke blunts
sometimes you got to take it back to 16
you know all right it's gonna be a great
podcast I wrote down will hunt wrote
down a few topics he's gonna be the OCD
guy in the group post at the time I wish
I could read your writing dude you know
that's a another topic hunt was recently
diagnosed with asthma how's that going
for you I can't walk upstairs that fast
[Music]
temporary asthma with bronchitis right
now so I'm like off all the [ __ ]
pieces and she sounds like a definitely
definitely part of the speeding Viper
Club you were up in a helicopter jumping
out of a helicopter onto a 1,400 foot
Mountain on skis 14
[Music]
yeah I was just in Silverton like two
weeks ago doing a bunch of healthy drops
and skiing 13,000 foot cliffs with Vitus
yeah I had bronchitis cute Laurinaitis
at that point yes still jumping out of
the hill and dad whatever you did last
week you're a [ __ ] my buddy hunt was on
top of a 14,000 foot mountain jumping
out of a helicopter on skis and [ __ ]
five feet of POW and now it goes to the
inhaler our butanol OG player as long as
you feel good does it help yeah since
you invited me here I want to definitely
make sure to take some time to rip all
your companies Graeme Gatsby
tell tell me give you a couple seconds
to hype up the gasps Graeme Gatsby V
Graeme Gatsby calm if you want to check
it out it's a media and lifestyle
website and since that's been started
years ago there's now like a large
portfolio of awesome people and brands
that make the country have green and
healthy wellness down in Colorado
Springs with this dispensary Apothic
Anna cannabis topicals and lotions we
can yeah the whole Turk squad how I get
down you know I have my own moniker here
called the gatherer with the text room
there's like 34 34 down here and the VIP
is sold out at 50 the cannabis Grand Cru
is a big you know super high echelon
limited to 500 people in its event that
travels all over the country that I
helped produce smokey brand
you know custom sublimated socks and
sublimated clothing plus knitted stuff
and we source stuff for you know all
kinds of unbelievable brands so we can
get just about anything we want printed
on some song write anything that you
want on a sock and anyone on a shirt
pretty much anything that you want and
concentrate for them anything you want
in topicals anything you want on the
shelf
anything you need work I'm just now
working on this 3d printing company
that's gonna start up and ever pretty
soon so it's kind of like you know
whatever comes through and how we can do
it to maximize the whole network a
personal request for some Apothic Anna
I've got a friend who she's got bad skin
okay and she would love a cannabis
product or a more organic healthy
product to help her clear up her
blemishes dope so let's get a path to
count on that one rashes irritations
cuts burns blisters like a wood there's
a rig for you shout out to the mad Rob
rig yes for a dab a minute ago and I
just shiny fest talking yeah you're just
like yeah I mean it's if you go to the
website follow us on instagram at Graeme
Gatsby but it's a just a gigantic
network of people much like I reinter
pecs and everything else that we do it's
you know trying to be as community-based
and making sure people are getting
forward and being positive and there's
tons of brands I mean the guys that are
in the room were probably the most
important ones because this is how we
all make it happen
[Music]
you know shallots Colorado Springs
you've been super kind
[Music]
is increased
please don't squish me you reminded me
you asked me when I got here why they
made me change the name yes it used to
be I grow I grow culture yeah yeah I
grow like based on the iPhone and the I
back and the high cortisol is culture
you listen on your iPhone but there's an
educational entity that does
agricultural educational seminars or
some kind of [ __ ] for colleges he goes
for the inhaler
[Music]
we're like the avatar of another guy in
Bangladesh you know
content is king as they say in its
quality and consistency you wanna have
the right branding together
you're not trying to put up pictures of
brick walls all kinds of weird things
like that way you can expose I will tell
you the one thing that I've learned over
the years is that your audience I knew
of Terp X before they ever had a
Colorado presence because of their
cup-winning
who relax speaking to me I'm gonna do
this dr. pepper into the room what's
going on this guy pretty much most every
time I saw him he had a dr. pepper you
know he had to start getting all healthy
and everything you know we put the dr.
peppers away for a while it's just hard
for him to sit here at this table and
watch you enjoying beans lip balm
[ __ ] drinks they make all kinds of
stuff with the 23 flavor turn see that
perfection left-handed lefty show it's
like orange cookies I can just smell it
yeah how long has it been even in Vegas
really No
[Music]
you have to talk about Apothic Anna the
Gatsby is gonna give these some time
here in just in random conversation that
there are several badass new products
coming out in the future through the
turf X line my attention of course I
asked this while George's taking a meet
[Music]
bringing out standard there's gonna be a
couple different things there's
definitely gonna be some some just
regular BHO pens that being grown for
we've got some edibles that are gonna
start coming out here
[Music]
yeah that's definitely your badge
picture is hilarious and the best story
about that one I told the boys but when
I got my picture taken at the meed the
little lady that works the computer
[Music]
all right so we have sir packs a little
bit what's uh we mentioned a bunch of
products what's your favorite one the
most that you're most excited about that
you want to hype up language to say
which one of these things fingers off
after you do that dude I don't even want
to touch you now I would say we're
pretty excited about the edibles coming
out you know that's something that we
were working on for a while but we just
didn't want to you know drank yeah we
didn't want to hit the market before you
know we've really had everything figured
out especially without restrictive
everything every ropes like Peter North
on that I think I want to dab on that
one definitely silent to the whole room
gonna be on point once we can actually
say there's gonna and I will say I'll go
a little bit more in-depth on some
things yeah might roll might roll handus
don't get me on comments with all the
new products they have coming to you I
mean you have an unbelievable way to
kind of get a comprehensive medication
on you can ingest cutting through some
new CBD strains here we've already got
but you know we've got some truly truly
unique terpene profiles on a lot of [ __ ]
that we're looking for I threw down
something I think should be high in CBD
if it comes through for you guys dope
should be high in CBD the uglier plants
will be higher in CBD yeah that's a
great way to describe it I mean people
that are at home growing hemp rope Kona
cannabis it's okay - oops
all right Tirpitz edibles how long until
you think I can have Sumter pecks
edibles and is it gonna be like bility
beans curious I'm sure it was a show my
jobs to ask questions were your
headphones and take a DAB what is that
about you don't have to I was just
[ __ ] with you because it was weird
it's like turning down the radio so you
can see better we've got a few things
that we're making this week we're
sending everything to get its the Shelf
because Murray no doubt you guys if you
guys can take the 1200 milligrams
allenge in a day challenge so kind of
like no mountain of brass can we get a
little bit of guitar but yeah like I
mean the 12-under milligram challenge is
much like know about Nebraska in a sense
where the name kind of gives it away but
there's a lot more in depth about your
passion for the actual event so you know
you want to start off probably with
maybe 400 to 800 milligrams and slowly
work your way up to 12 and then at that
point you go outside and put your hands
up in the air and scream up the jaw
thank you and mental or physical
challenge it's something that you need
to work yourself up to you know you
can't just jump in sponsor can I get a
sponsor for this row down I need 1,200
and then I need 800 so now we're at
2,000 okay I want to do it like a 300 I
think I've done 350 I mean a 350
I found best to imbibe the 1200
milligrams of straight capsules and you
open the capsules up and take them while
they're half okay and then you just
pretty much you know you just jump right
in like Allen's carpet see the the the
last time we were preparing for the
milligrams at 1200 milligrams challenged
it I was actually pretty disappointed
because I was you know talking hell of
[ __ ] on everybody because I've been
training really hard like I was waking
up every day just slamming you know
eating a thousand milligrams for
breakfast you know what I'm saying then
having another couple hundred for lunch
you know what I'm saying I was ready by
the time that happened everybody else
had been eaten so many capsules to
training for training for the challenge
that it was just like [ __ ] wasn't going
well business in Washington who was
gonna be doing it with us he broke like
two mothership minis that he knocked
over his mother it's not like you want
to go straight to the black diamonds at
the mountain and throw your serious 1200
to make sure we were over a thousand and
if you really want to get intense you
tried it 2500 yeah that just sounds the
rim again soon that's like that's like
the gram dab of edibles if you don't
smoke those are obviously good ways to
do it if you're really trying to get you
know some sort of sedation for me it was
just the fact like I don't have anxiety
and I'm extremely focused and let's be
real if you're trying to like never get
sick you know cancer everything pretty
much
so if you eat that [ __ ] you're gonna be
like we figured if we could do like 1200
milligrams for a month there was no way
that we would ever have any pathogens
cancers [ __ ] because we're just
super sad
yeah so I need a sponsor somebody throw
down like 2500 pills
[Music]
a real high CBD have I told you guys
about my CBD adventures have you
listened to the episode with CBD now you
guys roll extract extract artist what
are you guys call yourselves house
extract artist the term anymore is there
a is there a work to use because I've
noticed if I smoke too much CBD I can't
bust a nut to really perform that kind
of research on myself I went to a
dispensary I had a medicine and we
smoked out and we went to the house and
tried to [ __ ] shag and there was no
it was fun dude we're both like yeah but
like an hour of just
[Music]
I was talking to a nurse and she said I
think she's a paramedic or something and
she said that there is an electrical
response in your brain that causes a
seizure and that same electrical
response in your brain is responsible
for your orgasm it's like the electrical
firing when you smoke CBD it turns that
off that's why you don't have a seizure
you're coding you're freaking [ __ ]
receptor - he was putting like the cover
over it it's like getting an elevator
with no 13th floor but just something I
just never thought we'd share grow a lot
of hemp in China and they use that [ __ ]
and it ain't working over there
give John John a microphone so you're
saying CPD's will actually make you last
longer yes
much longer I couldn't so I couldn't
come at all so the truth yeah if you're
a minute man then get up on the CBD
[Music]
about getting back up after you long
enough to even care we've gotten way off
course for twenties coming up I've been
told that there is a cannabis cut booth
there is some things in the work
obviously we talked about all the
different rings but lots of brands
smokey brand what are the big badass
clothing companies that I have worked
with they've decided to kind of do this
Roche every year so I'll be you know
Manning up and running their production
for the Denver cannabis cup coming up
Seattle San Fran LA and then we'll be
doing agenda and magic AG big gallery
we'll be doing like varieties of like
cannabis cups to glass shows but this
cannabis cup in Denver we will have a
smoky brand booth that'll be probably
like four or five brands from the
Turkana and i region etics and dude it's
damsel shout out to damsel I don't think
you guys will be appearing I'm not sure
we'll be in our booth yeah Banks crew
I'll be at the the cannabis caboose I'll
be at the cup roaming around so Russ and
Jeff will be up there I probably won't
have any seeds because honestly I'm
going to a I want to sound like a dick
there's a private party Friday night
between a bunch of seed breeders and
trainers and true but you've invited all
these and my seeds will probably be
eaten up then the only seeds will be
giving away are the ones he's picking up
for me on Friday night
you've got a surplus of Irish there
might be a couple packs in my backpack
when I start actually there might be a
couple in there right now guys Tora Bora
across to King stopper grapes king Kim
grape stopper oh gee if you're in a new
state if you can't find the yeah I don't
work hard to keep stuff going I'm
actually working on the black cherry Kim
f2 right now I'm actually harvesting I
did the pheno hunt to find the female
that I want to breed with and I'm
harvesting them now I think I chose the
right [ __ ] good I've got a purple one
[Music]
their arguments I've crossed the lemon
Geoffrey to the Grateful dog and there
are arguments over what the name is
gonna be
[Music]
you know I don't [ __ ] around and it's
gonna make some Terp X shatter or some
not if I can make my own hash I don't
have my own backup and luckily I've got
friends and let me use their back I can
make some decent but garden of Weeden
shadow boys they live five minutes away
from me that's my homies they make most
my hash for me and since nobody's had a
harvest for a minute and we are hash
heads and we smoked all our hash it's
been turf axe is my we send a lot of
people up there we need to work out some
sort of affiliate program another so if
you guys are in Denver or if you're in
Pueblo drive to Springs and go get this
hash is it worth the 45-minute Drive I
do it every week I'm up here once a week
usually on a Thursday that's true coming
on Fridays cuz it's donut day bro oh
yeah that is we do do a donuts every
Friday morning dealer made us do it we
play hip hop all day we have Amy's
Donuts in the lobby for all the people
that come through while they
quickly I got I should have waited to
deliver that new drop I delivered a new
drop of flavors over there at clothes
tonight I should have came right when
they open tomorrow so I could have got
first pick at the ranch they keep us
with everything from that Elvis with
blueberry with the rainbow I've only had
one I want to know about this name
Drake's handkerchief put the Nature Boy
Ric Flair on the mic because that's his
name get up on the top rope
[Music]
on the video game uncharted Drake is an
adventurer because since moving to
[ __ ] Colorado I've seen more flow
smells or tastes exactly like [ __ ]
flow than I've seen ever in my [ __ ]
life what's up with that is that the
bomb I don't they don't like push they
don't like where's the cush it goes the
dogs trying to go outside okay it's cool
I think I mean I think a lot of it is
the fact that like that blue dream just
blows up like a balloon for people that
don't know what they're doing
the flow is super easy to grow and if
your mediocre grower and you need to
pull some weight dream dream is for you
if you never grown wheat you've never
grown weed before and you're about the
flow that goes around here actually came
from DJ short gave that cut to Ed
Rosenthal who passed it around to a few
people out here and my friend Tom I had
a dispensary here and a dispensary in
Pueblo and he spread that out through
his dispensaries a lot and also went
through other sources I'm not saying he
put it all over
but that cut I actually think his DJ's
flow to cut and not flow I think back in
the 1940s when they so I crossed the
blue dream to the Grateful dog and I
call it the Blue Heeler and unfixed Blue
Dream you made the made much larger
grateful dog nuggets and it comes out a
lot like grateful dog just better
harvests you can polish a turd yes I
have to keep a mother plant of this f2
of black cherry Kim with black cherry
Kim pollen and I want to call it Garcia
[Music]
name for that lemon Jeffrey grateful dog
I'm working on I want to work for I'm
looking for in a rise male plant right
now I wanna start using the arise as my
breeding staple that'll be my next boy
that goes for a long time okay
golden go crossed a day breaker so it's
sweet like the breakers a great plan
yeah and anything you put to the gold
and go it makes resin like it just resin
comes out of that [ __ ] so yeah that
male will make everything resin he and
stinky so I want to talk about something
real quick this is the new thing going
on all
[Music]
I have not tried it actually I have an
interview we're ahead of ourselves in
recording but I've left a blank spot to
throw in an interview with carving
starry-eyed love to see some locals do
it so that I could take a dab of it talk
about on the show somebody go to the
beauty supply store and pick up a hair
straightener
[Music]
yes you you took a couple seconds and
looked at him on bed bath and beyond put
the dab torches the little no stick mats
and turkey basters all in the same area
and Pyrex dishes it's like a computer
program they say it seems like people
are buying a lot of torches and Turkey
bases at the same time we should put
them together before your birthday or
[Music]
wrote down the phrase getting globby and
put little marks by what are no slabby
a long time ago I bought a piece of
equipment called a compressor doesn't
let that all that microphone get to all
of here do you want to get it up
[Music]
commercials because I guess what you
guys
[Music]
Rakeem company the organic portions of
this episode were brought to you by my
good friends at the rocky man worm
company shout out to Allen and Jay and
Sean and everybody over there visit the
rocky Matt and warm company and Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings Africa
night crawlers red wigglers come on
let's do some dirty jokes
go there go there go there you can check
them out Rocky Mountain worm company
calm or 411 Tijuana Street in Colorado
Springs Colorado make sure you tell
those guys you heard them heard about
them through the podcast to Alan and the
boys we were talking about before the
show too because I was saying that some
impressive [ __ ] that you guys got going
over there no pun intended literally
good [ __ ] yeah it's good [ __ ] over there
were JT the boys JT and the boys got a
DAB on the dabber here what else you
guys get slabby we went over all your
notes I wasn't I'm ready to let it get a
little bit looser it's why I read the
commercials Oh
like little kids behave in the behaving
themselves we got two four five grown
men in the room plus a guy that snuck
away cuz he's too shy for the podcast
and the guitar guitar yeah let's get the
guitar back I think it's probably talk
for another few seconds I'm gonna take a
DAB just like Joey P I think I think
this is probably time to you know give a
little shout-out to dr. pepper for all
the sponsoring that they do for us but
obviously we need the we need to give a
little bit of a talk about you know the
stick-to-itiveness and wherewithal
sometimes out there we're noticing that
some of you works are slacking slipping
on your pimpin as they say you don't if
you're gonna bring an ashy pimp an for
the low down lowball price you better
make sure that [ __ ] is frosty on this
cheek stuff that I be seeing around all
these dudes with like 35 hatpins
homeboys that don't have no girls but
drive a rental car and have
other ships in the coil rig but you
[Music]
morning but you got like 35 [ __ ] rigs
in the basement that you kick it on in
like you get on the forums I'm not
trying to harsh anybody's mellow on the
west coast of the east coast or any
[ __ ] if you want to get down on the
[ __ ] Pandi rigs and you want to
wear all that crap is cool I'm just
saying the day become a grown-ass man
and you want to get grown-ass man [ __ ]
you got to put that [ __ ] in the box move
it to the left like they're doing like
the whole wedding cross your arms
together and take each other's [ __ ]
dad it's cute my favorite episodes to
record and I hate to say that to all my
homies record with me but you guys
brought something to the table that has
actually sitting next to my business
partner and my father my friend yeah
there's nobody here old enough to be
your father that doesn't make any sense
the Terp ex-king basically I would say
the you know fatherly figure
[Music]
you know the guy who you know your Brian
Epstein of bro we're gonna get serious
for half a second we were talking today
at the shop about being under
high-intensity discharge lights
taught me something I never thought
about guys cover your skin up in the
grow rooms if you're if you're in your
own personal girl you're probably
alright but if you're in like a room
with like 20 or 30 or 40 or like I work
with there's a hundred and twenty lights
in some of the places cover your skin up
cover the top of your head wear some
glasses definitely people are getting
melanoma people are seeing weird [ __ ] on
their heads are getting like signs of
sunburn their hair is falling out and
[ __ ] you're gonna go blind in there get
some good glasses I didn't even think of
that I only think about the
cover up your skin cover your hands no
for sure yeah it's definitely just or a
sunscreen producer so for a scientist
it's been talked about here there you
know obviously it's the exposure rate
that your room for six to eight hours a
day I use long sleeves and pubes should
be there's a tattoo the difference I can
see the difference in your arm tattoos
and your body tattoos from having a
shirt and where you're exposed like the
dude static guys and you have to go
through and I can only imagine this you
know
[Music]
all right so drink and we're promised a
song after a dad what happened is the
bread so I'm gonna come out today is the
first global release of the bread you
guys you guys did like a nice little
pretty face leftover triplets with the
logo on the website there's a bunch of
places you guys knew of or folks can get
it but it's only medical so I didn't
want to tease old out-of-staters
[Music]
between an hour 30 and 40 minutes maybe
an hour today and recreational hoping to
turn them away now
[Music]
it didn't cost my car it was just
stopped on that middle part of his chest
until he breathes again
[Music]
sectors sectors whoops
the microphone in front of the guitar we
can get some audio in here get a lot of
listens the great show it's been fun
with this many people are super exciting
Trap House to get down we're here I'm
gonna leave the gear and we'll just
record again tomorrow is fine are you
ready to jam
I'm ready son
[Music]
where you keep another breath
did you
[Music]
where you keeping all the bread
did you healed I said where are you
keeping oh my [ __ ] looking for
[Music]
not the kind that you eat but the gun
that you smoke
I just want some bread did you hear what
I said bread
I just want that [ __ ] bread bread
[Music]
didn't even listen to a [ __ ] word I
said I won't break
[Music]
where are you keeping nother place where
you keeping all the bread where you keep
another pray
keeping all the bread
[Music]
we'd love to see you yes visit John John
John's a kak at Nintendo with two g's on
Instagram is our man
[Music]
the crowd goes crazy to find you or
Instagram bro Eric underscore cheater
Eric er okay I'm John John at nut Tendo
- geez I'm drop e-tag mic drop
[Music]
talk about a bucket you guys are down
with the bucket you'll figure it out
we'll talk about that don't forget to
check out our sponsors Rocky Mount
Warren Company and hydro indoor growing
supplies if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like me to review or some
edibles you'd like me to sample for you
all the info you need do you wanna say
social media you can hit me up it's g f
YH podcast and think about that I forgot
it find me on Facebook don't forget
every show is available on iTunes
stitcher and I read genetics Colorado
calm dude the donation button I added a
donation button to the podcast page on I
read genetics Colorado calm people have
been donating money I appreciate that so
much
I promised I would go to a specific
cause it's going to that cause that will
end in May and then after that we'll
figure out a new cause for that but
[ __ ] appreciate that from the bottom
of my heart thanks for throwing down
yeah follow I reach in that excited
Instagram super huge shout out to my
ninja spins until next time you guys
take a fat dad and give your mom a hug
for me here it goes the song from our
friends with the tur pecks crew
we're crowing from our hearts
[Music]
we're gonna start that one from the top
again
[Music]
crow in from our hearts for growing from
my god I reach F with that big book dick
taken dab fideos like a DAB chick
[Music]
we've got crimey catsby what the [ __ ] is
he saying
[Music]
I don't know that's why we're on the
podcast show and not the radio
[Music]
hey then we got the tur pecs crew we are
crazy singing these songs for you with
me the best
[Music]
our from here and I'm kind of scared to
go there
[Music]
I'm gonna switch it up
got a cloth on your heart yeah
who shout out the choir school
[Music]
I don't know about you guys but I've
been walking around singing no belt no
braska for like a week now it's uh yeah
the only downfall is they used a lot of
inside jokes you know like and they
tried to explain him to the best of the
ability but it's it's more one of those
things you had to bend I was just
laughing every time they would say
something like ham wallet it got pushed
off like it wasn't anything I was
letting [ __ ] just slide by because the
more I was like ah [ __ ] the more it came
out it was fun to do but it was fun just
letting some [ __ ] slide too and you you
would hear one of them like every
everyone throughout the podcast like you
edit this right like just a little bit
[Music]
and I just cut out an hour and 20 right
out of the middle they started playing
no I'm gonna record from here you guys
are getting recorded they didn't know I
had been recording for like a full hour
kind of like you guys don't realize I've
been recording for at least a minute do
a podcast ready let's do this I'm gonna
drop in the intro song
[Music]
yeah welcome back out of his community
it's time for episode number 60 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you under house Rasta Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always I have to
send a huge big thank-you shout out to
the mystic roots band thanks to say
thanks for letting me use their music on
the show big huge thanks to Kat coot and
the entire mystic roots DTF Oh dab the
[ __ ] out today and a bit on some tour
packs shatter I also got some black
cherry Kim shatter from the garden of
Weeden it's been a good day when what
day is it that you're not the [ __ ] out
[Music]
early morning until I at least get a few
things done yeah I mean I've come over
here a couple times and it's like seven
ten you know first one of the day yeah
if I dab during work what I'm trying to
get a lot of [ __ ] done I just get out of
focus myself Yeah right just try to wait
and reward yourself a little
it's like grateful dog right after
breakfast like it's gonna be a real yeah
my buddy Mitch did also shout out Mitch
he said that when you're dab in every
hour becomes 45 minutes of productive
time so didn't I kind of believe him I
would have agree I would argue with that
between sativa and indica you know I'm
saying you're a brilliant eva guy and
usually if I come over hang your reel
ripped off the TV dabs I don't go home
and like no I'm like what can we clean
where where do we need to get that way
but I end up doing some useless [ __ ] all
the dishes are perfectly clean in the
kitchen but it was useless I should have
been
without happened we're gonna talk about
some Jamaican stuff I'm gonna mention
something about ladybugs that'll listen
or emailed me about and if we have time
I might talk about my beau Kashi bucket
I'm not sure how far we're gonna get
with all the news articles that I found
one thing I do want to mention it's our
birthday know how you were gonna do it
this will be out like March 29th I think
and I think today the 28th is the day
that the first episode was ever released
some commercials I'll give you guys the
option I've got some SF vog I've got
Gorilla Glue and I've got lemonade which
one should we dab here you already know
that I'm gonna pitch towards the sfv
because it is a it is a dank straying
from topics and we give my baby this is
the San Fernando Valley made popular I
don't even know it's really popular from
the Cali connection is who put out the
seeds but
but they put out the seeds of the sfv
and it's a great breeding strain it
tastes good
it's a super nice high turf X blasted
extracted this and everything turf x
does is quality they change their labels
I like their new logo shout out also
check out their new website and they do
a hell of a job dude I have been driving
around in my car and just randomly like
I've got Tourette's like my wife has no
idea my wife she's definitely hurt it
like every every time I'm sitting in
there hitting the bowl it's it just it
comes out whether there's no melt or not
so yeah I've got maybe another day
before I get the downloaded to phone
don't you see you have a forever forever
number on your phone the podcast that I
have delicious it may be coughing little
that's my fault is a big dab it tastes
really it's earthy cushy maybe a hint of
coffee yeah it's got a good nice earthy
cushy flavor I definitely approve I like
it it's not a sativa that's for sure it
made my eyes go whoa gonna make me get a
little slow I approve
I approve I'm gonna have to smoke a
sativa here in a minute so I'm glad he's
interested in this eliminating my new
favorites turf x-ray at least this run
this time
I smoked between the flavors I got the
chem dog and the one I got was it's gone
it was my favorite it was delicious
[Music]
I mean I used to smoke just flowers what
happened appropriately-sized ab yeah
Mike's got to take dabs four hands over
there
we've been rambling for a minute I do
need to do two commercials to locations
to serve Colorado visit the Denver store
62 71 Beach Street or check out the
Pueblo location 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out high
growth for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
check this out guys when you go to high
girl indoor growing supplies when you're
checking out tell them I listen to the
girl from your heart podcast they're
gonna give you commercial pricing on
everything you purchase you're gonna pay
the same amount that I pay you're gonna
pay with Adam pays you're gonna pay what
Mike pays you're gonna pay what Jesse
pays and Jesse works there better
discount than Jesse gets and he's the
manager at the joint and I'm gonna be
honest like you don't need a discount
we are the best price bang in town you
said well I'm just I think we all kind
of are part of hydro because we all love
burn and burns he's my brother man
Jesse's our brother but burns a young
lady who weighs like a hundred pounds
and they get a truck dropped off and
they just throw the truck out there's
all your [ __ ] burn and so we all love
her and we've all grab a pile of soil or
whatever we can move for so yeah we're
all part of team hydro I can call us
that the next girl meeting April 26th at
hydro indoor growing supplies I think
the meeting will start at 6 o'clock I
will have something prepared I will
speak about something I don't know what
it'll be yet Jesse and I will
collaborate and talk about what needs to
be discussed if you've got an idea and
you're coming to the meeting let me know
what you'd like me to talk about the
girl meeting April 26th at Highgrove
indoor growing supplies I'll talk about
that more in the future keep reminding
you guys I felt like the last meeting
like a lot of stuff was talked about
pretense but then when it came down to
who's got any questions everybody was
maybe a little embarrassed to speak up
in front of the crowd and it wasn't it's
because you're in a community of growers
and I don't really think that should be
the place to be embarrassed that's the
place to get help but nobody wanted to
show that they were yellow belts when
there were fifth degree black belts in
the room absolutely it would have been
rough to be the first that we write down
questions
[Music]
all right one more commercial the
organic portions of this episode are
sponsored by my great friends at the
rocky mountain worm company what's up J
I hope you're listening
here's your advertisement bro visit the
rocky mountain warmth company and
Colorado Springs for fresh worm castings
African nightcrawlers red wigglers and
all of your organic soil amendments the
Rocky Mountain worm company has
dragonfly earth medicine products in
stock now Rocky Mountain one company
will ship to your door you can get the
same worm castings well it's again that
I use that Jesse uses that Adam uses
that Sean uses that half of Pueblo uses
right now the most of Colorado Springs
is using right to your door check out
Rocky Mountain worm company com you can
get all the same [ __ ] I'm using the
prices are amazing the products are
great if you visit the store it 411
Tijuana Street and Colorado Springs make
sure you tell them you heard about them
through the podcast those guys are
friendly they're just business people
they are community members of the grow
community and the hype on that stuff is
real life is real bro it is mics here
Mike has the privilege of taking my old
soil out of the pot and putting it into
the recycling bin for soil this is
serious privilege [ __ ] you're teh
mover yeah I get to play with dirt all
day did you see in the past 20 pots that
we have harvested have you seen a
massive increase in my root mass yeah
the amount of root material in these
pauses insane lately people I've been
I've been breaking up dirt pots but I
think about it but everybody's been
breaking over old pot and had like a
handful of little tiny sad-ass root
there and lately you've got to smash the
root ball against the wall for a little
bit just to get a some dirt back
spins hands and they're not in there any
longer you're gonna say we just let them
grow more time now they're actually in
there shorter because I ran this crop
really quickly I wanted to get some kind
of drop down they're not getting root
bound there's just an insane amount of
incredibly healthy root material and see
that's kind of what I was pointing at is
like if you're using that would it be
better to kind of transplant more you
know more often or just because a larger
pot would have been helpful but it
wasn't necessary it wasn't to that point
a larger pot from the get-go I wouldn't
necessarily say transplanting more
frequently would be a good thing there's
a lot of stress yeah but you know we've
gotten it down not to brag on ourselves
you can transplant some [ __ ] where
there's like zero stress where the
plants are even happier they're like oh
you guys get comfortable I like to go
myself I go from the cloner into a cup
actually I've been introduced to a new
product that I really like it's just
called a clone cup you can order them I
check them out on Instagram I don't know
where to order them they were kicked
down to me as a gift for a trial a trial
and I really like them they're harder
than a normal cup they're a little
bigger than a normal cup they're raised
a little and they've got holes so the
company I really like and then I let it
kind kind of close to rootbound
in that cup but not I just want to see
the thick roots on the outside if I
picked up the dirt I wanna see roots but
I don't let the plants start to stretch
in there and then I go to a three gallon
and then sometimes if I'm doing like a
breeding fino hunt I'll run them in
three all flower them out in the three
gallon well they're real sure if I'm
going bigger I'll throw them into a
seven gallon and flower mount in a seven
and I went the same amount of time I
just added grow Kashi worm castings the
Dragonfly earth medicine root dust the
black one I can't think of the name of
the battle's not over here
just simple stuff like that and I did a
little bit of fish hydrous late and I've
started to cut out though GT I'm not
using Oh GT now okay dude my roots were
huge yeah SuperDuper huge I could have
used a bigger pot but I don't think it
was necessary I think I did the right
amount it's and they weren't root bound
but the roots were spaghetti like I just
know that since we've started using them
having them in cups is almost like you
know it's you're literally it you have
to be on your stuff cause if you leave
them there's cops way that's I mean
regular plants do but with the worm
casting it is a little bit I know I said
I had a bunch of news but since we're
talking about all this organic stuff
another thing that I've noticed that has
really contributed to the improvement in
my plants I use it in my bedroom I use
it in my flowering room everything but
the clones gets it the clones get it now
as soon as they go into the dirt I feed
at this Shawn gave me something called a
bow Kashi bucket the [ __ ] bucket is
basically a five gallon bucket with a
piece of piece of plastic as a catch or
a shelf in there then that shelf has
holes in it and then underneath that
shelf is a spigot and the idea is that
you throw we'll talk about more in a
minute with more detail but you throw
your chute in there and it starts to get
funky and then you can turn the spigot
and get the chute out is why that little
shelf is in there you get juice out of
it juice juice nasty it's like a
miniature compost pile juice okay so the
best way and set up like a Gatorade
great way because I was going way way a
different way so you take the Boshy
bucket it's got a little shelf that you
put down some of them have it pre
affixed there's different models of the
bucket that you get so there's a little
shelf in there with holes in it I put
down a thin layer of newspaper just one
sheet of newspaper so that I made more
of a screen and then I put a small layer
of the bow Koshy down it comes with some
powdered stuff called Bokashi I
sprinkled about a handful of that on the
screen and then what you do is you just
put I put I'm a vegetarian and every
banana that I eat has a banana peel
every strawberry that I eat has
the leafy part at the end of it there
are some strawberries that come in the
package that are inedible
every time you I eat an onion the way I
clean my onion is I chop each end off of
the onion and then I can get that onion
skin right off of it and so I've got an
end of each one or each end of it and
the onion skin and then I clean it that
ends and the skin go into my little Bowl
and then once I've got this bowl filled
I throw all my banana peels my eggshells
my onion ends my carrots they got funky
the celery that I found coffee grounds
are you have to dry them set them out
and let them dry first if you're gonna
do that but I do my yerba matee that
I've cooked or that I've used and my
coffee grounds gonna send them on a
paper towel and let them dry for like 48
hours you don't want to put too much
moisture in there I could explain why
but it's too much - what else you can
put meat and dairy in there you can put
your meat and dairy products and bread
in there I choose not to put I don't eat
any meat or dairy and I only put a
little bit of be weird if your steaks go
or if your plants got pork chops and
steak and you didn't write that comes
here and I just put the vegetables and
the fruits and [ __ ] in there and
although like some grapes and so there's
apple cores and potato peels so you put
they say to put a two inch layer of food
waste in there and then sprinkle a
handful of the Bokashi and then another
two-inch layer and sprinkle a handful of
Bokashi I try not to open it very often
I throw all of my scraps into a bowl and
once the ball has starts to sneak up the
kitchen then I put that in the Bocage
bucket right Mike you've been here when
I open the bucket I don't recommend
going full work and keeping it in your
kitchen like some people it is right you
can smell the magic we're fermenting
banana peels apple cores grapes there
are eggshells in there so you keep
putting your keep packing your fruit
vegetables in there or your food waste
you can put your bacon and eggs in there
if you want to all your food waste can
go in there
then you pack it down with this little
packer and keep sprinkling in the coffee
and then you seal it right and then
after about it took me about 10 days
about ten days you unscrew the spigot
that's on there and I put a mason jar
underneath it and this juice comes out
and it starts off clear and kind of pink
or orange ish and it smells like oh it
is like the bar trash can they got
thrown up in and left in the Sun I feel
like it should be a game in the podcast
you should just have the jar sitting
here and people what is this I throw
that into a clean water with a bubbler
and it bubbles up real good and it makes
the stinkiest feed that to my plant and
I can see them dance around we have a
ladder or bucket yeah quick hole and
just slide the tube through just that's
the end of that story
it's more details I'll fill it up it's
almost to the top now I feel like I've
got one more good dump of my bowl of
banana peels ate a lot of bananas you
guys have a banana addiction I think
they're really good for me and they give
me a lot of energy and they're healthy
and they're organic bananas bananas but
I've got one more dump into there and
then once I dump that bowl into there
I'm out of coffee so I won't even be
able to put my coffee in there I'll seal
it and let it seal for about 14 days and
everything that's in there is
essentially pickling that's like
fermenting and pickling in there and
I'll pull out juice out of there I'll
get a lot of that I call it coffee juice
I'll probably get five six maybe eight
to ten depending on how I don't know how
soggy the top layer is gonna get I'll
get eight to ten jars hopefully of that
Kashi juice out of there and then I will
take two large kiddie pools of soil and
I will put half of that Kashi bucket on
the bottom of one kiddie pool and half
of the Kashi bucket on another kiddie
pool and cover that up with store bag
soil and mix that [ __ ] in and then in
like 14 to 21 days we'll have some day
composted soil I just watch Mike eyes
like immediately go pointed in words
like wait a minute one worm castings -
they're just yet but in the future there
will be castings added to that same soil
yes indeed yes and that soil will get
that'll just be the base like we need a
little bit of that soil per the regular
soil mixing bin we'll just cut it down
yeah and it'll make some dank soil
there'd be a lot of microbes in there
yeah between the grow koshy what else
are we use in fish hydro slates and the
dragonfly earth medicine you should see
the roots on my plants and the veg
growth happening in my plants there are
other things that we still have to
supplement and stuff but my roots are
amazing I'm super impressed and I'm
making my own [ __ ] I can make with a
handful of worm castings with one jar of
that Kashi tea with 15 scoops of grow
Kashi which sounds like a lot it's 10
scoops of grow Kashi there's never
enough really can't hurt yourself I mean
you can but and if you want to use
molasses it's like just like five ounces
if you don't want to use molasses you
don't need it but you could make I mean
25 gallons of nutrients with just that
right there and it was amazing it was
totally amazing green plants all my
veggies all my clothes that got put into
new pots they all got fed that and they
look completely happy they love life
everything is pretty much been switched
over to organic so it's to recycle all
of your garden stuff that's a good way
or all your garden stuff all your waste
all your food waste what the heck
happened my papers they all landed the
wrong order they're backwards it's weird
I'm confused just take your food scraps
and throw it in there and you can make
your own nutrients guys we can save the
world
one drink at a time one food at time one
yeah
paper towels and Kleenex and stuff in
there too because the Fitz paper it will
biodegrade in there I know you looked at
me like that's disgusting yeah it's
gross but it's not it's not looking for
the grow kashi website I couldn't find
there's there's another guy that does it
in 55-gallon drums and he's arms
sit there picture in a row of 55-gallon
drums and the big bowl into five-gallon
buckets and missing a portion of each
one yeah all of his feet you don't smell
it at that point
what's that town to the east of here
you know what the town I'm talking about
we're just cows like crammed into fences
they sell them there something I don't
know is horrible you could taste cow
yummy that's gonna have really smells so
I received an email let me where the
heck here is my phone I have to find
this email this is the ladybug email I
want to talk about I learned a little
bit about emails I'm searching for this
message bro I got hit in the head so
hard that I don't remember half of my
evening and I'm not even joking
ah we're at a friend's house who did you
deserve it myself there are two stairs
that dip down into this other part of
these people's house and right above the
stairs there's a like a there's a beam a
head thing like a [ __ ] what is like a
face Smasher head Smasher yeah dude
there's like a decorative awning thing
there I don't I don't remember hitting
it I did not feel it all I remember is
getting up off the ground and Shawn
looking at me going to Dar you okay
[Music]
I'm [ __ ] up he asked me not to see his
name there's parts of this email that I
won't read some of it was just for me
but he opens thanks for the awesome pod
style and mystic roots were a perfect
fit for bed music you're welcome to read
this on the pod but please don't mention
my real name just use vape dad on reddit
very active in our slash trees then he
talked about his soil where he is and
then he says I was reading a book called
cannabis cultivation the other day at
Barnes &amp; Noble and they recommended
putting ladybugs in our greenhouse to
fight Athens and caterpillars and a
whole assortment of pests so in
researching organic growing for no other
reason than I like the all-natural
aspect of it thinking thinking like this
I was wondering would it be a good idea
to raise loose ladybugs in your grow
room
what could they hurt in the stages of
growth if anything or could these be
nature's pest control for those aspiring
to care games this may be a dumb
question but I just wanted to ask a live
person with some real quantifiable
growing experience and thanks for the
pot and keep it up it's a really
beautiful thing you're doing by the way
I hope you get invited to the Joe Rogan
experience pod one day but I know your
plants would miss you thanks for all the
great free grow info
much love vape dad they seems real name
that email at all I don't know okay I
just wanted to make sure that I did not
I'm pretty high but I don't think you
did I don't think so so many cool things
dude you're welcome for all the free
grow info I am proud and happy to do
that my goal is to quit growing all the
mids and all I have to do is talking to
a microphone so I'm really excited to do
that you're very welcome Joe Rogan
experience podcast dude if I got there I
don't know what I would do I'd be super
stoked to do it I'd love to be on that
show with Ari and Joey Diaz so let's get
to the point here and dude you said this
may be a dumb question no dumb questions
bro never no dumb questions at all
somewhere I had training wheels at one
point and now I'm doing wheelies and you
just gotta start somewhere there are no
dumb questions my theory on ladybugs and
Michael probably back me up on this a
long time ago I did what I thought was
cute and I went to the hydro store and I
bought a thousand ladybugs yeah and let
them fly about the grow room they were
cute I got the camera took pictures of
ladybugs [ __ ] on my plants and it was
really cool yep did they sell 300 the
t-shirt from Amazon a flying all your
fans they fly up into your lights so
here's something that Sean taught me uh
credit to Sean king Cola he taught me
this and I'm gonna butcher it because I
had a head injury
ladybugs don't see in the same spectrum
as humans ladybugs see a UV spectrum
that it's only provided by the light so
when we take a ladybug and we put it in
a grow room all it sees is a grow light
and it all it doesn't see it it's
confused now and it wants to get toward
the white that it can't see and that's
why I'm the warmth and so it flies into
your hoods it flies into your fans and
you get to sweep them all up and they
smell terrible yeah they didn't do much
there are predatory mites that are worth
it
their work indoors but I don't think
that ladybugs praying mantis or cool
indoors they don't run away and ladybugs
are also micro Tori creatures they want
to take off they don't want to be there
they want to go in and they want to fly
away and they want to eat and they want
to fly away yeah so in my honest opinion
I would say no on the ladybugs in an
indoor situation if you have a
greenhouse or an outdoor situation and
you're ready to keep you're gonna have
to keep adding to them and you're also
gonna have to feed them they do require
food even if there are a feeds and [ __ ]
they're like you don't want to eat
hummus and falafel all day you need to
change so you're gonna provide them some
kind of food so keep that in mind if
you're gonna use them in an outdoor or
greenhouse situation but indoors I would
not do the ladybugs and then that food
could also bring other pests that's very
likely very likely at this point I tell
people to release them around their
their Gro not in their grow room at this
point so leave sprinkle them in the
front and backyard don't bother with
them otherwise just as like an extra
preventative measure and the thing about
the Mantis is I've been in a few pet
stores here in Colorado like you guys
carry mantas and I'm expecting to like
see a whole you know fish tank full of
mantises and like y'all take 30 of them
it's it's yeah yeah there's a website go
there are be co-organized they've got
all kinds of great [ __ ] they'll send you
bugs they'll send you nematodes some of
it is seasonal so you might not be able
to get everything but organic pest
control at its finest they don't pay me
to say that I just like sharing useful
[ __ ] with people we've been doing 32
minutes I'd like to go about 45 maybe an
hour at the most and I also want to read
some news articles so you guys want to
get into the news I do think so I kind
of agree with you I'm gonna take a drink
here we're gonna dab some lemonade from
her pecs I think was it John John that
recommended this to us somebody talk for
a second when I was down there he didn't
he had not had a sample of the review
yet so he couldn't really give me an
honest opinion but the name was enticing
but names can be misleading sometimes
yes we all know about the name game so
it was interesting hearing about where
the handkerchief came from and I'm a
gamer Mike's a gamer that was a pretty
[ __ ] funny story because I didn't get
it I'm not really a big Uncharted fan
but that was [ __ ] hilarious like on
the podcast I'm gonna go back I want to
go to the trippy mansion the trippy boy
trap house shoot kind of on a semi
frequent basis and do a podcast up there
so John John you need to be there again
at the next episode we'll give you your
own mic
and one mic that was being passed around
because there were a lot of people there
[Music]
I love that episode you do a lot of cool
[ __ ] but most of the time I mean I give
a [ __ ] if I wanted to go with that why
wasn't I there yeah yeah no I haven't
taken anybody to that little spot away
friends
[Music]
all right I'm gonna take my first dab of
this lemonade from turf bags big shout
out to turf X well I should taste it huh
cuz what if it's terrible I watched a
couple of their the the guys that were
on the podcast the old war videos that
they did on YouTube and stuff they used
to be on it all the time and I guess
they got busy I mean you can obviously
tell it's picked up yeah yeah oh these
black sure packs containers yeah the
popular yeah when you pull out one of
these people know what you got
um tasty definitely tasty women candy
with uh it's another flavor that I can't
yet describe it'll hit me in a minute
but it's definitely a sativa hi cuz my
head is going and I made my eyes wobbly
which is something that only a couple of
other strains have ever done wobbly eyed
sativa hit alright here we go oh that
was weird
still sounds weird is that one of us
[Music]
sorry guys that's what happens when the
Hino core touches the microphone or the
headphone jack robots for a minute there
I'll fix it in post I put half of the
tomorrow's it definitely has the high
limit terpene there yeah some candy so
the name is worthy candy yeah the name
is worthy that's definitely some
lemonade
I'm just gonna go back for a little mini
flavor yeah that was pretty smooth you
just worked the email cord the mic cable
the tobacco tobacco let's just do a
couple for maybe Wednesday or something
this one caught my attention actually
want to give a big shout out to one of
my Facebook friends Mike Holly we used
to call him by Cal it could be Michael
Holly but he's from Boston he's a
Masshole he's a cool-ass dude to tell
you the truth he knows what's up with
cannabis he's educated he's smart he can
separate the [ __ ] from the truth
you should be more known in our cannabis
community and I want to give him a
shout-out right now he probably doesn't
listen to this show in any way but you'd
shut out to Mike by Kaui you do a good
job where I appreciate all your Facebook
posts I see how much you try to help and
participate with our community and I
[ __ ] appreciate it that's what I
found out about this story but it says
pot pesticide contamination in Denver
grows the article is by William breeds
and it says I'm gonna choke her in a
second cuz I took a huge dab but just
bear with me 6 marijuana grows in Denver
were ordered to quarantine and possibly
destroy plant harvest after Denver Fire
Department officials determined that the
girl facilities weren't using chemicals
properly
[Music]
mike has moved away from the microphone
alright they're not using chemicals
properly bugs and pass for a fact of
life for commercial growers but dealing
with them appropriately is important
because eventually humans will consume
in the pot earlier this month the city
of Denver released a bulletin warning
crows our warning grows about the
improper use of pesticides because the
fire department's recent discovery the
city has ordered all licensed pot
growers in the city to send in pesticide
reports by April first pesticides and
agricultural chemicals must be used in
accordance with the product label and
with all applicable federal state and
local laws and regulations improper use
of pesticides on marijuana can raise
serious public health concerns the
bulletin reads the catch is that the
federal agency in charge of regulating
pesticide use the Environmental
Protection Agency doesn't have
acceptable levels for use on cannabis
since cannabis is illegal on a federal
level the Colorado Department of
Agriculture lacks official guidelines to
beyond suggesting that growers not use
any pesticides that haven't been
specifically tested labeled and assigned
to set tolerance for pot growing now
anybody that's listen to this podcast
for more than three or four episodes
already knows what my solution to part
of this problem is the environmental
protection agency does not have
acceptable levels for use of cannabis
since cannabis is illegal on a federal
level let's think about this solution
anybody legalize cannabis yes see that's
your first step that will make this a
little bit easier if with legalization
comes product safety people all right
does have an unofficial list of
pesticides that can be used on
unspecified crops that are intended for
human consumption however Oh consumption
however I kind of read that weird my
fault and the state marijuana
Enforcement Division has a strict list
of allowed pesticides as well as
instructions for how grow owners have to
store and dispose of them state law also
requires that shops write up standard
operating operating procedures for all
pesticide applications in Denver
dispensaries will now be required to
submit a list of every pesticide used
and how much of it
is used copies of those records must be
kept in the facility where the marijuana
has grown
additionally grows must send lists of
pesticides and information on their
safety to the Denver Fire Department and
a sign must be placed on the door of
every grill room listing any and all
pesticides used those businesses that
don't comply could face fines could face
fines and closures and let me tell you I
work with the dispensary and I'm there
on a daily base my daily basis the past
couple of weeks dude they are not joking
when they say they're gonna find you or
close you they will come in that day
they will find a violation that day they
will write a ten thousand dollar fine
and they will close your shop down right
on the spot everybody that's here leave
you're closed I've seen it happen
I represent but I've seen it happen to
another place people don't get the
amount of regulation and oversight that
this industry bmed is massive here
people it's been a long time since
anyone said it but you'll hear people
people who don't have an ID that want to
get in can you just let me in just once
it's like dude this is a billion-dollar
operation it's [ __ ] more money than
you could even imagine we're gonna risk
all of our business for one dude to
sneak through without his ID I saw the
price list for just some of the Grove
equipment that I ordered the other day
[Music]
it says that the Denver Department of
Public Health and Environment will be
inspecting cultivation sites as well as
infused product manufacturing sites so
what was happening guys you heard the
article there were some shops in Denver
some grows in Denver that were using
chemicals that should not have been
being used on the cannabis that they
were selling to the public and it's my
bad that the shops that were busting out
those $75 and $99 ounces probably those
guys
there's a picture of this article makes
it the best there is a picture of a guy
and like a Breaking Bad suit with the
full-on gas mask pouring a bottle of
monsanto chemicals into another
container and it's completely breaking
this article it looks like glue it looks
like he's pouring glue well Eagle 20
looks like that if you've ever seen
Eagle 20 we talked about it friends and
I equal 20 was probably one of the
products being used in all of this
[ __ ] if I read it right the shops
that have that crops quarantined right
now turn themselves in essentially like
they handed in their form that was doing
it for one oh wow Edwyn that they
started looking out of they were like
hey wait that's on the whatever list
this is the only article I've seen about
it there was another big change with
hash the other day where they're like we
schedule it
[Music]
I might skip this one and we might give
you guys a Wednesday more Lube no no if
you guys he's referring to the Floria
episode you guys this is not a weird
bromance going on here all right so
scroll down to the cannabis and this
article is by David McFadden of The
Associated Press there was a picture of
Bunny Wailer lighting up a big ol bowl
in front of a picture of King Haile
Selassie I and then to the right of him
as king Haile Selassie I and the Queen
sitting right next to him great shot
so I'll get into I'll get to the point
historic new ganja laws in Jamaica for
Rastafari religious use comma MMJ
program so Kingston Jamaica marijuana
has been pervasive but illegal in
Jamaica for decades consumed as a
medicinal herb tuft as a sacrament by
Rastafarians and sung about in the
islands famed reggae music after many
years of dialogue about the culturally
entrenched drug and embody emboldened
what and emboldened by changes to drug
laws in US states
Jamaica's Parliament on Tuesday Tuesday
night gave final approval to enact
decriminalizing small amounts of pot and
establishing a licensing agency to
regulate a lawful medical marijuana
industry yes we got marijuana in Jamaica
welcome to the club the historic
commitments paved the way for a cannabis
licensing authority to be established to
deal with regulating and cultivating and
distributing and distribution of
marijuana for medical and scientific
purposes both houses of Jamaica's
legislature have approved this
legislation what's so funny bro
[Music]
religious freedom adherence to the
homegrown Rastafari spiritual movement
can now freely use marijuana for
sacramental purposes for the first time
on the tropical land yes I Rastafari
possession of up to two ounces of
marijuana a petty offense that could
result in a ticket but not a criminal
record cultivation of the HealthSouth
illegal white Mike the truth it's not
gonna be anything fun you sleep on the
cement floor with the rats and you don't
get no food petty offense so you don't
go to jail that's way better five or
fewer plants on any premises would be
permitted five ganja plants now a
tourists who are prescribed medical
marijuana abroad will soon be able to
apply for permits authorizing them to
legally buy small amounts of Jamaican
wheat or ganja as it is known locally
that's 15 bucks so that you fill your
prescription I don't have to bring it
with me on the boat but yeah I can buy
it why I'm there yep not bring it back
on the boat you know but that's gonna be
a cruise
flava Cruz I don't know if anybody saw
my Instagram and Facebook post about
reggae cruise but in November I think
there's the biggest cruise with like 20
of my favorite reggae artists and
they're going to Jamaica and I gonna be
even more fun now okay on Wednesday
colorado-based united cannabis corp said
it has launched a partnership with
Jamaican agencies to launch a marijuana
research and development facility on the
island that they hope will lead ends and
medical cannabis products peter bunting
the islands national security minister
said the legislation does not mean
Jamaica plans to soften it stands on
transnational drug trafficking or
cultivation of illegal plots Jamaica has
long been considered the Caribbeans
largest supplier of pot to the US and
regional islands passage of this
legislation does not create a
free-for-all in the growing transporting
dealing or exporting of ganja security
forces will continue to rigorously
enforce Jamaican law with our
international treaty obligations bunting
said in Parliament William Brown field
the US assistant secretary for counter
narcotics Affairs damn glad that's not
my job told The Associated Press days
before the vote that Jamaican laws of
course to make his own business and
Jamaica's and Jamaica sovereign decision
but he noted that the trafficking of
marijuana into the US remains against
the law we expect the Jamaica and all
states party to the UN drug conventions
will uphold their obligations including
a firm commitment to combatting and
dismantling criminal organizations
involved in drug drug trafficking he
told AP in an email
once again you guys how do we stop
illegal cannabis trafficking by a small
plane at first we fly people straight
from Colorado to Jamaica for trip over
relaxing laws prohibiting ganja but
previous calls did you criminalize small
amounts of marijuana fizzled out because
officials feared it would bring
sanctions from Washington
Jamaican officials now have high hopes
that the island can become a player in
the nasty medical marijuana industry
health tourism and the development of
innovative pot derived items local
scientists already have a history of
treating marijuana derived products such
as kennesaw which helps relieve pressure
in the highs of glucomannan scientists
in Jamaica I've seen quite a few people
that are moving down that way as well a
lot of popular people coming up they
went there and helped to put this [ __ ]
in place and stuff like that all right
I'm gonna keep reading so uh where were
I Commerce Minister Anthony hi Alton
said the cannabis industry holds great
potential for Jamaica where marijuana
has long been grown illegally on
mountainsides and marshes the move by
Jamaican lawmakers adds to an
international trend of easing
restrictions on marijuana for medical or
personal use more than 20 US states
allow some form of medical marijuana and
last year
in Washington legalized personal use on
Tuesday Alaska Alaska became the third
US state to legalize the recreational
use of marijuana for adults in the
Americas Yero Uruguay last year became
the first nation to treat a legal
marijuana market in Argentina personal
possession of marijuana was
decriminalized under a 2009 Supreme
Court ruling that jail time for small
amounts of drugs violates the country's
constitution that's Chile permits use of
medical marijuana details of Jamaica's
Licensing Authority and its hope for
medical marijuana sector will need to be
refined in upcoming months but for now
Jamaican cannabis Crusaders applauded
the amendments this is a big step in the
right direction there's still a lot of
work to do said Delano cyber right
director of the cannabis commercial and
medical task force so big up to Jamaica
taken steps in the right direction
traveling and tourism is gonna happen
there because we did the ladybug thing
somebody sent me an email about
fermentation and your fermentation
methods I'm going to address that but
I'm wanting to do it when Sean's here
Shawna's the guy to talk to about
fermentations let's see I got to do some
shoutouts I want to give a big shout-out
to vigor lover thanks for the t-shirt
that is [ __ ] sweet hashtag
it's ms Linz happy birthday I don't know
if you listen to the podcast to help you
do it's your birthday happy birthday
girl James Holt dude you sent me a
compliment on Facebook and I told you
thanks for listening you didn't seem to
take me seriously like you seemed like I
was kind of [ __ ] you around but no I
was [ __ ] not condescending at all
when I said that all of that and I hope
you took me seriously because you're one
of the most badass professional guitar
players like your professionally the
demeanor the way you do [ __ ] you're a
professional and for you to compliment
me like that just meant a lot to me so I
wasn't even being a prick about it I was
[ __ ] totally serious dude that blew
my mind that you listened and that you
complimented me also big shout out to
Michael he's moving back to us Carolina
or Ohio to get a real job and handle
business I'm gonna miss you it's cool
having you around here good thanks thank
you listen to the one your absolute dude
you guys thanks for coming I call these
guys like a half hour ago you wanna come
over do podcast we do dropping dimes
what was that that's my ring oh man
you're pulling off your wedding ring
while you're on the show there will be a
growers meeting April 26th at hydro
indoor growing supplies prepare for the
cup cough yeah I can't wait for that
guys I hope to see everybody there
everybody there do you guys have any
shoutouts to give her anything like that
so I'm looking at my paper I think I
covered everything I want to cover
well Jesse Jesse shot it too Jesse hey
Jesse gross for sure thank you no gross
[Music]
there you go that's pretty cool yeah
yeah the comments of gotten better and
better man like I mean I understand that
everybody wants to just be like great
show but reading that from his cubicle
while he's at work that's awesome all
right guys we're gonna wrap up the show
I'll be back I think these boys don't
mind hanging out for another 30 minutes
we might kick out a Wednesday episode
for you I got two more news articles the
recording gears already warmed up the
emails hot we might just keep recording
here but we're gonna wrap up this
episode thanks for listening we'll be
back don't forget to check out the
sponsors the rocky mountain warm company
and hydro indoor growing supplies if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product that
you'd like me to review send me an email
let's go from your heart at hotmail.com
I'll get you all the information you
need if you've got something to say or
not into the social media thing you can
email me it's girlfriend hard at
hotmail.com don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is archived on I
read genetics Colorado com don't forget
about that donation button on the page
it's I read genetics Colorado calm over
the drawer for our podcast tab at the
top there's a donation button that goes
directly to my PayPal account you guys
I'll never charge you money for the
podcast the show will always be free but
if you do feel like making a donation
I would totally appreciate it give you a
thumbs up I'll give you a shout-out on
the show to people made contributions
and I think I said thanks if not all
make sure to do that on the next episode
my phone it's not on the right screen to
find that I don't always time on the
fritz buy a new iPhone today and I spent
probably three hours to find out that
the phone I want is an hour north of
here and I have to drive there to get it
so tomorrow that's our mission you guys
want to go to launch or something let's
do that we're on all the social media
sites just search for me on whatever you
use on Twitter it's @g fyh podcast dude
follow
I read genetics on Instagram do it lots
of dope cannabis pictures I got a new
camera I've been putting up some sweet
photography it definitely went up the
new buds I haven't started working like
full full-time at the spot yet until I
do you can catch me on bong TV randomly
like 3:00 in the morning to the bomb
crew shout out the DS DS is in the
process of copywriting assigns they came
up through I don't want to sing a line
from it right now so badly but I don't
want to ruin it until it's copyrighted
so once that's out we'll play it on the
podcast it'll be [ __ ] awesome it'll
probably be late spring early summer
before the songs done we'll play it on
the show shout out DS I hope you listen
to this one I will post a link to this
on blogtv shout out to the bong TV crew
also a big shout out sway ninja Spence
shout-out to you guys for showing up
chatter you guys for listening until
next time take a fat dad give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
oh it's up cannabis community it's time
for episode number 61 try to prevent
that cuz dude that was crazy man dude
I've heard the noise but neither me nor
Mike harden just use land right across
my input right here just right across my
body guys welcome to the girl from your
podcast
[Music]
a couple of beautiful clerks called
their sales associates beautiful as well
if you're in Denver go to the Denver
location it's 62 71 beach street if
you're in Pueblo check them out it's
6:18 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
no [ __ ] you guys I wouldn't
represent a company on my podcast that I
didn't love with my heart hydro is my
friends they've got a great great store
if you tell them you're listening to the
podcast they'll give you a fatty body
discount they will give you commercial
pricing on your entire order and it's
fabulous any money take some gorilla
glue dads but before I do that I gotta
read this next one also big huge shout
out much love to our friends at the
rocky mountain worm company like I said
before no [ __ ] I only rep companies
that I really love on the show and I use
the rocky mountain one company products
I check them out they've got dragonfly
earth medicine they've got worm castings
they've got sea crop they have got fish
Hydra slates they've got everything you
need if you ask they'll probably give
you a tour of the worm farm you can see
how the worms are made it's pretty cool
it's 411 Tijuana Street and Colorado
Springs Colorado if you don't want to
travel or if you're out of state they
will mail you worm castings they will
mail you
dragonfly earth medicine they will ship
to your front door I think you can get
live worms or worm I forgot what the
call Carlos here pew-pew man the baby
something like that I don't have the
website pulled up and you can use all
the [ __ ] that I'm using Mike dude you
about microphone stands but you cannot
fight with it is your friend that's
keeping that red thing in your face
where we need it be that microphone
stands friend I don't like it moment
with it alright guys go to rock you mat
and warm company calm and they will mail
you cool [ __ ] you have to pay for a
little funky today we're having a good
time we had an equipment if you want to
sponsor the show send me an email Tom
will get you all that information look
at you all squared up if you got a
product you want me to test out we like
testing out new [ __ ] on the show we need
more email we need an officially now of
the show this was a gift a hookup from
my good friend Gideon emo Tex a shout
out to the Gmail I'll be real specific
white Mike needs an email you would
never leave the house you would have no
reason to come over here anymore
[Music]
seriously inverter for my car for the
email if I have a passenger that can
hold on to it so nobody gets burned
it'll be awesome if you put it in the
cup holder it's gonna buddy but hey
anybody got my go-to reference you get a
high-five
dude it's tasty
they don't sponsor the show or anything
but I got some tasty tur pecs gorilla
glue shatter from green and healthy
wellness sponsor my happiness has been
brought to you by the friends of tur
pecs and green and healthy wellness that
was well put sir shout out to hunt in
his womb broom hey get that meat wallet
tight man you guys are pulling out all
the stops all we have to do is get
through three news articles and then we
can have fun I read commercials and such
yeah so let's get down to it let's I
gotta click doing the clickety clicks
sorry for the coffin the Mike definitely
has that glue taste yeah that gorilla
glue dabs tastes delicious hey Mike when
you set that down make sure you uh put
that right on my cable here
[Music]
my body told me get up walk away let's
just take off your headphones and walk
away from that that's how I feel when
you're over there like heating it up and
scraping the email you know when I come
over and it's like y'all he loves this
[ __ ] what this is this is Adams favorite
it says one surprising downside of
marijuana legalization major energy use
and then there's a picture we got three
to five growth facility here with the
ballast up on the ceiling just to kind
of show you a nice little visual of
electricity being ran better give some
credit here who Chris Mooney from The
Washington Post wrote this he says
across the country there's a growing
trend toward the legalization of
marijuana four states Oregon Washington
Colorado Alaska have voted to allow
people to possess limited amounts of
marijuana for personal use and also to
let producers apply for licenses to
produce and sell it
DC also just voted to allow voted to
allow personal possession all of this on
top of the 23 states that allow it for
medical reasons in some states we just
read two different articles that gave me
different numbers on that didn't we one
said 21 said 23 maybe they were taken at
different times maybe they're dabbing
also dabs the the way this gets counted
up is confusing because there's Senza
that second Sanjay Gupta special there's
been a whole bunch of CBD only states
across the South the pseudo medical how
you count that if you count that was
making the big fuss in New Jersey was
just in the news today one go back at it
like that should be the governor of
Florida too so I mean like I've Thor's
brother order in the court
are also now illegally cultivating and
producing marijuana a mainstream
industry is emerging yeah it's a little
heavy on the indica side so for daytime
million dollars in Colorado last year
for instance but there's a surprising
catch it turns out that indoor marijuana
growth in particular a cultivation
method often favored in the industry for
many reasons usings uses a surprising
amount of energy
indeed the level of power use appears to
be so significant that one scholar is
now suggesting that as the industry
grows states and localities should take
advantage of marijuana licensing
procedures to also regulate the
industry's use energy use and greenhouse
gas emissions damn hippie this new
industry this is a new industry that is
going to be pretty highly regulated I
felt like the state and local policy
makers have a unique opportunity to
incorporate energy usage and climate
assessments into their state marijuana
licensing fees says Geena Warren a
professor at the Texas A&amp;M University
School of Law whose paper titled
regulating pot to save the polar bear
energy and climate impacts of the
marijuana industry will soon appear in
the Columbia Journal of environmental
laws
[Music]
like an obstacle of a there's a comma
and then another comma and then a period
yeah that's good props the published
statistics on energy use from indoor
marijuana production will blow your mind
whether or not you use the stuff of
carbon footprint of indoor cannabis
production published in the journal
energy policy researcher Evan Mills
noted that on occasion previous
unrecognized spheres of energy used to
come to light and marijuana is a
textbook example the study estimated
that for cannabis both legal and illegal
uses six billion dollars worth of
electricity every year amounting to one
percent of overall u.s. electricity and
in some production intensive states like
California it was much higher three
percent Mills found further but I'm
going to assume that Colorado is going
to hit like that would be there is less
people here so one average kilogram of a
final product is associated with four
thousand six hundred kilograms of carbon
dioxide emissions to the atmosphere or
that of three million average u.s. cars
when aggregated across all national
production roll mills the reason is
simply the technique the technology
required specific energy uses include
high intensity lighting dehumidification
remove to remove water vapor and avoid
mold formation space heating or cooling
during non illuminated periods and
drying preheating of irrigation water
generation of carbon dioxide by burning
fossil fuel and ventilation and air
conditioning to remove waste heat right
that's a well-researched they did our
math and they haven't figured out how
much carbon dioxide the plant sent back
out there
well no but there's another side of that
coin depends on the plant I agree with
this article Foley I'm just saying
there's like there's there's a little
bit of subtraction that needs to be done
before we freak out a little true that
she keeps on going and she says oh
production also has environmental
consequences it has been charged with
deforestation and high levels of water
and pesticide use
but as pop becomes more legal and
mainstream notes Warren outdoor
producers will have to abide by
pre-existing in their environmental laws
just like everyone else in effect that
means indoor production the chief
climate change that makes indoor
production the chief climate change and
energy concern according to Warren's
article while underground indoor
marijuana production already consumed
the plenty of energy legalization will
increase energy use even further as the
industry grows so will its negative
externality she writes which is why
she's proposing that all states that
legalize marijuana use should also
require the growing industry to power
itself cleanly and it's not without
precedent starting in October of this
year Boulder County and Colorado will
require many facilities to directly
offset 100 percent of electricity
propane and natural gas consumption do
renewables or other means that's a fun
challenge yeah Warren says she's not
picking on the marijuana industry with
her proposals it's just that well we
don't often have new industries appear
that use a lot of energy and are likely
to be highly regulated as they become
legal I think it could actually be a
marketing tool for the industry says
Warren because if you have people who
are purchasing the product who are the
type of individual who cares about the
environment then they would gravitate
toward the green marijuana production
what you saying makes sense because we
are sucking up a lot of power and I've
thought about it I don't know how to do
it maybe somebody can send me an email
or something one thing I want to do I
consider myself a pro grower I could
grow you can give me a plant that's half
dead and in ninety days I'll give you
some tasty ass buds out of it I
overcome those problems in a grow room
now I want some guidance on how to
lessen my carbon footprint
I recycle my soil but still I have to
run lights for 12 hours on and 12 hours
off there's no way around it are there
other things we can do to kind of lessen
our carbon footprint if you guys know
send me ideas you can tweet them to me
it's at G fyh podcast you can email me
to grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
mean you would try to find those
cannabis cultivators we'll start looking
for places like wine yeah you know
places they would right next to rivers
where they can have a water bill talking
about like my pre-existing indoor grow
like people that have a home grow or a
small warehouse like I want to find out
ways that people like us like you you've
got a traphouse grow I want to see a way
that you can kind of make a little less
in your electricity bill just see if you
however much it is maybe cut 10% of that
off absolutely you could definitely do
that with solar you know I'm saying like
you're just cutting out the hundred
dollars that it takes to run your house
would be a hundred dollars less over a
year that would add up you know
tremendously that's 15 - you know quite
a bit $100 you know the local
application this is the city of Pueblo
just required everybody growing doors
you can't grow outside no in any fashion
this year that's kind of silly hopefully
in a year we'll have green house rules
down here but yet they cut it off and
but not until the very end no you're
talking about six persons in my own
backyard and illegal if you're not on
the game the Sun is not there looking
for more illegal pot grows here and cow
more than they were before we have
legalized cannabis to tell you the truth
because now they want to regulate the
[ __ ] out of it before they didn't have
time now it's an issue all right I want
to read which one do we want to do this
one which one the good one well they're
both good brother
[Music]
do you want to read the one written by
they're both written by the same person
sweet we'll do that no Kristin actually
is writing a lot do you want to do the
one about racism it says the
legalization of marijuana in Colorado
hasn't solved the racial disparities in
enforcement the drug policy performers
had hoped to end with blacks still far
more likely than whites to be charged
with pot related crimes a new report
says the report issued Wednesday by the
pro-legalization drug policy Alliance
showed that marijuana arrests in
Colorado all but stopped after voters
made the drug legal in small amounts for
those 21 and older but the report noted
continuing racial disparities involving
the marijuana crimes that remain
including public use in possession in
excess of the ounce limit study the
study examined drug arrests in all 64
Colorado counties for two years before
and after legalization in 2012 the total
number of charges for pot possession
distribution and cultivation plummeted
by almost 95% from about 39,000 in 2010
to just over 2000 last year that's if it
only takes an hour of the cops time
that's 37 cop hours 37,000 37,000 cop
hours we just reallocated to [ __ ] that's
worth something yeah they could be out
solving a crime any crime looking for
your bike that got stolen
yep for something the bad happened I
don't even want to create crimes in my
head I have to say it has been nice like
not worrying about the bag that's in my
pocket yeah only crime most marijuana
consumers like traffic infractions the
only problem is once you pull me over
here you can have my sweater give me
five minutes and then when you come back
it smells like yeah all right so I'm
gonna keep reading because we want to
get through a couple articles even after
legalization blacks were more likely
twice as likely
oh sorry I read that wrong blacks were
more than I've stuttered because
American would be the correct term
[Music]
african-american folks were more than
twice as likely as White's
oddly you tell us blacks were also more
much more likely to be charged with
illegal cultivation of pot or possession
of more than an ounce legalization for
the issues that law enforcement had with
the black and brown communities that
aren't way Colorado director for the
drug policy Alliance still the drop-off
and overall arrest is good news for
minorities said Tony Newman also of the
drug policy Alliance despite the
uprising racial disparities the massive
drops and arrests have been enormous ly
beneficial to people of color Newman
said is this is this my system or I
think we stopped referring to people by
the general the term that I related to
in there
I can't even now just based on a largest
ethnic minority Latinos that's because
data comes from the National incident
based reporting system system which does
not tally numbers for Latinos
one of the region's top officials for
coordinating drug enforcement of the
Rocky Mountain high intensity drug
trafficking area program officers are
not for marijuana distribution charges
blacks accounted for about 22% of such
arrests in 2010 and around 18 percent in
2014 the arrest data got a mixed
response from the regional head of the
n-double a-c-p if the head of the
n-double a-c-p know that you were
calling them blacks when you wrote this
on the overall decrease in arrests
charges and cases ignored is enormous ly
beneficial to communities of color who
bore the brunt of marijuana prohibition
rosemary Harris little said in a
statement however we are concerned with
the rise in a disparity for the charge
of public consumption and Cha and
challenged law enforcement to ensure
this reality is not a discriminatory in
any manner wow that was hard to read I
in 2014 the years the year Colorado's
recreational marijuana stores opened
blacks were three point nine percent of
the population but accounted for nine
point two percent of pop possession
arrests for illegal marijuana
cultivation this disparities didn't just
persist they got much worse in 2010
White's in Colorado were slightly more
likely than blacks to be arrested for
growing pot after legalization the
arrests rate for whites dropped in
traumatically but ticked up for blacks
in 2014 the arrest rate for blacks was
roughly 2.5 times higher there's a lot
more of this article but I'm not gonna
read it it's almost done
but we get the point in the 60s
but yeah this strikes me as a little bit
odd do you Mike tell me do you dislike
all of us in public you wouldn't want to
say she stated in a courtroom you know I
mean or politics I mean let's just be
real though no civil rights I don't even
want to be called the whites over here
the whites and they're not the blacks
[Music]
don't a lot but it's still high for
black my head that's roughly 22,000
people of color that didn't get a rest
or [ __ ] with last year but still the
data so we your opinion on that article
the people that are listening tweet me
email me you know how to do it I said it
earlier written a racist racist to say
it that way Colorado bill seeks to
standardize marijuana testing what I've
noticed is a lot of people in Colorado
don't trust the testing facilities
anymore because we'll take a test to one
lab and it'll come out at 22 percent you
can take another test to another lab
he'll come out of 29 percent and of
course everyone's gonna start going to
the lab that gets higher tests because
you want to be able to brag about
higher results so it's there's no real
standard for the testing lab so we can
all just open our own lab pretty much
and be like AHA the testing labs those
high-dollar people couldn't pay more for
better testing roads so Colorado is
moving to establish another marijuana
first the first government standards for
marijuana testing a bill approved by its
first committee in the state legislature
on Thursday would create a statewide
laboratory standard for the state's 18
pot testing labs currently the labs are
certified by the state health
authorities but they don't have uniform
rules for testing pot potency
homogeneity and contaminants as required
by state law lab owners say they need
the standards because different labs now
produce very different results existing
pot tests generally just looked for
whether the drug whether the drug is
present not how strong it is in most
industries there are long established
long established processes said he and
bérenger owner of a pot testing lab
called rm3 however for cannabis like
most of the industry we're making up the
rules as we go along I'm glad he admits
that the labs can currently be used or
did I click there we go
the labs can currently be used by
licensed marijuana producers the bill
was amended to remove lab access to
private individuals and industrial hemp
growers now covered in separate bills
still pending in the legislature which
kind of bars me from getting my cannabis
tested now the stuff that I used to grow
up my private girl for my patients I was
able to take that to the lab and get it
tested and we could see what was in
there I think we all need access to that
I don't understand why they cut us off
this is the latest step in a dance
that's been going on for ten years
like I remember we didn't have testing
labs because the existing labs that had
the equipment and the know-how are
banned from working with candidates
because they all require FDA a federal
license yeah so we had to build these
from the ground up I didn't know there
were 18 in the state that's pretty cool
it's a separate bill advanced Thursday
in a Senate committee would allow
industrial hemp growers to use the labs
to Colorado currently allows farmers to
grow hemp marijuana's non-intoxicating
cousin but only if the plans fall below
a threshold for the plants intoxicating
ingredient THC it's not an ingredient
however the farmers
can take their plants to a lab to make
sure they're meeting the standard the
testing bill creates what's called a
reference library a standard set of
protocols for testing pot the lab owner
said the state means to essentially
referee all the methodologies that were
using we all understand the need to
reveal the special sauce we've been
using to further the industry behringer
said the bill now heads to a separate
committee before consideration by the
full house full house I just watch that
I agree this needs to happen do we need
to know this is huge it's one of the
beautiful parts of legalization is it's
it's like everything else these guys are
the regulators they need to be regulated
people the testing labs for sure need to
know what they're doing they all me and
using the same equipment playing by the
same rules we're gonna start seeing
reality in our testing but you can spot
[ __ ] on the shelf if you're us I
know your flower doesn't have 40% THC
the claims they have a 30% strain and
I've seen it and it's mid it is not 30%
[Music]
it was like definitely like but now with
these testing labs if we get them all
standardized and regulated then we won't
have to worry like if you're like this
hash was tested super clean and super
high in potency like where'd you get it
done did you get it at the place that
you pay a lot more and they just give
you really high reasonably small if you
gotta test it steep hill I trust you but
I don't know any of the other places
steep hill gave me a tour of their
facility and showed me what's going on
they blew my mind all the other places
you just give them a sample and they
drive away and send you an email later
there
they're they're 100% cannabis - correct
yeah that's right I'm just saying
they're not another laboratory like
science stuff in here more important is
we just required that all edible dose
and be pretty much perfect
yeah you guys remember how that first
regulatory check went through zero and
appear what's going on there are a whole
bunch of companies that couldn't make it
and then we had new rules that require
that only ten milligrams of THC are in
each easily identifiable segment which
meant no more 450 milligrams I pulled
one out of the fridge one of the podcast
almost I want I want this 1,200
milligrams challenge you know just want
to drop down I don't know if you want to
do it the news articles I want to talk
about the growers meeting that is coming
up at hydro indoor growing supplies you
guys want to be at this you guys want to
come hey I made the last when I was
we didn't get a lot talked about that
the community was we was there it
definitely got red-eyed it was a bonding
experience so come on out you guys or
growing supplies on April 26th I think
it starts at six o'clock I'm going to
put together a presentation and I will
talk I'm not sure about what yet I've
got 26 days to figure it out yes some
emails send me all that good stuff we'll
get it figured out I'll do a grow lesson
like 30 or 40 minutes it'll turn into an
hour with questions I like it so if you
guys have any topic you want me to talk
about about on the show or at the
meeting you can send them to me it's a
girl from a heart of hotmail.com
I've said that a lot of times you guys
have any shoutouts you want to do before
we wrap it up boys this week what night
is it really it's actually Friday night
isn't it it's Friday night
three dudes on a Friday night recording
a podcast in my kitchen right now
there's a big party raging behind us but
it's with water I'll be back
probably I'll be back Monday for sure
with a solid episode for you put
together a lot of lot of stuff don't
forget to check out the sponsors rocky
mountain worm company hydro indoor
drawing supplies if you're interested in
sponsoring the show send me an email to
grow from your heart a hotmail.com if
you have something you want to say you
can email me anything just tell me go
calm don't forget that every episode is
available on iTunes and stitcher and I
region etics Colorado com
don't forget about the donation button
it's IRA genetics Colorado calm and then
you click on the girl from your heart
podcasts tab then you click on that
donation button and then it's two clicks
1 million dollars yep and then lots and
then he hit donate
[Music]
we'll go to cause I mentioned before
April 1st or May 1st but we are
collecting money for my daughter to go
on an educational adventure in Hawaii
she's a bright kid she deserves quite a
bit
only like 30 kids in the whole nation
i'm obviously my phone is resetting
having a note on there i was gonna read
at the end of the show constantly four
or five thousand bucks for this trip to
tell you the truth there are other
things that required they're required
like a plane ticket the class itself
yeah you can't drive white yeah that'd
be fun maybe uh if you have ever driven
to hawaii we'll have to find another
worthy cause for that I need some new
microphone covers here these things are
getting a little funky and spitting into
these for a while there are a couple of
adapters making that Terminator sound
I'd be cool anyway all the social media
sites search for me find me follow me be
my friend I love it if you really want
to hook it up go to the I read genetics
colorado website join the web forum and
create an account there i'm on there
semi frequently and try to get on there
like every Monday night and post
pictures of the garden
if you have questions I definitely
communicate with everybody on there I
like it I like it follow I read genetics
on Instagram I post some pretty quality
cannabis photography I like it I gotta
give a big shout-out to these boys for
hanging out this is the second episode
in a row we've recorded tonight I throw
it to blow it out you can hear it right
now some for big dab and a drink thanks
for listening until next time take a big
fat dab of Sumter packs and give your
mom a hug for me all right podcast rule
thanks again for listening to a long
chunk of episodes those were a couple of
my favorite episodes episode with Terp
ex was one of the best episodes I
recorded what are the most fun I can't
say was one of the best it was one of
the most fun episodes I ever recorded
it's fun getting guys with guitars on
the podcast change up the pace a little
bit
anyhow thank you again for listening
make sure you follow me on twitter at g
f YH podcast make sure you check out us
check us out on Facebook words are hard
today sorry I've been smoking this uh
dub wise distillate from pure distillate
I put some dub wise distillate with some
lemon Geoffrey hi terpene full spectrum
extract into the banger and a little bit
in a good way anywho I was saying stuff
follow us on social media Facebook girl
from your heart podcast uh what else do
you do send me an email grow for me a
heart at hotmail.com
let me know what you think of these
shows and I will read your messages on a
future episode that's a lot of [ __ ] to
talk about anyway guys I'm getting out
here thanks again for listening until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me