yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 223 of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shut up my friends in the
mystic roots band will item use their
music on my podcast big shout out to Kat
ku and the entire mystic roots crew
happy 7/10 everybody if you're listening
to this episode on the day it comes out
you are listening on 7 10 which is July
10 2017 if you don't know what 7 10 is
it's a dabber holiday it's a hash smoker
holiday and we'll talk a little more
about it in just a few minutes but
before we get there I want to thank you
guys for something and then I want to
ask you for a little more that's a good
way to do it right say thanks and then
ask for more on the last two episodes
I've been looking for suggestions for a
new strain name i bred Flo to arise and
I've been asking the listeners to send
me straight names I've gotten a lot of
great contributions there have been some
really good ones I'm not gonna read any
of them off because I don't want to read
some and not read some and just feel
like I'm leaving people out but I feel
like I've got a good idea of what that
strain will be called when it's released
I'm not gonna release that here on the
show but I think I have a good idea now
what I want from you and thanks to
everybody who has sent me great name
suggestions now what I'm asking for is
suggestions for white widow crossed to
arise that's right I took a white widow
girl and I crossed it to the arize mail
so any cool name suggestions would be
appreciated you can send those name
suggestions to me I grow from your heart
at hotmail.com or you can tweet them to
me at ji
YH podcast or you can find me on
Facebook under the girl from your heart
podcast or you can follow me on
instagram my instagram is a little
different it's Irie underscore genetics
on Instagram I use my other company name
it's I read genetics that's where all
the seeds are handled through I post a
lot of great pictures of my personal
grows my breeding projects I post
pictures of commercial grows I try to
post a picture of almost every grow I
get to visit this because I like to
share with you guys so check me out on
Instagram it's higher we underscore
genetics and if you've got any
recommendations for the name of white
widow to arise I would love to hear your
recommendation all right what else do I
have going on listen or comments let's
read some listener comments on iTunes
you guys we haven't read the iTunes
comments in a little while it is July
there are a whole bunch of brand new
comments let's get right into it I'm
gonna drop the music right out fade that
out nice and slow let's get into the
iTunes comments this first
iTunes comment comes from it's actually
an iTunes review if you want to leave an
iTunes review all you have to do is go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store type in
the girl from your heart podcast a
little icon with my face and a red
golden Green Rasta flag will pop up
click on that right in the middle it
says ratings and reviews click on there
and then it shows you the spot to click
on some stars to rate it says click to
rate so far everybody 62 people have
given me a 5 star rating
I'll click on as many stars as you feel
I deserve then after that type in a
little review and let me know what you
think of the show and I'll read your
comments on the podcast sometimes it
takes me a few episodes to get to them I
like to let them build up but I do read
them so let's get started reading them
this one comes from a person who calls
themselves do be brought a 7/10 perfect
that I'm reading this on the 7/10
episode they left this comment or this
review on July 5th so it's just left a
couple of days ago and it goes like this
while growing up in Wisconsin we always
had a lot of cheese and not the kind
rasta Jeff teaches us so graciously to
grow he's very he's a very well-spoken
podcaster who has a good voice and
outstanding audio equipment this is an
extremely high quality podcast that not
only sports great information but also a
super friendly vibe my mom digs the hugs
too awesome that's a great comment man
thanks for the
five star review and the good comment
the dude says I'm a very well-spoken
podcaster with a good voice well thank
you that was a gift I guess uh and
outstanding audio equipment yes I have
got some tremendous gear I've got
several different ways to record my main
setup is a spaceship looking device over
here some insight into that I guess I
used to be a drummer I'm still a drummer
but I used to be a traveling drummer and
a recording drummer my job was to play
the damn drums I am using a Macky 1402
VL z3 mixer it was purchased to be my
drum mixer this used to be this was on
stage for several shows the drums would
be plugged into this the mics run mics
to the drums and then plug those into
this you know plug-in drums I know the
mic cords would run to this mixer I
would mix all the sound with this mixer
right here then run it to my in-ear
monitors and then run that out to the
house mix and I would run all the other
instruments into here and run them in my
in-ear monitor so that I could hear them
as I wanted I can control my own monitor
mix I never had to deal with the sound
guy blowing out my ears ah it was much
easier that way but so I've got the
Mackie the Mackie runs to a dbx
compressor and then the dbx compressor
runs to a task cam the u.s. 1200 USB
which runs into the macbook so yes there
are some stuff going on to make it sound
pretty good we've got a pretty nice
preamps in the Mackie and then the
tascam I do
it's got preamps in it that sound pretty
good and then I turn up the gain just a
little bit right there
and then I used the dbx to kind of just
filter out all the noise and make it
sound smooth so thanks for the audio
compliment that's how I do it a lot of
people ask how I make the show sound so
good that's how it's a task cam USB 1200
a dbx compressor
I've also got a livewire power
conditioner in here just because I'm
that's part of my recording setup and my
traveling tour set up and all that [ __ ]
I'm used to seeing it so I put it in
here when I set this up and gives me
another spot honestly I use that plug
for the power conditioner i plug in my
iphone right there a whole bunch so it's
super damn convenient anyway that's how
the show sounds so good then I run it
into GarageBand it's just going into the
old GarageBand GarageBand 6 nice and
easy to edit at the end I don't do
anything to it to make it sound better
at the end it doesn't get ran through
anything I could run it through
levelizer or something like that but I
don't I just let it go
just like it isn't post-its
thanks for the comment on the audio
sound I appreciate the people I notice
how hard I try to make the audio sound
good thank you bro thanks for the
five-star review I said bro I'm gonna
assume that since your name is do be
brought a 7/10 you're a bro either way
thanks Berlin also they say that I've
got great information and a super
friendly vibe perfect that's how I'm
going for I [ __ ] nailed it I like to
give you good information I'd like to
bring a friendly vibe as a friendly
hippie type Rasta man trying to put a
smile on your face and have one on my
own and then you say your mom digs the
hugs which is always [ __ ] cool so hey
do be beretta take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me alright let's move
on to the next five star review this one
was left on June 5th so it's obviously
been a minute since I've read comments
this comment was left by a listener who
calls themselves B cognate at the
headline of the comment is hands down
the best podcast I goes like this this
show provides awesome grow advice and is
highly entertaining would recommend to
anyone interested in cannabis
hey thanks my goal is to provide awesome
grow advice and also entertain you I'm
kind of a jokester sort of a dude so I'm
glad you're entertained also it keeps
your attention I think you I paid better
attention in classes to teachers that
gave a [ __ ] and connected and add some
personality other than those teachers
that are always like turn to page 37 and
let's do the work not always bored the
[ __ ] out of me and you're not gonna
learn from that you're gonna get bored
and turn the page like I used to do so
try to be entertaining also and then you
say would recommend to anyone interested
in cannabis yes please do recommend this
podcast to everyone interested in
cannabis even if people are just
learning about cannabis recommend my
podcast to them just be like hey do you
listen to the show anybody that just
listens to podcasts in general have them
listen to my podcast please I would
appreciate that awesome be cognitive
thank you for the iTunes comment and
review and also thanks for the 5-star
review you know what I'm gonna click it
says what's this review helpful I'm
gonna click YES on because Nana and I'm
gonna click YES on do be brought a
seven-ten your comments we're very
helpful thanks a lot
alright let's move on to the next iTunes
review and comment this person left a
five star rating and
their name is I'm guessing that's
Colorado jab it's colo jab
they left their comment on June 1st and
it goes like this I'm loving this
podcast if you grow or or are into
cannabis this one will educate and
entertain I see a theme here you guys
are entertained and you're getting
educated and you love the show that's
[ __ ] awesome thank you thanks for
loving the show the show loves you back
if thanks for letting me entertain and
educate you for about an hour once a
weekend also thanks for the five-star
review I appreciate that let's see where
is the next review this one was left May
15th and is left by a person who calls
themselves Jon Funkytown Kingston the
headline is one love of course they left
a five-star rating and the comment goes
like this great podcast I love finding
new grow and cannabis related podcasts
thanks for I think so much for taking
time to make this happen please check me
out on Instagram and then they give
their Instagram handle and since you
were smooth enough to sneak that in
there I think I may have read this
comment before now that I see that or
somebody else did this but since you're
smooth enough to sneak it in there
it's the kind of cannabis da ki nd
cannabis check them out on Instagram
they just got a free plug I'm gonna
follow them in his review he also says
thanks for taking the time to make the
podcast happen dude you're very welcome
thanks for taking the time to leave me a
good review I hope people check you out
on Instagram you better be clicking like
on all my pics after this one bro
alright let's go to our next five-star
review this is gonna be the last one for
this episode so if you're getting bored
with the reviews we are almost done it
goes like this it was left on May 5th it
was left by somebody who calls
themselves live lime the headline is
truly Irie the comic goes like this
polite informed and medicated this shows
a must listen whenever whether you were
in trim jail driving or any cubicle
thanks Ross to Jeff for the knowledge
give your mom a hug for me so this dude
says I'm polite and I'm informed and I'm
medicated those are all things I would
agree with I try to be polite I could be
a [ __ ] sometimes and I'm my comedian
mouth and mind gets ahead of me but I
try to be polite so thanks for that
compliment informed yes I am informed I
try to stay informed and educated with
cannabis
medicated I am highly medicated it's the
seven ten episode so I'm certainly
medicated we'll talk about that in a
minute
this shows a must listen yes you must
listen please you must also tell your
friends to listen and then you say
whether you're in trim jail which you
guys if you've never been to trim jail
that means when you're trimming and
you've just been trimming and trimming
and trimming for hours we've got people
that we paid a trim and they trim for
eight hours a day and that looks like
Jail so with if you're in trim jail or
if you're driving driving is where I
listen to most of my podcasts or if
you're in a cubicle this is the show to
listen to and the dude says thanks Ross
to Jeff for the knowledge you're very
welcome
for sharing the knowledge I I don't feel
like it would be safe to learn this much
and not spread it somehow that's like my
return I've been given a couple of gifts
and I like to put them back out there so
you're very welcome
and thanks for the cool compliment
thanks for appreciating the show and
thanks for doing it looks like you're in
trim jail quite often though so thanks
for doing what you do for cannabis and
I'll give my mom a hug for you she'll
think it's weird when I'm like a live
lime said give you a hug like what the
[ __ ] is that about but I'll do it bro
it'll be awkward for everybody and I
like awkward alright everybody I want to
thank you guys for leaving iTunes
reviews once again if you want to leave
an iTunes review simply go to iTunes
find the iTunes Store search for the
girl from your heart podcast right in
the middle it says ratings and reviews
click on there I bet you can figure out
the rest from there so far everybody has
given me a five star review there's 62 5
star reviews up here alright you guys
let's move forward with the show a
little bit at the top of the show I told
you that I was going to talk a little
bit about 7/10 and the meaning and of
course the origin of the phrase 7/10 if
you don't know what 710 is 710 is the
dad smoker holiday 7/10 is when you're
supposed to smoke hash 7/10 is the new
4/20 that's a phrase coined by my friend
Adam ill he always says 7/10 is the new
4/20 and I agree with him so what is
7/10 all about I'll take a few seconds
here and explain it to you obviously if
you turn the number 710 upside down it
says oil so 7/10 became the time to
smoke oil that's that's fairly obvious
so everybody was smoking weed at 4:20
and then all the
hache craze came along and everyone
started taking dabs and so somebody and
we'll talk about who in just a couple of
seconds somebody decided that 7:10 since
it was oil upside-down 710 in the
evening or if you're like me 710 in the
morning or both if you're like me I
guess was the best time to smoke some
dabs
so 7:10 upside down or oil upside down
is 710 that's pretty much where it
originated now one thing I can tell you
is that 710 is not the temperature of
your email a lot of people said 710 is
the perfect temp for your email it may
be for your email but it is not for all
emails and I'm gonna rant for a second
on why think about this you've got an
email with the box with a number on it
that is sending something down a cable
to a coil that is attached to a nail
that has got to heat up now your box
that has a number on it doesn't know if
you just put that coil on a quartz nail
on a titanium nail or if you wrapped it
around your finger all it knows is that
that coil needs to heat up to about a
specific temperature range there is not
in most emails that I am aware of there
is not a thermostat in that coil it is
sending a frequency an amount of
electricity through that coil and that
much power at the end of it is causing
that much heat it is not it's not like a
range on your stereo it's not a specific
measurement it's just like you know that
when your car when you turn the car
stereo up to 23 it sounds good if you go
up to like 29 it starts to crackle a
little bit when you hit 32 it sounds
like total [ __ ]
so each email will have its own
adjusting range where it will be perfect
and not all of them will dial in at 710
my email that I use from giddy up in the
Gmail depending on which nail I put on
it I need to adjust it anywhere from
around 600 to 800 if I use the
highly-educated the and which one is
that it's the H nail it's just the old
school email insert if I use that one ah
that one I need to put it down in the
like 650s if I use the new one with a
quartz dish in that big titanium shroud
I have to crank that [ __ ] up
closer to 800 because all the extra
stuff the bit the nail head is much
bigger so your box your email box
doesn't know
know the surface on the the temperature
on the surface of the nail so that is
not true a lot of people think that 710
is the center the temperature on the
surface of the nail that's inaccurate
sorry I stuttered so many times trying
to say that I think I got my point
across so that is not what 710 means
what 710 means is oil upside down and
it's time to take a dab now let's talk a
little bit how it originated I want to
give a shout out to somebody I feel is
highly responsible for many advances in
our current hash culture in the 7-10
movement in dab culture and our ability
to smoke dabs a true innovator he's a
musical artist he makes titanium nails
he now makes quartz nails he was the
originator of the email of course I owe
a huge shout out to task rock of highly
educated titanium big shout out much
respect to the best of my knowledge task
rock and the guy from health Stone glass
and the guy from BHO clothing came up
with the idea for 710 and task rock is
the person who coined the phrase 710 so
a big shot at the task happy 7/10 to
everybody in the dab community everybody
take a big fat dab right now and give
some praise to task I'm actually gonna
grab a dabber right now and I'm going to
heat myself up a dab and take a dab with
you guys on the show I usually don't dad
on the show I usually do it during a
break or something because I've been
coughing a lot sometimes I get super
rambley just don't do it on the show try
to get my [ __ ] together but you know it
at 7:10 and we're gonna dab forecast
rocks let's all dad together right now I
am dabbing some I've been calling it
lemon pee it's lemon skunk and pro dad
geum shatter and then i've got some of
this this lemon jeffery hi terpene full
spectrum extract i dunk the dab into
here give it a little swirl then next
time we'll smoke some of this lemon
Jeffrey high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract with a high Terp dumped into it
but right now let's get down on this one
I'm gonna heat the nail here I'm hitting
the Hitman the little hammer head perk
with the yellow logo on it and then I've
got the highly-educated nail that's got
the the titanium base with the screw on
quartz dish so let's go and heat up a
phat dab or heat up the nail for myself
take a phat dab of course I'm using this
super dope coil condenser decorated
torch to heat up the nail
I apologize if you hear that ridiculous
noise from the torch in the background
is going but sometimes it's what you got
to do for a fat dab it's heating up
gonna heat it till it glows and you know
what we're gonna do two things here in
honor of Mickey Martin I'm gonna hit
this [ __ ] while it's glowing red shout
out to mickey Martin hashtag glow squad
huge shot at the task rock let's do this
dab with me you guys oh god that's hot I
hate it way too hot oh man red means go
hit it when it's real hot see what it
does to you no don't do it it's better
if you let it cool the Terps taste
better if you let it cool but I feel
like I get something different when I go
in super hot like that Oh see what I was
talking about
I don't dab on the shows it makes me
ramble and it makes me all dumb for a
second
whoo happy 7/10 everybody oh that was
too hot I like it Oh my body's dying I'm
gonna take a drink no it was for Micky
Martin a task rock ok I'm back on my
game all right which direction do we
want to go oh [ __ ] let's do something
important I came across this just a
couple of days ago ladies and gentlemen
a lot of us use pesticides in our garden
if you work in Colorado Washington or
Oregon or any of the states that have
regulated legalized cannabis grows there
are lists of pesticides that you are and
are not allowed to use now those
pesticides have been approved or
disapproved for multiple reasons
mainly anything approved for tobacco has
been approved for use on cannabis among
amongst the things that have been
approved for cannabis is as a trawl you
were allowed to use as a trawl and a
recreational grow if used a prop
appropriately excuse me I'm trying to
cough off that dab without coughing into
the mic too much
okay so as the trawl we've trusted and
has a trawl we trust in the Department
of Ag to do their inspections we trust
in these companies to put things in the
bottle that they say is in the bottle on
June 28th the Oregon Department of
Agriculture released the following
statement pesticide advisory misbranded
/ adulterated pesticide products
presence of several undeclared pesticide
residues so what this is already hinting
at is that there is [ __ ] in the bottle
that nobody told us about I'll go ahead
and read the rest of the notice the
Oregon Department of Agriculture has
ordered stoppage of sale and
distribution of two pesticide products
manufactured by pbi gordon corporation
after finding the presence of several
pesticide active ingredients not listed
on the product label as a trawl hydro
botanical insecticide and as a trawl ec
insecticide are labeled for use on
ornamental food and feed crops as an
insecticide insect growth regulator and
repellent these products may also be
used in the production of cannabis both
products list the active ingredient as
adder Acton derived from neem seeds and
may be identified BBE
by the EPA registration number 2 - 1 7 -
8 3 6 the products are listed for
organic use by the organic materials
review Institute also known as armory in
addition the Oregon Department of
Agriculture is asking growers who may
have purchased the pesticide product to
refrain from using it Oregon Department
of Agriculture's actions came following
an investigation of the product and
laboratory analysis found the presence
of the pesticide active ingredients and
there's a bunch of words in here I'm a
[ __ ] but they found permethrin Bev in
Tharin cypermethrin safe love rin and
claw claw pepero sclera peripheral i'm
gonna try you guys i'm gonna sound this
out like it did in school
clora pie riff boasts chlorpyrifos
chlorpyrifos that's where we're gonna
say it sounds like a Greek god they
found chlorophyll foes in there I don't
know what that is to tell you the honest
truth but none of which were listed on
either product label so we are trusting
companies to package to make a product
and package a product and print a label
on the product and be honest with us and
tell us what they are selling us we rely
on them for that because we've been take
these products that are approved by the
Department of Agriculture and we apply
them to our plants then they are tested
because they are tested by the meb and
private labs test these plants before I
so if I work in a commercial girl I'm
sure you guys know that by now I am the
production the cultivation manager for
Three Rivers dispensary Three Rivers
Development I apply pesticides to plants
with worker protection safety training I
am pesticide safety trained I understand
what I'm doing I understand when and how
to apply a pesticide I applied these
pesticides to my crops before I am
allowed to pass these crops from my grow
to the retail end they must be tested by
a laboratory for pesticide residuals for
mold residuals for contaminants for they
test for so much [ __ ] now they are going
to find because of this company lied
they're going to find things that I
can't pronounce that are not allowed to
be in there because this company put
them in the bottle and did not say that
it was there so now there are going to
be crops that will have to be destroyed
and there will be businesses that don't
make money there will be patients that
don't get medicine this is gonna just
[ __ ] up a lot of that's gonna snowball
this isn't just one small thing this
company the company that made the
pesticide isn't gonna be the only one to
get [ __ ] and honestly the patients
that consumed any of the medicine that
was sprayed with this by the people that
did not know it was in there they're
really the ones getting [ __ ] so
there's more to this pesticide advisory
newsletter that went out and I'll
continue to read it I think I stopped
right about here in an in an abundance
of caution a statewide stop sale use or
removal order has been issued by the
Oregon Department of Agriculture to pbi
Gordon Corporation of Kansas City the
order calls for the company to
immediately cease all sales offers of
sale or other distribution of the
product
in Oregon so they can no longer sell
this product in Oregon I honestly think
it's been banned in the Colorado amed
use for quite a while anyway I haven't
seen as a trawl in a grow I haven't used
as a trawl on a grow in quite a while I
think as a Max in Evergreen have been
the to go twos lately there are a few
other things I should tell you guys
about a product called Graham Devo check
out grande evo water dispersed granules
it looks expensive but once you read
about how to use it it is very cost
effective and it's worth it it is a
multi-purpose product it will help you
get rid of powdery mildew it help you
get rid of most of your bugs you can use
it as a soil drench it will not affect
your roots at all you can use it as a
foliar feed it has so many applications
grande evo wdg check that [ __ ] out just
a little tip for you then I'm gonna go
on with this letter it also says
retailers and the general public in
possession of as at all products
manufactured by PBR Gordon Corporation
are advised not to sell offer for sale
or distribute them Oda will be working
with the manufacturer to determine the
appropriate disposition of product that
is currently in commerce or with growers
OTAs investigation will proceed to
address violations of Oregon's pesticide
law which include misbranding of a
pesticide product adulteration of a
pesticide product and making false or
misleading claims about a pesticide
product for additional information and
there is a number to contact the Oregon
Department of Agriculture I'm not gonna
give out their phone number here at my
podcast that may result in trolling and
we don't need that but ladies and
gentlemen if you're using as a trawl
because you think it is semi safe and
it's much more gentle than a lot of
products that are out there I would
recommend as a trawl before a lot of
things if you're using as a trawl you
may want to reconsider if you've got a
whole bunch of it I might not want to
use it for a little while until they get
this figured out and find out which
batches were adulterated
I know pesticides are expensive and if
you've got a bunch of this stuff for
your commercial girl or whatever it's
gonna be hard to set that money aside
and buy another product but you've got
some thinking to do and if you're in
Oregon you can't use it at all
and if you're in Colorado I don't think
you're able to use it if you're using as
a trawl and you can't replace it just
run
soon and when you do run out by a Xamax
that's and just don't buy anymore as a
child no matter what state you're in I
wouldn't risk it because you're thinking
you're giving one thing and they're
selling you another don't risk it just
go get a Xamax or evergreen or get them
both and switch between asthmatics and
evergreen and that'll really solve your
problem anyway it's always a good idea
to switch up pesticides anyway because
your bugs will start building a
resistance so if you hit them one day
with a Xamax and then you hit him the
next time with evergreen and then you
hit him with that as a max the next time
they're not gonna know what to just do
so you're just gonna hit him with
multiple modes they'll get the least
resistance and then your pesticides will
continue to work so that's my advice
you're rid of the as a trawl bison has a
max by a little bit of evergreen and
then you'll be clear and then also try
some uh grande Evo in the mix there
you should be pest free hopefully all
the other products we're trusting are
putting in the bottle what we think
they're putting in there because this is
a little this is the second time we've
heard about a product being adulterated
and making people fail tests so
hopefully it doesn't happen again if you
were in the pesticide industry stop
[ __ ] around come on quit lying to us
I'm sure there are huge fines and [ __ ]
involved in this because this is uh it
says on the bottom include misbranding
of a pesticide product adulteration of a
pressed pesticide product and making
false or misleading claims about a
pesticide product that sounds like
important [ __ ] that could probably be
some federal [ __ ] but I don't know
anyway let's move away from that and
let's move into an email I don't know if
this person let's scan it real quick
okay this person wants to call
themselves aam B so shot it's a zombie
if you want to send me an email it's a
girl from your heart at hotmail calm
let's read this email right here it says
what's up Rasta Jeff long time listener
here and I'd first like to thank you for
all the work you do your podcast is
absolutely the best pot cannabis podcast
I have found whether you're getting
rambling by yourself or with the full
table it is so entertaining and
informative I do love it when y'all
ramble so that's the best opening I love
that you're very welcome
you say thank you right at the start
you're very welcome and I love hearing
that my podcast is absolutely the best
cannabis podcast that puts a huge smile
on my face and I'd like it that you like
it when I'm by myself cuz I've been by
my
self lately I've been recording late at
night for some reason it's just when I
can find the time I love it that you
like it when I ramble because bro I have
been getting [ __ ] rambley lately
let's move on with the email a little
bit you go on to say so with the
obligatory praise out of the way I have
several questions for you my wife is a
travel nurse and we are going to Boulder
for our next contract we got married in
Colorado and we love that state we have
been considering buying a house in
Pueblo but not but have not had a chance
to come there yet
I was hoping you would be able to steer
us in the right direction as far as
areas to avoid and possibly areas to
look into all right now it's hard to
give honest advice and opinions about a
place when you've got negative things to
say and you've got to live here and I'm
sure that a lot of people already know
what I'm gonna say so we'll get right to
it if you come here and you plan to move
here I would not recommend you move to
the east side every towns got it's
shitty side and the east side has a
reputation for being the shitty side of
town so yes there are good things on the
east side we've got a really cool skate
park there is good [ __ ] over there but
certain parts of the east side you do
not want to [ __ ] around in there are
also parts of the west side that I would
not recommend you [ __ ] around in other
than that most of the town is pretty
cool it kind of depends on your
preference and your income and if you're
trying to buy or if you're trying to
rent it kind of depends on what you're
looking to do if you want to be right
downtown that's not too bad it's going
to be a little more expensive and you're
not gonna have any parking but that's
how it goes wherever you live downtown
so that's an option if you want to be
away from the people I would recommend
Pueblo County like unincorporated Pueblo
County the grow rules are different
taxes are cheaper if you want something
a little more it's kind of a little more
privacy a little newer a little more
modern there's another City it is 15
minutes west of Pueblo and it's called
Pueblo West that's a cool little spot
you can get really big giant houses out
there with a little more space it's a
little more expensive than Pueblo but
it's also cleaner safer and nicer
there's less traffic and it's more of a
little upscale kind of a vibe amore
if kind of a community one thing I can
complain about pueblos is there's no
[ __ ] food here around nine o'clock if
you're hungry after 8:30 nine maybe ten
o'clock good luck
there's no food to be had here there are
those shitty burrito places those places
that they have everywhere the Mexican
food places that are open late but if
you're like me you don't really prefer
that there's one place around here that
I will eat at this a little Mexican
place it closes at nine o'clock so most
of the food shuts down there's not a lot
of good food chains here that's it but
they're coming those things are coming a
lot of people talk a lot of [ __ ] about
Pueblo Colorado but it is really
changing and cannabis is really putting
a big change on this place cannabis
brings business business brings money
money brings people people bring more
money it's making a huge change here but
anyway I would stay off the east side if
you're trying to move here as parts of
the West siders shitty decent places the
south side is pretty cool it's mellow
Regency is not a bad area it's
affordable the houses are a good size
it's not too far from schools and
shopping and everything it's right off
of Pueblo Boulevard so you can get
everywhere quickly it's not too far from
I 25 and highway 50 Regency is a pretty
decent area
um I think University Park on the north
side is a pretty nice area it's a little
more expensive the north side is cool El
Camino on the south side if you're
looking to buy a house El Camino is a
good area to buy a semi large house
right now because a lot of people are
moving out and they're upgrading to
larger houses leaving the houses in El
Camino available I talked about Pueblo
West I talked about the county those are
the notes I wrote down for housing
recommendations in Pueblo if Pablo is
too small a lot of people feel trapped
in a small town like this there's not a
lot of food here there's not a lot of
options here it's kind of uh it's an
older town with a different type of
mentality that is evolving it's getting
there but it's not quite there yet
people ask me why I don't leave here
it's because I'm proud of it and I see
potential and I see what's coming and
I've been here for so long that I feel
like I can't abandon the city that let
me be me I've Forrest as a person here I
really became what I am here in Pueblo
Colorado so I can't abandon this place
I'm watching it becomes something and
I'm proud of this little place but if
it's not for you I understand that if
it's too small for you if it's too it's
not your thing I get that
a lot of people leave here there's a
slightly aggressive vibe here we've got
a steel mill and [ __ ] like that
it's just a different vibe it's it's a
hard working steel toe boots leather
jacket kind of a vibe here with a lot of
the community so it's not for a lot of
people if you're into a bigger city
Colorado Springs is really cool it's a
little more military vibe but it's got
more stuff you can get food after nine
o'clock it's got all of the restaurants
you can think of they're there all the
stores they're all there a lot of the
Pueblo stores are kind of we get the
smaller version of all the stores but
that's just that's just small [ __ ]
complaints anyway let me move on with
this email because there's more to it he
also says also while there's no shortage
of dispensaries where I'll be the last
time I visited quality varied widely
from location to location
well it's your current recommendation
for best quality well obviously since I
work for Three Rivers I'm going to say
that I would recommend you go to Three
Rivers in Pueblo Colorado and you shop
on the recreational side excuse me I'm
trying to burp into the microphone again
hey when you walk into Three Rivers you
can go left or you can go right there
are two windows to walk to the left
window is recreational the right window
is medical if you don't have a medical
card anybody 21 and over with an ID can
shop over there on the recreational side
there is great product there that
product is not grown in my facility that
product is grown by a good friend of
mine and I trust that product I know who
grows that I know how it's grown it's
grown with the same methods and
techniques as my grow just in another
building so I would recommend three
rivers that's in Pueblo if you can't
make it to Pueblo I would check out the
recreational side of kind love in Denver
that's one of the best dispensaries I
honestly don't have a lot of other
recommendations in Denver because I
don't shop at dispensaries I don't go to
a lot of dispensaries because I'm mostly
self defit self self deficient is almost
what I said I'm mostly self-sufficient
and I don't have to do a lot of shopping
if I do shopping I just go buy extracts
and I usually go to apothecary for that
ah but quality will vary and that's one
strange thing is from batch to batch
from vendor to vendor stuff will be so
different sometimes and sometimes it's
hard to predict so I think your best bet
would be to go to
three rivers and go to the recreational
side there or go to kind love in Denver
and get products there because in
Colorado Springs it is all medical
product it looks like you're gonna be in
Boulder your email says that you're
going to Boulder I am not too familiar
with dispensaries in Boulder I would
recommend going to weed Maps download
weed maps on your phone open up weed
maps and check out the reviews on
dispensaries and then if there's a
certain strain you're looking for or
something maybe that'll help you decide
which dispensary to go to but often
times you can tell when you drive by a
dispensary if it's somewhere you want to
go here's a weird if you get a feeling
at a dispensary like [ __ ] this place or
oh I don't know you don't have to shop
there you can leave there are a lot more
to go to so you'll get a feeling that's
usually it's just like the same way that
people choose their liquor stores or
their bar that they drink at or whatever
we choose our dispensaries very
similarly
you just get a vibe you go in you either
love it or hate it and if you love it
you go back if you hate it you don't go
back so check them out don't go into one
and don't be afraid to walk out without
spending anything should be alright man
I don't see what I was looking for and
they may act weird to you they may act
like you wasted their time but you did
not waste anybody's time you found out
what you needed to find out which is
their products or not what you need
you're not required to spend anything
you don't you're not expected to spend
money if you go to Target or Walmart you
can walk in and not find what you want
and then you can leave you can do the
same thing at the dispensary so while
you're in Boulder check them out Gillen
weed maps get some recommendations
alright there's more to the email he
says assuming I get a Colorado license
right away how long is the process for
getting a medical marijuana card so when
you move here you'll get an ID all you
need is that ID and then immediately you
can go to the marijuana doctor the
hardest part of that may be setting the
appointment some places can get you in
right away some doctors are pretty
backed up it just depends on if you can
find a place to get you in some places
they'll get you in that day if they get
you in that day they will fill out your
paperwork for you online if you can do
an online registration which I'm sure
you can it just takes a couple of clicks
you will have your medical marijuana
card within 48 hours when I did it my
card was approved and I was able to
digitally print
my renewed card within 24 I was 12 hours
later honestly I turned it in at like 2
o'clock in like 2 o'clock that morning I
got an email saying hey you've got your
card so it shouldn't be too long I don't
think for a brand new card registering
online I think it could be like is
quickly from having your license getting
the doctor appointment may be the hard
part once you see the doc I think 48
hours from there you should have a card
I can't promise you that but for a
renewal that's all it took for a brand
new card I don't think it should be much
longer then to wrap up the email our
friend zombie says obviously I'd love to
meet you and your crew and dab the [ __ ]
out and then he says who wouldn't I love
hearing that who wouldn't want to come
dad with us come on you guys come dad we
need to do a girl from your heart dab
session then he says but short of that
any help with the above questions would
be greatly appreciated and he says one
love from zombie hey bro I hope I
answered all of your questions
thoroughly and appropriately and if I
spark for any questions just send me an
email and I will answer them a little
more for you hey when you come to
Colorado if you come down to Pueblo and
visit I'd love to meet you bro I've got
some dads I've got some turps
I've got a clean rig if you've got a
cool voice and some [ __ ] to say I've
also got another microphone we'll put
you on a podcast
thanks for the email dude if anybody
wants to email me it's a girl from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you
all right podcast world I've been going
for close to 40 minutes now I want to
thank everybody for listening to this
podcast I would appreciate it if you
follow me on Twitter once again it's @gf
wih podcast you can find me on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast and if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into all the social media stuff you
can simply send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com also
don't forget about patreon if you want
more information about patreon and ways
you can contribute to the podcast
check out patreon.com/lenguin
[Music]
I hope everybody had a safe and fun 7 10
taking dad's with me I want to give a
huge shout out to Alaska Matt and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
yeah
[Music]
I see the way you understand anyway
about money
I mean everybody
[Music]