yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 225 of the
girl from your heart podcast you're a
source for cannabis news education and
conversation try to fear a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jack I want to thank you guys again for
joining as always I need to send a huge
thank you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roof band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
crew ladies and gentlemen I just took a
giant dab of some lemon Geoffrey hi
cannabinoid full spectrum extract I
dumped that into the lemon Geoffrey Hite
terpene full spectrum extract staking
the dab everything was going well and
right towards the end of the dab I just
started [ __ ] sneezing and I don't
know what happened it sneezed about 12
times in a row the smoke came out of my
ears the smoke came out of my eyes I
feel like the smoke came out of my nose
it really was kind of kind of not
pleasant for a couple of seconds there
my face feels all swollen and puffy like
after you sneeze a whole bunch but the
good side is it feels super medicated my
head is very mellow after that there
should be a fun intro I hope everybody
had a good 7 10 I know I did I took some
fat dabs I did not give your mom a hug
for me though I will next time all right
let's get this podcast on the road you
guys it has been hot I hope you've been
dealing with the heat hope everything
has been going well in your garden hope
the air conditioner is holding up hope
your brain hasn't melted hope you're
staying hydrated be careful out there if
you're going to any festivals or
anything stay hydrated if you were at
Challis I hope you survived Big Ups if
you survived chalice chalice was a
festival a hash music and art festival
hosted by our friends at Hitman glass I
was out in a northern part of California
I want to say Oxnard but I could be
wrong I was seeing people posting
pictures of 110 112 and I think somebody
posted a hundred and 18 degrees out
there people are out there smoking hash
and watching music and having a good
time
better people than me [ __ ] that I don't
want to go play when it's 118 degrees
all I want to do is turn on the
air-conditioner and stay the [ __ ] inside
I don't even want to mess around with
118 that does not sound like a good idea
at all
I am super pale for some reasons when I
go out in the Sun I'm like I'm almost
gingery my beard comes in red but my
hair is blonde but uh when I go out in
the Sun I just burn and just roast I'll
turn bright red and then I'll peel
sometimes and then the next day I'm not
even a Sun Tan anymore so it's gonna
shitty I don't get a Sun Tan or anything
I just go from white to lobster red to
peel to nothing alright I'm already off
to a good ramble this should be a good
podcast let's see let's get into a
little bit of a breeding update I keep
talking about the breeding project I'm
currently working on if you guys know
anything about me no I'm working within
a rise mail arises a golden go female
pollinated by a Daybreaker male the
arise progeny has tested in the high 20s
and low 30s and THC very consistently
shout-out to our friends at org antica
in new mexico they grow the arize so far
they have tested the highest I've ever
seen a test they tested at 35 percent
THC that's the highest that I've ever
seen steep hill test so big love to our
friends at arg antica so I'm using a
male from the arize his name is Solomon
I named him King Solomon on June 18th I
used King Solomon to pollinate a
redheaded stranger a proto Geum from
Ethos genetics a Flo Kalonji Kush
grateful dog we got hell's og in there
there's a lemon skunk in there Capleton
chefs oh geez white widow platinum tangi
chem for Jack flash
critical mass and a whole bunch of other
stuff anyway I pollinated them on the
18th
today it is let's look down and see what
the date is today as 7:13 as I record so
that means they were pollinated almost a
month ago
the seeds are forming the seeds are fat
I can see the seeds in the buds you
don't need any sort of assistance to see
them the buds are swollen
swell swollen up with seeds that was
harder to say than it looked but I'm
very excited they should be done
somewhere between two and four weeks I'm
probably gonna let them go the
four weeks to make sure that they are
done the only problem with letting seeds
go too long is sometimes they get a
little too hard and they don't germinate
well I'm none of these that are being
made out of this batch you're going to
market these are all for myself I've got
plenty of other things that are
available for market but yeah that's
where this breeding project is honestly
something I don't know why I was really
excited about the Platinum tangi to
arise I want to put that orange flavor
but since I've been watching it happen
the Kim for a Ryze combination has just
been making me more and more excited and
also I'm growing the Kim for in the
commercial grower at Three Rivers and it
just gets huge and chunky and stinks so
it's been getting me excited so I'm
excited about the rise to Kim for but
there's gonna be a lot of cool new [ __ ]
coming up the seeds are getting huge you
can see them in there you guys they're
not quite turning dark yet they're white
they're going kind of grayish they'll go
white then the kind of this grayish
color and then they'll turn the green
and it'll start turning that
tiger-stripe thing and that's when
they're done they're kind of doing the
first transition part they're getting
there they're there almost starting to
be like real seeds all right so that's
an update on the breeding project thanks
for paying attention to the breeding
project also huge thanks to everybody
who have been sending me on a stream
name ideas I'm working on new strains
all the time I have a couple of new
strains that could use names those
strains have been Flo cross to the arize
and of course white widow cross to arise
people have been sending in names I
think I've decided the name for Flo to
arise Y widow to arise does not have a
name yet if you've got any suggestions
I'd love to hear them you can tweet me
at G f YH podcast of course you can send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you can also find me on
Instagram it's Irie underscore genetics
on Instagram alright that's enough of
that let's move forward a little bit
where do we go next patreon holy crap
you guys huge thank you to everybody who
contributed to the patreon in the past
and in the present this month was a
great month for patreon if you don't
know what patreon is let me explain it
to you
patreon is a service that allows you as
a listener to financially contribute to
the podcast that's right if you feel
like this podcast is worth a couple of
bucks of your time you can go to
patreon.com/scishow
begging for money but if you feel like
the show is worth a couple of bucks I
would love it if you threw them my
direction what I will do with those
couple of dollars is I will keep my
website up that hosts this podcast my
website is Irie genetics Colorado calm
it looks like [ __ ] right now I apologize
I focus more on the podcast and more on
like grows then I do the website but the
point is the podcast webpage is where
the podcast is hosted so I have to keep
the webpage alive that's where the
podcast goes it goes into an RSS feed
then it ends up in iTunes and stitcher
so that you're able to listen to it for
free all I'm asking for is help in
covering the cost of my website I also
buy these little phone microphone covers
for when people come over I do a few
other things I buy water bottles for
everybody I also dad everybody the [ __ ]
out so I'm just looking for a little
little financial help for the things
that I have spent on the podcast so it
doesn't all come out of my pocket if you
guys can't contribute I will continue to
do it out of my pocket because I [ __ ]
love podcasting I love cannabis and I
love you guys so if you want to learn
how to contribute simply go to
patreon.com
is patr e o n patreon.com slash grow
from your heart I once again huge thank
you to everybody who's contributed and
if you can't contribute don't feel bad I
still want you to listen to this podcast
they're just a few people out there that
have asked how they can help out and now
they've got a way to do it so thank you
alright moving forward I've got a little
teaser I was contacted by a company
called pl grow and they are going to
send us a product to review on the show
the product is coming all the way from
Australia so it's gonna be a little
while but I am excited to get the
product I'm excited to test it out and
then I'm even more excited to get behind
the microphone until you guys all about
what these people sent me so big shout
out to our friends at PL Gro I really
look forward to the box from Australia
alright you guys I'm gonna press pause
here I need to take a drink my throat's
already doing that thing where it sounds
like [ __ ] so I'm gonna press pause I'm
gonna take a drink hmm yep see there it
goes and of course I'm gonna take a
couple of gigantic tabs then I'll be
right back and we're going to read some
emails from our friends our first email
is going to be about trellising a
commercial grow in a perpetual cycle and
then we have another email that goes
right along with that so stick around
take a couple of dabs and I'll be right
back
all right podcast world I am back I just
took a gigantic dab of some what was
this it was strawberry I don't want to
say the wrong thing it was strawberry
icy ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary extracts I headed up to
apothecary on ambrosia days I got to see
some cool glassblowing shot to her
friends at the glass grind what's up
Logan thanks for letting me watch a blow
glass dude that was cool man
it was a hundred degrees that day it was
super sunshiny and dude had a tent a
little booth set up with two torches
there actually to elevate had a booth
there also and occasionally these guys
would fire up their torches and blow
glass and I couldn't even go near the
damn booth when they were working the
glass cuz it was so hot shot at all the
glass workers who were doing glass in
the [ __ ] heat uh you're you're
tougher man than me and woman there was
a woman glass blower also mad respect
for the people out there in the [ __ ]
heat working behind a torch not me but
anyway I went to the ambrosia days on
was 79 the day before 7:10 we picked up
some pretty stylish hash I got some I
think one of my favorites was honestly
this strawberry I see and I was
pleasantly surprised by some Killer
Queen ambrosia and also the high
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract we got
some Clementine I got the Clementine the
ambrosia and also some Clementine Terps
and some Clementine I think there was
some high cannabinoid full spectrum
extract there was a bunch of great stuff
there I got a bunch of great things I've
honestly been sitting on a bunch of this
lemon Jeffrey high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract been saving it for
7/10 I've got one gram of it left and I
don't want to smoke it my next things
I'll be smoking I'm gonna finish this
strawberry I see ambrosia and this
Killer Queen high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract probably by the
end of tonight and then I'll be out all
my 7 10 fancy goodies
come on apothecary have another sale
I'll have to go back up there and get
myself some more goodies I shot it to
Cooper
what up coop I saw you up there at the
ambrosia days good talking to you coop
had a little little surgery it's good to
hear your taint is doing well my friend
all right I got weird super fast as soon
as I said taint I regretted it but I'm
not going to edit that out let's move
forward and work on some emails I've
been getting a lot of great emails from
listeners and I love doing shows based
on listener content that lets me know
them that I'm hitting my target it lets
me know I'm helping at least one person
so if you've got a question or if you
need some guidance on a grow or want to
know something about cannabis I would
love the opportunity to help you out
send me your email it's growth from your
heart at hotmail.com and I will read
your email on a future episode I know a
lot of people have sent me emails and
they're gonna say what the hell dude I
sent you a message a long time ago you
still haven't read it I get a lot of
emails like I said I'm working my way
through it and I'm getting caught up now
that I bought the printer and I've been
printing out the messages it's so much
easier so your chances are getting much
higher that your message will be read on
the show so let's start with this one
right here this one comes from a person
who calls themselves Aaron and they say
you can use my name the message goes
like this hi there I recently found your
podcast and is now part of my daily work
routine I actually work on a commercial
rec grow in Oregon and introduced it to
a few of my co-workers hey thank you man
I love it when people share the podcast
hopefully those people listen and then
hopefully they share it with somebody
else in the podcast grows and grows and
grows that's how it works oh thank you
for that ah then he says now on to the
questions I've got a bunch but we'll
only throw a few at you now hey I look
forward to the other questions
Aaron how you say you've got more
questions I want to hear them so shoot
it my way then you say recently you
talked about doing a scrog a screen of
green and your commercial grows how do
you work that into a perpetual cycle
also I'm having issues with russet mites
and route a fits what can I do to get
rid of them the more organic the better
could you also point me in the direction
of where to find a grow Kashi bucket or
how to make one much thanks from Aaron
you can use my name all right now the
first question is how do you work that
screen of green into a perpetual cycle I
depends on how you're doing the
perpetual the way that I do it in the
grow at Three Rivers is we've got three
separate rooms that are used for flower
rooms so we veg in one room and then we
move the plants to the flower room and I
like to leave them in the flower room
for about a week before I flip
so they go in there the day they get
moved into the flower room they get
trellis they get scrubbed out we put the
screen up the minute those plants are
done being moved in that's the next step
once they're in there we just start
scrubbing and then we put the we put the
scrog kind of low so we honestly lower
the plants anywhere from four to six
inches lower than what they were with
that first scrub just bring them down
right away spread them up our spread
them apart and lower them down so the
way we're doing is we're doing the whole
room at one time that's what's making it
work we move it all into there then we
scrub it on day one and pull it all down
and let it grow then we flip it a week
later and then about two maybe three
weeks after that we throw on the second
net and then sometimes two or three
weeks after that we throw on a third net
so that's basically how we're able to do
it in a perpetual grow if you're doing
more than one phase in a tray or one
area it's gonna be really hard to scrub
that's gonna be a real [ __ ] unless you
learn how to never cut the screen down
when we harvest we cut the screen out so
everything just comes down you may have
to use something a little more rigid
than a net they sell plastic screens
that you can use or chicken wire or
something so that you can manipulate the
plants through there and then when you
harvest one section you don't have to
cut the net down but that's gonna be a
real [ __ ] the only way I can't say the
only because there are always options
the way it works for us is by doing
whole sections or whole rooms at one
time I wouldn't recommend try a tray
like an 8 by 4 tray I wouldn't try to do
one side 30 days ahead of the other and
try to scrog it that's gonna [ __ ]
suck I would get another tray or I would
just do a bigger room and I would do two
separate sections for a scrog um maybe
you want to 5x5 tables instead of one
five by ten or four by two four by fours
instead of one four by eight to scrub
like that it would just be easier in my
opinion so the way that we do it for a
perpetual cycle is I move them into the
flour room I scrub them that day they
veg for a week then they flip about two
weeks later another net the first net of
strog is to spread them out the plants
are tall it just goes straight up I put
that net on there and I just pull them
down and I double their width and I
lower them by about four to six inches
so they're just put your arm straight up
in the air now imagine if somebody just
grabbed her arms and pulled them down
and made a Y and major Y wider that's
what I do to the plants just give them
go from a Y to a T and now they start
growing up maybe if you turn your wrists
up and that's what they start doing they
just start shooting up from there by
week two they need a trellis the second
trellis is just to support the buds
because now the buds are growing it's to
give them a little support kind of hold
them up then the third one is for those
giant donkey dick buds I just start
flopping over I like to just put that
third trellis in there when you draw
stuff like Jack flash Kim for Bordello
blueberry headband those things all
require a third trellis if you do it
right all right I hope I rambled on
enough to answer that part of your
question of the second part you're
having issues with Russert mites and
Root aphids what can you do to get rid
of them the more organic the better
Russert mites are a [ __ ] Russert mites
can destroy your crop hopefully you sent
this July eleventh what they're
recording it's the 13th hopefully these
things haven't eaten your whole crop yet
because they [ __ ] have the
opportunity by now Russert mites are a
real pain in the ass most of your
pesticides that are allowed by the
marijuana Enforcement Division in
Colorado won't be strong enough to take
down some Russert mites I'm not sure
what you're allowed to use in Oregon but
one thing that I was told worked
amazingly well in a commercial grow in
Colorado was granulated sulfur i
granulated sulfur was applied to the
plants as a foliar spray with he mix it
with water and spray it on the plants I
don't remember the ratio if you really
need specific info on the ratio of
granulated sulfur and water to apply to
plants as a mite aside and a fungicide
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I will ask my friend I was
having this conversation with he will
remind me the exact grams per gallon and
we'll get you guys all set up but my
friend used granulated sulfur in water
and applied it as a foliar spray on the
top and bottoms of the leaves the
underside of the leaves and it got rid
of his Russert mites to applications he
did an application on Monday and another
application on Friday and when we looked
again on Monday there was no sign of
Russert mites so that's one thing
that'll work and the good thing about
that is it's not considered a pest
so uh it may be there may be loopholes
on if you are are not allowed to use it
you can use it in Colorado because it's
not a pesticide it doesn't have to be
marked as a spray with the Department of
Ag so you're allowed to use that here I
think one thing I should say if you use
the granulated sulfur do not apply any
oils to your plants a week before or
after using the sulfur five days should
be safe I'm gonna say a week just to be
extra safe um if you add something like
as a max or smite or even as a trawl or
anything like that
evergreen if you add that after the
sulfur has been applied or before the
sulfur has been applied the oil and the
sulfur will combine and there's a
chemical reaction that happens that
[ __ ] decimates your plants do not do
it it will ruin your crop don't do it do
not apply sulfur and oils to your plants
within five days of each other
maybe even a week to be safe all right
don't do that so you can use granulated
sulfur to start getting rid of the
Russert mites if you don't you may be in
flower I understand you could be in
flower you don't want to put that
[ __ ] flavor in your buds you've got
to decide now do I want to spray the
sulfur or do I want to lose my entire
crop to russets because once they eat
the flowering plants they're headed
right back to the veg plants are headed
to the mom plants that are going to the
clones
you're gonna eat [ __ ] everything so
you may need to go crazy you may need to
spray them with the sulfur if that
doesn't work or you don't want to use
that you can try zero tall zero
tolerance may help you out if you're in
flower it won't leave a funky flavor you
can use it late in flower if necessary I
never recommend spraying anything late
in flower but if you've got russet my
tip you got to go hard right now um
other things I can recommend that will
help you are grande evo grande evo as a
powder i recommend grande evo wdg water
dispersed granules do somewhere between
10 and 15 grams of grande Evo per gallon
of water and apply it as a foliar feed
you can also use as a max you can use
evergreen those may help you get rid of
you're russets but you're gonna have to
be very diligent you're gonna have to
treat these plants like every other day
depending on what products you're using
what you're gonna have to stay on top of
it another thing you can do to get rid
of the mites is D foliate heavily if
there's a mite or a mite egg or some
might damage on the leaf just pull that
[ __ ] leaf off put it in a trash bag
seal it get it off site do whatever you
got to do to get that [ __ ] bag of
leaves the [ __ ] out of there you're just
taking colonies of my it's somewhere
else
get rid of them burn them with fire if
you have the option so grande evo you
can mix grande evo as a max push you can
mix a lot of pesticides together and you
can come at it for multiple modes of
attack and then you get the least amount
of resistance so if your imagine if I
came at you with a karate chop and a
knife and a gun you have no way to
[ __ ] block that that's what you have
to do to these spider mites you got a
karate kick them you got a stab wound
you got to shoot them all at the same
[ __ ] time so maybe some grande Evo
maybe some has a max maybe put in some
some push from veg bloom just because
you're gonna hit him with all this bad
stuff put some push in there to kind of
make the plants happy while you're doing
it maybe you can hit them with some
evergreen or some smite maybe some
double nickel there are a lot of things
you can put in there but I think the
Grand Evo is gonna help
I think the sulfur is probably your best
bet if none of that stuff works or if
none of that sounds like a good idea to
you maybe it's time to try some predator
mites beneficial mites like this one's
hard to announce the and bleah seus
Endor Sony I'm gonna spell it for its AM
Bly sei US a nd RSO and I am Bleus Endor
Sony is known to eat the russet mite so
maybe you need to get some of those guys
release them in your garden get a lot of
them then maybe they'll get in there and
they will eat the [ __ ] out of your
russets I would also recommend some per
symulast mites they're always good and
the source Keys get in there I'm not
sure if the source keys will eat the
russets but they should there should be
no reason why they shouldn't they want
to get in there and eat so some swore
skis what are they called they are
ambitious
sworsky ah there's photos Caelius /
similes and then the new guy we learned
about the ambitious and ER sony
those are great predators that would get
in there and they would eat the [ __ ] out
of those bugs that way they're 100%
organic it's all natural not applying
anything you're just releasing bugs the
way that nature would do it so that's an
option also that's a whole bunch of
different options I hope something there
works for you if you need more guidance
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you already know that and we
won't narrow down what to do and good
luck with the [ __ ] russets they are a
[ __ ] the next one is rude aphids rude
aphids are fairly easy to get rid of you
just got to kind of kind of make him not
want to be there that's really easy you
can do a route drench with Grand Evo
when you google grande Evo it's gonna
look [ __ ] expensive I apologize for
the price of that but it works that's
all I've got to say I would do anywhere
between 10 and 15 grams of grande Evo
and a gallon per gallon of water and do
a root drench and just soak every plant
with the grande Evo mix that should get
rid of your root a fence you can use
grande Evo you can also use evergreen as
a soil drench somewhere around 15
milliliters per gallon of evergreen as a
soil drench works very well to get rid
of root a fidus gnats anything in the
soil like that if you are if your plants
are more established and they're
stronger you can get closer to 30 mils
per gallon but be very careful I would
start with 15 then maybe try 20 then see
what 30 does maybe try 30 on one or two
plants if it doesn't [ __ ] them up then
go ahead and feed them that that will
help get rid of root a fits also there's
another product called patan Agard max
it's Bota and i GA are debo tanah guard
max ma x/x botanic garden Matt but tanah
guard max is kind of pricey but it will
work very well to get rid of your
soil-borne pests
I think it's organic I'm not certain it
is approved by the meed in Colorado the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
does allow and the Department of
Agriculture will allow the use of all of
the products I've listed the Grand Evo
as it max evergreen botanic guard
cease smite all of those I'm pretty sure
at this time are legal and able to be
used the zero tall what else is on here
double nickels on my list those are just
a bunch of pesticides and products that
I
know that we used quite frequently in
the commercial growth settings those are
all allowed by the meed I do not know
the new rules on the sulfur I did not
apply the sulfur in my grow that was not
my research to be done but it worked so
you may want to do research if you're in
Oregon find out if it's allowed see if
it even needs to be mentioned since it's
not a pesticide it's not a food does it
even need to be listed on your
ingredients list I don't know the rules
about that so there are several products
you can use to get rid of your root
aphids now I know you're gonna say I
want to go organic and I don't want to
go putting products into my soil and
that shit's gonna be expensive
so you know what I'm gonna say let's go
to our friends at our baku organics and
let's grab some beneficial insects i
think the ones that you're gonna want to
get rid of your root aphids are going to
be called
oh you know what it's funny they're
called a fin parasites and aphid
predators that's what you want but first
i would recommend making sure that what
you've got our a Fitz
Athens have I'm pretty sure that I was
taught that the difference between the
aphids and the fungus gnats all a thens
have two little tailpipes is what I'm
pretty sure I was taught and then fungus
gnats are just the little black flies
that if you smack the pot they fly up
out of the pot so I would I would verify
which insect you've got and then I would
work from there and work on getting rid
of them if you've got a Fedor fungus
gnats all of the the sprays and drenches
I mentioned will work but you may need
different predator bugs to get rid of
different bugs all right so I'm gonna
move forward with this email man I
really hope I helped you out I hope I
gave you a lot of options the last part
of the email says could you also point
me in the direction of where to find a
grow a grow Kashi bucket or how to make
one yes they are easy to search for on
Amazon but you have to search for a bo
khosh eb o ka shi bo khosh e compost kit
there 49.99 on Amazon which is a very
reasonable price I grow stores they're
closer to 60 because they know they can
mark that [ __ ] up on you so a bo khosh e
bucket just go search for bo khosh e on
amazon it should come up also when you
type in bo khosh e type in bo khosh e
bucket DIY it'll show you how to do it
yourself it's super simple here's a very
quick basic rundown
how to do it and I'm just doing this by
looking at the Bokashi bucket both on my
counter a few feet away from me and in
this picture here on Amazon you're gonna
need a five-gallon bucket you're going
to need another bucket it can either be
a three or a five as long as it's about
the same diameter as the other bucket
it's going to kind of work as a lid for
the other bucket and it's also gonna
have a lid on it so it needs to get a
lid on it and also be about the same
size so two five-gallon buckets or a
five and a three or near the same
diameter um the five-gallon bucket you
will put a hole near the bottom they
will have a spigot in this is where you
will drain it so you've got your five
gallon bucket with the drain toward the
bottom so that you could drain it now
you take your three gallon bucket and
poke some holes in the bottom of that
now you throw all of your [ __ ] into the
three gallon bucket you add your bow
kocchi activator which you'll have to
order also you need some bocaj your grow
Kashi bio activator they just need a
little bit of it to get it started so
you put some you've got your three
gallon bucket with holes in it I put
down a layer of newspaper just a stop
shift from falling through the holes
once it builds up the moisture will poke
through the paper and you'll be able to
drain it properly and it will slow down
any debris from falling through and
clogging up your spigot so you got a
five gallon bucket with a spigot on it
then you've got aa three gallon bucket
with holes in it then you put a layer of
one sheet of newspaper on top of the
holes then you put your food waste I put
all my vegetable scraps in there my
avocado seeds the shells from my
avocados the ends for my tomatoes the
ends from the carrots leftover salads
whatever like that [ __ ] any vegetables
or fruit the ends of the strawberries
the ends of the watermelons it all goes
in the book ah she bucket so I put about
an inch or two inches worth of food
waste in there and then I sprinkle a
handful of the activator on there so
you'll have the five gallon bucket then
you set the three gallon bucket inside
of it do the paper put the food waste in
there sprinkle the bio activator on
there and seal the lid and every time
you have I would save up the scraps in a
bowl I don't open it every time because
it starts to [ __ ] stink and oxygen
does not help you want to keep the
oxygen you want to keep this thing
sealed up so I keep all my food scraps
in a bowl kind of near the bucket and
then when the bowl starts getting full I
peel off the
I throw in a bowl full of food scraps
and then I put in a sprinkle just a
little sprinkle a nice little layer of
the activator and then I seal it back up
and then after about 10 to 15 Dasia so
you can days ish
you can usually start opening the spigot
and draining out a little bit of the
juice I could probably open it right now
and get half a mason jar full of just
disgusting juice out of that thing and
that's called leachate and it is high in
a lot of things Sean and Jessi tell me
it's mostly lactic acid bacteria I've
noticed that it really works like it
works like an enzyme would work for your
plants I've noticed when I recycled soil
I used to do a lot of soil recycling if
I would put the lactic acid bacteria I
would dilute it heavily and put the
lactic acid bacteria in there those old
roots would really decay much more
quickly so I think it helps speed up the
decay of dying in dead matter and also
I've used it to unclog shower drains and
sink drains and I've noticed that when
you pour it down the drain it leaves the
chrome super shiny so it's got to be
doing something I removes dead and dying
organic matter very well and when you
feed it to your plants when you just mix
a little bit of in with the with your
regular basic feed or with your making a
tea or whatever the plants [ __ ] love
it the roots go crazy so it's definitely
a good thing to add to your lineup and
once again you can get it at amazon.com
just go to Amazon and search for the BOK
a shi Bo kashi compost kit the base
model for 49.99 it looks like it even
comes with the bag of the activator you
get the cool little rake to match the
[ __ ] down because you want to push down
the stuff inside there and then it comes
with some instructions man just be
prepared it [ __ ] stinks when you
crack it open when you go mashing the
stuff down in there to make room to ever
squeeze the air out oh it stinks
it will run everybody out of the house
so you may want to do it outside if you
make your own make sure it doesn't leak
because when it starts to drip in that
juice that juice will stink forever
forget it on your hands your hands will
stink for ever all right I'm gonna press
pause I'm gonna take a quick drink and
then I'm gonna read another email that
kind of goes along with this one because
it talks about scrog
all right podcaster old I am back and I
am well hydrated I am well dabbed and
now
time to get to this next email this one
comes from our friend dank mile and it
goes like this
what's up Rasta last episode you spoke
on scroggins Evy foliated I have limited
space with the screen of green method
but one of the first things that I
noticed was how limited your your
mobility can be especially in the middle
of the canopy I was wondering if you
could go more into depth on how you
would advise someone to defoliate four
five by five by five canopies in a
rather tight 12 by 12 grow room I love
the show I haven't missed any of your
new episodes since I started listening a
couple years back
I've ran a five pack of black cherry Kim
and have found a keeper that's very
impressive
Khem dominant with plush berry coming
through in the bag appeal if you ever
come to the Midwest cup I'll show you
some samples take it easy
dank mile alright there are some great
talking points in this email so let's
start with the defoliating yes when you
were doing a screen of green method I
recommend heavy defoliation I take off a
lot of leaves if you look at my pictures
from the commercial grow you'll notice
that we make them naked when it comes
trim time there's not a lot of big fan
leaf to take off because I've already
taken it off by week six so I do
recommend heavy defoliating you've got
limited space I understand that I work
in a room that has 24 tables and they've
got about a foot of square of extra
footage on each side of me total around
the entire room there's 12 inches of
extra space I would say it's maybe 18
inches I can walk through there but
there's 18 inches of extra space so I've
got to slide the plants the trays apart
gonna walk in there I got a water gotta
slide them back together it is a pain in
the ass so I know what you're dealing
with ah the way to do it I catch myself
laying on my back inside of a tray I
catch myself just crawling like a monkey
under there however I can I'm 6 foot 5
so I can reach quite aways I can reach
all the way to the center of that canopy
but sometimes I can't get to the other
side of a tray so I will literally lay
on my back and wiggle army crawl
underneath the canopy and get to what I
need to get to the only way to do it is
just get in there and do it but I'll be
very careful if you've got to crawl on
the ground crawl on the ground you got
to get down there and climb up in the
tables climb up in the tables just be
careful not to [ __ ] anything up but
that's the only way to do it is just get
in there and do it it's a pain in the
ass I know and it's really frustrating
so tight just put on some good music get
in the right headspace and go in there
and just get it done bro it's the only
way you can do it it's the only way it's
gonna happen is if you get in there and
pull those leaves yourself I've spent an
entire eight-hour shift just pulling
leaves by myself in one room so get in
there do it you got four tables man it
won't be that hard it will take that
long and it will improve the quality of
your product it will allow for more
light penetration it'll prevent bugs
it'll prevent pests it'll prevent molds
it'll just help you out overall so
getting there just pull them off that's
all you can do just stretch get taller I
guess or climb up right in there it's
always fun when you walk into the grow
and you find me I'm six and a half feet
tall you guys like seriously I'm 6 foot
5 and 200 pounds my wingspan is super
long you'll find me just curled up
underneath the table just picking leaves
I think it's hilarious all right I want
to keep going with the email he goes on
to say I love the show I haven't missed
any of your new episodes since I started
listening a couple years back that's
awesome man thanks for the dedication I
appreciate that I hope you're also
enjoying the throwback Thursday episodes
those are for the guys like you that
missed all that old stuff you keep going
and you say I ran a five pack of black
cherry Kim and found it keeper man
that's some old school stuff I haven't
grown or made black cherry Kim in a
really long time so if you've got that
keeper keep it do not let go of it there
are no more seeds I will not make more
seeds of that I don't have more seeds of
it that is something that is in my past
so hang on to that don't let it go it's
cool to chew on that's Kim dominant with
plush berry through the bag appeal
that's pretty cool a lot of them came
out either really purple or really green
it sounds like you got one kind of in
the middle that's pretty cool and if I
do ever come to the Midwest cup I'd love
to see some samples also if you're ever
in Colorado I would love to see your
samples dank Miley I hope I helped you
out I know I told you pretty much just
reach in there and do it
but that's the only way you can do it
bro unless you can get yourself one of
those mechanical arms remember when
you're a kid you had that thing the fake
hand you could squeeze it and it was
like a claw give him one of those and
get in there and pick leaves with that
but honestly the best way is just shimmy
on up the table crawl underneath the
screen get him in or just defoliate by
hand that's how I do it all right Nick
Mile thanks again for the email ladies
and gentlemen if you'd like to send me
an email I would love to hear from you
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I will read your messages on an upcoming
episode alright ladies and gentlemen
I've been going
for just over 35 minutes and when I go
by myself my voice tends to burn out a
little bit I can already feel it doing
it so instead of making you guys listen
into an episode where I'm just clearing
my throat and sounding like [ __ ] I'm
gonna say thank you for listening I'm
gonna remind you to stalk me on social
media I would love it if you follow me
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast on
Facebook you can search for the growth
from your heart podcast if you would
love to see my cannabis photography I
put a lot of work into my cannabis
photography I've recently learned that I
love taking pictures as much as I love
growing and smoking cannabis I love
taking pictures of the plants I grow as
much as I love growing it as much as I
love consuming it as part of the passion
for me
I checked me out it's IRA underscore
genetics on Instagram I RIE underscore
genetics on Instagram that's my seed
company
it's my Instagram page check it out I'm
sure you'd love my photography also let
me remind you again about patreon
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
if you're interested in supporting the
podcast I would truly appreciate it
ladies and gentlemen I think that's all
I've got for you this week I'm gonna
wrap it up I want to give a huge shout
out to my friend Toni T and New Mexico
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
he says one thing the changes are my
mystery baby boy field I
to go
[Music]
but she can't be equal but you can try
she confusing me I don't know what you
think what you do to me first you treat
me like a king and then she through with
me but truly I give her loving every day
cuz it's my duty even if she kind of
moody tries to make you a key
[Music]
make everything new
every little thing she does his magic
it's tragic trying to keep up with there
is the day to daily task it seems like
I've got folk girls and one she's cranky
and mean but crazy and fun I don't know
which said I'm I see is this your
reality is when you would be always
switching personality but it's worth the
risk
I keep a Hershey kiss because chocolate
is the key to her heart
[Music]
it's not always easy but she's your best
friend you don't try so hard
when you think you have to make you down
it's not a game that you can win
[Music]
some denim
you
[Music]