hey what's up podcast world it's Rasta
Jeff and it's Thursday so that means
it's time for another throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast this time I'm posting episode 66
67 68 69 and 70 of the girl from Earhart
podcast if you're new to the show let me
explain what I'm doing a lot of
listeners have been asking for the old
episodes a lot of the old episodes have
really detailed grow lessons and there's
an episode where I schedule a perpetual
grow there's an episode where I talk
about drying and cheering buds a lot of
the good stuff is in the old episodes
when I first started and a lot of those
episodes have fallen out of the feed
iTunes and stitcher only holds 100
episodes this will be episode 226 so
that means there are a hundred and
twenty-six episodes that have fallen out
of iTunes I wanted to put them back
somehow but I figured that every time I
put in a new episode a new one falls
right out so I'm doing 3-hour chunks of
episodes 3 hours is about as long as my
recording software wants to handle 3
hours seems to be about the biggest file
you guys can download into your phones
without messing up your data plans so
I'm doing 3-hour chunks of old episodes
that puts usually 3 to 5 episodes in a
block that way you guys can hear the old
gems and then I can continue to put out
old stuff on Thursdays new stuff on
Mondays and everybody gets old content
and new content and you can get all
caught up
also I'm posting the old videos to
YouTube I'm making videos as I go along
I am up to number 65 now so if you want
to check them out on YouTube number one
through 65 is available on the grill
from your heart podcast youtube channel
also let me do a quick disclaimer before
we get into the episodes if I mention
any advertising and he promos and he
giveaways any contests anything like
that that has long expired all of that
stuff is done there are no giveaways
there are no promos there are no
contests right now nothing's going on
also the social media has changed if you
want to send me an email the new email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com on twitter it's at g f YH
podcast on facebook it is girl from your
heart podcast and if you want to find me
on instagram its Irie underscore
genetics ir i underscore genetics I read
genetics is of course my seed company my
breeding program I check that out on
Instagram I would appreciate it ladies
and gentlemen I feel like I've been
rambling for a long time I hope this
made some sense to you
with no further ado here's a
throwbackthursday chunk of old episodes
of the girl from your heart podcast
here's episode 65 no you know what I
[ __ ] up I said the wrong numbers it's
66 67 68 69 and 70
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 66 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker for a hardcore
gabber if your cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host Rasta jeff thanks again for joining
me I need to send a huge thank you shout
out to the mystic roots man for letting
me use their music on the show
big thanks to Kat Keith and the entire
mystic roots crew you guys i'm company
with a solo episode gonna talk all about
my cannabis prep experience over the
weekend but before we get that far this
podcast is brought to you by hi girl
indoor growing supplies hi girl indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or check out the
Pueblo location on 618 East 4th Street
in beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
put your favorite nutrients at Highgrove
indoor growing supplies also when you
check out a hydro tell them you listen
to the girl from your heart podcast and
they will give you commercial pricing on
your entire purchase the organic
portions of this episode are brought to
you by my great friends at the Rocky
Mountain warm company visit the rocky
mount warm company in Colorado Springs
for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments the Rocky
Mountain worm company has dragonfly
earth medicine products in stock right
now the Rocky Mountain worm company will
ship to your door you can get the same
warm castings that I use and many of the
same immittance amendments that I use
through the Rocky Mountain worm
company.com website check that out today
if you visit the store at 4:11 Tijuana
Street let them know you listen the girl
from your art podcast all right I think
that's enough fads for today much love
and much respect all the sponsors for
making the show possible if you're
interested in sponsoring the show please
send me an email it's girl from your
heart at hotmail.com
I'll get you all of the information that
you need all right I do have one more
important thing before we get to my
cannabis cup review the growers meeting
I've been hyping up this big growers
meeting at high girl indoor growing
supplies I'm a dick because
have to announce right now that the
growing meeting the Gerber's meeting
hydro indoor growing supplies has been
postponed it will not be April 26 as
I've said before we're working on a new
date I apologize this is beyond my
control this is not me I am only the
messenger here there's a lot going on
that I'm not even sure about why it's
been changed exactly there are a lot of
circumstances so it's me on my control
to be on Jessie's control we all
apologize but the growers meeting of
hydro indoor growing supplies has been
cancelled or postponed is a better word
so until you hear another date I
apologize
I sincerely apologize I was looking
forward to meeting you I had some [ __ ]
written down either way I did write some
stuff that I want to talk about on the
podcast in a future episode so I said
we're gonna talk about grow room
scheduling like planning out a routine
and a pattern for your room so that you
can have a productive room I'm still
gonna write that out completely well and
we'll talk about that on the podcast
anyway highly distracting to me we'll
just lower that good enough there we go
alright I took a bunch of notes because
it was a long weekend I want to try to
cover a few things excuse me I'm burping
so the cannabis cup was Saturday Sunday
and Monday in Denver at a place called
the Denver Mart it's off of 50th in
Washington or off of 58th Street 925
it's at 50th in Washington was where
most of the action was um there was no
there was a lot of parking but it was
all [ __ ] a [ __ ] it cost 30
bucks to park in most places so let me
back up we'll talk about Friday night um
cuz Friday nights when it all kind of
started for me you guys heard about my
Morgan heritage concert adventure and
then Thursday I went and got stoned with
the reggae bands and hydrorite
so that was the last episode so I left
you guys off on Thursday Friday night I
packed up headed to Denver the weather
was terrible it rained the entire drive
to Denver that's a 125 miles it took me
close to two and a half hours just to
get to the south end of Denver I drove
to garden of Weeden had a Airbnb spot
just outs
of Boulder I was almost a boulder
honestly I was in Louisville Colorado
there's a gorgeous little beat air B&amp;B
house that they got there sweet score
but it's kind of far out of the way for
me anyway I drove out there I got dabbed
out with some of the crew from garden of
Weeden I wanted to meet up with those
guys hang out with them on a Friday
night which I'm glad I did because
they've been busy as [ __ ] since then so
I hung out with the garden of Weeden
crew then I headed back to the hotel
like I kind of hungry got kind of tired
so I headed back to the hotel my hotel
super cozy I was glad I got that room
that I got it was cheap so I was a
little questioning I was kind of
questioning on what how it was gonna be
as affordable and it was cozy it was a
great room for one guy that was a little
bed a couch a desk a TV I barely turned
on the TV used as a nightlight mainly I
got some pizza delivered and I went to
sleep I said I hate the [ __ ] out of some
pizza some local pizza that was around
there and they know what to sleep
Saturday morning woke up early too I get
to the cup around 9:00
that's about 8:30 8:45 when I got to the
cup the parking lots were starting to
get full already but there was one spot
I found it was open right away right
near the gate it cost me 30 bucks to
park about 30 feet from the gate that I
needed to use so I parked my car I got
myself organized they headed into the
cup is about 9:00 I had a vendor
wristband so I was able to get in before
everybody else the event doesn't open
till noon
having the vendor wristband really
helped me out I got in at 9:00 I was
gonna need to see the cannabis cup come
together when I walked in I was just a
bunch of empty spaces with square booths
and a bunch of walkways on the people
were emptying everything out of boxes
and everyone was all frantic and moving
around I wasn't the smoke fest that you
guys saw that everybody that went there
saw it was chaos people look stressed as
[ __ ] so anyway by noon the place was
packed and jumpin I got an early
I immediately started linking up with
people that I know there were it only
took me a few seconds to walk in and see
people that I know also I need to give a
big shout out to Robert and Anita I
don't know if they listened to the
podcast or not but I have some friends
that are local friends I bumped into so
there's a big-ass line outside the cup
right and there was a vendor entrance
and I just walked right in it nobody
asked me for any credentials I never
showed a wristband I never showed her an
idea never showed a ticket I walked
right in that son of a [ __ ]
where I passed everybody right into the
thing house in the cannabis cup at 9:00
a.m. while everybody else is waiting in
line and so uh I'm a kind guy had bumped
into Robert and Anita while I was in
line or while I was walking from the car
I saw them they were going to actually
use a porta potti and I thought well
should I saw my friends I should call
them and tell them about this so I
invited them to come join me and I met
them over by another area there's inside
the event and then they walked around
with me for a little while and hung out
so that was fun yeah so big shout out to
Robert and Anita for keeping me company
for the first part of the morning there
that was kind of fun actually
I knew a lot of people there at the cup
and they kind of got annoyed that every
10 feet we would walk somebody would
bump into me and take a picture with us
and hang out them they wanted to go
cannabis cup so they ditched me what
should they didn't really teach me they
told me they were taking off which was
cool so Robert had fun left me wandering
around for myself for a little while I
bumped into so many people actually I
went to a booth I was looking to dab I
wanted a dad and I ran into Johnny be
from no goon on stick and he had a cool
booth and he said what's up and his crew
said hi to me in at the back of their
booth they shared a booth with some
other people and these fellers ah man I
feel like a dick right now because there
were two brothers that look for
Fairley's very very similar
I got him confused multiple times I
learned him by the end of the weekend
but one dude's name was Ari and there's
a brother with dreadlocks and there was
another guy that looked very much like
Ari they gave me you can hear the
parchment paper right now they gave me a
little everyone's given out their
shatter in these little envelopes these
little I think they used to be for coin
trading these little coin envelopes this
one is labeled MOT extractions cheesenut
run one gram so they gave me this and
I've still got quite a bit of it left
all I'm gonna do right now for you guys
for MOT extractions I'm gonna take a dab
of this cheesenut run honestly I already
know that I love it but I wanna take a
dab of it until you oh that's deep here
we go take this medium sized dab on the
show here we'll talk about some MOT
extractions nut rod
this is the first ad that I took at the
Cannabis Cup so this was how I walked
into the cup this is what I was
introduced with so I'm gonna take it all
right I took a nice chunky size dad
wasn't too ridiculous good and chunky
though there's a good dab
there's no cough so talk about the
flavor the flavor is very smooth it
doesn't taste like cheese to me or the
stream the cheese I get kind of uh
there's some sweetness to it there's a
little bit of funk to it you know the
cheese is setting it now that it's a
draw my tongue is kind of absorbing it a
little the cottonmouth thing is kicking
in I gotta take a drink by the way
excuse me hold on okay there's
definitely the hint of the cheese in
there a little funk a little sour I like
it I'm definitely gonna smoke the rest
of this grand that they gave me I
approve you guys it tastes good I got a
nice mellow indica hi my eyes got a
droopy the appearance it's super clear
it's right between shatter and snap you
know I've had it for several days here
it was in my car for a day and it's
still stable that still looks good I
approve you guys I will give a positive
thumbs up shout out this is Rasta Jeff
approved MOT extractions cheesenut Ron
so check those guys out final on
Instagram or something I will after the
show I'll follow you guys after the show
now that I approve of your product they
were super kind of me
big shout out for all the morning dabs
so let me find my notes I took here I
honestly have notes because I'm trying
to cover all this stuff so we got there
oh so yeah here we go eventually I
bumped into my friend Jay what's up Jay
I hope you're listening with this
episode
shout out to at dreadful Jan Instagram
that's my buddy there one of my best
friends everybody thought that was my
girlfriend
ah no offense to Jay she's not my
girlfriend that's just like when my best
friends ah and she lives with Cali and I
live in Colorado so she can really you
know that'd be awkward to have a
girlfriend so far away and honestly if
she stays my friend we'll be best
friends forever so we can't [ __ ] that up
anyway shout out to Jay eventually I
bumped into her bumped into her [ __ ] she
ran from across the cup and tackled
hugged me she jumped up and watched up
onto me and gave me the biggest we just
haven't seen her in a year so it's great
to get that hug what's up mom I miss you
already
Phil have been gone for a few days so uh
Jan I raised the cup for most of the
first day together I walked around
selling seeds I took a box of seeds and
I weren't I read genetics t-shirt and
put my dreadlocks down and just walk
with my box of seeds and I sold plenty
of packs of seeds that was kind of nice
I did spend some time at the sour seeds
it's shout-out to Rob at the sour seed
Co shout out to rusty a can of pitcher
the first day I spent some time at that
booth it was great but honestly I had
more seed sales by walking around and I
got to see more people so I've been in
the booths idea and just went and
mingled it was a great time so I also
got a lot of compliments on the podcast
that was really cool I expected more
reaction to the seeds and whatnot I
thought people would be more interested
in my beans but a lot of people knew who
I was because of the podcast so it's
gonna neat that this podcast has reached
the same amount of notoriety as the seed
company or am i I'm not even using the
notes anymore I'm just [ __ ] rambling
just tell you the trees trying to talk
about my show talk about my experience
on the show on the podcast cannabis cup
it got cold yes that's where I was it
got [ __ ] cold you guys all weekend
the weather kept changing so we got cold
this is Saturday night so I headed back
to the hotel room to warm up get some
food I had some of that pizza that I had
left over from the night before that was
pretty big delicious I actually took a
couple fatty dabs and fell asleep for a
couple hours cuz I got a sunburn I was
up early but after that I woke up and I
headed to a private party there was a
private party outside the oriental
theater and so we weren't able to smoke
in the theatre I never even made it
inside the theater honestly it was loud
as [ __ ] and crowded but we weren't able
to smoke in there because the fire
department the police and the meed were
all doing random inspections on clubs
that weekend to see who was smoking cuz
they knew people are gonna be smoking in
clubs and it's illegal to smoke in
places so we weren't allowed to smoke in
there so we found a way around it and
I guess since the party's over excuse me
I'm burping I guess since the party's
over I could blow up the spot this is
how we did it outside the theater these
people Park to tour buses one of the
tour buses had a private party and since
the bus is private nobody can come in
and tell us that we can't smoke there if
the cops aren't even welcome on the bus
without a warrant or unless a crime
happens in there the fire department has
no damn reason and the meed is
definitely not coming on a private tour
bus so some of our friends I don't wanna
see their names have a big shout out for
you guys listen to this show that was
[ __ ] smooth of you to pull it off that
way they set up tour buses and we just
went up on the tour buses you had to be
kind of invited yet didn't know it was
up i got a facebook in a text message
saying hey bro this is where we are
we're on these buses so it up on the bus
dabbed out in one there's a bongo these
one party one tour bus who set up like a
party bus there's a bond going around
people were serving drinks there's a
full-on DJ that was pretty dank the
other bus the other bus was being used
for a private breeders only seed swap
type of efan I got to go there and meet
a bunch of breeders a lot of like Dark
Horse genetics was in there the guy that
just bread the cherry Afghan man I wish
we could remember your name smell
delicious bro that guy was in there a
lot of people were in there so people
are swapping seeds and there's a little
seed sales going on in there
that was great but he got kind of late I
got to give some of my seats to some
really respectful people mr. spliff of
cannabis has some our mr. spliff of now
he's of gauge green but mr. spliff has
some of my US beans now he'll be doing
that stuff I got late so I went back to
my hotel to gear up for gate day two
because this was only the first day of
the copy guys I get to meet up with a
lot of people I get to hang out tasks
Rock I don't want to list all the people
that I saw because I will forget more
people than I remember it was a huge
weekend and I got a sunburn
I got dabbed out and I recently had a
head injury and I feel like I don't
remember as much [ __ ] as I should but uh
for Sunday I slept in a little because
it wore myself out Saturday I definitely
was exhausted I slept in a little I
headed to the cup around lunchtime I got
smart Oh to the grocery store and got a
bunch of fruit and since I had the
vendor wristband I was able to take some
fruit and some healthy drinks into my
backpack with me and sneak those inside
didn't have a security thing to go
through
all the normal people had to go through
security I got the little VIP vendor
pass no I just got to walk right past
all that [ __ ] that was awesome
so do that dab is working by the way
that she's definitely kicking in with me
so I had some food it took me about an
hour to park that day from the time I
got you know what before I got to the
58th Street exit traffic was already
backed up on the exit and it took me 15
minutes to get from the exit to the
parking areas and then I had to drive
around for another 20 or 30 to find a
parking spot and the parking cost me 20
or 30 bucks each day so I got into the
cup I wandered around and then
eventually I bumped into Jay again ah
her and I walked around the cup and
bumped into a bunch of friends until we
decided we needed some serious dabs at
the Cannabis Cup you think there's a lot
of places to hang out and take some dabs
but there was really not a lot of comfy
places to just chill out and smoke there
are some VIP areas and [ __ ] but they
fill up quickly so my friend Jay and I
Julie
we found a loading dock area and we made
a little area for ourselves and got
comfy there and just dabbed out and took
a bunch of selfies and had a good time
for a few so sunday was a really fun day
it was more relaxing Saturday Saturday
was kind of crowded it's gonna hustle
and bustle II cuz everyone's trying to
meet up with all their friends it's like
the first day of school I haven't seen a
lot of those people in close to a year
if not a year so I was mostly pumping in
her friends and hanging out with Jay
until the evening when we headed to the
award ceremony let's see there's a
three-day event so I'm confused by that
I get [ __ ] up on that all the time
usually you do the awards at the last
day but they didn't which we'll talk
about something on that also so until
the awards ceremony the highlight of my
day was probably hanging out and eating
lunch with Addison de Moura the lines
were really long and all the food trucks
but there's one food truck that serves
organic gluten-free food and it's funny
because there's chicken legs hot dogs
burgers french fries all kinds of food
trucks right and then in the middle
there's this one little blue baby blue
food truck that sells salads for nine
bucks I got a salad with some chopped up
strawberries and some blueberries and
some fruit that I couldn't identify it
was delicious I mean it was good I just
don't know what the hell it was and then
in the bottom there were chunks
of feta and then every time I stirred it
I found another layer of goodness in
there but there was honey all over it
for dressing I was nine bucks but that
was like the most uh most edible stuff
I'm a vegetarian and I try to eat well
so I was the most edible stuff there so
that wine was to people long there's two
people in front of me and I had my food
in less than like five minutes Jay
wanted some food from another car and
she waited in line for the entire time
that I was in line plus the time that I
ate my food plus a little bit longer
some people walked by and saw me at a
table and I was sitting at a table where
four people could fit they saw me there
by myself know like hey dude can we eat
with you and as like well [ __ ] yeah you
got plenty of time and those people ate
their meals cleaned up after themselves
shook my hand said goodbye and took off
before Jay even got her food that's how
long some of the food lines were ah so
since I'm sitting by the organic food
truck eating my food my buddy Addison
tomorrow walked up and sat down and
ordered food at the food truck and then
after that he came and sat down with me
and I think having lunch with that he
might have been my highlight of my
afternoon up until the award ceremony
Addison is a busy man and it seems like
everybody at the Cannabis Cup knew him
so getting an hour out of his life for
him to just sit down and hang out not
talk business to just be my bro for an
hour and hang out ketchup was really an
honor so shout out to Addison I hope you
get to hear this bro so after a bunch of
dabs with Addison and dab so hard and
Julie joined us at the table we made
another friend at the table too I cannot
remember her name her name might have
been Elise yeah was her name was Elise
she was a medical cannabis user and she
uses cannabis for several reasons and
she was just waiting for her friend and
lion also so she sat down and ate with
me and said she ate with me when she was
done I gave her some dabs just like the
rest of the truth she really appreciated
it I misjudged that lady she was I don't
even want to guess how old she was older
than me and she seemed all nice and kind
but she took a dad like a [ __ ]
champion I should have given her larger
dabs
it's pretty funny so after the a bunch
of dabs and she was time for the award
ceremony the award ceremony was really
neat it's kind of like the first award
they made a mistake they announced the
third place is the first place in the
first place is the third place and it
was always already chaos but that's how
High Times likes to do [ __ ]
so they finally got their [ __ ] together
Vader won the first three awards we'll
talk about that in a minute but one
thing that really stood out to me was
when High Times brought out two members
of the Jamaican ganja Farmers
Association one guy was he had short
hair and wore a jacket and then the
other guy was taller and had dreadlocks
to his ass and he was the representative
of the Rasta community and these guys
spoke about legalization in Jamaica and
they announced that the high times would
be hosting a cannabis cup on the island
of Jamaica in November so I'm thinking
about going but honestly I don't know if
I want to travel to Jamaica for a
cannabis cup it might not be the most
financially sound idea but I'll think
about it
in a lot of things I'm thinking about
one thing I thought was funny when the
Jamaican came out the Jamaican guy the
Rasta started speaking he said greetings
in the name of the Most High his
Imperial Majesty King Haile Selassie I
had the first jaw and all of the Rastas
in the room yield Rastafari and a guy
behind me bumped his buddy on the
shoulder and said what did he just say
and I jokingly turned back and politely
said he said hello I thought it was
pretty funny because the dude behind me
had no idea what this little Rasta man
just said so I was really excited to see
a Rasta man come out it's a cannabis cup
and tell me that there's gonna be a
cannabis cup in Jamaica in November that
was kind of neat just to see some true
Rastas come on get to celebrate
Rastafari at the Cannabis Cup was nice
also so let's talk about the awards here
we go I'm proud as [ __ ] to announce that
Spencer and Maddy from the garden of
Weeden won first place for best CBD
concentrate at the Cannabis Cup that's
it that means that means we've had a
cannabis cup winner on this podcast now
yeah the first female to come to record
at my house and be on the podcast is
also a cannabis cup winner in the CBD
extract category I'm proud of [ __ ] for
my crew to tell you the truth I had that
head wound right I didn't feel good for
a few days and I went to spence's to go
kick back just to get away and he had
just made the cup entry and he's like
try this dog
my CBD entry and I hid it and it tasted
like I just bit into oranges it tastes
like I had a mouthful of delicious sweet
oranges but I'm drooling now and I kind
of want an orange because of this but
and I blew it out and I had had a
concussion and it felt like I had a belt
tied around my head I feel like just
pressure around my head when I blew out
this dab it felt like you undid the belt
a couple of notches and he gave me a
couple of more tabs and I looked at him
and I was like bro I am the most
comfortable right now that I have been
in several days because I was in pain
and my head hurt and I wasn't feeling
right then those dabs like sent me right
dude and he told me he said you look
like you're the best you've been in a
few days like I guess people could
physically see that I didn't feel good I
didn't realize I was showing it but
those dads were amazing they definitely
helped me out so big shout out to Spence
big shout out to Maddie much love to the
entire squad at the garden of Weeden Big
Mike song sloppy everybody so rockin
Donna everybody over there I love all
you guys I'm super [ __ ] proud of you
guys haven't had a chance to visit them
since the Cannabis Cup victory but I'm
sure I'll get him on the show Spence if
you're listening bro you know you gotta
come be on the podcast I haven't even
bothered them about you guys because
it's only been a few days after the cup
everyone's just getting home getting
back to our normal routines getting our
dogs loved on getting our plants caught
up catching up with all of our friends
here back where we live and [ __ ] so I'll
get them on the show I will get them on
the show the second place in the same
category I'm kind of proud of this went
to our friends Joey and Shelley at
natural mystic cannabis caregivers in
Colorado Springs with their CBD entry I
have it on a screen far away here
I'm gonna tell you what they entered I'm
gonna press pause for a second I'm gonna
pull up the winners and like computers
kind of far out of reach all right I got
the article here sorry I had to reach
for it the second-place winner in the
best CBD concentrate went to natural
mystic cannabis caregivers with their
canna tonic which actually is a great
strain if you listen to the episode I
did with Angela about CBD medicine
catatonic might have been the culprit
there that was the high CBD medicine so
big shadow to natural mystic cannabis
caregivers I'll tell you the third place
since we're on the whole category
it was industrial hemp CBD extract with
oh that looks crazy dude
it's I so I so deal I so D all si and it
looks like it doesn't look like any
cannabis product ever it looks like
white powdery substance is that I don't
even want to tell you what it looks like
it looks like drugs dude if you showed
up with that they put that on my table I
tell you to [ __ ] leave that's funny
alright so big shout out to Joey and
Shelly at the natural mystic cannabis
caregivers also I need to give a huge
big shout out to my friend Noah at
champion cannabis let's see what they
actually call themselves I know they go
by champion cannabis but their
dispensary one is a different name I'm
scrolling up through that this article
is long let's see do you just want me to
read all of them let's see we're just
gonna go through and read all of the
winners of the 2015 high times us
cannabis cup and dead for here it goes
I'm gonna go kind of quickly best
colorado sativa flower first place ghost
train haze from green man cannabis
second place sweet silver haze from
Rocky Mountain High third place Pootie
Tang from Star buds and I'm reading this
all off the High Times website so if
anything goes wrong excuse me it's on
them best the us sativa flower first
place ghost train haze number 13
Greenway Las Vegas that's my friend Noah
shout out to Noah champion cannabis
Greenway Las Vegas we'll hear more of
that more of them as we go through these
winners so second place veganic
Strawberry Cough private stock four buds
and roses of LA yes my friend Noah
beat the [ __ ] out of Kyle kushman in the
cannabis cup right there that's what
that means
Cushman's second place my buddy Noah
first place third place was Krista Green
crack run by Christopher Stine then
we're gonna move on to the best colorado
indica flowers first place louis xiii
from green man cannabis
second place Colorado Bubba from ahem MJ
America the boulder location in third
place black fire from Doc's apothecary
in collaboration with the ethos
collective big shout out to the ethos
collective check those guys out on
Instagram everything they do looks like
fire the best us indica flower first
place granddaddy perps from herbal
healing second place kosher cush from
green wolf LA with cushko third place da
vinci OG from green wolf la with ghost
crow then we're gonna move on to best
colorado hybrid flower they did two
categories here you keep me say colorado
and us the u.s. means the whole united
states and Colorado was limited to
Colorado dispensaries is how I heard it
explained so the best Colorado hybrid
flower was first place Kong from all
greens huge shout out to Jessica that
was grown by a beautiful female make
sure you follow her on Instagram it's at
miss green thumb that's a friend of mine
she is an awesome grower proven by her
Cup win right here second place
Starkiller from Green Man cannabis third
place o gkb cookies from nmj america
downtown OG kb cookies is a killer
strain the shot of it hit on this
website is amazing let's see we're
moving on to best us hybrid flower first
place TST cookies from Green Wolf and
top shelf Terps that photo of that butt
is nice second place Cali Kush farms
Emperor cookie dough from Green wolf la
where the webpage go
oh it's refreshing here we go third
place mega wellness OG from the weed the
Wellness earth energy dispensary in with
nameless genetics alright that's a long
title there so we'll move on to best
sativa concentrate first place lemon no
strawberry lemonade live resident bike
rocket family farms by dabble Isha's
extracts so it means Crockett grew that
that's the strawberry lemon-aid live
resin you guys we've talked about that
on the show that is the stuff if you're
looking for Terps second place
wonderland live resident green wolf LA
with dabble Isha's Crockett family farms
and GC rebellion farms that's a huge
collaboration third place tangey number
17 from Gold Coast extracts now we're
gonna move on to best indica
concentrates the first-place crown og
from green wolf la nature's lab extracts
and crown og
second place space Valley og fresh
frozen from pink house with Incredibles
third place cush company og live
resident batter cush company with
nature's lab extracts and weed Studio
City that's a long title the picture
that one looks crazy it looks like um it
looks like a piece of sponge ah best
hybrid concentrate first place goes to B
mega wellness OG nameless genetics with
the weed of Studio City second place
goes to crown oh gee crumble dream wolf
la nature's lab extracts crown OG a
third place Skywalker og cush from dab
Vader Vader extracts the best
non-solvent hash first place
cookies-and-cream cuban tech to dry sift
by exotic genetics you guys to the best
of my knowledge that was blasted by a
beautiful woman and shout out to cuban
tech that dudes cool as [ __ ] shadow to
the dreadlocks a second place strawberry
banana land one 2273 you yeah we'll
explain that on another episode trichome
heavy extracts with GC rebellion farms
green wolf la and DNA third place Kimbo
cush cuban tech dry sift cuban hash
queen with exotic genetics that's uh
another extract ran by a lady right
there the best edible bubba kush root
beer 100 milligram from Keef Cola
signature now I find it weird that
Keith's Cola was a sponsor and also won
first place I don't think that that's
[ __ ] fair at all to tell you the truth
you shouldn't be able to enter and be a
sponsor as my opinion second place ask
God Oh bar from Incredibles that's
actually a hell of a product I promote
that eat that tastes good you'll be hi I
approve Rasta Jeff approved a third
place orange creamsicle cream pop from
secret sweets and trichome heavy
extracts in a collaboration effort with
DNA I did not get to try that but I have
had other sacred sweets products and
they're always delicious they put out
some stars
awesome Star of David shape products
that are amazing I have proof best
topical angel selves
champion cannabis with Evo lab so those
are my friends from Las Vegas they're
second place high gasm Genesis compound
and essences high gasm the product
packages they show here
show that it's an edible personal
lubricant there is one package that says
hi gasm and the package has a green logo
and it doesn't have a flavor there's one
next to it that is yellow or with the
yellow highlighted pack label and it is
labeled [ __ ] Oh nut Co CK - OH - nut
[ __ ] Oh nut the one the third product is
labeled high gasm the flavor the label
is a little bit purplish and the flavor
is blueberry so these are flavored
edible personal lubricants that are
infused with cannabis so that's our
second place winner the third place
winner was Floria guys we talked about
Floria on a previous episode that the
packaging says pleasure with an so best
CBD flower was tora bora from MMJ
america - great strain i grow the shoot
out of Tora Bora a second place the net
how did the Nubia from aficionado
freeborn selections third place sleeping
giant from Elemental seeds and then this
is where we move on to best CBD
concentrate we've been here before first
place Oh G tonic from the smokers club
in collaboration with the garden of
Weeden the smokers Club was the sponsor
the garden of Weeden was the grower and
the extractor that was all done by
spence matty and the garden of Weeden -
big shout out to those guys again
so proud of you guys so awesome that
they live in my neighborhood they put
this little town on the map
they've only lived in Colorado for two
years they're from North Carolina they
came here with the mission and they're
[ __ ] killing it so second place was
canna tonic from natural mystic cannabis
care givers if you have to go to a
dispensary for CBD medicine
I either recommend the green and healthy
well are green and healthy cannabis or
natural mystic cannabis caregivers
there's the only two spots that syndra -
they're both medical shops those are the
only places to go - we talked about the
third place that is industrial hemp CBD
extract so then we move on to best CBD
edible I had the honor of meeting the
guy from foxtrax
Fox extracts this dude made a 160
milligrams banana pudding bar in
collaboration with shoe melt and it won
first place in the best CBD edible and
dude I eat three squares of that thing
and it's 160 milligrams
eight we're not even gonna do too much
that's twenty forty sixty eight sixty
milligrams of that thing and I was high
I was pretty high from that thing I
wasn't like high I was like rubbery and
relax that was quiet and mellow for most
of the afternoon
maybe that's why Saturday was so mellow
for me so the second place was rocky CBD
and rich premium protein bar from TC
labs and TC treats the third place was
cherry drops teacher from Great Lakes
hemp supplements so it goes on to best
booth first place Vader extracts second
place rx green solution and the ethos
collective third place the green
solution best product Moxie mix from
Vader extract second place Cloud V third
place oil slingshot the oil slick for my
sweet new hat and a pretty cool looking
the oil slick at Anu happy and I like it
best glass was from Qbert and Vader
extract second place mothership third
place hitman glass best vape 7/10
kingpin Cloud V third place incredible
milkshake machine there are a few more
things what do we have People's Choice
flowers Cindy white from the green
solution
second place Grizz cush from native
roots third place bubba kush from the
clinic Colorado I've smoked that that's
a great flower People's Choice
concentrates Sour Diesel shatter took
first place from the green solution
second place kosher cush live resin
butter from the clinic I bet that's
delicious because they'd love they're
kosher cush ah third place orange Hara
wanna shatter from native roots
apothecary so guys those are all of the
winners from the 2015 high times us
cannabis cup thanks for letting me read
all those to you took me a minute and I
stumbled a lot but I hope you
appreciated it because I just totally
got sidetracked don't like thirty five
minutes into this podcast when I fix
this microphone so it'll quit wobbling
to my phone we could really do a lot
more business with this show here we go
was delicious it's not only did it wreck
me but it was amazingly delicious if
they gave me a bunch of those and just
set it next to me I would be really high
because they taste too good to stop
eating so shout outs all my friends they
got cannabis cups shout to everybody
that want a cannabis cup yeah I'm proud
of you guys it's great to be
my cup winners so after the cup Sunday I
was treated to a super tasty dinner at
the yard house with a few friends the
yard house is on the 16th Street Mall in
Denver go there you guys it's a super
tasty place the vibe is pretty cool I'll
definitely go back there for sure I had
a pizza from there and I also had the
angel hair pasta meal from there it was
super dank my friend Dean is a heathen
I'm just picking on him I love you guys
don't worry I don't judge
he had a burger and dude it looked
amazing that burger was like a foot tall
off the plate I don't know how that dude
was able to eat that looked good so
let's talk about something that I found
kind of disrespectful at the Cannabis
Cup a company called Vader won several
awards they won the first three awards
that were given away at the cup they had
a huge set up at the they had a place
called invader village in the cannabis
cup is a huge setup with a stage they
had live musical acts they had semi
famous celebrities at the booths all day
my friend had a bill was they're
launching prizes into the crowd he had
the t-shirt gun the t-shirt cannon he
would fill it up with packages of
shatter and launch and joints and bags
of weed and launch bags of weed and
shatter and joints into the crowd of
people people would go nuts and get it
so they win best booth they want all
kinds of prizes right this is Saturday
night the cup happens Sunday or Monday
this is Sunday night when they win
everything
Monday is 4/20 everyone smoked right we
show up for the cup Vader village is
gone they have taken down their entire
booth tore down everything the [ __ ] down
they want several awards and they packed
up at night while everyone was asleep
and they took off Monday before the
couple open at noon and that just seems
disrespectful to me like if you're gonna
come to a competition if you're gonna
come to an event and you're gonna build
a big-ass stage and make a big spectacle
then you win hang out for the last day
and play with all the cool kids don't be
a dick and leave I just found that
disrespectful that's not even my event
whatever I found that rude so congrats
on all your wins Vader but that was not
a classy move to do that um so let's
move on a little bit this leads me into
Monday
my name is day three of the cannabis cup
monday was 4/20 in the place was super
the weather had been sketchy all weekend
so at some points I was wearing a
t-shirt and I was sweating and then
other times I was had a hoodie on with
my hood up and I was freezing so the
weather was super sketchy Monday had a
nice break in the weather so it felt
like everybody showed up for the last
part of the day like around 3 o'clock he
got pretty nice the place was stupid
crowded for 4:20 on 4/20 at 4:20 it was
crazy but I got there around lunchtime I
milled around said goodbye to everyone
that I hung out with because I I only
see a lot of these people once a year
you know all these seed companies all my
friends from the internet we only need
up like once a year because this is
where everybody is Booth's picked up a
couple of pieces of merchandise
surprisingly the only thing I really
bought oh man I gotta give a huge shout
out did I write this down this is all my
other notes so I'll skip that for a
minute
I got more notes to read hang out with
Addison engage green mister spliff saw a
lot of people so a lot of cool ass
people so I can't really describe it
it's kind of like a State Fair or any
other trade show but had the best
cannabis and extracts on the planet and
then a thousand of your favorite friends
that's kind of what the cup is like
shout out to Aaron Brooks I almost
forgot that one I did not write that
down I was great to see you there that
was a pleasant surprise check out Aaron
Brooks he's an artist he doesn't eat
[ __ ] so that was Monday at the Cannabis
Cup after the cup I headed to the Mellow
Mushroom to meet up with a few friends
of mine because Doug Benson was in town
doing a comedy show at Comedy Works
recording his next comedy special that
he has titled
what the hell did he call it promotional
tool as the name of his new album and I
got to see him record that I've kind of
got some hookups at the comedy work so I
might have been sitting right in the
front row big shout at the comedy works
for that shout out to Baker for the
whole Comedy Works crew for treating me
like royalty every time I go there so
I'm gonna leave you guys off on my
cannabis cup recap by saying that
it's a great time it was great seeing
everybody dude if I got to see you there
thanks for shaking my hand thanks for
walking up to me thanks for talking to
me thanks for meeting me I have a couple
of gifts here that I should talk about
but uh I'm gonna wrap up this part and
we're gonna move on to a couple of the
things my friend Clint that has been on
the show is going to show up tomorrow
night and record with me and we will
talk about our experience at the Doug
Benson comedy show and we'll also talk
about a we saw Greg Proops record a
podcast Wednesday night at comedy works
and we also got to hang out with Greg
Proops and in guy OB Lum after the show
so we'll talk about that with Clint on
the next episode let's see I gotta jump
back to the note so don't skip anything
but I think the next part that I want to
do is I'm gonna do a couple shout outs
so Josh my friend Josh won second place
in the Adam Dunn show Invitational which
was kind of a private grow competition
Josh did huge shot I don't know if you
listen to the episode or the podcast
like every episode religiously but when
he finally do hear this cuz I'm sure
you're behind when you finally hear this
dude huge shout-out and congrats for
winning if they hadn't done show he took
second place which is huge is his first
competition he's ever entered and he
took second place so you know the dudes
killing it I'm proud of him he should be
proud of himself
let's see shout out to Josh we got that
covered Oh take dabs and review them see
that's the part I'm excited about
sometimes it pays to be Rasta Jeff and
have a little podcast because while I
was at the Cannabis Cup somebody walked
up to me and this happened two days in a
row he walked up to me and he handed me
these little packages and it says
electrum extracts I'm just gonna pull
this hard to read so I can see it it
says electrum extracts and you unfold it
on the other side it says lemon
sometimes banana cush contains 100%
organic cannabis whole plant extracted
via n butane and propane mix in a
closed-loop extraction system and as
Instagram check this out as electrum
extracts elec TR um extracts on
instagram then it says not for use by
children so what he gave me here he
handed me some butane hash oil my
favorite thing some BHO some dabs bro
and what he said was I want you to try
this on
so and let me know what you think so
here we go
I'm going to try the lemon skunk banana
Kush I'm reaching for all my tools right
now cleaning off the carb cap unwrapping
the parchments a nice friendly portion
he gave me - I've already dabbed a few
dabs I don't remember what it would have
weighed but I'm gonna take a
decent-sized dab here and then we'll
talk about it there we go this is
electrum extracts but lemons banana dab
with me if you've got some dabs dab with
me come on let's do this here we go
three two one dab
it tastes good in the weigh-in usually
you don't taste good smoke until the way
out that's a citrusy and lemony on the
way in all right I definitely taste the
lemons I don't taste the banana pushcart
but I taste the lemon spunk for sure and
here's something I noticed a lot of
these lemon skunk strains I've got a
lemon skunk plant that I bred to the
golden goat made lemon Geoffrey when I
make dabs out of the lemon skunk or the
lemon Geoffrey it makes my eyes bounce
up and down a little bit for a second
like you're dry it when you're driving
down it a [ __ ] up graded dirt road and
your eyes just go this lemons got banana
cush dab just made my eyes do that so
that's cool I like that that's a good
sativa high from that I approve man it's
a big shout out to electrum extracts I
do approve of your product that is good
[ __ ] yeah get that take dad's of that if
that's available somewhere I want some
more of that lemons got banana cush
that's tasty bro good work thanks for
giving me that I appreciate that he's
like my friend said you had a podcast I
should give this to you please review it
so I did that it's awesome she works out
sometimes when you're hasta Jeff another
one - should we try it on the show I
think we should have be silly not to
right here we go this one is rare
dankness sativa blend so this one's just
gonna be straight ahead Ripper
I haven't tried this one yet unfolding
it looking at it it's gonna sappy it
stick into the parchment a little more
than the other one did oh but it's got a
nice amber e color to it let's see I'm
smelling it off the parchment
it's an odd flavor kind of a lime more
line than what I'm used to
in cannabis oh that's a big dad okay
we're out of this so we're gonna take a
DAB once again guys join me hope you got
a DAB this is the sativa blend cannabis
this is whole plant extract it via so a
whole plant does that mean that you just
Chuck the cut the buds off the sticks
and do like fan leaves and nugs all at
once I've done that at school it comes
out great I like to do that with my CBD
medicine so you get that full spectrum
just curious with that a whole plant
they're hinting out there all right guys
here we go that lime flavor catches me
but this one's good oh it's the team of
two cuz my head is just like that I love
that feeling yeah okay definitely both
of those were smooth both of them had a
nice texture both more well done there's
too much of a lime flavor on this rare
dankness one for me but it's just a
personal thing but overall that's a
great hash both of these are great the
only the only reason I don't give this
one a perfect 10 is cuz the wine thing
is not my flavor the orange flavored one
or the lemon flavoured one wins so I do
give you a thumbs up on both of these
overall electrum extracts you guys win
dude shoutout I like it alright took
care of that thank you guys for giving
me hash oh you guys get me hash that's
super cool I love when people walk up to
me and give me stuff makes me feel great
talk about the edibles I ate oh yeah so
I went to a comedy show and I was gonna
talk about that more but I want to give
a shadow I'm thinking about it when I
saw Doug Benson Monday night on my way
into the show I had a Claudia berry
because my friend Claude the Candyman
from sweet stone can be shout out make
sure you check out sweets no candy
Claude gave me a banana Claudie bear it
was dipped in chocolate and if you know
me you know I freaking love banana and
you also know that I love chocolate so a
hundred milligram edible dipped it was
banana flavored dipped in chocolate was
the perfect [ __ ] gift for me so shout
out to Claude shout out the sweets no
candy that edible worked
I was super stoned and super smiley for
the whole comedy show that was great so
Wednesday night I saw Greg Proops and I
ate a 100 milligram watermelon candy for
a dull use in only it says indica on it
it says contains two pieces at 50
milligrams each and you know what these
guys didn't do bro they did not put any
sort of branding on here but you know if
they did hit me up on Instagram so we're
gonna hit Instagram right quick we're
gonna see if I have the message where he
asked me if I ate the edible yet his
name is Ryan is made of cannabis on
Instagram so this dude game is edible
and it's a Lego man it was actually two
Lego man 50 milligrams each and I eat
both of them we were at dinner at the
mellow mushroom and I tore him open
walls waiting for the pizza to come and
ate these suckers um I usually don't eat
gummies just because of I'm just a picky
sucker when it comes to my diet
these are pretty good they were not bad
at all the watermelon candy flavor was
pretty pretty damn good and I liked him
and I was definitely high for the whole
comedy show I smiled like a child for
the whole show so big shout out to Ryan
is made of cannabis big thanks through
the edibles that you gave me dude that
was awesome I appreciate it very very
much I've got a TD we're going like 47
minutes we're gonna have to wrap this up
guys the next episode will be Clint and
I talking about the comedy shows that we
have recently gone to I am working on
the grow room scheduled episode that I
prepared for hydros meeting which is not
happening I should mention that again
guys 47 minutes in the meeting and hydro
and heroic supplies has been postponed
to a better time we will let you know
when the better time is there's a lot
going on got to do that in the future
we'll have another episode on improving
your crop real soon we'll also have a
with Jesse doing outdoor stuff and more
organics with Shaun so let's get some
shoutouts done and let's get out of here
pretty soon I owe a big shot at to
Danielle I owe a huge shout-out to Julie
what's up Jules thanks for hanging out
with me at the cup also a huge shot at
to Dean also shot to Kelso Marley also
everyone who complimented on the podcast
at the Cannabis Cup also everybody who
walked up and gave me a high-five shook
my hand gave me a hug any sort of
compliment all of you people that said
what's up at the Cannabis Cup I
appreciate all of you
big thanks to oil slick for the sweet
new hat that looks fresh on me also SoCo
glass so your huge shout out for the
sick new Pandey thanks a lot brother
this thing looks really stylee it
matches my new hat it works perfectly
thanks to task rock for the hookups and
the conversation I got a sweet new nail
it works great I freaking love it
thanks to High Times thanks to Danny
Danko thanks to Bobby black thanks to
everybody from High Times I'm gonna skip
a lot of buddy there a lot of people
there a dance guy drawn a complete
[ __ ] blank on Mike's name Mike Mike
from the podcast Mike Hughes jeez I'm
sorry dude I can't believe I just forgot
your name shout out to Mike Hughes I
feel like a dick yeah everybody from the
cannabis cup everybody be cleaned up
after us that place was a mess next time
you guys pick up four pieces of trash if
they're yours or not also I met a ton of
cool people tons of cool people but and
this is serious some of the coolest
folks that I met or my friends decent
gore also known as Bryan and Jan I was a
pleasure to meet both you guys and I
wish you a beautiful future together
there are my friends from a chatroom
oddly enough
and I've never met them in person but I
met them in person for the very first
time at the canvas cup and they were
cooler than I ever expected or could
have imagined guys it's been 49 minutes
I need to wrap this up and get out of
here you get a TV about now thanks for
listening I'll be back in just a few
days with clay we'll throw out a
Wednesday episode see how you guys are
doing I don't forget to check out the
sponsors Rocky Mountain warm company and
hydro indoor growing supplies also check
out nature's green remedies dot-com if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you
like me to review send it to me or send
me an email from Merida
mail.com we'll get you all the
information you need if you have
something you'd like to say find me on a
social media it's a Twitter as @g fyh
podcast there's a Facebook just search
for girl from your heart podcast if you
don't want to be on the social media you
can send me an email it's girl from your
heart at hotmail.com don't forget to the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode will always be
archived on ira genetics Colorado comm
don't forget I added a donation button
to the podcast page if you feel like
this show is worth a few bucks
you can go to my website I read genetics
Colorado comm stick on the girl from
your heart podcast tab at the top right
there's a donation button with a little
PayPal logo that goes directly to my
PayPal account
I'll never charge you anything for this
podcast it is free but if you feel like
making a contribution I would greatly
appreciate once again a huge shout out
to my ninja Spence thanks for listening
until next time you guys take a fat dab
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 67 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation professional grower if
you're a new smoker or hardcore camera
if your cannabis activists even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you thank you joining me I'm
your host Rasta Jeff as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to the
mystic roots fan for let them use their
music on the show
big thanks to Kat - and the entire
mystic roots crew what's up guys I'm
sitting at the table with my good buddy
I'm hanging out man I'm gonna turn down
that music that's gonna loud in the
headphones there yeah we're good we're
good
I love the reggae real loud in the year
if it's too loud you're too old y'all
yeah you can turn down the volume on
your phone this podcast is brought to
you by my friends at hydro indoor
growing supplies hi girl and her growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store 60 to 71
Beach Street or check out the pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street and
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out hi
girls for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
get your favorite nutrients at high grow
indoor growing supplies big shout out to
burn and Jessie well your hydro make
sure you let them know you listen to the
girl from your heart podcast and they
will give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that's a sweet hookup
the organic portions of this podcasters
are brought to you by my friends at the
rocky mountain worm company visit the
rocky mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments the Rocky
Mountain worm company has dragonfly
earth medicine products in stock right
now the Rocky Mountain worm company will
ship to your door you can get the same
worm castings that I use in my garden
and many of the same amendments that I
use through www.rockymountainatvmc.com
ake sure you tell them you heard about
them through the podcast big shout out
to Jay also a big shout out to nature's
green remedies dot-com thanks for their
support all the time
I don't have a coupon code for you this
month much respect all the sponsors to
make the show possible if one of you are
interested in sponsoring the podcast
send me an email
girl from your heart at hotmail.com I'll
get you all the information that you
need
so Clinton back is stable he got himself
some water he got me some water I
appreciate it
Clinton I had the pleasure to go to a
couple of comedy shows over the past
week coming out a couple weeks yes put
it on a Wednesday this will be like the
first or the 29th or something of me I
feel it hey everybody uh just so you
know Mother's Day May 10th there you go
don't [ __ ] forget your mug for me as
Mother's Day by the [ __ ] and flowers
that's right I'm just thinking ahead
yes I'm helping out every single one of
us donor boys it's like oh [ __ ] I forgot
I'm trying to at least maybe you guys
already have a good heads up dude this
will be out before Mother's Day you guys
don't forget don't [ __ ] it up love your
mama it's where you came from as my
sponsor is your mom is Mother's Day and
we get to brag yeah what we're doing May
10th bro
I dunno what we're doing May template
and I will be seeing Doug Benson hosting
his podcast Doug loves movies at Comedy
Works my favorite comedy club on the
damn planet the only comedy club that's
worth the [ __ ] we go to will be worth a
[ __ ] and then we'll talk now I love to
Denver improv so I have to back that
place that was sweet Comedy Works is my
favorite comedy club on the planet that
I've ever been to it's awesome it's
amazing we could see Doug Benson there
maintains recording his podcast doubles
movies Doug loves movies yes if you guys
are into Doug Benson check that out I do
need to give you a quick apology sorry
about the growers meeting I had very
short notice that that was not gonna
happen the growers meaning didn't happen
if you guys showed up I'm in my house
right now it's the time of the meeting
we're here recording taking dad's is
about 7 10
yeah this is when the meeting should be
happening but I got a free time some
free time so we came here and recorded a
podcast I apologize I don't work for hi
girl I was just simply trying to help
them out I was advertising I don't know
what happened I don't know why they
couldn't do it I hope everything is cool
with those guys I love them big shout
out to burn everybody in hi grow burnin
Jessie
I apologize we'll get another meeting
together it will happen I won't do this
to you guys again let's get on with what
we were saying Doug Benson we get to see
him May 10th I'm gonna start it off by
saying this I really hope he does a
better show than he did when we saw him
Monday night yeah dude that was we we
went up I took a buddy of mine Jeff came
up as well and then so shoutouts my
buddy drew cuz he'll be listening dude
shoutout to my friend Danielle that's
right I ended up realizing I had a
plus-one available for the comedy show
and I called her about two and a half
hours before the show and I said if you
can get your cute little ass to Denver
the pueblos from Pueblo to the
restaurant where we're all gonna eat I
will order you food and have a plate of
food waiting for you by the time you get
there you can grub down and we got to
get to the show and I told her please be
here by this time and she made it five
minutes or later yeah shout out to a
girl that got ready got herself
beautiful and drove to Denver in two and
a half hours ladies possible you can do
it I'm proud of you so big shout out
today I appreciate it I'm glad you got
to come to the show with this so and
also shout out to your friend that you
brought with us man yeah I got to meet
him and he seems like a fun guy we have
common friends so we're definitely too
but it's the same thing as like I just
wore one degree of separation from
everybody one degree of Kevin Bacon from
every single truth that's the truth
so shout out to Drew's good meeting you
bro glad to meet you were definitely
gonna hang out take some dabs together I
saw the picture of Drew's car ride home
bro well fortunately was after the show
we got to the car
do you did pass the [ __ ] out and it was
hilarious to watch like he kept like
trying to like lay over on to me as I'm
driving I kept up and like shoving back
like get over the batter finish the job
you started your front yours car has got
those pink couch seats so I'm sure
you're just thinking he's cuddle up on
the couch with you that's that is the
most comfortable seats you've ever
ridden I don't know about that it's
pretty comfortable his car is a boat you
guys is good you could go on a cruise in
Clint's car that's right everybody
coming out for the cruise will be going
mate and we were front row we were front
row to the mushroom and Kelso Marley
right we've made friends with this
lovely waitress at the mellow mushroom
she is a fellow grower she's an extract
artist she has a [ __ ] cool dog named
Zephyr yeah so shout out to Kelso shout
out shout out to Zephyr she told me that
they listen to the podcast so they're
checking it out she's she's not only an
awesome waitress but she's a cool lady
I've been talking to her on Instagram
and whatnot she seems like great chicks
oh yeah check out that mellow mushroom -
that place is delicious yeah Clint's a
carnivore the carnivorous meat-eating
freak over there and I am a scrawny
[ __ ] hippy vegetarian they have a meal
on that menu for everybody yep I'm
completely satisfied Clint is satisfied
we sit across the table from each other
and belittle each other's food you
should feed my
[Music]
now we can go on to the Doug Benson part
we all shout out to Baker Baker and
Comedy Works also yeah I happen to have
some VIP preferred seating status at
Comedy Works as long as I let them know
I'm coming in advance they will get me
some VIP seats so we saw Doug Benson
we were front [ __ ] row for Doug
Benson yeah it was great got to see him
record his comedy special it was the
third time they had done that show that
night so we'll get on with that in a
second um the show opened with Graham
Elwood how did you feel about Graham
Elwood Duhamel what was one of the
funniest guys I've seen in a long time
now I was really [ __ ] high school I
don't remember a lot of what he said and
I would zone out like he'd go on some
rant and I just start zoning out [ __ ]
high as [ __ ] just like man it would be
cool to see like what the inside of a
rainbow looks like he was still talking
about something like like his kid or
something like that's something happy
and I just went to the extra happy place
I guess I looked over a couple times
yeah I can tell you were zoned out oh
yeah
so grab Mel woods hilarious you guys
he's got a fake band known as the
whistling Bane's he's on a lot of
podcasts if you listen to that Doug
Benson podcast you will hear some grand
Melwood he's also got his own podcast
called the comedy film nerds Graham
actually invited me to the LA pod fest
in Los Angeles and he told me that there
is a big room where you can set up and
everybody records their podcast out
there and he said that if I come he
would be on my show and he shook my hand
so if I make it to LA pod fast pod fest
you guys will hear Graham Elwood on the
podcast that would be [ __ ] cool he
was he was a really nice guy I know that
I can't keep it in check tonight I've
said the f-bomb probably 15 times
already yeah
but but Graham amazed me because he was
funny and he was clean which is hard to
do so like just more props to him he was
really funny if he would ever listen to
this I hope he would hear us say that uh
he was the best part of that night
because Doug Benson came on after him
and Doug first thing he said he goes uh
I woke up this morning I started smoking
this was on 4/20 yeah this was on 4/20
so let's yeah let's remind the people
that yeah so he woke up he started
smoking he did a 420 show up til he was
he was smoking up until then he just
kept smoking all day and that was the
first thing he said is like he did all
he could do to make it to where he
couldn't make it to that last show his
goal was to be too high to record that
show I think he succeeded you know I've
seen I've gotten Doug Benson high
several times and I've never seen him
that high I got high like bragging but
I'm kind of not bros with internet
buddies with Twitter friends with Doug
we're talking [ __ ] some of the comedians
know who I am by now because I've gone
to enough shows so he'd relies on Ross
did you have to get him high before the
show he knows I've got some dank weed
and I'm not psycho so he hits me up he
hit me up to get him high what time I
got him high and he told me from the
stage he [ __ ] up a joke and looked at
me and said you got me too I bro yeah
that night he was three or four times
beyond that level of Highness he was he
was so [ __ ] skinny I'd [ __ ] you
could not see when I was anyone I was
always I think what I was working kind
of but it was it was [ __ ] I don't
know dude he was so baked that he just
he it just wasn't even that much fun he
kept putting his head on the microphone
you guys heard this sound a lot and that
was his head hitting the microphone so
that he could take a little break he was
I mean he was laughing at his own jokes
and there was some really hilarious [ __ ]
that he said he spent 30 minutes reading
[ __ ] tweets thank you the first 30
minutes of his show he read tweets which
he what the problem was that 30 minutes
was only divided up by like five tweets
yes it wasn't like a whole bunch of
tweets it was like five people that were
audacious enough to pull their phone out
in a comedy show
and send him a shout or and tweet it
right then yeah that's we're up front
row I can't do that grandma started me
because my phone was on my lap because
it's too big for my pocket I got this
iPhone six-plus my lap and gram kept
looking at it I felt like grandma would
looked at my phone twice like he's got
[Music]
grandma's checking it out literally on
he had to move the mic from his face and
yaw on stage performing his comedy
special so he actually said ah this is
my third time recording this and what I
want to do is make sure to get the jokes
that I didn't get perfect the last
couple of times no now don't don't let
me say anything other than I respect him
for being honest but I just didn't pay
to go see a guy just kind of muddle
through something right do you know what
I mean yeah when I go to see a concert I
don't want to watch Metallica do
soundcheck five times that would be well
I mean maybe I don't want to watch him
try to do some song they haven't done
right in a couple of weeks properly
we're gonna try it yeah three times yeah
I mean things I guess he did things
three times that day though he did a
couple of the bits twice because he
forgot he did one when he was doing a
bit fo yeah well it's because he broke
it off early in the first part he didn't
tell like the same part of the story
dude I don't remember how high were we
part of that was because he had a pocket
full of notes if it worked disheveled it
looked like it looks like your grandpa
had gone to Lowe's you know when grandpa
comes home from going out all day he's
got a pocketful of receipts and a couple
of breath mints and a [ __ ] toothpick
and like well he had there's like four
or five different colors of pieces of
paper in there there was a receipt for
Barnes and Noble in there that I could
see like I don't know if he had
scribbled on all of it but that's what
that's where his notes were
in that handful of grandpa is also the
name of my new metal band made it this
far into this podcast we salute you you
know we're probably not gonna be talking
too much about growing you could put
your notebook away there will be nothing
to write down notes right and then
that's where we were there yeah and then
he just and I think he needs glasses a
little bit because they were [ __ ]
closed locked up somebody threw a joint
on stage and it took him two minutes to
was waiting and if you've ever seen the
comedy works like stage it's well lit
and it's maybe the size of your kitchen
table yes it's not a big thing there was
nothing on the stage it's like a blue
carpet what did somebody say the floor
looked like somebody tweeted oh yeah or
a salon floor vacuumed beautifully it
was perfect anyway no but it was just
like 30 minutes on five tweets which was
kind of boring got into some other stuff
and then he tried to do like other
tweets or something like later in the
show didn't he wasn't he doing tweet
relief oh yeah he did a thing it's
watch this knot that is a game that he
plays on a show where he lets the
audience members select movies and then
he decides which one to watch but he was
too high to keep track of what the other
audience members were saying it was the
things called promotional tool and I
mean we we definitely felt like we got
used like a tool yeah it did it felt a
little like like you know what guys it
sucks to be you but this is what's
happening and maybe that's the way it
has to be I didn't want to be like that
was kind of [ __ ] whack for my twenty
bucks
well you went and hung out with Doug and
then me and my boy drew took off
yeah we were all stupidly enough there
were three car loads of people from
Pueblo with one or two people in each
car because we didn't plan I had come
from the cannabis cup you came up on
your own and then I invited Danielle
right after you left I was already in
monument by the time she had me up yeah
well she made it so I'm proud of her
super proud she made that but yes we all
had to get in separate cars so once we
linked up and talked about it it was
like yeah I felt like we kind of were
his guinea pigs
he saved the [ __ ] show Doug I'm not
being disrespectful to you but I just
feel like that third show man you were
too high and if I wasn't unlike a loyal
Doug fan so it's kind of neat for me to
see that like I've seen enough Doug
that's why I'm watching my friend do
comedy now whatever and I feel AP seats
and [ __ ] but if I was a normal civilian
listener I might not have been impressed
with that show well like I told you the
only interaction I've had with them is
just listening to Doug loves movies yeah
and so that's not a whole lot of Doug
that's a lot of everybody else right I
haven't watched Doug specials before
that was my first chance of seeing Doug
Benson and I was not impressed I've said
it on the podcast before that I think
maybe Doug's excessive cannabis use may
be slowing down his comedy and his
career and I think that our experience
solidifies my theory yeah yeah and that
sucks because cannabis shouldn't be used
as a slowing down it should be used as a
way to move yourself forward
well then real quick and then we didn't
bring this up before but when when there
was that he said we're all gonna go
smoke outside and I was like alright
cool
so we'll go smoke there was what like a
hundred people people I was like a
hundred people in that alleyway I don't
know if you guys have ever seen that
economy works alleyway but it's probably
30 feet wide
yeah well I'm just trying to give it a
little bit of practice and a person on
either side of the car yeah I guess all
right so so we'll say ten feet wide
maybe fifteen but there was there was
like 75 to honor people are a lot of
people in there um and and it started
feeling real bro II well while Doug was
smoking Doug could take a hit of a joint
and everybody would cheer for it yeah as
though he was like some hero like coming
home from war and this was his first
like step on American soil it was [ __ ]
it was just like yeah that's that's it
like we're doing it we're outside didn't
call it Rado doing it it was just like
no this is this isn't the attitude I
want to have around weed yeah yeah it
kind of wasn't it seemed like we were
taking tequila shots and everybody was
high-fiving shots yeah yeah that's how I
felt about it I'm glad that I didn't I
didn't stick around I have to get home I
was dying
actually Doug usually hangs out and
smokes with everybody but he uh he
smoked with a few people and then he
knows me so he actually turned to me and
he said hey Ross - Jeff how are you man
and how was your drive cuz he knows I
Drive far and when the crowd saw him
heard him address me they [ __ ]
separated and let him and I kind of hang
out and take some pictures and chill for
a minute
he shoots my head and left it just
wandered I was it yeah there was still a
lot of people there and he left so I saw
in guy Oh at that point I'm guy Oh bila
because if you know and guyot check him
out it's his name is a hardest bolts nga
I owe 420 at in jail in guy Oh 420 check
him out on Twitter he's the cannabis
activists he is a podcaster he's a he's
a comedian he's a jack-of-all-trades but
he's definitely a pot smoker and a pot
connoisseur so I bumped into a guy oh
we've been Twitter friends and whatnot
we've been in the same area same
industry for a long time but I finally
bumped into the dude and made friends
with them he followed me on Twitter he
followed
friend on Twitter and then I thought
that was the end of my meeting with an
guy oh I thought we had met and shook
hands and [ __ ]
so everybody went our separate ways
Clint drove home like you said because
he was tired yeah obviously drew needed
a nap he made it 30 minutes I made sure
Danielle got to her car safely and we
all headed back south to the lovely city
of Pueblo Tuesday I had to drive almost
all the way back I drove up to the north
end of Springs to meet up with some
friends for some food that we're leaving
back to Cali I got to introduce our
friend Danielle to our friend my friend
Jay
they've been Twitter and Instagram
friends for a long time they finally got
to meet up so I put them two chicks in a
parking lot let them hula-hoop together
for a minute it was re yeah you have to
make some friends out of those two shout
out to them two ladies so that was my
Tuesday then Wednesday Clint met me at
my house right around 4:20 ish and then
we boogied up to go see mr. Greg Proops
yo record the world's smartest podcast
check that one out it may lose some of
you guys some you guys may like it Clint
I could tell that it was a little bit
lost during the show yeah it was either
lost or it was just I don't know he gets
a little ratty you know how it is yeah
he calls that the boring preachy part of
his show that's a good portion of his
show apparently because uh there was a
lot of preachy parts there was some joke
parts at the start they just take a
little while he's got like a lot of
references and stuff that just it just
takes a while to get to things I'm more
of a you know let me hit you with the
left and a right black his comedy he's
doing he's a smart guy and I like the
guy and he's funny like some of the
jokes he had were really funny it just
takes a little while to get there but
he's I'm pretty sure he's like improving
all of that all of that Wednesday was
the podcast Thursday Friday and Saturday
he's doing stand-up which will be
completely different than what you saw
that's the thing is like improv is a
different thing to me you know what I
mean like I do stand-up I don't do
improv and it's nothing against improv I
just don't do it so I don't know those
skills like those guys are better at
many many things but I think just
getting to the joke and keeping people
laughing that's where stand-up reigns
right
keeping you engaged and stuff like that
now improv is kind of like well let's
try to figure out how do we get back to
this like neutral points or whatever so
that way we can make it funny in here
but those guys that's a challenge and a
half what the audience is a little bit
more gives you more leeway with that oh
yeah you know what I mean so maybe you
guys know in the podcast were giving him
more leeway than I was well I'm not
they're just for the funny I'm expecting
to be enlightened a little by Greg
educated slightly offended at some
points I know he's the thinking man's
comedian he you have to den he calls
himself the world's smartest man it's
not it's that's a joke that's just a but
it's smart dude he's a smart sucker and
he's been doing improv we you asked him
how long you've been doing comedy and he
just shook his head at you I think you
just wanted to say like longer than
you've been alive and that was what I
was but but and and I wasn't trying to
say it like oh how long you been
I was just wanted to ask him like well
how long you know this is like a goal of
mine to be you and he kind of did kind
of just dismiss me as though I was
saying like an [ __ ] but what I meant
like was all respect like if you'd like
I just I just want to know that there is
the possibility that in like you've been
doing this for 30 years that's what it
takes to get to you cool man
I'd love to yeah that's where I want to
be any guys he's the one from whose line
is it anyway
his name is show right whose line is it
anyway he's uh no offense to Greg but
he's probably the one that you call the
gay one yeah he's not he's got a
beautiful wife named Jennifer and he is
completely straight and he stands up for
women's rights it's just like I probably
wouldn't want to marry that guy nothing
else about that situation he wears a
suit all of the time he had a suit with
an kind of it it's a blueish jacket with
a purple shirt underneath it yo can he
had a purple hankie in one pocket and at
one point he pulled out a hankie out of
his jacket pocket to do a joke and the
hankie out of his pocket was perfectly
pressed and it was purple and it had
gold pinstriping on it dude his pocket
hanky was [ __ ]
like this dude is stylish from
head-to-toe his shoes were sharp the
only thing that shocked me about the man
was uh so we saw the comp we saw him
record a show while he's recording to
the show I look to the right and I see
an guy oh sitting backstage at Comedy
Works yeah so I was like we're gonna
hang out with some guy Olin Gregg watch
this so after the show we get bustle
doubt and after a couple of times of me
looking over at Clinton he's looking
like he's gonna fall asleep also shout
out to our friend Joe our friend Joe met
up with us we almost left Joe out sorry
about that Joe joined us for the comedy
show Joe had a great time Joe was a huge
Proops fan so uh I looked over in
Gregg's kind of far Clint's gonna fall
into sleep a couple of times and then
after the show we're looking for the
guys and we can't find him and a friend
of mine is like dude they're down here
in this area smokin just walk back there
and I walk back there and I could hear a
guy from a block away he's got a very
recognizable voice so we walk down the
stairs and they're just hanging out
smoking so and guy who greets me and
knew my name and then I introduced
myself to Greg Proops he sticks out his
hand we shake hands
I asked if we're interrupting they said
no I lit a joint that's just what I felt
like needed to happen hanging out with
these guys was the thing that shocked me
about Greg he smokes cigarettes I never
would have guessed Greg Proops smokes
cigarettes I don't know why he would
have thought that he was smarter than
that is that what you're saying I think
so yes nothing against you cigarette
smokers I know because I have just
recently finally got I quit my ecig to
I'm just doing weed now which you know
that's that's a good thing or a bad
thing well it's better for me but it
could also get me fired from a job oh
yeah Clint this is bobby mcgee here
[Music]
anyway no I understand cutting
cigarettes out his heart and but Greg
Proops doing it it just it was like wow
let's that was weird huh and it's stuck
too that's kind of it was so weird that
like I smell his cigarette worse than I
could smell all the dank around us
Shantanu and guy oh he pulled out some
tangi from cali doing it
steak and some flavor to it that tangi
was delicious I think it's a chance to
try ice melt it I was already too high
by the time he had pulled that out ice
melts it though I think my plant emoji
trumped it the Platinum OD was I gave
him the last of my platinum og that I
had with me and he looked quite
impressed with it he was he was a nice
guy too so and guy was a great dude that
is true we smoked with these guys for
like an hour and they were talking to us
not at us not about us like we were just
hanging out with normal people
at one point Greg Proops was telling a
baseball story go figure
if you know anything about proofs you
know he's a huge baseball fan and he was
talking about a player leading off of
first blade base in a celebration and in
the umpire yelled play ball and the guy
just stayed way off of first blade base
and so the first baseman reaches over
with the ball and tags him out and as he
talks about tagging about he damn near
punched me in the tape because he tagged
me out as like a physical act to show
what happened he was being cool story
was the Kansas City Royals own George
Brett for all the stoner [ __ ]
baseball that was the story you were
that we were being told 5,000 light up
on you - yeah yeah that's exactly
celebrating his 3,000 tip but so when
Proops was acting out the smack he
smacked me his buddy and I tried not to
light up like a schoolgirl because I was
stupid excited but I thought I was
pretty awesome
oops is one of my heroes he's a comedy
nerd and he's a comedy legend and I'm a
podcaster and he's got a great podcast
so something about Enys articulate and
he makes me speak and write better it
actually makes me more conscious of my
my vocabulary in my mouth when I'm
truckin when I'm not super dad down he's
uh he was really funny you know there
was some really funny parts to Doug too
though you know but you know between the
shows I I had a rough weekend because I
would say you know but grandma that was
my favorite Elwood Elwood Graham Elwood
Graham Elwood yes as I said yes just
like he said wasn't recorded or anything
wasn't anyway
Graham Graham
was my favorite of the little excursion
Clint is kind of ODA comedy show
you've got comedy blue balls right now
I'd assume mate it'll be fun come back
you know that would be nice
because I'd love to know who's gonna be
all that but I'm gonna have my tat or my
nametag ready there you go
I don't know if I want to take my old
I've got a nametag made guys if you
don't know what we're talking about when
you go see Doug Benson do Doug love
movies Doug loves movies you gotta take
a nametag with you I don't know if I
wanna take my old name tag or found a
print up a new one movies on May 10th
Joey Diaz coming up after that that's
June in June and then what else do we
have coming up Bryan Callen show Bryan
Callen I think it sounds like I'm going
to see Bryan Callen guys are gonna sort
of listen to more Bryan Callen Bryan oh
that's why the fighter and the kid right
yeah dude no it's it's it's gonna be fun
dude that's the thing it's just fun
going thing is like I'm not gonna
complain about this like these couple of
days cuz they were fun days and and it's
funny that I can still be a little bit
like it wasn't that great but we hung
out with groups and on Gayo for a
[ __ ] hour yeah for an hour and just
rates like bros yeah yeah so I don't
know what the hell I'm complaining about
and I could have probably smoked with
Doug I just didn't feel like copping in
that crowd yeah that was a big crowd but
we're gonna see Doug here in like two
weeks
so yeah everything's good man Mother's
Day guys have we mentioned the mother's
days 30 minutes ago all right 30 minutes
that's good anything else you want to
add about the the comedy shows before we
start wrapping it up and moving on to
different subjects
[Music]
again Comedy Works is one of the best
clubs if you haven't been there please
go check it out it doesn't matter who
you go see it's gonna be fun it's we
have great service there all the time
they got waitresses running all over the
place and with us you know we're doing
every Thursday down here in Pueblo so if
you want to see open mic comedy we're
still doing that every Thursday at the
rainbow at the rainbow hey guys I know I
keep talking about being VIP at Comedy
Works and they treat me like a pimp
they will treat you like a pimp as well
they treat everybody like a rockstar
there
I'm just six five with dreadlocks and
they recognize my high ass every time so
they remember me and I've made friends
we're coming back kind of you know
frequently yeah fairly frequent I bring
dank dank weed and I might smoke out in
the back every time with you who's never
really hung out with you out in public a
comedy show at the house though I don't
know if you do because I am you know I'm
just really hi plenty of people out
there in the mornings it was crazy this
this time in the mornings well I guess
you said that on the last podcast how
you talked about
yeah yeah just how busy this is how busy
yeah how many people are running around
there are thousands of people there I
never look for the official ticket sales
to see how many people were there
thousands there were people that I know
I'm good on that one but thanks there
are people that I did not get to see he
just tried to pass me a bowl of flowers
and I turned it down because flowers
really give me stupid bad cottonmouths
on the show I'll take a cab though so
you said Thursday's at the rainbow bar
there's the rainbow bar 9:00 p.m. come
check it out you know wild cousins just
trying to keep keep going you know it's
tough because we're not in the the big
city doing the the big boy shows now my
boy John bueno starting to take off he's
gonna he's really given 100% to it good
I really think that he's gonna be one of
the first guys out of Pueblo to really
cuz he's funny he's a good guy and he
wants it I saw his post about doing some
show where he's hosting it so I was
proud of him for that yeah I think he's
going up to Longmont to host some is
there a cover charge for your show on
Thursdays at the rainbow the rainbow is
free every free come see some free
comedy guys it's open mic errs but oh we
might get some weird [ __ ] here we should
be cool everything should have worked I
think everything's cool still happening
yeah yeah so uh those shows are gonna be
free welcome back part two because we
just recorded looks like everything
worked but uh I could tell the Garage
Band was pissed off at me for a second
there was an update on the computer and
everything's still kind of wonky but uh
so yeah I'm about to take this dab is
what I was gonna do the free shows
you'll see some open my cruiser
what type of cuckoo will we see if these
open mic events on a Thursday who do you
think will show up you know we got a lot
of guys myself I'm gonna get back after
it I took a little bit of a break but I
got to get back after it and then my boy
Paul Rizal is he's uh he's there every
Thursday really funny guy if you guys
listen to the episode 62 wild cousins he
was the
funny one yeah he was the funny one
that's looking for a dude to hook up
with do it I [ __ ] was funny
oh we had a good time he's really funny
John Beunos like I said really really
funny we got other guys coming through
sometimes it's brand new guys if you're
a brand new guy and you want to try
comedy there's no better place for a new
gal oh yeah please I'm sorry I meant
when I say dude
I mean guy and gal yes ex guy
I just mean anybody I really don't mean
it as like only guys can do whatever
weird I wish more ladies that come out
they don't they don't want to do it
anyway maybe I'm intimidating I'm six
foot five four foot dreadlocks just
Mother's Day Mother's Day yes he's
taking your mom out Instagram Twitter
it's at all Clint that's all Clint hi he
hasn't been posting a lot lately
[ __ ] yeah social media take some auto
your damn time I've noticed like I post
a lot and then I catch myself like COD
and on here for 30 minutes dude thank
you for coming to podcast yeah thanks
for hanging out with me at comedy shows
yeah thanks for all the shows we have
played together in the future
dude we have a lot of fun thanks to the
audience yeah team tall guy thanks to
the audience here that's think this one
was a little rambling
I apologize it was a lot of rambly but
sometimes you got to cut loose and have
a comedy show instead of all about
uptight weed I'm sure you guys are
getting a lot of weed anyway if you made
it this far
good job yeah yeah make sure you clean
the filters and air conditioners and
calibrate your pH meters there you go
that was some weed advice for the show
you did it we got some
man also make sure that they don't have
centipedes cuz those are guys thanks for
listening I'm gonna be back in a few
days with another episode I'm not sure
if it'll be I'm not sure if this came
out on a Wednesday or Monday so not sure
how this is gonna go we'll see how it
works I don't forget to check out the
sponsors Rocky Mountain worm company
hydro and our drawing supplies and
nature's green remedies comm trying to
come down to pueblos check out the
comedy shows at the rainbow bar on
Thursdays they're funny they're free and
they serve booze so if it's not funny to
Street bar go outside and smoke a fat
joint and then it'll be funny it'll be
great if you want to sponsor the podcast
if you have a product you'd like me to
review send me an e mails graph my heart
hotmail.com will get you all the
information you need don't forget to the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode will always and
forever be archived on I read genetics
Colorado comm also don't forget about
the donation button on top of the IRA
genetics Colorado comm website there's a
girl from your heart podcasts tab at the
top right there's a Pay Pal button click
right on there and you can make a
donation
I'll never charge you anything for the
podcast it's always gonna be free
because I love you but if you feel like
making a contribution I would appreciate
it and I'll say thank you on the show
what else do I want to say find me on
social media make sure you follow me on
Instagram it's a Tyree genetics once
again congrats in a big shout outs my
ninja spits thanks again for listening
until next time take the fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me put the hand
full of grandpa
[Music]
thanks for joining me as always I want
to send a big thank you shout out to the
mystic roots man for letting me use
their music on the show
big thanks to Kat and the entire mystic
[Music]
music I'm gonna do a lesson on grow room
scheduling well I've started working on
that and I have got a lot of information
before I get to that part I want to talk
about a couple of things I went and got
my medical marijuana card renewed a
couple of days ago music real quiet here
just start the show right now no ads
this time you guys no ads a quick show
at the hydro ordering supplies and super
huge shout out to Rocky Mountain warm
company and nature's green remedies
that's my ads for today I got a lot to
talk about
I got my medical marijuana card renewed
dude the process has gotten super simple
I pretty much called made an appointment
I showed up they got me in at my
scheduled appointment time that's the
first time that's ever happened at a
Medical Marijuana doctor ah they got me
in there I mean they got my it's a it's
not a license guys it's nobody here has
a marijuana license it's a medical
marijuana recommendation from a doctor
that's not a prescription it's not a
license so he writes out a
recommendation for you and then um you
know I was debating if I wanted to talk
about this or not on the table and the
doctor's office there's just a little
sign and it says increased black count
will require records and then there's a
dollar sign and then an amount of plants
and then another dollar sign and an
amount of plants and if you provide
records and you tell this doctor that
you were in need of a higher plant count
he will increase your plant count for a
small fee so if you're not a Colorado
resident and if you're not familiar with
all that that means is when you go to
this doctor when you get your medical
marijuana card
now allowed to grow six plants in your
private residence these doctors are now
able to write in recommendations that
you are able to grow more cannabis and
possess more cannabis than the original
six but to do that you've got to bring a
little bit of doctor note some sort of
history some sort of record saying that
something's wrong with you and you also
have to pay a fee so for a small fee I
walked out of there with a handsome
plant count I won't talk about the
numbers on the show I don't really have
a huge plant count I don't need that
many I just want it to be safe so and I
went for what he would give me just see
if he would do it and I got the highest
he offered there so that was super easy
I want to talk about the benefits of
doing that um the reason I did is
because of course I grow and I want to
keep my grow protected with my medical
marijuana card that allows me it gives
me a little bit more safety I feel like
and also the recreational shops are
really high priced if you were to buy a
gram of hash at a recreational shop it
would cost you probably twice as much as
it would at a medical shop so I keep my
medical marijuana privileges intact a
lot for that because sometimes I do run
out of shatter and I have to go I go to
green and healthy wellness and Colorado
Springs and I purchased grams of hash
from our friends hunt and the Jordans
and the John's a bit healthy walnut so
that's a good reason to keep my medical
marijuana card intact so I talked about
the benefits I talked about the process
and I talked about the cost I feel like
you cover the medical marijuana card
experience it was super easy this time
I'm not gonna say the doctor's name or
anything on the podcast but if you'd
like his information just email me it's
grow from a heart of hotmail.com and
I'll get you that doctor he is in Pueblo
Colorado so if you're looking for a
doctor in Pueblo I've got a
recommendation for you let's move on to
my next topic I really want to get to
the grow lesson but I've got a few
things written down that I want to cover
this is just kind of a personal thing I
keep seeing a lot of people talking
about the temperature of their email the
email is the little box that plugs into
the wall that's got a
an LED or an LCD display on there's
usually an LED right little LED light
display shows numbers and then it's got
an up-and-down switch on it you can make
the temperature hotter and cooler and
then the one I have actually has a USB
port in it so that you can charge your
iPhone or whatever kind of phone you got
on there but then it's got a little cord
that comes out and it attaches to the
nail and it heats up the nail 40 all the
time so that's the email then your dad
nail is always hot right is it
temperature on your nail does not match
what the numbers on that box say that's
what I'm trying to get to here that's
gonna be my point a lot of people say
they've seen pictures of my email and
right now it's flashing at 8:52 it's
jumping between 850 and 850 - and
honestly if you try to take a DAB with
that 852 degrees I feel like that'd be
too hot but that is not a representation
of degrees that is simply a setting on
the box I don't think that and maybe
there is one brand maybe one or two
brands that does this but I don't think
that that coil is sending the
temperature to that nail and all the way
back to there and telling it that it's
860 degrees that is more of a setting
like a like if you turn your volume on
your car stereo to 11 you're not putting
out 11 anything so you're just on 11 you
know that 11 is like I know that my car
stereo I can crank it up to about 28
before the subwoofer starts sounding
like complete crap so I know that 26 is
my ideal temp on my car stereo it
doesn't mean I'm putting out 26 anything
in particulars it's just the level where
it is and that's what I think your
emails are doing we have established
that the 816 I'm seeing on my screen
right now on my LED is actually a
frequency that is being put out and
that's what's being measured by that
number so you got to keep in mind that
that number has to travel all the way
down the cord and then it has to get to
the coil and that coil is the heating
part that coil has to heat whatever type
of nail you're using I'm using this new
highly educated
it's the email insert which one is it
it's got the name printed on it let me
read it
I knew the name until I started talking
it is the HED adapter so I'm using that
one so you've got to heat up this
barrel-shaped piece and then the head of
the nail heats up after that is the
heats gotta travel
for it to know what the exact heat is on
the head of that nail would be kind of
kind of ridiculous to ask of that device
so my point is that number doesn't match
that head of the nail guys that is a
frequency or a dial setting so when you
find the ideal number just remember that
ideal number and that's kind of where
you want to be you're not actually
getting at 856 degrees or I've seen some
of them said perfectly 710 because
people think that's the perfect temp the
number is not correlating to the nail
you guys so when you see my pictures in
a/c 850 quit bitching at me I think
that's my point here all right I have
another topic written down the next one
oh the pesticide issue man we talked
about this a little bit in a previous
episode I talked about some of the
dispensaries that got in trouble and I
saw a quick article scroll through my
phone here should've been a little more
prepared people are kind of upset about
this pesticide issue and here's what I
saw this was all over it was Oliver
social media websites today it says
pesticide violations were issued to the
following recreational marijuana grow
facilities and then it lists mindful
green solutions evolutionary Holdings
Green Cross Colorado MMJ America organic
greens altitude East treatments are Ino
and sweet leaf all violators were using
eagle 20 and petroleum-based fungicide
that is harmful to humans and animals
altitude each treatments was also using
mallet and habit both harmful to humans
and animals drink ross denver was also
using mallet many of these violations
are well known and then it goes on to
talk about a lot more stuff you know I
don't know the original source of that
because I've seen it cut and pasted on
so many different social media sites
that I don't know who to give credit to
that but uh these guys were spraying
Eagle 20 on plants and then selling
those buds to people and the weird part
here is MMJ America just won a cannabis
cup so what's going on with that these
guys are did they enter their Eagle 20
Laden buds into the cannabis cup or are
they growing separate cups or separate
crops and entering that and not even
giving the public a chance to go by that
because
suspect if that's what some of the shops
do so these plants have been taken off
the market those plants will never make
it to harvest and those buds will never
be sold to customers or patients but I'm
sure that there was medicine or product
that did make it out of the door and has
been treated with eagle 20 or whatever
else they were listening here that we
definitely should not be consuming if
this were to happen - if these were
tomatoes and they discovered that these
people had been spraying Tomatoes with
these products the tomato farmer or
distributor or whoever's in charge at
that point would have to go make some
sort of a press release and apologize
they'd have to be held accountable this
would have been a much larger deal if
this would have been another
agricultural product or a horticultural
product and what's ridiculous is the
cannabis industry makes so much money
that they should have been kind of on
top of this and been doing the right
thing anyway like we're getting a legal
cannabis here and then we're trying to
set the pace here and then they're gonna
go and do [ __ ] like this which really
puts I don't know kind of a black eye on
the legal cannabis industry I don't know
I think that the people that were a
leading industry should have been more
responsible with our industry all right
so I can't seem to not shop at those
stores or anything like that do what you
want to do but I would definitely pay
more attention to where my medicine is
coming from and I would pay more
attention to what's going in my medicine
all the more reason you guys to grow
your own cannabis that's my solution
that's what I think I've got a couple
more notes what else did I want to get
on to actually we're gonna let's just
get right to it I want to talk about
grow room scheduling you guys we're ten
minutes into the show already and I have
got a lot of notes here so this is
probably gonna end up taking us a couple
of episodes here honestly so we're gonna
get through the veg process today and
then the next lesson we'll be planning
your flowering cycles so I wrote a whole
bunch of stuff and honestly it took me a
little bit to get this together because
I and I'm gonna apologize right now I
know that the last few episodes have
been a little wonky I seriously had a
major concussion and I can't focus to
write long long things like I used to
long lessons and [ __ ] it's coming back
to me slowly but it takes me a little
more effort and a lot more time to focus
and write down [ __ ]
so please bear with me but the lessons
are coming back things are getting
better I know that things have not been
the way they should be with the show but
I have not been the way I should be so I
couldn't bring you the show you needed
I'm getting my [ __ ] back together which
means the show is getting at [ __ ] back
together - I apologize for being kind of
slacking off but I didn't even know when
you get a head injury you don't know
what the hell is going on and it's crazy
weird so I'm getting back to it the
show's getting back to it so let me
prove that to you here's what I have
written and I have got a lot here I
think I'm gonna try to read it off the
computer because the phone screen is
tiny let's put the same thing here on
the phone same thing on the computer
does it match up dated all right we're
gonna read it off the phone it goes like
this so an average bro should take about
100 to 120 days maybe 150 days total in
the soil before harvesting drying
trimming and curing our goal our goal is
to provide our plants with optimal
conditions appropriate feedings careful
training and selective pruning in order
to produce the finest medicine we can
offer to our patients or clients I think
that every day in each cycle is an
opportunity to show the plants some love
and help your crop reach its full
potential I feel like each feeding each
application of tea's bug sprays foliar
feeding and any interaction with your
plants is your chance to make sure your
crop reaches your clients expectations
and the plants full potential a great
way to improve your crops is to start a
solid grow schedule today I want to talk
about two different schedules a grower
should be on top of the first schedule
will be the basic planning of a crop
from seed to clone all the way up to
harvest time I want to discuss the
phases of growth from a small cloner
seedling into vegetative growth into the
flowering phase on a breakdown the
flowering phase in two trimesters and
talk about what the plants are doing and
what they want through the flowering
phase I'll also talk about what you
could be doing at each phase to improve
your harvest um I wrote here that if I
can get you through 120 day girl lesson
in this episode I'll just start my I'll
start my discussion on planning a
schedule that keeps your grow spaced
producing as much herb as possible with
as little downtime as possible this of
course will take multiple lights and at
least two small grow spaces but setting
up a small perpetual grow to keep
yourself supplied with head stash is
probably easier than you think I realize
now that I've written way too
much for one episode so this is
definitely gonna be broken down you guys
so here's what we get into it before you
begin your grow I suggest getting
yourself a planner and making a schedule
in advance you can be flexible because
these are plants but try to stick with
your plan if you can I also suggest
taking a lot of notes you guys take a
lot of notes don't wonder what you did
to that plant to make it so special
write down what you did so that you know
all right so here's where I'll describe
the phases of growth and timeframes of
our plants I said that this grows gonna
take about 100 to 120 days if you want
to go larger plants you can go to 150
I've seen people take a lot longer
that's the vege period is what you're
gonna make your difference there so
we'll start off with seedlings or clones
right and that's gonna take about 14
days to be in the seedling phase I think
about 14 days when you start germinating
it from the day you germinate it so the
day it's like a little plant it's about
14 days we're gonna call that 14 days a
clone takes about 14 days to root and
get ready to be a plant so I'm gonna say
seedling and clone phase is about 14
days the veg growth depends on your goal
you guys if you want to veg if you're
going in small pots you can veg for 2
weeks if you're gonna go into larger
pots you can veg
I've seen people veg for 3045 days I've
also seen guys veg for 60 days some of
the outdoor plants that people veg for
the the early start of the year before
the outdoor season
I've seen people veg plants were 4 or 5
or 6 months to put them outside so
what's gonna happen is your plants are
gonna get bigger and bigger and bigger
it's a longer you veg so we're just
gonna go for a short veg in this one
so you're flowering phase I'm gonna go
for a nine-week flowering phase most of
the plants I work with are about 9 to 10
weeks nine weeks is a good number
because that gives us three trimesters
of three weeks you should talk about I
can talk about my theory of the
trimesters on the plants so yeah that'll
help us out so we got 14 days in
seedling 63 days and flowering are you
looking at 77 days there that gives us
about 30 days to veg and fix any
problems so let's just basically start a
short grow from cedar clone this is kind
of the drama to talk about now is
basically the type I would of grow I
would do if I were searching through a
10 pack of seeds to find the
purrs in the pack so for this I would
usually use like a three gallon pot or a
five gallon pot and I would use I don't
know probably like between nine and
sixteen just depends on how small I'm
gonna keep the plants and how tight I
want to cramp them in the space under
the light there's just one light as all
I'm talking about right now so if we
start from seeds or clones the only
difference will be the first two weeks
really once the clones root and the
seedlings take off everything I'm
talking about is gonna work the same for
seeds in clumps if you're working with
seeds you'll have to be sure that you
eliminate the males before we get too
far into flower but that's gonna be your
major difference so let's start with
this I will say this is like if we're
starting day one will say start day one
right now so today we we would cut our
clones and start germinating our seeds
I'm not gonna do any lessons on
germinating seeds or cutting clones
because I'm pretty sure I've covered
that in past episodes if you need a
refresher course go back and listen to
those or if you guys want a brand new
episode on that email me and I will go
back and listen to the old episode and
I'll try to do an update for you but
only enough enough people asked for it
that episodes out there so it should
work so we cut our clones we start our
seeds for day one this is where you want
to mark the date get out your grow
calendar and Mark it today is day one
for clothes and seeds I recommend a 24
hour light cycle you guys to start the
first couple of weeks the first few days
are just a waiting game pretty much if
you're waiting for seeds they'll pop up
they'll pop up from whatever medium
you've put them in in like 48 hours
hopefully or maybe it'll take them a
couple days to start growing to the
light I suggest putting your seedlings
into I use beer cups like Solo cups ah
put those put your seedlings into the
cups the white potting mix with plenty
of drainage and holes in the bottoms of
the cups of course once your seedlings
have developed a nice tap root of like
about an inch to three inches long
that's when you want to throw those in
your dirt so cones will be lazy but
they'll root around 10 to 14 days some
of you guys are gonna take a little
longer to get your clones to root it's
all about a healthy mother plant a good
rooting environment be patient and if it
takes you more time to get your clones
rooted just plan that into your next run
give yourself an extra week on extra
five days whatever it takes and then
you'll start learning how to keep
healthier mother plants you'll start
learning how to clone better and you'll
speed up your cloning time it'll get
better take a lot of extra clones at
first cuz they're gonna die if you're
not good at cloning if you're new at
this
take extras because you will lose some
and don't be sad about it so after
several days let's see where was I the
seedings ceilings are gonna start
growing tall and skinny in the first few
days after several days they'll develop
their first true leaves by this time the
clones are rooted and ready for cups and
the seedlings will be small plants and
catching up to the clones so I wouldn't
feed the seedlings until about 7 to 10
days in and when you do feed them focus
on root inoculant and building a good
root base for the plants I like a worm
casting tea or something like that maybe
something like great white you can use a
GT something something that focuses on
root inoculants you want
trichoderma yeah you guys hopefully
you've caught on to what I'm talking
about by now
I've talked a lot about root inoculant
with Shawn so I would feed the clones
the same thing when you put those into
cups I definitely like to feed my clones
and my seedlings a lot of root
inoculants to get that soil funky and
get the roots FAT FAT better roots the
better the fruits is what I say all the
time so by now I feel like we should be
putting our clones into cups and
starting week 3 if everything went
correctly we fed the plants once now
this makes me feel like everything is
one lesson now now that we've gotten to
week three in the clones and the
seedlings are caught up I feel like
there won't be much difference between
the cloud and the seedling clone and the
seedling that was hard to say the
seedlings may grow more quickly because
they have what we call seed vigor but
that's not always the case if you have
good clones I've seen some clones
outgrow seedlings before it's been kind
of surprising so all we've done up to
this point is pretty much plant our
seeds and clones we've gotten our
starter plants in two cups and we've fed
them some worm tea or some root
inoculant maybe some great white maybe
some o GT something like that to get
them started and now I'm gonna call this
the beginning of veg some people may
call it pre veg because we haven't done
into our big pots yet but I'm gonna call
it veg starting now now that we've
gotten out of the cloner now that we're
not little baby seedlings anymore I'm
gonna say we're into veg so the veg
state can last as long as you want
the longer you veg like I said earlier
the larger your plants are gonna get the
veg phase is where we do 90% of the
topping training and pruning of your
plants we kind of do a lesson on topping
and stuff like that but I plan to do
another episode all about improved
your crops and improving your improving
your yields and things so that'll come
in handy also your plants are gonna take
up 90% of the nitrogen that they use
through their entire lives during the
veg estate vegetative phase of their
plants people tend to really overlook
the veg phase and they focus only on the
bloom phase because that's when you can
see your buds but the veg phase is just
as important and so is your veg space
you guys a lot of people don't spend the
time building a proper veg room and now
it really would help you out if you if
you teach those kids how to run before
you put them on the track they'd be a
lot better performing kid so I feel like
if we use each day as a chance to
prepare the plants for bloom our crop
will look much better at harvest time my
veg phase for my example of this grow is
gonna be short you guys gosh press pause
and take a drink I'll probably take a
dabble on that excuse me for one second
alright guys I feel like we are at the
beginning of veg is where I left off so
I like to feed my plants the first day
of each week Monday's are usually my
feeding day for my personal crops for me
starting everything on a Monday helps me
keep track of everything so in the first
day of veg I would feed my plants a nice
base nutrient a white humic acid some
potassium silicates to build strong cell
walls and I would also keep focusing on
root development we shouldn't need any
cal-mag or anything like that for the
first couple of weeks everything should
be cool so for the first couple of weeks
your plan should be cooling the cups but
we're gonna have to plant them into
larger pots pretty soon you don't want
to see them get root bound in those cups
and they'll also get tall and skinny we
want them to Bush out a little bit so
when we put them into a larger pot
they'll start pushing out so it's also a
good time to adjust your lights from 24
hours to an 18-6 schedule you want them
on for 18 hours off for 6 plants like a
rest period and it's also gonna save you
money on your energy bill so now you've
got your plants in two cups they're nice
and healthy they're starting to kind of
grow a little bit they've got nice roots
or about three weeks in I think by the
fourth week is when we should start
putting everything into larger pots if
we leave them in the cups too long
they're gonna get root bound they're
gonna start getting Scratchy and also
when you put them into bigger pots they
can go a little bit longer without
needing water so that'll help you out
too so if you're gonna veg for a couple
extra weeks and you have times first
time and space bill for bigger pots for
my example we're just gonna
you a quick crop and we're gonna use
three gallon pots and they'll be just
fine so carefully put everything from
your cups into a three gallon pot or a
larger pot which every gonna use um and
I think I've talked about transplanting
I think I've talked a little bit about
doing that so if you guys need help
transplant me let me know and I'll talk
more about that but I'm pretty sure I've
covered it so carefully put everything
into a larger pot and feed them it
should be about a week for maybe into
week five by now you guys I hope you
started doing these indica into pots
around week four I hope you didn't wait
too long so feed them and you're gonna
feed them a strong dose of root
inoculant of course we're always gonna
do that through veg right up to kind of
the start of a flower feed them a veg
based nutrient I use if I'm using
bottled nutrients for this I would
recommend a botanic air pure blend Pro
soil formula the growth formula they
don't pay me to say that it's just what
I use I would use some humic acid in
there for this grow for my
recommendation if you're using bottles I
would say liquid karma from botanic air
I've used a fulvic acid which organic
hair sells a liquid fulvic acid that
works great for this I would use some
cal-mag at this point you guys you're
going to start eating some cal-mag in
there a very light dose of cal-mag to
start because your babies aren't ready
for it just yet possibly and I don't
want you to burn them so be careful with
that cal-mag but it's about to be time I
would also recommend something to feed
the microbes basic molasses or something
like Humboldt honey or something like
that
hi Bree would be good anything like that
with a lot of molasses II type stuff
there so now our plants are in their
final pots they've been fed these plants
can be topped or super cropped or
manipulated into a screen of green or
whatever you have planned for them I'll
just make sure that if you're gonna do
any topping or pruning do that about ten
to ten to fourteen days before you start
flowering the plants your plants need a
little bit of time to recover after
you've topped up plants our apical
dominate which means they want to top so
after you've cut the tops the hormones
have to move around it's got to move
hormones around you want those hormones
built up in the tips of your plants
before you flower to them it's really
helpful for your plants if you start
topping stuff and pruning things that
flower right away you're just gonna make
little tiny buds and confuse the [ __ ]
out of your plant it
disappointed so now that we are in our
bigger pots and we fed everything I'm
gonna say we are in full veg mode we
have our plants in the finishing pots
things have been topped in super crops
we've got our whites on a veg schedule
of 18 on and six hours off we should be
feeding a solid veg recipe at the start
of every week and watching for any signs
of bug problems it'd be a good idea to
start a bug prevention regimen by now if
you haven't already started spraying or
doing something to keep the mites away
neem oil is a great way to prevent bugs
while you're in veg but do not ever
spray a flowering plant with neem oil
one application of neem oil on a
flowering plant will ruin the entire
thing the flavor will be miserable if
you make extracts they will taste like
neem oil I just please don't do that you
guys don't spray anything on your
flowering plants any bug sprays or
anything on your flowering plants if
you're gonna spray stuff on flowering
plants make sure it's a well
well-thought-out foliar feed so I said
that we should feed on Monday of every
week right that's my opinion I like to
feed on Monday I mix up nutrients I mix
up a nice reservoir of nutrients and
feed the plants every Monday they get a
nice healthy feed and then usually by
Wednesday or Thursday they need more
they need a water
so I'll just feed them clean pH balanced
water with no nutrients in it I'll just
feed them that and then on Monday again
I will give them nutrients and then the
next time that they're thirsty probably
that next Wednesday or Thursday they
will get a fully organic worm tea that I
have brewed for like 36 hours
I'll put worm castings in there and put
CRO Kashi in there put a little bit of
uh dragonfly earth medicine the lush
roots in there put a little bit of fish
Hydra sleet put some sea crop and then
I'll feed my plants that and they get
fed teas probably twice in veg and
probably three times during the flower
phase and I think it makes a huge
difference because I make a pretty
awesome tea that Shawn taught me how to
make I really think it makes a
difference so that's kind of my feeding
idea I don't think I've ever broken down
my week to week feeding schedule I don't
want to be responsible for your weekly
feeding I kind of want to let you
experience
find what works for you but if you've
got questions about specific nutrients
let me know and I'll do my best to
figure out how to incorporate that into
your girl for you that's gonna take a
lot of work so like I've seen earlier we
can veg as long as we want from my
example we're gonna veg for about 30
days you can top and manipulate the
plants as much as you want one veg that
I already read this no but I would stop
talking about
I would stop talking topping about two
weeks before flowering my short crops
don't really get much topping and
pruning you guys if I'm earning a seed
crop and I want to see what the
seedlings are I really don't top much I
take two clones from each plant just
before I flower it I clean up the
bottoms just a little bit and then once
I flower I clean up the bottoms once I
flower but my small crops really don't
get much topping or pruning I try to let
that if the test crops just in and out
quickly so I can see what I'm working
with because if I've got a bunch of boys
in there or if I don't see the traits
I'm looking for then I just want to get
that out of there and scrap it as soon
as possible I'm looking for specific
traits at this point basically we need
to watch for bugs watch for problems and
keep the plants as healthy and happy as
possible so I suggest checking each
plant every single day I know that
sounds ridiculous but however many
plants you've got you should be in there
you should touch every plant every
single day that's how you know you're
drawing from your heart that's how you
know you've got solid medicine that
doesn't need to be sprayed with Eagle 20
that's how you know that if you do see a
problem you'll be on top of it you'll be
able to cure it you'll be able to solve
the problem before it gets out of
control that's super important being a
good gardener so I suggest checking each
day and make notes of what you see if
you see anything that stands out to you
make a note of it if it's good if it's
bad if it's weird if you're not sure if
it's new if it's questionable make a
note and don't forget because I know
you're gonna say I'll remember ship the
notes are in my head dude where pot
heads were pot growers we're dabbers
you're gonna forget you're gonna forget
something write it down and when maybe
one day you're gonna want to run a
business and the guy with the notes will
get the opportunity to run a business
over the guy with the head full of
[ __ ] and ideas you've written
something down that shows you've done
something the other guy's like I
remember doing this the people that are
hiring you to be their master girl right
their dispensary don't want your hopes
and dreams in your head
see it on paper if you take notes you
got something that's documented and now
that it's legal you don't have to worry
about it I understand the old-school
drillers didn't want any notes I get it
but now he can so so set a date for your
flowering cycle is what I think you
should do decide how long you want to
veg send a date for your flowering cycle
and then commit to that and veg for that
long get your plants trimmed up get them
pruned get them topped if you're gonna
put them in a screen of green like
Spence taught us about put them in the
screen of green get them nice and happy
and we'll get them ready for the
flowering cycle I've gone for 30 minutes
I don't think I can get enough of the
flowering cycle to make it worth your
listen in to this episode so I think
we're just gonna start wrapping up the
show at 30 minutes you guys really
listen a lot when I put out shorter
episodes you don't seem to get the
attention deficit disorder so we're just
gonna do a short episode here I
appreciate you guys for listening I will
come back in a week and I will have a
solid lesson about the flowering
schedule for you I hope to get Spence on
an upcoming episode I was talking to
Sean and he'll be back in the future
I've got an episode coming up about how
to improve your garden I've got a lot of
things planned you guys I'm really
getting back on my game so I'm getting
more lessons written down getting more
episodes planned I appreciate you
sticking through my rough patch there
while I had to do some sloppy episodes
big thanks to everybody who sent me well
wishes on taking care of my head wishing
me better on my head I feel much better
I'd like to say I'm about I kept sin as
90% I'm about 85% back I keep noticing
sometimes I'll say the wrong word in a
sentence the other day I told somebody
that I was going to eat this banana and
I was actually holding a burrito and I
didn't even realize that I'd I kept
saying banana but it was a burrito and
they corrected me and I said yeah this
banana is tasty and they're like it's a
[ __ ] burrito dude so I realized I was
doing that I was describing something
that was purple and I called it orange
and I know I did that but I don't yeah
so there's stuff like that that's going
on in my head that's still a little bit
goofy and sometimes I forget my password
still and I try to log into my computer
but I'm getting it back together so I do
appreciate you guys sticking with me
through that it's been a really scary
time but I feel like I'm coming back
together so let's wrap off the show guys
a [ __ ] rambly today
ah where is that part that I read oh
yeah it says thanks for listening to
another episode I'll be back in another
week I don't forget to check out the
sponsors I didn't do much ads cuz I
wanted to get the show going check out
our sponsors just Rocky Mountain warm
company and hydro indoor growing
supplies to Colorado based businesses
that I truly support with all my heart
if you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like to us to review send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I will get you all of the information
that you need don't forget to the show
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is archived on IR e
Genetics Colorado com don't forget that
we did add a donation button to the
podcast page on the website if you feel
like the show was worth a couple of
bucks you can go to my website I region
etics Colorado com click on the girl
from your heart podcasts tab at the top
right there's a PayPal logo click on
that make a small donation it goes
directly to my PayPal account because
I'm never gonna charge you for the
podcast the show is always gonna be free
but if you do feel like making a
contribution it would be greatly
appreciated I can use a new microphone I
can use these microphone covers this
one's all grimy
ya know beggin just if it's if it's
something on your mind I would
appreciate it we are on all the social
media sites just search for us it's a
girl from your heart on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast you can find me on Facebook
please you guys follow I read genetics
on Instagram I post a lot of sweet
cannabis photography there I've recently
joined what - called massroots
but I'm not getting much response so I
may quit posting there eventually but
definitely check me out on Instagram you
guys huge shout-outs main interest pants
thanks again for listening until next
time take your fat dad and give your mom
a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 69 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
[Music]
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host Rasta Jeff thanks again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you shout out to the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on the show
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew nobody's hanging out
with me today it's me all by myself
before we get too far I do need to send
you guys a huge apology I know that
there was an issue with the last episode
I posted the stitcher but it has since
been corrected drop down that music a
little bit I'm gonna repeat that the
last episode I posted the stitcher went
up I went to iTunes it went to stitcher
I went to the website everything went
perfectly but for some reason when
stitcher grabbed it it only took the
first 14 or 15 minutes of it so for the
first couple of days of the week you
guys were only able to access a 15
minute episode right when the Gros
lesson came in everything cut off I
apologize for that
Didrik got it fixed it took him a couple
of days but stitcher did repair that for
me so a big shout out the stitcher big
thanks to everybody who listened to that
episode if you guys tried to listen and
gave up because it sucked go back and
the whole episode is there now it's a 30
something minute episode we cover most
of veg growth so now that that's out of
the way let's move forward with the show
I received a question that I want to
answer it'll be real quick somebody
asked me why do you turn off the lights
during your foliar feeding when I'm
using a bug spray or a foliar feed I
turn off the lights because when you
spray the plants with a liquid it makes
little bubbles on there right and then
you've got these high-intensity
discharge lights right above them and it
works the same way as if you took a
magnifying glass and shone the Sun
through it it makes that little I call
it a reflector bubble and the magnifying
glass of the Sun work and it makes that
little dot on [ __ ] and then it burns it
it'll create you can catch paper on fire
when I was a kid I remember
ants and [ __ ] with the magnifying glass
using the Sun the bubble on your plants
will do the exact same thing will create
that magnifier bubble the light will hit
your feet or a bug spray I fully
recommend you turn off the lights it's
ideal to do it right before the lights
go out if you can but sometimes we have
jobs and prevent us from doing that so
that is why I turn off the lights when I
follow your feet and that's why I
recommend you turn off the lights when
you follow your feet or bug spray let's
see what's going on in my world man I
was at the spa yesterday I spent a
couple hours out at the spot dispensary
in Pueblo West and things are really
moving forward I should be out there
growing cannabis very soon mainly we are
waiting for inspections from the city we
need a couple small more we need a few
small steps to get through before I am
able to put plants in the spot
dispensary and start growing
recreational cannabis that you will be
able to come try that's right I'll let
you guys know when the plants are in
there I'll let you know when we put them
in the flower I'll let you guys know
when they're ready I'll let you guys
know when you can come get it also
before we get to the grow lesson I
wanted to talk about how much I feel
like my head is improving if you guys
follow the show I had a serious
concussion a few episodes the beginning
of April mid-april were a little bit I'm
gonna say there were shitty in my
opinion I know they were not up to the
standard I have created they did not
follow the format that I've created but
honestly I was not in my head I was
recovering from a major head wound but
the good part is I feel like I'm getting
my [ __ ] together it's been a week since
I sat down to record and it came
together the recording equipment came
together easily my podcast notes came
together easily the notes that I wrote
last week I brushed them up and made a
lot more sense out of them so the good
part is I feel like I'm getting back
together I want to thank you guys for
sticking with me through my head injury
while I've been kind of a [ __ ] I
have not been all here and I know that I
appreciate you guys that have not
abandoned me and my show through that
time that's cool of you also extra huge
shout outs all the people who have sent
me love and support and well-wishes
telling me to get better telling
to take care of my head several people
volunteered to come do chores for me so
I appreciate that you guys have no idea
what that means to me I'm getting back
on my feet I've been on my feet but I'm
getting my head back in there while I'm
doing it so let's move on to the guys
I've written a bunch of stuff and I'm
gonna try to convince it all into one
lesson for you so I may leave a little
bit out if you have any questions just
ask and I'll go back over anything I
went too fast on alright I'm gonna take
a quick drink and a DAB and we're going
to get on with the grow lesson guys well
I'm taking a DAB make sure you support
our sponsors the rocky mountain worm
company if you need organic soil
amendments or high-quality worm castings
check out www.sceeto.com today alright
guys in the last episode I talked a lot
about vegetative growth and we got right
up to the first day of flowering and
that's where I want to start off today
let's start a flowering cycle the first
let's talk a little bit about the
flowering period I've alluded that there
are three trimesters to the flowering
period don't let me explain a little
what I meant by that for this we're
gonna talk about a nine week plan a nine
week flowering plant will use grateful
dog as an example cuz it likes to finish
in about nine weeks so that's perfect
the first trimester is what I would
refer to as the transition phase the
second trimester is full flower and the
finishing and the third trimester is the
finishing and ripening phase so I'm
gonna try to talk a little bit about
what the plants want during each
trimester and I'll do my best to kind of
break it down week by week for you and
let you know what to feed and what you
can be doing to your plants each week
we'll find like the main important
things to do to your plants each week
and then I'll give you some ideas that
will really improve your crops and then
in a future episode we're gonna focus
all about improving your crops so let's
get on it let's start a flowering cycle
today would be day one of week one a
flower so I would start on a Monday
that's just my preference we've talked
about that I would go to that Monday and
I would say day one a flower a week one
day one then I would go through and mark
that calendar week two week three week
four week five week six so that it's
easily easily viewable alright so you
want to set the lights for a twelve
twelve cycle that means we want the
lights to be
on for 12 hours and offer 12 hours of
uninterrupted darkness every day and
every night we can't have any dark
during the night cycle I can't stress or
any light during the night cycle I can't
stress how important it is to have total
darkness for the dark period of your
bloom cycle the room needs to be totally
pitch-black dark if you can see any
light in there it's too much if you can
stand in the room and put your hand in
front of your face if you can see your
hand at all you need more darkness in
there that's completely important it's
also let's see where was it's equally
important not to interrupt the dark
period interrupting the dark trade will
cause your plants to possibly Herm and
possibly make seeds your plants are
asleep you want to let them sleep it
pisses you off when I wake you up in the
middle and I'd piss your plants off too
so running a twelve twelve cycle I like
to keep my metal halide bulbs in for the
first two weeks of flowering for the
first week of flowering alright here we
go for the first week of flowering I
would feed my vegetative base nutrients
and I would start pumping up my P and K
values okay and I would also keep
focusing on root development a little
bit if I were using bottled nutrients I
would use a little bit of liquid karma
some silica blast I would use a little
bit of humble honey and some roots zho
or something similar some kind of
similar rooting powder or maybe some
like what was I using before OGT that
works great white shark works anything
like that would work for you and also
maybe I would add in some hydrazine I
don't expect to see a whole lot of
action from the plants your first week
of flower this is the start of the
transitional period like I said this is
transitional phase from vegetable and
then in about six to ten days is where
you're really gonna see your changes so
let me add something here while I'm
thinking about it your plants are gonna
get fed nutrients on every Monday but
they're probably gonna get thirsty you
need a drink before the next Monday so
it's probably gonna be Wednesday or
Thursday but on that day water your
plants with just clean water pH dat 6.5
you don't want to feed every day because
in your plants are going to start to get
over fertilized and they are going to
get what we call nutrient lock out all
of your bottle nutrients are assault
based and if we keep feeding these salts
to our plants
they get salty and they don't want to
take up more salts so they simply stop
taking up nutrients and that's called
nutrient lockout so we're gonna feed
clean water every Wednesday or Thursday
and prevent that nutrient lockout by
giving these girls a fresh drink so
that's going to put us into week two for
week two I would start feeding my bloom
base nutrients and I would add some
cal-mag I would add this is if you're
gonna use bottled nutrients and this is
what I would use if I were using liquid
karma if you're using a different brand
all of these products are easily
replaceable just look at your feet chart
and look at your the other brand and
replace the bottles it'll be that easy
so for week two I would do some cal mags
some liquid karma silica blast and I
would add a little bit of cplex
a week to is where you really need to
start paying attention for mail plants
if you started from seeds you're gonna
start seeing little ball sacks develop
if you've got males in there get them
out in week two you should start seeing
pre flowers and the plants are starting
to stretch by the end of this week you
should have identified your males and
isolated them if you don't plan on
breeding definitely get those males out
of there cut them down if you put them
in the garage they may keep going if you
put them somewhere they may keep going
and make pollen kill them cut them down
kill them unless you plan on breeding
and if you plan on breeding then I don't
need to tell you what to do with males
you've already got that figured out so
for week two they're pretty much just
gonna grow you're gonna start seeing
flowering set flower sets start to
develop you'll start to see the sex if
you're using feminized seeds still pay
attention to the sex you may get some
piranha hermaphrodites some [ __ ] could
have gone wrong you may have gotten the
wrong seeds you never know pay attention
don't take that feminized label as the
complete this will be a perfect female
plant that could not be the case
alright so week three week three is a
busy week this is where we really start
getting busy you should have identified
your males by now you should have pulled
them hopefully if you had clones of
those you tossed the clones of the males
also so if you don't have nice bud sites
developing by the beginning of week
three you may have a light leak or
another issue during your dark period if
you're not starting to see little
dandelion looking bud sides by now go in
the room at night and make sure you're
not going
a light leak a small light leak will
prevent your frontier plants from going
into flower so for week three I would
feed my bloom base nutrients I would
feed cal-mag I would introduce full vex
I believe liquid karma I would use hydro
Plex see Plex silica blast humble honey
and hydros I'm this week this will be
the basic recipe through flowering - the
hydros I'm my only hydros I'm every
other feed I do add a few other things
to my personal mix but this will get you
guys through flowering I don't want to
get too crazy and have you buying a
whole bunch of things when you're not
ready for that so I did get this mix
from the botanic air website if you need
help mixing up a great botanical recipe
just go to the botanic air website go to
the nutrient calculator basically
filling it and asks how many weeks you
want to veg how many weeks you want to
flower it asks you which bottles of
nutrients you've got you click on those
and it'll tell you what to feed I would
recommend reducing it just a little bit
feed your plants a reduced mix and see
how they react
you can always feed more but you can't
unfilled your plants once they've burned
themselves so don't overdo it they do I
like botanic air I like the company but
they are a company they need you to buy
more so they kind of tell you to use a
little bit extra as my opinion the more
you use the sooner you got to buy
another bottle anyway let's talk more
about week 3 um yeah you can go get that
on the botanic air website is where I
left off right alright if you're using a
different brand they do have a different
feeding chart online for you to follow
almost all the popular brands have a
feeding chart right now and you can
easily like i said you can easily swap
out bottle for bottle if you know if you
just read like I said liquid caramel
read the bottle see what's in there look
at whatever brand you're using and
there's the equivalent for your brand is
there it's all basically the same [ __ ] I
just prefer botanic air if I'm going
bottled news
all right so I also like to add a nice
dose of carbs and sugars at week three
we're going to start seeing resin
production around week mid week three
early week four you'll very little resin
production but it will start and why not
give it some carbs and sugars to start
contributing to that that's my opinion I
also think the carbs and sugars keep the
mykos in your root zone living and
healthy and happy so that is always a
good idea to add those guys so in Week
three we should really see both sites of
developing this is a good time to start
lolli popping your plants what that
means is kind of cleaning up the bottom
little mini buds and the sucker branches
that aren't gonna get enough light to
become viable buds just get in there and
clean that [ __ ] right out don't be
afraid we'll do a whole lesson on Wally
poppin if we haven't already you want to
get in there the lights only gonna
penetrate your canopy about eighteen to
twenty maybe twenty four inches if
you're using regular thousand watt bulbs
if you're using lower wattage you've got
even less penetration so you're gonna
want to get in there if your plants
three foot tall you don't need a whole
three foot stock you want to kind of
clean off the bottom twelve inches or so
and that gives you more airflow down
there those buds that develop down there
are just gonna be wispy [ __ ] anyway
unless you're gonna make hash with it
clean that up send all that energy up to
the top of the plant because you don't
always try them time trimming that
bottom [ __ ] anyway bottoms also I would
recommend switching for a metal halide
bulbs to high pressure sodium bulbs at
the start of week three week three is
the last week of the first trimester and
it's the last week of the transition and
stretching phase so after this week your
plants will quit stretching so much week
three is really the super stretch and
then week four they'll quit stretching
and start working more on buds for you
so in week 3 you want a lollipop and you
want to change to your high pressure
sodium bulbs are your main goals for
week three guys I know I'm going kind of
fast but we got nine weeks to cover here
and I'm only to week four and we're 15
minutes in already so
I'll week four I'm gonna feed a very
similar mix than I would in week three
ah week four is the end of the stretch
phase and the start of actual bud growth
you'll really start to see buds
developing by now and if you don't
you've got a problem we need to get in
there and make sure you've got darkness
make sure you don't have some shitty
plants so week four is another week to
lollipop you can definitely get in there
and lollipop a little bit more i just
use my thumbnail I don't trim my
thumbnail all the way down I just use
that to pick off those little sucker
buds collect them up put them in a
little trash can and toss them those are
put in the compost pile if you're doing
that all that energy could go up to the
top of the plant if you guys are growing
for just - you could do whatever you
want with that I get it so now it's also
a good time to start adding stakes or
some sort of supports to the branches
cuz we're gonna get some hefty buds and
once we get into week five and six we're
really gonna need stakes to support
everything but by week five and six it's
such a [ __ ] to maneuver those plants
your branches got long sticky colas on
there and you don't want to be playing
with the resin getting the resin all
over your clothes you want to leave that
on the plants so get in there about week
four and I like to put a stake to
support the middle Cola because I know
I'm gonna have a big huge fat cola then
I like to put about four maybe six and
sticks around the pot because I'm gonna
get some big colas and I use those
sticks to strap up my major colas just
right to the stick I do it early because
like I'm saying in week five and six I'm
gonna have some buds going on that I
don't want to have to mess with so much
and if I got them all strapped up
already I don't have to worry about it
what I'm working with soil plants I
usually don't use a trellis or a screen
or anything but at the dispensary where
I'm running the big grow we're
definitely using a trellis and if you're
gonna trellis the plants you need to get
that in there during your veg cycle
that's why when I was doing the veg
lesson I mentioned that this is the week
to do any type of trellising and [ __ ]
like that that'll have to happen in bed
you guys because those plants are gonna
grow up into that trellis and you don't
want to be bending them and folding them
and manipulating them in Flour so you
have to be prepared for that that's why
we're making a schedule now before we
put these plants in the dirt or in the
rockwool cubes
so get your stakes up you guys water
healthy get your stakes up more lollipop
not s'what you're doing for a week for
let's transition into week five now this
is when the fun starts you guys the
plants start getting photogenic the buds
start getting chunky since we're gettin
chunky buds it's a good time to stop
fooling your feeding I don't talk a lot
about foliar feeding I will in the
future foliar feeding can lead to a lot
of problems if it's done incorrectly or
at the wrong time so I haven't
introduced that yet but if you have gone
on your own and started full of your
feeding week five is what I would
recommend you quit
it's also important to pay attention to
your humidity in week 5 high humidity
and big buds can be a great way to
create powdery mildew or other mold
related problems I'm sure you guys that
listen to the podcast have heard me talk
about growing in a new room I was in a
basement
I had a exterior wall corner that got
really cold in that corner pocket right
there had a lot of cold air and I had a
5 ounce white rhino plant that I cut
down and discovered powdery mildew on
one butt of it as I was cutting it down
and I threw the entire plant away about
probably 5 ounces worth a good cannabis
somewhere between 4 and 6 ounces is what
those plants were averaging so 5 ounces
that my patients did not get to enjoy
because I let it get powdery mildew so
pay attention to the room don't let your
room get too humid my problem was that
it was cold and I was letting cold air
mix with the warm air and that created
mildew in my room but I learned from it
I learned a whole lot that she will
never happen to me again hey guys if it
happens to you don't don't feel bad
shit's gonna happen you just have to
learn from it it's how you deal with it
is what makes you the grower so do your
best to get the humidity under control
you don't want too much humidity in
there you do not want to start getting
mildew um for a week 5 I would recommend
getting your humidity right around fifty
percent if you can get it to 40 there's
nothing wrong with that you don't want
it too high that's when you're gonna get
problems too low of humidity your rooms
gonna dry up kind of quickly and the
buds don't get as sticky I don't think
but if you have the option or if you're
stuck with one if you have to go to
higher to low definitely go to low of
humidity so let's see we talked about
getting rid of the humidity I'm reading
notes as I do this oh this is where I
would stop lollipop you guys week five
don't wall-e pop anymore
you can if he wants you but you should
have gotten all that taken care of by
now and you're just gonna kind of shock
the plan if you keep doing it you may if
you keep lolli popping and [ __ ] with
the plant this far and you may cause it
to stress out in her just depends on
what other stress you're giving to the
plant so you should have a room full of
sexy chunky buds by now they're gonna
start falling over and needing attention
so hopefully you've got plenty of sticks
in there you're in there paying
attention every day you're gonna go in
there one day and you're gonna find a
bud that you didn't notice and it's
gonna be straight sideways
like it's ready to break don't panic
just get in there and support it give it
some support that shit's gonna happen to
you and you're gonna learn all these
things over a couple of grows of what to
look for and you'll learn to stop
panicking when you see a problem guys
don't panic
that's I know I keep saying that but if
you freak out you're just gonna make it
worse
when you see a problem in the grow room
just take a minute it's a plant we can
fix it hopefully if not we'll just make
be HOF it you're gonna be okay
so for week five I like to add a really
strong dose of sugars and carbs one of
my favorite bottled products is humble
honey I use that at week three but I use
a nice fat dose of it again at week five
so for week five you want to make sure
you've got your supports in place if you
haven't done in week four you may need
to add a few more sticks in place for
week five to get those bigger buds up in
place what I do I put a I think it's a
six foot tall bamboo sticks I grow big
plants you guys I put a six-foot tall
bamboo stick toward the outer edge of
the plant because I don't want to
disrupt too much of the root I just
shove it right into there then I grab
the bud that needs some support and I
use I've used several different things
but right now I'm using they call them
fuzzy sticks
I got a Hobby Lobby had a whole bunch
for really cheap so I bought a [ __ ] ton
of them it's kind of like a it's a pipe
cleaner essentially it's like a really
long bread tie that you can handle
better so I just take that and I wrap
that right around the stalk of the bud
that's gonna fall over and maybe maybe
I'll do part of the bud just depends on
how I have you the bud is if I feel like
it'll break the stick but then I take
that just wrap it around the bud or the
stalk and wrap that around the stick
itself so that it's just strapped right
up to it like you got a broken finger
just give that sucker some support he's
doing it fallin over I'm breaking these
your whole goal maybe if you tip it a
little bit if it's at an angle it's a
good idea because then you can expose
more of that bud to the white instead of
just having it completely up and down if
you tip it you get a little more surface
area for that light to hit which will
increase your harvests so week five you
want to work on your supports you want
to feed some sugars and carbs you want
to monitor your humidity get it around
50 to 40% and keep it there because
you're gonna start getting chunkier buds
and you don't need mildew and you're
gonna stop foliar feeding all right
so that's what's gonna happen in week
five that's gonna move us into week six
in week six I would feed a very similar
recipe as I did in week five I'd use
high amounts of P and K and lots of
sugars and carbs
I would reduce my base nutrients and
focus on resin production and healthy
plants
week six will be our last full feeding
hour but should be chunky and the resin
should be starting to cover the buds and
the small leaves after growing a strain
that Purple's up now is a good time to
lower the temps a few degrees during the
night cycles I try to keep my grow rooms
about 77 or 74 to 77 degrees during the
light period during the dark period I
try to get it down to about 68 69
degrees at this point in week 6 if I'm
working with something that will purple
up a little bit like the Kalonji Kush or
the flow or the ghost doji or The
Grateful dog I would drop the temps down
just a few more to like 65 degrees maybe
67 and if you get to that 65 at night
you'll see it in at night or to those
plants will start to purple up the
leaves will turn purple for you
higher CBD plants I think like more cold
but that's just my experience with the
Tora Bora and the night nurse you may
have a totally different plant so don't
take that as rule that's just my
experience so you might want to lower
the tips do stal ittle bit if you're
trying to pull out the purples if you
have more sativa dominant plants this
would probably piss off the Capleton the
white widow would not like it
lemon Geoffrey would not like that don't
put those in the cold but cushy plants
indica dominant plants give him a little
bit of cold and they'll purple up for
you about week six you're gonna have to
use more air conditioning so that may
cost you a little bit but I think it's
worth it for the plant that enjoys that
so we accept a great week for
photography you guys you got big chunky
buds this is however your last feeding
so whatever your plants are lacking or
whatever you haven't gotten in there
this is probably your last chance to do
it we are going to feed on week seven
but we're not going to feed the entire
program we're just gonna give a little
bit of stuff to keep it alive and happy
and healthy
so week six basically work on a good
feeding lower your tips if you want make
sure you've got everything supported and
staked up make sure nothing falls over
keep going through every single week you
guys and check for Herms check for mails
check for issues I should say this also
every day if you can do it every day go
in your garden and grab each plant and
just grab one leaf and flip it upside
down and inspect the [ __ ] out of it if
you see any signs of bugs any kinds of
pests that's when we need to get in
there and really deal with it hopefully
you're not too far into flower by the
time we discover a pest if you're in
flower when we discover pests that's a
whole nother conversation that's when
you have to decide are these pests going
to ruin my garden before harvest time or
can I Radek ate these pests somehow
there are a lot of decisions to make in
that scramble mode we'll talk about that
in another episode I do have a whole
pest management episode and the works so
week six we have lowered the tips that's
our last big feeding we got chunky
bullets hopefully took a lot of pictures
in week six because week six is
photogenic week seven this is when we
start what I've been calling the third
trimester this is ripening and the flush
phase we won't feed most of our
nutrients this week I would only use the
humble honey for the yucca extract and
the sweetener in there that's really
gonna make your plant sweet it's gonna
make them dense up and it's gonna make
them taste good and it's gonna make them
stinky I would also use cplex I think
SEAPLEX really contributes to the aroma
and flavor of a cush dominant plant a
lot of SEAPLEX and your cushy plants
will bring out that funk that fede smell
I really love it a grateful dog loves
SEAPLEX
if you're growing grateful dog when you
track it open there is a an offensive
odor that comes out of it it's almost
foot like it's almost armpit like and it
has a scent of fuel to it I think if you
pump up the SEAPLEX or a sea kelp based
product when you grow grateful dog it
will definitely increase that funky
aster pain
so we're using couple honey cplex hydros
I'm also I like enzymes at this face to
start breaking down dead material dead
roots that have maybe deep died and need
to be decomposed in their the hikers
line will help eliminate that [ __ ] and
speed things along for the flush phase
also add some full vex if you want to
speed things up and our friend Sean
taught us that you can use Oh G T to
speed up the flushing phase of your
plants because the rock phosphates make
the plant
cycle too quickly it speeds up the
nutritive cycle so that will kind of
assist us in the flush phase if we like
to I do not use any of that [ __ ] like
final phase or clear X or any of that um
I feel like that stuff leaves a little
bit of a flavor in the plant and I also
believe that if we are growing properly
and we're flushing properly we don't
need that product that's just another
product to sell there is a science
behind it like I said earlier we are
filling the plant with salts and those
flushing agents are basically sugars and
complexions breakdown salts which would
break the bond of the salt around the
Newt the root base which would allow
cleaner absorption of the roots and
everything will just taste better and
flow better but I don't think that
they're necessary unless you [ __ ] up
at some point they grow so we're very
close to harvest time we really need to
start getting the excess nutrients out
of our buds before we cut them down and
prepare them so we need to start getting
the nitrogen the phosphorus the
potassium the mag anaise the calcium
magnesium all the [ __ ] that we've been
shoving into these plants we want to get
it out of there now so that moves us
into week eight excuse me week eight is
the beginning the official beginning of
the flush phase um what I like to do and
this kind of depends on your setup if
you have smaller pots you can move the
pots to the bathroom of the shower
throw a cinder block put something down
so you don't scratch up the baths to
over the shower you guys put a towel
down throw a cinder block or a bucket
right in the bathtub or the shower and
then if you're using a three gallon pot
I like to run about nine or ten gallons
of water right through that pot I know
that sounds excessive but what you're
doing you want to walk you're washing
the dirt you want to get all of the
nutrients that we've poured into this
plant through the past
seven weeks we need to rinse all that
[ __ ] out of the dirt now so and it's
also in the plant the plant has been
eating it so we have to kind of starve
the plant for the next two weeks if
you're using bigger pots it might not be
feasible or rational to drag them to
another room that's fine in a seven
gallon pot I usually pour about a gallon
and a half of water through it and just
let it fill up in that little tray and
then I use a shop vac a wet/dry vac to
go suck the water out of the trays I
know that sounds excessive but I really
like to clean out the plants if this
method doesn't work for you well you
have to really focus on when you're
flushing you want water to come out of
the bottom of the pot you need like if I
would like to say at least ten percent
of the water I want to see that come
back out of the bottom that's how I know
I'm actually flushing that plan and
pushing something out if nothing's
coming out of the bottom nothing's
coming out you got to get water to float
to get all those nutrients out and
you're gonna want to do that without
drowning your plant you're gonna want to
flush it let it kind of dry and then
flush it again as many times as we can
until the end of week nine so the week
eight is a start of flushing you're
probably gonna water the [ __ ] out of it
on Monday it's not gonna be ready for
water again until probably Thursday or
Friday because you watered it so heavily
don't be in too much of a rush to water
it again because you will drown the damn
planet so Thursday or Friday when you
water it again do the same thing lots of
water just lots of water just let it go
right on through just let it drain right
on through if you've got like a floor
drain or something just keep pouring
water through you can't over flush in my
opinion it's ideal to use three times
the volume of the pot so if you've got a
nine gallon pot or a three gallon pot
you want to use nine gallons of water if
you've got a five gallon pot you want to
put fifteen gallons of water through
that [ __ ]
right no what I said finally I'll pop 15
gals why that's three times yeah just
making sure I'm doing good math here
head injuries coming back alright so
flush really good you guys I [ __ ] a lot
about cannabis because it's improperly
flushed when you're smoking a joint if
the joint won't stay lit if you have to
keep relighting it there's a good chance
it wasn't flushed properly or I rolled
it and I don't roll with the [ __ ] but if
your ashes are black and chunky there
are still nutrients in there you want a
nice clean white ash that's nice and
smooth and soft
you don't want chunks if you ask me your
hand it should feel nice you should
almost enjoy that nice smooth texture of
the ashes if your plants were flushed
properly one of my biggest complaints
about dispensary cannabis and I am
trying to fix this in my shop they don't
flush they do not flush and they do not
cure they pretty much say shits done cut
it down and sell it and I don't like
that so we're gonna try to change that
where I'm working flushing is important
you guys I can't stress that so from
week eight you want to flush run plenty
of clean water through that pot week
nine flushing is in full effect week
nine ends at day 63 on day 60 here's
what I recommend go in the grow room and
start taking off all of the big fan
leaves any leaf that has a PD 'el that's
a stem you guys any leaf that has a stem
that you can get to take some scissors
and cut that [ __ ] off really close to
the bud just go in there and delete the
entire room you don't need these leaves
anymore this is gonna save you time when
it comes to harvest so day 60 you walked
in there and he took off all of those
leaves boom now this may sound crazy
this is what I do in my groves I've got
three days left right on the first on
day 61 I reduce my lights from 12 12 to
10 14 I'm on for 10 hours and I'm off
for 14 the plants are going oh [ __ ] he's
gonna kill us now the time is near they
know it the next day I'll drop him down
to eight hours I'm on day three I'll
give in 24 hours of total darkness so
day 63 no light at all I'll leave them
off for the entire day
day 64 wake up bright and early nice and
ready go in and cut down the entire room
and just let them hang that's harvest
day that's 63 or 64 days you guys nine
weeks of full flower I got through that
in 30 minutes I didn't have to kind of I
did have to kind of skip a couple of
details I'm gonna take a drink I'm sorry
I'm trying to talk right through this
but I got a throat let me take a drink
here that's a little better I got you
guys through nine weeks in 30 minutes I
left some stuff out but I feel like that
leaves me more [ __ ] to teach you guys
and more tips to give you in the future
you'll survive a crop with everything I
taught you
I'm something that I should mention if
you do grow a longer strain I would
recommend reducing the light to 11 hours
on and 13 hours off around week 9 this
is only for drawing something that takes
11 weeks or more some sativas won't
finish up without a shortened day period
the reason is they are from an area that
only have a few hours difference in the
natural day and night cycle so we need
to encourage them excuse me I just
burped Brent to the microphone we need
to encourage these plants to finish up
by shortening the days what happens when
we shorten the days is the plant
realizes that winter is coming and our
plants main goal is to pollinate and
create seeds and since it hasn't
received any pollen it's kind of being
stubborn about finishing it's like I
really think it's like a dude at a party
it thinks if it hangs out later enough
there's still a chance to get inlaid so
what we got to do is we got to start
messing with the lights and tell these
guys your time's up dude we got to tell
the girls actually I'm gonna turn the
lights down and they'll start finishing
on their own otherwise some of these
sativas will just keep on goin I had a
Durbin poison strain that went for 14
weeks and then I was getting tired of
that [ __ ] cuz needed the room and it
was I was done growing that strain in
that crop and I wouldn't finish and then
I thought well why don't I just reduce
the lights down a little bit and speed
this up and you know what within one
week of reducing the lights it finished
I just had to tell it so
so also you may want to feed for a
little bit longer if you're running a
longer plan I would extend the week six
regimen if you have to extend anything
I'll just repeat week six until you get
to the like if you have three extra
weeks just do week six three extra times
that's what I'm trying to say here guys
my voice is burning out I've got a
little bit more stuff here but I'm
running out of throat so I think we're
gonna do another 35 minutes show and
wrap this [ __ ] up put a bow on it I
appreciate you guys for listening to me
if you want more information please
email me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
you can find me on facebook it's grow
from your heart you can tweet me it's at
gfy each podcast if you are on instagram
make sure you follow me it's a tyree
genetics send me a message on one of
those platforms and say hey bro when you
were doing your grow lesson I needed to
know this and you didn't tell me and I
will make a lesson out of that just for
you in the future guys I apologize that
my throat is burning out here let's just
wrap it up so I don't have to sound like
[ __ ] anymore thanks for listening I
really do appreciate it I think you can
tell that my head is getting better I
really can I ordered a product from
Annette comm called alpha brain if you
listen to Joe Rogan or any of those
other podcasts you've heard about alpha
brain alpha brain is used by public
speakers and lecturers and folks in that
type of a position that have to speak
right but they say that alpha brain it's
a nootropic and it is supposed to
increase your ability to recall names
and facts and locations and it's
supposed to broaden your vocabulary so
maybe that'll improve my head injury and
fix all my problems all right I really
don't have a voice left so don't forget
to check out our sponsors the rocky
mountain warm company and hydro indoor
growing supplies make sure you visit
nature's green remedies calm for all
your seeds if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like me to review send me
an email I already told you guys it's
girl from your heart I'll calm I'll get
you all the information that you need
check us out on all the social media
sites I'd really appreciate it don't
forget to the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
will always and forever be archived on I
read genetics call
Oh calm don't forget about the donation
button on the podcast page that's right
go to I read genetics Colorado comm go
to the girl from your heart podcast tab
at the top right there's a little PayPal
logo that's a donation button click on
that that goes directly to my PayPal
account
I'm never gonna charge you guys for the
podcast this is always gonna be free but
if you feel like making a contribution
to say thank you
I would definitely appreciate it I do
put at least three hours into every
episode plus the hour that it takes to
record I do research I write all this
stuff out I'm not asking for anything
but some people want to do that and I'm
not gonna stop you so throw down if you
want to we're on all the social media
societies I think I already said that
yeah no more rambling dude make sure you
guys follow me on Instagram I'm almost
at 15,000 followers I really want to hit
that fifteen thousand mark I'm not sure
why but I do once again big shout-out to
my ninja spits thanks again for
listening you guys until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
the girl from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education
[Music]
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you for joining me as always
I want to send a big huge thank you
shout out to the mystic Ruth man for
letting me use their music on the show
right now it's called the doggy dub make
sure you support my friends in the
mystic roots crew what's up everybody
I've got a great show put together for
you together for you guys music that's
really distracting just cut that right
out there we go
so I got a few things I want to talk
about first I want to give a huge shout
out to everybody that's helped me out
this past week um I was driving up to
Colorado Springs to go see our good
friends hunt and damsel and of course
the Jordans and of course John Randall's
jr. was headed up there Springs gonna
make go pay them a visit and the [ __ ]
transmission went out on my car about a
mile from Colorado Springs I could see
the first exit in Colorado Springs I
could see the damn circle Drive Lake
Avenue sign right in front of me but I
just couldn't get off the highway my car
pretty much exploded it felt like I was
doing a good 75 miles an hour on the
interstate in the rain
I felt like my car down shifted from 75
I immediately was going about 45 miles
an hour
it sounded like is what it felt like to
me I felt like my engine was trying to
jump out of the car and into my lap so
of course I hit the brakes signal got
over as quickly as I could get to the
side of the road turn on the hazards
called triple-a it took triple-a they've
quoted me 85 minutes to get there they
got there in 65 so suck in 85 minute 85
minute wait is a long wait 65 minutes
was less than what they promised me so I
guess that that's a good job on triple
A's part I made friends with the Triple
A tow truck driver I wish I had your
business card with me right now in my
pocket but I have said it somewhere you
know what it's actually in the car
that's broken down that is it the
mechanic shop so once I get your card
out of there I'll give you a shout-out
on the show because the truck driver was
a cool guy they did a great job they
were super kind they'd had to tell me
about
50 miles home get me back to the house
but I'm here I'm safe I don't have a car
for a little bit here we're figuring
that out it's gonna cost a little bit to
get that son of a [ __ ] fixed but anyway
friend move on trying to have a good
week
we were gonna talk about cannabis here
but I want to talk a little bit first
you guys know that I hit my head at the
beginning of April right now I'm
recording this the date is May 14th as
we record I feel like I'm getting it
back together so much you guys I want to
thank you for tolerating my [ __ ]
well I've had a head wound I know I've
been goofy I really do I wasn't all
there I apologize
did you guys that stuck with me you're
my friends I love you thanks for
supporting the show thanks for being
there while I was kind of down I want to
talk about a product they ordered online
I've been taking something called alpha
brain you can get it on it calm there's
two ends in that it's onn i tee on it
Labs makes a lot of great products I'm
gonna reach for my bottle of alpha brain
right here hold on all right I got the
bottle in my hand alpha brain is a
complete Earth grown nootropic with
alpha GPC and AC 11 you know that sounds
like a bunch of [ __ ] to you guys but
they say that lecturers educators
speakers public speakers radio
personalities and folks like that use
alpha brain the guy that inspired me to
use it is Joe Rogan when Joe Rogan does
his podcast he takes a couple alpha
brain when he does the UFC events he
announces the commentates on the UFC's
he does 3 alpha brain pills for that
I've been taking two a day and I can
feel a sharpness in my brain my
vocabulary is stronger I had a problem
after I hit my head I would try to
recall words and I'd say hey can you
hand me my my and I just couldn't think
of what basic words were like
screwdriver or a flashlight sometimes I
would just forget words but the Alpha
brain is making that [ __ ] come back to
me it's making me a better speaker it's
making me remember and recall more let's
we can be calmer I've described it as
maybe I've said this on the show maybe
I'm full of [ __ ] with my memory saying
but I've described it as my brain has
the main track that's happening there's
like gotta wake up you gotta poop you
gotta brush your teeth you got to get to
work on time you got to do your chores
you got to call this person you know
that track is playing in your head but
there's all
side [ __ ] that goes on in your head
like taxes and it just whispers at you
occasionally or I wonder what that
girl's doing or I miss somebody or just
[ __ ] that happens in your head that
you really don't need to be focusing on
right now I feel like weird things pop
up into your head and the alpha brain
has kind of quieted that secondary track
so what I'm able to focus on what I'm
supposed to focus on which gets me to my
point the podcasts are getting much
better you guys I'm gonna make the
podcast a lot better much much better so
shout out to alpha brain shout out to
Han it labs I take two a day
and I definitely feel I'm more talkative
but it's because my thoughts are more
clear and I could put together much
better sentences much better podcasts
definitely how do I got the phone on
loud here that's ridiculous they put
that [ __ ] on silent I apologize that's
very unprofessional podcast behavior
here we go another product you heard us
talk about Floria on a previous podcast
episode Floria is a medicated personal
lubricant which means it is a sexual
lubricant that it contains cannabis
somebody heard that I talked about it on
the show and they gave me a product
called Evo's and from what I can tell
Evo's and Floria are very very similar
fairly similar was what I wanted to say
ahh
they are both coconut oil infused with
cannabis and they are meant to be
applied to you know the instructions
pretty much they apply it to the
female's parts so I'm gonna be straight
up about this I got some Evo's and I my
partner's goods and uh it made a
difference it definitely there was
nothing to complain about before
everything was going just fine but when
we added that stuff it made it a little
uh it made my junk warm it felt like
it's already warm I know but it felt a
little warmer and tingly or it made my
stuff feel a little more alert like it
was definitely a heightened experience
and she agreed she said that it was
definitely a heightened experience it's
just coconut oil and cannabis so I had
no worries about putting it on my body
or in her body or whatever it washed off
really cleanly and really quickly one
funny thing that I said when I was done
and I'm sorry if I'm being too explicit
you guys but it's my podcast and I'll
talk about my
if I want what I was done ah I was I
felt I wasn't aroused okay I was all
done and soft I don't want floppy but I
felt like my dick was fluffy like I've
given somebody a massage with a posse
can a lotion before and I've explained
my hands like feeling like I was wearing
Mickey Mouse gloves my dick felt like it
was fluffy like to the touch if I would
touch it I felt like it was thicker than
it was that's a weird on the show but I
tried the Evo's and if you're looking
for something to add to the bedroom fun
and you want to go to the dispensary and
spend a few bucks there is nothing wrong
with evos it worked I would use it I
would do that again if you're listening
let's do that again
so we talked about alpha brain we talked
about Evo's let's change the tone a
little bit this is something that is not
good that happens um I was trying to
explain to a friend something and I
don't know the science behind it but I
know that this is happening when my dad
break gets dirty my chunk of globby
resin in there and this probably applies
to the bond with bond resin if you're
just smoking flour but I've noticed that
when I'm hitting the dab break once the
rig gets dirty I feel like that chunk of
resin in there is actually stealing part
of my dad I feel like when you've got a
big floater if you look at my rig right
now there is like a quarter gram of hash
just floating in my rig water and it's
not old the rig water has only been in
there for three or four days at the most
we just dab heavy here the seal never
turns off you guys that's like the
coffee pot it turns on at a certain time
in the morning and then it goes off
right when I go to bed so I'm taking big
fat gloves are now clean the regen take
fat globs fat globs I get super baked
like just like I should but as the rig
gets dirtier I stop getting as high and
stop choking and stop enjoying my dab as
much as it gets dirtier I think that
chunk of resin in there collects the
resin that's the smoke it collects all
your cannabinoids and your smoke and
your whatever you're trying to get it
sticks to that ball and it's ripping you
off so my point clean the [ __ ] rig go
get some rubbing alcohol if it's really
super sticky get yourself some kosher
salt fill the rig halfway up with
alcohol put a little bit of kosher salt
in there the salt is working as an
abrasive it's gonna scratch all that
resin off of there cover up both holes
go somewhere you got a carpeted floor if
you're a pothead and to shake the [ __ ]
out of that rig and the reason we're
going to the carpeted
so that when you drop the rig you have a
better chance of living just be careful
just go shake the [ __ ] out of that rig
and then yeah that's disgusting but just
pour all that [ __ ] reclaim right down
the drain and get rid of it you don't
want that I know a lot of people that
use it I'm not gonna hey Lenny if you do
I wouldn't use it especially if you just
mix alcohol into it but flush that [ __ ]
right down the drain get rid of it and
then rinse the rig out a couple of times
with super hot water let it dry let it
cool down to a normal tip fill it back
up with water at the right depth what is
that a right amount of water whatever
the right level throw your nail on there
and get down on some clean tasty dabs
and enjoy the flavor of your dabs again
I really think a clean rig is more
important than people realize alright
that's enough of that PSA I've got more
[ __ ] written down here what else is next
somebody was asking me I got an email or
a Facebook message I cannot recall where
it came from right now but somebody was
asking me about rig selection how do I
choose a good rig personally if you're
dabbing I prefer a small rig over a big
piece the reason we used to smoke pop
out of a giant bong is so that you can
fill all that space with the big thick
chunky hit of smoke and then when you
pull that carb or you pull the bowl out
or you take your finger off however you
carb your bowl or your bong if you're
from the 70s you just take your finger
off that hole in the back if you're from
the future you got to pull the stem out
when you carve it you're supposed to get
all that [ __ ] smoke and your lungs
right at once boom you just got a big ol
bong hit and that's why you get baked
from the bong that's the purpose fill
that piece clear it get all your smoke
when we're smoking dabs your dabs just
burning up right when you put it on the
nail and you start smoking and you're
getting it I don't think we need a big
ass piece for a dab I like the little
tiny rig tour when you put it on there
you put the carb cap on there you inhale
you get that smoke right to your face
we're not trying to build a whole bunch
of smoke into one chamber and then clear
it we just want that dab you go through
the rig through the water to cool and
then into your face so my main
recommendation is something kind of
small my favourite rig and you're gonna
think I'm crazy but my favourite rig is
my hitman sidecar it's just the right
height I'm thinking that's probably five
inches tall something like that if you
go up to the mouthpiece it's probably
seven inches tall it's a little rig I
like my mad Robbery
that suckers probably four inches tall
at the most you don't need a lot of
percolation on a rig if you've got
something that gets plenty of bubbles
you don't need a lot of diffusion all
you want to do is call a cool your dab
smoke you don't want it coming off of
that hot nail directly into your lung so
you put a little water through there
just enough to cool it like I don't like
a lot of water on my rig and also I
think over percolation on a dab like if
you've got too many sections of water
you're kind of overdoing it I like to
Touro cans that have the the tree perk
and then it's got the little showerhead
perk in the middle those are great but
my favorite is the hitman I really do
like the mothership rigs those things
hit like a boss but you're looking at
like 2500 to 3000 for a rig if you're
asking me for advice
you don't need advice on a mothership
get yourself a nice hitman rig don't be
afraid of uh you don't have to buy
name-brand glass just keep in mind that
if you're buying Chinese made glass
there's probably some Chinese little kid
making it in unsafe conditions they
don't have good eye protection they're
probably barefoot
just try to you can buy some American
class to do that it's worth the extra
few bucks just to know that you have
ethically made glass they think it's
some karma like I said hit man's a good
company they don't support the show or
anything but they're always innovators
they leave the glass game in my opinion
if you want to go expensive get yourself
a oil or some beer glass or something
like that coils gonna be ridiculous you
guys I'm just talking about my favorite
rigs here one thing I'm gonna mention so
get a small rig with out a lot of
percolation something that keeps the
nail a little bit away from your face
when you're checking out these rigs at
the store trying to put the nail that
you're gonna buy right on that rig and
then see how far away that nail is from
your face because I don't really like
the nail higher than the mouthpiece or
reel right in my face I needed a couple
inches away from my nose so they can see
where I'm putting the DAP I'd only go
cross-eyed
all right the important part the most
important part when you're buying a rig
is the nail that's what you're heating
up to a couple hundred degrees that's
what you're putting your extract on it's
gonna be heated and cooled and he didn't
cold all the time excuse me I'm burping
here I'm gonna take a drink right quick
excuse me all right I apologize for the
silence I needed a drink so get a good
quality titanium nail the only brand I
will recommend for titanium is
highly-educated titanium they make a
nail for your ring no matter what you're
trying to do highly-educated
has got the perfect nail for you I
promise if you need guidance on the nail
hit me up send me a picture of your rig
I'll tell you what kind of nail to buy I
do really like the quartz nails if you
get a good quality quartz nail
I recommend the Heylin honey hole if you
do big fat dabs if you're into smoking
solvent less and BHO definitely get the
honey hole it holds a lot of heat for
when you smoke solve it list it's got a
lot of room to get a big solvent less
dab in there I also like the clave
banger the clave banger is gonna be a
little bit pricey but they are awesome
they taste super clean who just made the
trough was that Joe Halen they just made
the trough I've not had a chance to try
the trough yet but they look amazing if
it's made out of good quality quartz I
bet it's gonna be a good quartz banger
there is a company that is selling they
call them quartz bangers it's the nail
that it's quartz it looks like a faucets
about kind of with a little bucket at
the end of it they put your dab in the
bucket part guys there's a company
that's selling those that's claiming
their quartz in their glass be careful
you don't want to buy glass and reheat
it and let it cool and reheat it let it
cool it's gonna break you want a good
quartz piece quartz can handle the ship
also we go back to that stuff talking
about what's made in America what's made
in China try to do that with your quartz
products also get a Halen honey hole
get a real clave banger or get yourself
a real highly educated titanium nail
those are the only nails I will support
on this show so come on guys send me
some nails don't really I'm just kidding
I've got all the nails I can use right
now oh so good nail is key that's the
point here also recently I discovered
something that the people in Colorado
may be excited about occasionally kind
love in Denver has occasionally been
putting out clones of my lemon Geoffrey
they were I've actually bought seeds
from me at an event they bought several
packages of seeds and they ran the lemon
Geoffrey and they found their phenotypes
that are killer I've seen the lab tests
they've tested from the 24 to 26 s and
they actually said that they could have
grown the herb better but there was an
issue so that means that next time
you're gonna see 28 to 29 percent on the
limit Geoffrey from kind love so
occasionally you can pick up lemon
Geoffrey clones and kind love and they
are beautiful I've seen pictures of them
their big fat healthy luscious clones I
definitely recommend that call before
you drive they will not reserve a clone
for you so you have to call you have to
say do they have this clone and if they
say yes then you got to get in the car
and haul ass over there because they
will not reserve a clone for you but
they might have it all right I feel like
I'm talking a million miles an hour I'm
gonna press pause take a DAB and then
we're gonna get into some news I'll be
right back guys
the organic portions of this episode
were sponsored by my friends at the
rocky mountain worm company visit the
rocky mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
night crawlers red wigglers and all of
your soil amendments rocky mountain worm
company has dragonfly earth medicine
products in stock right now the Rocky
Mountain worm company will ship to your
door you can get the same warm castings
that I use plus many of the same
amendments I use in my garden through
Rocky Mountain worm company.com check
that out today
[Music]
I'm use the music on the show guys so I
want to talk about some news like I said
but to lead into the news I want to talk
a little bit about a comedy show that I
went to recently Clint and I were
bragging that we got to go see the
taping of Doug loves movies which is one
of my favorite podcasts
Doug Benson is a weed comedian he does a
show called Doug loves movies where they
play games he usually brings three
comedians or some level of superstars to
the show with him and they are his
contestants and they play for the
audience in the audience will win the
prize is based on who wins in the crowd
so Doug loves movies came to comedy
works in downtown Denver you guys know
how much I love comedy works big shot at
the Baker big shot at the comedy works
big shout out to the entire crew there I
felt that coming so Clint and I actually
shot it to Clint Clint drove me up there
because like I said my transmission is
[ __ ] so Clint drove us up there and got
us to the Mellow Mushroom shout out to
the mushroom they always feed us well
got us to comedy works we got to see the
show we talked about Doug's last show
not being up to standards this time we
laughed our asses off he completely
completely made up for the lack of funny
in the last show so I'm catching my
breath after that cough I apologize some
pretty gnarly dabs company thanks for
that I'm gonna read this article I'm
just trying to catch my breath before I
do it you guys know Benson he pulled off
a great show a great podcast you can
listen to the exact episode if you go to
iTunes search for Doug Benson it's Doug
loves movies the episode actually is
titled something about I'm gonna look at
my phone right here so that I can tell
you accurately what it is we're going
there got this iPhone takes a second it
is holy crap he does a lot of episodes
bro it's titled Jeff Teague Julian
McCullough and Ricardo Baca guest and it
was put up on Monday so check that out
if you want to you guys I was sitting in
the front row
shoutout to my friends at Comedy Works I
owe somebody an apology oh I gotta fix
that sound equipment I got this [ __ ]
spiked up I also many
apology a company works a patron I was
gifted the luxury of kind of a lifetime
VI pass for comedy we're a VIP pass for
comedy works as long as I call ahead and
let my friend know that I'm coming I can
get a VIP seat in the front row let them
know how many of us there will be and
they'll put me in the front row as long
as I've got tickets so I called ahead I
made arrangements to have my front-row
privileges I was told that's cool
we got to the club and when it was time
to seat us the seating people kind of
looked at each other with some concern
and the one guy said you [ __ ] up you
go tell him so the one seating person I
don't know what he's called I'm gonna
call him an usher that sounds about
right but the one huh sure dude had to
go tell two people that they had to move
because the seats that they were sitting
in up front had been reserved for Doug's
VIP special guests I felt bad for that
because those people probably waited in
line for a good hour while I was at the
mellow mushroom eating pizza or in the
car taking fat dabs all I'm thinking
about it shoutout to Claude the candy
man I ate a sweet stone kandi Claudia
bare before I went into the show about
two hours before the show and by
Showtime I was sweet stoned for sure
so they had to go and move these two
people because I've got this VIP pass so
they sit Clint and I and the most prime
[ __ ] seats in the club right up front
and it's kind of awkward I could feel
hatred people were staring at us like we
were huge dicks and then eventually the
guy sitting next to us got tired of the
tension and he just said so who the [ __ ]
are you guys and Clint said nobody I'm
with him and they're like who are you
and I was like we're just friends of
Doug's and they said yeah they moved our
friends because you guys are Doug
special guests and I felt kind of like a
[ __ ] for that so we do apologize but
had a great ass time up front that was a
good ass show let's go and read this
article I've been talking for a long
time about it and I've just got an
article written I was excited because
what Doug does dude excuse all the
coughing throat clearing I just took
some gnarly dabs of some gorilla glue
hopefully that was the last one of those
not the good not the dad clearing I was
excited because when he announced his
guests he said Ricardo Baca and I knew
who that was right away and a lot of art
news on this show is written by Ricardo
Baca
so this says commedia podcast listened
to marijuana editor Ricardo Baca on Doug
loves movies comedians Jeff Tate and
Julian McCullough joined weed editor
Ricardo Baca on Doug Benson's popular
movie podcast of course this came out
May 11th and it was in the cannabis it's
written by Ricardo Baca it says talk
about nerves as as 4:20 p.m. Denver time
approached on May 10th
aka Mother's Day I was sitting in comm
unit Comedy Works greenroom with some
insanely talented stand-up comics
getting ready to take the stage for a
taping of my single favorite podcast in
the world comic Doug Benson also a legit
weed hero had generously asked me to be
a guest on his movie podcast Doug loves
movies after seeing the marijuana
journalism documentary rolling papers at
the South by Southwest Film Festival -
fun I'm gonna jump in right here
I mentioned rolling papers a movie a
camera crew followed what's the name
Ricardo Baca around for a year and
followed members of his staff in part of
the newspaper they followed him for an
entire year and recorded and made a
documentary about the journalism
marijuana journalism that has developed
in Colorado and they've dubbed the movie
rolling papers it was purchased after
its first showing at the South by
Southwest festival so that's coming out
in the future um I'll keep you guys
updated when that comes out excuse all
the coffee
I apologize at the weed show you get it
I hope you're coughing with me then the
article goes on to say and then the
nerves came on lots of people listen to
this I thought but after my mean after
meeting my fellow guests whip-smart
comedians Jeff Tate and Julian
McCullough
and seeing Benson again I knew we were
in for a good time the podcast taping
was a blast the sold-out crowd at Comedy
Works was super rad and Benson's team
took less than 24 hours to launch it and
he means the podcast you know everyone
can listen via the embedded Doug loves
movies site or iTunes so yeah if you go
to Doug loves
dot-com or go to iTunes you can listen
to it it was a great great podcast
ricardo Baca did quite damn well he was
on stage with three weighty top level
comedians and he held his own he did not
try to step up and be a comedian he
remained Ricardo Baca and I respected
him for that he left the comedians
comedy and he did his job and was the
person that they invited because my
throat is tickly I'm gonna press pause
for a second I'll be right back with
another news article excuse me and I
apologize oh my gosh you guys wouldn't
believe what I just spit up I should
have took a picture of that for you man
I should have recorded the sound of that
hitting or ever it landed that was thick
here's the side note on the Cannabis the
strain of the day is golden goat thought
that's cool people will often credit me
for making the golden goat I did not
invent the golden goat I simply put it
into feminized seed for the world to
enjoy golden goat was created by mr.
Dane in Topeka Kansas shut up mr. Dane
oh I'm catching my breath I'm sure you
can hear that a little bit but we are
gonna read another news article gonna
fix some recording equipment and blowing
some [ __ ] up I've got the air
conditioner next to me and I don't think
you guys can hear it but the recording
equipment is struggling to keep me in
this [ __ ] air conditioner separate
the recording here it's pretty neat
watching the lights light up anyway this
one hits close to home because I do live
in Pueblo Colorado I am actually the
grower at a very popular dispensary in
Pueblo West Colorado Pueblo West is like
a sub development just outside of the
city of Pueblo it's about 10 minutes to
the west
obviously it's Pueblo West it's a little
nicer it's exactly complete a little
completely a little nicer it's newer so
it doesn't have old town problems it
doesn't have the old rickety parts of
town so it looks a lot nicer
we also have a part that we call the
county which if you drive outside of
city limits there are a lot of stores
and shopping areas in the county and the
county and Pueblo West are allowed to
have dispensaries but the city of Pueblo
has not been allowed dispensaries I'm
going to read an article that came out
May 12th apologize for this throat I
just took some gnarly dad's I'll quit
taking so many dad's on the show so that
you guys can hear me also come be on the
show talk to me talk while I'm clearing
my throat and you guys can give me a
break this article says pueblos
pawnshops voters will decide whether to
allow retail sales in November it's only
by the aps who gets credit for this
pueblos bubble lawmakers are letting the
voters decide whether to allow
recreational marijuana shops in their
city the public often reports concerned
residents filled the city council
chambers Monday night many wearing
yellow shirts that said voice your
choice and urging their elected
officials to put the issue to voters
councilman Bob shilling was the only
vote in favor of licensing retail pot
shops but said that he hasn't opposed a
vote in November several of the six
council members who voted against
adopting the ordinance had been in favor
before the public hearing including
President Steve Nawrocki excuse me guys
I'm sorry he said there isn't the issue
isn't worth dividing the public over
they did vote and they did decide to
push back the vote there will be no
recreational or medical marijuana shops
in the city of Pueblo until they vote
again which will be in November so you
guys if you live in Pueblo
you have to drive 15 minutes to the
county or to Pueblo West to go purchase
your cannabis and then drive back and
then the city that you live in isn't
getting your tax money for the cannabis
that you're able to purchase because of
these stupid [ __ ] regulations that
Pablo's been juggling with
I've been in the legal medical marijuana
industry in this city since should we
had the first shop I think that was nine
years ago when we had Madame our
downtown and since that is closed there
has not been another medical shop or a
recreational shop in the city that was
legally licensed there have been places
that popped up randomly and we're closed
but I think it's kind of [ __ ] I
shouldn't use the word [ __ ] that's
mean to the [ __ ] people I think it's
a ridiculous and stupid that we are not
allowed to have a recreational cannabis
shop within city limits they need the
tax money this town is broke and hurtin
bunch of weed money would really help
this city here's another news article
that I found interesting it says castle
rock man pleads guilty to mail in
Colorado pot across the country this one
is written by Anthony cotton of the
Denver Post it was published May 12th
here's you're gonna you're gonna catch
on right away my point when I start
reading this it says a Castle Rock man
pleaded guilty on charges that included
sending more than a hundred packages
that included marijuana to locations
across the country and receiving several
hundred thousand dollars through the
mail in return according to you
according to the United States District
Attorney's Office Bryan Daniel Evans age
42 began mailing pot packages in April
of 2014 he continued through that fall
haven't pleaded guilty this April
officials said Evans first came under
suspicion on April 2nd 2014 when the US
postal inspector came across a
suspicious mailing they may have
contained narcotics or narcotic proceeds
the first package in question came from
Missouri and it contained cash that
package was sent to a commercial mail
receiving agency mailbox and was
addressed to an individual in lonetree
an ongoing investigation traced the car
under surveillance to Evans who has also
seen mailing parcels from post offices
in the metro area
officials said inspectors also conducted
search a search of Alvin's apartment
that that search recovered 580 grams of
bag marijuana 800 grams of marijuana
extract or hash oil wow that's a lot of
hash oil bro that's close to two pounds
five thousand four hundred eighty grams
of marijuana edibles for a total weight
of six thousand eight hundred and sixty
grams of marijuana wait a minute you
guys heard that stupid [ __ ] in there
right five thousand four hundred eighty
grams of marijuana edibles they're
[ __ ] weighing the brownies and
charging him with the weight of the
[ __ ] brownies for the grams of Pop
that's [ __ ] wack bro that is
inaccurate that's not cool that's like
when the baggie - you can't do that man
that this whole article is [ __ ] up
this guy should not have done that but
that part right there is wrong the
article a search of his vehicle found an
additional 78 grams of liquid marijuana
he probably had some team sure you guys
he had previously mailed two additional
packages that were seized by law
enforcement those packages contained
three thousand six hundred and
fifty-four grams of marijuana in total
inspectors learned that Elvin sent
eleven thousand 26 grams of marijuana
law enforcement also had seized during
the investigation more than 53,000
dollars in cash which was the proceeded
proceeds from his illegal narcotics
transaction that money was forfeited to
the government as part of Elvis plea
agreement
Alvin's pled guilty to three account
three counts of possession of a
controlled substance with the intent to
distribute he now faces more than twenty
years in federal prison and up to a 1
million dollar fine per count so my
point here people is quit mailing weed
out of Colorado unless you want to end
up in federal prison doing 20 years and
facing up to 1 million dollars in fines
per count there are several reasons we
shouldn't be mailing cannabis out of
state you guys first off it's illegal
and you're gonna go to prison and you're
gonna get butt raped doesn't sound like
fun to me doesn't sound like the [ __ ]
profit I'm making from it not at all
second of all in Colorado the people
that have fought hard to legalize
cannabis medically and recreationally we
did it for here and you're [ __ ] it up
by mailing it somewhere else it's very
small where ever you're sending it
they're responsible for legalizing
cannabis in their area not us and by
sending it out you're [ __ ] up what we
work hard for we're making something
shiny we've got a system that works we
have created laws
we're playing by the rules and then
you're gonna be a [ __ ] [ __ ] and
take the rules that we've made even grow
and smoke all the weed you want you can
also weed in Colorado quit sitting it
out of state you don't need to do that
that's [ __ ] it up making everybody
look bad and you're gonna get caught and
get butt-rape and go to jail you get all
read about you in the future keep
sinning that [ __ ] I will proudly read
your name and laugh at you on the show
don't send cannabis out of state that's
[ __ ] my point you guys get it right
everywhere
do your part contact your local Congress
people go to City Council meetings do
that [ __ ] where you are and get it
legalized in your area so that you don't
have to give them there's not enough
herb here people are hurtin for herbs
there are patients that want cannabis
that don't have any medicine here and
we're sending that [ __ ] to other states
to make a profit that's [ __ ] up take
the money out of cannabis put more
compassion into cannabis that's what I'm
saying what else do I have for you we've
got 30 minutes what so let's just chat
for a minute I have promised you a
scheduling episode I told you I was
gonna do an episode about scheduling
your drove for a perpetual cycle I'm
having block I don't know how many
lights you have so I don't know how to
write a perpetual cycle for your room
but I have found a solution so I'm
writing it based on that we'll get it
together that'll probably be one or two
episodes away the other episode I have
been teasing about is improving your
garden so I was gonna say top 10 ways to
improve your garden I've got about 30
ways written down that could be a long
episode that is definitely coming I
don't want to talk too much about any of
that stuff because we'll just save it
for the actual show I want to give a
huge shot at again to Clint and Baker
also a big shout out to Comedy Works big
shout out to everybody who has helped me
deal with not having a car this week or
this weekend that's been a real pain in
the ass you guys if we had some plans
that I had to cancel or rearrange I
apologize we had a blown transmission my
Chevrolet's will get me so far but the
weather has been shitty and I'm stuck so
you gotta come to me so you want to take
some dad there if you want to be able to
podcast you got to come to me I'm gonna
wrap up the show you guys you pay a lot
more attention to a 35 40 minutes
episode than you do those hour shows let
me know what you think
yeah go to uh stitcher or iTunes or
Twitter or Facebook or email me and tell
me if you prefer the 30-minute episodes
over the hour-long episodes I think it's
better when I do two 30-minute episodes
instead of the long hour and you guys
really listen more my throat doesn't
[ __ ] up as much if we have a guest we'll
go an hour but it's just me I'm gonna
try to go about 30 and try to do two
episodes a week it's better for
everybody that way in my opinion let me
know what you think the show isn't just
for me the show is a lot for you so
thanks for listening guys I'm gonna wrap
it up I'll be back in a few days with
another episode probably about ways to
improve your garden but don't forget to
check out our sponsors to Rocky Mountain
worm company if you guys are interested
in sponsoring the podcast or if you have
a product you'd like me to review send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all of the
information that you need guys now that
the show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for a girl
from your heart find the review section
give me a five star rating and then
after that type in a comment and let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comment on a future
episode stitcher keeps changing the way
the comments are handled so leave a
comment there and I will do my best to
find it if you have something you're not
into the social media thing you can't
email me like I said earlier square for
me hard at hotmail.com if you want to
find me on twitter it's at gfy each
podcast or at rasta Jeff 420 that also
works make sure you follow
I read genetics on Instagram we just hit
15,000 followers big up to everybody
that follows us on Instagram I
appreciate that also don't forget to the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is forever archived
on I read genetics Colorado dot-com we
did add that donation button on the
podcast page guys my transmission blew
the [ __ ] up so to tell you the truth as
of what episode is this this is number
70 that adventure that we were talking
about from my daughter the deadline for
that was the first so the new Pay Pal
button that goes to my transmission from
here on out straight-up honest about
that [ __ ] so yeah go to the website
it's IRA Genetics Colorado com click on
the girl from your heart podcast tab at
the top right there's a little PayPal
logo
click on that throw in a dollar throw in
five dollars throw in five hundred
dollars transmission is $2,600 so we're
working our way toward that we'll get
there don't worry guys I got it I'll
never charge you for this podcast it's
always gonna be free but if you feel
like making a contribution saying thank
you that it's definitely appreciated I
feel like I'm baking now let's get away
from this we're on all the social media
sites already said that guys thanks for
listening to me clear my throat a bunch
of times the next episode will be more
educational yeah shout out to my ninja
Spence
shout out to Maddy shatters the garden
of Weeden sloppy big shout out brother I
read about your medical issue and I need
to visit with you I don't have a car we
need to get together a DAB and smoke bro
I want to talk to you about that big
shout-out to sloppy love you sloppy well
if you like family so until next time
you guys take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
all right podcast wrote I wanna thank
you again for listening to a long
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast I'll be back Monday with the
fresh episode until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me