[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 227 and grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff wanna
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots men I let him use their music on
my podcast big shout out to cat food in
the entire mystic roots crew I did it
Mike I made it all the way through the
intro without a cough without a wheeze
betta sneeze well done sir
Oh ladies and gentlemen welcome to the
show white Mike Mike is back what's up
everybody how you doing today bro you're
doing great doing very well man uh can
we announce your your new situation on
the show here can we talk about that
should I ask you first I guess what can
do a little bit Dennis so uh most of you
folks probably know that I am the lead
cultivator high in the cult leader at
Three Rivers cultivation ah and now Mike
is officially on board he is part of the
Three Rivers Parvati now part of the
Cole thanks for joining the Cole with
this you drank the kool-aid is the only
place that's good to get outs to feel
special for hearing that yeah this is
the official the official announcement
if you want to a stock Mike on the on
the social medias you should follow me
an emo Punk 15 on Twitter I need to also
check out his Facebook page it's pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws yes I try to
do a decent intro for my guys yeah you
got a point Mike might post a whole
bunch of great cannabis related news and
information there's there are several
Facebook pages that are cannabis haters
and they like to post a bunch of
[ __ ] and Mike only post the truth I
support 99% of what Mike post and what I
don't agree with is just like
opinionated stuff from other writers
having opinions on things the science
and the facts on the politics
I [ __ ] agree right it's it's fun
because I hate on that page from both
sides of the cannabis argument I get
activists that are upset that I won't
post their latest meme and I think it
anti-pop people pissed that I exist at
all and keep the bunking there [ __ ]
the meme game is a whole different
that's that's middle school and we're
trying to play college level cannabis
politics here likes to take you late the
argument is sort of the pages basic go
ahead and feed that music at its awkward
limits that lowering it down let me do a
little correction on the last episode
there's a group called pl grow that's
gonna send me a test item they've got a
product for me to review I haven't quite
gotten it to me I've been in contact
with them I [ __ ] up you guys I said
they are from Australia they're not from
Australia they're from the UK so
correction important correct people you
know I felt bad they emailed me like
just one small thing we're from the UK
yeah yeah I apologize you guys and now
you got to shout outs on the show
instead of just one because I made a
mistake
alright so gosh Mike I don't know what
happened dude Mike went down to go smoke
a cigarette before the podcast and while
he was out there I just started coughing
my throat just started acting like man
and my lung started juicing up on me and
before the show my traditional cough
didn't really materialize did you get it
I may have taken your cough I may have a
sympathy cough for you is that possible
is that a real thing - her magic bro
magic sympathy dab cough I took plenty
of dads maybe I had a delayed cough I
was smoking some of the uh what did I
have the Killer Queen I can have
annoying full-spectrum extract it was
really tasty I made me dad now but after
a couple of minutes it just made me
start like he starts heating the Banger
and immediately the room smelled
delicious that's because I've been
smoking ah the beautiful miss Jenny Beth
went to apothecary and she got some of
the Clementine she got the I don't know
I think she had the high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract and I picked up
some of the high turk full-spectrum
extract so we were tag-team dabbing each
other and then we went a little hard on
the Terps and put in the nail and it
just tastes like that forever and then
I've been pouring a lot of B I've got
these little lemon Jeffrey
Turpin full-spectrum extract that's the
flavor I just pour this in there dude I
just pour these little things like but
two maybe three or four drops depending
on where I'm trying to go should a small
dab and four drops of this hey dude you
just blow clouds and there's something
there's cannabinoids in this it's not
just pure Terps but it's mostly Terps
turfs have a lot to do with where the
high goes absolutely absolutely i think
i think the THC makes you go it makes
you go up and then the Terps to decide
if you get the munchies if you get an i
high if you get creative if you want to
do the dishes if you get panicky I think
the Terps are all about pain relief pain
relief okay there's a bunch of different
stuff that the Terps are affecting it's
not just fun aspects the hi it's it's
medical aspects of it too
alright I think the limonene which is
what this is names that's my personal
take I feel like that so I doubt a way
too much on the show I've got a brain
injury
sometimes it feels like my brain skips
like an old CD like and I could feel it
it just like the song will be played a
lot of people are going what remember
CDs you guys back in the day these
silver shiny things so a lot of those
used to skip anyway you it would sound
like this boom dude dude sometimes my
brain does the key part and it's from a
[ __ ] traumatic brain injury there's a
dent in my brain where information skips
I don't know it sometimes there it goes
uh and it seems like dumb [ __ ] that I
don't really need to remember is what
left a lot of the important [ __ ] has
been coming back right but I feel like
the limonene puts a little patch in the
divot it puts some bondo in the brain
dent and it helps that the bridge they
got broken it helps it reconnect you
when I get the black cherry flavor okay
I I know that along with that flavor I'm
gonna get a really nice hit of pain
relief in about four to eight minutes
okay and it's part that cannabinoids
that's really helpful with the pain
relief CBD CBD op sorry on Friday I can
tell you can think about CBD I
looking at new lights flashing on the
board across from me and I got
distracted and dabbed out sorry folks
turn off the iPad CD and then common
terpenes that you find alongside CBD
that add that flavor to it my tongue
knows that like when that hits my eyes
light up and I start looking for where
it came from and where I can get more of
it I did an episode a while back called
follow your nose because I believe that
your body and your nose know what's best
for you that's why that's why oranges
smell and I said this in the other
episode I'm just repeating myself at
this point but that's why I said oranges
smell good and [ __ ] smells bad you're
supposed to eat oranges oranges make you
feel good they have vitamin C their
natural sugar there's fiber there's
other stuff in there I don't know
there's fiber in there but I assume
it'll be fiber and calcium in the
goddamn orange [ __ ] you're not supposed
to eat that that's why it smells bad
there's [ __ ] in there it's already been
done there's a reason 99% of people
salivate when they smell me over fire
yeah like that's how people didn't die
of starvation for most of our history
when you like when you're in a
supermarket you're just a little bit
hungry
and you get hit with that fresh fruit
smell like off the oranges for me yeah
just stare at him and I'm like alright I
have to buy four yep that doesn't happen
so much with the pears for me
miss Jenny Beth she loves oranges
oranges is her turf that's the one that
fixes her her that's her medical and her
recreational smoke my kid was mad for
citrus anything citrus I love the lemon
Terps my friend Kelly she doesn't smoke
cannabis you met Kelly she doesn't
consume cannabis but she hates the smell
of oranges she's like orange anything I
can't stand it like so I'm curious she
live endure is what she likes she told
me that lavender and lilacs are her type
of thing which is really funny because
lilacs in lavender make me feel like I
inhaled something I feel part of C I
like all three of those yeah lilacs and
lavender are not for me but the - don't
make me hungry and the third one does
they're supposed to be calming and
relaxing smells and they honestly just
bother the [ __ ] out of me I'm not a calm
and relaxed person my whole house reeks
of lavender like constantly we use on
everything
all right no I won't be back ladies
gentlemen I do have a podcast plan but I
love the comfort of when you just show
up bro it's fun working with you now
this wasn't a planned show necessarily
it was we both finally found 45 free
minutes yeah yes like bro what are you
doing night he's like I don't know
podcasts I guess come over and so he
called me and he's here dude thanks for
taking time away from the kid yeah and
the wife also shout-out to Jen I know
you don't listen but hey shout out wife
so let's move on to some [ __ ] on a
podcast bro we promised them a show
let's talk about some stuff ok so
somebody the other day a friend of mine
is willing to grow and he was like so
Rasta Jeff what is the secret weapon is
there a magic bullet for my grow that I
can buy it will give me the highest THC
the best flavor the biggest yields what
can i buy ok so my answer is yes and I
have a specific reason and a specific
bullet ok what's your answer oh I want
to hear yours because I get to talk a
lot on a show do a hundred percent yes
there's a magic bullet it's a [ __ ]
grow book why the girl book read the
grow book that's your Silver Bullet well
there goes the episode I wrote I'm
[ __ ] we're done take a fat dad view
remote for me there's a reason that's
the only silver bullet if you've never
grown cannabis before you don't know
what you're getting into you don't know
what the parameters are you don't know
what its needs are and are going to be
down the line as it progresses through
its lifecycle he's the easiest way to
get that [ __ ] figured out and get going
successfully is to go to a book store
pick out a Negro book on the shelf buy
and read it
this guy's got two or three of the best
cannabis growers as teachers I'm one of
his teachers he sees me on a daily basis
he's got another guy that is a very good
teacher that's been to his grow also and
will help him out but he was in you're
right bike you're you're [ __ ] so
right I I can't believe I didn't tell
him yes go buy a damn grow book dude but
I was like no honestly there is no one
magic bullet he thought that if he
bought a specific light
he would do it he thought that maybe I
could tell him by this bottle and it
would do it but I had to tell him
there's no secret weapon do there's no
ninja sword there's no you can't just
get one thing Oh what I had to explain
him was and this is just my opinion the
girl book is the secret weapon you guys
to everything knowledge is key so go get
yourself a girl book I recommend there's
an n rows and Thal book it's the
Oaksterdam course guide I highly
recommend that book that is a good book
the problem with the Gro book is like
every six months they're [ __ ]
outdated that's why I do a podcast well
the nice thing about any grow any grow
guide I mean even some of the more
advanced ones the more topical ones
they're gonna cover the basics and I
mean it's like anything there is an
advanced class knowing a lot more will
produce some significantly better
results but if you know the basic rules
of the game you can take your ass to any
[ __ ] field and play right and if you
sit down and read a Negro book it's
gonna lay out here's the ABCDE basic
level one checklist that you need to go
through you know here's what you need to
know super basic about lighting rights
what you need to know super basic about
feeding light and dark periods
harvesting here's a small list of common
pitfalls that people fall into look out
for right you actually just nailed a
couple of things that I was gonna what I
was gonna mention to the person that
asked me this question I told it
basically what I told was there's no
magic secret weapon it's everything yeah
everything is what matters the most it's
you have to dial in everything the
plants start at a ten the plants start
at their highest potential they are
tense and basically we [ __ ] them up by
limiting them so you have to find out
how to limit them and get out of their
way as much as you can you have to and I
wrote down la WS laws is something that
every grower should know about its
lights air water and soil those are the
main things you need to worry about you
have to have the best lighting you can
get I I suggest that you have to have
the best you get put the best lighting
you can afford and maintain and maintain
in your grow space yes if you've got a
small space don't put a 2000 watt [ __ ]
it's
in there if you've got a small space go
get yourself a t5 go get yourself a
[ __ ] LED and put it in the small
space if you've got big space put big
lights in there oh yeah every time I
answer this question the person I'm
talking to seems incredibly hesitant to
take the advice of go by the book
because they're excited it can't be that
hard it's a weed your high ass can do it
right it doesn't seem complicated at the
beginning and honestly if you could just
take the seed you found in your bag out
in your backyard in water with your
sprinklers like you do your flowerbed
and not get robbed and killed or
arrested for doing so it would be a lot
simpler but because you're attempting to
take something out of its environment
and create an environment where it will
thrive artificially there's some ground
rules that you just need to familiarize
yourself with and honestly when until
you sit down and write the book you
don't really like triple-check am i
hitting every point that a new person is
gonna need to know be successful I went
and did a consult for a dude when I was
first starting out doing consulting and
I forgot like three important things
when I was there the first day that I
didn't think about till I got home and I
said the dude along he goes look dude
I'm really sorry but this this and this
don't know why that didn't occur to me
yesterday really sorry I didn't include
all of this information during your
physical consult
feel free to ask me more questions over
email
sorry bro not driving back northglenn
but it just happens in when you get to
the point of publishing a grou guide you
and a couple other growers have gone
over and been like yep bro you hit all
the steps that's how you go from the
dugout to home plate right once you got
the book you still got to worry about
you've got the grill built and now your
plants are growing and you still can't
just buy one thing to put in that grow
you've got to get good lights and then
you got to get I recommend the kavita's
if you've got a big space if you've got
a little space if they could be to 750 s
or the 650 s and then just work your way
down based on your space then you need
good nutrients if you don't have and
there's no magic nutrients you can buy
you got to do
the research and you got to find figure
out if you want to use organic figure
out if you want to use non-organic
figure out it's up to you how you want
to do it it's all the more non organic
and this may a lot of people are gonna
argue with me but this is my opinion the
more non-organic you go the more bottle
base you get the more simple it is but
when you work more towards the organics
there's a little more work to it but
it's also a little more pleasing product
to some people to know it's all organic
Mike just gave me kind of a know there's
there's boy I know a couple of organic
people that like they could spend three
years trying to teach me their method
and I'd only know a part of it right
right and I know bottled people the same
way I was just picturing in my head the
full advanced line you can do everything
the advanced nutrients line does with
veg bloom and two or three bottles of
extra additives and this is where taking
the time to do a little research and
education comes in incredibly handy go
to the gross store ask the person behind
the counter doesn't ask the gross tour
dude the gross tour dude is paid to sell
a certain [ __ ] brand he uses this
brand one thing that pisses me off about
gross stores and it also happens at
Guitar Center it happens it Best Buy you
go somewhere and Guitar Center is
[ __ ] notorious for this do you like
hey I want to buy these kind of
drumsticks the drum guy goes [ __ ] those
sticks bro I played these sticks they're
all that [ __ ] matter and he spins his
sticks and flips his hair around like
he's cooler than everybody and I'm like
I don't [ __ ] care about your emo band
I want these sticks that came for and so
I feel like they do the same [ __ ] at
gross virgia like a man I came to buy
botanic and like [ __ ] the tiny camera I
use psycho bro that's all that matters
and they treat you like they're better
than you and I would like push whatever
brand whose rep has a special going on
that month or whichever brand threw them
free [ __ ] yeah or whichever brand gave
them a [ __ ] hammers about to expire
look and see what shirt they're wearing
and if that's what they're pitching you
I mean somebody's [ __ ] doing it it's
yeah so there are plenty of places to do
your research on what's new and what's
what's gear to get I have been using for
years botanic air pure blend Pro they've
been bought out by a company that I'm
not sure I want to support so when I run
out of botanic air pure blend Pro
product pure blend of pro of products
that's hard to [ __ ] to say winner is
high
I think I'm going to switch to another
brand if it is small and I don't know if
I want to say the name of the company on
the show right now because I I'm gonna
switch to new millennium I'll be using
veg bloom base with new millennium
additives and shine and plus life and
mammoth peat that's what I plan on
switching to in the long run it'll be a
slow process because I've got a lot of
botanic hair products left but once
those are gone it'll be replaced with
new millennium yeah but [ __ ] happens
it's big companies and that's gonna
happen so I would recommend veg bloom is
great if you want something simple a veg
bloom
I like the veg bloom the one for the
dirty it's it's called dirty it's for
hard water most you guys probably live
in an area where you've got hard water
so you want the dirty veg bloom dirty
I had shine add plus life spring with
push and then maybe add like some
mammoth pee it's not even necessary if
you're using the plus life I was using
the mammoth pee to start him to get him
going faster and then maybe something
you might need some cal-mag in there
maybe a kelp product just to beat them
up but honestly the plus the veg bloom
with the plus life the shine and the
push spray is you can get through the
whole process with that if what Jeff
said just now didn't make a lot of sense
to you please go buy the book or go to
the vegetable website they don't pay me
or anything I just like the veg bloom
products they're super easy to use and
they give great results and listen to
back episodes of the show or the correct
strain for cush type strains veg blooms
[ __ ] awesome for other strains it
doesn't do as well if you've got like an
OG Kush or a grateful dog type of strain
the veg bloom will do wonderfully it
felt like I was trying to get it
something else
but for certain strains it'll do a
really good job it's real simple
oh it's gonna say to go to hydroponic
research com hydroponic - research calm
that's the veg bloom website all their
informations there they'll be feed
charts it's real easy just there's
[ __ ] three three dry products and a
foliar spray super simple I'm gonna quit
pitching bedroom there pay me so you got
good nutrients you have to get your pH
dialed in you have to find out what pH
those plants like start at 6 5 and see
what
with your planets learn how do I
identify pH problems raise them up or
down if you need to
I hardly ever check the pH of my soil I
haven't ever checked the pH of the soil
in the [ __ ] commercial reason Coco
I've never checked the pH of the Coco at
the commercial girl I checked the runoff
I checked the pH of the runoff and I
checked the EC the electrical
conductivity of the runoff but I do not
check the [ __ ] Coco itself I can tell
what's going on by what goes in and what
comes out another thing you to keep in
mind is the co2 you guys are you on
menteng co2 you can give it a lot of co2
the natural environment rocks around 400
ppm s of co2 depends on where you are
these plants can take I've seen people
push them up in the 2200 ppm of car wash
to run around 15 yeah we rock about 1500
at the big row but you can push them
temperatures you've got a dial in
temperatures do you have temperature
swings is it too hot during the day is
it too cold during the night is it too
hot during the night too cold during the
day any of that is gonna [ __ ] with your
planet so there's no one magic thing so
far I've already read off like a list of
seven or eight things moisture in the
soil moisture in the room floor
temperature temperature I I've got a
tour of a major facility not that long
ago plants on concrete in February
[ __ ] yeah you can't do that in
Colorado take off your shoes and walk
around on the concrete that's the first
time I saw that in a how to build your
grow room video dude in the video is he
showing people how to build his little
room in Amsterdam bust his shoes and
socks off and walks around on the floor
he's like this is way too cold and he
goes and installs some pads on the floor
yeah and I just rocked my world I never
would have thought of that before but it
get huge effect you've got these pots
filled with dirt and roots and then
you're gonna pour water into it it's
gonna get cold it's ice cold on that
floor yep and if you're in a warehouse
or a basement it's gonna get you super
chilly the acronym you gave out earlier
I like that the four points that it hid
and I liked it it spelled out laws it's
the laws is the one thing we didn't
bring up so far in [ __ ] you should take
a minute to look up if you want to be
successful growing dude the local laws
you're gonna want to know those
they're gonna apply they're gonna impact
yeah we live in a legal state it's
totally legal to grow here the smell of
marijuana is no longer probable cause in
Colorado I had cops pounding on my door
wondering if I knew my neighbor because
they thought he was growing in why he
wouldn't answer his door and I was like
he ain't home bro and they're like what
do you mean and I was like there's six
cars in the driveway but the one he
drives every day they're like have a
nice day and they's you know kept
talking to me and they're like yeah we
know he's growing a whole bunch of weed
because and get this folks they accused
him of screwing up people's cable
connections and their radio frequencies
in the area with his little tiny home
grill with the right amount of ballasts
that's actually possible with the right
equipment in the right number of pieces
you can [ __ ] with radio frequencies a
little bit but you can't [ __ ] with no
people's cable right they're just trying
to face just cause sense it was the the
other person that was staying with me at
the time mentioned something about our
cable while the cop happened to be
standing in earshot and so he tried to
like use it as a in in with me like
Brody did a jerk next door that's
growing weed is poking up your TV it's
just nonsense trying to find a way to
your friend I know for a fact that dude
next door is 100% illegal cuz he showed
off his grow to me one night like super
proud of having finished building it and
like I high-fived him and like made sure
to wash my clothes right after cuz it
wasn't pro status but um it was small
and couldn't possibly fit one six plants
let alone exceed any sort of limit but
even in our little place there worried
about it and if it's not the cops that
notice that you're growing weed and are
interested in it it's the neighborhood
teenagers or the creepy biker dude up
the street like just you're gonna want
to think about all that stuff before you
go down this road because if you don't
that's where the really nasty problems
and headaches and black guys for the
community come in the duties throws 30
plants in his backyard stinks out the
neighborhood and ends up shooting one of
the local teenagers during harvest right
right this guy this guy's doing an
indoor girl you know who this just look
up the local laws
you know how to best protect yourself
and in what parameters you want to
operate under yes it's just a good good
another point to look up is oh it's
something that goes right along with the
type of nutrients you're gonna buy I
think the type of that shows you know
those the kind of person you are the
type of nutrients you buy the amount
yeah the amount of attention you pay to
the WHA that's all gonna reflect in your
garden and the type of person that you
are but all right let's focus back down
on here a little bit Mike wants you to
buy books and follow the rules a lot you
guys ah
I want to give a lot of credit to what
I'm talking about to a guy known as soma
soma is a cannabis breeder he's an old
hippie he's got some dreadlocks he wears
a bunch of crystals he's kind of a weird
dude I kind of used to look up to him
quite a bit he teaches us about a thing
called mimetics he says if there are 64
squares on the chess board and every one
of them is an opportunity to improve or
[ __ ] up your garden so think about where
you're putting your kings and queens on
the chessboard and play chess the best
that you can I'm a medics that's all the
things in your environment I did not
Google this word this is just from my
memory from what soma told me my medics
is all the things in your environment
combined every little detail that you
can see and cannot see can't control and
cannot control those are mimetics the
way that Mike is looking off into the
distance right now like he's confused
that is part of the mimetics of my
environment even though it doesn't
affect me it is still part of it somehow
it's the mimetics of this room the
airflow coming out of that duct that's
one of the things on my chessboard that
light coming from above that's one of
the things on my chessboard the window
open over there that's one of the parts
of my chess where those are all
affecting my environment in my
performance right now and every one of
those things has a very small impact the
dr. pepper the water the dad rig all of
those things have this bone right here
is distracting so all those things have
a few pieces of mimetics on my chest
where your plants have the same option
in the grow so every piece every piece
of dust in there as part of that grow
environment is affecting that plant in
some weird way so shout out to soma for
putting the mimetics idea into my head
that kind of put a lot of it opened up a
lot of stuff in my brain it's super
important I mean you're really creating
an artificial environment for a life in
the amount of little pieces that can
impact that in the environment you
create is just limitless how many times
have we stood in the same grow room
looking for new issues issues we haven't
seen before issues that have come up
since the last cleaning and just knowing
what to look out for it takes a long
time to to be able to look into a space
and think okay if I'm gonna do a small
grow here these are the things that are
gonna be major issues here these are the
things I'm gonna need to upgrade or
purchase or this is the kind of size I
could get away with just taking the time
to understand what your parameters are
it's gonna help you out a lot like it's
hard to know where to put the pieces on
a chessboard if you don't know how to
play the game not sure that mimetics is
the word I'm looking for now that I'm
kind of looking at Wikipedia but shot it
to someone for teaching me a word I
[ __ ] forgot I could be Maddox this is
the Wikipedia for mimetics isn't really
not what I wanted one thing I wrote down
is you can't put turbos on an 86 Ford
Escort and expect to win a race if
you're gonna build a race car you got to
get a racing transmission you've got to
get yourself a racing steering wheel you
need a racing harness a lot of you
[ __ ] need a helmet I figured a
race you got to get all the racing gear
you can't just throw up some big lights
and think that that was the main point
of this question you can't just buy one
thing you've got to get it all correct
and if you've got a budget I would say
start with the lights then go nutrients
then work on the soil and then then
spend your budget where you can
otherwise don't just go best lights and
then shitty soil and shitty nutrients
you gotta kind of figure out where to
spread the spread
um we used to joke all the time that
there should be a cannabis Protective
Services people you could call to come
in and rescue plants that were
essentially being tortured to death by
morons and universally it was people who
loved cannabis wanted to produce their
own cannabis had a huge passion for
growing and not a single [ __ ] clue
about how to go about it
and did they they had you know a six
hundred dollar budget and went to the
grocer and bought a $580 light and then
a $2.00 watering can and a $3.00 pot and
said I got what I need they went home
they dug up some soil out of the
backyard in the pot they planted their
little plant
they stuck it under their giant light
and a 95 degree garage and shut the door
and called it a grow room
you see something like that and you feel
bad for the person because you know
there's they drop their whole nut on a
lot one piece of gear that's not useful
on its own and now you're running that
white it's just gonna cost and now
they're out the cost of that light every
month extra that's money that they could
be saving to buy the two pieces of gear
to make that one secure to the dudes
house and he had the LED light like 13
feet off the ground and that [ __ ]
plant he's like look how much this plant
is grown in the past couple days I was
like bro there's like a foot and a half
between node spacing that thing is not
growing that's called stretching and it
was in a pot the size of like a 1 liter
soda bottle yeah sorry I don't make fun
of that poor guy but if you would have
just thought about it and put that lot
the right light or put that light closer
to the plant he would add much more
success yeah I mean just where he was
playing video games is it a weed plant
next to him playing video games I can't
tell you how many people I've seen chain
smoking cigarettes in their grow room
because they heard somewhere that the
plants like extra carbon dioxide and
they heard somewhere that carbon dioxide
is something that comes off cigarettes
yummy and they take - technically true
pieces of information slam them together
in their head in a way that sort of
makes sense on surface and then they
can't figure out why their plants are
super sick it's like because you're
blowing that toxic smoke at them like
it's it's not good for oh you don't like
it I know so many people whose their the
big problem and they're Gro turned out
to be their dog likes to piss on their
plants oh that's awesome yeah I know who
that was I've seen it happiness three or
four people it happened to the one
[ __ ] dude you're thinking of like six
times but I mean some people are slower
learners because keep your pets and your
cigarettes out of your grow room a lot
of people like to take pictures of their
dogs and their cats in their grow room
but I think got bugs bro no matter how
clean he is but he's covered burgers got
bugs he's not [ __ ] in the yard he's
got some bugs on him don't let him in
the grow i barely let Mike in the grow
if you're in a gross if you're in a
bookstore or at a computer
first four grow books you see will cover
every issue we've brought up so far at
least enough to keep you from screwing
it up real bad fair yeah yeah yeah I was
just waiting for you to tie that around
to the dog walking in it's just some
sort of dog I mean dogs is one of those
things that every grow books gonna mesh
and keep your [ __ ] dog out of the
grower yeah
and so there's dogs in half the grow
rooms in America you see him in all the
people that post pictures their private
growing Instagram whatever my dog's name
is Bruno likes to hang out by the plants
I'm like yeah Bruno does he's [ __ ]
putting bugs and all kinds of [ __ ] on
your plants you guys that's a garden
that's a medical product you some of you
[ __ ] hippies would you don't have
your dog right by the food when you're
cooking but you do so I'm just gonna
stop all right it's there's no one thing
you can buy you got to do everything
with love everything with care the best
you can these plants start off with
potential to be 100 percent and as you
get in their way and you [ __ ] them up
you bring them down so if you give
everything you can the best you can
they'll come out 100 and then you'll do
it better next time you gotta learn one
thing I can recommend go trying to grow
17 different [ __ ] strains pick a
strain and grow it dial it in lock it in
nail it
get that one and get it going the right
way instead of trying to mess you can't
have seven girlfriend's you'll never
make them happy you can make one
girlfriend really really has a great
bucket analogy because each plant is
almost if not exactly as complicated as
a girlfriend it wants different things
at different times for different reasons
and if you've got a first-time grow you
don't want to be trying to make seven
different types of nutrients in in like
liter cup sizes you'll go and say you
wonder why is this OG Kush plant look
totally happy but this haze plant looks
like [ __ ] it's because you got a cal mag
deficiency because those plants want
completely [ __ ] different things then
you gonna learn how to mix nutrients for
two sides of the room and you're gonna
[ __ ] yourself it's gonna be hard or you
don't wanna plant that's trying to be
seven feet tall on one plant that's
trying to be 3 and a half feet tall yeah
or one plant that finishes in nine weeks
and one that finishes in seven and you
got to figure out how you're gonna you
just gotta start flushing over here and
cut down half the room and then
just sucks pick one strain run the [ __ ]
out of it that's my idea if you're an
experienced grower do whatever the [ __ ]
you want grow 32 strains in one room
make some flavors but if you're new and
you're trying to get you dialed in one
strains so much easier yeah all right I
hope I made a lot of sense because we
got real sidetracked yeah you can't put
turbos on an 86 escort and expect to win
races that was that was my favorite part
of that all right I've got a really cool
email from a guy who calls himself
arachnid death yeah
spider death does that mean that he is
the spider that kills or that he is
killed by spiders or the spider killer
he's a spider killer maybe arachnid
death
I expect another email I want to know
are you the spider killer enquiring
minds and [ __ ] bro were you killed by a
spider or you like maybe he's if it's
the second one away for a while let's
get to the emails his first things first
thank you so much for what you do I
wanted to take a moment and share some
stuff with you
I recently exited the military after
eight years of service I joined at 24
after being laid off from what I thought
would be the start of my lifetime career
after year of unemployment during the
economic downturn of 2008 I decided to
join the service to provide for my
family
before joining I thoroughly enjoyed
consuming cannabis on the rag in the
four months since my exit I've more than
enjoyed my eat-in trip my reintroduction
into cannabis however much has changed
in eight years dabs weren't a thing that
I'm aware of back then Alize not in
southern Ohio very I'm gonna say that
that was probably an uncommon kind of
pump the dabs were thing in southern
Ohio now yeah yeah he keeps going on he
says what advice would you give someone
like me I'm eager to try a DAB and I
have a friend willing to host me I don't
know what to expect for my first time
and I know it's different for everyone
but I was hoping you could try and
explain it to me I don't know how
significant it is my friend has a nectar
collector set up I'm currently only
going through a quarter ounce of
cannabis flower I'm going to assume he
says I'm only going through a quarter
every six weeks he's going through a
quarter ounce of flowers every six weeks
oh this guy's smoking around a gram a
week yeah so that's a buffer to a day
basically a one hit and quit each time I
smoked would you recommend that I
attempt to up my tolerance if so how I'm
a stay-at-home dad now so my smoking
really only occurs in the evenings when
I'm not the sole care caregiver to a
toddler what are your thoughts man I've
been listening for a while to your show
oh I was turned on to your show from the
dude grow show but I haven't listened to
them in months I thought I'd share oh
another paragraph sorry I've got this on
multiple pages I thought I'd share my
what I listen to when I smoke
information with you because if you guys
remember on 4/20 I asked everybody to
tell me what they listened to when they
get stoned so he's gonna tell us about
his music interest it goes like this I'm
a huge fan of music my tastes have grown
to be more eclectic since high school
my friends and I used to cruise around
on my car and smoke and listen to
Slipknot and similar occasionally
pausing for an in-car mosh you were the
other car in my high school I was in a
different car than that we were there
the deadheads in tie-dye a [ __ ] long
hair we did not do the moshing I was
kind of different-sized to the park yeah
yeah the stoners prefer the Lodi's
prefer the grassy knoll is what I think
the line is from clueless
I enjoy some rap and reggae I've been
listening to the higher vibes playlist
not Spotify and I dig it I created my
own playlist with my favorites from it
they include songs from revolution stick
figure tribal seeds and dirty heads I'm
sorry I did one of those he said I'm
sorry if these aren't up to par bro
you're doing good so far don't worry I
also says I swear to keep meaning to
list I swear I keep meaning to listen to
mystic roots been but I've heard on your
show makes me think I'd like them
overall so after my evening smoke sesh I
like to grab my sketchbook and my
headphones and listen to my Irie beats
while sketching in my book I love being
able to unwind with my pipe and art and
letting the huge changes in my life melt
into the background for a while on a
recent episode you stated that
recreational use is medical use I was
unsure of my opinion until you made that
statement you're totally right using
this flower in any manner that lets you
reduce stress or just generally enjoy
your life more counts as medicinal you
it's well said thanks for listening to a
rambling man I know you enjoy that
thanks for everything you do and stay
Irie are acne death and then he's got a
PS I wanted to take a special moment and
thank you for sharing your experience
with TBI I can tell that sharing like
that was difficult I hope it helped I
hope it helped I know it helped me
realize how seriously it can affect
somebody's psyche and then he states
that he's been in the military and he
knows plenty of people with a TBI super
common to people who serve in and around
him I'm sure yes yes oh man
first off we got to say thanks for your
service huge thank you so much for your
service that was an awesome email too by
the way thank you so much for that we're
gonna go back through and hit some
talking points here but uh I have said
it before I had done a dreadlocks
[ __ ] pot-smoking hippie I'm not into
war and [ __ ] but I appreciate that there
are guys that sign up and we're willing
to go to war so that you and I don't
have to right because if people didn't
sign up they would draft [ __ ]
and bro your six something but your body
type for 260 they'd [ __ ] draft dress
and turn you into a soldier bro you a
soldier I would also I'm [ __ ] 6 5 and
210 pounds I'd be the first guy on
operation hide behind him until he gets
shot like [ __ ] smoking weed would be
on purpose to death by the drill
sergeant on the second day of boot camp
keep calling and brah I'm so not that's
just not me and I because it's not me
and I know what that lifestyle would do
to me and because I also know how vital
it is for our way of life like I just
have a huge amount of respect yes did
sir absolutely I'm not I never support a
war but I always support our troops it's
the best way I think I could put that
all right so first thing he says thank
you bro [ __ ] thank you so thanks in
return
I appreciate the thank you uh message
received let's see there's a lot to talk
about here
reintroduction to cannabis after [ __ ]
eight years that's awesome I can only
imagine what a eight year cannabis break
would be like ah so it's a hell of a
tolerance Brad he says what advice would
you give somebody like me because he's
eager to try a DAB he's got a friend
that'll help him and he doesn't know
what to expect
ah let's try to explain to him a little
bit about what he's gonna get from his
first dab and then he also states that
his buddies got a nectar collector I
want to know is this nectar collector
does it have water some of the nectar
collectors don't have water some do I
will in the hole the nectar collector
period water no water it's harder to
size you're hit that way if you're not
careful true only set aside a very small
part on so the nectar collector you heat
it up and it just looks like a giant
straw and it's got a hopefully a crystal
a quartz crystal a glass or a titanium
tip the three types of tips that I would
hit off oh I wouldn't dam off of
anything else
glass quartz crystal or titanium there
may be something else I'm not aware of
but I don't think I dab off anything
else hopefully it's got that hopefully
it's got water I really hope your first
dab comes through an apparatus that has
got water without water a dad is hot as
[ __ ] on your lungs part of the
experience of a dad is the hint itself
in your body in your lungs your physical
reaction to that new smoke that new it's
a different level of heat than what
you're used to smoking this vapor is
very very different than a smoke yes yes
it feels heavy it feels sometimes he
feels like some like someone just got
their foot on your chest and you just
you just can't breathe right last for a
couple few seconds in my Jenny Beth says
I can't say a couple of you anymore
couple could be like a couple few could
be anywhere between three to eight let's
come right in a couple that's my thing
but it only hurts for a couple few
seconds like three to eight seconds
we're gonna say it just feels like you
might die but I find it pleasant it's
like a whole but I like I kind of like
that scary part of a dad he's a weird
guy that eats insanely hot jalapenos and
[ __ ] for entertainment I recommend you
take a dab smaller than a piece of rice
you want a very very small it's sort of
like I like to think of it this way
you're a beer drinker
you've worked yourself up to going it
out and having a 40 ounce beer after
work chillin at the bar for an hour
going home not intoxicated if you switch
the hard liquor you don't start with the
40 ounce month and that's what a lot of
people try to try to do with their first
dab is they end up taking something
that's like you fill the pint glass with
vodka that was a bad idea
yeah and their friends let them do it
because they think it's funny and it's
that makes people so not adapt you want
a grain of rice or half a granary size a
grain of rice is probably a big enough
dad for your first try so you've got
your nectar collector hopefully it's got
water and don't suck so hard you get the
water in your mouth give it a give it a
test before you even heat it and start
smoking through it put that nectar
collector up to your mouth and pull
through it and see what that experience
is like feel that then have put the
little half green of rice dab on
whatever you're smoking off of I do not
like smoking off of oil slick pads I do
not like smoking out of silicone
containers I like to put it on glass I
put my dab on glass it's the only thing
I [ __ ] trust for this I don't like
the other [ __ ] I'm sorry I'm picky I
don't want to smoke your silicone I
don't want to burn [ __ ] with my [ __ ]
nectar collector I don't like that so I
highly recommend you put it on glass set
your little dab on a piece of glass heat
up your nectar collector touch the
nectar collector to the dab and inhale
kind of inhale right before you touch it
as soon as it touches it's gonna
vaporize take your little dab you only
want that much smoke like it should
sound like this like seriously that's
probably enough smoke for your first dad
just a little you can always you can
always smoke more but Ron white told joe
rogan on a podcast one time he goes well
you can't unsmoked that joint now Kenya
cuz Rogan was talking some [ __ ]
nonsense
[ __ ] were you so you can't
unsmoked dab but you can take another
one and you're gonna want to so [ __ ]
take the small ones if you take another
one instead just coughing for 30 minutes
but I'm off track get a little half
green piece of rice heat that
[ __ ] up take a little dab don't
hold it in like you do when you smoke
flowers it's just in and out in and out
you just want to breathe it in breathe
it out no I don't know what to expect
for my first time and I know it's
different for a
but I was hoping you could try and
explain it to me the smokes gonna go in
you're gonna go holy [ __ ] as soon as it
hits your lungs your lungs go kiddo get
out get out
let it out your eyes are gonna start to
water your face is gonna turn red you're
going to sweat alone you're gonna sweat
you're gonna I hope you sweat that's
part of a good dab is like every sweat
gland on your body just threw up its I
love it it's kind of a good cleansing
feeling you sweat like a son of a [ __ ]
I'm reaching for my shatter while I can
I'm reaching for water cuz just talking
about it you're gonna get this head rush
feeling you're gonna get really super
high really super fast a lot of people
kind of panic from that just chill out
you're okay you you sounds like you're a
veteran your soldier soldiers through
you'll be [ __ ] just fine um you said
you've got a buddy who's that who's down
to roll with you through this and just
as long as you guys are cool with each
other get along reasonably well and he's
cool if you sleep on his couch for six
hours you're not gonna have any problem
yeah you may need a little nap at the
end of all this just a little rest just
these 1s pros every now and again we
have to hit pause on the show and just
show four four teams Jesse's been here
and halfway into the show he gave me
that no so it happens take a little half
a DAB you're gonna get sweaty you're
gonna get hot you're gonna get your
throat may burn from it you make off you
may shoot a booger out of your nose all
of that [ __ ] is part of your first AB
that's part of the club that's welcome
to the dab club Michael [ __ ] coughed
for 20 minutes and shoot a booger out of
his nose I'm in davon for years and I
still cough yeah a while I gave James a
DAB the other day my buddy James has got
a shaved head he just shaved his head
real close up a little buzz cut and he's
got a little beard and I can it looks
like you were just like his head and it
just kept dripping I was like where's it
all coming from he's like Mouse man I'm
sweating like a [ __ ] back here
it was so funny watching James when he
dabs every day with me dad got him I
just moved from one spot to another and
in the middle of the move I stopped and
took a DAB and it was a little big and
it was a little hot I have changed
shirts at let's talk about temperature
you don't want a really hot dab
and abs burn your lungs hot dabs burnt
herbs hot dabs I do hot dabs you feel a
hot dab in your lungs a lot Jeff does a
hot dab for a specific reason he takes a
hot dad because he takes a huge dab and
if the dab isn't hot enough at the
beginning there's not enough heat there
in the middle and end to properly give
him the hit around its waist
three-quarters of what I just threw in
the nail and then it you end up q-tip in
and a like a Maura I'm gonna a humble
brag is what I think this might have
been called back in the day what we just
told this listener to smoke is half of a
grain of rice for his first time and
it's going to be effective it's not
gonna leave him short of anything he'll
be high from this arachnid death that
you'll get high from this and if you
don't smoke another one if you don't
smoke another one like well dad hits you
immediately so you'll know you like do I
want another one or not and you'll know
yes or no ah and then start playing
games with yourself see how much of a
dad you can take what I like to do with
the nectar collector I will make a worm
I'll take a long ass like a [ __ ]
three or four inch worm of hash and lay
it in the on the on whatever piece of
glass I'm using and I will smoke the
whole [ __ ] thing with the nectar
collector like a goddamn ant eater
sucking up a line of ants but what I was
getting at is we just told this guy to
smoke a piece of rice the dab I just put
on this dabber
that's probably 0.3 of a gram that's
like a pointer finger nail tip it
towards man you got big man hands it's a
decent guys ring finger nail I'll give
it a read three or four times thicker
than anything I'm gonna take this tab
here in just a second when Mike's talk
talking and it's not gonna ruin me up
hopefully not gonna cough it'll make my
eyes the touch read for a few minutes
this this kind of ties into another
piece he mentions his what he listen to
what he's listening to when he smokes
and then says he hopes that's up to
snuff and when I read that the first
thing that hit me was bro it's it's
music do you like oh well the only
person who gets to decide if it's up to
snuff is you yes and with the with the
dab size
but people have this weird competition
thing that they do with everything
you're gonna eat one doughnut I'm gonna
eat too
you're gonna hit on one chick I'm gonna
hit on two you're gonna take one Deb I'm
gonna take two please don't do that with
hash I got it marijuana is totally fun
until you weigh over do it um and if you
just kind of go easy and figure out
where your limits are a little bit
you're gonna have such a better time
remember the do we having to call his
wife to come pick his ass up remember
the cop that had to call 9-1-1 because
he was too high and thought he was dying
he was dying it happens people end up
don't put a space between those
sentences because we just said the guy
that called 911 cause you thought he was
dying then you said it happens people do
not die from cannabis that's a pause
can't die from consuming too much weed
but you can make yourself miserable by
consuming consuming too much weed in the
legalization stage there was a big bump
and people calling poison control and
then showing up at the ers for just
having way over consumed not paying
attention
typically with edibles people [ __ ]
hate adult hate reading labels we don't
real Able's for [ __ ] and so a lot of
people way over consumed edibles and
ended up in the hospital the first time
they ate edibles in Colorado or
Washington just because they never read
the label and if you just take the
little dev and see where you're at
you're gonna have a great time if you if
you look at your friend that's a regular
dabber and try to mimic their
consumption level you're gonna have a
miserable [ __ ] time maybe maybe he's
gonna [ __ ] love it that could be like
me I'm a savage and I love just crossing
that threshold pretty much everyone I
know has a type of alcoholic beverage
that they can't even think about yeah
they they start to say whiskey sour or
whatever it is for that it's Jose Cuervo
their nose starts running a little under
their throat and their start tongue
starts getting real thick and dry and
everyone has that because when you were
first learning to consume alcohol you
way overdid it with whatever product um
and if you can just avoid doing that to
yourself with hash you don't ever have
to be the guy that has to yeah the first
time I took a DAB I pooped myself and
fell asleep on Jerry's couch I do
put too much of a dab in the rig for
myself so I just tag team buddy past the
leftover dad - Mike that's why he cut
out team work I'm gonna turn Mike's mic
down for just a minute bro when you're
ready give me a thumbs up
who was it trying to be rude and kill
him you guys that was kind of a bigger
dad than Mike needed he's got a thumbs
down he just there's two thumbs down
like do not [ __ ] with my microphone I
would ask Mike a question he can listen
but it's gonna be a minute before he
replies our listener says I smoke one
hit each time and I quit because he's
gay I'm pretty sure he's plenty high can
we quantify what a DAB is going to do to
him like how many hits do you think a
dab equals if he takes one hit at a time
how many hits do you think it would take
to get to a small dab would you say
three you just showed me six so six hits
off of your pipe you're gonna have to
work your way up to six it's off your
pipe to achieve what you get with one
dad ish ish okay I would almost agree
with that I'd say yeah I said 5 was my
first guess I was gonna say 5 or 10 and
you gave me 6 so yeah and then just
imagine that you're gonna be 6 times
higher when you take a DAB you're gonna
be 6 times higher than when you smoked
that one hit a weed that you smoke and
we don't know what kind of weed you're
smoking are you smoking high grade we'd
be smoking Mexican brick weed if you're
smoking Mexican brick weed and you step
up to a dad it's going to be a game
[ __ ] changer one thing to mention the
dabs will ruin your tolerance for weed
if you start regularly can for sure yeah
I don't I can smoke all the joints if
you've got joints I'll smoke them all
like bring them and we'll smoke them all
get cottonmouth and I'll get a sore
throat eventually but I won't get stoned
but I have to be really careful with my
hash consumption or I'll ruin flowers
for myself for a while yeah and I fixed
that with just a quick little vacation I
like to smoke flowers at concerts and
stuff and I smoke a lot of flowers
flowers still my favorite way to go it's
flowers in a bong it's the way it all
started flowers in a bong
I was smoking flowers in a bong a little
while back I'm old man my lungs don't
work anymore that's hard it's funny my
lungs like the bong hit a lot more than
they like the davit I could tell and
it's because I'm a smoker my lungs have
been trained for 20 years if you tell
this guy to expect coughing did we
mention that you're gonna go off
uncomfortable you just heard might cough
for a long time you throats designed to
prevent you from doing what you're
trying to do with it if you are a smoker
it's going to increase your coffee you
notice I don't cough my dad my friend
Elijah he doesn't cop when he dad
we don't smoke cigarettes Mike and James
they cough like sons of [ __ ] when
they dad and they both Bryant caught
it's you guys all smoked cigarettes I
can feel it because it's not just when I
dab when I hit a vape of any kind even
the little oil sticker or whatever hash
cartridges when I hit one of those or
nicotine vape or even one of the little
electronic cigarettes that you get at
the gas stations rattles ooh sure I feel
the same pressure or burn or tightness
that I that causes the cough when I dab
it's the heated liquid vapor versus a
smoke just jar and loose all your tar
lung it's totally different
it's like water and air going through a
hose but this dude asked would you
recommend that I attempt to up my
tolerance and if so how I would not at
all recommend that
yeah you're a cheap date stay that way
right like I can recommend you spend
more on dinners too right now it doesn't
cost you a lot to get high it's easier
to conceal you could wear more expensive
shoes there's just there's no reason to
push your tolerance further up when you
start dabbing it's going to do it itself
so don't dab too frequently and then
just keep your stash of don't buy dabs
maybe only down only dab when your buddy
dabs you know which is dick move but I
mean if you don't buy it then you don't
have it there to just become a dad head
you're not always dabbing I'm just kind
of enjoying the thought of what it would
be like to be able to get to where I'd
want to be after a hit or two
like how much cheaper that would be how
much how much time I would save that way
yeah
like even when I'm dab in because I'm a
smoker and my lungs can't handle giant
dabs I've got to sit down and take three
or four which means I've got to eat the
nail three or four times wait for the
diver to cool three or four times get
distracted three or four times and all
of a sudden hour and a half's gone by
and I've gotten baked once like if I
could take a puff be fried and be back
to doing whatever it was yeah that would
be preferable that's my take one giant
dad there's something happens something
happens to me when I take one big
gigantic dab it doesn't happen when I
take six or seven little tiny dad's it
just doesn't do it one big dad really
just just does it for me
it uh it's different for everybody and
honestly with cannabis there's so many
different ways to consume it just
playing with the different ones of
finding your favorite that's a little
harder where you are versus where we are
true but true
ah dude I was gonna say that's why I got
a little quiet I should remember what
the [ __ ] is gonna say do you notice that
back in the day when you smoked and went
to work not to say that we might take
dabs and go to work now I never did that
I can't answer this question okay you
don't have these jobs anymore you don't
[ __ ] work there so [ __ ] those places
when you worked in places before when
you weren't allowed to smoke when you
walked in there did you just feel [ __ ]
super high like like I'm not supposed to
be high at work I'm really high suddenly
and now that it's okay to show up for
work medicated so that you're not in
pain and nobody judges you and nobody
cares does it affect your level of
Highness or medication this it affects
my anxiety level around it okay yeah I
think that's to be honest because I'm in
a fire I'm in an environment where I can
be honest with my boss that I took this
cannabis product or that cannabis
product this morning well I'm working a
full shift to do my job as expected I am
go home everybody's fine nobody gives a
[ __ ]
I find myself
more concerned with making sure it's
never an issue okay I would feel worse
being too baked to do what I needed to
do now then I would have at the coats
more when I was 18
all right does that make sense yeah no
I'm kind of the same way I won the boss
so I make sure not to get [ __ ] blown
out baked right like yeah I still pay
more attention and like yeah they like
they don't get mad and as they know if
they know that we're smoking nobody said
anything I don't know he's not gonna
call this out on it and so like they
know that we're all medical marijuana
patients so like we work hard and
nobody's calling us out for not having
sore knees and so I make sure not to
just be ripped when I show up or so
right like what we do is body intensive
to being able to do it for eight hours a
day five days a week I deal with all the
contractors and the city people so I
can't be blown represent our company all
hey bro
trying to be bright-eyed wide-eyed
mostly ready to rock my favorites when
I've been in a grow and I'm like balls
deep in a project and a contractor rings
a doorbell and I answered the door like
what's up mother human I haven't seen
other humans in like seven hours it's
good to see it they're like eh I think
they just looking like a [ __ ] caveman
it's so funny when I was working
strictly the retail side you don't carry
that wonderful odor with you so much
when you go to lunch I was standing it
like [ __ ] subway today and I I look
up and I look around there's a little
line he had to chill for a minute I
didn't have to do anything so I'm
playing with my phone I look up and I'm
getting weird looks from like seven
people so the first thing I do is glance
down and I'm like no flies closed what
the [ __ ] oh I get it
I smell [ __ ] awesome yeah and they're
all wondering if I'm too high to talk or
if I work with it yep yeah yep okay I
showed up to a restaurant in Colorado
Springs where you order at a window and
then you sit down and they bring your
food out to you and we ordered and we
paid and the guy goes all right you'll
be sitting outside right we'll bring
that right to you and it was [ __ ]
snow in dude and we're like now I'm
sitting outside what the [ __ ] like oh we
really can't have you guys in here and I
kind of
looked at him in my the person who was
with me looked at me like and like Saudi
not like [ __ ] dreadlocks or what's
the [ __ ] problem is that was the only
issue we could spot like you check the
fly I got cash everything cool here in
pants why are you offend yeah I got sure
I got shoes I wanna [ __ ] service
you'll have to sit outside you guys reek
of marijuana and I was like oh sorry can
we get our money back and they're like
what I was like if we have to sit
outside in the [ __ ] snow we're not
eating here and if you don't appreciate
how I earned my money at my job today
I'm not [ __ ] spending my money here
please give me a full refund for all of
our orders and we did not eat at that
[ __ ] place yeah I hear people
bitching about the smell and smelling on
people who work with it while there is
fined like shopping for groceries or
going about their life or taking money
to the bank and how is sort of chuckle
and wonder if people that work in other
industries that produce an odor like if
there are people in their town they're
like [ __ ] fish market people right
dude II walked by I lived near a town
that was famous for its odor because of
a specific industry really yep I don't
remember anybody being like
[ __ ] dog food workers right
like no the dog food plant took all the
heat yeah that worked there like no one
was pissed at them no one was like man I
was at [ __ ] Walmart the other day the
dude [ __ ] dog food smell so you just
never it it never came up in any other
aspect of my life and I know there are
other industries where because what
you're doing produces a heavy smell does
everyone in your town [ __ ] about people
smelling like that I don't know email me
tweet me an email punk 15 are still
listening they're still listening this
guy's still listening at least cuz he
sent us an email and he gives a lot of
[ __ ] thanks for listening man ah so know
our our bottom line is do not increase
your tolerance they achieved eight it's
fun nope maybe maybe sometimes on Friday
take three or four puffs see what you
can do you know but don't don't try to
step it up just to step it up for the
sake of stepping it up
that's not necessary let's talk about
your music selections here it all sucks
your loser
only kidding dude I'm almost 40 years
old and uh your music selection like
Mike said that's all up to you I don't
give a [ __ ] what people think about my
music selection did I will listen to on
the same car ride I listen to fish I'll
listen to journey and then I'll listen
to [ __ ] Snoop Dogg I'm the same car
ride there was a spot in like my early
20s where I stopped carrying what I was
listening to in a way that other people
would consider yeah like when I was a
teenager and I was bump into something I
knew that I liked that wasn't popular
and I'm coming to a stoplight where
other people are gonna be able to both
hear and identify me I turned that down
and just enjoy it quietly with my
windows up and when we were doing 55
again I'd pump it back out now [ __ ] it
I'll let you listen to whatever the [ __ ]
you want oh yeah you're right next to me
you get to hear the reggae channel on
Sirius XM happy turn it up I was
listening to Joey Diaz his podcast uncle
Joey the Church of what's happening now
and I was in traffic like near our house
near where I live there's a street where
traffic is booked in the morning it does
it okay normally it takes me 15 minutes
to get it to work
I left 35 minutes earlier than and I was
still [ __ ] late that's how that's how
the construction of the traffic our Joey
Diaz was just tossing up a [ __ ] storm
about something and I look over in the
little half [ __ ] with the [ __ ] flag
and it's waving everyone to slow down is
staring at my car like what is that guy
[ __ ] listening to it was so funny I
didn't care I didn't change anything but
I just thought it was Joey Diaz will let
it out who Joey Diaz will call you a
[ __ ] and go off for ten minutes
and it was hilarious
I was listen to a podcast today when it
ended the next one in my queue came up
and it was Kevin Smith and Jason Mewes
podcast is particularly filthy and I let
it roll for about half an hour before it
clicked that I was at work maybe find
another podcast you can listen to that
yes we listen to wheeler Walker jr. at
work sometimes so let's get back into
this news email because we've been
recording for an hour and four minutes
soon it was a kick-ass email we had to
go off on it he says I'm a huge fan of
music my tastes have grown to be more
eclectic since high school then he talks
about my friends and I used to cruise
around on my car and smoke and listen to
Slipknot and similar occasionally
pausing for a car wash like I said
earlier dude I was a teenager and I was
into Metallica I got in
Pantera I dabbled in the like the
Cannibal Corpse deicide type of [ __ ] for
a minute and then when I started heavily
smoking cannabis my music tastes changed
drastically I started The Nine Inch
Nails Primus sort of thing and then I
went to a REM concert and I thought it
was a huge REM fan and then happen to
most people a lot of different stuff you
went 3:11 route is there out mic went
and then yeah my first 311 shows from
life I'd listen to the Grateful Dead
sporadically but my friend Greg
introduced me to the Grateful Dead and
then he took me to a Phish show at Red
Rocks and all hell broke loose that's
how that happened so I never got into
the heavy stuff this is funny all right
before I found 3:11 in my life changed
forever the CD that I was most hyped to
buy that summer was [ __ ] so for real
yeah you heard it here first you
admitted that on a podcast just like
what you like yo the student says I know
you enjoy some rap and reggae which is
right up my alley says he's been
listening to the ivory right I revived
channel which is and then he's selected
his favorites which is revolution stick
figure tribal seeds and dirty heads
which is all acceptable reggae I call
that white boy surf dub or surf reggae
that's good stuff I like more of the
Jamaican reggae stuff most of the time
but if you're listening to stick figure
and revolution you're already doing it
right you're gonna be just fine those
are up to par you keep meaning to listen
to the mystic roots man no pressure bro
check them out you're gonna love it they
do got a lot of good stuff old stuff and
new stuff on mystic routes get yourself
a bowl fire it up pull up YouTube and do
mystic roots past the marijuana turn it
up
sit back close your eyes and just enjoy
the next seven minutes that songs
probably ten years old it's amazing but
I make sure to get it at least once a
week in my list and then check out some
of the newer stuff with Katherine
singing with Katherine Ramirez on vocals
now because she wasn't with the band
back in the day and they pensive lineup
changes over the years and Kat sings and
it's a totally different vibe I [ __ ]
dig it go see him live if they come near
you they they toured a lot so I'm gonna
keep moving on the email we are a rambly
pair of stoners two night bro you
mentioned you smoke and grab your
sketchbook what are you draw man
want to see some of your art if you're
kind enough to share I would appreciate
it show me what you got I used to draw
when I was a youngster I feel like I
lost my passion for art for some reason
um let's see dude medical use
recreational uses medical use I
completely agree that's that's a great
statement thank you for saying that
anything that makes you feel better man
I'm sure you got some PTSD or something
from being in the military I'm sure
something hurts and it's and you're a
parent so sometimes you just need an
escape without even going anywhere you
still got to be there so that's it is
its medical ah let's see he also says
thanks for listening to a rambling man
dude thanks for the great email because
you gave us like an hour worth of solid
material so that's awesome thanks for
everything you do and stay I react in
death and then I want to do with the the
PS I want to take a special moment thank
you for sharing your experience with TBI
you could tell sharing like that was
difficult uh dude it was a little bit
difficult I tried to hide up there's a
couple spots with my voice shake I was
like do I want to share this much about
myself but uh I appreciate you guys for
listening so I felt like I just needed
to be as honest as I could with you
because what's the point of recording
show if you don't make it honest and
real it's called girl from your heart so
I did it all from my heart on that
arachnid death thank you so much for
your military service thank you for
returning to the team cannabis we like
having you on the green team and also
thank you for the huge great email I
appreciate that I hope we gave you some
useful advice don't increase your intake
just to be on the cool team go slow with
the dabs don't go too hot it should be
that's a mistake that we made that you
can definitely learn from in a book we
used to think you had to go real hot
back in the day it doesn't matter what
you're hitting it what type of tip is on
your nectar collector that you're using
or what type of nail or bang or setup
you end up seeing if it's glowing it's
too hot
yes no I'm gonna get some glow squad
hate for that but y'all are nuts
hashtag glow squad shout out to Mickey
Martin
yep that killed it what size Miller
email that was a gmail man I appreciate
it if you've got any more questions
please sit him to me it's a girl from
your heart at hotmail.com you guys I've
got a stack of emails on my desk I just
can't get through all of them in one
episode I'm making sure we only get the
one email per show yeah you make a good
podcast you add some conversation it's
not just talking this was a good show we
had fun we took some dabs we made some
friends yeah didn't we both needed to
get nothing doing a good show this was
good it's cathartic it's fun hanging out
not at work not on the clock
yep dude welcome to the team I
appreciate that I'm glad you see the
potential in that team because if you
ever have you ever been out there and
you're just like oh this works well this
is well thought out
I like this like I've had that
experience all week it's been awesome I
feel blessed to be to be on the team now
so yeah if you're listening thank you
yeah
Mike is the one trimming that weed this
week that's that's when you're a new guy
we make you trim for a week so he's
trimming buds so tell us what you think
of the trim job 15 on Twitter yeah all
right you guys we should probably wrap
up this podcast we've been going for an
hour and 10 minutes dude let's get Mike
thanks for coming taking time away from
the little guy time away from the wife
time away from your [ __ ] pack of dogs
thanks for listening and the new house
over here just do a good show and chill
for them take some dabs
thanks to everybody for listening I
appreciate it it's fun hanging out with
everybody giving everybody some grow
advice I feel like we're all friends now
it's awesome
I'd love to hear from you let me know
what you think of this podcast grow from
hard at hotmail.com you can find me on
the tweeter satg fyh podcast can stalk
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from our podcast or on Instagram if
you want to check out my cannabis
photography i on instagram i am i real
or genetics i RIE underscore genetics
that is my seed company that's my
breeding program check out all my super
Cannabis photography there are pictures
from the grower three rivers there's
pictures from my personal bro there's
pictures from other friends grow that
don't want to be identified i take all
the pictures myself a lot of it is
strains that i have bred i take a lot of
pride of my own grows in my photos so
check it out you might enjoy it also um
check out patreon.com slash rule from
your heart if you are interested in
supporting the podcast financially
that's how you can do it
patreon.com slash girl from your heart
patreon is patr e o n patreon.com slash
girl from your heart for more
information there i would love your
support if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you've got
a product you would like Mike and I to
review contact me send me an email grow
from your heart at hotmail.com give you
all the information you need on how to
get a product in my hands we will check
it out we will talk about it on the show
and we can ship it back to you if you
want it back if not we'll add it to the
collection of coolest toys that sits on
the table the podcast gasps good to come
and smoke through play with whatever we
can do it however you would like like
you got anything to say before we wrap
up this hour and fifteen minute podcast
keep the emails coming folks that was
amazing yes and there are a lot of
emails in the pile we just can't get
through because Mike talks a lot lots of
great points in and honestly when I go
back and listen to shows the ones with
listener generated content where
somebody has a specific question those
tend to be the shows that I find myself
really getting into a third I'm cool a
third time you listen three times I need
you listed off all the [ __ ] I got going
right now like I can only take [ __ ]
Pandora for so many hours a day and so I
end up going through podcasts and I'll
burn through an entire run of a podcast
nice nice I think I'm listening to too
many shows cuz I can't get them all in
when you're going 18 hours a day there's
always something playing in the
background you just burn through a lot
of [ __ ] content very true I hope you
guys are enjoying the Thursday episodes
I'm putting out I've been putting out I
am big old chunk Thursday I've been
trying to get like five episodes dude
that three three and a half hour chunk
oh yes does that not [ __ ] up your phones
I'd not mess up your data is everything
legit with them I'm on Wi-Fi constantly
okay
off Wi-Fi long enough for that to [ __ ]
with me cool I just didn't I got an
iPhone and I got the unlimited plan it's
funny worry I got an offer for the
internet company who used to [ __ ] me
with that particular trick and so I feel
for people who have to deal with data
stuff like that but yeah be careful
which episode you download yes three
hours day episodes can't get along but
man I love that big fat chunk of cannae
saved them as a smaller file they're not
as high-quality so they're the same size
file as a short episode because they're
not saved as a Apple enhanced podcast
file I just save it as a shitty mp3 for
the start of the show the original topic
old shows deep in the playlist we've
covered everything you're gonna find in
a grow book two or three different ways
oh yeah if you take if you like the show
and you don't like reading you can dig
through old episodes and learn
everything you need to know to be a
really successful grower and I've
currently got the first 65 episodes
available on my youtube channel it grow
from your heart on YouTube I don't know
how to find it it's like just go to
youtube and search for girl from her
podcasts will come up there's a playlist
of the first 20 that's borrowed from the
IRA genetics YouTube channel which
doesn't do [ __ ] anymore there's nothing
up there but uh the the playlist is
there and then the other 45 are there on
the grow from your heart channel so you
can watch the first 60 episodes you guys
it's not video of me it's just
screenshots of random [ __ ] but all of
the audio is that you listen to and
wanna say like 33 to 36 in like 40 or 50
up into the 70s there are a lot of great
episodes there are episodes where we sit
down and it the show starts off with get
your pen yeah well I've written entire
I've typed out entire seven or eight ten
page [ __ ] podcasts where the hyper
specific with every step of the process
yeah yeah there's a series where Jeff
brought in different experts in each
little piece and interviewed them that's
just incredible in an insanely
informative I'll have to get back to
that one of these days when we get more
time to we legalize it and we all got
ridiculous
these huge jobs now because I am yeah
nevermind I'm getting a lot more lights
real soon I'm building a whole nother
facility it's gonna be overwhelming I
can't [ __ ] wait I'm excited to be
overwhelmed overwhelmed is my favorite
way to be lately not to overstate it but
we could do a demolition derby in the
space they had the same building we were
building to grow in recently hosted a
dodgeball tournament a what's it called
roller derby and what else was happening
in there there were like three or four
events in the building because it's the
grow hasn't been built in there yet it's
just we're just taking it over now yeah
the former tenants did a [ __ ] roller
derby thing in there a dodgeball event
it's huge and we're gonna fill it with
lights pretty soon the plans are there
it's in action so I don't know how much
of that should I'm supposed to spill
that's not my business to share so um
thank you guys for listening to all that
private information I'm not gonna add
any bro nobody gives a [ __ ] that's cool
that might just give me the edit that
and I'm like no we're all friends here
all right guys in this podcast thank
everybody for listening to an hour and
15 minute episode of the door from the
heart podcaster I think Mike once again
for joining me um I think that's all I
am responsible for in this episode for
saying thank you - I want to thank
everybody that has sent me emails I want
to thank arachnid death for serving I
want to thank arachnid death for the
excellent email only give a huge shout
out to my friend the dab in granny
what's up granny I miss you I love you
everyday we have to get together to take
dab soon granny and I have been talking
about going somewhere together we may
record a podcast there I want to talk
too much about it because I just want to
let it happen
so look forward to that ladies and
gentlemen until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
nobody won who Brun the car everybody
wants money pimping when you around
nobody want no clown take on everybody
want to really bond
office in your lasagna competing
collision our zucchini
just a little Iza so I noodle me push
that fool Angela invitamos fear us so
many goals on top spot Souls I passed
everything
my lord I am to pray on my will the
memory Allah is italic the papyri
Hashanah that unify relieve defrost
Trish and inspect them on so bright a
fun debate about those tears no tears em
evil deeds departure nobody wanna be
gone
everybody wants to read upon
[Music]
everybody
everybody want to compete with Christian
be lumpy from early this morning the
budget naughty mini pie no fried
dumpling passing no one to say journey
[Music]
you want to read it
ha ha
[Music]