yo it's Bobby hustle representing for
the real big b sound Joseph star no boy
can't play with like no broken guitar
hey yo Nick T you know it's St smoking
hard it's the
[Music]
hustle
another
[Music]
bus only only only only only
only
shiny yeah what's up ladies and
gentlemen welcome to episode number 23
of the igro culture
podcast I'm your host rosta Jeff thanks
for joining me for another episode
today's intro music was brought to you
by DJ niik check out DJ Nick on
Soundcloud big up and much respect to DJ
Nick in this episode Jesse joins us for
another outdoor grow lesson but first
we've got to pay some bills this podcast
is brought to you by Nature's green
remedies.com visit Natures green
remedies.com for gag green genetics L PL
Labs Sin City rare dankness mile high
can Aventure iy genetics and many more
trusted Brands if you purchase two five
packs of I genetics you will receive a
free two pack or purchase two 10 packs
and receive a free five pack so that's
buy 10 get two free buy 20 get five free
Nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code rosta Jeff for 15% off
any order and you always get free
shipping at naturegreen remedies.com
once again that coupon code is rosta
Jeff capital r a s a capital j e FF all
one word Rasta Jeff for 15% off and
that's any brand you don't have to
purchase I genetics you can purchase any
brand on the website and you will get
that 15% off with that code and of
course free shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com
the show is also brought to you by hyro
indoor growing supplies hyro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
627 1 Beach Street Unit F or stop by the
new peblo location at 618 East 4th
Street in peblo Colorado check out High
gr for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget to check out
www.hr denver.com for current store
hours and special sales go to the P
location tell them Rost to Jeff sent you
and of course don't forget about the
special they're having on the soil
that's one tote of soil for $550 we've
talked about that on a couple episodes
it's a whole bunch of soil for a really
good price $600 if you need it delivered
anywhere in Colorado so give them a call
or check out hyro denver.com for more
information on that one and this show is
also brought to you by our good friends
at oil slick oil slick tools to help you
concentrate check out oilslick pad.com
for more information go check oilslick
out on Twitter follow them under @
oilslick pad send them a tweet and tell
them you're listening to the igro
culture
podcast also this show is brought to you
by our friends at tree Thugger tocom
tree thug.com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree thug.com for
concert and Festival news and reviews
www.re Thugger dcom big shout out to my
buddy Ryan over there at tree Thugger
thanks for supporting us I really
appreciate it much respect to all the
sponsors that make this show
possible I really appreciate you guys
for listening and supporting the
show uh you guys might remember I took a
uh I ate a 350 milligram edible on an
episode well I've got a little bit of
news that I just found let me scroll to
it and I got it right here on this page
I'm actually going to drop the music out
it's a little distracting for me once
again shout out to Nick for letting me
play the music I really appreciate that
uh let me tell you the name of the song
that we're listening to that was the
Sumit turnup
2014 electric dance hall music volume
one live uh on DJ Nick's SoundCloud page
there's a [ __ ] sweet shot of DJ Nick
DJing at Red Rock so you look stylish in
that shot brother much respect thanks
for letting me play your stuff so let's
let's get down to this news article oh
excuse me my voice is of course raspy
from dabin that's uh that's uh part for
the course right so it says tougher
rules on Colorado marijuana edibles for
serving size and child safety this
article is by Eric Gorski from The
Denver Post it says Colorado's
recreational marijuana edible
manufacturers face tougher rules on
potency serving size and packaging of
their products under stop Gap rules
adopted by state Regulators Thursday the
new guidelines in response crafted in
response to concerns about overc
consumption by inexperienced consumers
will do away with bite-sized products
that pack in 100 Mig of the psychoactive
chemical THC the maximum allowed by
state law products may contain up to 100
milligrams of THC but they must be
easily broken off into pieces that have
10 milligrams or fewer the standardized
edible serving size under state law so
now they uh We've standardized
apparently 10 Mig is a serving of edible
cannabis so if you buy a 100 milligram
bar they want it easily divisible in 10
pieces uh I shouldn't say names of
products but you know have a kit kat is
already kind of separated into servings
that's kind of how I see they could do
it and uh sorry Kit Kat that I Ed you
but your serving [ __ ] is perfect for my
example or Hershey's bar has got they're
already divided perfectly so that's what
they're going to require of all of these
pieces and I got to say that uh that
edible that I ate on the show was 350
milligram it was small uh I'm trying to
measure it in my head to give to have
something to compare it to uh but it was
quite tiny uh man I don't have anything
in my range that is about the same size
it was about the size of the top of a
pill bottle cap like that cap on your
pill bottle was about that big uh like
an inch and a half by an inch and a half
and it was slightly thick uh but the
thing was there was no way to judge uh
you could break it in half I guess and
kind of eyeball it but there was no way
to really judge the size of that sort of
an edible so they're going to make it to
where they have to be easily broken up
and then that way you eat 10 Mig instead
of trying to guess instead of getting
wrecked but anyway and another change
manufacturers will be required to put
single serving Edibles in child
resistant packaging before shipping them
to stores instead of relying on stores
to provide the packaging as customers
leave with their purchases so I think
that means more costs also that's going
to go up because the manufacturer now
has to pay for that and then that's just
going to get moved right on down the
line to the dispensary and that's going
to get pushed right on Down the Line you
because now you're able to bring in they
give you this uh big white it looks like
a money envelope kind of like a bank bag
but it's got a child resistant zipper
thing on it that's got like a clasp on
the zipper that you have to know how to
open uh and if you bring that you can
put all of your Edibles and stuff in
there and they let that count as your
childproof container and you actually
you can buy those or they charge you for
them a at a lot of the dispensaries so
there's going to go put that right on
the product already you're going to pay
a little more but I guess uh a couple of
bucks to Keep Kids Safe is what we got
to do and then you get into the argument
of what about parenting it's not uh it's
not all about the products it's about
the parenting but that's another
argument probably a whole another
podcast that talks about that so the
rules this one says the rules which uh
still must be made permanent in a
process that will include public comment
will go into effect November 1st they
grew out of meetings with health
officials Regulators industry
representatives and activists on both
sides the marijuana enforcement
division's primary concern is to ensure
Public Safety atrice Bryant a
spokeswoman for the Department of
Revenue wrote in an email marijuana
enforcement division feels that clear
serving size requirements within the
industry is a vital part of responsible
regulation Rachel O'Brien a founding
member of smart Colorado which supports
tighter restrictions on marijuana said
the rules are a step in the right
direction but time will tell whether
they go far enough Edibles manufacturers
responding to public demand already
shifted to lower potency edible since
recreational sales began January 1st
said Mike Elliot executive director of
the marijuana Industry Group the free
market has largely addressed this
problem he said well I kind of agree uh
that 350 milligram edible that I ate it
[ __ ] me up and I'm a professional pot
smoker I take dabs all day uh I wake and
bake on a regular basis you know I'm not
bragging about how much I smoke or
anything but I I get down uh I'm smoking
live resin right now uh I probably took
a couple of half gr dabs
today uh and that edible wrecked me so
if somebody if a normal civilian got a
hold of that thing and ate the whole
thing they'd be destroyed and they would
have a miserable experience so I think
clearly marking it is a key that's a
great idea we all remember the story of
the lady uh from New York Marino Dow
that ate too much Edibles and thought
she was [ __ ] turning herself inside
out and dying in her hotel room nobody
wants to be that guy well guys I think
that's enough news for the day I just
kind of wanted to read you that one
article Jesse came over uh we did a
little outdoor grow lesson sounds like
my voice is about to blow out anyway so
I'm going to turn up the music and then
we'll be back with the grow lesson
thanks for joining us hang on for just
one second hey if you got a Dabber if
you got a joint if you got a bowl if you
got an edible if you've got a drinkable
uh if you've got some topical hey
consume that at this time because I'm
going to take a dab and that means that
kind of technically we are getting high
together so when this music starts count
to about 30 and that means we're getting
high together right about then here we
go
[Music]
all right guys you got the nail hot you
got your bowl packed you got a joint
rolled you got something going on let's
get stone together I'm going to take a
dab I'm taking a dab of some girl got
cookies live resin made by a close
friend uh I'm going to hit a Hitman mini
cake with a highly educated uh it's the
Infiniti Nail hooked up to an
eail um it's the old temp temple because
at one point I had a had arranged a
sponsorship deal or something with the
temp temple but they've since sold the
company so I've got the temp temple it's
set at 460 I like it uh that's just
about right I think so I've also got a
highly educated titanium carb cap so I'm
going to drop the dab onto the nail and
then pop the carb cap so get high with
me guys here we
go all right we'll be right back in just
a second with Jesse's outdoor grow
[Music]
lesson
yo what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to the show hey I've got
Jesse back we're going to do another
grow lesson uh before we do that man I
want to say congratulations on the air
Jesse just got married uh his wedding
was awesome I'm sure you've heard his
talk about it so uh welcome to the show
and congratulations bro thank you thank
you you look like a new man you got a
your hair is halfway combed you got a
big old smile on your face got a haircut
groom the beard a little so oh I wasn't
going to mention the grooming of the
beard did you get did you have to get
refitted for your dress after they
groomed your
beard no cuz it still stayed in place
there you go his beard is manly as [ __ ]
you guys if he'll let me post a picture
of him we'll put a picture up on the uh
Instagram or somewhere so you guys can
see what a man beard looks like for sure
Colorado man
beard turn myself up a little I'm not
loud enough sorry it's an ego thing I
got to come up more on the computer here
awesome so uh Jesse is uh part of the
hyro uh store his wife works there are
you uh how involved are you are you an
employee or are you just kind of helping
in behind the scenes I am a uh helping
be behind the scenes uh helping uh with
uh training uh employees on product
lines and stuff cool um I'm also doing
uh commercial sales for dispensaries
caregiver grows stuff like that so sweet
um get at me I'll uh I'll beat anyone's
price he'll beat anyone's price it's an
ego thing speaking of
egos pushing the mic closer to his face
so you guys can hear him a little bit
better I'll turn me down and him up
that'll make this happen uh So speaking
of hyro a couple of people that have
been listening to the podcast kind of
called us out they said 550 bucks for a
tote of soil if I go online that's only
$299 they're correct I did some research
uh the caveat is if you pay
$299 shipping is $249
because it's got to be shipped on a
FedEx truck we were just talking about
how big a tote of soil is it's about the
size of a
Volkswagen uh it's probably 3 and 1/2 4T
wide by 3 and 1/2 to 4T tall depending
on how much uh it's been compressed cuz
it is going to be kind of squished down
by uh gravity and being moved around and
they're they're heavy as [ __ ] yeah how
are they get that off the truck when
they bring it to your house uh with a
pallet jack so yeah you know right to
your front yard so figure out it you
know figure it out from there yeah know
where it's going to go when they get
there maybe you can sweet talk the guy
into into getting it there so uh uh this
show is brought to you by Hy gr indor
growing supplies make sure you check out
hyro I'm pretty sure I already said that
once in the show but I like giving them
love because they give us a lot of love
uh Jesse's back he's going to give us a
grow lesson uh we should review a little
bit of what we've done uh by now we
should have some big ass bushes that are
in the veg stage right oh yeah yeah uh
we've talked a little bit about feeding
we've talked about top dressing a little
tiny bit we're going to talk more about
that uh we should have them kind of uh
let's see we're about to start the bloom
phase and the stretch phase so if we
want to top them and do some training
now is kind of our last chance we should
stop topping by now right unless we've
got plants that are going to clear the
fence yeah unless you know um unless
Height's a concern and that's your
motivation for topping um uh but you
know in that case by all means you know
do what you need to do to get your crop
in so yeah yeah you don't want the
neighbors seeing that you don't want the
people walking down the street to see
that [ __ ] so uh if you need and if you
don't have to do it uh we can pull the
plants down a little bit if you uh have
been taken care of it you should be able
to grab some branches the tall ones and
just pull them down and then maybe uh
tie them to a steak or maybe tie them to
Something in the garden that's already
there like a rock or something uh you
can use a steak in the ground I use Big
Bamboo poles just spread that plant out
to where instead of growing straight up
you kind of got it growing a little
horizontally now as your time to get it
going cuz uh I think within the next uh
10 days here we're going to everyone's
going to go into flower real heavily
yeah I believe so I've got some uh I've
got a strain that's a Tom Hills deep
chunk crossed with a a G13 sorry I fixed
that noise guys I couldn't find it I
fixed all that noise I just noticed it
so much better my
headphones um you know I've got a a
strain that's got you know some kind of
land R stuff in it um and it has started
flowering okay actually snuck up on me
and I had to take clones that are kind
of pre-flowering so so guys that's one
thing we're going to talk about get
clones uh if you've got some outdoor
plants and you're waiting for them to go
and flower and you need some clones from
them so you can grow next year get
clones now uh I always say and this is
I'm going to go off on a little side R
here I warned Jesse there'd be a rant
about this uh if you're growing from
seed or a clone that is brand new to you
take some clones before you go into
flower uh it's really frustrating when
you grow a plant and it's done and you
smoke it with some of your friends and
they're like what the hell is this and
you're like it's the best and you all
agree and they go I can't wait till you
grow it even better next time and you go
oh yeah I don't have a clone of that so
we're never going to get to taste this
ever again except this one round that's
the most frustrating heartbreaking
feeling so take clones you guys
definitely take clones from everything
that you grow if you've got the option
that's some uh that's a some killer
advice from a seed company owner well
yeah I'd want you to buy more seeds
right but what if you find that keeper
what if you get that or how about when
you do get that black Cher
keeper Harvest heavy it tastes dank it
[ __ ] gets you high as hell you're
going to wish you had a clone of that
yep yeah I I wish you had a clone of it
too cuz I want to cut when I find you at
the Canabis C or something I need a
clone of that one so get some clones all
the time I'm glad you mentioned the seed
company thing even that's that's Sound
Advice right there if I'm a seed guy
yeah for sure so uh yeah we were talking
about getting those plants below the
fence line you can kind of you can do
the low stress technique uh you can do a
little bit of super cropping like s does
uh kind of crack them and bend them a
little bit uh now's your last chance
really cuz you're going into flower in
about 10 days and I really don't like to
mess with plants uh there are hormones
in your plants oxin and cyto Canin that
move around with they find the tops of
the plants and affect the gra the top of
the plant and the way that stuff grows
uh you don't want to disrupt that right
now that's going to that'll freak your
plants out a little bit Yeah mess up bud
sizes yeah but you can still uh you can
still kind of pull them down and low
stress training them but you don't want
to go and kick their ass real bad or
anything I've uh had uh one of my first
Seasons growing outdoors I didn't top
and all the plants were from seed so the
the merry stem you know was just or the
main stock was uh you know just as
straight as could be and uh I tied a
rope around the top of
the sorry keep ducking and weaving on
the microphone they keep doing it too to
today yeah Jesse brought over some live
resin really high oh you got to like the
live resin great unicorn hash the
Unicorn hash yeah yeah so uh the the
ones you did from
seeding um tied the Rope uh around the
top of the plant and just pulled the
whole freaking thing down almost made
like a bow and arrow looking thing
exctly yeah yeah and uh the result was
just like this whole hro of buds it was
super cool all the side branches took
over and started they all went up yeah
talking about the hormones and stuff
Canabis wants cannabis wants one
dominant top on the plant something I
know what it is but I'm not going to
we'll go I'm trying to go slowly with
the listeners and get everybody up to
speed and not try to Ed Rosenthal people
when you talk to Ed he forgets that
we're not all doctors and scientist yeah
a weed scientist and he'll just blow
your mind so I'm trying to go slow for
you guys we'll talk about the oxin and
cyto Canin and the other hormones and
plants that make them want to grow a top
bud but when you cut out that top Bud
all the other bottom buds go hey I've
got the opportunity it's like when you
kill kill the you kill the leader all
the all the little tribes men think that
they could be the leader now that's kind
of what the top the bottom buds do so if
you grab that plant pull it over like a
fishing pole would bend when you got a
fish uh all those little branches that
you've got those little sucker buds that
often times we cut off those will create
nice little bud sides cuz now they're
they've got the chance to become a top
and they're also exposed to more light
yeah oh yeah yeah cool it's a real neat
effect so we should be in the stretch
phase or starting to pre-flow right yeah
oh totally yeah are you doing anything
for bugs now um I I spray with neem oil
um and I just did it the last time
um as soon as I notice flour uh I I
really don't especially Outdoors um I
really don't like spraying the plant
with anything me too um so uh I stop uh
the kelp Mills compost tea sprays um and
the ne oil
sprays um I do that individually ually I
don't you know just stop the whole
garden as each strain starts flowering
it's like oh can't spray that plant
anymore so you know um
so um in Southern Colorado we're getting
a lot of rain right now and there's some
weird bugs popping up um yeah little
flying CRS I've never seen yeah stuff's
going to be out of balance um I
personally haven't noticed um any uh you
know them being uh Predator plant
Predators but um it could be so but
those things are going to look for homes
and they're going to lay eggs because
their normal homes for laying eggs are
going to be disrupted and you're going
to have to go look under your leaves and
if you find some [ __ ] put on some gloves
and just clean them out of there just
clean that stuff out yeah if you want to
give if you're a hippie you want to give
those bugs a new home feel free to re
relocate them [ __ ] those bugs [ __ ] yeah
I'd throw them in the [ __ ] burn if
compost pile feed them to the
chickens oh I bet your chickens would
love you for that how are you dealing
with all the rain because it has been
raining every every day from about 6:00
to 9:00 for the past week until today
when it was [ __ ] sweltering hot at
once again um I keep my plants hollowed
out so you know the the foliage on the
inside um uh there isn't really any um e
even in veg I I do that um especially as
it gets later in veg um but uh and you
guys will learn what to cut up your
plants a little bit that that helps I
think a lot um the biggest thing the
rain has been doing to me is uh saving
me from having to water my
plants yeah so uh my main outdoor
Garden's in a depression so um a couple
acres drain into it um works out real
nice plenty of water for the plants
there you go yeah I have yet to be out
there so uh H hand we need to go on a
short little road trip I just bought my
dad's uh first uh dab rig so oh man I
got to meet your dad at the wedding I
was I I thought that was who he was he
didn't introduce himself it was loud he
just walked up shook my hand nodded at
me and gave me the like a man handshake
and a man nod like you're welcome and I
like you and he walked away and he
didn't speak because it was so loud at
where we were I wouldn't have heard him
if he did speak and I was like that's
probably pops right there but I'm not
certain and dude he uh he beams this
energy of you [ __ ] respect me that's
just what comes off of him you you do
respect me it's just and I don't want to
know what'll happen if I don't because I
have no intention but uh he just looks
like a man that commands a little bit of
respect yeah he's uh yeah in his younger
days he was um um I I've seen him do
some stuff Mortal men can't do so yeah
well I watched him do Immortal [ __ ] uh
he out dabbed and outrank everybody at
the [ __ ] table where he was and then
stood up and called us youngsters
[ __ ] cuz we couldn't keep up you guys
going to dab or what like [ __ ] man I'm
falling out of my chair dab out over
here well I could use a dab then yes sir
Mr we're on it he's a good guy I had fun
though I had fun with your your whole
family was great dude that was awesome
your wedding will be talked about not
only on this podcast but in Colorado for
years to come I hope so that's what I
was shooting for with it so first dab
bar in a Colorado wedding that I'm aware
of yeah me too so was awesome it was
funny the day after the wedding I saw um
I still haven't gotten to read it with
the Washington Post or the New York
Times had an article about uh marijuana
being a welcome guest at uh Colorado and
Washington uh weddings and I was like
damn wow you're right they're absolutely
correct you know there were usually at
weddings uh and this is just a cliche
thing there's usually one fight and it's
usually like a sisterly thing or some
[ __ ] some oh my God I can't believe you
you know it just gets [ __ ] stupid and
it's a drunk family member we didn't
have that we we actually almost did but
I I I derailed it so but yeah no that's
uh
yeah um it it was very chill and
laidback so and good job to everybody
for getting home safely I watched
everybody at the end of the night uh
search for rides and all the people that
were sober were kind enough to get all
you silly drunk [ __ ] home that was
cool yeah we we party hardy but uh we do
you know try to be safe as possible so
yeah well driving from there you had to
be safe there were cops everywhere as
she came back wasn't let no one and yeah
yeah all right guys we're talking about
a grow lesson we're starting to bloom uh
do you guys know what you're looking for
when you're going into flower are you
looking for your Mals are you for your
females uh pretty soon I hope so yeah if
you're growing Outdoors near us I really
hope so I hope you know how to find it's
on purpose and then right on yeah yeah
so uh so quickly if you're looking for
females uh it looks like they're growing
a cotton ball when they start to flower
it looks like you're getting a dandelion
when they're making flowers if you've
got uh some balls and literally it looks
like you're growing little little pack
of bananas yeah they start green they
start green yeah then they turn into
balls kill those plants unless you're
looking to make seeds and piss off all
your neighbors that grow weed and seed
up all their crops kill those male
plants yeah uh or yeah just kill them
and if you have clones uh call
me yeah we'll see what kind of Mals you
got and maybe we'll do something fun
with those so yeah you're looking for
the you want the dandelion looking ones
that's the easiest way to describe it
honestly we got to do we you guys got to
read some books if you aren't familiar
with males and females you got to catch
up a little bit do a little bit of
reading that's kind of what a grower
needs to know that [ __ ] you should be
doing so identify the males pull the
males and even femin seeds keep an eye
on them yeah it's feminizing is not a
100% not 100% we say 99% which uh still
there's problems happen when you're
making if you use certain methods you're
less likely to get fem but if you use
certain methods then fem occur often
I've seen it at a a big dispens for grow
grew out of like 250 femin seeds they
had like four males and they didn't pay
attention no no it all got wrecked and
uh the owner was quite pissed and you
know it was explained to him you know
99% do the math 250 plants yep and now
he's got a problem with femin seeds
right yes I want push that right a
little bit you're cool we just want to I
want to make sure that people hear you
dispensary owners uh in general don't
like growing from seed so yeah I agree
ones that do uh mad props to you guys
yes uh man you get such great [ __ ] when
you grow from seed you don't know what
you're proprietary genetics and you
don't have the Clone that everybody in
your neighborhood's growing everybody
around here right now has a damn Blue
Dream clone flow flow I kind of like
that I give out flow to new Growers if
you're like I'm new and I need to grow
I'm like try this fla and actually I
think that's floa I don't really think
that cut we have is flow I've always
thought that exact same thing so I've
heard that story there's somebody in
Colorado that posted on Facebook that
they know that that's floa and that they
actually got that cut from Ed Rosenthal
so if you're listening to this show
please tweet me or Facebook me uh you
can go to I genetics or IG gr culture on
Facebook or Twitter uh please cuz I want
to know more about the cut of flow that
goes around Colorado uh there's a cut
called Tangerine that is not Tangi it's
it's the Tang which I think is so
confusing I think that is flow and
Durban Poison okay oh okay okay okay
yeah yeah yeah gotta yeah if anybody in
Colorado knows what I'm talking about
it's not Tangi everyone calls it tang
and they called it the tang tang the
tang tang for a little while around here
oh okay okay yeah Prett sure that's flow
and Durban Poison cross T Tang I
remember a big full full spread uh um
dispensary had about that
strain way back in the day uh near the
Fort Collins area made that one really
is from what I know there's a lot of
that's the problem with the weed world
because by the time I give you a clone
the story has changed and then you give
it to somebody else and the story has
totally changed and then they pass it on
and now it's not even the same strain
and it's being hoarded or it's being
hoard out for way too much
money it's not being grown to its
potential because it's not being called
what it is yeah patients are getting
jacked yeah yeah so we're in the stretch
phase we're blooming we're getting off
track here uh it's cool well yeah it's
cool they seem to like the listeners
have responded man they like it when I
get all high and just talk nice yeah
they like it when I kind of go off
course cuz I ate a big ass edible oh
guys I'm I survived that edible I ate I
got to tell you I felt like [ __ ] for the
whole next day though uh eating that
whole edible really uh took a toll on my
body uh I'm getting old as part of what
I'm trying to say I'm 35 now and I think
when I was 25 I probably could have done
it and not felt like [ __ ] the next day
but I had to go get some kombucha and
[ __ ] eat a big fat meal I try had to
try to put myself back on track but no
disrespect to that edible company I was
not supposed to eat all of it at once no
I listened to that episode so I was high
you weren't yeah not at all you weren't
even supposed to eat half of that once
no
yeah so why do they make the stuff so
good though oh it was delicious too if
that was just a like a restaurant dinner
or a restaurant dessert I'd order that I
need that peanut butter thing you serve
put some ice cream with it it'd be
delicious so since we're going into
flour we're starting to stretch a little
bit we're looking for the males we're
looking for hermaphrodites also if it's
questionable if it's weird keep a really
good eye on it lower inner
branches uh that's a good spot to look
for Hermes where you don't get as much
light straight on the top too top lead
bud it's a common area too so uh get
those out of there the males in the the
Herms get them out of there put them in
the fire pit uh he guess be careful when
you're throwing away your trash if you
live in a non-legal State that's
something that I just want to throw out
there for you just compost it yeah
compost it if you can feed it to your
chickens come on Jesse not all of us
have a farm some of us are city folk
here there's another there's another
podcast where one of the guys has
chickens oh yeah uh I shout those guys
out so we could say that uh shout out to
crunchy yeah word what's up homie what
up bro he cooked me dinner one time
indirectly I was at an event or at a
party where he was the chef and he made
dinner for everybody and props man good
cooking he actually asked me about my
dietary needs cuz he saw that I got
dreadlocks he knew I was a rosta rostas
have strict dietary restrictions and he
was respectful to that and made a meal
around what I can and cannot eat I
always do that when I barbecue with
vegetarian friends you don't know that
yet but well you invited me and you
assured me that there would be
vegetarian friendly food I appreciate
that so guys respect your vegetarian
friends sure don't make fun of them
that's just stupid yeah it is yeah do
you yeah dude that is so stupid we make
fun of you back when you do it because
good they deserve it your col's full of
[ __ ] rotten and you're telling me I'm
stupid for not eating it so
yeah we get even in our own ways and and
then you guys
die hey hey hey
no I don't even know any good vegetarian
jokes neither do I uh what do you call a
vegetarian with diarrhea that's a Sal
That's a classic one that's the only one
I got for you all right uh vegetarian
let's feed our ganja plants uh we're
going into bloom so we can slowly
decrease the nitrogen and increase the
phosphorus and
potassium uh if you're top dressing you
can switch your te's to the more
phosphorus and potassium based te's for
sure uh if you're using the like
granulated products that they sell in
the store you can go ahead and switch to
the bloom version of those products now
you don't have to keep using that veg
stuff yeah uh slowly switch that stuff
though
um still well I don't yeah um assuming
you've only applied it one or two times
something like that um mix a little just
make sure you have nitrogen cuz a lot of
time those uh products are pretty low on
nitrogen okay on the bloom side so maybe
well actually when I feed my indoor
plants I don't switch the day that I put
them into flow I don't just say they're
in flow let's cut out all the veg NES
and go to just my bloom schedule I kind
of phase it out there's like a twoe
period And I also keep my metal Hy
lights in for about 14 to 21 days to
keep them short and stocky and then when
you switch them you really see them they
stay low and the butts fatten up so
that's yeah so just slowly I like to
phase out my veg into my Bloom feed is
what I think I'm trying to
say um but uh yeah start that Mexican B
guano um epom salts if you're using that
um it's a good time to be uh fer you
know one last Fier spray Mexican or
Jamaican B guano uh Jamaican there you
go yeah it's want to correct I think you
said High PK uh like um some companies
have blended guanas with uh different
NPK values so just you want a high PK so
uh any alphaalpha meal with this feed um
I love that stuff
so um yeah I mean it's a great time to
go ahead and top dress some in um Al
falam mil um you know it's really
accessible nitrogen so what else are you
putting in your tea right now some
Jamaican guano yeah some alphalpha meal
yep um molasses molasses all the time um
some uh Rocky Mountain earthworm uh
Factory or some War poop yeah yeah he's
got the bomb stuff I can't uh I'm kind
of St I can't Rocky Mountain uh I don't
remember the name of worm company I
think is what it is yeah yeah if you
Google Rocky Mountain worm you'll find
what we're talking about I've had my own
uh or I've made my own worm castings
before and they didn't look as good as
his do so um it's all about what you
feed those worms for sure for sure yeah
know he's got a real cool setup go check
him out up in Springs that's a free
shout out too yeah we do a lot of free
shout outs for sure it's good stuff
though people grow good stuff it's
Community man it's Community it's not
all about business all the
time um some micos uh you know there's
several different brands of it ogt great
white shark yeah uh zho if you're using
banic hair yeah um
okay uh the Orca stuff liquid um that's
half dead I've never tried that yeah I
always fear that liquids are going to
wreak havoc on the rest of my stuff yeah
cuz you don't know what preservative
there is in there yeah and the powders
you can sprinkle it right near the root
Zone and yeah and see that it's on there
and be happy with that so yeah the ogt
is available at hyro poblo that stuff's
awesome that's what I would recommend
out of all that you can uh I can see a
difference when I feed my plants that
within 24 hours uh the next light cycle
two light cycles later I guess when they
come on they are praying they're up the
leaves are pointing straight up like yes
make them pre yeah they they love that
[ __ ] that should be their slogan yeah no
that's uh ogt is the bomb uh great white
shark is really good at getting rid of
soil based insects nice something in
there doesn't like yeah um uh I've heard
the grok Kashi does same thing too so
we're doing some experiments with that
right now so yeah Jesse mentioned before
we recorded that he got some grok Kashi
if you guys aren't paying attention to
the grok Kashi it's
probiotics uh big love to the probiotic
Farmers Alliance what up Gage green and
all the guys running the probiotic
pharmac Alliance Gage green yeah forgot
about that yeah it's key play and uh I
don't know if I should used Mike's real
name but what's up
Mike uh those guys are inspiring uh
people ask where I get a lot of my
inspiration and a lot of my ideas and
[ __ ] uh a lot of it currently comes from
Gage that's who I'm on
now there was a time where it was all
Som of course you I didn't know S I had
no idea what that was and then a friend
of mine was like you remind me of s and
I Googled it and I was like that could
be my father
[ __ ] that's racist say whoever told you
that yeah it kind of is you're both
white and have
dreadlocks it's all about the vibe it
was more about the vibe someone talks
about my Medics and I'm really big on
the mics if we'll talk about more about
that later that's the it's like a the
The Vibes subcool always gets me going
subol I was into subcool for a little
while uh not to be a hater I lost
interest when it got dramatic with him
and Miss Jill on the weed nerd show
that's when I fell off sorry that's
where I lost interest uh and then uh
I've always been a big fan of Jorge and
Ed Rosenthal all that stuff but I like
reading that's always gets me fired up
and yeah lately Gage green has been one
of the best breeder I was a I was a Cali
Connection Fanboy for a little while I'm
pretty decent friends with swerve and
Adam Mill so for sure yeah he's got it
going on yeah dude that's that's a good
seed company right there you work hard
you get paid good they were kind enough
to let us hang out in their Booth uh for
420 at the Cannabis Cup on 420 at 420 so
everyone else is crowded and chaotic and
I was sitting on a couch taking a dab
with Adam Mill so any I was at the
Cannabis Cup anyone who had a couch
anywhere was chilling so yeah yeah that
was that was a hot cup yeah can't wait
for 420 again this year I hear big
things are coming I thought 2 years ago
was crowded but it was more chaotic two
years ago for sure though oh that year
when you couldn't walk through yeah yeah
yeah yeah was the alley that alley was
ridiculous big shout out the High Times
crew Danny Dano Bobby black Nico I'm
gonna miss a lot because there's a lot
of you guys Mr Dan
Sky shout out to you guys for coming to
Colorado and doing a huge ass event
that's a lot of work you guys look like
you're going [ __ ] crazy when you come
here and do it running around all
chaotic for sure yeah and Danny Dano
will take time to talk to you I walked
by just kindly I said free weed just
joking around and he turned around and
shook my hand and talked to me and it
was kind of he didn't need to do that he
was busy you know yeah I interrupted him
right in the middle of a conversation I
was like hey thanks for recording free
weed dude hey Danny you haven't put out
a podcast in over a month we need a new
episode of free weed I'm trying to fill
your Gap dude I'm trying to fill your
gap for you that's gross I'm never going
to say that
to uh feeling Danny Dano's Gap
there's a podcast called free weed it's
uh hosted by Danny Danko and Mike Hughes
uh it's a High Times production I'm not
sponsored by them in any way I just have
respect for people uh Danny Dano and the
free weed podcast are actually part of
what inspired this show for sure I like
to do things my way and I kind of
combined a lot of my favorite people's
shows and do my own thing here and we
have the igro culture podcast what's up
Mike Hughes too yeah oh I mention I made
sure to say my is on Mak make sure he
gets love feel bad for the uh um for
Mike yeah he contributes it should be
free weed with Danny and Mike they're Mr
Danny you hear that guys just kidding
just kidding we'll tag at Danny Dano in
this episode we'll see I'm not sure if I
follow my cu's but we'll tag him also
we'll see if they can listen to this and
uh you better hook me up with something
Mike pack of raw papers hey that'll work
his name is Jesse Gro so if you want to
give a shout out it's rosta Jeff and
Jesse GR grow for sure I think I said
your full name on the other podcast uh
sorry it's gotten to the point I don't
really give a [ __ ] uh I tried to keep my
identity kind of separate from the I
genetics I grow culture stuff but
everybody knows it's rust CH you can't
after the first cannabis cut people took
pictures with me and they're like look
I'm getting high with iy genetics and I
was like well they know I'm the [ __ ]
ridiculously tall white guy with red box
this is game over I remember when we
first met you uh told me something about
that and then within like a few weeks
you're like ah
whatever try to keep it on the down low
man yeah after the cup when I went and
subcool is there with packs of seeds in
his hand like what's up I'm subcool
here's seeds I was like I don't have
[ __ ] to worry about like yeah yeah he
doesn't even live in this state and just
yeah change my whole outlook on things
for sure all right guys we've talked a
little bit about outdoor growing we're
starting to bloom I told you how to find
your mails your hermaphrodites get those
out of there we told you to cut clones
make sure you cut clones you don't want
to grow some [ __ ] and then be like this
is my best strain ever and it's gone
I've done that I actually grew a strain
I don't know if I even want to say the
name Kevin if you're listening it was
that uh that strain that you and Pops
loved it's gone I couldn't get it to
root those clones would not take roots
for the life of me so I've had that
happen it got away I've got another pack
of those seeds we'll see if that works
uh you got to stop topping but you can
super crop and train your stuff we were
talking about what Jesse puts in I try
to uh he doesn't realize I'm trying to
fish out what he's putting in his tea
cuz he doesn't like to tell us he
doesn't like to share all the info so
slowly pry it out of him we got molasses
we got alfalfa meal we got guano we got
worm castings we got micos are you using
any sort of seelp right now yeah kelp
yeah uh the Dr Neptune stuff see details
for like a um couple cups um yeah and
now it's flower time so uh blood meal
bone meal any of that stuff yet I've
never put any of that stuff oh you don't
like slaughterhouse products well no I
use it I've never put it in a tea um um
but top dressing yeah I do have an issue
with slaughterhouse products but I also
have a uh a [ __ ] ton of slaughterhouse
products so you're a farmer and you
understand you uh you balance it out
yeah I mean there's nothing wrong with
blood Mills just like where well I mean
I guess the argument could be made that
there is something wrong with it but the
biggest thing with commercial blood
Mills we don't know where it came from
um you know those or at least that's my
big issue with it and those cows were
fed [ __ ] that I probably highly
disapprove of so yeah um and don't want
to put into my body part of why I'm a
vegetarian is cuz the way they treat
cows you know yeah for sure there's no
need to contribute to that in my opinion
in general I don't really like eating
beef um I can't stand ground beef it's
one of the most disgusting things I can
that's the most questionable meat like
what ground up what I hate when I'm
working and in a hurry and yeah as a
farmer and a grower are you bothered by
like fast food joints by seeing what
people are eating yeah um process any
kind of processed meat um and I'm just
as guilty of it um I I try hard when I
get busy in life um you know it's just
it's hard to cook and it's easy to drive
through a drive-thru and uh but yeah
that's that's why this country is so fat
that's why we have cancer that's
everything it's just yeah I agree with I
have huge issue with all that stuff yeah
we paid people will pay top dollar for
their booze pay top dollar for their
herb but then spend 99 cent a [ __ ]
cheeseburg yeah yeah yeah spend those
bucks on yourself guys yeah uh cancer is
expensive later in your life just cook
at home it's good for relationships cook
with friends eat with friends eat with
you know your wife your girlfriend your
kids it's just you know it's just good
so you cook with friends for
relationships that's some sound advice
from Jesse you learned some [ __ ] on
accident today you didn't think that was
coming all right uh we've done 30
minutes man you got anything else you
want to add to the grow lesson before we
kind of start wrapping it up um a little
D vegging um go ahead and pull up the
bottoms of the plants uh so clip off any
uh shave their legs shave their legs
that's make them sexy all that bottom
stuff is going to be crap and lar and
it's going to kind of take away from the
top of your plant so take that bottom
the little sucker leaves you can tell
what I'm talking about if it's not
making and you can do this all the way
up to like three or four weeks into
bloom if you want keep doing it yeah
yeah yeah just take off all that crap
that is in the way you'll know if it
doesn't look like it's going to be a bud
worth trimming take it off it doesn't
need to be there and throw it away don't
just throw it on the ground I see a lot
of you guys cut your leaves off and
throw them in the ground don't do that
reuse it in some way um yeah uh I've
been oh mulching that's what we'll throw
up real quick um and mulching up a
little bit uh little
Alfalfa um some old hay that we had
laying around um actually I think it was
straw but um whatever all the city Folk
yeah that's the same [ __ ] um some
compost um and uh you know just helps
hold water um it's getting into the hot
time of year normally uh we're monsoon
season right now apparently
but um you know this other people in
other parts of the country you know this
mulching Up's good and it's also a great
way to get rid of all your green waste
so um you know that's it it's just a a
big old cycle if you're if you're
juicing uh you could juice your cannabis
leaves if you haven't been spraying [ __ ]
on them if you've put NE oil or some
chemicals do not juice them please don't
if your uh if your leaves are clean uh
go ahead and Juice those and taste that
up yeah so we're mulching now you have
taught us a lot of stuff everyone's
going to move to the country and abandon
the city and all move out to the middle
of nowhere and just start these organic
small not even large scale just small
scale organic ganja Farms yeah you don't
have to do much I mean just do your part
grow your own food grow your own herb
get some chickens make your own eggs you
know I don't e fer uh I really try not
to eat eggs if you like it's just not
that just seems funky to me I can't eat
but grocery store eggs if yeah if I it's
kind of where I'm headed if I had
chickens bro we'd eat eggs every day I'd
go out and get two or three eggs from
the chickens and we'd do it like the uh
your shirts you're wearing their uh you
know the that yellow is like grocery
store yellow and their orange is like
what my eggs look like so you know
that's probably 10 times the nutrients
in there yeah also flavor they they have
a flavor yeah um you you just think eggs
have flavor till till you have good ones
so you have a good Farm Fresh Egg and I
I have my chickens in the city too so we
have them at the farm too but I also
have chickens in my backyard so you can
have chickens over there yeah that's
cool that's cool I didn't know you could
do that can have a in PUO you can have
don't quote me on this but I think it's
six or seven um no encroachment um which
means you know you can't build it right
next to your your chicken pin right next
to your fence um it's got to be 5 ft
from a property line um no roosters so
yeah and and they can't be a nuisance
which you know takes a while to develop
a nuisance so I have one that I'm about
ready to kill I can't believe none of my
neighbors have called
in it wakes me up too early I'm like
you're next [ __ ] yeah your name is
dinner
[ __ ] chicken noodle soup awesome
once again bro congratulations we'll
quit talking about the wedding on the
show it was so much fun guys talk about
it so much epic parties so
congratulations to your wife also thank
you uh I don't know if she listens but I
hope you do burn occasionally I force
her too she always laughs at me for
listening to myself well yeah you got to
remember what you said sure you didn't
say anything silly on the show yeah yeah
you're getting really good at this so
I'm looking forward to more episodes cuz
you're starting to get comfortable aw
when do you think you come back about
two or three weeks when we start kicking
into flower for sure yeah um I'll give
you a call as soon as like I get some
good bud set so yeah sounds good to me
yeah so guys we're going to take some
dabs um go check out hyro denver.com I
think is the website yeah something yeah
go look at that while we uh take some
dabs and I'll be back to wrap up the
show in just a minute dude thanks again
for coming on we look forward to having
you back yeah yeah Peace and Love Every
have a good one
[Music]
everyone
all right ladies and gentlemen there was
another great grow lesson from Jesse I
want to give him a big shout out for
coming out and taking some time out from
his garden uh he's got a farm he's got a
family he's newly married so uh takes
him little effort to get over here and I
appreciate it thanks a lot bro look
forward to having you
back uh coming up in future episode I
plan to have a little debate on uh well
not a debate but a discussion a friendly
discussion on uh the classic question of
Clone versus seed and also we'll have a
little subtopic of femin versus regular
seeds I know a lot of people are opposed
to feminized seeds so we can talk a
little bit about that clear up some
myths give some people some information
I'll check it out that's red rat in the
song there yeah turn that up for a
minute let's get
down it's a pretty good mix NC shout out
for this brand new mix the niik you just
made pretty smooth I like it all right
so now the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
igro culture find the review section
give us a fivar r after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future podcast you can also leave
your comments on Stitcher and I'll read
those comments too it's a little harder
to get to those comments but I will read
them I search for them don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
swell. and also each and every episode
is archived at iy gentics
color.com make sure you follow us on uh
where are you going to follow us you're
going to follow us on Instagram Twitter
Facebook uh make sure you check out igr
culture on Instagram and Twitter follow
us on Facebook at ulture you can email
me ulture hotmail.com if you want to see
some awesome cannabis photography you
can always check out @ iry gentics on
Instagram I think that's all I got for
you guys this episode so uh number 25 is
coming up make sure you listen to 25
it'll work to your
benefit big old shout out to my ninja
Spence shout out to DJ Nick
T shout out to to Peter and Jaden get
off the couch you lazy
[ __ ] thanks for listening you guys take
a fat dab give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me