hey everyone this is damp and rainy and
you're listening to the grow from your
heard podcast yeah welcome back cannabis
community it's time for episode number
231 of The Grove from your heart podcast
your source for cannabis news education
and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends at the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to cash to the entire mystic roots crew
ladies and gentlemen I dabbed out this
evening I'm having a great day I hope
you guys are having a good day also
thank you for joining me
let's talk about what I'm dabbing on I
just took a giant dab of some lemon
Geoffrey hi cannabinoid full spectrum
extract with a little bit of height herb
full spectrum extract pour it into the
banger and it can I change my BAE I wish
you guys were here to dab with me one of
these days maybe right I want to talk
about a new toy I got you guys I picked
up a thing called a thermal banger I've
talked about a banger on the show before
a banger is basically it attaches to a
rig which is basically a small bubbler
or a pipe or maybe even a bong I prefer
a smaller bubbler I like a handheld
sidecar size sort of bubbler thing
Google a hitman hammerhead sidecar those
are some of my favorite rigs they're
affordable and I like the style and the
function of the size and shape it's
perfect but anyway I get the 14 mil mail
attachment coming out here the the joint
coming out then the banger attaches to
that it's got a 14 millimeter female
then it comes up and it's got a 90
degree turn on it been on that it's got
like a it looks like maybe an
upside-down thimbles made out of glass
it's all glass it looks like a thimble
and then on the inside of that is a
smaller thimble on the inside so it's
maybe like a big like a soda bottle lid
or a water bottle lid it's about that
diameter then a little bit taller than
that maybe one and a half of those tall
then on the inside is another one
another cylinder I guess you could say
it looks like a cup with a cup inside of
it a bowl with a cup inside of it and
you keep the outside and you put the dab
on the inside one and then he put so
when I bought it they didn't have these
caps available I bought it over at
elevate glass on 517 south they own when
I bought the thermal banger is what it's
called they didn't have these bubble
caps so I bought it and I took it home
and I tried to take a dab with a normal
carbon cap but it just wasn't doing it
for me a senators I like that kind of
sucks the next time I went to higher
elevations masterpiece productions which
is elevates sister store just across
town like hey how'd you like your
thermal banger I was like it sucks and
they're like do you have a bubble cap
for it and I was like no sir I do not
and they're like let's get you a bubble
cap for us and I've got a bubble cap
and let me tell you the buffle cap in
the thermal banger make an amazing
[ __ ] dab I've been getting extra high
lately I mix the dabs I already take
gigantic dabs and it just makes the
gigantic dab I take seem even gigantic
her which I know isn't even a word but
it is now when you dab with me take
gigantic her dabs that should be a
bumper sticker take gigantic er dabs
it's good for you anyway let's talk
about what I'm smoking on that's put me
in this condition I talked about the
lemon Geoffrey high cannabinoid and
Haider full-spectrum extracts I've also
got some of this star dog ambrosia I
just held it up to the microphone like
you guys would be able to smell it
that's that's how high that [ __ ] made me
anyway I've also got some screaming
tangerines which smells it just screams
tangerines we need to add that the whole
room smells like a tangerine for a
little bit I've also got the gorilla
glue we talked about in a previous
previous episode I went back and bought
more because I like what it does to my
face it makes me nice and high that's my
the lemony stuff is the rectory are the
medical cannabis for me a little better
I think that when I'm dabbing stuff that
has like citrus and lemons that's kind
of more medical for me when I smoke this
gassy flavored stuff that's recreational
that gives me a recreational high trust
me I think if I take enough dabs of any
strain it becomes recreational but still
recreationally use as medical use
because if it makes you feel better it
makes you feel better it's mental health
it's physical health it's all related
anyway the gorilla glue gets me really
high they had some oh I've got some star
dog batter also what else do we have
sitting here's some Clementine I like
this Clementine it's more flavour then
he gets me high but maybe that's because
it's fixing something that I'm not
noticing but I really do enjoy the
flavor of the Clementine and also what
did I get the the sour amnesia it
smelled really good in the jar and it
smells pretty good in the jar I've
stirred it up and I've dabbed out of it
a lot but the flavor I'm smelling it
again the flavor just doesn't come
through in a DAB it doesn't that flavor
I was hoping it different there would be
more flavor to it the high is okay it's
acceptable but I that flavour just
didn't come through that was what I
bought it for anyway I've got a whole
bunch of tasty hatcher I've been dabbing
a whole smorgasbord of it today I've
also got some lemon Geoffrey terms and
I've got some of the Clementine Terp so
I don't dunked a little bit of the
Clementine batter into the Clementine
turps and took a little
that citrus flavor is always nice I've
learned that if I overheat the
Clementine if a Clementine dab gets too
hot in my opinion it tastes a little bit
like orange chicken or some sort of
orange flavored Chinese food which I
know sounds weird because I don't even
eat chicken but it tastes like some kind
of Chinese food is what it reminds me of
orange syrup II think that like sticky
orange syrup that comes on Chinese food
maybe I'm crazy no I certainly am crazy
but maybe that opinion is crazy because
I'm gonna take a quick drink I'm not
even gonna press pause she's gonna take
a drink moisten up throat and we'll keep
talking here
all right hopefully that keeps me going
for a couple of minutes so let's update
you guys on a breeding project I've been
talking about a breeding project quite
frequently on the podcast and I am proud
to say that those seeds have been
successfully harvested there are quite a
few great new crosses some of them were
just testers that will probably be kept
privately for myself the Platinum tangi
to arise I don't know how how much
that'll get spread out that'll probably
stay right here in my vault I'll grow
those out find the great ones and then
maybe breed with or two that the Kim for
to arise won't go too far but things I
do plan on making for like a production
run I have to test them you guys have to
see if they're worth a [ __ ] but
something I know they'll be good just
because I'm a good breeder I have a good
intuition I grow from my heart breed
with love I know these are gonna be well
the Capleton to arise the Kalonji to
arise flow to arise those things are
gonna be bred I'm sure that those will
get released because I like to make a
lot of those the Platinum tangi was just
kind of a personal project for myself
the Platinum tangi came before a couple
those won't go anywhere but Capleton
flow Kalonji Kush maybe even the
redheaded stranger to arise but like I
said I got a test them all see if
they're worth a [ __ ] before I let
anybody even touch them
once I've tested a few I'll give them
out to other people to test so they'll
go through two or three rounds of
testing before they were ever even be
giving out as freebies or for sale
anywhere so that'll be a while but
there's a lot of whole new great [ __ ]
there's Jeff Shoji to arise hell's OG to
arise Kalonji kush canadensis
camphor critical mass platinum tangi did
a whole bunch of cool stuff to arise to
see the plants have been so the way I
did it this time I cut down the plant ID
foliated it heavily I took almost all of
the leaves off of the plant then I
bucked the buds off of the sticks and
then I just put all of the buds into
Tupperware dishes and they're carefully
labeled with what plant they are and
they're all sitting in a little area
they're just drying out now and when
they dry I will go and just crumble them
up into the little Tupperware dish
they're in then you just basically tip
it to the side and all the seeds were a
lot and all the bud stays up at the top
they just gather up all the seeds put
them in a jar label it and then I go
through in the future and sort out all
the bad lookin seeds and those go to
actually in his burn feed or I just
throw them away or did they end up his
chicken
mainly they go into the mix with the
chicken feet just to make you go a
little bit further there's not a lot of
them but something's got to happen with
them so they just get thrown in with the
chicken feeder with the bird feed not my
chickens are my Birds they get taken
somewhere else for that Oh what else was
I gonna say about the breeding project
oh here we go if you're breeding with
multiple females and one male in a room
timing is a [ __ ] the lemon skunk that I
bred with yes I did breed two lemons
smoked to make more Firefly seeds and I
also made more morning dew seeds the
grateful dog to arise there's more of
that the lemons going to arise there's
plenty more of that but what I was gonna
say the lemon skunk is it really strong
sativa it takes longer than almost
everything else in that room to flower
and it really showed me that when I
tried to breed with it I should have put
that plant in to flower a week to ten
days before everything else and it would
have made more seeds it made a very
minimal amount of seeds because I tried
to time it with everything else so my
advice to you is if you're going to
breed and in the future I do have an
email about breeding I'm going to get to
it I'm just overwhelmed with emails
working my way through them when when
you do breed think more about plants
that time up better because I put a 72
day plant in with 56 and 60 day plants
and tried to breed and it kind of [ __ ]
up they didn't do anything wrong it just
everything probably made like a thousand
seeds and this one made like five
hundred that's that's what went wrong
and once it'll run so did I tell you
guys that I was breeding in cups most of
my plants in the breeding project were
in larger pots but I had some that I
just wanted to make a few for myself
like we talked about earlier the
Platinum tangi the chem for those plants
were in beer cups you guys I had them on
a table in a beer cup and I floured them
all the way out in the beer cup i bred
to them in a beer cup they made about
fifty seeds each plant and as a breeder
that's all I need for myself to do
plenty of stuff so if you're looking to
breed don't be intimidated don't be
afraid you can do it in very small pots
and make fifty to a hundred seeds for
yourself with no problem
so that's really easy to do I wouldn't
breed under anything smaller than a 600
watt light I tried to breed with the 400
and it didn't make [ __ ] for seeds the
600 did okay honestly a thousand is
where it's at if you're trying to breed
and make healthy solid seeds so you
can't do small pots if you just want to
do like a 5x5 space of cups or three
gallon pots or I like six-inch net pots
however you want to do it you don't have
to
to do a breeding project the timing is
the crucial part is what I think I was
trying to say when I got off on a rant
anyway the seed project has been
harvested what's my next order of
business I owe a shout out to a couple
of really kind and generous people I'll
give a shout out I'm not sure if either
of these guys want me to say their names
because they have contributed on patreon
and I try to keep it kind of private and
not blast everybody's name of a big
shout out to John B and Steven P patreon
contributors they have made very
generous patreon contributions for a
couple of months now I does not go
unnoticed if you guys ever have
questions or anything like that make
sure you email them to me and let me
know who you are remind me that you're
John B and Steven P from patreon and
I'll definitely get your questions to
the top of the list and try to help you
guys out I completely appreciate your
generosity and support that shows me
that you guys trust me and that you
believe in me and then I'm helping you
out in some sort of way and that means a
lot to me that means more to me I'd
appreciate the contribution but if
you're gonna throw that at me that means
that you trust me and you believe in me
so thank you that means a lot to me too
a guy putting out a podcast every week
that makes it well worth it
all right let me tell you about patreon
since I'm bacon dudes for contributing
to patreon patreon is a website patreon
is also a service that allows you as a
listener to financially contribute to
the podcast that's right I'm not trying
to beg for money but if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
if you feel like my time my effort my
energy my guidance my support my
knowledge my help my consultations were
worth a couple of bucks you can go to
patreon.com/scishow from your heart and
all the information that you need will
be right there you can sign up to become
a patreon contributor and that will
allow you to contribute to the show what
that would do for me honestly I will use
those funds to pay for the cost of my
website I have a website which is where
I host this podcast it does cost me a
few bucks every year to keep that up I
post a lot of content so there's a lot
of bandwidth there's a lot of storage
that I pay for there are 230 episodes
the podcast that means that there are a
hundred of them are available on the
feed if I can learn how to make my
website show more I'll put them all up
there I just cannot learn how to do that
my web guy doesn't know how to do it if
we can figure out how to get all 231
available they would be there on the
website for you I just don't know how to
make that yeah find that damn button to
click yet anyways got to be there
somewhere but what I'll do with your
funds
maybe I'll pay somebody who's better at
web hosting I'm just kidding my guy's
good he's just busy ah but I will pay
for the website with the funds that you
send my way I also these little
microphone covers I'm rubbing this one
right here I have guests on the show
quite often I try to replace these when
Mike comes over I try not to make Mike
use the same microphone cover that maybe
granny or Lindsay or Chris whoever else
has been on the show in the past I try
not to make them share I think that kind
of gets a little funky if you have them
on there for too long I can smell my own
if I use it for too long and if I can
smell my own that means other people can
smell other people's even sooner and
that's just gross to do that to them so
I swap out these microphone covers I
also have to buy new memory cards from
my zoom h6 occasionally because it eats
them for some reason just basic stuff
like that I'm not begging but if you
feel like you want to contribute that's
what it would help me with and I would
appreciate it
also there's little things on their tour
if you donate if you contribute a
certain amount it puts you in line to
get your questions answered first email
me or something when you do that let me
know that you did that because patreon
isn't good at notifying me of that stuff
I have to go check every month so send
me an email and say hey dude I just
contributed this much on patreon and I
would like my question answered and I
will get it I'll put you right at the
top of the list all print your email out
and then I will write on it patreon then
I'll make sure to give you a shout out
and I will also read your email so
patreon.com slash go from your heart
that would allow you as a listener to
financially contribute to the podcast
now I will quit begging and we'll move
forward with the podcast what else has
been going on in the world of Rasta Jeff
and I read genetics and the girl from
your heart podcast for those of you who
do not know I am the lead cultivator for
three rivers there's a dispensary in
Pueblo called Three Rivers we have a
medical side and a recreational side if
you live in Colorado and you're a
medical marijuana patient you can shop
on the medical side if you do not have
your medical marijuana recommendation
from a doctor if you're coming from out
of state and you're 21 and over you are
allowed to shop on the recreational side
i think i said that right the medical
side and the recreational side but i am
currently running the grove for the
medical side we are building a very
large facility that will host more
medical and our recreational grow and i
will be running that grow as well
recently we had a a volunteer inspection
a compliance inspection from the
Department of Agriculture
if you run or work in a large grow in
Colorado any type of girl if you're
growing tomatoes if you're growing
lettuce if you're growing whatever
happened down there cantaloupes or
peaches but cannabis right now is where
they're focused but if you're growing
anything if you have a farm that's
licensed you will be visited and
inspected by the Colorado Department of
Agriculture their goal and their main
mission is to make sure that you are not
putting any humans or animals in danger
they don't want you to kill animals they
don't want you to kill people and they
don't want you to kill the environment
that is their main goal it was a little
nerve-racking when I was told hey the
Department of Agriculture is coming to
inspect your facility to tell you the
truth I got like Oh what is that like
but I have a compliance officer that
guides me through things at the grow and
we got together and they make a
checklist the Department of Ag makes it
very easy they make a checklist that you
can go through and make sure that
everything is order in order they tell
you what you are allowed and are not
allowed to have on premises they tell
you what you are and are not allowed to
do and as long as you're following basic
safety rules you're already doing these
things I have been trained in worker
protection safety by the Department of
Agriculture so I already knew what I
needed to look for and prepare for what
I needed to train my guys on so these
guys if you have a grow they will be at
your if you're running a cannabis grow
they will be at your cannabis grow
eventually if they have not been there I
recommend that you call and you schedule
a voluntary compliance check if they
come for a voluntary compliance check
unless they see I think the guy said
he's looking for anything that would
cause immediate threat to human or
animal safety unless they see anything
that's a blatant [ __ ] unless you're
doing something stupid if you call for a
voluntary compliance check they are not
going to write you up or find you for
anything we didn't have anything to be
written up for but they were very happy
with us and they said hey we want you
guys to call so that we can come out
here and tell you what to do because you
don't know what you're doing wrong until
you're corrected so if you've got a
facility I would recommend you call the
Colorado Department of Agriculture and
schedule a compliance check a voluntary
compliance check this could prevent the
things like we spoke about in a previous
episode where people were not applying
the proper pesticide
they're not applying them properly if
somebody woulda came out there and spoke
with those folks they could have gotten
it correct and they would not have had
as large of a problem if you schedule
them to come out there they'll come out
there and look at your girl all they did
they looked at our pesticide logs I'm
not sure how much I'm supposed to talk
about they looked at our pesticide logs
they looked for our MSDS logs which is
the material safety data sheets you have
to have every pesticide and product
that's in the grow you have to have the
material safety data sheet available in
a central location they made sure we had
I wash stations they honestly didn't
even check for fire extinguishers we had
fire extinguishers in all the proper
places they did not even check for those
they asked us a lot of questions about
our pesticide application procedures how
do you do it where do you do it what do
you wear when you do it they just
basically wanted to make sure that we
were doing everything safely and
correctly there were a couple of things
he's like hey you do that right but have
you ever thought about this and then he
would encourage thought in my mind and
he would make me think of a better safer
more practical way to do some things
because I'm a smart dude but honestly
I'm gonna miss some [ __ ] we're all going
to miss a few things and a little bit of
guidance should be appreciated a little
bit of education should be appreciated
so I was grateful if this dude pointed a
couple of things out there was no
violation or anything but he's like did
you ever think of this did you ever
think of this and he just gave us a few
ideas on ways we could improve safety
there was really no reason for me to be
nervous or intimidated by a Department
of Agriculture inspection the guy was
really cool he was very knowledgeable
and he did not want to write anybody up
for anything he wanted to make sure we
were doing things correctly he wanted to
leave us a list of things we could
improve and then as we were talking the
dude was just very knowledgeable and he
seemed to know a lot about pesticide
application he knew a lot about
agriculture he was just a very
knowledgeable guy so as we spoke he
taught me a lot of great things he was
taught me a lot about respirators a lot
about respirator use because we're
required to have respirator training and
I was unaware of that it's not in some
of the paperwork that I've got but it's
in the updated paperwork and he was like
hey that's new [ __ ] you have this many
days to get that taken care of so I'll
be back in 60 to 90 days to check on me
and to tell you the truth we've already
scheduled all of the respirator training
everything will have been handled very
soon you guys if you're using a
respirator make sure you're using the
right cartridges on the respirator and
maybe even go to a doctor and make sure
your lungs are properly equipped to wear
that
sprayer and then maybe even get a fit
test and make sure you're wearing the
respirator correctly because there are
if you're not wearing it properly there
are leaks and you're just breathing in
the pesticide anyway and you make little
little air holes that actually bring in
more than you would if you just opened
it freely as you create a little suction
anyway the Department of Agriculture was
great I had no reason to be intimidated
and if you have a facility I recommend
that you call and volunteer for a
voluntary compliance check I learned a
lot of things and that way if you are
screwing up they'll come tell you hey
you're screwing up they don't show up
surprisingly bill I can't look you
[ __ ] up you got this in this together
basically you have to keep your
pesticides away from all your nutrients
and you have to have all your equipment
accessible you have to have your safety
equipment accessible you have to have
all of your paperwork your spray logs or
MSDS sheets and all of your Department
of Agriculture posters that racist
poster you have to have that accessible
and also you need I wash stations and
they're going to ask you a lot of
questions about what happens if your
worker sprays pesticides in his eyes
what are you going to do how's this
gonna happen
who's going to drive them to the
hospital where is the hospital who does
he notify if something happens be
prepared for those types of questions
fortunately I'm a smart dude we're kind
of prepared and I have a great
compliance officer so I answered all of
those questions correctly then they pull
aside all of the growers anybody that
applies pesticides or any sort of sprays
using the pesticide application device
ah they ask them a lot of questions also
and they also inspected all of the
pesticide applicators we've got a paint
sprayer and then we've got some smaller
things that we use they inspected all of
those they asked us how we clean them
how often we clean them there were a lot
of questions basically make sure you're
doing [ __ ] right and everything will be
okay but if you don't schedule the
voluntarily voluntary inspection they
can just show up and inspect and then if
you [ __ ] up they can find you they can
do whatever they want but basically
they're making sure you're not causing
any immediate threat to human health or
safety as well their main goal so
shadows my new friend at the Department
of Agriculture it was great learning a
lot from you I doubt you listened to the
podcast but if you do big thumbs up I
had a great day with you all right you
guys I need to press pause I'm talking
really fast so you know what let's not
even press pause let's just take a DAB
together and then then we're gonna get
into some emails I hope that this works
out because I gotta get my [ __ ] in a
pile I got this email right here I'm
trying to set myself up for
success y'all um let's dab some of this
what do we want to get into let's get
into some Clementine it's not real heavy
doesn't [ __ ] me up too bad it makes me
functional let's say I'm out of the one
I've already opened that's a freshie
right there got the Clementine
there we go that's one I've been dipping
into you gets me nice and high and gives
me a good buzz but it doesn't [ __ ] me
that order can't function and think
about a podcast where you get all weird
sometimes I get quiet when I take dad
sometimes I ramble when I take dad's
gonna depends on what I'm smoking
apparently right now I'm rambling so
we're getting adapt together I got a
decent sized dab of some Clementine
batter on my pencil dabber here
I have got my hitman hammerhead sidecar
with the yellow label on it I like the
hammerhead perk on the inside honestly
that's why I use it it makes the just
hits well I like to flirt out mouthpiece
a lot of people are haters on hit man
glass but it hits well so I don't even
care it hits man and then of course I
have got the dual layered thermal banger
here heating the [ __ ] out of that and
I've also got my bubble cap Within Reach
so you guys if you were at home if
you're wherever you are if you just
place where you could take a DAB take a
phat dab with me and then if your mom's
around certainly give her a hug heating
this up it's gonna take a couple of
seconds cuz it's the thermal banger
wanna try to go kind of low temp on this
dab not take too long thanks for joining
me for a dab you guys tweet me send me a
tweet let me know what you're dabbing
while you're dabbing with me
that's plenty hot I got my coil
condenser decorated torch here shot as
my friends at elevate glass for keeping
me laced up Storch was a gift from the
beautiful miss Jenny beasts a shout out
for the gift
I'm Melissa snail cool it's a thing
about a dabber a banger you got to heat
it up then you gotta let it cool and get
it just right it's getting there
and I just gotta talk my way through it
don't let it get cold if I hit it too
hot it'll make me cough so here we go I
think this is just about right here we
go take a dad with me you guys take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
my don't let it cool just a little too
much with dates so good
put the cap on as a good dab yep that
thermal banger in the bubble cap that
makes everything alright
I got hash oil all over the email paper
here I got my finger
back into a podcast ladies and gentlemen
thank you for joining me thanks for
tolerating a DAB with me I hope you took
a fat dab of something though if you're
talking funny - I hope your head is
vibrating
let's get into some emails oh I feel
like I'm in a coffin I'm not gonna let
myself cuz I'm a Jedi this email comes
from one of my favorite emailers one of
my favorite listeners this guy
communicates with me quite a bit
this guy's mr. Saint skinny this is a
long email but it's wonderful it goes a
lot like this hey Jeff sorry it's taking
me so long to respond I've been having a
rough time keeping up with every day
lately but things are settling down for
now we got the call the other day from
one of the nurses and they have good
news
mamma Saints new immune system is 100%
engrafted she's doing great
although going a little crazy being
stuck in the house all time all the time
but overall things are good there's that
cough I said I wasn't gonna do sorry I
didn't mean to lie to you
big shot at the Saints Ginny's mom I'm
glad you're doing great you'll be fine
in the house just take care yourself Get
Well listen to a lot of podcasts get
yourself some Netflix he'll be okay keep
going with the email it goes I want to
thank you for the shout out and love
sent to Ma Saint and myself we were
actually on the way home from the Cancer
Center which happens to be in the same
hospital they were coming home from when
you did the first shout out and it was
definitely needed that day the process
has been rough on both of us
but especially mama st. Jude I'm glad I
could give you a shout out at just the
right time it seems like a lot of life
happens just as it's supposed to that
way to continue with the email that says
you asked me about the name Saint skinny
and how I got it here's the answer you
guys I've been cylinder since I started
high school and high school was a point
that I basically only owned black shirts
and black or blue jeans one day we were
playing hacky sack and my buddy [ __ ]
decided to give me the name skinny black
which I didn't know as a character and
hustle and flow I was given the name
because he's skinny and I always wore
black I'm almost immediately it changed
to just skinny a couple years later I
was listening to a song called seen
Jamie and I would replace Jimmy with
skinny whenever it came up in the song
I put seeing skinny is my middle name in
facebook as a joke and it just stuck I
hope all is well with you and yours keep
doing what you do you're a great asset
to the community and doing a great job
breaking the stoner stereotype Saint
skinny it's good to know more about my
friends I'm glad glad I know about that
I'm glad I know that about you sorry
that dad was [ __ ] my brain up right
now and also man thanks for noticing
that I have broken the
stoner stereotype which is not accurate
right now it's I'm hiya [ __ ] I can't
even talk right but most of the time I
do break that stoner stereotype I get
some [ __ ] done I speak well try to be on
time for stuff thanks for noticing that
I'm N I think too noticing I'm an asset
that's that's great for you to say I
appreciate that it makes it all worth
the work that I put into this podcast I
try to do a lot
he anemia email with keep a diary
growers love from sane then he goes on
and says PS whether you knew it or not
that episode in which you read my email
was pretty much a dude grows crew
special three of the emails he read were
from people that are part of the dude
grows crew including myself anyway I'm
gonna go do a fat dad and Mama st. Oh
and hug mama see take it easy bro I
ain't skinny that's a great email man
it's good to hear that mom is doing well
too bad she's stuck in the house but hey
that's [ __ ] awesome that she's doing
well her immune system will boost back
up should be doing good again man thanks
for all the info about yourself I like
knowing stuff about my friends
that's pretty rad why did they call me
Rasta Jeff I guess would be fair
cuz I've got dreadlocks down to my ass
and I listen to reggae and I'm a Rasta
man - my name is Jeff so just Rasta Jeff
was just an easy nickname for me to
acquire a lot of my friends call me
wookie because I'm six five and I have
dreadlocks and kind of a Chewbacca I
prefer not to wear shoes too often and
sometimes I could use a shower so that's
why they call me wookie and then back in
the day my friends used to call me hippy
ah
because I was just a great big hippy I
worked in a place and one of the old
guys asked my best friend why do you
call him hippy and my buddy's response
was because it's better than calling him
up [ __ ] in front of everybody and I
laughed pretty good at that so shout out
to my buddy Rob the dude
Rob the dude it's a good dude I miss
that guy one of my best friends anyway
skinny thanks for the email dude I
appreciate it if you ever have any more
questions or anything else to say I hope
you contact me let's see what else did I
miss anything in here the dude grows cup
man shout at all my friends if the dude
grows cup if you don't know what the
dude grows crew is dude grosses another
podcast about cannabis it's a different
style than my show Scotty real and the
dudes sit around to talk about a
recharge all day so give them a listen
you guys might enjoy the podcast I
listen when I can I can't listen
constantly I listen to so many podcasts
but I do listen to the dude bro show and
I definitely will be at the dude grow
if they throw another event I will go I
may even compete because last time one
of my strains won second place and I
didn't even grow it it was at second or
third it was a tie for it became it I
don't remember sue the second or third
place but one of my strains lemon Jeffry
won an award and I didn't even grow it
so I imagined that if I grew and I
entered it it would [ __ ] win right
that just makes sense all right skinny
thanks for the messages dude I hope mom
as well I hope you were well I take it
fat dab right now and give mama Saint or
mama skinny a hug for me make sure she
hears this dude
make sure she hears this hope you're
doing well mama all right you got
another email this one starts off and
specifically says please don't use my
name you can call me Parliament thanks
and with that being said let's get down
to the brass tacks man if I'm not
mistaken biochar is carbon-based
material that is burned without air I
was looking at the wood chips the wood
oh and wood pellets from my electric
smoker and noticed that they were burned
but not ash is that biochar is it good
to use as an amendment to cocoa can it
be used in a tea I would imagine it
would be great for compost I know that
wood ash contains a lot of potassium but
goodies can be gained from this
by-product or but can goodies be gained
from this byproduct of carnivorous
indulgence business out of the way on to
the pleasantries I would like to say
that it was made aware of your podcast
from the dude grow show your show has
become one of my favorite podcasts and I
never miss an episode
I'd love to throwbackthursday episodes
and the fact that they are super long
don't be afraid to put out long episodes
like 2 or 3 hours
fans will listen then again what the
[ __ ] do I know dude it sounds like you
know a lot so far I'm happy with this
email you've asked a great question
so you spark some thought in my mind in
other people's minds ah you've given me
a compliment and you even mentioned the
dude grow show and told me where you
came from I'm in so far sounds like you
know a [ __ ] lot I agree with
everything you've said so far we're
gonna talk about the biochar biochar
party here in just a minute and dude
thanks for mentioning the throwback
Thursday episodes I'll keep putting
those out I'm gonna get caught up
eventually and that's gonna be weird
then what the hell am I gonna do on
Thursdays but I'm gonna keep going with
the email he says thanks for the
knowledge thanks for the consistency
with your episodes dude that is the most
challenging part the consistency I
promise to put out an episode every
Monday and I've been trying to do every
Thursday and I haven't missed one for
like six months now I've never missed a
Monday show so you're welcome for the
consistency that's the challenge of a
podcaster he goes on and he says I
really look forward to them thanks for
being cool as [ __ ] and since I know
you're already gonna take a fat dab go
ahead and give your mom a hug for me I
will do that and then I like that the
ending to this email he says and the
words of Joey Diaz stay black [ __ ]
man that's the best [ __ ] ending to an
email ever sincerely and then he says
his name and then he ends it with uh I'm
just gonna say Parliament that's what he
said they call him so Parliament thanks
for the email bro um I love the good
question because biochar
I never thought too much about biochar
I've heard of them using biochar a lot
at the warm factory but I have not
thought about too much of it as in a
cocoa amendment until you spark that
thought in my head so let's talk about
biochar for just a second one thing that
you said is that biochar is one of the
main things was that it was made without
oxygen and you were doing that it sounds
like but how are you removing the oxygen
is there a vacuum there is there an
absence of oxygen or is there just
free-flowing oxygen as their passive
oxygen I'm not doubting you or your idea
that there is an oxygen there I'm just
wondering is there oxygen flowing
through there is there some oxygen
but anyway I'm also one of the things
that identifies it as biochar is the
specific temperature it says
temperatures of four to five hundred
degrees produce more char while
temperatures above 700 favor the yield
of liquid and gas component so you'll be
pulling out more liquids and gases at
higher temperatures so it kind of
depends on if what temperature you're
getting into and how much char is
happening and also biochar is really
fine so if you're gonna make the biochar
out of that stuff I would almost start
the char wants and then shred it up real
fine or break it up even smaller make
the pellets even smaller and then reach
are them maybe if you can crush them up
or break them in half or something
because the biochar the smaller it is
the more surface can get charred I'll
see you have more surface area that is
burned and it's got the carbon available
you're making the carbon available it's
that dusty part the part that kind of
sticks to your fingers and makes your
fingers all black and you end up looking
like a coal miner that's the part that
you're kind of looking for I think and
you want to make as much surface area as
you can
so char as much as you can and then it
will work better as an amendment if it
is
and more available one thing I think
about the biochar is they feed it to
worms and the worms pass it and it makes
it smaller and more bioavailable and the
worms also love it so I think make it
smaller burn it again and then feed it
to earthworms red wigglers and stuff
like that and then I think you're
basically making biochar but you're
close already I think you're mostly
correct and I'm just getting my
information from the internet and you're
really close you are making low budget
biochar you're off to a good start but
there are a couple more things that
sounds like you could probably do and I
hope that answered your question my
advice would be like I said char it
crush it again cardigans wear all of it
is charred make sure that every but I'm
not I don't I haven't used your pellet
stove so I don't know how burned it's
getting on the inside or on the outside
of the pellets but make sure it's all
charred make sure it's really fine and
then use some of it and then maybe if
you have the availability feed some of
that to some red wiggler worms and then
use that and then see if you see a
difference in the one the plant without
the biochar the plant with the homemade
biochar and then the plant with the
biochar fed to worms and if you see
differences take notes that's the way
that you really would know if you did it
correctly and if it's biochar it sounds
very similar it really does sound like
you're close and it's probably going to
do the same thing it's going to add that
carbon to it it's gonna help it's gonna
help so I think you're onto the right
track dude thanks for the email thanks
for the compliment about to
throwbackthursday episodes and thanks
for the Joey Diaz quote that means a lot
to me that lets me know that you really
have learned Who I am so thanks for the
email bro if anybody else out there
would like to send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to answer your questions on the
show I love answering listened or
generated content it lets me know that
I'm hitting my target it lets me know
that I'm getting to my audience in a way
that's helping I appreciate it I would
love to hear from you also I would love
it if you stalked me on all of the
social media you can find me on Facebook
it's the girl from your heart podcast
you can find me on twitter at g f YH
podcast and a force of course you can
send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
also if you're into Instagram you can
find me on Instagram it's Irene or
genetics I just hit 14,000 followers on
Instagram I just posted a post that got
over a thousand lights I've never hit a
thousand likes before so I'm at 14,000
followers and I posted a 1,000
like photo so you might want to check me
out i RIE underscore genetics on
Instagram that is my seed company that's
my breeding project I post a lot of
photos from the commercial grower posted
a lot of pictures from my breeding stuff
I post a lot of personal pictures from
my personal grows I think you might
enjoy it
also don't forget about patreon
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
also I've been posting videos to YouTube
by the time you hear this I think about
70 to 75 videos will be posted to
YouTube if you don't want to listen to
the long episodes or if you're not able
to listen to those you can go to youtube
search for the girl from your heart
podcast the first 20 episodes are on the
old agriculture feed if you don't know
about agriculture the show was
originally called agriculture I was kind
of forced to change it that was already
somebody else's business name they work
with colleges and they make
college-level horticultural materials I
didn't want to step on anybody's name so
I changed my name to the girl from your
heart podcast which is much more
appropriate because I grow from my heart
I want you to grow from your heart so
all of the stuff is on YouTube episode 1
through 20 is on the hydro culture
YouTube channel 21 through 72 75 by now
is available on the girl from your heart
podcast YouTube channel I've got more
videos man I just got and post them I've
got to get them up there they were
coming I will get all of them up there
so far I'm recording episode 231 I plan
to get 231 videos up on it the YouTube
channel they will all be there for
everyone to watch and enjoy basically
it's just a picture of myself scrolling
across the screen the whole time but
it's for people that can't listen
through YouTube or through iTunes or
stitcher or however else you listen to a
podcast it's just another option for
people to check out the show alright
I've been rambling for about 36 minutes
you guys I'm going to wrap up the
podcast my throat's doing that thing
where it starts cut now I'm gonna give a
huge shout out to my friend bone Ellis
she was in a conversation with a doctor
who said that strains don't matter when
it came to medical cannabis and she
definitely did her job of standing up
for specific strains and strain names
and she stood up for breeders and she
made me proud and she actually mentioned
me so I owe you a big shout out thanks
for standing up for the breeders
standing up for strains and silly stray
names and specifically for standing up
for me and for cannabis and general bow
your a soldier to to have you on the
team so shout out to bone Ellis thanks
to everybody for listening until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
like I told what I said
steal your face
[Music]
[Applause]
like Steve
[Music]
the track
[Applause]
[Music]
these go
my skin
[Music]
please
[Applause]
[Music]
let's go
[Applause]
[Music]
baby
the bag
in the same
[Music]
No
like I don't
see
Stan
[Music]
and
[Applause]
[Music]
like a stand
please
[Music]
likeness
the track
[Music]
back