yo what a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
and it's Thursday so that means it's
time for another throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast before I get into the block of
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any promotions any contests or any
giveaways those have all expired there
are currently no contest no promotions
no advertising or no giveaways also let
me update all of the social media if you
want to find me on Twitter you can find
me at G f YH podcast on Twitter on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast and if you'd like to
send me an email
it's drove from your heart at
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen I hope
you enjoyed these chunks of old episodes
so here we go the throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 85 of the
girlfriend heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
if you're a cannabis activists or if
you're someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you as always
I need to send a huge thank you shout
out to the mystic roots band for letting
me use the music on the show big thanks
to Kat coupe and the entire mystic roots
crew what's up ladies and gentlemen I
hope everyone's having a great day we're
coming to you it's about 7:10 p.m. so
everyone sitting here taking some fat
dad's at the table let me introduce to
you our super photography expert our dab
master I'm just making sure photography
guide for the day this is my good buddy
Joe to my left how you doing brother
welcome to the show thank you thanks for
coming to my dining room I wanted to
call it sticky knob studios a long time
ago and somebody told me that that just
sounds disgusting
well it's cuz there's hash all over
everything now after taking so many dabs
but ladies and gentleman directly in
front of me also here joining us on
microphone is my good buddy sloppy how
you doing brother
no glad to be here really high some
giggles here in this podcast but it's
gonna be fun since we're talking about
dads this is a good time to give a big
shout out to our friend Bobo blaster Co
this guy calls himself Bobo Blaster :
Instagram he's got a website furniture
there you go it's burnisher dot Big
Cartel calm you can check it out
this dude makes furniture with an email
attached to it bro there's nothing
cooler there's nothing better you can
sit at a coffee table and slop and I
were sittin at the coffee table takin
dabs just chatting it was kind of
amazing
it was lovely beautiful and it's nice
it's beautiful over there it's gorgeous
it is a sexy table dude I really
appreciate you sending me that I
recommend that everybody else checks out
furniture dot Big Cartel
calm it fall on one face are on
Instagram its Bobo blaster Co Bo Bo
blaster Co very sir
very creative very creative Instagram
handle but I meet in this week I'm going
to ask him what he got that from um
let's see before we get too far I get to
dab doubt this podcast is brought to you
by our good friends at hydro indoor
growing supplies I grow indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store at 62 71
Beach Street or check out the beautiful
Pueblo location featuring Jesse and burn
chat at the Jesse and burn the Pueblo
location is at 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
you guys when you're checking out at
high growing or growing supplies let
them know that you listen to the girl
from your heart podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that's a big fat hookup
who doesn't love to save money money is
expensive put some pennies back in your
pocket save those dollars shop with my
good friends at hydro indoor growing
supplies big shout out to hydro if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
podcast send me an email it's a girl
from your heart at hotmail.com I will
get you all of the information that you
need to sponsor the show um I think
that's enough ads you guys let's get
down to business I invited my good buddy
Joe over because we want to learn a
little bit about cannabis photography
Joe I got to give you a compliment you
take really great cannabis pictures well
thank you very much I appreciate that
very very much you probably an expert
before I'm no expert who has had a
camera for a while I like that I like
the modesty there I appreciate that
and I definitely like being corrected on
the show so these are enthusiasts with a
lot of experience here that's what we'll
call not an expert so take everything he
has with the grain of salt you guys I'm
just kidding do I trust you and respect
your opinion so that's why I brought you
here and slop series gonna chime in once
in a while and then we're going to we're
gonna do this episode live you're ready
to have another fat dab session then
we're gonna record an episode featuring
or a good buddy slop over here so let's
jump into the photography with our good
buddy who is almost an expert in my
opinion Joe what we want to do is
improve the listeners photography did I
just say that yeah anyway what we want
to do is improve their photography so I
guess the main thing
that I'll start with is what you guys
need to do is think about why are you
shooting photography what's your point
are you gonna do it for advertising are
you gonna do it for magazine shots or
are you simply just trying to be cool on
social media and get a lot of followers
because that's gonna make a huge
difference in a lot of the equipment
that you need to purchase so that's
pretty much what I came up with and then
I wanted to ask Joe if you could
elaborate on that and then also if he
could help us select a camera for our
purchase and our for our purpose and
possibly that fits our budget does that
make any sense Dee bro
yeah most certainly awesome if you're
doing the social media thing stick with
your phone you your phone is an amazing
device even born some that's ridiculous
as long as you have the proper lighting
that phone will do everything that you
need for the point shoot if you're a
blogger somebody who's taking pictures
of food or friends little videos here
and there even if you're filming YouTube
videos point-and-shoot you can point you
to to $500 600 if you want to really go
crazy on them okay and you can get an
amazing blog worthy Internet worthy
camera all the capabilities that you
need and then if you like you said
advertising and really you really want
nice pictures you can put them on blogs
to certainly no limits but if you must
have the camera quality the top of
camera quality in all aspects that's
definitely the DSLR a digital
single-lens reflex camera nice yeah yeah
that's the way to do it you guys it will
not be a test so you don't have to try
to remember that
yes all right don't really know what it
means but I know that that's what that's
Joe prove the point right there just
think about what you're shooting for if
you're just trying to be on Instagram if
you're going blogging you don't need to
spend a million dollars on all of your
equipment if you're just trying to shoot
some Instagram pictures if you trying to
be a Twitter guy if you're doing
Facebook you can use your phone all of
the new iPhones the Samsung phones my
iPhone 6 takes amazing pictures all the
new phones you can get really quality
pictures and he said
lighting will get into lighting in just
a minute if you guys want to be you know
I've had a magazine shot and I did not
use the super expensive camera I used a
camera for that so it's not all about
the camera a lot of it is about the
settings a lot of it is about the
lighting a lot of it is about learning
where to shoot from and maybe a little
bit of editing but we'll get into that
more so select the camera that fits your
budget get the best camera you can for
your budget when I first bought my
camera I was intimidated
I bought a point-and-shoot camera and I
feel like I almost I didn't waste the
$200 but if I would have put that money
toward my nice DSLR camera in the
beginning I would be further in shooting
I don't be intimidated by a camera with
a lot of settings most of the new DSLRs
I think all of them have an auto setting
and so you can learn through that auto
setting most all new cameras are
extremely user friendly manufacturers
know who they're making cameras for they
know what their audiences even if you've
never used if as long as you're
technology capable as long as you yea be
technology capable by any camera you
want and you will be able to figure it
out if it's not on your own through
experimenting YouTube YouTube definitely
yeah YouTube is always a good resource
just type in this camera and then the
question you have about it and it will
pop up 17 videos and watch a couple of
them and filter out the [ __ ] cuz
every one of those guys is gonna tell
you some weird thing that is unnecessary
so just watch three videos and figure
out get the median there you go alright
so select figure out why you're gonna
shoot it's like the best camera you can
for your purpose if you're gonna go
shooting for Instagram don't buy a
thousand dollar camera don't buy the d30
for Instagram shots unless you can't
afford it you know if you want the best
pictures on Instagram you will have the
best do you want the crispest
the crispiest pictures many times do we
have to say a word to make it a word
around all right so then selected get
the best camera you can you guys and
then learn it and also while you're
shopping there are a couple of
accessories that we talked about this a
little bit before there are definitely
some accessories that we would all
recommend while you're shopping get
yourself a tripod yes if you don't get a
start interrupt no don't get a cheap
tripod like their tripods out there for
20 and 30 dollars which
work but they're plastic and they
they're soft and they're not meant to
last and are not meant to really be
hauled around and that guy stuff and if
you're not gonna haul it around you're
just gonna leave you to one place and
take pictures always buy that twenty or
thirty dollar one but the difference
between a thirty dollar tripod and a $70
tripod is giant it's metal it's very
sturdy it's gonna last forever
it will last as many cameras as you
could buy I ruined my $30 tripod quite
quickly the height adjustment stripped
out so it's not get one height if I want
to move it up I gotta like yank it so
I've got the $70 die next one that they
have it Best Buy dude great investment I
agree the tripod will make your pictures
your photos will be not wobbly you'll be
able to leave the shutter open a little
bit longer because you're not holding it
in no matter how steady you think you
are you're shaking yes and the way
physics works think about like a
flashlight if you turn the flashlight
you make a nice arc with the light
you're doing that with the lens you're
not just wobbling it you're waving the
whole end of the lens because the part
that's shooting is wiggling in a much
yeah that's you're making a cone shape
sorry that's science move on also get
yourself a nice case if you can get a
bag a soft bag or a case or something
for the camera do that because you're
gonna want to carry extra lenses you're
gonna want to carry a lens cleaner you
need a little soft cloth to clean off
the lint especially when shooting
cannabis my lens is freakin sticky all
the time it's gonna clean it off I get
too close to the plants or something and
then just you touch it and then
trichomes all over your lens old cotton
t-shirts no socks
don't use actually a fresh anything you
know don't use like anything soft and I
can tell you what not to use but just
it's really okay don't press too hard to
scratch up the lens and I personally
like to go to the sunglasses store and
get that little rag that they use to
clean your sunglasses real fiber yes of
microfiber that's what it's called they
think that works perfect for Mike
totally alright so don't skimp on the
case either cases backpacks you know a
$70 $100 case you know you're putting a
thousand dollar camera and it may be
true and and a thousand dollar lens you
know what's a hundred dollar case if
first is a $50 case that gets thrown at
the airport or something I don't know
I'm all about initial investment not too
shabby
especially if you're traveling you know
the best way to not get your camera
stolen out of your vehicle when you're
traveling cover it up hang it on your
neck and take pictures with you while
you're running around never know what
the craziest [ __ ] happens when you don't
have your camera with you
you can like almost guarantee you're not
gonna get robbed you're not gonna get
jacked there won't be a catastrophe if
you've got your camera on you that was
great
get yourself a good tripod get yourself
a good case get some lenses now what
kind of lens is for shooting cannabis
photography yeah could you recommend a
few lenses I don't want to give any like
specific lens to get just because
everybody you know I don't want it to be
bad and then you say oh this guy said
that I love that but it's are you trying
to take pictures of trichomes or trying
to take pictures of buds off the plant
on the plant you want to take pictures
of the whole plant different lenses are
gonna do different things you can get
you know shorter focal length plants or
plants shorter focal length lenses for
portraits and that's just really general
you can get all different if there's all
different kinds of lenses it really
depends on what you want to do and each
camera is gonna have different lenses
he's gonna have different we're just
talking about DSLRs right now would that
cuz that's the only thing that lenses
really applied to your lens and you're
buying your lens in your body separate I
mean if you're buying them in a box
together it's set you're getting that
for a reason if you're buying we got the
body that you want because that the body
has all the features that you want and
then the lens because that lens has all
the features that you want it depends on
what you want to do so when it says body
only they're sending me a usable camera
with no lens correct okay that's that's
misleading I did not know anything about
that when I was camera shopping was like
what the hell does that mean body only I
wonder if there were mechanics and
there oh yeah it's misleading is that
like just the plastic or is it yeah no I
know that there you go guys that was a
good piece of advice um but that said
you can certainly get lenses that fit
all applications you can get like the
telephoto lens it's telephoto and
tell'em acro so you like I use just as
the easy lens for all aspects I use it I
think it's it in 18 to 200 it's it's a
huge range it's and that fits anything
that you want you want to take a picture
of a mountain you're good you want to
take a picture of a trichome you're good
yeah there you go this is my go-to lens
right here that's what I use quite often
everything that you needed to do yeah
without getting too specific okay so
guys what I use since Joe approves of my
set up here I'm using the Nikon d3200
and I bought the package that comes with
the case and the two lenses and I
usually use the 55 to 200 lens but when
I want to get in there sometimes it's
hard to maneuver around the grow room if
you can't back up from the plant if
you're up close then I'll switch to the
I'm looking at the right number so I
don't mislead anybody here
it's the 18 to 55 is the one I use when
I can't maneuver around the room - well
if I'm further away I go for this longer
lens if I'm close in tight I use the 18
to 55 I get much better shots with this
55 to 200 lens this is my go to right
here so when we're saying all of this
basically you to take the macro shots on
that 55 to 200 you put it all the way to
200 and on a tripod and you're gonna be
about 1820 inches away from the nug with
your 200 zoomed all the way out into
that nook and that's how you're getting
your macro shots okay in that specific
zoomed all the way out or all the way in
well you're zoomed into what a giant on
the 200 here 200 is extended as far as
it will go
you're set it to 200 so the lens is out
super long and on your viewfinder it's
zoomed
in on your subject okay and then that's
where you find your macros setting and
that lends nice yeah that's so that's
but that's in these types of lenses that
do everything I think I've been off the
mic for so much of this but that's so
those are my mics those are lenses that
do everything if you want to take
pictures of just the trichomes you know
really close-up things going on in your
garden you could take you know awesome
pictures of soil who knows what you'll
find in there you could take pictures of
whole nugs trichomes that's really what
you're looking for you want to get like
a dedicated macro lens because some
things it won't take pictures of
mountains something that won't take
pictures of your family
that's no portraits just little tiny
stuff just little things okay yeah get
the right lens for the right jobs
actually do your researcher look for
something that's gonna shoot in five two
one
that's all about a full full resolution
on big prints essentially okay like if
you have an 8 by 11 picture of a
trichome and it's perfectly in focused
and beautiful
that's because somebody was using like a
5 to 1 lens it would allow you to shoot
that whole frame okay that makes sense I
get it you're zoomed into life like
you're zoomed into real life so
basically people got to know what
they're aiming for and that can lead us
into another part of this we're gonna
kind of skip a little part of the notes
that we made but we'll do that instead
of just shooting at random [ __ ] kind of
plan out your shot also that's a good
thing that's a good point since talking
about leader lens you're gonna have to
know what you're aiming for when you put
this lens on your camera you can't go
put it on your macro lens and then try
to take a picture of the top : you get
your 200 lens out to take pictures at
the top I kind of know what you're
aiming for plan your shot and like think
about like josa if you want to take a
picture of a trichome if you want to
take a picture of some soil think about
it and you'll you'll see
when he walks through the grow room
something will go right here look at
this and when it catches your eye that
means it catches the camera and try to
stand where you were land it got your
eye trying to try to replicate that a
little bit don't uh don't be scared to
take a lot of pictures even the same
thing and then you know they'll be that
one that's just like rice is the one
like if you have the time to you know
take some dabs and look through your
pictures like exactly we're not wasting
film anymore
we're just clicking away on a memory
card we're wasting RAM and we can delete
it all do it all over again tomorrow
so you just plan out your shot choose
the right lens for your shot yeah on
just just to make a correction on that
with the 200 the 55 to 200 when you're
at 200 I don't want anybody to think
that you can take a picture of a
trichome with the 200 it won't work that
way yeah I was gonna think of that you
can take a picture you can take really
close up good shots of nugs on your
plant you could take where you will see
each individual trichome as a dot
sometimes the stalk just depending on
how good the lighting is but don't think
you're gonna get that real super
official macro photography with without
a macro specific lens
I just wrote something down to try not
to forget it we're gonna go into
lighting next because you just hinted on
that but it has one huge hint I can give
you just super quickly get yourself
either a method seven lens or you can
just put the sunglasses right over your
camera if you're ghetto you can do that
[Music]
method seven makes a filter that cuts
out the hid the high intensity discharge
light it cuts that color out and you can
see the natural color of your plants so
if you're not able to take the plants
out of the room the method seven lens is
a good way to go so let's work into
lighting a little bit how should we be
lighting our cannabis plants when we're
taking pictures ideally not around HBS
lights not even t5 lights that's not
true light I mean it's super white it
looks good but it's not the true
representation of your plant okay
it puts a little bit of a blue to it
I've noticed certainly it could put any
hue on it just depending on the other
lights in the room or number a factor is
expecting from yeah okay
so you're lighting what's easiest you
know get in a room with really good
outside lighting or you know a whole
bunch of CFLs they're pretty pretty flat
white easy to color balance off of your
camera if you want to get into your
settings and do that but that's ideal if
you don't have that you have to stay in
your girl room you know turn the HPS
lights off and just turn your overhead
light on and use a flash okay
a flash will overcome a lot is the the
stock flash that came on most of our DSL
camera is going to be DSLR cameras is
that gonna be good enough or should we
get like a ring like a like an
aftermarket flash if you can afford an
aftermarket flash it is going to be a
lot far superior look through the one
built in but that's one that's built in
is not too shabby either it will
definitely get the job done for most
applications okay when you're getting an
aftermarket flash you should really know
why you're about to spend one hundred
and sixty dollars on a flash like
there's reasons for it I don't want to
tell you what they are because that's
cheating figure out the reason but we'll
get to some reasons later so more
lighting is usually the key right more
light more lighting the better so I mean
if you can Sun lights the most ideal but
I know everybody can't take their plants
outside my favorite meme is the old lady
looking out the window and it says
there's my neighbor taking pictures of
his bongs in the sunlight again all the
time I do because I follow usually pot
plants glass and pit bulls as my
Instagram feed so I wrote down settings
what kind of settings should I throw my
is it cool to just walk in there on auto
auto firing or absolutely there's
nothing wrong with that you'll get
pictures it'll be it'll be useful they
might not be the best but there
certainly will be usable be compared to
if you just throw it in manual without
knowing anything you know it'll prolly
just be black but settings you you when
you don't have ideal I'd say throw it in
auto from the most
there's no there's no reason to not use
auto if you have great lighting Auto is
the best setting just because it's
continually correct it will just make
everything easy and pretty and you can
focus on taking the pictures especially
if you're not getting paid like you
don't need to be 1,000% perfect on
everything very true if they're just for
your Instagram feed right you don't need
to be all critical about of course if
you want to be critical more power to
you yeah that's part of the art so
settings are gonna be for what if you
want to take pictures in the dark just
using flash randomly to overcome the HBS
or when the HBS's are on and you have to
change the setting in your camera to
filter out that on the fly don't be
afraid to change settings you guys it's
something you're gonna have to learn to
do with the camera it's something I've
just recently accepted is it every shot
I may have to change a setting to photos
I thought I could just go in there and
put it on you know put the after setting
here to the ISO to here put the white
balance here just go there and shoot
from every angle and it'd be legit but
you want to shoot from you want to take
all the pictures you want to take from
thee without moving
basically yeah standard one spot take
all the pictures you want to take and
move to the next spot take all the
pictures you want to take and do it
systematically okay I mean tell anybody
what to do no but that's what especially
when you're going through your pictures
and everything is grouped I mean you're
gonna be sitting down standing up
leaning over leaning backwards in one
spot without moving too much so you
really get a good feel of what that
angle is bringing to the table yeah and
don't be afraid to take weird angles you
guys some of the best shots are really
weird angles hanging off of a ladder
upside down backwards that's right good
[ __ ] comes out of there alright so we
talked about settings a little bit we
got lighting we got lint selection
sloppy brought up a great point earlier
slop asked me what is acceptable editing
for cannabis photography and Joe had a
great answer I'll let you give that
answer it just don't don't edit
maliciously yes by that Joe means like
myself I'm a seed breeder right I own a
company I try to sell seeds if I were to
edit the photos I take of the plants
that come from my seeds I feel like you
would be misleading I added out the
background I added out people
I added out other plants if there's
another plant next to it I'll go ahead
and blur that one but I don't edit the
subject at all most of the time like 99%
of my Instagram and my website are all
unedited and if they are edited you can
tell cuz it's black and white or it's
something awkward but if you're in there
making the pistils pink and you're
trying to sell a pack of seeds and those
pistols weren't pink that's what we'll
call malicious editing don't do that
[ __ ] but if you're doing it for art
like look at this beautiful cannabis
plant that's cool but if you're trying
to take credit for growing this
beautiful play with the colors and there
are certain instances when you have to
edit like if you weren't you know you're
not always in the best condition for
pictures right you don't always have the
best opportunity to take a picture
sometimes you just have to snap snap
snap snap you got to come back to some
Photoshop and clean it up yep which is
acceptable at that point it just depends
on what you're doing with it yeah I
agree
all right so now that you've learned how
to select a camera you've got all your
accessories you figured out what kind of
lenses you're gonna use you got a cool
light to play with
you've been tweaking on the camera
settings you learned how to do some
editing I just gotta get there in a grow
room or whatever your plants are and
just take a shitload of pictures you
guys just take pictures change the
settings play with the settings don't be
afraid like I said earlier don't be
afraid to get out of auto if you get out
of auto mode I like to take pictures in
Auto and then take a note on where what
Otto did Otto will say everything Otto
put the ISO at this or the white balance
or the shutter speed or the aperture
setting was here I ought oh we'll take a
note for you in the photo if you save it
right and then look at that no and then
write that down and then if you've got a
really killer picture try to duplicate
that setting in that environment then
remember like when I was in this setting
flat this environment last time I threw
on this setting and I took really killer
pictures and then you'll start making
mental notes of it you'll just it'll
start coming naturally to you
that's really nifty that's
if the shoes on the camera if you saw if
you see if you've got a decent camera a
good expensive camera it'll show you
what the settings were when you take it
and unfortunately a lot of those cameras
are also putting GPS locations in there
so you have to go turn that setting off
in your camera that's a good tip guys is
the future don't want that so then go
take pictures you guys and then just
start planning out better shots just
start shooting more and then you'll
learn how to set it you'll learn how to
get to a better setting you'll learn how
to plan out your shot frame your shot
and then you'll learn more how to edit
them and then I think that'll put you on
the way to making amazing photography
and then you can have seventeen to
twenty five to fifty five thousand
followers on Instagram and you can write
in the club yeah take notes when you do
it there you go slap how many Instagram
followers do you have over there all
right I feel like I have covered all of
the notes that I have written down I see
that Joe's got a little what do you call
it bullet point thing over there
something yeah yeah the only thing
really that I would want to say is use
the Internet it's an amazing resource
for everything you know anything that
you want to learn about anything
especially photography is out there
there's a lot of people who have blogs
and YouTube channels I like a guy that
calls himself fro grows I think okay
he's got a YouTube channel on
photography a lot of photographers are
kind of stale to watch because they're
good at photography and not personal
presentation yeah but frog Rose is
definitely educational absolutely that's
all I'm saying is find somebody that you
can watch and just watch them work you
can learn a lot from them yeah you can
it's such a crash course sometimes on
YouTube they show you exactly what you
want to see all right it's not you got
anything to say over there bro you look
blaze yeah don't be scared to use your
imagination and just get in the grow
room and
and get down on one knee or look at it
from a weird angle take pictures from
inside the plant like really get in
there the possibilities for pictures are
endless like do it your imagination is
the only limit yeah you're an
imagination is key guys I think we've
got a great podcast here we should start
wrapping this up while we're ahead right
surely all right all right you guys
we're gonna be back in a couple of days
we're gonna do another episode with
sloppy and then I've got a couple other
things planned out so I'm gonna wrap up
the show take some dabs I want to thank
you guys for joining me I don't forget
to check out our sponsors hydro indoor
growing supplies if you are interested
in sponsoring the podcast send me an
email is perfectly heart of hotmail.com
you guys now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart podcast
give me a five star rating please come
on you know I'm not gonna beg for
anything click reviews - there you go
your podcast app there you go and then
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show I will read your
comment on a future episode if you say
that the show is awesome I will read it
if you tell me that the show is terrible
I will read it I promise you no matter
what almost no matter what you write
iTunes will filter out any crazy [ __ ] so
you'd think so we'll see what happens
make sure you follow me on all the
social media sites you guys I'm on
Facebook it's grow from a heart I'm on
Instagram under I read genetics I'm on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast you guys
I'm so addicted to periscope I think
everybody in this room is addicted to
periscope periscope is an app for your
iPhone or your Android device I've been
talking about it quite heavily I'm gonna
have to take the needle out at some
point
it's once or twice a day and just ramble
on about random [ __ ] that's happening in
my life I give words of wisdom and I
also just talk about growing plants it's
pretty fun do I slay the trophies I got
my troll poof's troll proof panties on
it's good
I better not say all that because I just
challenged people to leave comments and
the show is available on iTunes the show
is available on stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
I don't forget we added that donation
button to the podcast page I'm not
trying to beg for anything but if you
feel like the show is worth a few bucks
you go to my website I region etics
Colorado com click on the girl from a
heart podcast tab on the top right
there's a donation button that goes to
my PayPal account
I'm never gonna charge you guys for the
podcast the show is always gonna be free
right now I'm trying to buy a zoom h6 so
that I could take the podcast on the
road go do more recording with the
trippy boys the turbek screw with hunt
I'll take the show to more events we'll
do some more [ __ ] if I have a mobile
device that I can rely on it'll be
awesome so if you want to contribute I
would give you a big shout-out on the
show make sure you follow me on all the
social media already begged for all that
you guys all want to thank my guests for
joining me
awesome show you guys I really
appreciate it that was a lot of fun it
was a lot of fun thanks for having us oh
man guys we back we're gonna record some
more big shout out to my ninja Spence
he's got the coolest tattoo I've ever
seen he's got a tattoo of his dog Nani
on the back of his arm the sweetest dog
and the sweetest tattoos a shadow twin
ninjas spins thanks again for listening
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
all the time
in the bush
[Music]
you know what's up cannabis community
it's time for episode number 86 of the
girl free heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you joining
me as always I need to give a huge thank
you shout out to the mystic roots band
that's whose music is way too light of
my headphones turn that down a little
bit big shout out to Kat coot and the
entire mystic roots crew make sure you
check out the mystic roots band and stay
positive sound you guys I'm joined once
again by my good friends Joe welcome
back brother Joe thanks you joining me
oh it's pleasure Jeff the sarcastic tone
in your voice is beautiful my friend
thank you joining me once again also
sitting across the table from me is my
tattooed and studly friend just
listening to learn about cannabis and
get a little bit of insight into our
world here in Colorado I appreciate you
for joining us so uh I'm gonna read a
quick ad because of course we got to pay
for one sponsor here it goes like this
this podcast is brought to you by my
good friends at Highgrove indoor growing
supplies high-growth indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store 62 71
beach street or check out the pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out
hydro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
check out you guys when you're at hydro
nerve drug supplies make sure you
mentioned that you listen to the girl
from your heart podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that will save you a lot
of money money is good money is
expensive you can't buy more money the
only way you can get more money is to
bust your ass all the money you save is
a good damn thing right so go shop with
my good friends at high grilling or
drawing supplies make sure you give a
big high-five to burn tell everybody
there that rasta Jeff sent you
all right if you guys are interested in
sponsoring the show send me an e-mail
I'll get you all the information that
you need I have to grow from your heart
at hotmail.com that's enough for the
technical ads and all that stuff ladies
and gentlemen the reason we have
gathered here today I wanted to talk to
my buddy sloppy he was talking about
wanting to be on the podcast knows like
well what's up bro what do you want to
talk about and he's like I want to talk
about my life-changing transition from
ah I'm gonna kind of summarize her slops
kind of uh slet slops a buff dude he's
got some muscles on him he's tatted up
he looks like you could be the guy in
Grand Theft Auto kind of I was gonna
talk about that too people would look at
me and just assume I'm just an [ __ ]
like I hold the door for people in there
like we're not gonna get too deep into
it but sloppy does have a history and
sloppy's move to Colorado and I've heard
a lot about slop I know about slops past
I know where he's come from and I tell
you the truth men since I've known you
you've been nothing but a respectful
respectable [ __ ] generous honest dude
thank you oh for sure man fist bump
across the table here let me know we'll
get it going slide the dabs over here
right so yeah telling everybody how much
of a criminal you are and how you would
never assume that I had any kind of
besides just stereotyping like tattoos
hey we can't be seen right now I get
comfortable but yeah besides
stereotyping I just from appearance the
way that I present myself you you
wouldn't really assume that I had any
past experience with organizations or
just criminal activity at all but uh man
the main thing I want to talk about is
just
really like how much has changed being
able to smoke bud freely and grow but in
the stress reliever that comes with it
uh I mean I started smoking weed back in
fifth grade I don't know the age that
you are in fifth grade I have been yeah
I wouldn't you were probably 14 um I
went to a minority school I am NOT a
minority so I was integrated into a
minority school and put in the paper and
stuff and it was 5th grade through 12th
grade in one school and I used to walk
home with all the older kids I won't say
any names but shout out to who you are
and you know the neighborhood was right
behind the school so we would walk home
and they always smoked every day and
then one day they were just like do you
want to smoke too and I didn't even know
it was bad I've seen other people smoke
cigarettes I don't really know the
difference between what people are
smoking and I remember that day we
smoked a blunt we went and sat in their
shed and played Sega Genesis for like
two hours until my mom got off work and
they never brought up anything being
wrong until right when my mom was gonna
get there and they looked at me and said
tell her you have a headache and go to
your room don't eat anything and then
that was the daily routine after that
forever but I've always had to hide
smoking weed and and all of that own I
have a paraphernalia charge for a roach
literally just a roach in North Carolina
that's where I'm from North Carolina
they're [ __ ] like they don't care
they they came to a house they were
serving a warrant they smelled marijuana
came in the house they I was there's
like
I was the only white person there and
they kept there was like two bombs in
the house and the police came up to me
and they're like oh these must be yours
because you're white and I'm a smartass
so I looked at them was like actually I
smoke blunts instead of just being like
I don't smoke cuz you know I'm an
[ __ ] uh
so they walked over to the ashtray
grabbed a roach dropped in front of me
and said paraphernalia and it is still
to this day on my record was that a
felony or a misdemeanor misdemeanor okay
I hate that there's only two levels of
charges like misdemeanor felony because
felonies are in there with like rapists
and murderers that's that's messed up
like in North Carolina you can get a
felony I think they changed it now but
when I was growing up anything over 1/2
ounce of marijuana was a felony so I
don't need that but now I think you can
have an ounce and a half which still
isn't [ __ ] like you could have a pound
of hurt anybody it's all about what
you're doing
um but marijuana really gave me an out
from where I was before I was in
Colorado I was in a camper that was like
10 by 10 with no insulation it had nails
coming through the roof and I literally
ran an extension cord from the camper to
somebody's well because you know what
the well they had that for like lights
and stuff and I had my Mac computer in
there and I just made music and and
smoke weed and did mushrooms and stuff
so it's a good life it was it was
alright but it was it was it was shitty
you know and then one day a good friend
of mine Spencer from Garden whedon a big
shout out to all of them Mattia my
everybody really uh but he just called
or like we were talking on Facebook at
first and then he called me he was like
are you really sleeping outside and ah
yeah I mean is that really outside but
yeah kinda he's like well would you
rather just come here and grow weed and
it was really an impulse decision like
everybody thought I was bullshitting I
was like in two weeks
I'm how like I'm going to Colorado how I
heard it - yeah it was like two weeks
gonna take the room downstairs
alright you know and I did take that
room and I slept right next to that oven
forever and it is like chilled out boom
ya know uh I did I just told everybody I
was leaving nobody believed me - we came
and I was gone and I don't miss it at
all it's been it's been amazing here
just there's so many people with the
same line stay and positive energies and
just trying to help each other and
progress in life I feel like that's big
people don't like progressing I'm right
some people are stuck and want to be
okay with where they are yeah in content
that's why I got this group of people
here at this table because we're all
people that are all about moving each
other and ourselves forward a little bit
can't ever be comfortable no no as soon
as you're comfortable that's when you
start [ __ ] up stagnation yeah if you
want to be ahead you got to keep moving
right yeah if you're if life is super
duper easy and you do the same thing
every day and not much changes and
you're unhappy about it
the only one thing to do that's right
yep make the progression take the next
steps like if you're already stuck and
frustrated what are you gonna do make
yourself more stuck and frustrated like
a good friend Joey Diaz would say grow
some [ __ ] balls got some time yes yes
he would say don't be scared yeah all
right shlop so you were moving in a
trailer and big shot at the garden of
Weeden because you know what if spin
Sandman he would not have encouraged you
to move out here I wouldn't ever met you
so much respect to that whole crew
there's some of my favorite people right
now yeah for sure
beautiful Bunch only showed me extreme
love situations people that they've
introduced to me have been totally cool
all right so you came out here and now
you're you live Oh Spence for a little
while and you start learning how to grow
yes it was um like I can remember so
vividly the first time that garden of
Weeden oh I could remember the first
time I took official dab I got off I got
off the plane and when she pulled the
ring in the torch out man he pulled the
ring in the torch out I looked at
earlier
[Music]
no it's weed and then I took a DAB and I
literally just laid my face on the
window and just stared so you're saying
I've been in the car when you got your
first dab yes you were off the plane
within three seconds of being in the car
yes but I can I can I can totally
remember the first time that they were
like the lights cut on and they were
like brought me into the garden it was
I would like to say it was all white
widow and to blue dream plants in there
and all you could smell was the blue
dream it was that is correct amazing yes
I remember the feeling like in my body
of like overwhelming sensations that
like I honestly thought that I would
never experience something like that
without going to another country because
it's crazy it's just plants but back in
North Carolina if you have that mini
plate you are they think they like coma
swat4 andi Taisen and shooting like this
plan is in a spongy and kill the first
thing they would shoot your dog I know
this sounds crazy but if they shoot my
dog in front of me it's going down you
know and I I hate the judgment on pit
bulls like how you can't bring him to
Denver and stuff that's like yeah one of
the sweetest dogs I know is a pit bull
and she will climb up into your lap and
let you pet her like a kitty yeah and
she's precious and she's a pit bull her
boyfriend / brother because I'm not sure
what the relationship is there I've seen
a little bit of both that dude is also
one he's a dumbass but he's one of the
sweetest dogs ever it is made of bricks
but he's still one of the coolest dogs
dogs children you can raise them to be
good but your questions man I was like
hearing about how you moved here and
then you started growing weed you saw
some white widow and some blue dream
mind did you get to trim that uh-oh my
first trim I remember uh everybody was
all Oh like bite not wanting to trim
acting like he was about to be there's
like cards like [ __ ] awesome you know
this is the greatest thing ever
and now you know I've trimmed like 100
or so more plants and I'm like [ __ ]
trimming I can totally remember the
first time doing it and I love if I have
company from out of town coming trying
to get them into a harvest and just get
them involved in anyway because like I
said like a lot of people on in any
legal states in general just think that
like this is impossible
oh yeah it's my totally do we can
legalize cannabis nationwide we can all
be grown a little bit of ganja in our
house excuse me not have to go to the
street corner and have to [ __ ] waste
money on canvas not have to worry or
wonder we were all talking about earlier
how we all love that we grow the weed in
the group like we you bring your herb
and I'm not afraid to smoke Joe's err
and sloppy it wasn't always like that I
used to smoke smoking that sexy maxi
brick for sure 500 a pound and [ __ ] with
Spence and Matty they taught you how to
trim is that what pretty much
springboarded you into growing huh it
was really it was really just I needed
something to have that I could be proud
of and look forward to and involve
myself in and keep my mind functioning
and have goals and objectives with it
and uh you know has somebody that smokes
growing has always been a dream like I
wish I could try to do this and see what
happens so as soon as a dream is
presented you have to take it if you
don't take it you're lame cannabis is
his anti-crime
yes and I remember yo it is it is
cannabis helps me in so many ways
without cannabis I don't know if I would
have and failure without cannabis and
failure I don't think I would be the
person that I am today what's been your
biggest failure at growing cannabis my
[ __ ] might man like not thoroughly
checking clones from from people and
stuff like that and then not being on
top of sprays and then just mites being
a persistent little [ __ ] yeah well you
know no it's beautiful in there right
now um I can remember my first harvest
my first harvest honestly blew my mind I
had very very you know very good first
grow yeah first time I've ever grown
anything and I black tarry camp
shout-out to Irene uh that's it was
beautiful dark purple and stinky Yeti
the Yeti was so dense to Jesse for his
final my Yeti yeah for sure
I had train wreck that just smelled so
potent and then sour patch coach which
was I mean it's just it smoked the salt
pepper ketchup yes Saul speaking uh
that's funny I was with him once and uh
we were doing clones and I said spk no
there I was like yo it's just it's so
beautiful here if you smoke and you want
to be somewhere where you're accepted
and you have events that you can go to
and like you don't have to go out of the
country anymore you you could come here
or really you could just start doing
stuff to make it legal where you are
that's what I keep telling people to do
yeah yeah so you don't have to move
stand up for your state I mean it's not
gonna happen everywhere but it could
there's already an activist group in
your state making strides find them yes
whatever state you are in
fine fine then trying to normal just
start in the basic easiest place it
might give us a nice lesson a few
episodes back it's titled getting
involved if you guys want
how to get involved with some sort of
cannabis movement definitely check out
that and then also just contact your
local normal n ORM L the National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws contact them they'll tell you how
to get started in teaming up with locals
in your area how to change the rules and
do stuff like that so slop is here now
though he's here so he's gotten away
from his nefarious life is enough area
sacked ivities he's put some people
behind him changed himself up and no
dude I see you doing well bro yeah get
yourself a normal day job you're doing
[ __ ] business what else do you do when
you're not at work and when you're not
in the garden I make music that's one of
the main things I do I really like
rapping I paint I love I'm fairly new at
it I'm not great one already yeah yeah
that was pretty cool Big Ups to who
bought that it was like Dan dangles for
20 I think I nice yeah for sure Big Ups
to him but I just like if I could give
anybody advice it'd be uh do stuff that
you enjoy doing and do it as much as you
can
I mean I tried to go in the garden as
much as I can making music I have a
regular garden like my broccolis are
looking amazing right now a garden in
the front of your house yes [ __ ]
great what if you catch people in the in
the front of your house there's picking
stuff I was like if they need it that
bad right can I steal my zucchini you
know just came to my cucumbers like what
yeah just do what you want to do and do
the most of it like for sure there you
go and be nice to other people there's a
lot of conceited people in this world
that just don't even notice other
individuals in their life like how do
you go somewhere public and not
acknowledge that you're gonna be around
other people
just don't get it I like slops way of
thinking to drop some random knowledge
on Excel oh man I call people out
sometimes and like the other day this
lady shoutout to the lady just pushed
her cart right in the entrance door of
Walmart and just left it there and I was
like yo you could push it at two feet
that way and she tried to keep walking I
was like yo you lazy [ __ ] and you try
to say the use is bad like put your card
up you just blocked everybody from
walking because you get like you're the
only person at Walmart see that's why
like cannabis I can go home and smoke
and forget about that sounds like
something I would have ranted about on
periscope
shoutout to ya yo everybody jump on
periscope and make it a daily thing like
oh I'm sloppy 9 1 9 periscope and all
all social media is the same but parent
you know the other day I was chilling
with some kids in Tokyo and they were
skateboarding and stuff it is really
cool to see like uh real perspectives of
other places and the way that they
interact and just all kinds of stuff I
really enjoy periscope it's it's it's a
know it's the best social everything app
out at the moment like watching or
broadcasting more I would say watching
just because I like other countries I
like seeing what's up in China and China
is one of the best kids that you're an
American they'll be cool to be talking
in a Russian accent
and Russian and they'll see something
that you're American like or America do
you we kill you and then they just go
right back to their Russian and you're
like oh shoot Brazil is super nice yes
bye as well
and I'm trying to be a dick about it but
the United Arab Emirates does not like
white people when we go on periscope at
least once a day I jump on and do a
quick like sometimes you never know with
me it could turn into an hour and a half
right so you got people watching and
they're talking to me it could be yeah I
get podcast information like people ask
me questions I'm like oh yeah I'm gonna
write that down listen to the podcast
I'll tell you that on the next show so I
get stuff like that and then I've
actually done a live show with
everything on periscope so hopefully
I'll do that in the future I only did it
I didn't announce it because I wanted to
do like a practice run everybody so next
time all like yeah I did a because I
don't want anyone to think there's a
real day right oh yeah and if you're
gonna join periscope and just be a
[ __ ] creeper just let the trolls
alright you guys we can go like 25
minutes sloppy what's next for you bro
you're here you're in Colorado you got
your feet on the ground you got some
[ __ ] set up you seem to be doing pretty
good for yourself you said it yourself
quit moving or if you quit moving you'll
get stagnant so what's next I'm really
gonna start trying to really step my
garden up and try to grow some amazing
weed I want to bring weed to my friends
that they can look at and be like dang
you know I'm saying
I'm also trying to move my family out
here I'm a big family man Mama's here
Saturday
your nephews cute as [ __ ] if I wanna get
the fam out here but honestly honestly
if you really want to know what's next
for me I'm trying to I'm trying to get
out of the country within the next like
ten years I want to be exploring places
I'd like to check out other places but
uh but I would never go somewhere that
that cannabis is frowned upon we get ran
over by a camel in two minutes like they
drive tanks and Humvees and shift on the
street and may box and MacLaren's
[Music]
definitely what's next is just
self-improvement nice trying to grow as
a person improve as the self get the
family out here you're gonna take off
entries see I say that be saying that
forever it may never happen it would
have to be the same as moving to
Colorado and impulse do it now a thing I
would just like to go yeah I want to
travel all over the place to eventually
cannabis will take me all over the world
there's a lot of things coming over here
what's a worldwide podcast you know I'll
throw a [ __ ] book bag on and do it we
grow a wave of the future I want for the
car but I foresee a lot of armed birds
you know and and the thing with the car
is you could have the quick D attachment
so it just looks like a breathalyzer
in the car the car the [ __ ] in the
car because I got pulled over you know I
got off my car so the beauty of Colorado
alcoholic
[Music]
Oh to do that kind of [ __ ] if you got a
deal with cops just know your rights but
keep your mouth shut
let's don't try to be assertive to the
police just do yeah seriously keep in
mind they got a gun they're afraid of
you I don't know who you are oh they
know who I am
we've been close to a half-hour
he hasn't got anything funny want to
ramble about here at the end of the show
we've been kind of rambling anyway but
they think you want to wrap up with slop
since its kind of kind of a sloppy nine
one nine to show the staff slop tart
slap up a lot of dabs a lot of apps well
I once I Twitter like how many ways can
you say sloppy and I literally got like
70 something responses oh nice the
slapping aider and she's like nah I just
really appreciate you it yo this is this
is awesome bro I appreciate you being
here
I'm sure man you're great
you know I know I know it's a man in the
room with Irish yeah yeah yeah I look
forward to more if it happens aw dude
we'll do this again you guys are good
Joe how about yourself man anything -
any words of wisdom for the end of the
podcast nothing too much else so I gotta
read a commercial or like some closing
[ __ ] and then I'm gonna try to get Joe
to do a little bit of beatboxing and
then maybe we can get slapped and I
never gave slop credit you guys remember
that in the garden of Weeden getting
weeded song that was my homie sloppy we
played that on the podcast a couple of
times
sure thanks for coming thanks for doing
that before I ask you guys to beatbox
huge thanks to both you guys come into
taking an hour out of your day welcome
back people will have questions for both
of you so we'll get answers
[Music]
Joe's rappin slops gonna freestyle over
to happen whatever you guys are ready
all right you guys to another episode
I'll be back I'm not sure when I'm gonna
post another episode of probably be
Monday morning don't forget about our
sponsor hydro indoor growing supplies if
you were interested in sponsoring the
podcast we got a product you'd like me
to review send me an email it's grossly
hard a hotmail.com I have a lot of fun
reviewing products I told you guys about
the torch list email that I tried it was
super fresh let me review your product
we'll talk all about it not the show's
over you guys go to iTunes search for
the girl from a heart podcast find the
review section to give me a five star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think about the show
and I will read your comment on a future
episode you guys behave yourselves don't
type in crazy [ __ ] just to get me to
read it if you got something to say all
the social media stuff email me at
script me hard at hotmail.com but I
would love it if you checked me out on
Facebook Instagram Twitter or periscope
YouTube whatever else you can think of
just just check it out I love all the
interaction whichever one you do follow
me there don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher in every
single episode is archived on I read
genetics Colorado calm you guys you know
all about the donation button by now
right go to the website go to the
podcast tab hit the donation' button
if you feel like the show is worth a
couple of bucks I feel like my time my
energy was worth a few bucks throw in a
few bucks I'm seriously trying to work
up to a zoom h6 so that we could take
the podcast a few more places I would
love to get that here before the next
couple of months anyway if you want to
make a contribution just go to the
website throw a few bucks at the Pay Pal
account I'm not begging for a lot if you
got $5.00 if you got $10 that would work
if you want to add some zeros on to the
end of that I am not going to complain
it would be much appreciated I feel like
I'm begging now so I'm gonna move on
with this part thanks to my guests once
again for coming out big shout out to my
ninja Spence thanks again for listening
you guys until next time take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 87 the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
if you're a new smoker or a hardcore
gabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host they probably Ross - Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always I
want to send a huge thank you shout out
to the mystic roots band to letting me
use their music on the show this podcast
is brought to you by my good friends at
hydro indoor growing supplies Tigerland
or growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or check out the
Pueblo location on 618 East 4th Street
pricey and a great selection of indoor
grow supplies you guys you can get your
favorite nutrients at high growing or
growing supplies a gross nor ran by
folks who grow and check it out hydro is
running a special for the podcast
listeners when you check out a high
growing or growing supplies tell them
you listen to the growth from your heart
a podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase that'll save you a lot of money
that's the same discount hook you up
make sure you support hydro indoor
growing supplies in Denver and Pueblo
Colorado much respect to hydro if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
podcast you can send me an email let's
go from your heart at hotmail.com and I
will get you all of the information that
you do need all right guys I want to
give a huge shout out to my friend Fred
Garvin I'm gonna turn this music down
just a little more I don't give you a
huge shout out to Fred Garvin I posted
something to Facebook and Fred politely
commented saying hey Jeff you've been
doing a great job but you've kind of
strayed away from the grow lessons and
he asked for more grow lessons Fred I
can't agree with you more
I have strayed away from the girl
lessons that I've tried to provide you
there's been so much great news I don't
know that all the news has been great
but there's been so much important
that I felt like it's been my job to
bring that news to the cannabis world so
you're right I have gotten a little bit
away from the grow lessons and I got a
lot into the news but you know what
we're gonna get back in the grow lessons
I've got part of this will be a little
bit about grow lessons and then the next
episode is going to be about pH which is
all about growing so Fred you're totally
correct and I will fix that we'll get
back to the grow lessons my friend but
before we get that far I know I just
said we're gonna get back in a girl
lessons and get away from the news but
I've already had this episode plan so
you're gonna have to bear with me
because there's a very important news
article that I want to read to you I'm
thumbing through my computer trying to
find it now to tell you the truth there
we go all right we're gonna get right to
it this news article comes from the
cannabis I found this very important
since I have recently taken over as the
lead grower at the spot dispensary in
Pueblo West Colorado I'm running a large
facility things like this really stand
out to me so let's get right to the
article you guys business from the
cannabis and it was written by Kristen
Wyatt of The Associated Press the
headline is unknowns abound in pesticide
use for growing pot then the sub
headline says there is no federal agency
that will recognize this as a legitimate
crop pest management information
regarding this crop devolves to internet
chats and hearsay says Whitney Crenshaw
a Colorado State University entomologist
and pesticide expert so obviously this
is going to be about pesticides and bugs
and cannabis plants so the article goes
like this microscopic bugs and mildew
can destroy a marijuana operation faster
than any police raise and because the
crop has been illegal for so long either
growers nor scientists have any reliable
research to help fight the infestation
the number one obstacle can be bugs it
is hard as hell to get rid of bugs in a
grow room if you're not experienced and
if you don't know what you're doing so
we'll keep going it says as legal
marijuana moves from basements and
backwoods to warehouses and commercial
fields the mold and spider mites that
once ruined only a few plants at a time
can now quickly create a multi-million
dollar crisis for growers some returning
to industrial-strength chemicals raising
concerns about safety they see
multi-million dollar crisis for growers
they are not kidding you guys the
facility that we are that I am
that I am helping them finish build we
have four flower grooms and one of those
rooms has 26
kavita lights hanging in there our
projections are almost anybody's goal if
you're drawing with a Kavita your goal
is 2 pounds per light so that's 52
projected pounds of cannabis coming out
of that room I can't really tell you
what the going rate is for a pound of
cannabis in Colorado right now at a
retail center or being sold from retail
to retail center but that is quite an
investment if I were to [ __ ] up 52
pounds of weed that would really cost us
quite a bit of money we would not make
money that's a bummer the first place
you can't pay the bills then your short
money then you don't have product on the
shelf it would cause a lot of problems
obviously you can see how 152 pounds
artist it really caused a lot of
problems and then you've got all the
wasted time and the wasted plants
because the plants cost money all the
wasted nutrients all the wasted
electricity it could really add up
quickly so I'm going to continue the
article here where was I herbicides and
insecticides are regulated by the
federal government which still regards
almost all marijuana as an illicit crop
so there's no roadmap to help pop
farmers chemists and horticulturalists
can't offer much assistance either
they sometimes disagree about how to
combat the problem largely because the
plant is used in many different ways
smoke eaten and sometimes rubbed into
the skin we have an industry that's been
illegal for so many years that there's
no research there's no guidelines
there's nothing said Frank Conrad live
director of Colorado green lab a pod
testing lab in Denver
in states that regulate marijuana
officials are just starting to draft
rules governing safe levels of chemicals
so far there have been no reports on any
human illness traced to chemicals used
on marijuana but worries due for cysts
the city of Denver the spring quarantine
tens of thousands of marijuana plants at
11 growing facilities after health
inspectors suspected use of unauthorized
pesticides some of the plants were later
released after tests revealed the pot
was safe but two producers voluntarily
destroyed their plants actually there
was about 600
of cannabis voluntarily destroyed
because of illegal pesticides the
article says businesses still have at
least some plants in quarantine the
article goes on to say in Oregon a June
investigation by The Oregonian newspaper
found pesticides in excess of legal
limits on produce on products ranging
from marijuana buds too concentrated
marijuana oils other pesticides are
detected on the marijuana are not
regulated by Oregon's marijuana rules
meaning the products containing those
chemicals still can be sold there the US
Environmental Protection Agency which
decides which pesticides can be used on
which crops just said last month they
Colorado and Washington authorities that
they could apply to have some cannabis
related chemicals approved through
what's called a special local need
registration but that process could take
years so looks like we're on our way but
it could take Colorado and Oregon
require retail marijuana to undergo
testing for pesticides and other
contaminants but as the Oregon an
investigation showed the testing regimes
are imperfect and Colorado hasn't yet
implemented requirements for retail pot
to undergo pesticide testing because of
regulatory delays there aren't any labs
here that'll test for you guys that's
part of the problem a Washington state
is still working on its pesticide rules
the nation's largest marijuana producer
California has no regulations at all for
growing commercial pot you know up until
this industry got hugely popular on a
recreational and legal level the
guidelines and the people who were
responsible for quality control
were the growers we were the ones
responsible for that it was a craft it
was an art it was something that we were
proud of we would not let out a product
that had been sprayed with some [ __ ]
or a product that had powdery mildew on
it we were the ones who were responsible
for that and took that responsibility
and now that it's so commercially
popular and everybody's buying and
growing and selling cannabis the art and
the love I hope you guys heard that that
was some amazing thunder it's finally
raining we've needed it but it was my
responsibility now that it's so popular
everyone's worried about the money
gotten away from the art and the pride
and they're just doing whatever they can
do to get plants on the ground pounds
out the door and money in the cash
register
customers out the door and that's not
really what it's about
so since people have lost the heart
they're not growing from their heart
like I try to teach them to do we have
to come up with some sort of testing and
we have to create rules and this is
where we are so it says it's a lot more
difficult than it sounds and it's
expensive Washington liquor bore
Washington's Liquor Control Board
spokesman Brian Smith said about testing
for pesticides as a result unscrupulous
pot growers can use banned chemicals
with little chance of being caught we
were taken by surprise this whole
pesticides taken by surprise this whole
pesticide issue said Ashley Kilroy
Denver's Director of Marijuana Policy
she was talking to a room of about 200
pot industry workers who invited and
yeah it doesn't it's missing a word here
invited lunch after the invited to a
lunch maybe earlier this month to
learned about pesticide quarantines and
rules sorry they skipped a word of this
article and it totally threw me off it's
just as invited lunch so that's weird
we'll keep going what the growers heard
wasn't encouraging there's no federal
agency that will recognize this as a
legitimate crop said Whitney Crenshaw a
Colorado State University entomologist
and pesticide expert regulators just
bury their heads and as a result pest
management information regarding this
crop devolves to internet chats and
hearsay and you guys don't want to go
start reading about how to battle bugs
or powdery mildew on a large scale on
the internet because there's so much
[ __ ] that you'll have to feed
through that if you don't have a good
base knowledge it'll just confuse you
and mess you up even more so marijuana
growers are indeed guessing when they
treat their plants for example one of
the chemicals cited in Denver
quarantines a fungicide called eagle 20
is commonly used on grapes and hops but
can become dangerous when heated and is
banned for use on tobacco no research
exists on whether the fungicide is safe
for use on pot that will be eat now
something i've read recently about
exactly Eagle 20 is Eagle 20 gets inside
of a per
it goes in the play is what it doesn't
it stops the plan from producing powdery
mildew and it can last for sixty to
ninety days in the plan so that's a
little crazy if you understand the plant
biology there but also what I've read is
if it gets on your skin it absorbs into
your skin and it changes your RNA and
you won't notice it because you might
not live long enough to even notice the
changes that occurred in your body but
your grandchildren will be affected by
this your grandchildren will have birth
defects attention deficit disorders that
is what this type of chemical does it
doesn't [ __ ] you up but it messes you up
in the insides to where your kids kids
are messed up which is that's got to be
some serious dangerous [ __ ] I don't want
to mess with
I don't want sprayed on my plants I
don't want sprayed on your plants we'll
keep doing here
several fog growers interviewed by The
Associated Press agreed that research is
needed on pesticides for pot but they
pointed out that pesticides are widely
used on food crops and that weed
consumers have never before had as much
information about the marijuana they buy
it's just like broccoli or spinach or
peaches or anything the plant isn't
susceptible to certain pests said
Gabriel Fair 4th anyway who is
cultivation manager of Denver's herbal
remedies I apologize for butchering your
name there Ferris does not use any
banned chemicals on his plants and it
was not affected by the quarantines but
he questioned some of the banned
chemicals if you have all these
chemicals that are safe on product to
eat but you can't use them on marijuana
I don't know that I agree with that
the oldest marijuana legalization
advocacy group Keith Straub of the
normal organization National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws pointed out that regulators today
are at least starting to look at
marijuana safely in the 1980's the
federal government used an herbicide
called paraquat to kill illicit
marijuana crops even though the poison
had been banned from national forests
because of environmental concerns normal
complained to the White House that some
of the weeds survived it was turning up
on the street the response was it's
illegal and we don't have any obligation
not to poison its crop recalled
no one was taking us seriously that is
kind of sick baby poison to this weed
the weed made it to the street and when
they said hey this weeds out there they
went
problem bro it's illegal don't [ __ ] with
it oh it's tough love from the
government right their recent actions by
states with legal weed have been
encouraging if slow he said the idea
that it's been up it's been on the black
market people are fine so therefore we
don't need testing is absurd Straub said
no one would want to be using a product
that hole has mold or pesticides and
that is very true nobody wants to smoke
a product that has mold or pesticides in
it that's just gross why do you even
want to put that into your body why do
you want to put that in your pipe
why do you as a grower why would you
want to put that out there why would you
act like you're proud why would you even
sell that to somebody that's just
weirdness to me so that article came
from I'm scrolling back up to remember
her name it is Kristin Wyatt from The
Associated Press I need a drink alright
so was a grower I find it kind of wrong
that people would even spray some of
this [ __ ] on their plants I don't use
anything that is not completely organic
and honestly I avoid using sprays but
since I work in agro and I go to a lot
of groves I know that I'm putting myself
at risk so I need some sort of safety
net so I do use products I try not to
use too much neem oil because neem oil
will definitely affect the flavor of my
extracts so there are certain things
that I'll use certain things that I
won't use and we've definitely been
talking about what we will and won't use
at the shop because there are things
that we definitely do not want to put in
our crop as a shop I think you guys are
gonna grow weed or cannabis or pot or
whatever you want to call it who's gonna
consume the products that you're growing
our goal is to make people feel better
and not give them cancer or lung disease
alright so don't spray some [ __ ] on your
plants it's gonna give somebody cancer
or lung disease
don't spray anything on your plants that
you wouldn't spray on your produce and
then eat it I think that's what that
should be our new guideline and also you
guys think about what would happen if we
gave some contaminated products to a
person with a compromised immune system
I'm a caregiver and one of my favorite
patients I'm a medical marijuana
caregiver which means I am I responsible
for growing
a few people's medical cannabis and I've
got a patient his name is Doug and
Doug's an older dude he's over 50 years
old and he's not in good health since
I've known him he's had three or four
major health problems in just a few
years that I've known it I grow medical
cannabis for Doug to make Doug feel
better I grow medical cannabis for Doug
to help Doug live longer I'm trying to
improve Doug's life when I'm mixing up
nutrients and reading the back of a
nutrient bottle Doug
feel better so if I see powdery mildew
in a crop I cut the crop down I clean
the room I start over and figure out why
I think about Doug before I apply
anything every I research I try to be
good to myself I try to be good to Doug
I try to be good to anybody else it's
gonna smoke this stuff or eat this stuff
or make cash out of this stuff because
it's going into a sick person's body we
don't want to kill them we want to make
them feel better so a lot of people I
wrote this down a lot of people are
gonna have the excuse of it they didn't
know they were using some dangerous
pesticides like I said earlier as a
grower that is your responsibility
you're supposed to read every bottle
everything that you when you go to the
grocery you should have already read
about that product before you bought it
today read every bottle and then go if
you don't know what that one ingredient
is if you don't know what spinosad is if
you heard me recommend spinosad to get
rid of white flies on the show if you
don't know what that is before you spray
go read what that [ __ ] is and understand
what you're spraying on your plants
that's your responsibility as a grower
you should have read every bottle you
should have researched everything so
that you know what you're putting into
yourself and so that you know what you
are giving to sick and this counts even
if it's a commercial or a recreational
grow because you don't know where that
product is going to end up you have no
idea who's gonna be smoking it we don't
want to make more people more sick
let's work on healing people you guys be
more responsible with your grows please
that's my point
big shout out to Kristen Wyatt from The
Associated Press all so much respect to
the cannabis for always keeping the good
news come in my direction you guys it is
7:10 there's some killer Thunder rolling
through my neighborhood right now it
sounds great it is finally cooled off
it's been stupid hot here the past few
days it's 7:10 and put myself together a
fat damn I hope you guys are getting a
dad together on the count of five let's
do a DAB here together you guys one two
three sorry about the silence while I'm
dead but because her dad annoys me so it
wasn't super silent alright so I got an
email recently no this was a Facebook
message
it was an email I don't remember I got a
message from somebody who follows me on
Facebook and also supports my periscope
because I saw you on periscope and you
reminded me about this question I
appreciate it if you're not checking out
periscope you should definitely do that
you can get it on Apple devices you can
get it on Android devices the periscope
app is fun you download it go follow me
when I come on live it will whistle at
you you can open up the screen and you
can watch me rant or ramble or take
dad's or walk through a grow room or
whatever I happen to be doing that day
is a live broadcast and then the video
stays up for 24 hours unless I said
something stupid and then I go delete
the whole video most of the time I leave
it up so you guys check it out on
periscope I'm coughing from that dab I'm
gonna take a drink then I'm gonna get on
to the point to this next topic here
all right big shout out to root beer
alright this next topic is carbon
filters like I was saying my friend sent
me an email asking about carbon filters
let me start off by saying that the
information that you sent me you had an
idea of which carbon filter you wanted
you have chosen the right filter that's
what I think from the info that you gave
me you were talking about getting the 13
inch tall with either let's talk a
little bit about selecting the carbon
filter you guys first of all I should
explain to you what a carbon filter is
maybe you're new maybe you're not
familiar a carbon filter is what we use
to take the air to take the smell out of
the air if the air is leaving your grow
room it's gonna stink like crazy if you
have flowering plants you have a blower
or an inline fan blowing air out of your
get some fresh air in there when you're
blowing that old air out it is going to
smell like cannabis it's gonna stink
like a skunk or fruit or berries it's
gonna stink if you're doing it right so
the carbon filter passes through the
carbon filter will be cleaned the carbon
filters a cylinder with activated
charcoal in it connects to your inline
fan and then it blows air through the
carbon filter first and then you can do
inline fan or ducting however you choose
but then you go out of your Dro area and
the air goes through the carbon filter
has all the contaminants removed and
those contaminants include the odor so
that's basically the stone version of
what a carbon filter is a cylinder with
activated quartz charcoal the connects
to your inline fan as air goes through
it it removes contaminated
so now we'll talk a little bit about how
to select your carbon filter is this is
the part that our friend needed health
with the goal of your carbon filter and
your blower in your room is to exchange
the air in your grow room every one to
three minutes for best odor control
because what that means is you want to
take all of the air out of your room if
you don't want to empty it then refill
it of course you want to be sucking air
out of the room and refilling every one
to three minutes all right you want to
get the air completely exchanged every
two to three minutes or twenty to thirty
times an hour inch for best motor
control so to do that you need to find
the cubic volume of the room and to do
that you measure length times width
times height all right and that will EQ
equal the cubic volume of the room once
you know the cubic volume of your room
then you need to get an inline fan that
will pull that volume of air twenty to
thirty times per hour through your room
and then you'll find a carbon filter
that matches that and that's easy
because the alright what you need to do
you'll find the cubic volume of the room
right I'm gonna make up a room this room
is twelve by twelve that's got a twelve
by twelve footprint with an eight-foot
ceiling right so that I did the math
that comes out to 1152 cubic feet for
that's the cubic volume of the room so
you want a blower ideally it would pool
it would have a CFM rating of 1152 or
close to that if you go look at the
vortex fan they actually sell one it is
an 1140 CFM so I would use that on
either a 6 or an 8 inch duct that's what
I would recommend and then you would
want to find a carbon filter that is
rated for the same amount of CFM's they
come in ranges so you're gonna need a
carbon filter that is able to scrub
about 1152 cubic feet of volume in your
room would be ideal you can go half of
that which is about 576 but you don't
want to go much lower than that if you
point to a third of that
you're looking in the three Hades and
you're not gonna be pulling enough
humidity out that way and it's you may
get the smell out that way but you're
not gonna be cooling the room and you're
definitely not gonna remove enough
humidity of [ __ ] so I'd recommend going
five seventy-five to like eleven fifty
two maybe of 1200 at the max but that's
how you need to select your blower a
blowers that is going to pull the
appropriate amount of air and then the
carbon filter will follow the blower
make sure you get the right size flange
on there they come in anywhere from a
four all the way up to I think a sixteen
as I've seen in use but so once you find
your carbon filter that matches your
blower I would recommend that you hate
the carbon filter as high as you can in
the room hanging up as high as you can
because heat rises you want to keep your
air conditioned air down low and you
want to keep your heat that's up top you
want to suck that out make sure you guys
change out the carbon filter remember
they don't last more than a year maybe
two some of them are rechargeable but
from what I have found it's actually
much cheaper to just go buy a new one
the hard part is finding an economical
or not economical and environmentally
friendly way to get rid of your old
carbon filter if you guys have any
suggestions on that you can send me an
email score from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to share that information
on the show if somebody to dispose of
their carbon filter more properly I've
got a couple lined up in my garage that
I don't know what to do with alright
guys I hope that made sense that was my
very quick lesson on how to select a
carbon filter a carbon filter from the
roof from the ceiling I mean make sure
you do it smartly wisely my grammar is
terrible today make sure you use a stud
and not like a guy like myself or Jessi
make sure you find a beam in the room
just do everything smart don't destroy
the house don't hurt yourself especially
hanging a forty pound fifty pound carbon
filter above your head that [ __ ] could
fall I don't want it to break you I
don't want it to break your plants I
love you guys I would miss you if you
quit listening definitely hate it if you
hurt yourself
careful safety first since I'm talking
about that here's a piece of advice that
I don't talk about often enough somebody
was like hey bro if you could put like
one or two essential pieces of gear and
a grow roof that I may have overlooked
what would they be you know what I told
him I sent a fire extinguisher on the
outside of the room right outside the
door and a smoke alarm inside of the
room that's something I definitely
recommend go to smoke alarm in there
outside of the residential grow because
you don't want to have to run in the
grow room to find the fire extinguisher
in the worst-case scenario you want it
right outside to kick open the door
start spraying if that's what needs to
be done I hope that never has to happen
for you guys but I hope you do have a
fire extinguisher in the case that you
do need it I hope you had a smoke alarm
to give you some heads-up we've been
going just about almost 27 minutes I
feel like if I start doing the closing
now we should wrap up right on time for
a 30 minute episode you guys I really
appreciate it you've been listening to
these 30 minutes 30 minutes episodes a
whole lot more than you did those 45 and
hour-long shows I feel like a lot of you
pot smokers have a TD or maybe you just
have a short lunch break or something
but I appreciate you guys listening I
can see that you listen to the whole
episode and I can see who cuts I can't
see who but I can see that a lot of the
listeners cut out at certain times so
I've learned is it about 36 minutes is
your attention span so I try to keep
them about 36 minutes 40 at the most but
I appreciate everybody for listening you
guys I'm gonna start closing up the show
make sure you check out our sponsors you
guys don't forget about hydro indoor
growing supplies definitely love those
guys if you remind them that you listen
to the door from your heart podcast they
will give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase they've got a lot of
great stuff in there they don't have
what you want they can definitely order
it for you it only take them a few days
they've got another location in Denver
so if you're at the Pueblo shop if they
don't have what you want they could
possibly get it from Denver if not
they'll get it from the vendor they'll
get it from a distributor it will be
there it'll be fresh it'll be new it'll
be awesome so make sure you shop at
hydro drawing supplies also you guys I
want to remind you that nature is green
remedies dot-com has changed
name their website is now under the dank
team.com
the da NK te am calm the day team calm
make sure you check out the dank team
calm and all your feminized and regular
regularized seeds from them they are
most likely sold out of all ira genetics
products they may have some double eyes
left but they don't have much if they do
have anything hey guys if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you've got a product you'd like me to
review just send me an email to grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
i'll get you all the information that
you need now that show's over you guys
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart podcast to find the review section
give me a 5 star rating and after that
type in a comment and let me know what
you think of the show and I promise you
I will read your comment on a future
episode
if you want to leave a comment on
stitcher you can do that but I do not
promise you that I will find it because
stitcher likes to change the way
comments are left and it kind of sucks
you can always contact me on Facebook
it's grow from attack notes just grow
from your heart on Facebook right yeah
you can find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast of course there's the email it's
go from your heart at hotmail.com
I love all the social media interaction
don't forget about all that stuff every
show is available on I read genetics
Colorado calm the top 20 are the most
current 20 episodes holy crap that was
hard to say are always on iTunes and
stitcher so you can always listen that
way if you want to go back to the
archives I read genetics Colorado calm /
girl from your heart - podcast has every
episode all the way back to embarrassing
number 1 you can listen to episode
number 2 when I had Addison tomorrow on
to talk about lab testing all of the
episodes are up there go amuse yourself
to the podcast page a little while back
a couple of people have taken advantage
of that big shout out thank you to those
guys if you feel like the show was worth
a few bucks you can always go to the
website as I read genetics colorado
click on the girl from your heart
podcasts tab at the top right there's
that Pay Pal logo if you click on that
make a small donation it goes directly
to my PayPal account
I'm never gonna charge you guys for this
podcast this show is always gonna be
free I'm giving you the girl from your
heart
cast free from my heart it's my gift to
you I feel like I've been blessed by
this power for my blessed with knowledge
for this plant and I feel like you'd be
ashamed to share this and keep it to
myself so I want to share this knowledge
with you guys it's free it's yours here
you go but if you feel like you would
like to make a contribution all you have
to do is hit that PayPal button
everything would be appreciated so I
would appreciate that media sites make
sure you check that out
make sure you follow I read genetics on
Instagram I just got 17,000 Instagram
followers they've been posting up
pictures of the fire you guys have also
been putting up my periscope rants on
YouTube I read genetics has a YouTube
channel if you want to see something
music videos of you just taking dad's
late at night I'm checking out the burn
at your table on YouTube I review some
hash on the YouTube channel so check
that if it's that out if you would like
go subscribe to that before the hard
time thank you for listening to this
podcast I really appreciate you guys
supporting me for following the things
that I do it's really fun to have people
that are so interactive I've got a lot
of loyal fans and I appreciate you guys
till the very end I'll be back in
another week the next episode is going
to be about pH and why pH is important
and what it does for your plants I will
probably have another news article and
then I'll be back in the future with a
lot more grow lessons you guys want to
give a big shout out to my ninja spits
thanks again for listening and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me before I sign off I'd
like to dedicate this episode to Bryan
Richie may your music and your memory
live forever
[Music]
you
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host Jeff I want to thank you guys for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to the mystic
Bruce band for letting me use their
music on my show
big thanks to Kat and the entire mystic
roots crew right now you guys are
listening to a song called the doggy dub
off of the album the constant struggle
make sure you support and check out the
album is called make sure you check that
out Wednesday wherever you are whatever
you're doing I hope you're loading up a
bowl I hope you're twisting up a joint I
hope you're packing up the vaporizer
maybe you're eating an edible I hope
you're heating up the nail I hope you're
taking a dab with me I hope that in some
way shape or form you are consuming some
type of high-grade high-quality super
delicious dank cannabis products with me
right now I hope so a big shout out to
whoever is smoking token dab in eatin
some edibles big shout out to everybody
hope you guys are joining me hope it's
organic I hope it's clean I hope it's
fresh all right so I got a couple things
I want to talk about I want to take a
minute to give a huge thank you to my
friend sunny sunny sometimes listens to
this show I also want to thank rev a
couple other people that you guys
probably have never heard of I
especially want to thank Donovan McNeely
Dan Lazzarini Kenny Nicholson Wayne
DeHerrera the list just goes on and on
so I'll tell you what I'm talking about
unfortunately a couple of weeks ago a
good friend of mine by the name of Brian
Richie he passed away he left this earth
and he left us a little saddened Brian
was a great musician Brian is probably
oh let's see
Brian was probably close to 40 years
older than me pretty close 35 to 40
years older than myself and I met Brian
I was a musician just starting out I was
playing in a club and Brian saw me play
and he said young man you've got a gift
and my band needs a drummer and I'd like
you to play with us and you know this
old guy approaches me and asked me to
play I kind of thought I don't want to
play with a bunch of old guys I'm a
young rock star but for some reason I
did it something in my heart said you
should go play with these old guys and
see what they're doing and until I
played with them I was not a drummer I
was a guy with a drum set that was
hitting drums with my friends um Brian
and the band I joined with Brian turned
me into a musician I was not a musician
until that point um Brian gave me
musical career advice Brian gave me
stage advice Brian taught me a lot about
being a professional musician Brian took
me out of the bar mentality of playing
as a bar musician just playing for free
beer trying to be a rock star he put me
in the mentality and mindset of a
working drummer and I will never forget
that so I'm always grateful to Brian
Richie for the what did he see in me he
had confidence in me he had faith in me
and he saw that and he put me behind the
drums in his band when I wasn't ready
and let me earn my position there and I
worked hard to be the drummer that he
needed so I've been going on for a long
time about it but Brian I miss you bro
thanks for what you did to my musical
career thanks for what he did to my
mindset as a musician now what I'm
getting to a Saturday we threw a giant
party Brian didn't want a funeral they
didn't want sadness but I thought that
it was my duty to throw a party for the
man and get all of our favorite mutual
friends and musicians together in one
room and play one big jam in one last
hurrah for our friend Brian so I
organized an event in my friend Sonny's
house he's got a large jam space with
like a large jam room his house is like
a club he's got a small club attached to
the back of his house so I made a
Facebook event I sent out a few phone
calls a few invites I got our old band
together came and jammed another band
that Brian was in came and jammed and a
bunch of Brian's old friends came and
played music
we had a potluck big shout out to George
Samaras he brought a lot of great
goodies I appreciate that big shout to
everybody who attended the party big
shout out to everybody who played at the
party big shout to Danielle
helping me organize the party um this
party meant a lot to me and it was a
complete success and I am totally
satisfied and grateful and I wanted to
share all of it with you guys and give a
big THANK YOU to everybody so everyone
can hear it all at once I hope you guys
listening will move on I'm sorry I don't
want to meter I don't want to ramble
about this party too much but I was
super excited and I feel like I wanted
to thank everybody on the podcast
publicly so thank you guys I appreciate
it it's good to know that I can put
together a party like that I only had
about four or five days to organize and
I got about eighty people in this place
so I was really proud I was really happy
to honor Brian that way so big shops
everybody Brent I miss you bro we will
move on I'm a few weeks ago well it's
been ongoing over the past few weeks we
have talked about a raid that happened
at a Santa Ana California dispensary
I'll give you guys a little update these
cops raided a dispensary they treated
all of the people in the dispensary like
[ __ ]
once the dispensary was emptied of
people they took down all the cameras
and then they began to they proceeded to
destroy this dispensary
they broke the TVs they broke the
security systems they cause damage to
the safes they caused the water damage
to the displays and then these police
officers had the audacity to eat edibles
on camera there happened to be another
hidden camera in the building that was
recording that the cops didn't know
about and they were caught talking mad
[ __ ] they shouldn't have been saying
they were eating edibles
they were playing darts and they were
acting like [ __ ] on camera so they
have been caught the dispensaries lawyer
discovered the video and filed a lawsuit
against specific law enforcement
officers now here is where we are today
here's an article that I found on
reason.com written by Jacob Solem and
the headline says suspended cops say
video of them eating marijuana edibles
during a raid violated their privacy the
sub headline is Santa Ana officers want
to stop their department from using the
footage to investigate them I'm gonna go
ahead and read you the article it says
remember the Santa Ana California cops
who were caught on video munching on
what seems to be cannister cannabis
infused chocolate bars after raiding an
unlicensed
medical marijuana dispensary in may the
Orange County Register reports that
three officers who were suspended after
the incident are trying to stop the
Santa Ana Police Department from using
the footage in its internal
investigation among other things their
lawsuit argues that the officers thought
they had disabled all of the security
cameras at sky high holistic and
therefore had a reasonable expectation
of privacy the cops complained that the
dispensary never got their permission to
record them as they searched the
premises so these cops are trying to
stop this video from being used in court
because they were illegally recorded
because since they had destroyed all of
the security cameras they therefore had
a reasonable expectation of privacy now
that means
that if I break into your house and you
film me [ __ ] your film because I had an
expectation of privacy while I broke
into your house and stole all your [ __ ]
that's what these cops are saying it's a
two-way street I don't think that a rule
works just for cops that doesn't work
for civilians right these cops are
trying to pull some [ __ ] I'm gonna keep
reading here it says all police print
all police personnel present had a
reasonable expectation that their
conversations were no longer being
recorded and the undercover officer is
feeling that they were safe to do so
remove their masks says the complaint
which was filed in Orange County
Superior Court without the illegal
recordings there would have been no
internal investigation of any officer
under California law all parties to a
confidential communication must consent
to being recorded but that rule does not
apply when the parties to the
communication may reasonably expect that
the communication may be overheard or
recorded in an interview with the
register Sky's lawyer Matthew Pappas
noted that police routinely used
surveillance camera video against
suspects it's pretty pathetic for police
to say if we don't like something that
it can be used then it can't be used as
evidence he said they knew they were on
video just because they messed missed
one camera doesn't make it illegal
I think we all agree here that this is
complete [ __ ] because if you were I
were caught doing something on a film no
matter how that film was made that film
would be used against us in a court of
law that film would probably be edited
by the opposing lawyers to make us look
like a pile of [ __ ] so I think that this
videotape should definitely be used in a
court of law these people in my opinion
they illegally [ __ ] attacked if you
know more about the story these people
illegally singled out this dispensary so
I hope that this video is used in court
if not there are bigger problems in
America than we knew about I'm gonna
give a huge shout out to reason.com
and also a big shout-out to Jacobs Solem
alright you guys my friend Fred Garvin
recently sent me an e-mail or was a
Facebook message and it said I don't
remember exactly what it said I'm gonna
kind of miss quote him ridiculously but
he said hey Jeff used to do a bunch of
girl lessons that was what the show is
about and recently you were not doing
grow lessons what the hell happened Fred
I agree with you I've responded to you
on Facebook I addressed this on the last
podcast I completely agree with you Fred
I need to get back to the grow lessons
so here's what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
take a phat dab and then I will be right
back and we will talk about the
importance of pH in your plants so hang
on for just one second you guys I'm
gonna take a DAB maybe get a drink and I
will be right back all right you guys I
am back after a couple of dabs and I am
feeling great now it's time to talk
about pH a little bit um I've got a few
notes here I'm gonna try to skim through
these without sounding like I'm reading
too much but I needed some notes to keep
myself on track because this has a lot
of numbers and a lot of important things
that we need to pay attention to so
let's get into it a little bit properly
properly adjusting the pH of your
nutrient solution can solve a lot of
problems and it can greatly improve the
quality of your crop I still do a little
bit of consulting and I really see a lot
of people overlooking the pH of their
nutrient solution and how important it
is to adjust the pH of their nutrient
solution before they feed their plants
these guys have a lot of problems in
their gardens that look like nutrient
deficiencies and I see them trying to
correct nutrient deficiencies like a lot
of times a pH imbalance will just will
look like
Fache itself as maybe a cal-mag problem
or maybe a phosphorus overload but a lot
of times it's just a simple pH problem
they could have been solved by adjusting
the pH of your nutrient solution before
you fed it to your plants um a lot of
people will talk about soil pH a lot of
people are gonna talk about different
areas of pH what I'm going to talk about
is the pH balance of your nutrient
solution whether it be soil or hydro if
you're working in soil the optimum pH
range for your soil garden is about 5.5
to 6.5 if you were working in hydro your
optimum range is going to be similar
between 5 8 and 6.2 now you keep hearing
me say that we need to be within a
certain pH range it would be ideal to
find a certain number and stick with it
is what most folks would think but the
reason we need a pH range is because
some nutrients that we're feeding our
plants some of the elements that our
plants are trying to absorb are
available at certain pH levels and some
are available at different pH levels so
I'm gonna pick like in soil nitrogen is
available and pretty either pretty much
suck up nitrogen at any point let's look
at iron iron is more available on the
lower side of the pH scale the 3.5 range
the 3.5 to about 6.5 is where you're
gonna pick up iron but if you get any
higher on the pH range you stop
absorbing the iron so then we're gonna
look at calcium calcium doesn't absorb
very well in the 5.0 range but it does
start picking up at 5.5 to 6.5 you can
really absorb calcium but if you go out
toward the 7.5 range you stop picking up
calcium so these nutrients have a window
where the pH is ideal for the plant to
absorb each nutrient and we have found
that in soil somewhere between 5 5 &amp; 6 5
is when all of these nutrients become
available at the same time ideally and
in Hydra like we said earlier it's five
point eight to six point two where these
nutrients become available and let me
tell you that the graph on the hydro
side is much smaller you have a much
more narrow
window of nutrient availability due to
pH I know that's a lot to absorb but
once it's clicks in it'll definitely
make sense to you let me try to explain
it like this a little bit when it's
really hot outside you don't want hot
cocoa but when it's really cold outside
you do and then when it's really cold
outside you don't want ice cream but
when it's warm outside you want ice
cream so what we got to do we got to
find that perfect day where you can have
hot cocoa for breakfast and you can have
ice cream for lunch and that's what
we're trying to do for the plants by
finding the perfect pH range we're
trying to find that optimum spot where
they're in the mood for all of the
nutrients we're feeding them all right
now we should probably talk about what
pH actually is and stands for pH means
potential hydrogen it's written with a
lowercase P and a capital H and what pH
is is the measure of acid to alkalinity
in our nutrient solution pH is measured
on a scale of zero to fourteen zero is
the most acidic seven is neutral which
means there's an equal concentration of
hydrogen and hydroxyl ions and then
fourteen is pure alkali and it's done
it's measured on what is called a love
the I always [ __ ] this weird word up you
only have to say it in this instance
it's a logarithmic scale which means
that every one point increase or
decrease in pH reflects a tenfold change
an acid or alkaline so in a solution
that's pH 5 that solution is 10 times
more acidic than a solution that is pH
at 6 so if you've got something that's
pH D at 4 is going to be 1,000 times
more acidic than a solution that's pH at
6 so keep that in mind when you guys are
using your pH pen that's something that
we'll talk about here in just a little
bit using your pH pen and your pH meter
you have to be really on the money when
you're adjusting your pH once you find
once you found that range that your
plants really like you're gonna want to
try to set it right about there all the
time so if you're using soil somewhere
within that 5-8 to 65 if you're in hydro
somewhere in that 5 6-2 6-3 range you're
gonna want to get your pH set and then
keep an eye on the plants and then pay
attention to where it the plants each
strain is gonna be a little different
you guys pay attention to where each
strain likes that [ __ ] pH set and try
to get it there every time and take
notes and keep in mind that point one on
there is a huge difference in your pH so
you can't just say I'm close enough you
got to get it close and we'll talk about
how to adjust the pH and measure that
here pretty soon so also you guys keep
in mind if you're running hydro your pH
is gonna change possibly every day
because you're going to have nutrients
absorbed by the plants you're going to
have water evaporate there are going to
be so many things that happen causing
your pH to change that you're gonna have
to be on that in hydro in soil you're
just gonna mix up the bucket I at the
end before you feed it to the plants you
will test it and then you will adjust it
alright actually seems like I'm getting
to the part where I should start
explaining how to pH test your water and
then how to correct the pH so let's get
into that a little bit here um first I
would if you're mixing a hydro kit go
ahead and mix it in your reservoir fill
it up - excuse me fill up your resin
with water however you normally do it to
the recommended amount if you have a 25
gallon rez go ahead and do 25 gallons if
you're doing a hydro kit if you're doing
soil and you do five-gallon buckets or
you got a big rez fill that up however
you normally would with the amount you
normally would then mix in your
nutrients just like you normally would
I'm gonna give a shout-out to my buddy
John he taught me something and I don't
know how fallow this is but it made
it's John says if you're using potassium
silicates pour that in your water very
first he had a good sound reason one day
we'll get John on the show and he can
explain why John says pour your
potassium silicates then if you're gonna
use cal-mag do your cal mag next and
then do all of your other nutrients
after that um his reasoning made sense
and i don't want to try to butcher the
reason that he told me so one day we'll
get John on the show to talk about it if
you're a listener and you have a good
example of why and you can explain it
send me an email and I would like to see
what you're thinking I want to see if
somebody else is on the same page as my
buddy John so fill your reservoir makes
your nutrients in there do your
potassium silicon first then do your cal
mag then do the rest of your nutrients
however you wish then um now is the time
when you need to use a PHP or some type
of pH meter or a pH probe and you need
to stick that into this nutrient
solution and you need to see what the
display says what the number reads on
the display if you can't afford a pH pin
or a pH meter you can use an aquarium
test kit to tell you what the pH is they
sell them at the aquarium shop you
probably pick it up at Walmart it's used
in a court in an aquarium environment to
tell you what the pH of your aquarium
water would be so that you don't kill
your fish it'll do the exact same thing
we're just testing for pH here this
stuff isn't going to go into your
nutrient solution you'll take some water
out you will actually you'll dip this
strip into the water I don't even
remember how to use the reagent should
it's been that long you put some water
on it and then you drop these chemicals
on it and it shows you what color it is
and you measure it up to the color and
if it's like real blue then you're the
wrong way and if it's a real red you're
the wrong way you want to get kind of in
the middle but those test strips they're
kind of a pain in the ass you guys you
can tell about my description that's why
I haven't used it in years that's why
I'll never use it again get yourself a
good pH pen or a pH meter
um the Pens are way easier to use do not
drop your pen in the water it'll be
toast
um keep your PIN calibrated if you don't
know how to calibrate it take it to your
local grower and they will probably
calibrate it for you and after this
or fourth time they'll get tired of
doing it and they will teach you how to
do it just go ask him how to do it
they'll calibrate your pH pin for you
always keep no matter what type of pH
pin you're using always keep the probe
the tip that white part in there always
keep that way here's something to
remember with a pH pin a pH tester a pH
probe other than the reagent if you're
using the expensive any kind of pen that
you dip in the water if it dries it dies
that is the thing to remember if it
dries it dies keep your pH pin wet
keep it calibrated keep it clean and
keep it handy all the time I myself I
use the blue lab three-in-one combo it's
got a pH meter a ppm meter and a
temperature gauge on there that's called
a thermometer right yeah it's got that
on there it's a three-in-one combo it's
a little pricey if you can't afford that
get yourself you know those yellow
Milwaukee's work that's you'll see that
if you go to the grocery look for a pH
pin you'll see the yellow Milwaukee pH
meter that thing's a piece of [ __ ] but
it will work it'll do what you need done
I would recommend a better one if you
can afford a more expensive higher
quality pH meter I would go for it but
that little yellow Milwaukee piece of
[ __ ] will work it will die on you soon
so be prepared to buy another one if you
can get the next upgraded one whatever
it is do that like I said I like blue
lab products my buddy John was telling
me he likes another brand for some
reason I stick with the blue lab I've
never had any problems ah that's what I
would do so you stick the meter in there
see you fill up your reservoir you mix
your nutrients in the proper order you
let it be it's gotta be at about room
temperature you guys like you don't want
your water too hot or too cold because
that will definitely affect the pH get
it at room temperature maybe set it in
the grow room if it's coming out of the
faucet too hot or too cold go set in
your grow room for a little while so
that it's the same temperature as your
room then make sure nutrients into there
I didn't put your pH meter in there it's
gonna show a number hopefully most of
tap water most municipal tap water comes
out depending on where you are it's
between 8 and 9 just depends on where
you are and that will change seasonally
you guys or when your local water
company cleans their pipes or does some
flushing or changes chemicals that they
want to use
or it'll be seasonal for sure pay
attention because in the summer and in
the winter I can tell the huge
difference in my water quality so pay
attention to that test your water once
in a while just pour water out of the
faucet let it get to room temperature
stick your pH probe in there and see
what it is occasionally just for fun you
should always be testing everything
that's going into your plants I'm always
curious about what's going into my
plants so he makes your stuff up where
the hell was I makes your stuff up stick
your pH bin in there it's gonna show you
a number
hopefully you're close you know what I
mean you're usually once you've makes
your nutrients you're hardly ever gonna
need pH up if you need to put pH up in
there you probably are mixing your
nutrients too strong you're probably
using something you shouldn't be using
you probably did something wrong
probably there are some instances where
your pH will drop really low that's okay
but you're gonna need to bring it back
up that doesn't happen very frequently
um you're gonna be too high you're
probably gonna be once you mix up your
nutrients you're probably gonna be about
7.2 you're gonna need to get that down
closer to the 6.5 range if you're in
soil if you're running hydro you want to
get that down closer to like the 6.0
kind of area I guess the way you're
gonna want to do that is slowly very
slowly add your pH down just a little
bit you guys don't get this [ __ ] in your
eyes don't get it on your skin if you're
new at this and you're intimidated or if
you're a clumsy [ __ ] put on some
gloves and put on some protective
goggles I have a friend who was in
Michigan I won't say his name cuz I
don't want to embarrass you but my
friend Jason he splashed some pH down
into his eye just a little bit he said
he got a small drop of pH in his eye and
he said he went completely blind in that
eye and he said it was so excruciating
that he couldn't open the other eye and
he had to use Siri on his iPhone to call
to come to his house and help him in his
bro because he couldn't [ __ ] see so
don't put yourself in that kind of
situation you guys be safe if you're
clumsy [ __ ] wear some goggles even if
you're a pro it might be a good idea to
wear some safety goggles or something
when you're mixing this stuff the pH can
real the pH adjusters can really really
mess with your eyes and your skin if
they get on you and get in your eye so
a little bit of pH down in there I would
start with like five to ten milliliters
that's five milliliters in a five-gallon
bucket is probably enough to drop your
pH down where you need it drop that in
there shake it up real good
put your pH meter back in there and see
what you're testing now you want to get
it right on the money it's gonna you're
gonna have to [ __ ] up a couple of
batches you might have to use pH up and
down so many times that you just don't
even want to use it because all the [ __ ]
that you've just added to your your
solution you got too much pH you up too
much pH down in there so you're gonna
have to just pour that and start over
but don't be afraid that's how you're
gonna learn you guys that is how you are
going to learn so add your pH up add
your pH down whichever you need to do
and then test it and once you've got it
right where you want it go ahead and
pour that water into your plants if it's
a soil garden if it's a hydro garden go
ahead and start turn it on the rez and
get it going are the pumps or whatever
you got to do there's so much there's so
many different ways to do hydro you guys
I am learning hydro all right I'm gonna
say that this lesson for pH is pretty
much wrapped up I feel like I've covered
all of my bullet points keep in mind
that your local water will change and
you should check that out um that's the
kind of [ __ ] that you should worry about
your local waters gonna change
frequently and there's nothing that you
can do about it you're gonna have to
just be on top of that the only way that
you can really control your water is if
you set up a reverse osmosis machine and
you start cleaning everything out of all
of your water and starting fresh but
that could be a whole nother lesson I'll
find I will try to find a water expert
if you were listening and you're an
expert on water and water quality for a
grow you let me know I'll bring you on
the show and you can teach us all about
water I know a lot about the plant but
there are so many niche in niche areas
that people have perfected like our
buddy Shawn's got organics figured out
and I seem to be the breeder in the
group and then Spence is the hatch guy
there are just so many small branches of
this that we've got figured out that
each person does their own little as
mastered so I'm gonna try to get a water
guy on here for you guys I will talk
about water quality and what you should
be looking for it could probably be just
a segment anyway I was gonna branch off
and say dude I have been learning hydro
I've been talking to my buddy John that
works with me at the spot he is the
hydro master
I will be learning so much hydro in a
crash course here in the next few months
that you guys are going to learn hydro
with me I will learn a bunch I will
start sharing the hydro talk with you
guys we are building the most killer
grow facility at the spot dispensary in
Pueblo es Colorado you guys there are
over a hundred lights and flower there
are four flowering rooms broken down
they have 24 to 26 lights per room um
we've got a really nice veggie area we
are running 50 foot long flood and drain
tables that we fill up fill up about 150
gallons worth of water for a res we
makes a hundred and fifty Cal ins worth
of newts we pump that into the table at
one end it shoots all the way to the
other end of the table goes into a drain
there's a pump a really snazzy pump the
quality they use at SeaWorld shoots all
of that water through 50 feet of tubing
I think it's 2 inch or 3 inch PVC all
the way back to the other end of the
table and then it dumps it back into the
table and just keeps recirculating it
and then under each plants and then we
have I can't really tell you too much
about how we do the plant sights because
that's kind of a proprietary thing we've
got each plant is designated its own
site and it's in a Rockville cube
and underneath each rockwool cube and
plant site there is a ring shooting a
lot of oxygen of underneath these plants
so it's we're feeding from the bottom
and the rock hole is waking it up and
then we may we're not sure if we want to
do this yet but there may be a drip line
put in to top feed all of the plants so
that we can drip that nutrient solution
into the rock pool cube from the top and
then just let the roots hang into that
oxygenated water but you guys I'm
learning so damn much about hydro I have
built we have built I can't say I built
I have been involved in building a huge
hydro environment and I have learned so
much without even putting plants in
there yet well you're almost ready for
plants in there we will be pulling
harvests out of there in no time it
feels like we are so ready I'm getting
stoked you guys can tell just by the
tone of my voice that I'm [ __ ]
excited about to grow at the spot
dispensary big shout out to the spot big
shout out to Dave and Robert thanks for
giving me the opportunity and also a big
shout out to the guys have been working
with my grow crew my construction crew
big shout out to John big shout out to
Joe and a super shout out to Jaime love
all you guys thanks for helping me out
thanks for supporting me thanks for
seeing the vision and thanks for being a
good team all right that's a big I thank
you for listening it feels like it's
almost time to wrap up the show since
you've listened to this far I'm gonna do
this to you this podcast was of course
brought to you by my good friends at
hydro indoor growing supplies hydro does
have two locations to serve Colorado
they have a Denver store it's on 62 71
beech tree and then there's my favorite
it's the Pueblo location on 618 East 4th
Street and beautiful Pueblo Colorado
check out hydro for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor growing
supplies you guys when you're at high
grow and you're checking out tell them
that you listen to the growth from your
heart podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase that'll save you a bunch of
bucks which is always a good thing
because money is expensive these days
alright no more ads you guys I won't do
any more ads at the end we're gonna go
ahead and wrap up the show I wanna thank
everybody for listening you guys know
the show's over make sure you go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store find the
review section search for the girl from
your heart podcast
give me a five star rating and type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show if you think the show is
crap
tell me I'll try to fix it if you think
the show is awesome tell me I'll keep
doing exactly what I'm doing
I appreciate the feedback also I'd love
for you guys to participate in the
social media I'm on Facebook it's grow
from your heart podcast I'm on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast we are on
instagram under at I read genetics I
love all of the interaction I'd love to
see you guys get involved I haven't been
doing as much periscope videos lately
because I've just been busy with work
but I will get back on that one cuz
that's a lot of fun if you have
something to say and you don't want to
say it on the social media you can
always email me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com look at you all of
the information that you need you guys
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode is always in forever archived on
I read genetics Colorado calm don't
forget there's just a donation button on
that page if you go to I read genetics
Colorado calm click on the girl from
your heart a podcast tab at the top
right there's a PayPal button I'm never
gonna charge you money for this podcast
this is free this is my gift to you but
if you feel like making a small
contribution or a large contribution I
would certainly appreciate it
all you gotta do is click on the PayPal
tab type in $1.00 type in $10 type in
$100 you put any amount you want I would
be super grateful I'll give you a shout
out on the show since it's a donation it
is tax-deductible you get to decide
where your money goes out of your taxes
instead of the government taking your
tax money and doing whatever they want
with it so you wanna make a contribution
I would appreciate that um I'll give you
a shout out that's enough begging I'll
quit begging for that now I'm working on
getting the new zoom h6 so that we could
take the podcast on the road go do the
show at a few more places go visit the
grimy Gatsby since we can't get you to
come down to Pueblo we'll do a podcast
with damsel in Colorado Springs if we
get the zoom h6 we'll get a lot of [ __ ]
going on but um I think that's all I got
for you today you guys make sure you
follow me on Instagram it's a Tyree
genetics I just hit 17 thousand
followers recently see what I'm doing
I'm posting pictures of the spot
dispensaries build up there I'm posting
pictures of my personal grow up there
I'm posting pictures of my adventures up
there by the great [ __ ] to check out so
you guys I want to give a big shout out
to my ninja spits thank you for
listening and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
leave your parents walk alone yes we are
in California the place we Plaza in the
car proposition 215 it's a medical need
[Music]
me help me my gunga bag is empty help me
and me
I got about should be plenty
[Music]
weed weed weed weed weed weed
I love the weeds
[Music]
mouse just smooth stats
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 89 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to fear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a veteran dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host they call me Rasta Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on the show big thanks to
Kat and the entire mystic everybody's
having a great day I'm coming to you on
a scorching hot Thursday it is stupid
hot today but we're gonna deal with a
we're gonna drink a lot of water we're
gonna water up the plants we're gonna
talk a little bit about some heat issues
that some friends of mine have been
having in their gardens and we'll talk
about ways to cure a little bit of heat
problems and then I've got some ranting
to do but before we get that far this
podcast is brought to you by my friends
at hydro indoor growing supplies hi Gro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street or
check out the pueblo location on 618
East 4th Street and beautiful Pueblo
Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor gross supplies you
guys when you're checking out at high
grow indoor grind supplies make sure you
let them know you listen to the girl
from your heart podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that's right you'll pay
what I pay but put some money back in
your pocket you guys we all know that
money is expensive these days all right
we're gonna get on with the show here I
want to let you guys know that I'm
recording with a new device today I'm
using the new zoom h6 handy recorder I
got the zoom h6 so that I will be able
to take this podcast on the road a
little bit it's a much smaller unit than
what I've been using this thing will fit
in my back pocket and I can carry it
around and I can do shows from events
such as the secret cup the cannabis cup
or wherever we may be so you guys look
forward to episodes with special guests
coming up because now I can take the
show to them instead of trying to get
people to come to me
I live in kind of a shitty part of
Colorado where nobody wants to go so
it's hard to get like damsel and hunt
and people like that to come here but if
I go to them they're happy to be on the
show so spend a few bucks I got the zoom
h6 we will take this show on the road
guys I'm gonna ask you to do me a favor
since you're listening to the show let
me know what you think of the sound
quality let me know if this quality is
acceptable let me know if it I've
changed anything that you've noticed
because if this isn't acceptable I'll go
back to using the main studio setup
I just wanted to pull this out give it a
try see what it was like before I try to
take it on the road and record with
other people so age six well you know
what you think of it you guys alright so
let's get into the show
I told you that I saw some ducting
issues I did a consultation for a friend
of mine I didn't even charge him for
the-- of the day but he's been saying
dude my room is getting way too hot this
summer what can I do and I was like you
know what that's a good start of a
podcast so I walked in there and and the
first thing I see is messy ass ducting
the students got a decent girl room he's
got enough air conditioning his plants
look good but his ducting was a complete
mess you guys and I've seen a lot of
messy ducting lately on my visits and
consultations so one thing I'll tell you
is keep in mind that every single twist
and Bend in your ducting Razoo reduces
your air flow and adds to the workload
of your blower whatever kind of inline
fan you're using every Bend puts more
strain and more pressure on that inline
fan and slows down the amount of air
you're moving so ideally ducting would
be in a straight line with zero curves
or bends or twists or anything like that
but I know that's not that's not
rational because of course we're growing
in houses and things like that and you
have to move the air around and not a
straight line sometimes but try to get
it as straight as you can
that'll save you a lot of money on
heating costs it'll save you money
because you don't have to run the blower
as hard it'll save you money because
you're more efficiently cooling so
straighten out oh I just noticed
something when you put the cell phone
too close to the h6 you get a little bit
of interference so that's good to know
sorry about that guys I hope you didn't
hear that too much I'm reading notes off
of my cell phone here which is why I did
that anyway try to keep producting in a
straight line another great way to save
some money on cooling you guys would be
to run your lights at night
kilowatts from The Electric Company are
actually cheaper at night so if you're
not running your electricity at peak
hours it'll save you a few bucks so what
I would recommend if you can do it and
this will only work for some people on
your lifestyle your schedule if you can
have your plants come on
right around here it gets dark about
nine o'clock eight or nine o'clock ish
right now it would be ideal to have your
lights come on
at 9:00 p.m. that way it's cool outside
the Sun has gone down the whites kick on
and that way you're not fighting the Sun
all day you're not adding Sun and grow
lights to that grow room to try to cool
down so turn on your lights at night if
you can that'll help you out all right
so you guys straighten out your ducting
wring your light cycle at night and
you'll save a few bucks on cooling costs
getting your plants too hot is gonna
cause them to become fluffy and it's
gonna decrease your harvest weight so
when you've got electricity bills to
cover every gram counts so you got to do
your best to pull every gram you can out
of the room since you've got to pay for
every kilowatt that you've used so
figure out how to get the ducting
straight start running the lights at
night and that will help you out quite a
bit something else you guys could keep
in mind during these hot summer months
is humidity as the temperatures rise the
humidity outside is rising also so be
aware of how humid your rooms are this
is the first year that I have personally
needed to go buy a dehumidifier from my
main flowering room fans and air
conditioning are not enough sometimes
you guys you need to remove the stagnant
humid air from your rooms and replace it
with fresh co2 rich air for your plants
so you guys make sure you're pulling
that air how that hot air needs to be
sucked out all right one more thing I
can think of to help you keep your rooms
cool is to pay attention to the filters
and your air conditioners guys those
filters are designed to last for a year
without being replaced but keep in mind
you guys are running them in a grow room
or there may be a lot of extra dirt a
lot of humidity and there's a lot of
extra work on that unit they don't
expect that unit to be competing with
four or five or six whatever you got
that many thousand watt lights they
don't expect that thing to come on when
you buy it and never shut off like a lot
of us do with an air conditioner so if
you've got an air conditioner that has
filters replace those once they get
clogged up if they're doesn't flow
through you don't get as much cooling
you're wasting electricity that
electricity is not turning
- a gram of weed so you're flushing
money down the toilet basically your air
conditioner may require a little extra
maintenance since we're working it so
hard you guys and also keep in mind
where you're putting your air
conditioner they may suck up a little
bit more dirt and [ __ ] like that just
depending on where you have put it all
right so that was a good little rant
since we're talking about replacing
things and things that you need to
upgrade in your grow room I figured I'd
make a little kind of a checklist of
things it would be a good idea to
replace and check on one thing that you
guys need to replace is your bulbs in
your grow rooms the HID bulbs don't last
forever if you're using good bulbs you
can switch those out about once every
six months or if you've got the budget
you can toss them every two crops which
would be about every four months that's
why if you're using moley as a flowering
cycle if you're buying those cheap plant
max bulbs you guys or whatever generic
brand you you're buying at your grow
shop I would recommend replacing those
every single flowering cycle those
aren't high quality bulbs and they burn
out a little bit quickly all right if
you're using those cheap bulbs guys what
I would recommend is harvest the room
empty the room clean it out and replace
those bulbs before you put new plants in
there again if you're using good bulbs
you can go probably two cycles maybe
three I definitely wouldn't go past for
flowering cycles but the same bulb I
would replace that the bulb will stop
putting out as much light but it will
still be sucking up as much electricity
it will still be making as much heat and
again you're not turning those kilowatts
into grams of weed which is your goal
you don't want to pay for electricity
that is just causing heat which is
making your air conditioner run stronger
which is pulling more electricity you
see the cycle here all right so don't
forget that your bulbs in your veg area
are just as important isn't your
flowering room you guys you got to swap
those bulbs out occasionally also I like
those new 315 bulbs I'll reason those at
the shop they seem to put out quite a
bit of light and they're affordable so
if you guys can afford the three 15s I
would definitely recommend those if you
want to go with your metal halide bulbs
I would recommend those again every
every two months every four months every
six months at the very longest you guys
I wouldn't run longer than six months on
the same bulb no matter what you're
doing with it if you've got those t5
bulbs you're gonna need to replace those
quite frequently those things just crap
out what I've noticed about the t5 is if
you buy a fixture with like 85
I was in it just pretty much planning on
replacing all eight t5 bulbs all at the
same time because they're all just gonna
start [ __ ] now when one goes out just go
buy the whole set all right you guys
we've talked about replacing your bulbs
now what about the ballasts if you're
using modern modern digital ballot
digital ballasts they'll last a while
most of them come with a nice warranty
so you didn't hear this from me but
anything that comes with a warranty that
will be replaced because of the warranty
I make sure to break that thing about a
month or two before the warranty is up
sometimes a few months before the
warranty is up just break it just
[ __ ] break it and then go get another
one on the warranty because these
companies are charging you enough for
[ __ ] anyway it should last a while
breaking they'll get a new one they're
gonna refurbish the one that you've got
they're gonna resell it as a refurbished
unit don't worry about them they make
plenty of money just break the [ __ ]
thing right before the warranty is up
and get yourself a new one those old
magnetic ballasts those things will go
forever you won't see any drop in light
power from a ballast from what I've
noticed they'll just die one day it
won't even warn you so when your ballast
warranty is about to be a go get another
one you guys that should be enough
ranting for now about fixing your rooms
one thing I should remind you of that I
have mentioned in a previous episode
since we're talking about replacing
things calibrate your pH meters you guys
your TDS pins your pH pins whatever else
you want to call it your EC meter if
you're in England or Britain you guys
calibrate those things quite frequently
because when that messes up you don't
even notice and you're just in there
trying to adjust pH and you're doing it
wrong and you don't know so you're gonna
start causing problems all right guys
I've been going for just over 10 minutes
here I need a quick dab so uh you know
let's do a dab on the air together I was
recently gifted some blueberry headband
from the spa it's actually the shatter
is from our boys at tur pecs I got it at
the Spock out in Pueblo West I'm gonna
take a quick drink of this bubbly
carbonated beverage I got here and then
we're gonna put together a dad and we're
gonna take a dad together so here we go
[Music]
all right I needed it carbonated drink
there that was much deserved I'm gonna
get a dad together real quick you guys
big shout out to something called the
perfect jar I was gifted a jar called
the perfect jar by my buddy hunt and
they might be right this might be the
perfect jar man this thing is nice it's
uh I don't even know what kind of
plastic this is it's real sturdy plastic
it's got a nice screw on lid it's
airtight it's nicely
it's got dividers inside I'm able to
carry my herb in one container I got a
dabber in one container and then like
four or five different kinds of shatter
and the other little containers there
nice container bro thanks huh I
appreciate you kicking that down so
today we are going to dab Z what did I
call it's blueberry headband from our
friends at tur pecks and I'm putting a
dab of it on the dabber right now as we
speak you guys we're dabbing out of the
Eric Ross 4.0 custom prototype that's
autographed by Eric Ross on the back
it's got his little signature edged in
the back to that it's got the highly
educated D mail big shot it's a highly
educated and task rock and that D mail
attachment is attached to what is called
the G nail coil by our friends at emote
F shout out to giddy up and emo Tech I'm
burping from that drink excuse me so
I've got the dab together you guys let's
take a DAB blueberry headband shatter
from torpex available at the spot
dispensary you know by the time you hear
this they'll have a totally different
brand of shatter and our totally
different flavor but let's review this
anyway here we go
[Music]
it's definitely smooth nice and smooth
no joke I like that so let me back up a
step here by looking at it it's nice and
glossy it's got a nice shine to it
ah it's nice and clear it's got a nice
clear amber yellow color so it looks
great on the inhale well let me talk
about the smell it just smelled like
hash let's smell it again let's put it
up to the nose just like shatter mostly
smells the same it's got that shatter II
like almost a honey kind of a sweet
smell to it
but anyway it looks good that smells
good when I taste it on the inhale I
definitely tasted the blueberry on the
exhale it had a hint of cushy chemi type
of stuff I'm an earthy flavor on the out
so the N is blueberries and there's a
hint of blueberry on the tongue still
but you know what the feeling is
straight headband it feels like I just
put a headband on my head it feels like
I just slowed down to tell you the truth
it was like chills I could just slow
down a whole bunch so well let's get
back into doing a podcast I certainly
approve of the blueberry headband it
tastes like blueberry it feels like
headband it's smooth I don't I smoked
for me to tell you the truth guys excuse
the cough alright now that I buy a [ __ ]
I want to answer some questions that
people have sent to me these questions
have come from periscope they've come
from Twitter I've gotten them in emails
and I have gotten them on Facebook you
guys if you're not checking it out on
periscope every occasionally I jump on
to periscope and just I take a couple of
dabs and I rant and I hang out with my
friends they talked about a few things
that are on my mind and then I just sign
out and say goodbye and I usually delete
the videos pretty quickly but if you
ever check out the periscope app make
sure you follow me and you can check out
some of the videos in the future I'll do
a full podcast on periscope and you'll
be able to jump in and ask me questions
and I'll be able to answer them live for
you the only problem with that right now
is you guys I'm taking over as the leaf
grower at the spot dispensary and
there's been a lot of work and some days
we work until noon other days we work
until 6:00 it's hard to guess
so right now scheduling things is a
little bit of a pain in the ass but I
promise you I'm gonna do this periscope
episode I just promised you so that
means I've got to do it I've never
promised you something and not done it
on this show all right so let me get to
the point here
questions and answers with Rasta Jeff
our first question is about a product
called OGT quite a while ago I mentioned
that I use a product called OGT veganic
secret sauce is what I think it's called
somebody asked me to talk a little bit
about it
I liked that product a whole bunch I'd
like it it's what it is I don't have any
of the product with me I've used all of
what I have and I kind of kind of
haven't been using it since I ran out I
replaced it with something else but what
it is is an organic tea that is able to
be mixed almost instantly and then fed
to your plants a lot of teas that we're
using need to be mixed up and they need
to brew for 24 to 48 hours this stuff
you can pour the powder into some water
give it a nice stir and feed it directly
to your plants
one thing that I did notice that it
promoted ridiculously healthy roots my
roots were growing quickly my roots were
growing out of the holes and the bottoms
of my pots the drainage holes my roots
were coming out of there looking for
somewhere else to go hide I have a
friend who breaks down the soil from my
harvested plants he gets paid to help me
out a little bit and when Mike was
breaking down those root balls
he asked me dude what have you been
doing differently lately because these
things are amazing a lot of that I will
attribute to the secret sauce the
OGT I think it was doing a lot of it it
was really great for the early lifecycle
of the plants and for veg know inin when
I went into flour here's something that
I didn't realize was happening I noticed
there was something weird and somebody
else pointed it out to me when I was in
flower and I was feeding OGT I would
feed it every other week and on those
weeks I would notice that my plants
would progress more into what looks like
a nutrient deficiency on some strains I
had strains that I I was feeding it just
like I have before and it looks like it
was becoming nitrogen deficient the
plant couldn't keep up with itself and
it was just burning out really early and
I mentioned that to our friend Sean and
I mentioned that the only thing I was
using differently was the OG tea and
Sean said that the rock phosphates that
they are using to produce the OG tea
speed up the nutritive cycle of your
plan so if you're going to use this
stuff I would only use it during the veg
cycle and use it very sparingly during
the flowering cycle because when I used
the recommended dosage it sped my plants
up almost too much and they weren't
burned but they were almost not able to
they were growing so quickly and using
nutrients so quickly if they were eating
all of their food for the week within
the first couple of the days and then
starving themselves is what it looked
like was happening so that is my little
rant on OGT it's a good product
but if you're going to use it be
prepared and you're gonna have to adjust
your feeding they're gonna have to pay
attention but I hope you're doing that
every time you put a new product into
your garden anyway alright so our next
question I want to move on where did I
put it here we go our next question
comes from periscope and somebody asked
me and this is gonna take me a little
bit to do to describe here but somebody
said what is solvent list because I was
talking about solvent list on periscope
and they did not have it in context so
let me try to describe to you what
solvent list is first off let me say
that solvent list is a marketing term
solvent Lissa's owned by McAtee of
essential extracts I don't know if it's
owned by him but it is the marketing
term that he has put on what he calls
solvent lists now that being said not
all solvent list hash has to come from
nicotine anything any hash that is made
without solvent can well be considered
solvent list in most cases in 99% of the
cases in the cannabis industry you know
I've never seen anything else called non
solvent maybe dry sift but that's
totally different
water hash or bubble hash is solvent
list it's made with ice and water it's
not the solvents that we are using is
BHO Pho there are a couple other gases
that people are using to extract hash
with lately but the propane and the
butane are the solvents and I know a lot
of people are gonna say but water is a
solvent as well right in this case and
I'm going to paraphrase what Nikita says
all of the time big shout out to DJ
nicotine
we're talking about solvent less hash
water is not being used as a solvent
it's being used as a mechanical
separator we're not trying to dissolve
the trichomes we're not trying to
dissolve the plant matter we're just
simply using it as a way to wash the
trichomes off of the leaves so solvent
less hash is basically hash made by
using ice or water solvent less made by
DJ naked tea is kept at a certain
temperature at all times and it never
gets warm it never gets dry and never
hardens up it's always got a nice greasy
texture to it it's always real tasty
that's solvent list all right so since
we're talking about solvent list let me
describe a couple of other types of hash
just to kind of put that in perspective
a little bit other types of hash that
are super popular right now that
everybody talks about are BHO which is
butane honey oil or butane hash or dabs
or shatter or wax that's pretty much the
most popular right now and then of
course there is live resin live resin is
basically it is BHO that is made from
fresh frozen plants and then it is
blasted through an obidos machine by emo
tech the only way that you can make live
resin is through an emo tech machine and
I know that sounds crazy but like I said
earlier nikka tea has made the marketing
term solvent list the poison emo tech
have come up with the term live resin so
unless you're running it emo textile in
an emo tech machine
you're not making live resin a lot of
people are gonna hate on me for that but
that is my theory and I'm sticking to it
alright time for one more question this
question comes from Facebook and it's
from our friend Bobby Bobby is starting
his first grow and he's asking if it is
ok to use Miracle Grow plant food or
Miracle Grow soil for his cannabis plant
and you guys I definitely have to say I
strongly recommend not using any miracle
girl products in your garden the Miracle
Grow soil has time-released fertilizers
in it which will last for up to six
months and you don't want nitrogen being
released into your plants for six months
so I would recommend not using that soil
use something like a fox farms product
or a roots organics product do something
like that if you're a new grower it
gives you a solid start
there's not nutrients in it that are
gonna screw you up
it'll have things in it that will help
you out from the very beginning as for
the the nutrients if you are trying to
use Miracle Grow nutrients that would
throw those away right away get rid of
the plant food heavier hydro shop head
to hydro indoor growing supplies and get
yourself a basic two or three part
nutrient solution there'll be a bottle a
a bottle beef of a brand that sounds
good to you the guys at the hydro shop
can definitely talk you through what you
need to help you pick a brand they're
mainly if you're just starting out
they're mainly the same thing I would
say go with something like the tannic
hair bio biz something simple just
something with an A and a B the general
organics or general hydroponics Florida
Nova stuff that's all fine any of that
stuff you want to go for it's pretty
much all the same thing if you're
starting out get yourself an A and a B
maybe a bloom booster and then maybe
like some sugary or something to sweeten
it up but definitely get away from that
Miracle Grow stuff go to the hydro shop
get something designed more toward
cannabis something that you can control
for each cycle of your plants cuz you're
not gonna want the same nutrients from
beginning to end you want a little bit
of grow in the beginning and you're
gonna taper the grow off as you get into
flower and you'll start using the bloom
solution so go get something that's more
designed for the plants that you are
growing Bobbie I hope that helps you out
you guys that are thinking about Miracle
Grow soil I hope I got you away from
that also here's something to think
about you guys Miracle Grow products are
all from Scots and Scots is a Monsanto
brand and we do not want to support
Monsanto because Monsanto does not
support the world so that's something to
think about think about where the
products you are buying are made and who
they affect and the impact that you will
have on the world
all right you guys I think that was
enough questions for one episode I
really want to thank everybody who sent
me questions if you want to send
questions to me via email if you want to
hit me up on Twitter if you want to
Facebook me however you want to get a
question to me if you're one of my
friends if you're one of the homies feel
free to send it to me via text message
you can message me directly on Instagram
on the hydrogen etics Instagram because
I love the questions I love the
interaction I love helping you guys
that's what I got the show going for so
I really appreciate it big shout out I
appreciate all
those questions alright guys I'll be
back next week for another episode I got
a question from a listener asking what
are the difference or what's the
difference between THC and CBD that may
be the next episode there may be one
before that episode it's gonna that's
gonna be a lot of putting together
there's a lot of work going into that
episode I'm not sure if it'll be ready
by the next one but it will definitely
have it ready by number 91 so you guys
I'm gonna wrap up the show thanks for
listening to another episode I'll be
back in just a few days don't forget to
check out our sponsor hydro indoor
growing supplies if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review just
send me an email let's go from your
heart a hotmail.com
look at you all of the information that
you do need guys now that the show is
over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for grow from your
heart give me a 5 star rating and after
that type in a review and let me know
what you think of the show and I will
read your comment on a future episode
you guys if you want to leave a comment
on stitcher I'd appreciate it but it's
really hard to find the comments on
stitcher stitcher is always changing
things so I would recommend just send me
a Facebook comment if that's what you
want to do on Facebook it's just grow
from your heart you can find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast on
Instagram I'm hat i read genetics guys
if you're not into all the social media
stuff you can email me it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't forget
the show is available on iTunes and
stitcher every single episode is always
and forever archived on I read genetics
Colorado comm we've got that donation
button up there on the podcast page guys
if you feel like this show is worth a
couple of bucks you can go to my website
I read genetics Colorado com click on
the girl from your heart podcast tab at
the top right there's a donation button
it's a little PayPal logo that goes
directly to my PayPal account
I'll never charge you guys for this
podcast this podcast is always going to
be free this is my gift to you but if
you do feel like making a small
contribution to say thank you it would
definitely be appreciated and I would
give you a shout out on the
you guys like I said we're on all the
social media sites make sure you check
us out there I'll be back in just a few
days guys big shout out to my ninja spin
so let me know what you thought of this
recording I recorded this on the zoom h6
I had to stop one time and do an
adjustment to the recording settings but
I think I've got it all figured out so
let me know what you think send me a
comment on Facebook on Instagram on
Twitter however you want to do it I
would appreciate it
until next time you guys thanks for
listening shadows my ninja Spence until
next time take a phat dab and get your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
all the homies on the track spitting the
truth
[Music]
all right podcast thank you guys again
for listening to a long block of old
episodes I would love it if you would
email me and let me know what you think
about these old episodes the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to stalk me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with the fresh new
episode and until next time take a fad
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
Oh