[Music]
yeah welcome back at this community it's
time for episode number 235 of the Grove
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dapper if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my friend
is the podcast for yield
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band Coletti means
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat who in the entire
mystic roots crew
yeah ladies and gentlemen I'm in a good
mood today I'm not exactly sure why but
I am NOT gonna question it I'm just
gonna go with it it might have something
to do with this sour Joker live batter I
just took a gigantic dab of you know how
much I love sativas if you're if you're
a podcast listener and you listen to my
show you know that I love to smoke these
sativas and right now the sour Joker is
doing something to my head I enjoy it
ladies and gentlemen ooh
slip that dab sink in for a minute I get
to brag a little bit last on the last
episode I talked about going to see
Steve Simone at comedy works and let me
tell you it was better than I had
anticipated I drove up to Denver and I
met up with the always lovely always
beautiful miss Jenny Beth she was in
Denver doing some Denver stuff her and I
met up we hung out we get a little
stoned in a parking garage we may have
taken some ridiculous sized ads in a
parking garage before we went to see the
show so we got super dabbed out and we
headed into comedy works but on the way
to comedy works I tweeted I said I am
driving 125 miles to see Steve Simone
talk about Chinese food because Steve
Simone does a bit about Chinese food
we'll get to that in a second
but Steve Simone retweeted it and liked
it and replied with I can't wait to see
you which had me excited because I met
Steve Simone a couple times and we've
hung out but we've never really
interacted a lot he did however send me
a letter and some stickers in the mail a
little while back so he knows I exist
and we have interacted I sent the tweet
he liked it he replied when I got there
they walked me and they're always lovely
always beautiful miss Jenny Beth right
up to the front so I get these amazing
front row seats was my friends at Comedy
Works take great care of me because I
have taken great care of them we go up
front and Steve Simone is in front of
the stage like setting up his microphone
and making sure everything's cool and he
sees me and he goes hey buddy and he
gave me a hug and told me that he loved
me he's like I Love You Man how was the
drive I told him it was cool and he's
like all right man I'll be right back
and he had to disappear he went
backstage the show started and there's
another opener whose name I cannot
recall right now the opener was funny
the main opener kind of the host of the
show he was funny but he told a joke
that was a ripoff
from Joey Diaz if anybody listens to the
podcast frequently you know I'm a comedy
nerd you know I let's do a lot of comedy
and you were never gonna tell a Joey
[ __ ] Diaz joke and it's gonna slide by
me this guy made a joke about being
allergic to peanuts and he said how are
we gonna be Isis if we can't beat up
Pina and that's a [ __ ] Joey Diaz
ripoff he's centered on the podcast I
also heard him sit in a live comedy show
my advice to you is if you're an
up-and-coming comedian don't ruin your
[ __ ] career by stealing somebody
else's joke this dude had me I was
laughing and then he said a Joey Diaz
joke and lost me anyway after that guy
was a comedian by the name of Brant
Tobler Brant Tobler did not steal any
material Brant Tobler was [ __ ]
hilarious the whole show that had me
laughing my ass off being down there in
the front row you get a lot of
interaction so they look you straight in
the face they make sure that you're
laughing because that's the only way
they know if the jokes are going well so
they pay a lot attention to my laughter
I try to laugh and let him know hey bro
you're doing a good job
Brant Tobler was hilarious he told a
couple of really good he tells long
stories his jokes are long his bits are
long and I enjoy that it gets you sucked
in you feel involved and then all of a
sudden there's just this funny this wave
of funny and once you're so invested in
a story these guys can tell you seven or
eight punchlines just after telling you
his story and I was laughing so hard my
face hurt a little bit from Brant
Tobler's jokes but anyway Brant Tobler
finished up he probably did a good 25
the first guy did 15 Brent Tobler
probably did 25 and then my buddy mr.
Steve Simone the host of the good times
with steep Simone podcast came out and
did it was a long show I don't know how
long he did but he just sits on this
little there's a barstool he sits on the
barstool and he just got comfortable it
felt like I was just hanging out with
Steve Simone he was right in my face he
was right in front of me just telling
jokes to me in the front row right there
it was pretty hilarious so I mentioned
earlier that I tweeted about Chinese
food so if you know Steve Simone Steve
Simone can do a lot of material on
Chinese food he can make you laugh for
three hours about Chinese food and I've
heard a lot of it the material I've
heard about Chinese food was always
about him being an adult and getting
Chinese food his the most popular bit is
and I'm not gonna ruin his bit but I'll
give you the premise that when Chinese
food you order Chinese food and it's
mysterious because you don't know what
the [ __ ] on the menu is you're like what
what what does this mean what are these
words and it's all like mystical in the
order and I'm not doing his jokes
justice I'm not trying I don't want it
to be dumb so that if you do hear his ah
you can still laugh at his jokes and
then he talks about when the food
arrives all these containers show up and
all these adults are arguing over who's
is what because nobody even knows what
they ordered and then you look at your
friends and you're like damn that looks
good
it'd serve one ends up trading a scoop
and it's all about being an adult and
how amazing Chinese food is and I know
it sounds crazy that the guy can tell
three hours of jokes I saw him do 45
minutes on Chinese food the last time I
saw him so he talked about Chinese food
for a long time right
Steve Simone did his act this time at
comedy works he probably went for 30 45
minutes and then he sat on a stool and
he pushed his sleeves on his sweater up
and he looked me in the face and he goes
you guys want to hear about the first
time I ate Chinese food and that's not
exactly what he said but that's
basically how how he did it and he
looked me straight in the face and he's
like well here's the first time I had
Chinese food and he proceeded to tell
the story of the how he discovered
Chinese food and going to the restaurant
to get Chinese food and one of the parts
that caught me was he walked in the
restaurant he goes I walked in and
there's a giant mother-effing dragon and
I'm like I'm home yeah it's not exactly
how he tells the bits I'm not steep
Simone but it's [ __ ] hilarious so I
got to he did I feel like he kind of did
that for me he looked me directly in the
face and was like you want to hear about
my first time eat Chinese food as I
tweeted him that and he totally knew
that I was coming to see the Chinese
food joke and they always lovely always
beautiful miss Jenny Beth grabbed my leg
and gave me a little squeeze like hey
maybe this parts for you it was so cool
that we had that little connection with
Steve so Steve did the show and it was
hilarious the show ended and everybody
applauded and I'm up in the front row so
honestly that's the last seat to get out
of the venue like when the show ends
you're stuck because there's all these
people that were behind you now they're
actually the front of the line so
they're escaping the show first but I
was in no hurry because I knew I know
Steve Simone I know him very well he
went to the backstage to go like catch
his breath probably when got a bottle of
water took a break calm down for just a
couple of minutes and then he walked
right out from backstage up to me and he
had a tray of food in his hand he goes
hey buddy I've got a bunch of food if
you guys are hungry and I was like holy
[ __ ] I go I'm a vegetarian and he said
there's cheese pizza like he already
knew he's like there's cheese pizza
buddy don't worry he solved all the
problems he's like pizza pizza is a
back-up plan
I've got pizza for you and so I was like
well [ __ ] yeah and he goes stay right
here and Steve Simone went and wandered
around Comedy Works had to go talk to a
few people you know he was schmoozing it
up and then I I didn't see him for a few
minutes and so I walked down this one
little corridor Jenni and I walked down
the corridor and he goes hey come on and
he was just in this little back area by
himself setting up plates of food and he
was like come on buddy
and I went back
he's like man all this foods available
whatever you want to eat dig in and
people had brought Steve
there was pasta there was male there was
tortillas there were burrito fixins
there was pizza there were little
Tupperware dishes full of stuff that I
didn't even bother to open because there
was so much stuff there I didn't need to
find more food Steve was just grubbin
and munching down and Brandt Tobler came
back and Brandt Tobler Steve Simone
Jenny Beth and myself basically ate
dinner together I know it sounds like I
might be telling a story but we all sat
around and we ate dinner and [ __ ]
about life and it's really funny Steve
Simone does not use any profanity on
stage Steve doesn't cuss at all he's a
pretty good dude he wants to be able to
have he says grown-ups he's 40 years old
and he still calls adult grown-ups cuz
he's a little kid at heart which is what
I love about him and he's so honest and
so genuine and just so grateful for life
but I kind of forgot what the [ __ ] I was
gonna say now grown-ups he doesn't cuss
he wants to have a show for grown-ups
and that you could bring little kids to
he says he wants you want your grandma
to bring your grandson to the show and
have a good time his kind of his theory
and he was doing something and he said
[ __ ] in normal conversation he got food
on his shirt he said [ __ ] and Jenny and
I looked at each other and we got quiet
and Steve goes what and I go we just
heard the principal say [ __ ] and it was
really funny he's like now man I curse
offstage it was just really funny
because one time he did say mother
fudgin I'm like he was on stage and I
thought that was pretty funny too anyway
I huge shout out to my friend Baker
Baker if you're listening to this
podcast thank you huge thank you you
know why thank you much love
always big I love you every day Baker
even though I don't see you frequently
dude Jenni and I talk about you were
like that Baker kid is a good boy so
mint much-loved Baker you know who you
are brother I hope you're hearing this
also huge huge shout out to the best
comedy club on the planet or at least
the best comedy club in Colorado in this
part of the country the only place that
could even rival the place is the Comedy
Store in California a huge shot it's my
friends at Comedy Works in downtown
Denver a big shout out to windy big
shout out to all of the hosts and
hostesses and managers a big shout out
to the ticket people big shout out to
everybody at Comedy Works
I got mad love for everybody there they
show me mad love every time I go there
I'm not a comedian
I'm not a rock star but for some reason
everybody at Comedy Works treats me like
I am a [ __ ] rock star they roll out
the red carpet they take really good
care of me and I appreciate it huge I
made a left out the waitstaff huge
big ups to the waitstaff because I
always keep my drinks coming they know
what I want to drink already much love I
appreciate it and then I can't give a
big enough shout out and a big enough
thank you to Brant Tobler and of course
mr. Steve Simone dude I'm grateful for
you on Steve's podcast he does a
gratitude list I'm grateful to spend a
few moments with one of my favorite
comedians who changed my attitude who
gave me a little different outlook on
life at least maybe for a few days but
it did stick in the back of my head so
much love much respect thank you and of
course to Jenny Beth for being a
beautiful amazing great day I had a fun
time with you thanks for making
everything perfect that night super
great dab session in the car before and
after the show excellent all right you
guys I'm sure you don't wanna hear too
much about the dab session with my
girlfriend in the car let's talk more
about cannabis I want to do something
that may make me sound like a little bit
of an [ __ ] but it will make you a
better cannabis advocate or a cannabis
spokesperson in the future I hear a lot
of people say the wrong terminology when
it comes to cannabis and I I feel like
I'm responsible for teaching you the
correct terms I'm sort of a historian of
sorts I guess when I'm I'm podcasting
I'm an archivist you know I mean we're
marking history and the people that are
involved in cannabis right now our
pioneers we're starting an industry that
is very new and there are a lot of
people that are coming in that are new
that are saying that are just simply
making word mistakes one letter mistakes
and I want to correct you I'm not coming
to be an [ __ ] I want you to sound
like a better smarter grower
smarter advocate because people already
think we're lazy pockets people think
we're stoners people think we're not
paying attention so I think it's a
little important that we take the extra
effort to speak correctly to spell
correctly to have good grammar if you're
gonna put your [ __ ] out there in public
make it presentable so that people don't
think you're a lazy stoner so with all
that being said I've kind of created a
glossary and some things that I want to
go over it's just a short list and and I
I'm not trying to be an [ __ ] about it
it sounds like I'm being a stuck-up jerk
but I really want you to sound smarter
and I feel embarrassed for good growers
when they say the wrong [ __ ] I'm like ah
because ah one one thing can ruin all of
your credibility especially being a
pothead people already don't take you
seriously so if you go bruh too many
times they've already been respect you
you've lost credibility so if you say
try chromes instead of trichomes
you're gonna [ __ ] up your credibility so
that's the first thing we're gonna start
with the word is trichomes those
crystals that grow in your plants those
little mushroom looking things they are
trichomes don't call mrs. their resin
glands you can say resin glands but they
are trichome T RI CH om e trichome not
trichrome not trichome not tri chromes
but just a trichome okay all right
that's our first glossary word of the
day you see how easy it's gonna be there
are a few people right now they just
went oh [ __ ] I've been saying that wrong
for so long Thank You Rasta Jeff so the
word is trichome try to comb your hair
try comb but don't put the bee in there
there's no bee it's not a try comb but
it's a try comb all right try comb all
right that was easy enough I don't feel
so bad now the next one you guys this
bugs the [ __ ] out of me for some reason
quit saying CBDs it's not plural CBD is
not pluralized
they say I want a weed with a lot of CB
beads bro come on you want cannabis with
CBD high in CBD do you have you and this
is my at my comparison do you ever ask
for a glass of water 'z no matter how
much water is in your glass it's still
just water it's not plural waters maybe
if you gathered water from two sources
and mixed them you might have waters but
as far as I'm concerned this bottle of
water right here is water not waters I
don't want waters I would like a water
or some water
so let's not pluralizing CBD it just
sounds wonky to me I don't think it's
correct its CBD you know there's only
one CBB there are different cannabinoids
there are different terpenoids but there
is only one CBD all right that's my
story I'm sticking with it next
this one's directed at somebody
specifically and I'm sorry I must
correct you because every time I hear
you say I go goddamnit I love you every
day every time I hear your voice I'm
proud that you're doing what you do but
but it bugs the [ __ ] out of me when
people call a slab of shatter or some
hash they call it dab I want to buy some
dab no please don't say that a dab is
the thing that is on the tip of your
dabber the dab is the part you're
consuming you don't buy dab you may buy
a bath if somebody's got a dabber
they're gonna put a dab on it you may
buy a DAB but you don't buy dab you
don't you don't I'm sorry you know who
I'm talkin soon you're going [ __ ] Rasta
Jeff I already know you are but I still
love you I still love your podcast
just-just I'm not gonna call you I just
quit quit saying dad it's DAB's
you've got some concentrate ah you are
taking a DAB you're going to buy some
dabs maybe but it just bugs me when you
say I'm going to buy dab all right I
kind of feel like an [ __ ] for my
Corrections but some people are gonna
sound like better people just for me
helping you out a little bit I kind of
feel like it's my duty
so to recap that without feeling like a
jerk I am going to buy some concentrate
or I am going to buy some hash I'm going
to buy a slab and then I will take a dab
of my shatter I have got some dabs on my
shirt because I dropped some I've got a
dab stuck to the table that stuff works
but I don't have dabs stuck to my shirt
that just sounds weird I'm not mad at
you I just want you to sound better
trying to help you out all right let's
move forward and if I offended you I'm
sorry
send me hate mail to grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I'll read it and
I'll reply but I apologize in advance if
that sounded rude I felt kind of rude
doing it but honestly I just want you to
sound better I want everybody to be
better I'm trying to lift you up alright
I just looked up at the clock and it is
709 so that means we got to start
heating the nail because at 7:10 we're
gonna pick us a big old fat dab that's
right
slowly heat the nail gotta put some pain
of the torch is not enough butane of the
torch to make fire because this is not
professional podcasting right here we're
filling a torch with butane I'm just
using cheap butane and my elevat torch
now we're still gonna make it we're
gonna be on time 4 7 10 don't worry
even it up let's get hot I'm still using
the the thermo banger on the Hitman
hammerhead
rig and I've got the bubble cap right
here I'm actually using a custom a red
yellow and green pencil from tater glass
it was a gift from the always lovely
always beautiful Jenny Beth thank you
for the gift this nail is just about hot
enough it's got to cool down for just a
couple of seconds it is now 7:10 I'm
gonna take a 7/10 dab I hope you guys
are dabbing with me send me an email or
a tweet let me know what you're smoking
here we go cheers happy 7/10 everybody
all right ladies and gentlemen I've got
a nice let's work our way into some
emails now I've got a big stack of
emails right here I'm just gonna go
through and randomly pull out an email
out of this stack and I'm not even doing
any sort of selection I just want to
pull out this one right here and it says
let me get right for my face I'm making
sure they want me to or not want me to
say their name it doesn't give me
indication so I'm not going to say your
name you know who you are thanks for the
email if you'd like to send me an email
let's go from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to answer your questions on
the podcast this email goes like this hi
raasta Jeff hey you have talked about
breeding on the podcast but what about
just making seeds of your favorite
strain I have slowly collected a lot of
genetics and I'm having to keep cutting
clones just to keep them around I love
to be able to make seeds and then put
them away while I experiment while I
experiment with new strains
for example I just bought a five pack of
jelly bean and have two females and one
male right now can i pollinate just one
section of one of the females to make
some seeds for later
thanks for the best cannabis podcast out
there and then he signs his name dude
you are welcome for the best cannabis
podcast out there thanks for the huge
compliment I don't know that I'm the
best but since you say so that means
it's real man thank you also he'd shut
it to all the other cannabis podcasts
out there I listen to a lot of them and
I do appreciate them so to hear
you think I'm the best means a lot to me
that and that's serious I'm not even
joking so thanks let's get to the heart
of this email I love that you're working
with Jilly bean Jilly bean is so much
fun to work with uh you said you have
got two females and one male I hope I
hope you have got a candy store fee no
and an orange fee no there are good
chances of that if you pop five seeds
and you've you've got that mini if
you've got three around once a boy and
you've got two girls oh you'd be so
lucky to have the candy store in the
orange Fino the candy store one kind of
it smells like the candy store in the
mall is the best way to describe it you
know how some of the candy when you bite
into it it's got that real sweet but you
could taste it's still powdery and it's
like and it smells like jelly beans or
jelly I said jelly beans that's funny it
smells like jelly beans ah that's the
candy store fee no the orange feet Oh
smells like a glass of orange juice just
straight-up
orange juice with maybe like another
hint of like lemon or pineapple or
something but those are the two fee nose
that are well-known and if you've got
one of those you're a lucky dude if
you've got each of those you're super
lucky ah now you're male I'm not gonna
get too picky on male selection cuz
you've only got one but we do know that
it's a jelly bean so yes there is
nothing stopping you from putting that
male plant in with those two females and
letting him put pollen so you said ah
you said for example I just bought a
five pack can i pollinate just one
section of the females yes but that's a
pain in the ass I'm not getting pollen
on the other parts of the plant will be
a challenge what I would do is just put
I would put the male in the room about
14 days ahead and then I would put the
girl in there I would honestly if you
can keep them separate that's best
flower the male about 14 days ahead put
the girls in there if the girls about 21
days into flower that means if the boys
are gonna be about 35 days into flower
at that point Harry the boy into there
and shake it all over the girls now
those girls are totally pollinated one
thing you can do you can keep that boy
separate flower him out around day 14
you'll see him start dropping pollen
around day 20 to 25 to 30 he'll really
be dump it go in there with a jar or
some sort of receptacle and gather that
pollen then put it into a container
you want to get before you put into a
container you need to get all of the
male flowers out the male flowers hold
moisture moisture destroys pollen you
have to get all of the moisture out of
this pollen if you want it to be viable
if you want to store it and keep it you
need to get all of the moisture out our
friend Tony mr. toad taught us a long
time ago about using silica packets to
take the moisture out so some silica
packets in your container are always a
good idea to get the moisture out of
your pollen you can use a screen on top
of a jar you put the screen over the jar
I've seen people use a pantyhose you
stretch it real tight you just rub with
a credit card rub the pollen through the
screen and the male flowers gather up on
the top and you just scrape those right
off and discard them get all the male
flowers out of there or you can just
shake that pollen into something like a
magazine or a bowl and you can use a
paintbrush and go in the other room and
just paint a couple of branches with
that pollen it's really hard to control
pollen because it if you sneeze you just
[ __ ] everything up and everything's
flying around the whole room so be
really careful with the pollen you just
need to get it from the plant to the
female and apply it carefully you can do
with a q-tip you can do with a
paintbrush I just do it open pollination
style I let the male do his magic to the
girls just exactly how it's supposed to
they drop pollen I give them a good
shake the girls receive the pollen the
whole plant is seated I know maybe you
don't want to pollinate your whole crop
the whole room but that's an easy way to
make plenty of seeds honestly here's
something that I just recently did this
works this is true I ran my normal
breeding program I put some Capleton I
talked about it on the podcast I made
more seeds of the Firefly I made more
morning dew seeds but I also wanted to
make some new crosses and I wanted to
make some stuff that was just for me I
wanted to make platinum tangi to arise I
wanted to make an indention to arise
I took a candid enchilada platinum tan
gene there were a couple others they
were in a beer cup those Red Solo cups
that you get at a party for the keg I
put enough soil in there to fill that up
I put a little plant a little clone in
there and I let it grow is probably six
or eight inches tall and then I put it
into the breeding chamber to flower with
all the other big girls and I got pollen
on it just like I did all the big girls
and those plants were maybe a foot tall
maybe 10 to 12 inches tall out of the
pot by the time they were finished I
just took one bamboo stick and put it in
there and they stayed up real light I
had to lean him up against [ __ ] to keep
him upright because they got
top-heavy but they stayed up they
survived they made it all the way
through the cycle I harvested him I got
between 30 and 50 seeds from each plant
it was in a beer cup so you need enough
light to breed a 400 watt light doesn't
do it for me when I'm breathing I don't
feel like the seeds are robust enough
and he don't get enough a 600 did it a
thousand watt light is really what I
like for breeding I feel like you need
that power of that much light to get
yourself enough seeds and viable seeds
so put just one light worth of small
plants just bedroom for a little while
to where they're tiny put one light in
there of girls and one male in there and
just let him go and you will make plenty
of seeds for yourself but like I said if
you just want to pollinate one section
gather that pollen into a container get
a paintbrush dip it into the pollen just
like you're gonna do if you're gonna
paint and then paint that right onto the
pollen all right onto the plant right
onto the little the thickest most robust
pistol wet hairs you can find those are
that's where you want to put it just you
want those thick robust hairs that are
just they're just ready those are the
pistols you guys that is something we
should probably have gone over in the
glossary quits and hairs those are pears
those are pistol at hairs those are
those are known as pistols what their
job is is to collect the pollen they
collect the pollen and they slide the
pollen right down that and then they
continue on we don't need to talk about
what happens after that but anyway you
can tell that the plan has been
pollinated because those pistol it hairs
will turn brown and start crinkling up
over the next few days they'll start
crinkling up and turn it in and they'll
all be brown and crunchy that's a good
indicator that that section of the plant
has been pollinated um if you want to
pollinate one small section of the plant
if if you're gonna take pollen into a
room and you only want one plant
receiving pollen you can spray water on
the rest of the garden and hopefully
those plants will not be able to receive
pollen water deactivates pollen that's
why I'm so stressful about getting all
the male flowers and using a silica pack
in your pollen storage so spray the rest
of the plants take your male pollen in
there and paintbrush what you need to
and then spray the rest of the plant
down also if you feel like that's
necessary then spray yourself down to
deactivate off the pollen because you
don't want to take the pollen back into
the grow later or to somebody else's
grow or anything like that
so the simple answer is yes you can make
a bunch of seeds for yourself so that
you don't have to keep clones around if
you're using the male and the female of
the same strain you may be making f2 or
f3 or maybe even f4 or five of the
strain that you have purchased it just
depends on what a finial generation the
breeder you purchased it from has taken
it to I know DJ short likes to breed
things all the way up to like f4 or five
before he releases them so it doesn't
leave a lot of variation for you
breeding it to the F six or seven or
whatever it's going to which is gonna be
actually be a good thing for you there
are some breeders like gage green and
I'm not calling anybody out this is just
how they work I'm not saying gage sucks
or anything but gage green is known for
releasing f1 hybrids or poly hybrids so
when you breed those your f your he's
given you F ones you're going to make f2
if you take a male and a female of the
same seed stock and you cross them those
you are now making an f2 finial
generation kind of it depends on how the
first ones were bred but what for our
example here you're making it your F
doing your varietal ah so when you make
that f2 a lot of times the f2 s are
better than the F ones but you're gonna
see variants you're gonna see something
that looks like Grandma something look
looks like grandpa and they'll be on
both sides of the trait chart so how can
I explain this a little better let's say
you've got a strain like I'm just gonna
invent something so you've got white
widow crossed to grateful dog which is
actually capable too and then on the
other side you've got a rise or a little
say golden go across the Daybreaker
which is a ride if you cross the arise
and the Capleton you will see traits of
all four of the grandparents you'll see
white widow grateful dog golden go and
daybreak or representations in there but
sometimes that's a good thing
because some of those plants will
outperform the original parents you will
have created more robust faster growing
more resinous more desirable plants
you'll find better progeny and I think
the term for that is transgressive
segregation if anybody wants to google
and tell me if I'm right or wrong I
think the term transgressive segregation
is gonna have something about better
performing or extreme or turbo or
something like that something I'll say
turbo but it's gonna be something like
that that indicates transgressive
segregation and that I'm just indicating
that it outperform
it's parents is what I mean by the
transgressive segregation term here but
anyway you'll be making the next finial
generation which is which is always fun
too because you'll either be ah you'll
be stabilizing it or you'll be kind of
you'll find one that's way different
that you like better you'll have a lot
of fun with that and then you'll have
different phenotypes of seeds that you
created and this whole problem of having
to keep a whole bunch of strains around
is only going to compound itself once
you start making seeds trust me on that
that's how you get into plant hoarding
that's how you end up buying a warehouse
that's how you end up just going big and
ended up as a breeder and having tons of
[ __ ] good luck
also here's something that we should
talk about timing you're talking about
breeding timing is crucial when you're
breeding if you want to make seeds if
you want to make a lot of seeds if you
want to make it worth your time timing
is very important it's a good idea to
have the mail a little bit ahead of the
females if you've got the male and the
female if you start them flowering at
the same exact time next to each other
you'll get plenty of seeds if you want a
lot of seeds I suggest you let the male
flower get a fly flying in my face sorry
look I suggest you let the male flower
start him off 10 to 14 days early get
him flowering keep him away from the
girls then put the girls in the flower
ten to fourteen days after that uh you
will see the male starting to dump
pollen around day a fourteen Paula start
coming out pollen will really start
coming out of around day 25 around 8:30
your girl plants are going to want
pollen around day kind of depending on
the strain but around day 23 through 32
ish maybe 25 through 32 ish depending on
the strain and one thing I've noticed if
I'm breeding for Firefly I need to put
the lemon skunk plant into the flowering
room much earlier because it needs to
develop those tall buds and started
getting a lot of pistols on those tall
buds if I pollinate it too soon it quits
growing and I don't give it enough bud
sites to actually receive enough pollen
to make it worth of [ __ ] to breed too so
I put the lemon skunk plant in there a
little bit earlier then about four or
five days later I'll put Capleton in
there and then a few days later I will
put whatever Kalonji cush in there and
then I will pollinate them all at the
same time because they will all have
gotten to the right point is basically
what that is so timing is very crucial
when you're trying to breed
like I said if you just want to make a
few seeds for yourself put them in there
on the same day let it all happen
naturally or set that male plant in
another room collect the pollen you can
just set it on a ceramic plate or on a
mirror or you could just tap it every
couple of days and get some pollen out
of it until you've got enough to do what
you think you need to do it does not
take a lot of pollen to make plenty of
seeds you can make a lot of seeds with
one male plant just for a reference
point I'm not sure how much I should
talk about this but a plant in a beer
cup I can pull thirty to fifty seeds
from if done properly
oh also I should mention I forgot to
mention this I will pollinate twice
sometimes I'll hit the plants one time
and then I'll give them three to five
days and I will go back and read
pollinate just to make sure that I got
them sufficiently that's something I
forgot to mention I will go back now
what was I saying okay I can get about
thirty to fifty seeds from a plant in a
beer cup in a three gallon pot a plant
that I grow about a foot maybe two feet
tall before I flower it it ends up about
three three and a half feet tall usually
depending on the strain you guys I will
get five hundred to a thousand seeds out
of a plant like that so you only have if
you're making seeds for yourself you
only have to do that once and then
you've got a thousand seeds to work with
and that should last you a long time
unless you're running huge numbers which
is ridiculous but imagine how many
plants under that you can fit nine of
those three gallon pots under a light
comfortably maybe 12 if you cram them in
there maybe 16 if you really [ __ ]
force them in but I don't like to do
that I usually do about nine three
gallon pots and then or maybe nine five
gallon pots and then just around the
outer edge there I do a couple of cups
just for experiments so no making
commercial seed that's how that's how
that works per a thousand watt light I
got about nine plants probably get 500
seeds on average a thousand the
redheaded stranger will give me a
thousand seeds that plant just makes a
bunch of heads Kalonji push on the other
hand I'll get closer to 500 just kind of
depends on on the strain anyway I don't
know how much of that I should be
talking about so don't tell anybody I
hope I answered your question about
making seeds for yourself it is not as
hard or as scary as it sounds you guys
people get really intimidated when it
comes to male plants and breeding and
stuff like that but it's nature it's
really easy to do the hardest part is
not pollinating stuff on accident and
something super important to think about
is don't go to the gross
or don't go to the dispensary don't go
around any of your friends that grow
don't go to anybody's grow if you work
at a grouse stay the [ __ ] away from
there until you have completely showered
changed your clothes gotten totally wet
because you need to deactivate all of
that pollen be careful there'll be that
guy that goes and pollinates everybody's
garden on accident all right you guys
haven't known for 30 just over 31
minutes here and I haven't taken much of
a break or a drink or anything I did
take a dab in the middle of the show but
I think it's time start wrapping up the
podcast I want to thank everybody for
listening to another episode I hope you
enjoyed everything I said even if I had
to correct you on something don't take
it personally even if it was personal at
you I want you to be a better person
hey guys thanks for listening if you
learn anything from the show don't
forget about patreon patreon is a great
way to say thank you visit patreon.com
slash grow from your heart for more
information also make sure you check out
the podcast it is available on iTunes
stitcher and now about 75 videos are
currently available on YouTube I will be
posting more as time goes on I would
love it if you find me on YouTube just
search for the government heart podcast
give us a follow there also if you want
your email read on a future episode send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I would love to hear your
questions you just saw how I did it I
had a random stack of emails
there's about 12 them in the pile a
shuffle through and I pull out the
seventh one is what I think I did so I
read the seventh email in the pile just
totally random no favoritism or anything
like that I'd love it if you send me an
email once again girl from your heart at
hotmail.com also don't forget to stalk
me on all of the social media you can
find me on twitter it's at g f YH
podcast on facebook simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast and not
Instagram you guys I am approaching
15,000 followers on Instagram I used the
name of my seed company of course I'm a
seed breeder I've got a seam line of
Eila below check me out on instagram
it's i reaiiy rie genetics I re
underscore genetics ladies and gentlemen
Irene Durst or genetics I RIE
underscore G E and E t ICS I read
genetics on Instagram please do check me
out I would love it if you give me a
following post a lot of great cannabis
pictures there there is a shot of the
black cherry it was grown at Three
Rivers the three rivers grow in Pueblo
West and it has got about 2,200 lights
which is most likes I've ever gotten on
a photo I would love it if you take a
look at it click like you might love it
also ladies and gentlemen bet dad is
still ringing in my brain I think it's
time for me to get a drink in some food
ladies and gentlemen the beautiful dab
in granny fell down some stairs recently
and she hurt her foot really bad she's
got to bust it up anyway she [ __ ] her
[ __ ] up real good uh and we need to give
her all the love we can send to her so
whatever you believe in whatever you
think about sin love and light too dad
granny she's got a busted ankle ankle
toes foot region her ankle and foot is
in a cast and her toes are sticking out
of the cast and it looks like a package
of Vienna sausages
she's pretty swollen up she's pretty
purple she's gonna be okay but she needs
some love some white jeans or spirits
lifted she can only dab so hard
let's all send a huge gigantic shout out
to the dam and granny and until next
time take a fat dam and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
gathered in the masses just like witches
at black masses mine's a lot destruction
[Music]
Deb's construction in the fields of
bodies burn
she keeps turning
[Music]
brainwash my Heinz
now in darkness world stops turning
[Music]
ashes where the body's burning no more
war pigs of the power and God has struck
the hour day of judgment God is calling
the war piece crawling
[Music]
laughing spreads his wings
you