yo what a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
and it's Thursday so that means it's
time for another throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast before I get into the block of
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any promotions any contests or any
giveaways those have all expired there
are currently no contest no promotions
no advertising or no giveaways also let
me update all of the social media if you
want to find me on Twitter you can find
me at G f YH podcast on Twitter on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast and if you'd like to
send me an email
it's drove from your heart at
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen I hope
you enjoyed these chunks of old episodes
so here we go to throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 90 to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower the
pure professional grower if you're an
old-school smoker or here a pen d
warrant dad kid if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host they call me Rasta Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always I
want to send a huge thank you shout out
to the mystic roots band so let me play
their music on the show
big thanks to Kat and the entire turn
down that music a little bit you guys
our friend Jesse came over and we did
recorded for almost two hours
we had to stop for a second and fix the
headphone amplifier it tried to crap out
on us but we got everything back on
track so let's do a quick ad and then we
will get on to the show you guys this
podcast is brought to you by my good
friends at high grow indoor growing
supplies hi girl indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street or check out the Pueblo location
on 618 East 4th Street and beautiful
Pueblo Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies you
guys are good friend Jesse works at hi
girl he's the manager there his wife is
probably who you'll bump into either
Bernadette or LaDonna is most likely who
you're gonna see when you go in there
they're a couple other folks that work
there but it's most of the time it's
Jesse burn or LaDonna so when you go in
there you're shopping with my friends
these are really cool people there are
members of the community they're not
just sales folks with a store they're
there to help you out so make sure you
support our friends at Highgrove indoor
growing supplies and when you are
checking out at high grow indoor growing
supplies make sure you let them know you
listen to the girl from your heart
podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase that'll save you a few bucks we
all know that money is expensive
alright guys I've been rambling long
enough I'm gonna let this music fade out
and we will be right back with our good
friend Jesse alright guys I am back and
sitting across the table from me is our
good buddy Jesse how you doing today bro
pretty
thanks for coming I know you've been a
busy man so it's always good having you
it's a grower season season so you guys
I just thrown the microphones real quick
we were gonna do a podcast and then
Jesse mentioned something and I was like
I'm gonna hit record Jesse just said if
you were using general organics to not
adjust the pH when you're done I
completely agree with that then what did
you say to use to adjust the pH if you
had to oh nothing I was saying that it's
built into the formula the the CA mag
plus or calculus that it is they have
it's a pH buffer I'm not exactly sure on
the entire science of it but I do know
for a fact that uh if you try to pH it
it will mess your [ __ ] up you have some
funky looking plants right well because
if you're using organics it's already
it's organic and if you go and pour
acids in there that we're using I think
it's a phosphoric acid which is the pH
down I don't remember exactly what it is
yeah it's gonna go there and spirit
destroying all of your organics and your
micro life all right well I just wanted
to get that on recording guys since we
were talking about it sometimes the best
[ __ ] comes out before I turn on the
microphone so he's filling damn I wasted
some time there so I just want to put on
the mics and get that on there Jesse
welcome to the show my friend thanks for
coming I really appreciate having you
bro thanks for having me all right I'm
all choked up from some dads let's get
official I invited Jesse over to do a
podcast and my topic was our friend John
Rossum on periscope asked if he can grow
his bag seeds the short answer is hell
yes you can grow your bag seeds we've
got a really long answer also one thing
I want to mention though a lot of the
older cats that I try to pitch my seeds
to are flabbergasted and blown away by
the price of a 10 pack of seeds lately a
10 pack of seeds will go anyway depends
on the breeder anywhere from fifty to a
hundred bucks for a ten pack of good
regular or feminized 180 now for a 10
pack of seeds yes okay yeah some of
these higher known companies are
definitely able to get more money 150 to
200 bucks for a pack of seeds a lot of
people are gonna say what the hell and
then some of these old guys they say but
dude I've got a big baggy of seeds in my
closet from when I used to smoke pot and
sift it out on a record
ever on an album cover those seeds are
great I recommend you grow those but do
not try to sell those the reason they
aren't sellable the reason that the
seeds us breeders are selling and
pushing and promoting the reason they
cost more money is because we know what
the parents are we know what's gonna
come from those seeds we've done time
selecting the male and female to produce
a seed line that has probably gone
several years in testing and development
to figure out what we want know Herms
high-quality yeah consistency is
something I really know her a lot of
quality good resin production good
flowering time there are some plants
when you get them I've worked strains
down from 90-day flowering times by
breeding it into other things we've cut
it down by breeding several times we've
brought it to sixty days and it's still
pretty much the same plant all we've
done is breed it to shorter flowering
plants to put it to the flow grow the
seeds that come from that out find the
one that's a lot like the original male
or female whichever we were trying to do
and then put that back to flow his flow
is a quick plant so we just print seems
to flow and sped it up a little bit it
passes on traits really well - yes she
does
so if you guys were looking to start a
breeding project get a Colorado flow and
play with her because that's a fun one
to breed with but what I'm getting at is
those bagged seeds that these older cats
or maybe you younger cats have the
reason those aren't marketable and
sellable is because you don't know the
parents you don't know the genetic
heritage of them so they are not a
marketable seed but you can definitely
give them away
you can definitely grow the [ __ ] out of
them grow your bag seed you can have
hermaphrodites you guys you could have a
bunch of males you can have shitty-ass
ragweed but you could you very well
could have yeah I see looking good
Jesse's getting excited over here dog
I'm stoned I can barely [ __ ] yeah
exactly the stray dog came from Cham dog
was [ __ ] bag seed chem dog is known
as one of the strongest strains on earth
it's been on the cover of High Times
Magazine three or four times is the
single strongest strain on earth but
also that was old back seed when stain
strains weren't you know that's a really
deep discussion yes
you know yeah we could get way into the
chemical resin just a bunch of junk
strains back then you know I mean I'm
sure there was but you know it's with
chances are if somebody grew if you
bought that bag of weed and it had a
seed and their chances are it was decent
we yeah the only thing is we don't know
what it was it was a lot of people back
in the day don't even know what the girl
plant they got or what the buds they got
were they want to say this is like
Acapulco gold or something but it was
just whatever that dude said it was it
was before we really knew and cared a
lot about genetics yeah yeah and then
also on things you could get you could
even get Mexican autoflowering you never
know and some people want those Mexican
autoflowering plans some people would
love to have that some people people
message me all the time asking when I'm
gonna make OTO flowers
this wasn't that's that's my answer this
was never supposed to be about my brand
or my company but I read genetics will
never make auto flowering plants I don't
believe in the use of auto flowering I'm
actually straying far away from
feminized seeds because I like the males
in the population I think that we need
male plants and feminized seeds they
don't provide can't make it enough
feminized seeds to gallery' do yeah they
want so many of them damn things so
Jesse hit the head hit that nail right
on the head when he said you could have
the next chem dog chem dog came from
bagsied two dudes sold the guy a bag of
weed on a Grateful Dead parking lot in
95 I think it was chem dog found seeds
in that weed and he grew that [ __ ] and
out of one of those seeds and you guys
go google the legend of chem dog in the
13 beans if you listen to this podcast
and you want to be deep into the
cannabis culture and you want to know
some heritage google chem dog in the
legend of the 13 beans and also I got to
give a big shout out to the Adam Dunn
show a podcast they do an entire episode
where Kim dog actually calls in and they
discuss where this dream came from a lot
of the people that were in the chain of
that and everything and they all call
these people are on the old school
forums if any of the listeners are forum
junkies you know if they already know
the story
well I'm gonna write this down one day
we're gonna have to talk about og
and if OD means overgrow or not I want
to get a few older drillers on here and
see what I just said oh gee you meant
overgrowth the website overgrown calm it
was a website that we used to frequent
and talk about drunk cannabis some cool
was on there all the cool breeders were
on there everyone and there's uh there's
a theory that the OG Kush came from
overgrow but also people think it's the
Original Gangster I've also heard it
ocean grown we'll talk about that on
this show in the future we need a few
more
oh geez on the show to come talk with us
on that alright so grow out those bags
seeds because you can have chem dog you
guys you could also have junk you could
totally have junk there's a little pet
peeve don't sell clothes a junk yeah in
Colorado don't do that
yeah grow it out if you don't sell your
junky seeds from your junkie clones it's
really rude it is rude it's
disrespectful to your customers it's
disrespectful to your patients it's
disrespectful to the plant itself it's
disrespectful to the future of cannabis
yeah if you grow a plant and you take
clones of it don't give those clones out
until you have flowered the damn plant
and you verified that it's something
worthwhile there are so many strains
available grow something worthwhile if
it's not as a breeder it is so hard to
breathe something and then grow 100
seeds and realize that you have just
created [ __ ] hemp I think this train
doesn't do us any good I've got six
thousand seeds of it and all I'm going
to do is feed them to some birds because
I don't want anybody growing this I've
got one CrossFit there's a lemon cush
idea and dude it grew the fattest chunky
ax stall estates they were bigger than
my arms they didn't have any flavor or
any resin just grew the biggest hemp
ever is terrible so if you know I have
horrible Herman problems than all my own
drives me nuts
and your breeding projects yeah oh yeah
because that's so much of its involved
with Kim dog so yeah Kim does have a
tendency to Herman there see so you guys
got to find if you're gonna breed with
Kim dog make sure you uh bat cross or
out cross that hermie trait go find a
solid progeny to sell a progeny from
your F wands and/or
does yeah I'm just going ahead of myself
here all right so sometimes it's hard to
guess what pollinated the seeded buds
that you've got but you know that that
female makes quality medicine so maybe
the donor was a male in the room maybe
something harmed but it's probably just
a stress seed it's usually a light leak
or something like that is what's causing
these bags seeing a lot of overdue
regular watering
yes surprises surprises on the plants
definitely if you get them too hot and
let them get too dry they'll start
throwing out seeds a seed is the plant's
response of oh [ __ ]
the plant goes you know what I think I'm
gonna die here soon and it's only only
it's like a horny person it just wants
to reproduce that's the plan yeah just
to reproduce the resin is there to
protect the plant so that it can
reproduce the pistils which everybody
calls hairs those are there to collect
pollen so that it can reproduce
everything is all about these plants
reproducing so if you piss off a plant
it will try to make a seed as a reaction
it just wants to make sure that it
continues it doesn't want to be wiped
out the main job in life yeah that is
its job that's its purpose is to
reproduce and continue tricking it in
many ways so be respectful
yeah I think I had a list of which
strains were they are Gorilla Glue
number four and seven all the Gorilla
Glue strains were actually bagsied
accidental paulo nations that created
seeds that Josey Wales shout-out to
Josey Wales a grower slash breeder or
good accident
we're glad that happened thanks for
popping those beans golden goat one of
Colorado's most popular strains ever one
of my most popular strains for my
growing my photography you guys a lot of
people give me credit for breeding
golden goat I'm gonna say right now I
did not breed the golden go golden goat
was bred by a guy known as mr. dank in
Topeka Kansas yep and it was an accident
that was not meant to happen Jesse's
headphones are cutting out here I do my
cool I got you all right guys I think
we're back I think we recorded all the
first part - I'm pretty sure we're using
the zoom h6 handy recorder today and I'm
pretty sure I recorded that first part
so better take a quick break
livewire solutions a chayo for 4-channel
stereo headphone amplifier it's gonna
get a hammer put to it pretty soon here
because it just pisses me off though I
think we're on golden goat
I was saying that I did not breed the
golden go right that was mr. ding mr.
dink Redman Kansas of all places I did
however get a clone of it and I thought
when I first started breeding I thought
it Topeka Kansas of all damn places I
almost skipped right over that is the
that's probably the coolest town in
Kansas I'm gonna vote for Lawrence
[Music]
things in Lawrence Kansas that I can't
even talk about my disgust he boned uh
and that there's an army based outside
of there yeah he got t-bone there so we
ended up spending like a day and a half
in Lawrence Kansas and it's not the
Kansas I'm used to that's the treasure
there's a club every 30 seconds yes look
at the bar you know it's the liberal
stronghold it definitely is
kayuu Topeka is pretty close to all
right yeah whoo Topeka we went to
Wichita we went all over the place I
lived in Lawrence for a little while so
I had a good time there but the golden
goat I got a hold of a clone of it um my
good friend Josh a long time ago gave me
a clone of that the Hawaiian guy I
called the Hawaiian guy I call them
pineapple Express is what I used to call
him that dude in the long-ass time so
pineapple express brought me a clone of
the golden goat and when I first started
breeding one of my ideas was I felt bad
that in Colorado we had all of the elite
genetics and everybody and like I'm a
compassionate guy they were like how do
I get these clones I want clones I was
like I can't get you clones of these
elite cuts but I will make seeds of them
so my idea was to make seeds of the
golden goat just by reversing it so I
did put seeds of the golden goat out I'm
the one that made the s-1 feminized
golden goat seeds as far as I know I'm
the only one that has done that I put
about 5,000 of those seeds there are the
only people that are bred with it
you and I think Scott's done something
with it I've seen gage make one strain
what's golden yeah and then uh Holly
[ __ ] what's this seed company named Ali
Chi no [ __ ] there's a dude out of San
Francisco yeah Ali G her algae that's
what it is okay
I'm gonna have to kind of phonetically
but he's uh he's bred a couple strains
was going go cool it's a great it's a
great plan but it was like we're talking
about it was from a bag seed it was an
accident
that's a Colorado takes pretty much all
the credit for that but yeah an exam is
definitely a local string that's partly
my fault and it's a pain in the ass to
keep it yeah that's it's a pain in the
ass to keep a mother you have to take
clones from that golden goat often got
one hold on to it I guarantee in a few
more years that'll be it's a lot of
strains are getting harder to find it's
a truly good original you know the
old-school blueberry show yeah show me a
good Kim for give me a p90 one clone
yeah all right I'm gonna give you a
shout-out right quick jesse is actually
the moderator and he's the one that
started the what's the name of the
Facebook group uh Colorado dope cannabis
growers yeah so you guys joined Jesse's
Facebook group if you're serious um I
will troll you a little bit I hope you
have a little bit of thick skin I hope
you're not an Internet vagina because
I'm a troll and I'm gonna get you but
it's a fun group come join us
we they help you learn about cannabis in
a fun positive way we will clear up all
the rumors and myths if you have a
question
come join the group if you're a cannabis
grower or if you're curious about
cannabis we love teaching you we love
sharing them it's another avenue to do
that and its really if you're a total
noob you know not to be a dick but
that's it there are better groups to
find this you know this group is
comprised of growers only so you know
that's don't be shy you guys if you yeah
I mean or hit me up on Facebook or Jesse
directly and we will answer your
questions
may take a little bit longer he doesn't
carry the iPhone like I do he's not
attached to it like I am but I've
usually got the phone in my pocket when
I'm working at the spot I've got the
phone turned off because there's no
service back there anyway yeah yeah
services honey and girl rooms yeah dude
our facility is like a [ __ ] bomb
shelter I can look back there for six
months try to turn a radio on in the
middle of it when all the lights are on
although you get kavita's I don't know
if they still do you know we're way off
topic here but in Denver you guys this
is something that I recently heard and
or read about and had a conversation
with multiple people about in Denver
they're driving around ok if you're
running old school magnetic ballasts I'm
not sure if the new digital's will do it
but the old school magnetics if you're
running enough of those they put off an
AM frequency and if you take an AM radio
in that room you have it tuned into the
station it's working you can hear it if
you walk near those ballasts it will cut
out and make a weird humming noise it's
at a specific frequent frequency - yeah
and it's uh I've tried it on a couple of
places I know of it makes a hum and some
some like dashes and beeps it definitely
puts off a unique signal ok yeah the
Denver Police are using an ultra
sensitive radio pickup I'm not probably
a strong antenna is what I guess they're
using driving around through
neighborhoods and when they get that
they're driving back bio with infrared
cameras and now they're checking your
lights yeah and so I'm all over well
once they've done that they're going
back home or back to the station and
checking to see if you're a medical
marijuana caregiver so that you've got
permission to have all these lights or
since in the state of Colorado we're
only supposed to have six plants if
you've got all that light you're
supposed to be registered as a grower if
you're not they go and knock on your
door and ask what's going on yeah so in
Denver be careful for the cops or for
the guys using magnetic ballasts well
yeah come by some nanos from me or
Denver store there you go on Beech
Street yes ask for
Brandon or Cassandra Cassandra that's
the chick you'll see she's cool [ __ ] is
that the Denver store yeah tarah store
I've never been to the Denver store so I
may have to drop in there just go wander
around and not even tell them who I am
and just walk around and look at the
store I like to do that when they don't
know who I am all right so we're getting
we're getting high and getting off-topic
here but we've had a few dabs so that's
okay what else was I gonna say I'm gonna
be controversial here I cannot prove
this but it is my theory that the Girl
Scout cookies is probably a [ __ ] and
it was an accident and it's bagsied I
don't think they bred that on purpose
it's bred with it
yeah there's a reason I haven't released
any of my stuff yet unless I have very
high standards and I haven't been able
to achieve them yet but uh Girl Scout
cookies in my opinion as a term it does
not breach table I've crossed it too it
is really neat breeder it is a really
neat plant to breed with [ __ ] yeah but
it produces hermaphrodites I put it to
the Grateful dog and you would not
believe what it put out I'll show you a
little bit after we record here I've
seen some pictures I know a couple other
people that have grown that yeah yeah no
one's it's that's maybe not grateful dog
I'm thinking of the other one you know
after breeding with it and growing and
seeing a couple different hybrids of it
you know you can recognize it real quick
for sure um but yeah all right so while
we're talking about herm seeds seeds
about bagged seeds if you're gonna go
bag seeds already said that right you
gotta be careful for hermaphrodites when
you're drawing these bag seeds treat it
just like a normal seed during veg
you're not gonna know what the parents
are so you're gonna have to pay a lot of
attention to it during flower when you
start flowering you have to look every
single day for hermaphrodite flowers on
these plants oh yeah every day sometimes
twice a day look out for males too for
the first three weeks look out for males
I've had plants surprise me I thought
they were full-on female until about day
I mean popped open to nut sack somewhere
and I'm like oh that's got to go so look
for male flowers hurm flowers all over
the entire plant once or twice a day
through the entire bloom cycle you guys
of a bag seed because it could her mouth
there it had a seed for a reason and it
could her him out in the end of week
eight so if it does you neither need to
be able to harvest it before it produces
the seed or you need to get in there and
be able to tweeze out if it makes one or
two male flowers sometimes you can pull
them out with tweezers hit the plant
sprayed the plant with a water bottle
just missed it a little bit because this
deactivates pollen Moisture will ruin
pollen so give it a nice mist get in
there with some tweezers and pull out
those male flowers put them in a trash
bag throw them away I got in an argument
with someone in facebook clan the other
day I posted a picture of a French hemp
plant male and he told me that that
gross spot was ruined for life and that
pollen doesn't die and it travels for
hundreds of miles and and all that yeah
yeah I think to say about that Jeff I
just want to go to that forum or that
post and just troll that guy's what I
want to do no actually pollen you can
get rid of pollen quite easily sweep the
floor get in there with some water water
deactivates pollen egos it's all you
gotta do very fragile yes it's hard to
store in fact it's so hard to store you
have to keep it I keep my pollen I have
little vials of pollen that are sealed
and they are in sight of another jar
that is sealed and that is inside of a
refrigerator that stays dark
that's how careful I am with my pollen
big shout it's a can aventure what up
rusty rusty threw a bunch of pollen on
me the last time he was here he dropped
off like four or five little bags of
pollen so there may be some can aventure
i recross is coming up in the near
future that's where all my Yeti stuff
came from was a friendly pollen delivery
from someone that Yeti OG that you may
live resin with last summer
nice that stuff was memorable remarkable
legendary that was a good [ __ ] I wish
that was back around big shot at the
Spence he's the one that cookies oh yeah
there was just a little bit of that I
got some of that luckily I get to some
of the groups to that that was in the
spring you had some good runs that back
then too yeah yeah seems like everybody
got busy and carried away and all the
hash artists got too busy and we're just
all disconnected
you'd all reconnect again yeah all right
everybody on the podcast we need
everybody on the podcast again everybody
you got to come back we're gonna get a
party going yeah we haven't all
connected in a while you know episode
100 is coming up dude no yeah this is
gonna be number 90 I think right here
yeah damn yeah I didn't do an intro for
it but this I think this is number 90
yeah so number hundred is coming up you
guys if you have any cool ideas if you
want to be on episode number 100 hit me
up
it's a high region etics at hotmail.com
I'd love to have you on the show all
right so we're talking about bagged
seeds what else do you have to add about
bag seed bro or were we we're a Girl
Scout cookies I was assuming alleging
that Girl Scout cookies was probably an
accident and came from bagsied a part of
my theory on that is because I've heard
so many different rumors and legends of
how it was made and who made it
and I've never the people that are
alleged to have made it and I've never
said what it is and they won't
I hear it's an F what I hear a lot I'll
call him out they've said straight-up
they've said two or three different
stories so I wouldn't even believe
anything they said at this point I've
read at least three different stories
and high times and they all say they
came from the same people like and they
all say no one has it and that's a bunch
of [ __ ] it's everywhere if you don't
have Girl Scout cookies yeah by now let
us know because everybody in our crew
has a I've got the Platinum I've got the
forum
I've got cookies and cream by now I've
got cookie rack there's cookies that are
done with it and letting it go right
that's like pretty much all that
manion's wanna smoke his cookies oh
that's still one my favorite smokes I've
got some in the cloner now so let me
know if you want her to go back oh yeah
no I spread that around good yeah if you
if you really want something go to the
forums that's the truth I've got two
sources for claw two or three good
sources for clones around here and one
of them he gets everything from the
forum's he's kind of a quiet guy he does
not look like a pot grower he looks like
he probably would work on computers or
study law somewhere and so he shows up
with a briefcase and opens it up and
drops me off a few cuttings this Emmylou
[ __ ] that he got online I love when
clones come from him and also it seems
like right around the same time he gets
them either you or Spence will end up
with the same guy and you guys will
throw me a cut or I'll trade you a cut
just cuz that's how our group works and
I'll run them side-by-side and I'm
always so amazed that everybody got the
same cut
like how did Spence end up with this
Girl Scout cookies and my other friend
ended up with the Girl Scout cookies and
I ran him and there's the same [ __ ]
thing and they started from the same
seed somewhere it's so amazing to me and
then I mean just seeing I mean we've all
grown enough of it you can tell
instantly if it's it how do all these
people on the Internet have the same
freaking thing yeah it's crazy yeah
they're getting around people are flying
they're driving they're taking a horse I
don't know what they're doing so you
guys if you get some weed if you get
some good quality cannabis and it's got
a couple of healthy good-looking seeds
in there and you don't have money to
spend on some high quality seeds that we
know all the history behind them and
they were bred by magic elves in a
dungeon in Quebec but if you if you
don't want to pay good money for seeds
if you don't have access to good clones
just throw some of those bags seeds in a
paper towel germinate them just start
them out just like you would any other
seeds and pay a lot of attention and
then grow them out smoke it with your
friends here's something I really have
to say take a [ __ ] clone oh my god
you guys you wouldn't believe how many
people say look what I grew from seed no
Mike can I get a clone of that and like
I didn't take any clones yeah
dude take a clone it's not that hard you
take a little clone you dip it some [ __ ]
and you put in a ruder get some clones
if it hurts really bad don't take a
clone that's true it grows balls through
months grow more seeds these bag seeds
are free he already paid 50 bucks for
that eighth or whatever you paid for it
make sure you grow the seeds that are in
there and then you could have the next
chem dog you could grow the next Girl
Scout cookies you could grow the next
gorilla glue you could grow the next
golden goat
oh gee oh gee cush Tahoe what's another
one
creepy creepy he's ghost Sour Diesel
yeah yeah every single strain we were
smoking came from seed every one of them
yeah I can't think of one strain that
didn't come from seed and if you can
I'll give you $100
because every [ __ ] cannabis plant we
were smoking came from a seed somewhere
if you grow out that bag seed you could
have a cup winner right there because a
lot of times you don't even know what it
was bred with that's yours you don't
have to give anybody credit that's your
seed you found that so you've got the
that Jesse's pride and joy now and so
when the cannabis cup winnings come up
and the winner for the most heady indica
here in Denver Colorado at the cannabis
cup goes to Jesse for Jesse's mystery
funk and there you go man you just won
that cannabis cup what's up AG seed that
she found chem dog did it why couldn't
you yeah true story
all right I've been rambling a lot I
needed AB and then I think we're
thinking might be we would go for close
to 30 minutes here we could probably
start wrapping up this part dude all
right guys we tried to wrap up this
episode but the conversation kept going
so what I decided to do was to make this
a two-part episode so I will drop
episode number 91 Thursday morning and
that will be part two of hanging out so
I want to thank you guys for listening
to this episode I hope you join us for
part two don't forget to check out our
sponsor Highgrove indoor growing
supplies if you were interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like this review send me
an email it's grossly hard at
hotmail.com and we'll get you all the
information that you need you guys check
this out on all the social media or on
facebook we are on twitter
we're on instagram we'd love to hear
from you the facebook is simply grow up
from your heart the twitter is at a fyh
podcast excuse me on instagram we are I
read genetics we are almost 18,000
followers on Instagram it'd be really
cool to have you as a follower to check
us out on Instagram you guys if you have
anything you'd like to say and you're
not into the social media you can always
contact me it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com guys don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is always in
forever archive for high region etics
Colorado com
don't forget there's a donation button
on the podcast page if you go to I read
genetics Colorado comm click on the girl
from your heart podcast tab at the top
right is a donation button that goes
directly to my PayPal account
I'm never gonna charge you for this
podcast this will always be free but if
you do feel like making a contribution I
would greatly appreciate it and it will
give you a shout out on the show make
sure you guys check out the part 2 of
this episode on Thursday shout out to
manage of Spence thanks again for
listening until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 91 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations I try to fear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a hardcore Gabbar
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host
they call me Rasta Jeff thanks again for
joining me I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to the mystic roots band
for letting me play their music in my
podcast
big thanks to Kat kun and the entire
mystic roots crew because they don't
have any commercials for this week I
want to get right into the episode
before we get started I want to let you
know that this is a part two episode a
few days ago Jesse was here and we
recorded for quite a while
I put up the first half of the
conversation on Monday this is part two
it starts off with me I asked Jesse if
he had any guidance or advice to give
growers and then we'll just jump into
right where he started before we get
there I do want to make an apology I
posted episode 92 iTunes and my website
and stitcher and for some reason episode
90 did not make it to stitcher I like it
normally would have that was not my
issue it was stitchers issue they have
since been emailed as soon as stitcher
gets episode 90 up I will post episode
91 I don't want to cause any confusion
with stitcher I've emailed them and let
them know that my latest episode did not
post I don't want to have another
episode on to that and confuse them as
soon as the tree gets episode 90 out
episode 91 will be posted right after
that I appreciate you guys for being
patient I do apologise for any
inconvenience that may have caused I
feel like I've been rambling enough it's
almost two-minute intro let's get right
down to the part where Jesse and I are
talking so here we go I asked Jesse I
basically said do you have any guidance
that you would like to share with our
listeners and then here is what Jesse
had to say don't sell junk clones
don't sell junk clones don't sell
untested seeds oh my god I don't sell
clones of plants from seed that you
haven't even flowered yet yeah
definitely I've heard so many horror
stories at the gross store like I feel
so bad for people like I can't help them
it just it really sucks if you do that
stuff do it right if you get a bag seed
how does what's this hash this is
Startalk I'm taking the data start out
front just give it to max if you I
wasn't even gonna say now if you get a
backseat of it okay and then oh oh if
you did if you grow some weed and it's
got a bunch of seeds in it that star dog
plant just cuz it's wholly seeded to
[ __ ] doesn't mean you can call those
seed star dog those are not star dog
seeds those are unknown seeds unless you
hit that star dog girl with male star
dog pollen or manipulated the plant in
some other fashion to create Lou's s1
seeds it does happen you know if you
don't still not exactly it right but if
you might thing is if you don't know
what did it yeah don't call it start
yeah yeah because it could be there
could have been some pollen in there it
could have been another one of the
plants that firmed on it it could have
been a male in there
if if all you had was seven star dog
plants in there I guess you do have star
dog seeds if you light stressed it and
it produced a bunch of seeds you do now
have star dog seat it could have been a
a really special recessive cloned
phenotype and and what comes out is the
dominant piece of junk you know Riya yes
just you're gonna see grandpa when you
what the grandpa was you're gonna see
what grandma was and sometimes those
plants were shitty or something
you just never know a lot of what we
have now the plants that we're growing
now are like your dad's fault you know
what I mean Jessie's dad actually did
some breeding back then so they couldn't
run too much electricity they didn't
know what the hell they were looking for
they had the shittiest books everything
in the books back then was handed drawn
people were still they were still in
electricity back then yeah and
hand-drawn books that you had to go to
shady ass head shops to buy
well Frank I'm gonna take this dad we'll
start doing this but yeah those that
generation is responsible for the plants
that we have now those guys some of the
guys that went to war in other countries
brought back seeds from those regions
they grew those seeds they found that
somewhere too damn tall they found that
some took way too long and they got rid
of them and I bet you bro I bet they're
now that we've got room and space and
lights and Technology I bet some of the
gold was thrown the [ __ ] alone I
guarantee if you've got a bag of old
school seeds if you're like 50 or 60
years old and you've got a big sandwich
bag full of seeds that you had when you
were let's see I want to go back to the
70s so if you got some 35 year old seeds
40 year old seeds and you want to share
them send Jesse and I a sandwich baggie
fool we'll give you a clone of our
favorite [ __ ] yes I got some pretty old
seeds the other day shout-out to mr. G
and I can't remember is a llama box
llama box yeah thanks for the hook-up
guys oh yeah yeah he was one of the
winners for the 50 show that is true in
his little Twitter icon is a little
llama yeah I knew I remember that I was
taking a dad and that still made sense
to me shot at the green and healthy
wellness while I'm thinking about it you
guys I wrote it down to say this I was
supposed to say it in the intro but I
just took a DAB and I want to make sure
I don't forget green and healthy
wellness is not closed forever no I know
I hyped this shop in Colorado Springs
shout out to hunt shout it to damsel
shout it to Haley shout it to Jordan
Jordan Jordan and John Randall's Jude
News
but they had to shut their doors for a
little while the building I don't know
how much of this business is mine to air
the building in which they were located
was sold in the new owner did not want a
dispensary there it's basically the
story so they were forced to move they
do have a new location by the time you
hear this it is likely that they are
open to back for business and if they
are not trust me you guys green and
healthy wellness as fast as it go dude I
saw them working to tear down the
building and it was like army ants and
they're just
and buck wild it was crazy everybody was
sweaty and had this stressful look so
they're giving belly crow to yeah so
that's always fun yeah so they are eager
to get the new facility open they're not
gone forever you guys the tur pax hookup
at green &amp; Healthy wellness we'll be
back danzel will be back back if I
understand it right they actually got a
better building they got a better
location that building was a little
tight the parking would get a little
cramped in there sometimes yeah so they
will be back and it will be better than
ever they do apologize for the
inconvenience we know that a lot of
people rely on them for their medicine
they are a medical only shop so a lot of
patients are looking for a new spot for
medicine they'll be back you guys I
promise I certainly promise big shout
out to hunt was here the other day at
the house and hung out and we did make
promises to record together very soon
next that episode will feature the
lovely dude its damsel my favorite she's
a little famous on I took I'm sure I've
talked about it on the show I'm growing
a strain called damsels date I'm hunting
from seed I'm running three different
seed lines of stuff that I've crossed
and I'm looking to find her favorite
phenotype and then we're gonna name that
one damsels dank and it's gonna be
marketed at the dispensary that I
represent and the dispensary that she
represents and so I took a picture of
the seedling and sent it to her and I
said at the beginning and she put that
on Instagram and within an hour I had a
hundred new followers Jesus yeah dude
it's danzel that's my favorite Suicide
Girl that's hard to pick yeah that'll be
uh yeah bet that'll be a little bit
popular that'll get some stuff going for
both of us yes both brands suicide girls
dude its damsel Clint will be part of
that the Grammy Gatsby will be part of
advertising green and healthy wellness
will be carrying the flowers for sure in
the near future the spot will have the
flowers but you guys this is a year-long
project don't think this something this
is something that's gonna hit a few
weeks we bred a strength we bred a seed
line we bred three seed lines we took
those seed lines they germinated they
are now in veg
just got put into three gallon pots I've
got a run I think twenty two of them out
of the original I think thirty started
twenty two of them have made it to where
I think they'll make it to the flour
room I may take water two out one's too
tall and lanky it's a boy I can tell
just by looking so I kind of want to
just pull that one but then they'll
flower once they're flowered there's a
private party set up the dates already
been chosen as a location being put
together and the Grammy Gatsby is gonna
throw a tasting party and there will be
scorecards and video done and full-on
reviews so yeah we're taking this one
quite seriously and this just a fee no
hunt imagine if he was actually taking
the seeds to market right so two year
project yeah exactly because I would
want to run at least a hundred of those
seeds myself after I ran 20 or 50 of
them myself I would start sending 10
packs out to friends I'd give you ten of
them friends that are eager to grow they
would grow them right away they would
send me pictures they would send me
feedback if they're local I get to go I
get to go to roster Ralph's garden and
look at my blue heeler growing I get to
go to people's places and see my plants
growing in their garden to get feedback
which improves my breeding because then
I could say oh god I never want to breed
with that [ __ ] plant ever again what
is the Blue Heeler Blue Heelers is the
blue The Grateful dog okay shoutout to
Spencer for the name I was like I'm
gonna cross through the Blue Dream and
the Grateful dog because that's a blue
heeler seeds for that I I don't think
I've ever grown a blue dream cross it's
about my favorite strain in the world to
be honest that was Colorado was in love
with blue dream and the girls in
California are in love with blue dream
it's a cash crop plant it does have some
medicinal value but it's used too much
here as a cash crop plant for what it is
it's uh I forgot the cross of it
suddenly it's blueberry and Silver Haze
yeah yeah I guess it's by DJ shorts
selling ourselves like that isn't it
yeah that's actually true because I yea
that's up for debate guys if you know
the truth of where the blue dream came
from
the stories but it's a haze and it's a
blue dream and it's got some og I think
in there but you would think from what
I've read I remember thinking that would
be the ideal stream but then I remember
getting my hands on a couple of
different grows of it smoking it and
being like this is media voters of
amazing [ __ ] phenotype over these blue
dream phenotype is the most impressive
I've seen yeah it's just a phenotype you
guys it's labeled abd it's easy to think
that's just the blue dream that's
everywhere yeah I'm pretty sure it's the
one I bred - yeah but the blue dream
kicks out you can pull two pounds under
a thousand watt light and soil with that
blue dream code using with a short short
veg time we did a one with a real short
veg time last year outdoors it did like
three and a half pounds yeah but the
problem is it doesn't have an appealing
hi to me and it doesn't make enough hash
to make it worth its time space energy
nutrients whatever else you know what I
mean I could replace that with a Bounty
Killer and have way better medicine if
it smelled like it if it tasted like it
smelled you'd be the most popular strain
in the world yeah my dog was to put that
resin on it and it worked it definitely
worked it made it i shortened the
flowering time it made the plants a
little stockier and it put some resin
and a little bit of funk to it which is
what oh that's all that blue dream was
missing was resin and funk it was
getting too tall for the lot of indoor
grows
I bet the DJ short came out of it I mean
it anything with his stuffs always seems
to be really dominant a lot you know it
says a lot for his breeding because he's
taken to the five before he releases his
packages which is pretty impressive and
he has a style of his own I've heard him
argue with many people on podcasts and
interviews yes couple of minutes ago
I dissed the old generation DJ shorten
is the old generation bro we gotta give
him mad love oh he's one of the guys
back in the day that was doing it right
for genetics if it weren't for DJ sure I
don't think you and I would be where we
are in the cannabis game no I don't
think anyone would be I mean yeah DJ's
done a lot for the
and just everything it's I might be a
brick in the wall but DJ short was part
of the foundation oh yeah
cornerstone yes it's up there with some
of the original authors and stuff like
that guys like that yeah I'll give
sub-cooled man credit also he's not as
old as sub cool or as DJ short but he's
in that generation between them between
us and DJ gotta give him mad love for
his breeding and cool you did for the
community also since we're chef first
readers yeah and if we're gonna go with
old guys you guys know I'm gonna say it
soma deserves a high five taught me how
to grow on Oh G I did not know anything
about never I'd read so most posts but I
never realized he was a dreadlock and I
never knew he was a dirty hippie and I
didn't know he had amethyst everywhere
and crystals on everything I figured he
was an Indian dude the country India
yeah and my friend Donovan one day who
was a big user of overgrown calm
he was always on there one day he's like
bro you remind me so much of so by the
way that you talked because I was
preaching my girl from your heart theory
you know what I mean like doing your
grow room and I still think this you
gotta go in a grow room once in a while
and just sit there and just meditate and
just close your eyes and think about the
goodness that those plants are gonna do
because you're growing a plant that is
going to heal somebody in some sort of
way they're gonna feel better even if
there are recreational smoker if they're
a medical smoker somebody is gonna be
uplifted and better because of the
product that you're growing and that's
got to feel good inside so I go in there
and kind of meditate a little bit on
that and feel that gold and we'd share
it the plants like me I love them and
then they heal somebody else and that
person hugs me when they see me and it
just perpetuates this golden cycle so I
was talking about that exact hippie [ __ ]
that I just said and my buddy's like
dude you're like [ __ ] soma he's like
no go get his book his book like this
guy is who I was going to be in 20 years
if I didn't know I was already on the
path of being so much respect we just
got off on a random tangent of he didn't
know to organic before
Ennio y'all thought of it as cool as it
is no one's doing nothing new there true
I built him out of Rubbermaid containers
but I used the same you know principle
with the drainage do you think and
support 99% of what soma says some cool
I love his growing style sometimes he
says some [ __ ] that I'm not gonna put my
signature on yeah [ __ ] integrity he's
met a lot of strains and he was one of
the first people to take good pictures
of with a good camera buds and send him
into High Times anybody that's followed
me on Facebook since the beginning knows
without any saying that [ __ ] sub cool
inspired 50% of my photography that's
was like you should check out the weed
nerd okay there's a lot to learn in some
of his older episodes if you're
interested in the way he does things you
know sub cool on the YouTube the YouTube
the weed nerds the weed nerd yeah check
that out the older stuff is really good
there came a point when it got to be too
redundant redundant and he had yeah even
he knows that he says it all the time
episodes and there's only so much you
could talk about about cannabis you know
what I mean like there's always news and
stuff so that's why I fall to the news
sometimes but it's going to be now that
once we get to episode 100 we're gonna
go a little more in-depth I've gone
through the basics and now it's time to
dig in a little bit I think our friends
our listeners periscope I think that's a
really great tool for a podcast okay so
I've been opening periscope and doing
random [ __ ] on there occasionally but
now that we've got this good foundation
you guys have had your basic rudimentary
classes I think it's almost time around
episode 102 start pushing it and start
going to the B level courses we're in a
college level you guys here pretty soon
okay Sean back you'll have to get out
the notepad again we're gonna do real
ones so we're gonna wrap this part up
we've been doing for a long time dude
Jesse thanks for coming man oh yeah no
problem oh let's see let's do outdoor
update real quick okay
here lately in southern Colorado at
least it has been cold and humid at
night and hot and dry during the day
that is a recipe for powdery mold so bud
rot it's part of the reason Cali bud
stands out and they get a marine layer
with this too but you know this year
I've seen some a lot of Cali style or
what I always call Cali style problems
that we've never had here before so be
prepared for that stuff how can we
prevent getting powdery mildew with
these crispy cold nights that we're
getting and there's a lot of moisture in
the air tonight yeah yeah there's I mean
any number of things
I'm personally using AK teen ovate I
mean we're in bloom too but it's you
know that's I see it on the cucumbers I
see it on the squash I see it on the
watermelon that's a different strain it
doesn't really affect cannabis from what
I've seen and been told but to me it's
an indication that the the climate for
to grow is oh yeah his presence yes I
can't speak on that now but in the next
within the next thirty days I am going
to become what is called applicator
certified by the Department of
Agriculture nice my cousins oh yeah it's
it seems I've looked at the test it
seems to be fairly easy it's an
open-book test somebody that works I'm
now the lead grower myself and my friend
John are now the lead growers at the
spot dispensary and today we had our
first pre inspection from the Department
of Agriculture before we grow anything
in there I in our new grill areas Wow
dude it's I've only been out of the
industry for what nine months and well
things have changed yes yes you have to
have a Department of Agriculture
meetings there's about an hour and a
half long meeting they told us basically
what we need to do to be compliant which
is it's all basic stuff and it's mostly
since the spot was designed well it's
the [ __ ] that we're already doing but
you have to have one at least one person
on the staff that can train employees on
pesticide and insecticide
and fungicide safety good yeah and so I
took it upon myself to say hey I'm lead
grower
I'll go do this and it's the boss is
gonna pay for it of course cuz it's a
work-related thing and it's something
that I feel like I should do anyway like
when they offered that course I was like
I want to go to this I want to go to
this yeah okay yeah that's that's great
man within 30 days I will I have to take
those to the spot - I know some owners
would be really pissed about having to
do [ __ ] like this right it is hard to
survive right now if you don't have some
money to put in inventory if your
shelves aren't stocked with 20 different
kinds of buds if your shelves aren't
stocked with 20 different kinds of
edibles or different topicals a lollipop
over here some t-shirts over here socks
over here Chinese water pipes yeah yeah
good water pipes Chinese water pipes
knock off shout out to Three Rivers
organics I got some cool hitman [ __ ] in
there Wow your eyes are really red back
to the outdoors yes let's go but yeah
activate green cure I don't really see
that as a preventative but if you do use
it make sure you use it at night and
follow the directions whatever you know
there's all kinds of stuff you can be
spraying on it just get it get a good
one to stay away from neem oil since
it's all your plant should be in bloom
yeah I was gifted a product called
stylet oil I've heard of it
I do the consultation and somebody an
older gentleman who is not as
able-bodied as most of us he's a little
he's a little slower he might call in
handicapped he's trying to grow his own
cannabis it's his first grow that's the
second Grove and I gave him a free
consultation and he had just the starts
of powdery mildew
and I was like man I and he was in about
starting week three of flower and I like
man I don't really want you to spray
anything on there but you're gonna lose
your crop if you don't and he said I
googled some stuff and they say oils and
things and I said don't put a neem oil
on there I said put some worm casting
tea on there well didn't do a damn thing
that's most definitely preventative [ __ ]
so I told him I said well you're gonna
this crop is gonna be [ __ ] because the
powdery mildew was getting it wasn't
thick but you could see it popping up
into little circles ooh and so I said
you know I've got a product called
stylin oil that I've never used and a
friend of mine sent it to me to
encourage me to use it and he said that
it will destroy powdery mildew on
contact he says spray it on there and
he's an old dude I said this is your
medicine that you're and he said yes I
know I need this spray that on there he
knew what I was doing and it was it was
his decision I sprayed the stylet oil on
there dude that [ __ ] took down the
powdery mildew on contact it destroyed
it nice I've never actually used it I've
heard you can burn the [ __ ] out some
plants with it absolutely that's one of
the things a guy named I don't know if I
should say his real name he's known as
tree town is what I know him as a tree
town farmer he's the one that
recommended this to me and hooked me up
with it it was a vendor for the product
of course he's like check this out so uh
I didn't well I didn't have anything to
use it on in my grows like I didn't have
any mildew or anything like that so when
this dude was like I got powdery mildews
like this is what I've got to offer you
and something about the way that it
coats the leaves it causes it breaks the
membrane of the powdery mildew and it
doesn't allow it to grow on your leaf is
basically what I read and when that [ __ ]
hit the leaf it just washed it right off
we did it with the lights off turn the
lights off just turn it normal as you
should with most pesticides actually any
with any spray you want the lighter are
a few that you actually need the lights
on but
sometimes you need to heat the room
hopped yeah yeah that's what the deal is
yeah need to heat the room to activate
the oils and the plants so well we
sprayed it with the the the stylin oil
and then let it sit overnight and then
we went back the next morning and rinsed
the stylet oil off with just clean water
also very important yes most pesticides
yes you want to unclog the plants they
want to be able to breathe rinse that
[ __ ] off and then dude those plants just
came out of it and they're amazing
nice yeah he got to harvest his crop
this was several weeks ago he got to
harvest his crop I looked at it I helped
him trim something I showed him how to
trim it no signs of powdery mildew
gorgeous crops smelled pretty good I
haven't smoked any of it so I don't know
if it tastes like stylet oil but he's an
older cat he's been he's like your dad
you know just needs a bunch of herb to
smoke so he doesn't get hurt oil I think
that's a hybrid it's in this room I
should have had it handy before I
brought it up I wasn't prepared for that
so fail on my part yeah I did some
research on it once they said white it's
not it's not colored white it's just
considered a white oil it's not thick
and white or anything nice yeah when I
heard about it it was kind of pre Amazon
times I just couldn't get my hands on it
yeah it's it's available now and it's
cheap it's actually quite affordable so
as a preventative as an outdoor if you
need to rescue something it's something
you could look into drink here if you
hit it just right we'll we'll take care
of a light infestation but it's kind of
touchy to applying a foliar spray of any
type D leafing just removing the leaf of
and taking it out of the area washing
your hands don't touch them when they're
when it's wet that's actually I've been
told it spreads easier at that point so
okay that's something I've been told so
I would believe it I haven't been able
to put that to work too much but yeah
haven't had a need to if you've got
powdery mildew in your grow room you've
got something to correct in the room
you've got some work to do it's gonna
take you a little bit to fix that you
cannot spray away that problem
yeah there's an environmental problem
gotta clean it start getting fresh air
out of the refresher into the room
stealer out of the room lower the
humidity but if you get it also don't
feel bad I mean it can even happen
outdoors that happens yeah yeah it
happened the first time I moved into a
new house it was August when I moved in
so it was warm and then that first
winter crop I got powdery mildew it was
the concrete basement wall drastic
climate change season changes it's
easier to run that room in the fall
probably wasn't prepared for that
yeah don't I've been told that when I
talk about powdery mold and both of us
have been told that we make people feel
bad so don't feel bad if it happens you
guys person at the store told me that
it's because I just don't you never take
a picture your poops do you post the
gold on Instagram so don't worry you
guys I will I'll [ __ ] something up and
post a picture of it on Instagram just
for fun no it's just to show you the
roster Jeff [ __ ] up a fence and
fuck-ups recently the next time I make a
mistake I'll get out the camera and I'll
straight into the floor only a couple of
gallons of water but still when you hear
that [ __ ] overflow totally focused on
what I was doing and I have to take the
short bus to work tomorrow after this
[ __ ] I was with some people that uh in
the early days we were Phil and Reza's
and took off to lunch we went to the bar
had a couple beers came back two and a
half hours later and water was still
running
luckily it was a big like an old
mechanic shop just a big steel building
with a roll-up door on one side this was
still real early days it was most
definitely Trap House worthy but uh it
was a early legal Grove it was fun we
just roll up the door and I was a blast
back then we had our grow and our
dispensary was attached they were one
floor was the grow one floor was the
dispensary and so I would be I'd have we
had a camera of course with the monitor
up there so I could just look at the
monitor and hear the doorbell water
situation smoking a fat joint just water
plants living my life got reggae on and
then you hear the doorbell and just run
downstairs I wouldn't even put up the
joint I've seen barefoot and shirtless
felons working in drawings and colors
there's a barcode on any product it was
all just grown in someone's basement or
upstairs from the from the dispensary
and then trimming that brought right
immediately to the grow or to the
dispensary put in a jar and sold and
just what do you mean we had some weed
just survive no money and despite all
that certain shops still just boom had
the fire I used to be better I I think
it is the dispensary grows a lot of the
growers grown was late honest I used to
grow I worked at madam our dispensary I
was the manager my friend Tom was the
owner I was the manager right underneath
him
Tom handed me the keys one day and he
was like here you got a dispensary have
fun they paid me very well so I worked
at this dispensary and I would grow
cherry widow at home in my own home Russ
and then I would take that cherry widow
to the shop and sell it to the boss for
a decent price put it on the shelf
and that was the most fireweed we had in
there that week all right podcast rolled
I want to thank you guys for joining
Jesse and I on this lovely Thursday I
back Monday with a regular episode now
the show's over you guys please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast give me
a 5 star rating and type in a comment
and let me know what you think about the
show I would love to hear your opinion
when you give us stars on iTunes that
makes more people see the show and of
course the more people see the show the
more people will grow better cannabis or
people will become cannabis activists
more people will fight for the plant the
plant will become legalized worldwide
and we will not have to hide ourselves
anymore all right so please give me a
five star rating let me know what you
think I definitely appreciate it if
you've got something to say find me on
social media you know we're on Facebook
we are on Twitter on Facebook it's a
girl from your heart on Twitter it's at
G fyh podcast we do have an email
address it's roll from your heart at
hotmail.com be sure to follow I region
etics on Instagram we are almost to
18,000 followers I'd love for you to be
one of them you guys don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes the show
is available on stitcher and every
single episode is always and forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm you guys I want to thank you for
listening to this long rambling Thursday
episode Jessi and I talked for a long
time I thought you guys would want to
hear a bunch of it so I put it out as a
Thursday episode let me know what you
think
all right big shot it's manager Spence
thanks again for listening until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 92 of the
growth lahar podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber your cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
[Music]
thanks for joining me as always I need
to send a huge thank you shout out to
the mystic roots band for letting me
play their music on the show
big thanks to Kat the entire crew was
having a great week hope everyone's
having a good Monday or whatever it is
when you're listening to this I'm
smoking on some dabs of some haze I hope
you were smoking something delicious
right now great couple of weeks I'm
gonna read a few news articles here
today but first I want to ramble about a
few things that I have gotten to do this
past couple of weekends this episode is
gonna come out way after this but the
movie Straight Outta Compton recently
came out and I actually grew up in
Southern California
I grew up the intersection of Bellflower
Boulevard and Compton Boulevard so I was
blocks away from the actual City of
Compton NWA used to come do record
signings and appearances at a record
store about a block away from my house
so when I was like 10 years old
I actually met eazy-e and NWA and the
whole NWA crew I met Ice Cube I met
snoop I met MC Ren I met dr. Dre there
was another guy with them called himself
DJ speed yellow was there there were a
few more guys there and I remember I was
a little kid but I do remember that ah
their album was huge I'd already had the
Straight Outta Compton CD I was singing
[ __ ] the police all day long I was like
10 years old walking around my
neighborhood singing [ __ ] the police and
dope man but when they showed up to the
record store I remember the management
of the record store looking pissed off
because they were stupid hi everybody in
NWA showed up for that record signing
smelling like they just smoked a blunt
and easy easy van so seen the movie
Straight Outta Compton kind of was very
reminiscent for me it took me back to my
old neighborhood in my mind it took me
back to those time
brought me back to a lot of memories it
was really cool to see that the movie
was freaking awesome it was a great
movie I'll give that five golden pot
leaves I would recommend the movie
Straight Outta Compton to anybody the
guy that played the manager Paul
Giamatti I think his name is he did a
hell of a job all the actors did a great
job they actually used ice cubes son to
play cube he did a great job I think
everybody was perfect
hell of a good movie I would recommend
you guys go see that you've probably
already seen it by now if you haven't go
see it ah there's one really comedic
lion in the movie that made me laugh my
ass off that was what my best parts my
favorite parts of the movie that whole
scene was actually one of my favorite
parts of the movie from the beginning of
that scene until the joke that ends the
scene that was all my favorite parts one
thing I did notice I don't remember
which character it was but the manager
character Paul Giovanni's character the
manager he plays a guy named Jerry and
one of the rappers were having a private
conversation over a meal and they
completely repeated a section of
dialogue and it seemed weird to me it
felt like a bad editing job being
somebody that edits podcast and [ __ ] I
felt that the repetition of that
dialogue was kind of a waste of time it
felt like this to me I'm gonna kind of
do what I felt like I saw on the show
like the manager said so we can't
continue like this because we're gonna
go broke and the other guy replied well
yeah but this is how we [ __ ] live cuz
we're gangsters and then the manager
said but we can't continue to live like
this because we're gonna go broke and
the other guy said yeah but that's how
we live because we're [ __ ] gangsters
and then the movie kept going and I
looked at my date and I was like did
they just repeat some [ __ ] cuz it was
really awkward it didn't feel right in
the movie but other than that that was
the only flaw I found great movie
Straight Outta Compton movie gets 5
golden pot leaves let's move on to my
next little chicken scratch on this
paper let's see this Saturday or last
Saturday it would be I was invited to
the High Plains comedy fest in Denver
Colorado the High Plains comedy fest is
a comedy festival of course right it's
what it's called and they do these shows
throughout different clubs in the Denver
Colorado area so some of the
performances were at the high dive some
of the performances were at mutiny some
of the performances were at 3:00
and then later on at night performers
were headlining at places like the
Paramount Theater and Comedy Works I was
invited by my friend Baker what's up
Baker I don't know if you listen to the
podcast but if you do big shout out much
love Baker is a good friend of mine he
is linked up with the comedy world and
it is Baker's fault that I have gotten
to smoke weed and hash with some of my
favorite comedians you guys I'm not
gonna name drop I got to smoke hash and
weed with a lot of my favorite comedians
people that you listen to people that
have podcasts that we listen to their
podcasts I was kind of blown away I was
standing on Broadway in Denver just
smoking joints and bulls with
world-class comedians and they were all
treating me like I was one of them and
it's mostly Baker's fault and it was
also because I had the good weed so big
shot it's my Buddy Baker big shots of
the High Plains Comedy Festival I had a
wonderful freaking time also a big shout
out to our friends at grassroots
California unfortunately the grassroots
store had to close their doors but they
had a an awesome I was able to go there
and grabbed several grassroots hats for
the price of two so I am styled out all
right I think that's enough catching up
and humble bragging about what I've
gotten to do for the past couple of
weekends
of course fish is coming up here on the
next weekend so you guys will get to
hear a lot about that let's go ahead and
get into some of the news articles that
I have pulled up for you guys if you
have been following the show you will
remember that recently there was a raid
in California of a dispensary and when
the police raided this dispensary first
of all they treated all of the people
inside of the dispensary like complete
[ __ ]
they were completely disrespectful to a
woman in a wheelchair then they cleared
out the dispensary and proceeded to
destroy this dispensary but they did not
realize that they were on a hidden
camera as they destroyed the dispensary
they destroyed displays they destroyed
the security systems they just tore this
place apart
it was terrible as they were doing this
they were caught on camera
eating edibles from the dispensary so
the lawyer for the dispensary found the
tape edited the tape and put it it was
put up on YouTube it was all over the
Internet
but also they were trying to file a case
against the law enforcement officials
that were responsible for this raid and
for the eating of the edibles once the
video was introduced in a court case was
presented the Santa Ana police tried to
stop this footage from being used in a
raid because they were under the
presumption of privacy since they had
already taken down all of the cameras in
this dispensary
so these cops came and destroyed the
dispensary they were caught on hidden
camera doing [ __ ] they should not have
done and then they tried to block the
video from being used as evidence in a
case against them well now I am reading
on The Huffington Post this is an
article by a guy named Matt ferner and
the headline says judge says video
allegedly showing cops eating marijuana
candy can be used as evidence the sub
headline is an internal investigation of
three california police officers can use
security camera footage from a
dispensary raid and i think that this is
great news i'm going to go ahead and
read the article it is from los angeles
and it says in Orange County Superior
Court judge ruled Wednesday that a
controversial surveillance video
allegedly showing three police officers
eating marijuana infused candy and
mocking a disabled woman during am a
dispensary raid can be used in an
internal investigation by the Santa Ana
Police Department the unidentified
officers and their union the Santa Ana
Police Officers Association filed a
temporary restraining order earlier this
month to block the video from being used
in an ongoing internal investigation for
the officers conduct during the raid the
police argued their privacy was violated
when surveillance cameras recorded them
from inside sky-high holistic medical
marijuana dispensary after they thought
they had disabled all of them Superior
Court Judge Ronald Bauer rejected that
notion on Wednesday the Orange County
Register first reported saying that the
officers had no objectively reasonable
expectation that their actions and words
during the raid would not be observed
the officers should not expect privacy
on their on-duty performance of an
official function a team
marijuana dispensary power rolled they
have made no claim that their work
required secrecy or that it would be
impeded by public view Matthew papas the
dispensaries attorney said the ruling is
a critical victory for holding police
and public officials accountable for
their actions this ruling shows that the
court had the courage to say no to a
very powerful police officer union and
stand up for the rights of people who
had bad things like this happened pop
has told The Huffington Post pop is
released edited footage of the may 27th
raid in June that was published by
various local news outlets the edited
video which can be seen on YouTube it's
also here in this article if you guys
want to see it go to The Huffington Post
com
type in let's see where will you find it
just type in marijuana raid and I'm sure
you will find this I need to find where
I was now here we go
the vetted video which can be seen shows
officers busting down the door and
ordering everyone on the ground at
gunpoint which that's where the whole
comedy starts their battery using a
battering ram to pound in this door and
the funny part is that the business was
open all they had to do was turn the
handle and pull and they could have
gotten in very easily instead they used
a battering ram and pushed really hard
instead of just gently pulling so it
says the footage according to Pappas
shows police unsuccessfully disable it
disabling the shop surveillance cameras
which go on to record the officers
playing darts eating something which he
argues is marijuana infused infused food
and making a joke about an amputee who
uses a wheelchair did you punch that
one-legged old benita one officer asks I
was about to kick her in her [ __ ] nub
a female officer replies to laughter
Corey glaive the attorney representing
representing the officers and their
union argued that the video was edited
to distort the officers behavior during
the raid he previously told the HuffPost
that at least one officer voluntary
voluntarily took and passed a drug test
the result of which were were provided
to the SAPD Pappas denied the video was
doctored at the full video is more than
12 hours long he said so he released
edited versions with subtitles to show
that what officers were allegedly saying
the entire video has been made available
to the police department and that they
have seen the full unaltered version oh
and that they have seen the full
unaltered version Papa said
skyhigh holistic has filed a
multi-million dollar lawsuit against the
police department alleging that the
officers used excessive force during the
raid the dispensary is also seeking the
return of its property seized during the
raid which includes marijuana cannabis
infused edibles and thousands of dollars
in cash a hearing regarding the return
of the seized property is scheduled for
Friday glaive and SAPD
did not immediately respond to requests
for comment following the judge's ruling
so it looks like the ruling has been
made
oh no the ruling has been made that the
video will be usable um I will research
the hearing regarding the return of the
seized property I'm gonna make a note of
that sorry it takes me a minute to write
legibly but I'd rather take a break and
write it so that I remember to do it
alright so they will be able to use this
video in court which is a great thing
because if you were I were arrested and
there was a video of whatever we were
doing that video would be used against
us in court everything we say and/or do
will be used against us in a court of
law and even if we think that we have
some sort of assumption of privacy
they're not going to give us any privacy
this is America big brother is watching
you're on camera somewhere so keep that
in mind you guys I'm just glad that
they're gonna use this video because I
think it's [ __ ] up that these cops can
act like they're trying to do something
just and useful for us and then just go
ahead and be thugs they were gangsters
they went in there in [ __ ] stole and
destroyed [ __ ] they were vandals they
need to be held accountable that's my
opinion so I will keep you updated I'm
going to do some research on what
happened to the property I hope they get
their cannabis back I hope they get
their money back I hope they get their
edibles back I hope they make that cop
pay for the edible that he bought and
ate and I hope they also sue the [ __ ]
out of them for all the wages they've
lost in the mental anguish I hope this
comes back to bite this police force in
their asses alright I've got another
article this one comes from the
beautiful city of Pueblo Colorado you
know Facebook has been bustling about
the city of Pueblo Colorado and cannabis
I read a fact today you know I can't say
that it's a fact but I've seen this in
more than one place I have seen in red
that Pueblo Colorado now produces the
most
legal cannabis anywhere of anywhere on
the planet we produce more legal
cannabis than anywhere we are now the
new golden triangle here in Pueblo
Colorado I would believe that our roles
are great things are affordable here the
climate is perfect for growing cannabis
and everybody is moving here to grow
wheat everybody is coming to Pueblo
Colorado so from what I've seen on
Facebook and on the internet here Pueblo
Colorado has become the new Emerald
triangle we produce more cannabis than
anywhere else in the world or at least
the country
all right so this news article I try
that again cuz I stumbled this news
article comes from high country news and
the headline is the Silicon Valley of
marijuana local officials want Pablo
County Colorado to be the best place to
grow but not everyone is high on the
idea how this article was written by a
guy named Joel Warner and I will read it
for you actually this is great because
it starts off with a picture of the spot
dispensary and a lady says Tammy why age
52 shows her son and his friend the
product she bought at the spot 420 in
Pueblo West they drove from Florida for
the week so Tammy who has chronic back
pain from bone spurs could buy and smoke
pot legally there are a lot of great
pictures in this article I did not
realize that I'm gonna scroll through
the pictures right quick if there are
any more from Pueblo I will share them
with you Oh where's that a Pueblo
resident who moved from Maryland to work
in the industry smokes pot while
overlooking the marijuana plants he
grows in his backyard he was hired at a
greenhouse five days later so there's a
picture of some guys mediocre pot grow
mediocre pot in his backyard is back
here it's a mess anyway I'll keep
looking through these pictures here oh
this guy's in Pueblo West it says it put
his full name bill Rader age 60 carries
his favorite marijuana plant outside to
soak up the Sun in Pueblo West
campground where he's been living for
two months radar a veteran from Missouri
who smokes because he can't take pain
pills is one among many people who've
moved to Pueblo from out of state to
take advantage of marijuana legalization
this dudes living in a mobile home and
it just has pot plants sitting right
outside the mobile home here and he
lives in an RV park that's kind of weird
let's see oh there's the o.penvape rep i
know that guy from the shop rick ortiz
waters plants at los signos and outdoor
marijuana farm and here's a dude just
watering a bunch of clones there's some
great pictures in this article big big
shout out to the photographer
I recommend you guys reading this art
dude there we go that's a great shop of
my or a great photo of my shop
John Virna age 25 the grower at the spot
420 turns the lights on in a newly
constructed grosse showroom where
marijuana will be cultivated visitors
will be able to tour the warehouse you
guys if you go to high country news.com
and you look at the article the Silicon
Valley of marijuana there is an actual
photograph of the shop where I work the
grow room in which I work one of my
rooms to go take a look all right I've
been rambling for a long time let's get
into this article it goes like this
Marc Morley looks out over 30 acres he
owns east of Pueblo Colorado and
imagines the future on his on this
blustery May afternoon there's little
more than mud and puddles here bordered
by highway and railroad tracks and
flanked by farm buildings and rolling
hills but by the end of September if all
goes well he'll be looking at a pungent
green thicket as 14400 marijuana plants
reach their full eight-foot height it's
one of several major outdoor grows
launching this summer in Pueblo Colorado
eventually Morley plans to expand into
another 15,000 acres investing in
center-pivot irrigation greenhouses and
processing facilities able to handle
40,000 plants Morley age 55 and dressed
in jeans flannel shirt and a tiger's
baseball cap is a major Colorado Springs
real estate developer after a marijuana
dispensary opened in one of his
buildings he realized how lucrative the
business could be why he wondered am I
not doing this myself if he planted corn
on his corn on his land each acre would
require approximately 2.2 acre feet of
water per year and produced 768 dollars
in annual sales according to Rachel Zen
Cannella a pueblo based Colorado
Division of Water Resources engineer
that same acre planted with marijuana
would require roughly 2.6 5 feet of
water 2.65 acre feet of water excuse me
and gross Morley six million dollars
welcome to the big business of rural
Reed everal weed I'm sorry that's hard
to read ever since the local steel
industry collapsed in the 1980s Pueblo
County has been seeking an economic
savior nearly a third of its population
is on public assistance and in 2000 the
metropolitan area around
eponymous city had the highest
unemployment rate in the state when
Colorado voters passed amendment 64 in
2012 paving the way for legalized
marijuana the County Commissioners saw a
chance for revival
they hired Brian Vicente the Denver
lawyer who helped write the ballot
initiative to craft rules for growing
and selling pot outside city limits as a
result a result about 50 entities
including Morley are now licensed or
conditionally approved to do so in the
county historically the biggest opponent
of marijuana reform has been the
government that sent a says here the
tables have turned
no one else in history has taken as
comprehensive look at establishing
marijuana business laws but will
county's economy he adds has gone
through the roof and you guys this is my
my town this isn't this is where I live
I've lived here since I was
approximately fifteen years old I've
left a few times I've been back but I've
been here for quite a while I have seen
this town go from just a small boat out
it was a little podunk hick town when I
moved here then it turned into a city
and then I got going and then we had
some things happening and people were
buying houses and moving in and then at
one point everything stopped it seemed
like everything fell apart and everybody
went poor here myself included I was
struggling I worked [ __ ] jobs to get
myself through you know then I grew weed
on the side because it was the only way
that I could make ends meet was to grow
some cannabis now that we've got this
legal cannabis industry obviously I am
doing great for myself I have a legal
job I can go to work and pay taxes now
um it really helps our whole economy
because the people that were I'm gonna
see 22 to about 35 around here there
wasn't a lot for us to do we could
either work at gas stations or we could
work at a telemarketing place or we
could work Trappe jobs but with all of
the cannabis industry that has boomed up
myself and all of my friends are living
very well most of us grow weed most of
us trim weed most of us are bud tenders
9 out of 10 of my friends are involved
in the cannabis industry in some way and
none of us are hungry for anything
anymore
we've all got everything we need none of
us have to be criminals anymore we don't
have to do anything shady
we don't have to watch our backs
shoulders we go to work 9:00 to 5:00 or
whatever we do we work eight-hour
10-hour days you come home from work and
you don't have to worry about hustling
you don't have to worry about being a
drug dealer you don't have to worry
about the stupid [ __ ] that comes along
with an illegal pot industry I think
it's a great way to revive an economy
get benefits and health insurance and
pay taxes I mean you can't do that when
you're growing weed in the basement
selling it illegally they're not part of
the cogs of the community that make a
society work in the I of that society
you are a black-market drug dealer even
though you spend all your money and all
the restaurants and all the stores in
town people don't realize that now it
won't freak out when I walk into
Applebee's and buy dinner for me and all
my friends or wherever we go go to Qdoba
and buy the whole true dinner they don't
look at you like dirty drug dealer they
look at you like oh that man has a job
that's kind of nice it's a big
difference
feels different it feels better I'm
gonna continue on with the article it
says but the area's relationship with
pot means remains ambivalent this is
after all a place where irate voters
recall their state senator over new gun
restrictions some worried that the
county's latest growth industry is
bringing social problems along with
money and others doubt whether the bold
experiment will reap the promised
rewards up to the 1970s Puebla was known
as PU town because of the steel mill
says Palo McPheeters co-founder of
Pueblo for positive impact which is a
which opposes the county's pot friendly
laws now we're getting known for that
again because of marijuana that group
shows up at all this uh let's see Pueblo
for a positive impact they show up in
all of the City Council meetings and
they try to fight down cannabis and the
cannabis use but honestly guys they
don't do any research and they don't
know what they're talking about so if a
few members that do support cannabis
would show up we could shut these guys
up every week lately Mike is the only
one that goes to the meetings
so I'd like to ask you guys to come to
City Council meetings when they happen
on Mondays and help us speak positively
about cannabis I'm a hypocrite as I
can't make it to every meeting but I do
go and I do try to voice my opinion when
I can
sorry I'm burping excuse me I'm a
continued article it says the city of
Pueblo sometimes called the Pittsburgh
of the West and like its steel town
sister city back east its glory years
lie in the past call center is one of
the few active industries dot it's the
downtown area Pablo County director of
economic development Chris Markuson says
that one of his predecessors used to
drive potential business owners down the
East Side's crumbling streets and past
crack houses and say enthusiastically
look at these people to work for
anything hoping that the promise of a
cheap labor force would prove
irresistible amendment 64 gave local
governments the power to decide whether
and how to prevent recreational pol
within their communities the Pueblo City
Council for example banned recreational
pot shops and grows within city limits
it reacted similarly when medical
marijuana was legalized in 2000 placing
a moratorium on dispensaries the
Colorado marijuana enforcement divisions
2014 annual report says that 228 local
jurisdictions have voted to prohibit
medical and retail marijuana operations
but low County however rolled out the
welcome mat marijuana stores don't
require a lot of space a lot of space
but indoor grow operations can says
public County Commissioner Terry Hart
and Pueblo County got hit pretty hard on
the recession so we had a lot of empty
commercial buildings throughout the
county that realtor's were trying
desperately to fill like some other pot
friendly communities the county made
marijuana businesses a use by right in
industrial and business districts
meaning they weren't subject to
sometimes time-consuming and arduous
special reviews or approvals by local
government but Pueblo County offered
something beyond cheap real estate
unlike Denver it had an abundance of
available agricultural land so local
officials made marijuana cultivation a
use by right here right there too
likely the first Colorado County to do
so according to Vicente and Joan
Armstrong pueblos Pueblo County's
Planning Director the county had also
issued pioneering rules that prohibit
hemp crows with male plants from being
located within five miles of existing
marijuana grows this pre this prevents
cross-pollination that can lower the
marijuana plants THC content while
increasing
THC and hemp which can exceed 0.3
percent under state law
so that does make sense although they
kind of worded this weirdly you could
tell they don't know what they're
talking about but the city also issued
rules saying that you cannot grow hemp
within 5 miles of a cannabis grow which
is a great thing because like they say
here it prevents cross-pollination which
we're not too worried about getting the
cannabis into the hemp because we're not
growing male plants outside all of our
growers are pro growers and we've gotten
rid of the mail the only mails you would
find would be on the hemp farms we don't
need the hemp farms [ __ ] up the
cannabis plants I'll continue with the
article it says even the Pueblo Board of
Water Works the local utility that
leases water for businesses and
agricultural use is trying to
accommodate the industry last year when
the barrel of Reclamation reclamation
explicitly prohibited the use of federal
water for pot cultivation water boiler
water board employees calculated that
they could lease a few eight hundred
acre feet of raw water to marijuana
cultivators without running afoul of the
feds this was completely new territory
for us his resources manager Alan Ward
who notes ninety-two acre feet of the
so-called marijuana water was already
under contract as of this May when
amendment 64 was first passed I didn't
put much thought into how it was going
to affect my job but for a few months it
seemed like it was nearly all I was
focused on the new rules are more than
paying for themselves in 2014 the county
mended 1.8 million dollars from
licensing licensing fees for pot
establishments and marijuana sales taxes
covering the cost of its virtual
marijuana Department and boosting its
general fund since marijuana remains
illegal at the federal level most banks
are still cagey about allowing pot
businesses as customers that means
county staff have gotten used to pot
owners popping tens of thousands of
dollars in cash on their desks Markinson
says charter buses filled with Wall
Street investors have been touring local
farmland there's talk of branching
pueblos grown pot along the lines of
public green chili another celebrated
local crop it has the pueblo green chile
is famous [ __ ] here we have a chili
festival in September
come get your green chilies you'll smell
them four miles away see some good bands
playing but they're trying to brand the
Pueblo Grande pot which I've been
growing public on pot for several years
if that's a marketing tactic I'm [ __ ]
on it real estate prices are rising too
industrial properties have really
doubled in price
fifty dollars per square fit square foot
just since June of 2014 says local
realtor Kendall Curtis and now that the
first outdoor grows and greenhouses are
materializing agricultural land prices
have doubled up to ten thousand dollars
an acre all in all the southern Colorado
Growers Association the local marijuana
trade orgs in an organization claims the
industry has provided 1,300 new jobs and
contributed more than a hundred and
twenty million dollars to the local
economy because I can list twenty five
people I know that have jobs because of
this boom in cannabis and they all work
at the spot there's one shop that I can
list twenty five people that are
employed because of this cannabis
industry and that is one shop and I
think there are fourteen or sixteen
shops just in Pueblo West so that's a
lot of people that are employed because
of cannabis the county was also hoping
to attract marijuana testing labs and
processing plants Pablo could be the
Silicon Valley of marijuana says
Markuson the county's economic
development director he'd prefer that
he'd prefer that to becoming Napa Valley
to a let me try that again
he'd prefer that to be coming in Napa
Valley clone the county wants to export
its products not hosts bus loads of
marijuana Taurus former Growers
Association president Tommy J Doan is a
pueblo native restaurateur and rabbit
rodeo organizer who hosts an annual
Country Music Festival east of the city
he opened a dispensary nearby but he
doesn't smoke pot I'm 49 years old he
says once they legalized it I wasn't
going to be like whoohoo I'm going to be
a pothead which that's not cool you
don't have to be a pothead just to
consume cannabis the fact that Pueblo
County wants to keep a fairly low
profile hasn't appeased the industry's
critics though marijuana hearings are
heated County Commissioners have
received threatening phone calls and
growers worries that some zealot with a
crop duster could devastate the outdoor
harvest our commissioners rushed
headlong into this without consulting
the county residents complaints public
for positive impact McPheeters
I guess that's the head the head of that
organization that allowed a glut of
marijuana stores and indoor grows to
spring up in the pueblos in Pueblo West
the unincorporated suburb where she
lives
yeah like I said they're like 14 shops
out there and you know what none of them
cause any problems we have armed
security guards people pull into our
parking lot they
walk into our store they make a purchase
just like they would any other store
there's a sandwich shop right down the
street there's a saw and tool shop right
down the street the San Isabel Electric
is right across the street people pull
up in their car they walk in and they do
business they walk back out to their car
and they drive away nothing bad happens
on our dispensary if you try to do
something stupid or our dispensary our
security guard will walk outside and
tell you to leave if I see you smoking
on the premises of our dispensary I will
tell you to get the hell out of there
I'm rude about it so you can't smoke
here get the [ __ ] out of here what
are you trying to do and you people just
drive away I've got somebody smoking in
the back while I was headed for my lunch
break they just drove away we don't
tolerate that [ __ ] we don't want it we
are a business we're not there to cause
problems were there to make money I
don't see why people are so wrapped up
and not having a dispensary around them
I'll continue with the article the
growth has come at a steep social cost
McPheeters and other critics say
marijuana related crimes including the
2014 are armed robbery of a marijuana
shop have increased according to
undersheriff Junior Hall meanwhile local
affordable housing organizations and
shelters have been flooded with families
who traveled here hoping to find jobs in
the first four months of 2015 alone 306
households relocated to public because
of marijuana says and stable men who
directs a nonprofit housing assistance
organization called Posada it is not
easy to get a good-paying job in the pot
industry settlement says many people
can't pass the background checks and
other checks needed um so these people
are saying that cannabis is causing
problems because there was a break in an
armed robbery of a marijuana shop that's
one incident and that [ __ ] happens at
gas stations and liquor stores once a
week around here and nobody says [ __ ]
about it it happened to one dispensary
and it's [ __ ] headline news I dismiss
you're one there are so many days in a
year and so many dispensaries that this
one is going to happen that's just [ __ ]
that you expect in society and then they
say these 306 households that relocated
to puebla because of marijuana we didn't
send you an invitation we didn't ask
them to come we didn't bring them here
without a job and is their fault
that's not cannabis his fault they tried
to move here without getting a job first
they tried to move here without
getting the proper paperwork to work in
the industry they moved here without
knowing how to trim they just showed up
that's not our fault
that's not cannabis is fault that's poor
planning I'm gonna continue with the
article it says and the problems could
have been and the problems could have
repercussions far beyond Pablo County
and February a local couple filed a
lawsuit US District Court claiming that
the pot girl-next-door devalued their
property it's one of two lawsuits aimed
at striking down Colorado system on the
grounds that it conflicts with federal
drug laws even if the state laws stand
pat Oglesby a tax attorney who studies
marijuana at the center for new revenue
in north carolina isn't sure how much
Pablo has head start in the reefer race
will ultimately pay off a 2015 report he
co-authored concluded that roughly 220
thousand acres of pot would supplied the
entire US market
it sounds like they have a plan they
plan it sounds like they have a plan to
really have a huge amount of supply
while other jurisdictions aren't
licensing any growers so you could see
the county gaining a short-term
advantage and having a huge market share
says Oglesby whether that is an
advantage that can be kept over time I
don't know so he's saying let's see
where did he say that 20,000 acres of
pot would supply the entire US market I
don't know how accurate that is you guys
because right now um there is no pot on
the street the street has ran out of
weed because people don't want to go to
dispensaries and right now in my area
there is usually weed abundant there's
usually some dank a syrup on the streets
if you want to sack a weed it's not a
problem to get it out for somewhere
between 150 to 200 bucks for some fire
right now an ounce weed is always 200
bucks if you can find a good outs so
something's going on there smoking up
all the weed I don't know that 20,000
acres would supply the entire US market
because there are medical patients that
smoke a half ounce a day they turn it
into concentrates or edibles and they'll
consume a half ounce a day so this guy
may be under estimating this he's going
by just numbers that have been gathered
by polls excuse me I'm burping he's
going by numbers that have been gathered
by social scientists or whatever and
those numbers are probably not accurate
because people aren't honest when people
do polls and surveys I'm gonna keep
reading you guys it says
in the meantime the townie town the tiny
town of boom population 339 in eastern
Pueblo County seems grateful for the
boost entrepreneurs Marc Morley and Jeff
EOD food plant developer originally from
the East Coast stop in Boone one
afternoon for lunch after comparing
notes on their developing grow
operations äôt bought a nearby 500 acre
ranch where he spent six point six
million installing the first 16
cutting-edge large-scale large-scale
greenhouses that will require a hundred
and fifty employees he already has
several boonies as he calls them on his
crew and he's paying some of them to fix
up the town's century-old Veterans of
Foreign Wars building were morally and
äôt dine on frozen pizzas and takis
beers at the bar yes there is still a
sign on the VFW's wall VFW's wall
declaring a zero tolerance policy for
policy for drug use the bartender Edna
Rivera doesn't flinch as the two pot
barons brainstorm about recruiting
Israeli cannabis researchers as she
rightly observes between serving up
rounds of beers if it makes money I
don't care so you guys this article is
about my hometown it makes me kind of
proud to see that we are the Silicon
Valley of marijuana I'm kind of proud to
have been in this since the beginning I
was the manager and lead budtender at
the very first and only dispensary to
ever exist in the city of Pueblo
Colorado right now there are no
dispensaries in Pueblo Colorado we had
the only shop we were shut down by the
city that makes me proud to see that we
have bloomed to become this Silicon
Valley of marijuana in this article
there are three pictures that came from
my dispensary there's a picture of our
building with our Bob Marley on it
there's a picture of our badass one of
our grow rooms with my buddy John Verna
in there what's up John I hope you're
listening bro and then I'm looking at a
picture we've got a map inside of the
dispensary and it's a map that all of
the visitors can put a pin in the state
where they're from or the city where
they're from and they put a little
picture of our map in there and it's
getting filled up you guys somebody from
every state has been to our dispensary
it looks like oh what's this appear
maybe not up in Maine and there's
somebody from me and somebody from me
and has been to our shop are you guys
I'm getting rambley I think that's
enough podcast for this week I want to
thank everybody for listening I will be
back Monday with another episode
we don't have any sponsors this week or
any products to review but if you would
like to be a sponsor or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review to send
me an email it's grow for me hard at
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you do need I would
love to test out your products on the
show here on you guys now that the show
is over please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for growth from your
heart give us a 5 star rating and after
that type in a little comment and let me
know what you think about the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode find us on all the social media
you guys we're on Facebook it's grossly
heart podcast we're on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast and we are also on instagram
i use i read genetics on instagram we're
almost at 18,000 followers i would love
for you to be one of them if you've got
social media of course you can always
email me it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com i would love to hear from
you
you guys don't forget to the show is
available on iTunes and stitcher and
every single episode is archived on ira
genetics colorado comm if you get bored
check me out on periscope once in a
while i post a video to periscope about
once a day periscope is an app you can
get it for your Android device or your
iPhone so make sure you check out
periscope I've also been putting my
periscope videos up to YouTube they are
on the IRA Genetics YouTube channel if
you want to check that out that would be
cool go ahead and click subscribe on
there I think that's all I've got for
you guys this week so yeah I'm gonna
give a big shout out to my ninja Spence
big shout out to my buddy Baker I will
be back on Monday thanks again for
listening you guys until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
[ __ ] [ __ ] so they mace me
- they can't cope with me
[Music]
yeah welcome back campus community at
Sniper episode number 93 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
this my friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my show
big thanks to evening it's finally
cooled down a little bit it's almost 9
o'clock it's been hot as [ __ ] all day
it's been hard to cool down today so I'm
excited for a little bit of coolness I
hope you're getting a little bit of
sweet weather so that your grow room is
not going crazy
these hot temps have everybody
struggling it's almost over you guys the
fall is coming it will cool down I'm
looking forward to it so we don't have
any sponsors this week you guys but we
do have some good news let's just jump
right into it I hardly ever have like
news that we want to celebrate on the
podcast and this is definitely some news
worth celebrating I just have to make my
computer cooperate here we go I'm
getting to the news article that I want
to read um this is a great headline this
an article comes from the cannabis it is
written by summer Ballentine and the
headline says Jeff Maz in ski sentenced
to life for pot freed from Missouri
prison that's right this dude spent 20
years in prison for cannabis and he has
been released from prison this picture
of him shows him with a big-ass smile
the dude looks happy to be out of prison
who wouldn't be so I've got a huge
article here let's just get right into
it make this podcast get down to
business here we go looking for the
article cuz my computer is pissing me
off here we go alright
it says Jeff Mezvinsky sentenced to life
for pot freed from Missouri prison he
says I spent a third of my life in
prison it's a shame now I 62 after
serving 20 years of a life sentence
without parole for nonviolent marijuana
related conviction fiction's the article
says from Jefferson City Missouri a man
sentenced to life in prison without
parole on a marijuana related charge was
was freed Tuesday from Missouri prison
after
being behind bars for two decades a
period in which the nation's attitudes
toward pot have steadily softened family
friends supporters and reporters flocked
to meet Jeff Minsky as he stepped out of
the Jefferson City Correctional Center
into a sunny morning wearing a pair of
white tennis shoes and a shirt that read
I'm Jeff and I'm free
I want to shirt that says I'm Jeff and
I'm free I mean I'm Jeff and I'm free
[ __ ] will keep going it says he says I
spent a third of my life in prison said
mizanskey now 62 it was greeted by his
infant great-granddaughter it's a shame
after a breakfast of steak and eggs with
family Basinski said he planned to spend
his post prison life seeking a job in
advocating for the legalization of
marijuana
he criticized sentencing for some
drug-related crimes is unfair and
described his time behind bars as hell
his release followed years of lobbying
by relatives lawmakers and others who
argued that the sentence was too stiff
and that marijuana should not be
forbidden Lozinski was sinced in 1996
the same year California became the
first state to legalize marijuana for
medical purposes medical marijuana is
now legal in 23 states and recreational
marijuana has been legalized in Alaska
Colorado Oregon Washington State and
Washington DC the reason he's getting
out is because the public clearly has
changed it's changed its opinion about
marijuana and it's just one of many ways
in which that has been reflected in
recent years Edmonds in skis attorney
Dan meets such extreme cases should
further feel changing perceptions of
nonviolent drug crime sent Michelle
deach a senior lecturer at the lyndon b
johnson School of Public Affairs at the
University of Austin at Texas that's a
long title geez school johnson lyndon b
johnson School of Public Affairs at the
University of Austin Texas I'm glad I
don't have to say that [ __ ] in my title
every day I say hi I'm Ross too Jeff so
much easier the article says these cases
really become Exhibit A in the need for
sentencing reform said D I think that's
how you said that an attorney and expert
in criminal justice policy just last
year the heavily Republican Missouri
Legislature passed a law to allow
certain people with epsilen epilepsy to
seek treatment with the marijuana
extracting extract containing little of
the chemical that causes marijuana users
to feel high and larger amounts of a
chemical called Kenneth cannabidiol or
CBD
the patient's can include babies Veet
said nobody saw that coming he said
that's a pretty radical statement police
said he conspired to sell six pounds of
marijuana to a dealer connected with the
Mexican drug cartels at the time the
life with no parole sentences was
allowed under a Missouri law for repeat
drug offenders mizanskey already had to
drug convention convictions one for
possession and one for sale of marijuana
in 1984 and another for possessing
possession in 1991 he was the only
Missouri inmate serving such a sentence
for a nonviolent marijuana related
offense when Democratic governor jay
Nixon agreed in May to commute his
sentence commutation allowed mizanskey
to argue for his freedom before a parole
board which granted his request in
August
Nixon Nixon's actions are a reflection
of political confidence in changing
norms around marijuana use said Cecilia
clincal a criminal justice policy expert
at the University of Wisconsin law
school the governor cited mizanskey 'z
nonviolent record noting that none of
his offenses involved selling drugs to
children the law under which he was
originally sentenced has since been
changed
other states are reevaluating punishment
for drug possession crimes motivated in
large in large part by the high cost of
imprisoning low-level nonviolent
offenders you guys imagine how much it
cost to keep this dude in prison for
twenty years we could have sent people
to it cost more money to send people to
prison for years than it does to send
somebody to college is what I recently
read we probably could've send three or
four he was in there for twenty years
probably could have send five or ten
people to college for the cost that it
cost to house him and nothing came of it
maybe maybe in the long term he will
affect people being released maybe he
did some good I think that's called a
martyr is that what he was maybe he was
a martyr so maybe it was worth it for
the movement but not for him and not for
you no but they could have [ __ ]
educated some people for this cost I'm
gonna keep reading my article here it
says in Connecticut a new law will make
possession of small amounts of hard
drugs including heroin cocaine and crack
cocaine a misdemeanor for a first-time
offense rather than allowing for the
current maximum seven-year prison
sentence Nebraska and Alabama expect to
save hundreds of millions of dollars by
using new laws to cut down on the number
of offenders locked up for possessing
small amounts of drugs in Missouri
backers of two ballot initiatives to
legalize pot have permission from the
Secretary of State to begin collecting
signatures to put the issue before
voters in 2016 another petition proposes
reducing sentences for nonviolent drug
offenders or serving time without
opportunity for parole bosanski said he
will not smoke marijuana now that he's
free he's on parole after all but if it
ever becomes legal on the state and
federal level mizanskey said definitely
so big congratulations welcome home I
think he's gonna help out the movement
if they're releasing one guy
why aren't they gonna start releasing
all of the people who are in jail
anybody that committed any nonviolent
cannabis crime I think they should all
just start releasing them just go and
lock the cage and let those dudes out
and I'm a joint and 100 bucks and send
them on their way
all right that's uh my good news that is
my good news I do have some other good
news this is article number two this one
comes from the cannabis also I have to
give you a little ketchup story behind
this recently let me see if they tell
you in this okay there was recently a
bunch of marijuana products in Colorado
that were taken off of the shelves
because they were suspected of having
been produced with cannabis that had
been sprayed with pesticides that are
banned from the marijuana production
laws we have what's called the marijuana
Enforcement Division and they have made
laws in conjunction with the Department
of Agriculture to regulate the sprays
that can be put on these plants so
recently on the first a bunch of these
edibles and products were taken off of
shelves because they were suspected to
have been made with contaminated
cannabis I had that article planned to
read to you when I opened up my computer
today and went reading for news and
seeing what was going on the cannabis
has posted this article and it says
update Denver pot products passed
pesticide test hold lifted so I'm gonna
say that one more time just to make it
clear a denver pot products passed
pesticide test and the hold has been
lifted the sub-headline says marijuana
products from mountain high suckers and
MMJ america showed no trace of an
unapproved pesticide listed among their
ingredients the company owners said they
were using old labeling so here we go oh
there's articles by David McCoy ax from
The Denver Post I found it on the
cannabis tea and it goes like this
Denver Health officials Wednesday lifted
a day old order to hold hundreds of
marijuana infused Lawson jizz and raw
marijuana from two businesses after lab
tests showed no trace of unapproved
pesticides did among their ingredients
the owners of Mountain High suckers and
MMJ America each said they had been
using old labels they included among
their ingredients a pesticide that today
is not approved for marijuana use the
pesticide spinosad had not been barred
for use when the labels were made the
owner said it looks like this was just
an unfortunate labeling issue said dan
roland denver spokesman for its office
for its Office of Marijuana Policy sorry
for my stumble there a state law
requires marijuana companies to list on
their product labels all pesticides
contaminates and herbicides used in the
production process the city's
enforcement action is the latest in a
series of actions related to pesticides
used on recreational and medical
marijuana because the drug remains
illegal under federal law the US
Environmental Protection Agency will not
establish any allowable pesticide uses
on marijuana
technically no regulated pesticide can
be legally used on marijuana but state
agriculture officials have said as long
as its use does not violate it
pesticides label warnings and
restrictions it can be used on Monday
Denver Warren businesses that products
listing of unapproved pesticides should
be removed from shelves and destroyed or
returned to the manufacturer inspectors
ordered tests on the product holds
Tuesday after spotting spinosad listed
among other ingredients of mountain
highs lozenges and raw marijuana at MMJ
America shop on a rapaho Street excuse
me the test did not detect spinosad city
officials confirmed mountain-high had
been using old labels from when it
purchased marijuana trimming from a
grower that had been using spinosad
mountain-high co-owner Chad Tribble said
that was before the state said it could
not he said back then it wasn't a
problem Tribble said he just didn't look
back on the labels it was a mistake it
was on there but the tests were clear
undetected we've never had a black mark
before now said now he said news of the
city's action brought calls from as far
as Las Vegas not only did we test
negative for all pesticides we were told
by the city that just crossing off the
name because we're already had the bags
printed was acceptable MMJ owner Jake
Salazar that's what MMG owner Jake
Salazar said officials later told him he
needs to reprint the labels we order
pre-printed bags 70,000 units every time
last time we ordered them this wasn't a
banned substance we now have to throw
all of those bags away and reorder
70,000 more without that ingredient
which we clearly don't use Salazar said
the state's list of pesticides approved
for use on marijuana has been in the
drafting stage for about 18 months the
state will not say the pesticides are
safe for use on marijuana only that
their use does not violate label
restrain
on how they should be used some
pesticides are so non-toxic that the EPA
does not require them to be registered
nor restrict their use those can be used
on marijuana but the industry has
complained that they aren't potent
enough to eradicate the kinds of pests
and mildews that can decimate a crop
potentially worth millions of dollars
the city in the spring held more than a
100,000 marijuana plants at 11 grow
operations over concerns that unapproved
pesticides had been used on them so this
article was from David McCoy a-- and
those products did not test for spinosad
they were using old labels now this
really sparks a little bit of question
in my mind because I advocate spinosad I
like spinosad I've used a spinosad
recently so this has me thinking I need
to go in here and go to the Department
of Agriculture website and figure out
why or whichever website it is it may be
the meed
I need to go and figure out why I'm not
allowed to use spinosad because I run a
shop I run a grow at a shop I need to
find this list of pesticides I'm not
quite sure where I find this list of
pesticides I'm sure that the operations
manager at the dispensary has it so I
ask him for that list we're not at that
point yet so I don't need to know that
but I'm sure the marijuana Enforcement
Division webpage has a list of approved
or unapproved pesticides all you gotta
do is go there and look I really want to
know why spinosad has been banned
because I use that quite quite often I
will definitely figure out why because
something that will help prevent this um
every dispensary will now be required to
train all plant handlers in pesticide
management everybody every dispensary
needs on staff one person that can train
every new employee on pesticide safety
and to be able to train them you have to
be certified by the Department of
Agriculture you have to take an
applicator safety test and I have been
required to do that since I am the lead
grower at this spot dispensary so I will
be taking I will be studying and taking
that test and then I will know a lot of
stuff about pesticides and we will find
out why spinosad is unacceptable um the
Department of Agriculture representative
actually told me the reason that Eagle
20 is not allowed in commercial
drum roll please because when it burns
it turns into cyanide that's what the
guy from the Department of Agriculture
told me it had nothing to do with the
danger and toxicity of the chemical it
was actually because when it turns if
there's a fire it turns into cyanide and
the fire department doesn't want to deal
with that I found that rather
interesting all right guys I have got
one more news article this one is from
local news here this one comes from the
beautiful city of Pueblo Colorado I
talked a little bit about Pueblo last
time on the last episode talking about
how Colorado and Pueblo in general was
booming with cannabis and Pueblo
Colorado may become the may already be
the new Emerald triangle so this article
says funding college scholarships via
pot grows proposed in southern Colorado
so headline says gosh excuse my throat
I'm gonna take a drink before we even
get into this I'm gonna take a drink and
then I'm gonna take a DAB
hmm all right that was a good drink
excuse the throat claret on the podcast
I probably won't even edit that so I'm
sorry so far there's no editing to be
done in this show and I like it I'm
getting a DAB ready you guys I'm getting
ready some amnesia haze from our friends
at Colorado's best dad's I'm about to
take a fat chunky dab I'm getting it
going I hope you guys are gonna take a
dab with me on the podcast if you're
listening to the show get a DAB ready
get a ball ready if you're at work or
something sneak your vape in out let's
do it you guys let's get stoned together
on the count of six four five six
you
that's how we do it we take dad's in the
middle of the podcast we used to smoke
so much more hash on this show I've been
trying to get it a little tighter and
not be dad the [ __ ] out
it also helps my throat last longer all
right so well yeah that's it Anita Hayes
from Colorado's best dad's and it makes
my head [ __ ] spin it's so great he
gets me amped up
it makes me lively hypothetically if I
were going to come home on my lunch
break and smoke a bunch of dabs and need
to go back to work all energized and in
the zone hypothetically I would take 4
dabs of that and I'd be in the [ __ ]
zone when I went back to work
ah all right before I get onto this next
news article I am going to mention that
I am recording this podcast live on
periscope what up all my friends on
periscope thanks for watching if you
guys don't know what periscope is make
sure you or don't make sure but please I
invite you to use your Android device or
your iPhone device or your Apple device
and download an app called periscope and
then look for me I'm Ross to Jeff for 20
mazie to find look for me on there
follow me and usually daily I will do a
DAB on periscope with my friends you'll
get a chance to ask me a question and I
will rant for several minutes on your
question if it gets my brain going so
check me out on periscope you guys big
shout out to everybody that's watching
on periscope right now what up Nemo punk
what up El Diablo I can't see who else
is on there unless they send a comment
or something but what up to everybody
that's on there thanks for joining me I
hope you will join me on my next
periscope video sometimes I randomly
decide that I want to put the podcast on
periscope while I'm doing it and right
now it's kind of cool because I feel
like I'm talking to somebody there's
somebody just someone to look at instead
of just staring into the computer over
here I'm looking at my periscope trends
I can't see them but it feels like
they're there all right I've got another
news article up on the screen I took a
DAB and got all [ __ ] a TD inside
track but shoutout to dabs
let's read this article I read the
headline right funding caller funding
college scholarships be a pot roast
proposed in southern Colorado the sub
headline says Pablo County Commissioner
Sal pace says he hopes the measure that
would Institute a 5 percent excise tax
on wholesale marijuana transfers will
give Pablo kids a boost I am going to
read this article
and I have mixed opinions on this right
now but it's by Jessie Paul it's from
the Denver Post I of course found it on
our favorite news website the Cannabis
you guys I don't bring you all of the
news I select a few I pick and choose
what I think is best for the audience if
you don't get enough news from me I can
definitely recommend to the cannabis
high-quality cannabis news it's ran by a
dude named ricardo Baca who was a really
cool dude I support that [ __ ] go check
it out if you don't get enough from me
all right the article goes like this if
webelo county commissioner is proposing
a ballot measure for a program to fund
college scholarships through a marijuana
excise tax commissioner Sal pace says he
hopes the new measure will give webelo
kids a boost and help fight college debt
the County Commission is set to vote at
their Monday meeting on whether or not
the proposal will be placed on November
ballot elections the excise tax would be
levied when marijuana is transferred
from cultivation to a store Aces Office
said in a news release Wednesday he said
that Wednesday sorry I read that really
weird
Pablo counties perfect economic and
weather conditions have created a boom
of recreational cultivations without yet
generating a tax on these groves
beginning in 2017 graduating seniors
from all high schools and pueblos who
attend a public college or university in
Pueblo County will be eligible for
scholarships from the proposed program
that release said every kid deserves an
opportunity to succeed they said in a
statement
Pablo County has potential new tax
revenue from a marijuana industry that
can benefit the kids of pueblos the
ballot measure would propose a five
percent excise tax on recreational
marijuana grows from Pueblo County it
asks that on an annual basis no less
than 50% of tax revenue be designated
for scholarships fifty percent well if
you're doing it for this shouldn't a
hundred where's the other fifty going
Sal where is the other 50% going okay
the rest of the revenue would be used on
community projects like Colorado State
Fairs streetscape refurbishment medical
marijuana academic research and a
feasibility study on the potential
connection of Amtrak south and track
Southwest Chief to Pueblo and those all
sound like feasible options those seem
like they're worth some investment the
program may be expanded in future years
depending on revenue the really
said Tyler Henson president president of
the Colorado cannabis Chamber of
Commerce said he hopes the chin the
County Commission will fully examine the
measure before sending it to the ballot
under amendment 64 we gave local
governments two permission to make these
excise taxes he said I would just
caution the County Commissioners to look
at how this will affect sales in Pueblo
and be surrounding areas that's the
first thing I think of they're gonna add
5% more tax the tax is already really
high in Pueblo it's approximately 25
percent I don't know the exact
percentage to tell you the truth guys if
anybody on periscope maybe an emo Punk
if you want to throw up the actual
percentage of tax I'll say that on the
air
and I'll give you a shout-out also make
sure you guys follow my friend emo Punk
15 on Twitter he posts a lot of great
cannabis [ __ ] seventeen and a half
percent plus the 10 percent excise tax
that already exists so that's 27 percent
plus they're going to add another five
which will make it 32 percent excise tax
so this extra excise tax is just gonna
end up falling on the customer in the
end no matter how it works which is
going to make cannabis tax 32 percent
here in Pueblo which means it's gonna be
roughly $185 for a quarter of cannabis
which is ridiculous when you can go to
the street and you can get probably you
can get an ounce for that price on the
street you can get an ounce for $200 you
can get outs for 150 dollars on the
street and Pueblo Colorado so this is
going to turn around and put everybody
back at the black-market they're just
gonna ruin it they're trying to squeeze
too much blood out of one turnip I think
is what my grandma used to said trying
to squeeze blood out of a turnip I think
I think that's what these guys are
trying to do and they're gonna crash the
whole Marijuana thing all right you guys
I think that's enough podcast for this
week I'm gonna wrap this up I'm gonna go
see fish this weekend so when I come
back on Monday I will have a lot of cool
[ __ ] to talk about I want to thank you
guys for listening to another episode I
wanna thank all my friends on periscope
for joining me
thanks to Nemo punk thanks to El Diablo
thanks to all my friends that are on
there we don't have any sponsors this
week if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast send me an email it's girlfriend
hard at hotmail.com we'll get you all
the information that you do need you can
sponsor the show oh you guys now that
the show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for girl from
your heart
give me a five star rating please five
stars that'd be really cool and then
type
a little comment let me know what you
think about the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode I love
hearing what people have to say about
the show so um yeah once you guys follow
me on all the social media sites please
find me on Facebook it's uh grow from
your heart find me on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast don't forget you guys the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is available on I
read genetics Colorado com if you want
to follow follow me on Instagram dude
it's a diary genetics I should be at
18,000 followers by the time you check
it out I hope that you can be one of
those 18,000 followers I don't have a
lot else to say so I'm gonna wrap up the
show and go take some fat dabs only give
a big shout out to manager Spence thanks
again for listening until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
episode number 94 of the girl from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation activist
or even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host
they call me Rasta Jeff I want to thank
you guys for joining me as always I need
to send a huge thank-you shoutout to my
friends in the mystic roots band for
letting me use their music on the show
big thanks to catch the entire afternoon
at the spot dispensary for the day it's
hot as [ __ ] today it's about 90 degrees
conditioners we've done a little bit of
construction and some rebuilding so we
were testing everything out today
putting in some more putting in some
hours hope everyone's having a great day
if you are ever in southern Colorado if
you're in the Pueblo Colorado or the
Pueblo West area please stop by the spot
dispensary drop in if you need some
cannabis if you need some hash if you
need some edibles if you need some
topicals would love to see you at the
spot if you listen to the podcast drop
in tell them that you listen to the
podcast ask if I'm there if I am there
and I'm not busy they may call me from
the back and I may come out and shake
your hand and say hello it'd be great to
meet you that just kind of depends on
who's working and who's there if they're
able to do that they'll come get me and
I'll come say hi to you I'd love to meet
you anyway I've got a bunch of great
stuff to talk about today you guys I've
got some news articles I've got some
stuff like that but first I want to talk
about my weekend man I got to see my
favorite band if you guys know me you
know that my favorite band is Phish
I got to see - Phish shows over the
weekend I saw Saturday and Sunday night
at the Dick's Sporting Goods park in
Commerce City Colorado Saturday was a
pretty good show but sunday was a really
spectacular show they did some great
songs they did stuff they haven't played
in several years the band sounded great
the crowd was in a good mood everything
was amazing the only thing that kind of
sucked and it didn't suck really but my
favorite song from fish I think my
favorite song is called punch you in the
eye and the middle section of punch you
in the high is a jam that has been
labeled the landlady the landlady was
written first
punch you in the eye was written the
landlady was dropped into the middle of
punch you in the eyes the groove portion
and it's always been played as one piece
since then but on Sunday night they
opened with the landlady which is the
middle section of my favorite song so it
was a little disappointing knowing that
I wasn't gonna hear my favorite song
through the whole weekend but it was
okay because they made up for it by
playing some like I said some old songs
that I haven't heard in a long time and
stuff that they have not played in
several years if anybody hears a Phish
fan they played hard puah that means a
lot to people if you're a fish man they
don't play her pool very often and when
they do play hard pool it's a really
great thing so that's enough rambling
about the fish concert I had a great
time big shout out to fish they put on a
hell of a show it was the end of the
summer tour they played a Dan the life
by the Beatles they played a water they
played Talking Heads cover they played
after midnight they played a lot of
great [ __ ] so big shout out the fish I
had a wonderful time shot to everybody I
met on the fish lot I got to advertise
the podcast to a couple of people big
shout out to those folks if you're
listening now also shout out to Danielle
for being a great fishing companion I
had a great time with you thanks for
coming with me so it's enough ranting
about fish um you guys we got a new
comment on iTunes there might be two new
comments I don't remember if I read this
one or not so I'm gonna head to iTunes
right click and we will read this
comment and then I think we're gonna get
right into some news so let's read these
comments this comment comes from Eden
2013 and this was left August 27 so this
is a good chance I've read this but I
take a lot of dabs on the show so
there's a chance I did not read this I
don't remember it says educated and
entertained and they gave us five stars
it says thank you for this podcast I
appreciate how organized and articulate
you are I've learned so much I also love
your hippie love attitude great show I'm
looking forward to the college level
grow lessons you promised for episode
100 peace I think I read that because I
remember reading the college grow
lessons I promised those won't be on
episode 100 but they will after my
episode 100 I do kind of plan on kicking
up the education level on this podcast
I've gone kind of the intro level you
know what I mean you've had your
introductory courses from me if you've
been listening to all 90 something
episodes it's time for you to step up
your game and we're gonna start learning
a little bit more in depth [ __ ] after
episode 100 all right it's a big shout
out to our friend eat in 2013 you left a
sweet calm
and you gave me five stars I appreciate
that thanks a lot you did what you were
told there's nothing [ __ ] colder than
that
we've got another comment it comes from
our friend teacher from Philly and it
says five stars from Philly they gave me
five stars this comment was left
September 2nd it says I've been
listening for a while now and I have
some experience with your seeds I just
dropping a message to let you know I
appreciate the show knowledge is key so
thanks for sharing did you're very
welcome thanks for teaching it sounds
like you're a teacher that says teacher
from Philly it sounds like you're a
teacher I appreciate any type of teacher
I know how it is to be a teacher it's
hard it takes a lot of work and
dedication so I appreciate that I also
want to say thank you for noticing and
thanks for the comment that's really
awesome you guys I would love it if you
left a comment on iTunes just go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
girl from your heart click on it go to
the review section give me a five star
review and then type in a little comment
let me know what you think and I will
read your comment on a future episode
just like I did these so big thanks to
Eden 2013 and teacher from Philly I
appreciate those comments you guys
alright I've got a few news articles I
want to read but a lot of you guys are
out there smoking some cannabis right
now a lot if you were taking some dabs a
lot of your hittin the vaporizer a lot
of you or maybe eating some edibles or
whatever you're doing what I want to do
I want to do a DAB with everybody right
now and if you're not able to take a DAB
if you're listening to this podcast in
your cubicle or in the shop or in your
car and you're unable to take a fat dab
right now
then this dab that I'm about to take is
for you if you're somewhere where you're
able to take a DAB I want you to get a
DAB ready and I want you to dab with me
so start getting it ready I've got the
email so I'm already hot all I gotta do
is get it ready so right now I'm getting
a DAB ready you got a nice chunky dab
what am i smoking here I'm smoking some
candy crush some shatter it's real nice
and ambery real clear oh it's real real
shatter II so we're gonna put some of
this on the dabber here I've almost got
it ready alright now I want you guys to
start heating your nail usually takes
somewhere between 10 and 20 seconds so
if you need more time
I'll let you have it I'm kind of trying
to hesitate but it's hard to hesitate on
a podcast alright it's about dad time
you guys I'm getting the rig up to my
face all right I want everybody
listening to take a DAB with me right
now this would be a big group dab and
then we're gonna read some news and if
you cannot take a DAB all of us that are
dabbing are thinking about all of the
people that are at work or wherever they
are on the bus in a taxi if you're in an
uber you can probably smoke some weed
most uber drivers don't give a [ __ ] if
you smoke out there uber ride so if
you're in a noob er if no excuse get
down on a bowl get down on a dab but
here we go guys this is a group dab
let's do this on the count of six four
five six here we go fat dabs yeah that's
what I like I don't take a stab or the
waters got to be murky or something I
hope everybody got to take a dab with me
it is if you weren't able to take a DAB
I hope you're feeling the debt that I
just took I hope you're feeling the love
I hope you're feeling the vibe I really
appreciate you guys for joining me for a
dab all right I've been talking about
some news articles and I've been
rambling for a few minutes so let's open
up these news articles and just to uh
just for a disclaimer I know that
earlier in the future in the past
episode I said that I was gonna get more
into grow lessons I will do that I have
been doing that I've got a lot of stuff
coming up I've got a CBD episode coming
up I've got a few episodes in the works
that are partial episodes I'm taking
notes and getting [ __ ] ready but there
has been so much news that I feel it's
my responsibility to bring this news to
you so here comes the first news article
I found this article on the cannabis and
it was written by John Murray of the
Denver Post the headline says Denver's
social pot use plans are getting
overhauled the subway headline says the
idea isn't dead backers of the proposal
say they will join talks with city and
business leaders to try to work out a
compromise so the article goes like this
activists behind a proposed Denver
ballot initiative to allow some
marijuana use in bars and other
businesses say they will pull them
The Denver Post has confirmed their new
goal drafting a compromise measure with
city and business leaders the verbal
agreement with a group that includes
city attorney Scott Martinez averts a
public vote in November when they might
have allowed more extensive pot
consumption in publicly accessible
places than city officials and some
business leaders were comfortable with
Mason divert of the Marijuana Policy
Project said fellow backers of the
limited social cannabis use initiative
plan to announce the withdrawal Thursday
before Friday's expected certification
of the measure for the November third
ballot activists now will shift to
working with city officials and the
state restaurant and Lodging
associations to work out an ordinance
that they hope will be considered by the
Denver Council or by the City Council
excuse me within the next year the
downtown Denver partnership which
represents business interests in that
area also plans to take part
we're not approaching the withdrawal of
this initiative lightly said divert who
also was a co-author of Colorado's
marijuana legalizing amendment 64 in
2012 we believe that cannabis users
derive deserve the freedom and let me
try that again
we believe that cannabis users deserve
the freedom to congregate and socialize
to the same extent as alcohol users any
guys I'm gonna interject here when we
set up this cannabis system that we have
the whole model they modeled it after
was to make it like alcohol they wanted
to regulate it like alcohol and we're
all able to go to so many places and
drink alcohol all night long why aren't
there a few places for us to go and take
some dabs and smoke some flowers and
hang out with our friends we don't
always have to be at my house sitting at
the dab table we should be able to go
somewhere else there are so many stoners
out there that I don't know because
they're all at their house on their
couch taking dabs cuz they don't come to
my house and sit on my couch and take
dabs so we're never gonna meet if we had
a social club we'd go meet each other so
that way when somebody got tired of
smoking what am i smoking if I got tired
of smoking can't be cush I could go
trade them I can't be cush for some of
their OG Kush or whatever I'm just
making a nice little community a nice
little network I'm gonna keep on with
the article it says they found ready
support in the ballot petitioning
process turning in ten thousand seven
hundred signatures more than twice as
many as needed
although Denver police have shut down
private cannabis clubs of the city's
Marijuana Policy office this year began
examining
as an evolving regulatory mean to the
potential of allowing some social use of
marijuana
the idea came up in council race lap
races last spring with some successful
candidates open to the idea in part
because tourists lack places to consume
their purchases legally that's very true
you guys you can come to Colorado and if
you're not from here if you've got an
out-of-state license you can purchase up
to 7 grams of cannabis you can purchase
up to 7 grams of hash you can purchase
seven grams total in any combination of
edibles hash tinctures and topicals but
what you can't do once you've made the
purchase there's nowhere to [ __ ]
smoke you can't go to the hotel and
smoke because they don't allow smoking
you can't go to the park because that's
illegal
unless you know somebody you just have
all this cannabis that you can't smoke
and you're not allowed to take it to
your home state to smoke it because it's
illegal to travel across state lines
with it so I think that this smoking
lounge type of an environment is
something that we really really need
I'll continue with the article that says
but city efforts were in early stages
went Evert and brand facin T of cannabis
focused law firm vicente sinner burg
both frustrated with what they saw as an
action began to push for the initiative
to virt and several people involved in
the recent talk say it's too soon to
predict what will result options could
range from a narrow ordinance allows
private clubs to a more extensive law
that would break new ground in colorado
by allowing patrons of some bars to vape
inside or smoke outside as the
initiative proposed the initiative
withdrawal ensures we now have the time
and ability to include all interested
stakeholders to reach consensus on this
important issue said councilman Albus
Brooks who represents most of downtown
I'm committed to working on a broadly
acceptable solution but finding common
ground for an expansion of the current
law which restricts consumption mostly
to private residents might prove tricky
there's also the chance that a consensus
proposal won't go far enough for the
activists while Mayor Michael Hancock
administration took no position on the
proposed initiative the City Attorney's
Office questioned the legality of its
scope even state laws against public
consumption that its lawyers viewed as
conflicting and Sonya Riggs president
and CEO of the Colorado Restaurant
Association expressed adamant opposition
on behalf of about half of the state's
restaurants in part based on concerns
that insurers might drop coverage of
all restaurants because of liability
concerns this week the Colorado Hotel
and Lodging Association metro Denver
lodging Council and Colorado Restaurant
Association said in a statement that
they appreciated the activist withdrawal
of the initiative our respective
industries are committed to working with
the promote the proponents and the city
to find a solution that reflects the
interests and concerns of all
stakeholders their statement said the
proposed initiative divided Denver
restaurant and bar owners who would have
had the option to allow marijuana use
riggs said Wednesday that she would
approach the discussion with an open
mind
I do understand there's a concern from
their part that they need to have that
they need to have addressed she said of
initiative backers just as there's a
concern from our side for their part
city officials say they can't offer
assurances they also plan to gather
input from neighborhood and community
groups on the issue we can't guarantee
an outcome on it obviously but it's
something we've been looking at said
Ashley Kilroy Hancock's executive
director for Marijuana Policy we do
believe that there's area for a
conversation around this and that
there's a lot of other considerations
Martinez said his office isn't drawing
bright lines allowing policymakers to
consider all options first I'm not going
to throw down the legal hammer until we
were specific proposals he said until
there are specific proposals he said
sorry the word proposals is out of the
quotations so that was confusing until
our specific proposals he said adding
we're all working to find clarity within
the law so that people can operate with
certainty if activists are dissatisfied
with the coming decisions though they
will have a fallback option going back
to the ballot on their own next year at
a presidential election that probably
will have wider turnout than this fall
divert sees an even greater change for
passage but he said a successful
compromise with city officials and other
interests has more likely to result in a
law that we know the city would be
comfortable with and will not resist and
will actually implement so they pulled
their ballot so that they can rewrite it
where they can actually make it a little
bit more fair for the businesses and for
the people who want to consume so the
law or the proposal is not dead they're
going to rewrite it and they're gonna
try again it sounds like the city of
Denver wants to work with the cannabis
consumers it seems like the understand
of the revenue that is available they
understand the need
and they mentioned in this article that
out-of-staters don't have anywhere to
consume which is the main problem here
if those out-of-staters had somewhere to
consume they would go there they would
consume and then they're gonna get
hungry they're gonna get thirsty and
they're going to need entertainment
which is going to cause them or and not
cause them but yeah will cause them to
go spend more money and participate in
our economy and be part of our state's
cash flow a little better all right guys
I'm gonna go blow my nose I'm catching a
little bit of a head cold but I will be
right back all right guys I am back I
apologize if my voice sounds a little
bit nasally this week I'm catching a
little bit of a head cold I'm trying to
fight it off but like any other
professional this show must go on so I'm
doing the podcast and making the best of
it for you I appreciate you guys for
tolerating my a little bit of sniffles
and a little bit of a nasally voice all
right I've got another news article here
for you guys this is grounds for
celebration this may become a holiday in
Colorado if they continue to do this
annually the article here came from the
cannabis and it was written by Kristen
Wyatt from The Associated Press and the
headline says get ready for the one day
tax holiday on Colorado weed excuse me
guys I gotta take a drink here then I'll
get the show on the road all right so
the sub headline says we're thinking
there will be huge crowds says a shop
owner about the September 16 break on
the hefty Colorado marijuana tax on
recreational weed thanks to the tabor
law all right so that sounds confusing
to a lot of people but taxes are
ridiculously high on cannabis here in
Colorado and we're going to have a 1-day
tax free cannabis day in Colorado let me
read the article I'll explain it to you
Colorado's unusual tax laws forcing the
state to suspend taxes on recreational
marijuana for one day the sales tax
break down the sales tax break on
September 16th will save $20 off the
prices of a mid-grade
ounce of pot in the Denver area where
ounces this summer sell for about $200
before tax it's unusual for a state that
has many times rejected sales tax
holidays on things like school supplies
clothing or any of energy efficient
appliances officials say it could cost
the state 3 to 4 million dollars in one
day you guys they're going to lose 3 to
4 million dollars in taxes in a single
day
article goes on to say at first I was in
disbelief we were doing this said Cheri
Hackett who owns botanic air a
dispensary in the Denver suburb of
northglenn any guys that's boat and
Karen aa boat an acre the nutrient line
it's two separate businesses um once our
lawyers said no we really are doing this
we started getting ready or thinking
there will be huge crowds packet is
bringing science to alert customers to
the holiday and is trying to boost
inventory for a one-day crush of
businesses Colorado's taxpayer Bill of
Rights requires voter approval for new
taxes in 2013 a year after legalizing
recreational pot voters approved the 25
percent taxes but the law requires that
any new taxes be waived and refunded if
overall State collections exceed
projections given to voters when they
approved the new taxes in this case the
pot taxes were projected to raise 70
million dollars in 2014 they actually
raised 58 million dollars but because
overall tax collections that year
exceeded predicted projections Colorado
must ask voters for permission to keep
the money and it comply with the
requirement that the taxes revert to
zero lawmakers settled on a short one
day tax waiver that day is September
16th one day after the state's books for
the previous fiscal year are made final
all right so if you guys want to come to
Colorado and buy a quarter of cannabis
at a shop September 16th would be your
day to do it there will be no taxes
marijuana won't be completely tax free
that day a regular 2.9 percent sales tax
still applies as do medical marijuana
taxes and local pot taxes all right so
the extra local taxes that we pay here
in pueblo will still be tacked on for
pot retailers the holiday poses a
bizarre supply dilemma don't want plenty
of wheat on hand to sell to throngs of
pot shoppers but if they stock too much
product they'll forego their one-day
waiver on the 15% excise tax they pay
marijuana wholesalers a savvy retailer
would want to have shelves full enough
to supply crowds but bare enough to take
maximum of an advantage of the
restocking without paying excise taxes
before the business closes September 16
Ryan Fox who owns two denver
dispensaries and also a wholesale
partnering company hasn't decided what
sorts of deals to offer that day but
he's anticipating a windfall our hopes
are high and we're going to push as hard
as we can to see as many customers as we
can
Colorado voters will decide in November
whether to keep the pot taxes the 2013
taxing measure passed two-to-one and
state politicians seemed confident
voters will reauthorize the taxes the
state constitution requires refunds only
in a new tax and in new taxes first year
so voters won't be asked again all right
I read that a little weird so I'm gonna
read that last line again it says the
state constitution requires refunds only
any new taxes first year so voters won't
be asked again I kind of read that funny
the first time but this only comes up
when a tax is in its first year so they
won't be asking us this again the one
day tax break won't put too much of a
dent in the state's overall pot revenue
Colorado's pot collections are blooming
marijuana tax read revenues jumped from
25 million in the first five months of
2014 to 44 million in the first five
months of this year the increase has
been attributed to additional stores
opening Colorado now has 380
recreational pot dispensaries and 480
licensed recreational pot growers up
from a few dozen in the state's first
month of retail recreational pot any
guys those 480 recreational growers are
actually commercial growers that only
vend two dispensaries recreational
dispensaries that does not include
private grows so there are a lot more
private grows that are not counted so
you guys we made so much tax money that
we have to give our state a tax break
all the customers that come to buy
cannabis on September 16th will not have
to pay the regular cannabis tax so it's
gonna be awesome so if you come from out
of state we hope to see you at the spot
dispensary on September 16th if you come
from out of state if you come from
anywhere
make sure you ask for me I'll try to
come out from the back and say hi shake
your hand and see what's up
you know what I won't be at work on
September 16th that's funny I won't be
there so don't come to say hi to me I'm
seeing Morgan heritage and Damian Marley
and Taurus Riley on September 15th and
there's a good chance I will not show up
for work on the 16th so enjoy your
tax-free day without me that sounds like
fun
all right I've got another news article
to read to you I've actually got a
couple more let's see how long we've
been recording you know what let's see
we've been going 21 minutes all right I
can get two news articles and in the
next 10 or 15 minutes let's do this so
this article I've got two articles that
I'm gonna read back to back this one
came out on September 8th and then the
next article came out shortly after that
it came out on September 9th so they are
related articles I'm gonna go ahead and
get into the first one this is once
again from the cannabis written by David
McCoy and Ricardo Baca the headline says
Denver recalls mahatma pot extract over
unapproved pesticides the order comes
after an investigation by the Denver
Post and lab testing revealed three
unapproved pesticides in a pair of
Mahatma concentrates products the
article goes on like this state and
Denver inspectors on Tuesday ordered a
recall of marijuana extract sold by
Mahatma concentrates at the Denver Post
revealed contained high levels of
unapproved pesticides Mahatma colon or
Brett Mouser confirmed the recall of
products that were derived from
marijuana plants run by a supplier
treatments unlimited treatments Kohinoor
has acknowledged the denver company used
the unapproved pesticides treatments
earlier this year had a number of its
plants quarantined by city officials
because the pesticides can turn concerns
and later released tuesday's recall was
ordered by the denver department of
environment or environmental health and
the colorado marijuana enforcement
division following a story by the post
that revealed lab tests detected three
unapproved pesticides in a pair of
mahatma products the test commissioned
by the post found levels of oh gosh my
club you 10l and amid de claw rapid amid
a claw rapid in Mahatma's black label
grapefruit black label grapefruit diesel
wax there were six times the maximum
amount allowed by federal government on
any food product the pesticides also
were found in bahamas black label alpha
blue shatter but at lower levels
measures
verbal amounts of a vermin were found in
both samples only mahatma products
showing an origin number of 4 0 3 - 0 0
1 1 4 on their labels are subject to the
recall it was unclear how many products
with that origin number or sold bouncer
said he is preparing to handle return
products old placards were placed on
watch Norwich units from when recalled
product comes back into Mahatma he told
the post in an email once product
reaches us on this recall we will be
sending it out for testing and once
results are back and show passed then
the product will be released from the
city of been vers hold if product does
not pass we will be quarantine and
contacting the Med for further
instruction
Tuesday's actions are part of a supply
chain investigation according to dan
rollin smokes spokesman for Denver's
office of Marijuana Policy adding that
additional recalls are possible
inspectors visited Mahatma's facilities
and pored through records and products
and odor at treatment which also
operates altitude the dispensary shops
in Denver said he expects agency
inspectors to visit his facility on
Wednesday pesticides typically are
applied while a plant is growing not
after it has been harvested dried and
sold the post investigation found
mahatma had inadvertently mislabeled its
products to indicate the concentrate
came from plants it had grown the
pesticides were not included in the
products labels list of ingredients
state law requires labels to reflect any
pesticide or herbicide or a contaminant
that was used at any stage of a
marijuana products processing though the
law also requires cannabis businesses to
test for pesticides that provision has
not yet been enforced Mouser previously
said the businesses labels are only as
accurate as the information provided to
them we're going by what our clients
give us as far as an ingredient list he
told the post we go over the ingredients
list and we check that list again
against the approved pesticides list if
we find something that isn't on the list
we notified the processing client the
pesticides found in the post test are
among hundreds of Colorado Department of
Agriculture
has not approved for use on marijuana
because product labels restrict their
use to certain plant and crops or to
specific locations such as open fields
and residential Gardens because
marijuana is illegal under federal law
the US Environmental Protection Agency
will not certify any pesticide for use
on cannabis nor allow any testing as a
result there are no safety limits
established for their use specific to
cannabis or their ingestion by consumers
however the products are allowed on
other consumable items such as
strawberries tomatoes and grapes though
the level of pesticide residues allowed
on each does vary the Post found
pesticides levels Ejim us as much as six
times the highest amount allowed on an
edible food product and as high as 1,800
times the level Denver officials allowed
to be on release plants at hand core it
had quarantined earlier this year over
pesticide concerns this plant had 1,800
times the level that Denver allowed to
be released this plant had been sprayed
to [ __ ] whatever they were whatever
material they use these guys were
spraying the [ __ ] out of it all the time
and way too concentrated this is crazy I
don't know what kind of bugs they were
trying to treat for but they are not
quality farmers I'll go on with the
article it says enforcement of the
state's list of allowable pesticides is
sporadic at best with most city and
state officials responding to complaints
rather than inspecting each facility
Colorado had about five years of medical
marijuana cultivation and sales before
the state in 2013 began compiling a list
of which pesticides could be used on the
plants officials admit that reflects an
imperfect system Colorado's marijuana
Tsar Andrew Friedman said the state is
dealing with the problem as best it can
many growers are new to regulated
pesticide use beyond that like banking
the pesticide regulatory system is
heavily built on federal involvement Sen
Friedman director of Governor John
Hickenlooper office of Marijuana
coordination I know that's not a
completely satisfying answer and
honestly I wish we had these challenges
solved by day one but we're working
toward an enforceable solution that also
protects consumers from other
contaminants such as mold so you guys
they are trying to keep the cannabis
safe they're testing it now to find out
what is in it they are figuring out what
pesticides we should and should not be
using they are setting levels they are
try
to keep the consumer safe we have taken
this out of the basement we have put it
into the store and now we're putting it
into laboratories I hope this shows the
Colorado is doing our best to make a
legitimate business out of cannabis this
isn't just weed anymore this is a
product this is a commercial product
that's being tested I am impressed but
at the same time I'm bummed out that
there are well-known companies like
Mahatma that are still screwing it up
and mislabelling and making mistakes
like this Mihama has one cannabis cups I
have done business with Mahatma and
they've always been super kind to me so
it's a little disappointing to see an
industry leader come out and make a
mistake like this they will get it
together they'll get their [ __ ] together
and like they said they were only going
by the labels that they were given by
the growers so that was probably not
their fault I want to go ahead and give
them the benefit of the doubt Mahatma
didn't do this on purpose they were just
going off of labels so this next article
is completely related to this a lot of
this testing and pesticide testing and
safety inspections have all stemmed from
a few small incidents but it has sparked
a lot of investigation and it is going
to improve our industry in my opinion so
I'm going to read another article that
came out the day after the last article
this one says Colorado State AG
officials watch probes on pesticides
Colorado Department of Agriculture has
investigations underway on pesticide
misuse by Denver marijuana businesses
mahatma concentrates and treatments
unlimited so this is pretty much a
follow up of the last article I read
this is again by David McCoy and Ricardo
Baca and the article goes like this
Colorado agriculture officials have have
opened an investigation into a marijuana
grow operation named in a report by the
Denver Post about pesticide residues
residues and they confirmed a second
business named and the story was already
under scrutiny it is unclear which of
the two companies Mahatma concentrates
or treatments unlimited both in Denver
was already under scrutiny and officials
with the Colorado Department of
Agriculture would not elaborate but the
agency said investigations and two other
businesses used of pesticides is the
focus of its probe the CDA has one
ongoing investigation with one of the
growers and based on the information
supplied in the article we have opened a
second investigation into the other name
grower too
determine if they're pesticide use isn't
compliance with the Colorado pesticide
applicators Act CDA spokeswoman
Christie Lightcap said in an email
penalties on the growers could range
from a simple order to stop the
prohibited conduct to fines up to $1,000
for each violation under the Act repeat
offenders fines are doubled and chronic
offenders face potential license
sanctions like cap said although laws
require marijuana businesses to test for
pesticide residues that rule has not
only has not been enforced because only
one facility is certified to do that
analysis Colorado marijuana enforcement
division rules show marijuana that tests
positive for unapproved pesticides and
other contaminants must be destroyed or
decontaminated because I don't know how
to decontaminate cannabis you can't
really wash it off so I think your
option is to destroy it the Post on
Tuesday reported that two of eight lab
tested Commission on marijuana act
extracts found three unapproved
pesticides and products made by Mahatma
although Mahatma labels indicated the
tainted marijuana used to make these
extracts came from its own girl facility
documents showed the cannabis actually
came from treatments treatments co-owner
admitted that the company had used
products that contained the unapproved
pesticides treatments which operates a
pair of altitude the dispensary shops in
Denver was one of eleven marijuana
growers to have about one thousand per
hundred thousand plants quarantined
earlier this year by Denver health
officials over pesticide concerns the
city allowed most of the plants back
into commerce including those grown by
treatments when levels of pesticide
residues dropped to the lowest amount
allowed on food crops to other
businesses destroyed the plants rather
than wait for pesticide test results see
DA's announcement on Wednesday came a
day after the Denver Department of
Environmental Health issued a broad
recall of them of Mahatma products
following a visit to that shop
inspectors were expected to be a
treatments growing warehouse on
Wednesday retailers with recalled
products were instructed to remove them
from store shelves and either destroy
the products in compliance with any D
regulations or return the products to
the manufacturer said Dan Rowland
spokesman for the Denver's Office of
Marijuana Policy consumers should either
destroy any recalled product they have
or return it to the store of purchase
Roland said this information of
potential pesticide misuse is concerning
Lightcap said in an announcing
investigation the CDA has identified a
list of product
that can be used on marijuana and had as
it has been available to growers for
well over one year pesticides on
marijuana is a controversial topic
because no science no science exists to
say which products are safe for
consumers although several pesticides
are approved for use on some fruit and
vegetable crops the US Environmental
Protection Agency cannot say whether
they are safe on marijuana because the
plant is illegal under federal law CDA
has complied compiled a list of
pesticides some of them so non-toxic
that they do not require federal
registration that can be used on
marijuana based on their label
restrictions not on their safety it is a
violation of federal law to use any
pesticide contrary to its label
directions CDA has chosen those products
whose label restrictions were so broad
that using them on marijuana would not
be in violation but CDA officials have
constantly said they do not recommend
using pesticides on marijuana nor will
they say those products that appear on
its list of approved pesticides are
safety consumers we are in a completely
new business here and we're building a
space shuttle that is not done but has
not been done anywhere else
Colorado agricultural Commissioner Don
Brown said other states including New
Hampshire have restricted pesticides
allowed on marijuana only to those so
non-toxic that federal registration is
not required Colorado nearly did the
same but the industry argued that
non-toxic pesticides mainly organics
such as neem cinnamon and peppermint
oils or nearly strong enough to combat
effectively the pests and mildews that
most commonly attack their truck you
know I'm I'm kind of torn by pesticides
because I run a commercial grow and we
cannot lose a million-dollar harvest to
bugs so we have to do something to keep
bugs off of it I agree with this last
statement here that organics such as
neem oil cinnamon and peppermint oils
and rosemary oil is something and cedar
oil is also something commonly is those
oils are great as a preventative those
are wonderful on a small scale grow
unfortunately those types of oils will
end up in your concentrate just like all
of these pesticides
I can taste neem oil in your dabs if you
spray neem oil on your plants early
before a flower or just before a flower
or early into flower
I can taste the neem oil in your
extracts recently I had some dabs given
to me by an artist he wanted me to
sample them and I could taste the
rosemary oil in his concentrate so using
essential oils isn't always the cure
that end all the preventive the answer
also sometimes you have to use some type
of a pesticide especially when you're
getting clones from other people that's
where I find I get the bugs the most
often is when I get a clone as a gift
from another grower it almost always has
some kind of a bug on it so when you get
a new clone that's when I treat with I
use heavy [ __ ] depending on what the
clone is and what bugs I see on it but I
will use some pretty radical treatment
because I cannot risk my mother plants
giving spider mites I cannot risk my
mother plants getting broad mites I'm a
breeder I rely on my mother plants that
is my future that is my work I've spent
years developing those mother plants if
bugs destroyed those oh I would be
devastated so I do understand the need
for a little bit of a stronger pesticide
in a commercial environment something
that I have recently started doing I am
studying for a Department of Agriculture
pesticide applicators test I think
anybody that is spraying pesticides in
any type of a garden should have to at
least examine this test you don't have
to pass it I work in a commercial
facility I will be training new
employees on pesticide safety I'm
required to take this test I would
encourage anybody who's going to play
with pesticides to take this test it
will teach you a lot about pesticide
safety to start with how to handle a
pesticide how to apply a pesticide
safely what to wear when you're doing it
but it will also teach you what is in
almost everything there are very few
chemicals that they're using and all
these brands they're just different
brands with different labels it's the
same chemical in almost everything and
if you learn what chemicals kill which
bugs it makes your job a lot easier
so I recommend studying up on this
pesticide test go to your state's a
great Department of Agriculture website
and see if there's an applicator test
anybody who does a job like an
exterminator or something like that has
to pass this test so it's available in
your area it'll help you combat your
pest problems a lot better and it will
also keep you safe just something I
recommend
something I'm doing so do it with me
it'll be fun we can do it together all
right so my point with these articles is
that we are not screwing around here in
Colorado we are actually testing
products to make sure that things are
safe we have stepped up our game we're
gonna separate well I'm going to see a
lot of businesses fall apart because of
all this new regulation with pesticide
testing a lot of the growers that think
they are master growers and pro growers
are not going to know what to do once
they start getting rid of some of the
pesticides we're gonna have to start
using an integrated pest management
system was live insects it's gonna be a
whole different ballgame pretty soon I'm
gonna write that down because that
sounds like a good episode
good idea we could talk about integrated
burping we could talk about integrated
pest management on a whole other episode
we'll try to get Shawn over to talk
about organic integrated pest management
that'll be great all right guys let's
see how long I've been talking I just
feel like I've been gone for at least 35
minutes let's see 37 minutes I think
that's a long podcast you guys like to
listen to about 36 minutes worth of show
before you get bored so it's time for me
to wrap up this episode I wanna thank
everybody for joining me I really
appreciate you guys listening to me
especially today I've got a little bit
of a stuffy nose so I'm sure my voice is
a little bit nasally so I do appreciate
for sticking through this episode thanks
for listening to all the news I will be
back on Monday with another episode for
you I'm putting together the CBD episode
I've been talking about I'm putting
together three or four episodes they're
all here in this notebook of course now
we're gonna talk about integrated pest
management in a future episode so look
forward to that oh yeah that part about
going to iTunes go into the iTunes Store
search for girl from your heart podcast
and give me a five star rating and type
in a review and let me know what you
think of the show that would be really
cool the more people that give the show
a rating and a good review the more
people see the show the more people see
the show more people start growing
better cannabis the more people that are
drawn better cannabis which means the
more quality cannabis is available which
means weed will get cheaper and it's
just a good thing everyone will be able
to smoke cheaper cannabis we'll all have
an abundance of weed we can overthrow
the government so just share the show go
click like on it give me a comment let
me know what you think more people will
see it more people will listen
and then maybe one day you'll be
somewhere and somebody will smoke some
weed with you and you'd be like where'd
you learn to grow this I'll be like I
listened to that podcast damn me too
then everyone will have great weed
because of the show it'll be awesome all
right you guys I'm rambling I'm burning
out of breath um make sure you find me
on all the social media sites I would
love all that I'm on facebook I'm on
Twitter I'm on Instagram the Facebook is
grow from your heart the Twitter is @gf
wih podcast and on Instagram you have to
follow
I read genetics that's my seed company
please follow I read genetics post a lot
of great cannabis photography all right
guys that's all I've got for today my
throat is burnt my voice is shot so I'm
gonna give a big huge shout-out to my
ninja spits thanks again for listening
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me