yo what a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
and it's Thursday so that means it's
time for another throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast before I get into the block of
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any promotions any contests or any
giveaways those have all expired there
are currently no contest no promotions
no advertising or no giveaways also let
me update all of the social media if you
want to find me on Twitter you can find
me at G f YH podcast on Twitter on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast and if you'd like to
send me an email
it's drove from your heart at
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen I hope
you enjoyed these chunks of old episodes
so here we go the throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
community it is time for episode number
95 of the girl from your heart podcast
your source for cannabis news education
and conversational just someone who is
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys for
joining the show as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends animistic roots band for
allowing me to use their music on the
show big shout out to my friends that
joined me for the reggae show a couple
of days ago on Tuesday I got to go to
the Fillmore auditorium in Denver
Colorado and I got to see Morgan
Heritage Taurus Riley Stephen Marley and
Damian Marley
it was a great show lots of reggae lots
of good vibes lots of love lots of ganja
smokin big shout out to our knee and
reveille for being great friends they
joined me up there we had a great time
at the show and also big shout out to
Danielle for being a great reggae date
also big shout out to Rasta Stevie
what's that brother it was great seeing
you there I think sometimes you might
listen to the podcast all right you guys
I've got a couple of things coming up in
this episode we're going to address an
email that was sent to me from a friend
he wants to talk about something I said
in the episode about bagged seeds so we
will discuss that but first I want to
read a news article that just came out
this article came out on September 16th
I found it in the cannabis of course
this article was written by David McCoy
and Ricardo Baca
and the article headline says Colorado
AG examining pot industry use of organic
term sub-headline says because marijuana
is illegal under federal law the use of
the term organic is federally regulated
the state licensed cannabis business
can't be certified as organic no matter
their practices I'm gonna turn up my
headphones just a little bit and then I
will read this article for it
and funds allowed enough here we go Mic
Check headphones that's much better all
right historical goes like this
Colorado's Attorney General is
investigating several marijuana
businesses over concerns the word
organic in their names or advertising
might be misleading to consumers the
office is reviewing complaints from the
from the consumers that the merchants
have been misrepresenting their product
when they say organic or organically
grown said Roger Hudson spokesman for
state attorney general cynthia coffman
we're looking for information inside
those complaints to make a determination
on what those next steps are
is it consumer fraud is it criminal the
agz office would not give more detail on
the scope of the investigation but a
lawyer who represents a marijuana
business contacted by investigators said
it appears to have limits the inquiry
includes grow operations some with
organic in their names recently caught
up in Denver quarantines over pesticide
concern concerns attorney Sean
McAllister said sorry guys I read that
statement a little bit oddly but you
caught what I said or what it said the
AG is ensuring that business is ensuring
that businesses that use the word are at
least consistent with the concept of
organic McAllister said because
marijuana is illegal under federal law
and use of the term organic is federally
regulated a licensed cannabis business
cannot be certified as organic no matter
its practices as such no marijuana
businesses in Colorado can technically
use the word in its name or in selling
its product according to officials and
industry insiders potential fraud
penalties under the Colorado consumer
protection act include fines of up to
ten thousand dollars per violation
Federal Rules say that business is
wrongly selling a product as organic
could face fines of up to ten thousand
dollars
yet those rules have not been enforced
in Colorado's marijuana businesses until
now state marijuana license records show
that twenty nine businesses growers
retailers and dispensaries use the word
organic in their name some use a trade
name containing the word organic to
market marijuana products or use the
term or do use the term in their
advertised a spot check of websites by
the Denver Post found businesses
claiming to sell 100% organic cannabis
offering organic treatments of medical
marijuana or use only organic methods to
produce their product some shops
describe their product as grown in
organic soil or that they
use organic growing techniques another
website touts certification of organic
standards and testing that mirrors the
US Department of Agriculture organic
certification Brook Weis owner of the
growing kitchen in Boulder said that
she's willing to take the risk of
labeling her company's edibles made with
certified organic seeds and fruits as
organic even if the marijuana in them
isn't it's a principle an ideology that
doesn't belong to anybody she said
nothing her plants noting her plants
would be certified organic if that
existed on the list of sacrifices and
Gamble's I take organic is definitely on
there but river rock cannabis in Denver
has backed away from using the term
until recently the company had been
known as river rock organic medical
cannabis the Attorney General sent
something saying that no dispensary can
be certified as organic retail manager
Chris Haggerty said the company changed
signs stopped handing out promotional
items with the company's name and even
stopped selling t-shirts with the old
company name Haggerty said a group
seeking to have marijuana certifiable as
organic said a system for informing
consumers how marijuana is grown is
needed the word organic is being used
inappropriately by people who are using
very toxic chemicals
there's no governing agency that is
regulating that said John Paul max field
co-founder of the organic cannabis
Association in Denver in the absence of
a body coming through and branding
organic cannabis that term can be used
by everybody even if it's not done
properly the USDA accredits companies
and state governments to certify any
farm is complying with federal Organic
regulations for agricultural products no
company may use the term without this
certification marijuana may not be
certified organic under the USDA Organic
regulations said a USDA spokesman who
could not be named because it's the
agency's policy when discussing
marijuana marijuana is considered a
controlled substance at the federal
level an organic certification is
reserved for agricultural products the
USDA's National Organic Program rules
say companies with organic in their name
cannot prominently display it on a
product and cannot use the name at all
if it misrepresents that a product has
been certified organic
it falls to the Colorado Department of
Agriculture to certify and accredit
agricultural businesses in the state as
organic as well as police for
inappropriate and illegal uses of the
word on behalf of the USDA if the state
chose to certify marijuana as organic it
would have to ignore federal rules and
that's unlikely said Mitch here director
of CDA's plant industry division
um that's weird because we've already
ignored federal rules and we have
legalized recreational cannabis so why
wouldn't we just do it again anyway
that's my opinion on that the state's
inquiry came after the Denver Department
of Environmental Health this year
quarantined more than 100,000 marijuana
plants over pesticide concerns one
company organic greens tested positive
for unapproved pesticides but because it
operates publicly as natural remedies
the eggs office allowed it to keep its
name said McAllister its attorney
they're actual corporation name is
organic greens but they don't use it in
advertising so they don't publicize
themselves as organic they don't do any
advertising as organic so nobody's being
mislead McAllister said confirming the
company name under AG scrutiny
McAllister said the AG is focusing at
least in part on companies that have
used pesticide that have used pesticides
not allowed by the state for use on
marijuana they understand you can't get
federal certification for the word
organic in marijuana he said the agz
office is not substituting themselves
for a certification agency but if they
clearly but if it's clearly not organic
if someone's using Mallett or Eagle 20
they're also looking for those cases
ballot Neagle 20 our pesticide trade
beams well whose active ingredients
contain chemicals the state has not
approved for use on marijuana I've said
this on a previous episode but I was
speaking with somebody from the
Department of Agriculture they actually
came to I'm the master grower at the
spot dispensary so I had to meet with
the Department of Agriculture they sent
two reps down to come talk to us and the
main rep told me that the main reason
that Eagle 20 has been banned from
dispensary uses is because if there is a
fire and the Eagle 20 burns the
off-gassing
turns into cyanide and the fire
department doesn't want to go into a
building that is filled with the gas of
cyanide so that's mainly why Eagle 20
has been banned also it's completely
toxic but he didn't even seem to care
about the toxicity of the product he
just wanted to tell me about it turning
into cyanide is why it's been banned
from use in commercial growth facilities
so I'll keep going with the article
there's one more sentence here left one
more short paragraph it says although no
chemical pesticide can obtain federal
approval for use on cannabis state
agriculture officials have determined
which products have labels whose
restrictions are so broadly worded that
using them on marijuana would not be a
violation so they're cracking down on it
you guys when I first started in the
medical marijuana world I was shopping
at a dispensary that had the word
organic in it and I knew right away when
I looked at the medicine when I saw how
they grew I knew there was nothing to do
with actual organics and we're just
trying to use the word organic as a
a marketing ploy and it was working and
also just to put this out there they do
require that all of the ingredients used
in the grow anything that was sprayed or
fed to the plants does have to be listed
on an instruction list or instruction
ingredients list I'm sorry an
ingredients list on the outside of the
container so all of that [ __ ] does have
to be listed on the package that the
cannabis or hatch is sold and actually
let me reach over here this is just the
inner packaging this one doesn't have
the ingredients on it sorry but most of
the time it's got a few things written
on it and if you come by cannabis in the
state of Colorado you'll get a little
jar like a childproof jar or whatever
they put the cannabis in and it'll have
some ingredients listed on it and you'll
see things like calcium and you'll see
things like mykos and beneficial
bacteria and you'll see stuff like that
that's all what was used in the growing
of the plant so they will also hopefully
list any pesticides that were sprayed on
there all right so they're cracking down
on the name organic then they are also
cracking down to make sure that your
[ __ ] is organic which I really
appreciate I really like that because
there are a lot of shops serving up do
do that you can tell it was not
organically grown you can taste the
fertilizers in it I know friends that
own hydro shops and I know friends that
are reps and consultants for
dispensaries and they go to places they
claim to be running organics and then
when they make their order from the
hydro shop or when they set up a
nutrient schedule with the consultant
they go with the product that is
completely not organic and they don't
seem to give a [ __ ] but you can't say
anything you just gotta let them do
their thing
so I'm glad now somebody is going to
call them out and make them accountable
alright I'm gonna take a DAB in a quick
drink and then we're going to address an
email that was sent to us by a listener
about something I said an episode number
90 so hang out for a few seconds and
I'll be right back all right you guys I
am back I just wanted to let you know if
you hear a bunch of a ruckus in the
background there there are no hostages
in my house there's actually a football
game happening right now there's a
Denver Broncos game and my neighbors are
having a party and I got my window open
a little bit so whenever something
happens in the game you can hear them
either cheer or jeer whichever way it
goes
it's pretty entertaining so if you hear
the screams no I don't have hostages
here in the house it's just a football
game and people are going crazy
um so alright just a few days ago I
received an email from a friend of ours
let's get into this email and pulling it
up in my phone right now here we go
all right this email is from our friend
Justin and it says I just listened to
episode 90 I guess I was operating on
some incorrect information you and Jessi
seemed to feel like Herms are really bad
I was told her seeds were pretty much
feminized seeds
since the genetics all came from female
so basically we would revenge out plants
after harvest and then light poison them
to make seeds for the future so I'm
wondering if those progeny from the
seeds would be predisposed to Herm in
the future if you could just explain a
little to me or recover this on the show
I would super-duper love that thanks
Ross to Jeff from Justin G alright so
the seeds you're talking about are not
necessarily Herms hermaphrodite seeds
are different hermaphrodite seeds come
from when there is a female plant in the
room that suddenly pops a male flower
and that male flower pollinates the room
and a few seeds happen from that small
pollination so there's a big difference
in kind of a hermaphrodite seed and what
you're talking about I took a few notes
and wrote a few things down I'm gonna
kind of try to read this to you and
sound like I'm not reading something to
you but here's what I wrote those seeds
that you made are made by stressing the
plants so it has so as long as there
were no males or stray pollen available
to the females and also the females are
solid females the seeds produced will be
females because of the lack of a why
male chromosome so technically those
won't be herm seeds if the none of the
females hermaphrodite it and made male
flowers they release pollen on in there
and they should be feminized so as long
as none of your female plants are
throwing off bananas or male pollen
sacks you will be making female seeds
here um if a plant is allowed to flower
for too long it'll often make seeds if a
plant is light stressed which is what
you guys are doing then those plants
will make seeds and those seeds are
feminized another way to make feminized
seeds is soma takes a plant that is
almost finished it'll be around week six
or seven for like a nine week plan
he'll take it around week six or seven
and then he will light a small fire and
put that fire next to the plant to make
it feel like it's in a forest fire he
will heat the [ __ ] out of the plant
he'll move the heat around the plant and
kind of freak it out and that plant
thinks it's in a forest fire and it's
panic reaction is to start making seeds
so I'll have to give it four to six
weeks from there to finish seeding but
by week twelve someone will have a big
batch of feminized s1 seeds that don't
have any other chromosomes in them
except this chromosomes coming from that
plant so you're going to be basically
copying the plant that you just stressed
so you are making feminized seeds there
when Jesse and I were talking about
hermaphrodite seeds we were talking more
about seeds that were caused by a
hermaphrodite issue in a row say one of
your females were to pop a pollen sack
during week seven or whatever our week
six or seven and that hits another plan
and it pollinates and it makes a little
bit of seed that seed will be kind of
questionable it may have from afroditi
traits but it still could be gold as
what we were talking about so there's a
little bit of difference in herim seed
and what you're doing a herm seed is
kind of a trait issue what you're doing
is kind of a manipulation sort of a
stressing and a panic reaction sort of a
thing I encourage you to keep doing that
you got any extra seeds man I'd love to
grow a couple of those and see what they
do I'll take some pictures for you so
one thing that I do that's kind of on
this realm and this is just because I
wanted to rant about this it's kind of
what this reminded me of before I breed
with plants
I will take my females and I will put
them in the flowering room and I will
set the timer to twelve twelve and I'll
let them flower for about two weeks and
as soon as I see Bud set I will reverse
the timer from 9:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. I
will now have them off from 9:00 a.m.
and 9:00 p.m. and they will come on at
9:00 p.m. till 9:00 a.m. for about five
days and then after five or six days I
will put the timer back to the original
twelve twelve they'll come on at 9:00
a.m. and go off at 9:00 p.m.
and I'll pay real close attention to
them for about a week and a half and
then I'll [ __ ] with the timer again I'll
turn it on for twenty four hours
why not and then I'll just do weird
[ __ ] with my schedules in there and then
I'll put it back on 12:12 for a few days
and watch the plants and if they start
freaking out real bad then I kind of get
rid of the plants that can't handle some
stress sometimes I go why it stress
testing cuz a little bit will tell me
what I want to see but sometimes you get
curious as a grower and you want to go
through and really pummel a female plant
and see what that [ __ ] can handle
before you go putting her into a major
breeding project so I've actually got a
couple of plants that I can take them to
week two and totally reverse the light
cycle and it doesn't piss them off
I can do it a couple of times and they
don't her mout however if I let those
same plants go long enough without any
light stress if I let them go too long
they will start to produce seeds cuz
I've let some strains go up to 80 days
strains that should only go 60 I have
let them go 80 just to see what happens
when you grow as much as we do in a
plant with some things to tell you learn
a lot of [ __ ] I let him go a little bit
long just to see what happened and it
was seeded the plant had by that 20
extra days put seeds in my plant so you
can do it by light stress you can do it
by extending them there's a lot of
different ways to do it if you're going
to stress test your females I kind of
just told you how I would do it I would
just [ __ ] with the light cycles as a
breeder one thing I want to say is when
you grow out those seeds that you're
making from manipulated plants really
pay close attention to hermaphroditic
traits you may not find that
hermaphrodites until like week eight of
a nine week plant or of a ten week plant
so really pay attention to that that
shouldn't be there but you are making a
manipulated seed that's not natural so
there is a chance for some weirdness all
right I hope that answered your question
in your email go ahead and grow those
seeds out man that's a great way to keep
yourself self sustainable and keep
yourself supplied in seeds you'll be one
of those guys that has seeds when the
apocalypse comes so we'll be hanging out
all right guys if you want me to read
one of your emails on the show all you
got to do is send it to me it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I'd love
to answer your questions you know I love
the interaction I'd love you guys to
follow me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast find me on Facebook it's just
grow from your heart I love all of the
social media interaction I do try to
interact with everybody if you send me a
message and we'll
try to respond it does take me a little
bit sometimes because I do get a lot of
messages of course I've got the IRA
genetics email account that fills up
I've got my own personal email account
that fills up since I've been doing
periscope videos I've been getting a lot
more messages so things are going a
little bit crazy Facebook Instagram
Twitter all that stuff keeps me tied up
and I've been working at the spot doing
quite a few hours every week so that
limits my time for social media but I
will answer your question is what I
think I am giving to please interact
with me I would love it all right you
guys I think that's holy crap what
happened to my throat geez I apologize
for that I think that's all I've got
free for this week I thought those that
news article that email would take a
little bit longer to answer but I pretty
much covered that in 20 minutes so I'm
gonna wrap up this show I will be back I
am putting together at the episode about
CBD I'm trying to get more guests to
come be on the show now that uh it's
almost harvest season you guys so once
everybody cuts down everybody will be a
little bit more available we'll be able
to get all the growers back on the show
I got the zoom h6 so I'll be able to
take the show on the road now we'll go a
few places I just bought four
microphones and four new cables we'll be
able to take that wherever we want and
go do some recording with a lot more
people that's gonna open up a lot more
options on the next episode I plan to
answer another email that we got I want
to address something that I saw at a
growers house when I went to do a
consultation something that they did in
their car their garden that I had to I
felt the urge to correct them and I kind
of gave them some guidance on it so I'm
gonna share that with you guys you might
be making the same mistakes as this
other guy so I'm gonna share that with
you I've got a lot of great stuff
planned you guys I'll be back Monday
with another episode I want to thank you
guys for joining me we don't have any
sponsors if you want to sponsor the
podcast all you got to do is send me an
email let's go from your heart at
hotmail.com
I'll let you know everything you need to
know about sponsoring the show if you've
got a product that you would like me to
review same thing grow from your heart
at hotmail.com we would love to review
your products we'll give you an honest
opinion we will expose your product to
at least 5000 consumers that are right
up your alley so if you have a good
product let me know we'll get it out
there for you
if you have something to say find me on
all the social media you guys already
said that right all right
don't forget to the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is always in forever archived on I read
genetics Colorado com
don't forget I did put a donation button
on the podcast page if you feel like the
show is worth a couple of bucks go to
the website it's I read genetics
Colorado com click on the Grove from
your heart podcast tab at the top right
there's a donation but it's a little
PayPal logo that goes directly to my
PayPal account
I'm never gonna charge you for this
podcast you guys this podcast will
always be free the show is going to be
free I grow from my heart I give it to
you from my heart I hope you grow from
your heart in return but if you do feel
like making a contribution it would
definitely be appreciated
I just bought the new zoom h6 with
partially with contributions that came
in to the podcast so shout out to
everybody who has made a contribution in
the past also you guys know the show's
over
you can go to iTunes search for the
iTunes or go to the iTunes Store search
for girl from your heart find the girl
from your heart podcast leave me a five
star review and type in a little comment
and let me know what you think about the
podcast and I will read your comments on
a future episode the reason that we want
more ratings and more comments and more
reviews is because that makes us more
exposed to a larger audience the more
likes you get the more comments you get
the more Facebook shares you and exposes
you so the more people that see the show
the more people will learn how to grow
quality cannabis or people will quit
spring [ __ ] on their plants people will
learn how to look out for hermaphrodites
people will learn how to just grow
better cannabis overall everybody will
grow cannabis people will get the right
idea they will get a proper education
maybe somebody will listen to the show
that has never smoked pot before they'll
listen to the show and they'll say you
know what this guy smokes a gram of hash
every single day and he's mostly
articulate I know I've got some stoner
moments on this show but that's just me
but I'm mostly articulate maybe they'll
say this guy has his [ __ ] together
maybe weed isn't so bad then maybe
they'll lighten up and then maybe
they'll be on our side and then maybe
one day we can legalize cannabis
nationwide and then worldwide that's my
mission legalizing cannabis one click at
a time here at the grow from your heart
a podcast that's what we are doing all
right guys
what else to say so I'm gonna wrap up
the show um yeah follow me on Instagram
you guys I just hit 18,000 followers I'm
an 18 point 1k on Instagram right now
find me it's I read genetics on
Instagram you guys I want to give a huge
shout out to my ninja spin so thanks
again for listening until next time take
a big fat dad I'm just a little dad you
guys like a big one like a half a grab
make it count
you ready get it on the dabber take a
phat dab right after you blow it out
go give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back his community it's time for
episode number 96 of the girl from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education in conversation this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross for joining
I know the Monday episode was pretty
sure right after I put out the monday
episode right after I recorded the money
episode I want to go look at the news
and there was another news article that
I feel like you guys need to know about
so on this episode it's gonna be a
quickie just gonna be a midweek quickie
a Thursday bonus episode I hope you guys
enjoy it but I want to talk about a news
article and then I'm going to talk about
something that I saw while doing a
consultation at somebody's house I'm
going to try to give you a little bit of
guidance and help you improve something
so let's get into this news article that
made me want to record this one says
Denver issues two more pot recalls of
pot containing unapproved pesticides
they are at it again you guys this
article comes from the cannabis and it
is written by our friends David McCoy
and Ricardo Baca so let's get right down
to bidness very good goes like this
owners of to Denver marijuana growing
facilities on Friday said they were
voluntary voluntarily recalling their
products after city health officials
learned tests found unapproved
pesticides the recall of an undisclosed
amount of plants and edible products is
the second issued by the Denver
Department of Environmental Health in
just over a week underscoring the city's
enforcement efforts on companies
allegedly using disallowed chemicals
Department officials said retailers
should either destroy the recalled
products or return them to the
manufacturer ensue Murs who have had the
products who consumers who have the
products should return them to the store
of purchase or dispose of them take them
back you guys don't throw with them away
take them back go get your money back in
a replacement owners of the two impacted
businesses summit wellness which
operates as Denver rec Denver
recreational dispensary and sacred seed
confirmed they were removing products
from their store shelves
it's true a denver rec owner James
Monaco told the Denver Post about the
recall we're working through the process
and we'll have a statement on our
Twitter feed later tonight the sacred
seed recall apparently was the result of
pesticides a rogue employee secretly
applied in the middle of the night
without permission CEO Jeremy Kilbourne
told the Post now is that just an excuse
you guys or do you think that that
really happened do you think they really
had a rogue employee go in the grow
rooms in the middle of the night and
spray pesticides now that pesticide had
to be in the damn building for that dude
to put in the sprayer
let me see had to go to the store he had
to buy a pesticide he had to drive to
work he had to wait for everybody else
to leave he had to mix that [ __ ] up and
then he had to spray this [ __ ] on the
plants I'm not gonna lie call them out
and say [ __ ] but I might say that
I'm not completely sure I completely buy
that whole story because how would they
know that a rogue employee did that if
nobody ever said anything until the [ __ ]
was tested and found spray on it like
they just oh yeah that was that time
that that guy did that they didn't know
that I feel like they just made that up
the more I talk about it the more I feel
like they are just using that as a
cop-out anyway I want to get back into
the article the next paragraph lists all
of the origin RM CF numbers on all the
products that are recalled because I
don't feel the need to read all of these
numbers 90% of my audience is not in
Colorado anyway so most of you guys
don't have any of these products if you
bought mahatma products you may want to
contact the dispensary where you got
them and you may want to get a refund so
i'm going to continue it says as in the
city's prior marijuana recall return
products cannot be sold until additional
testing clears them of residues of the
disallowed pesticides the businesses
also have the discretion to destroy them
we're in a state of shock killed weren't
said we pulled everything off of our
shelves self quarantined our grow and
our product we don't wholesale so no one
has our product out there except the
small amount of trim for processing the
product subject to the recall had been
tested at Muhammad Mahatma concentrates
in Denver which was already under a
recall issued September 8th for its own
products that had tested positive for
pesticides that state agriculture
officials have not cleared for the use
on cannabis the city's inquiry of
Mahatma extended to several business
that send it marijuana trimmings for
processing into edible concentrates such
as wax and shatter which are then
returned or distributed to different
stores as a result of the first recall
Mahatma beacon pesticide testing on all
marijuana trimmings that arrived in its
Denver facility it was that testing that
found pesticides in the latest recalled
products Gilbert said Mihama informed
him of the test results and the company
immediately contacted officials at the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
we're going to be getting a tested and
figuring out the extent of damage and
destroying materials or throwing it out
however environmental help however
environmental health wants us to do
Kilbourne said we're reeling we're
reeling right now Kilburn said the
sacred seed employee responsible for the
pesticide misuse had left on Tuesday and
offered an explanation in a resignation
letter he said I'm so sorry we had a
minor bug problem and I was concerned we
were going to lose the crop kill Warren
said of the letter not only did we tell
him not to use those pesticides we had
sent him on to and two others to
specialized pesticide handlers training
through the Colorado Department of
Agriculture it was unclear how Dan rec
learned of the test results n'ver
inspectors said they only found
application log books for the past 30
days at Dan ray and the business that
older ones had been destroyed reports
show
this is weird a letter of resignation
with an apology and destroy Devas in
evidence this is turning into a cannabis
soap opera this is kind of neat the CDA
issued a list earlier this year of
products it says can be used on
marijuana because the drug is illegal
under federal law no pesticide is
specifically approved for use on
cannabis but some label restrictions are
so broadly written that using the
chemical would not violate federal law
mandates that no pesticide may be used
in a manner that is not consistent with
its label most marijuana growers are not
well-informed about pesticide use and
the rules behind them see dia CDA
officials have said so what appears to
solve a problem in a greenhouse could
actually be a violation of law
pesticides are regulated by the US
Environmental Protection Agency and it
offers no information about marijuana
because the drug is illegal so now we
are not able to test pesticides on
cannabis to find out the long-term
effect to find out how long that product
stays in the cannabis to find out how
much of it actually makes it to the
concentrate it's illegal to test these
pesticides on cannabis in the way that
we need to do it to find what combats
are our problems because cannabis is
federally illegal I'm sure you guys know
where I'm headed with this right the
solution to this problem right I'm sure
you guys all want to say it with me
legalize cannabis then we can test this
[ __ ] properly and we'll solve this
problem just legalize it they can make
money off of the testing labs would make
money there's another avenue of revenue
right there so there are more products
being recalled you guys because of
pesticides Mahama concentrates is
actually taking it upon themselves to
start testing everything that comes in
before they run it before they do the
extraction process they were testing all
the material that comes in I give kudos
to Mahatma that is a bold step and that
is a brave thing to do they have to pay
for the testing which cost money and
then they're also going to lose
clientele because anything that does
come back with the contaminate and it
cannot be ran so big shout out to
Mahatma you guys if you're coming to
Colorado to buy products I want you to
feel safe and this is what we're doing
to make you feel safe we're making sure
there are not ridiculous pesticides in
here
and they mentioned that Department of
Agriculture applicators training course
in this article if you are a growing
cannabis I recommend that you go and
read your state's pesticide applicators
training manual or certification manual
whatever it is it varies state by state
but your Department of Agriculture in
your state will have a an applicators
training guide or a certification guide
or something go read it you will learn
so much about pesticides about pesticide
use about pesticide safety you will
learn that most of these products are
all derived from the same thing and they
are mixed with other carrier agents and
that alone will be a useful tool in your
ganja growing arsenal alright I do in
the future plan on doing an integrated
pest management episode I've got two
people lined up that I want to have on
that show and getting them here at the
same time has been a challenge I may
just do two separate episodes and get
them both on separate episodes alright
that was the news article that I wanted
to read you guys I want to keep you guys
updated on what's going on here in
Denver or up in Denver I'm not in Denver
but here in Colorado up in Denver 100
miles but I want to keep it going
updated on what's going on let you know
how this pesticide drama has been going
and I wanted to kind of give props to
Mahatma concentrates for just stepping
up their game they're testing everything
now they found out they had a problem
instead of trying to hide it they're
like hey we [ __ ] up and look what
we're gonna do we're gonna test
everything it's gonna make a lot of
people accountable and I like the way
that this industry is moving all right I
do want to talk about one more thing you
guys this is just going to be a short
episode this is just a bonus Thursday
episode I wanted to get that news
article out but since I'm here recording
I want to talk about something that I
saw a few days ago while I was at a
consultation a lot of times when I go to
a consultation that people will have a
problem that they need corrected but
sometimes they just want me to observe
what they're doing and see what we can
improve or make easier for them that
will make their cannabis crop come out a
little bit better so I want to tell you
guys a little something about what I saw
at a consultation with a client a few
days ago and I just want to kind of
correct this and I don't know if you're
doing this wrong or if you could be
doing this better
I'm sure that there are a couple people
out there who will benefit from this so
I was just watching this guy working his
garden I just showed up at his house I
was like what's up man I know you need
help let's go check it out and we walked
out there and he said I saved all my
chores for when you got here and we're
just gonna do my gardening I was like
that sounds great
so I helped him out of filled some
buckets and we did what we did and I
watched him now the first thing this
dude did that I corrected was this guy
gets a five gallon bucket and He pours
his nutrients into a glass to measure
and then he pours all the nutrients into
the five gallon bucket you guys you
cannot do that I will explain why I am
NOT a scientist but I know why these are
the reason that they're sold in
different bottles so if you go by I'm
just gonna use advance nutrients because
it's the product that it's popped up in
my mind they've got they've got a flower
a they've got a flower B and then
there's like a bloom booster and then
there's like a flavor booster advanced
nutrients has so many bottles the reason
those are all sold separately is because
if they put those products all into one
container the elements in there will
bond that's why we need to add those
products to water and never mix them
together concentrate those are very
concentrated products you're only adding
a few milliliters to five gallons of
water so the first thing I'm gonna say
is fill up your container that you're
going to mix into probably a five gallon
bucket filled out with water first
preferably reverse osmosis water but we
can't all do that so fill your
five-gallon bucket with water always
fill it with water first then add the
nutrients to the water never mix
nutrients without water they are
buffered they are sold separately for a
reason they are buffered and chelated
and they are not meant to be mixed in
concentrate together so the best I can
recommend is to either mix them into a 1
gallon pitcher so that if you do make a
mistake you don't waste 5 gallons of
water or just mix the nutrients one at a
time into your five gallon bucket but
never pour them in concentrate form into
a container together that is not a good
thing you're causing problems already so
fill your bucket get a pitcher of water
from that bucket makes your nutrient
solution into the pitcher use a quality
measuring device you guys go get
something from the grocer
or a scientific store the stuff use for
your kitchen is closed but it is not
going to be as accurate as something you
could get from the gross store and do
not use something from the kitchen and
then put it back in the kitchen you
can't use the same [ __ ] you've got to
have a dedicated one for your Gro you
don't want to be mixing your whatever
kind of food you're mixing you're
measuring out your vanilla extract and
the same damn measuring device that
you're mixing up your nutrients don't do
that that's tacky and it's unsanitary
it's either gonna get you sick or your
plants sick don't [ __ ] with that go get
some dedicated stuff so measure really
carefully you guys be accurate with your
measurements if it says 25 milliliters
okay well here's something I should say
if the bottle says 50 milliliters
probably use half of that to start I
have never needed to use as much as
recommended on the bottle the nutrient
companies want you to buy more if they
recommend that you use a little bit
extra so you don't always have to use as
much as it says start with maybe a half
two thirds and work your way up from
there
but measure carefully if you're trying
to put in 25 milliliters measure 25
milliliters write it down so that if
something goes wrong you know next time
that 26 or 27 isn't what you did 25 is
what you did and it either worked or it
did not so 25 is your number to go to
next time and adjust from there so
measure carefully like I just said take
notes all the time I should always
remind you guys to take notes always
take notes when you're drawing cannabis
it's the only way you know what you did
or what you didn't do and what worked
and what didn't work I know you're gonna
think I'll remember doing that you're
growing cannabis which means you're
probably smoking cannabis which means
you're gonna forget so write that [ __ ]
down so now you've got everything
measured right you've taken a pitcher of
water you've poured your girl a into a
small measuring device dump that into
the pitcher or be into the measuring
device dump that in the pitcher all your
additives put that into there then clean
out your measuring device you guys go
clean it right now before you do
anything else go clean it all right so
now you've got a pitcher dump that
pitcher into your five-gallon bucket
with water in there so now you've got 5
gallons of perfectly mixed water
if you do make a mistake all you gotta
do is dump out that pitcher and then
just start fresh of course you wasted
your nutrients but you didn't just dump
out five gallons of water you don't have
to wait for a five-gallon bucket to
refill it'll help you out if you're
using reverse osmosis water you just
saved even more because when you make
reverse osmosis water there's a lot of
water that gets thrown away so it's hard
to it's hard to waste water when you're
using reverse osmosis water let's see um
so now you've got your bucket it's
filled with your nutrient solution it's
filled with water now it's time to test
the pH I've seen people adjust the pH of
their water before they add the
nutrients which is a fail because you're
going to pH it and then put [ __ ] in it
yeah so once you've got all of your
nutrients in there every single nutrient
that is when you adjust the pH use pH up
or pH down to correct it write it down
you guys write down the pH if you get it
at 6.5 write it down if you get it at
6.3 write that down if it's 6.7 write it
down if you're in hydro you're going
lower still write it the [ __ ] down so
that when you see those plants doing
something you know if you were right or
wrong with your measurement and you have
a reference for where to go to next time
you can't make adjustments if you don't
know what you did last time
so now we've got our nutrients mixed up
in a five-gallon bucket we've got it
properly pH to about 6.5 we wrote that
down we wrote down how much nutrients
we've used now it's time to water each
plant you guys when you go watering the
plants this is something that I saw my
my client do the other day he poured the
water directly in the center of the pot
right over the stalk right in the middle
of the damn plant
um if you're using enough water that'll
work but here's what I would recommend
it is wiser and more healthy for the
plant to start on the outer edge of the
plant because the roots that are newer
and fresher and growing and searching
for water are those outer roots so you
want to get the outer perimeter of the
dirt wet the inside of the roots on
there the water will work its way in
because the roots will pull it there so
think about a cannabis plant let's
envision a cannabis plant standing there
out in the field by itself or with other
friends whichever you got a cannabis
plant standing there the leaves hang off
of it and sort of like a tent shape if
you think about it it's like a tent it's
detecting the inside of that platform
oyster so when the rain hits it if rain
comes down from the sky rain hits the
plant and it's being brought out to the
outer edge of the plant hardly any water
will land on the ground near the stalk
of that plant because all the leaves are
pushing it out to the perimeter so I
kind of believe that a plant will grow
as wide as its root mass will allow it
so if you water the outer edge of that
pot then your plants gonna grow wider
because it's gonna feel like it's
getting more water also that whiteness
of the plant should kind of represent
the root mass so when the rain comes
down the rain will drip off of the plant
and fall right at the perimeter of the
plant and that's where those roots are
in my opinion and so it'll drink that
right up and it also if you water the
outside of that it'll keep your roots
active so don't go dumping the water
right in the middle of the pot kind of
try to water around the outer edge then
you're gonna want to soak the soil
anyway but make sure you get that outer
area wet that's that's the important
part not right there in the middle one
good way to do that you guys if you have
time and I hope you do make a little
mound around your stalk just grab a
handful of the soil in the in the pot
and just kind of make a little a cone
Euler shape like a mound around the
stalk so that when you water the water
runs down that and runs towards the
edges of the pots that's what I would
recommend so my point is try to get the
water to the outer edge of the pot not
so much in the center so that's a couple
of things that I saw at a consultation
that I thought I would share with you
guys also you guys clean up after
yourselves
um don't do something tomorrow that
could be done today because when you
start getting lazy as a grower that's
when you fall behind that's when she
gets messy when she gets behind and
messy is when you have problems when
you're growing on a professional level
and you're trying to have professional
quality buds for yourself and your
clients and your patients and whatever
you whoever else you're growing for you
need to be in there every day you need
to be diligent you need to be on top of
[ __ ] nothing can wait until tomorrow if
it needs to be done today you should
probably get in there and do it today
because plants are only alive if you
think about it your plants are only
alive they're in flower for nine weeks
that's 63 days plants only live for
about a hundred days indoors maybe 120
150 at the most so you've only got a
hundred and fifty days why not make
every single day for your plant
right your patients will know it your
flowers will show it in the end it'll be
well worth your time just get in there
and do that [ __ ] um let's see I want to
talk a little bit about defoliation a
little bit I've been experimenting with
defoliation what that is is just going
and taking off all of the big fan leaves
early and flower I put two plants side
by side the same exact strain I used a
Jeff Shoji because it's something I'm
very familiar with and I tore off all of
the fan leaves on one plant odd about a
week into flower I all of the fan leaves
if there was a pea deal I cut that leaf
off at the pineal right at the stem so
this plant looked completely naked it
was just a bunch of buds up a stick
there were no leaves and the one next to
it looks like a big leafy pot play um as
time went on the leaves grew back you
guys I went and cut those leaves off
again I did it about every seven to ten
days I was in there cutting off major
amounts of leaf off of these plants it
started growing so much leaf toward week
six that it looked just like the plant
next to it that I had never d foliated
it was spitting out a lot of leaf but I
kept cutting them off there's little
tiny leaves just trying to grow out um I
wasn't getting too crazy it was my first
time trying it but I noticed that the
lower buds got chunkier I didn't think
it would work that way because my
opinion has always been that those
bigger leaves were the solar collectors
they got off the light from my plant
that gave the plant energy um I may have
to experiment more with this defoliating
I've noticed they get a little better
airflow the plants seem to be just
happier when I cut down a lot of the
leaf so you guys if you have some leaves
that are shadowing a bud or if your
plant looks a little bit too leafy I
encourage you to choose one plant in
your garden and maybe experiment with a
little bit of extreme defoliation you
don't have to go extreme if you don't
want to but if you want to the plants
will handle that you guys I think I got
on the one plant that I did not
defoliate it was in a seven gallon pot I
got five and a half ounces of Jeff's OG
in the plant it was D foliated I got six
and a quarter so that's three quarters
of an ounce which is not a whole lot of
a difference when you go buy a whole
room
that's still 21 grams of cannabis just
by cutting off some leaves and I did
everything else the same you guys the
plants looked very similar up until that
moment so that's a little bit of
defoliating if you guys have any
comments or if you want to know more
about that let me know that's just
something I was playing with in my
garden and I thought I would share it
with you guys all right I'm gonna wrap
up this bonus Thursday episode I
appreciate you guys for hanging out with
me I think this is a good makeup for my
short episode last week right instead of
130-minute you guys got two 20-minute
episodes that should work for you did I
really appreciate you guys for listening
to me and supporting the podcast I've
been getting a lot a lot of listens
lately I can tell by the website I just
go and check out some stats it has a
really paying attention you're listening
to the show I completely appreciate it
you guys what I would truly appreciate
is if he went to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store find the review section give me a
5 star rating on there and type in a
comment let me know what you think about
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode the reason that I
want you guys to leave comments and give
me a five star rating is because that's
what moves me up in the ranks and iTunes
and if I move up in the ranks and iTunes
more people will see the show they'll
put my logo up there in the hot [ __ ]
section somewhere and then people will
click and they will listen and then more
people will learn how to grow quality
cannabis and the more people that are
learning to grow quality cannabis which
means will mean there's more quality
cannabis of cannabis available for
everyone to smoke dad English is getting
hard so I'm just gonna end this show
already
you guys don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm make sure you check me out on all
the social media I'm on all of them I'm
on most of them if I'm not on something
let me know I'll get on there
you guys I'm wrapping up this show my
throat's burning out and words are
getting hard so it's time to go take
some dabs until next time oh I almost
missed a part I'm gonna give a huge
shout-out to my ninja spits ah thanks
for listening until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
it's time for cannabis news this my
friends is the podcast I'm doing great
man thanks for joining me for those of
you guys that don't know Mike is a good
friend of mine we've been in the
cannabis industry the legal cannabis
industry together for close to 10 years
now ish maybe a little longer than that
that's the marijuana okay okay
I'll believe you Mike says we've been in
this industry to get it a lot longer
when you're tripping time kind of
stretches oh god it does and we've
trimmed a lot of you have trimmed a lot
of my herb for me I have so Mike's and
fellow cannabis activists a good friend
of mine and also a co-worker over at the
spot dispensary he's shaking his head
yes there's no need for you to respond
other than a head shake was appropriate
but it was just funny to watch you shake
your head and think that the people
might have heard that we're gonna talk
about that in just a second actually
let's just go for it today over at the
spot dispensary man we had a great great
moment we actually had the fire
inspector come in yeah this was a big
moment that's one of the last sign offs
we've been waiting on was gonna before I
get too far follow Mike on Twitter it's
all yeah Nemo punk one five make sure
you follow him there on the Twitter Nemo
punk 15 he's a cannabis activist he
posts a lot of good news related
articles he post a lot of great topics I
know he could be following him checking
out his feet stalking and boy you're
listening to the show it's always fun to
know who you're checking out follow me
and then shoot me a message or tweet and
let me know you're following from the
podcast yeah tweet at him he likes that
[ __ ] yes I do so today at the spot
dispensary the
a fire inspector the Pueblo West Metro
fire inspector showed up and we've got
these big windows he did a fire
inspection and of course we passed I'm
gonna jump right to that we [ __ ]
passed I'm not even gonna do any
hesitation to that one we passed with
flying colors but here's the great part
we've got these big sliding doors they
go over some windows our facility is set
up to be a touring facility so we put
giant glass windows between the tour
area and where the plants will be so
that the plants will not become
contaminated by anything that our
touring people will come in with and
also they won't be able to touch the
plant so it keeps us completely
compliant and legal so we've designed
the facility to be tore prepared so
we've got these big giant windows what
do you say they're 12 feet tall Mike
easy okz twelve all right so these are
big eight by twelve I'm just getting
there about eight feet wide by about
twelve feet tall
big-ass panes of glass with gigantic
their garage doors but calling them
garage doors down place that yeah it's
it's a good description but I can't do
better but yeah it under placed
significantly what we've got here their
garage doors made by Kodak and they are
used in the darkroom film developing
industry and the professional film
developing industry is what I was told
these doors are for so we've got these
grow rooms and of course in the night
cycle and the grow rooms we need a
hundred percent darkness and we need to
have that whenever the timer requires
that so these doors garage style doors
roll up and down on a little button and
it keeps the light out and it also maybe
we're doing something in there that we
don't want you to watch so maybe we can
close it down for privacy so the workers
can work in there without the torah' see
in that little area so the fire
inspector came and a big part of those
doors is their fire safety if there
happens to be a fire in that grow room
those doors will pop down the smoke
alarm will go off that when the smoke
alarm triggers a drop and those doors
all drop at one time and then the fire
hopefully is contained to that small
area and we can put it out
ah the fire inspector was walking around
he had his arms crossed trying to be
tough you know what I mean like the fire
inspector has to be a brute it can't be
a [ __ ] he has to hold his ground and be
a stern dude right and you can see the
look on his face like wow this is kind
of a nice facility
he was like checking it out like but he
was trying to not show it holding this
clipboard in his pan like a tough guy
and then he goes what I need to see is I
want you to trip one of these fire
alarms right here he just picked one
randomly and he goes I need all of these
doors to fall and we looked at each
other like they're gonna fall we've we
tested them all day yesterday we like
fine-tune this you know it's gonna work
he pushes the button and goes beep and
all the doors came down beautifully in
unison it sounds like a train starting
up when they go down because there's
like 15 of these doors that weigh 300
pounds each coming down on a track and
they just all perfectly in unison and
when they hit the floor there's a little
trigger that stops them and like a
hydraulic that makes him just when they
stop he uncrossed his arms and looked
around he goes I'm impressed I'm gonna
sign off inside our little fire paper
thing so it was so great to hear him the
way you impress the fire inspector
you're doing something right a lot of
people work that's absolutely true shot
at the Sam Sam was a big help that day
the Department of Agriculture told us
they were impressed because we are doing
what other people said is not possible
for a girl facility other people can't
seem to catch on and figure out how to
do what Robert has done in that place so
shout out to the spot you guys are doing
it right people keep asking me how long
it's getting closer guys it's getting
close make sure you drop in the spot
dispensary if you're ever in Pueblo or
Pueblo West Colorado this is not a spot
commercial I just wanted to talk about
some exciting [ __ ] that happened of
course and the lead grower at the spa
dispensary and what happens all day
keeps me excited we get to do some fun
[ __ ] you do something you love it
doesn't feel like work all day right
like there's a lot of [ __ ] about my job
the [ __ ] feels like work oh they have
not saying it doesn't but there's a lot
of really fun [ __ ] that happened to like
I've got some 90 percent THC hash in my
oval right now and it just only had a
job for like nine hours was all it was
on the shelf
basically the first 15 people to find
out
we had it bought it yeah I would have
bought it had I known it was there and I
don't even buy into rehashing off
deploys put a hat worn at work and said
put one in the safe for me and managers
didn't get a shot at it and bought
employee under employees because I mean
there's a lot of perks like that just
just roll through randomly well that's I
didn't this wasn't a topic plan for the
show or anything but let's talk about
this a little bit I'm gonna fix this
compressor here I did turn up your mic a
touch but here we go make this [ __ ] all
work let's talk about how people are
always coming in and dropping off
applications to the dispensary and I get
a lot of emails on the Huayra Genetics
Facebook website whatever my own
personal Facebook the girl from your
heart Facebook Instagram Twitter
whatever people are always asking how do
they they're always talking about how
they want to work in a dispensary
because they want to play with weed all
day and it must be fun to play with weed
as weed how long have you been a
budtender this time I know you're about
tender for a little while when we had
the other dispensary but going on about
five months now five months now
um as we'd just basically become a
product or is it something that's fluffy
and still amazing and unicorn [ __ ] still
it's still unicorn e today we got it at
a new edible option that I've had in the
back of my mind like when I see one grab
one and it's been seven years now and I
ain't [ __ ] seen one and they showed up
today in my own store and yeah I have
one sitting in my bag right now that's
gonna get devoured here shortly oh I saw
that edible yeah so still it's still
like it's you still have a unit or at
least once a week something comes
through that getting it in checking it
out getting to tell other people about
it all they just blows my mind awesome
now how much what percentage of your day
and I'm going somewhere with this
I'm kind of baiting you what percentage
of your day is that unicorn chase I'm
just titled at the unicorn chase at work
I don't know 5% yeah okay and the other
95% is [ __ ] work right not quite okay
we're gonna freeze it like rolling doing
our pre-rolled joints we do like a pound
of worth at a time so that's 450 joints
and change and it takes days to go from
this is what we're gonna pre-roll to
here's what we have on our pre-roll
selection and the entire time it's in
the corner of the sales floor so we have
customers all day going all do that
looks like the best job ever and it's
not at all the best job ever it would be
if you could smoke one of them the whole
time you were rolling then it wouldn't
be so terrible but just just sit there
girl joint after joint after joint after
joint after joint without being able to
smoke it your hands get sticky you can't
touch your face like it's easily the
hardest grind at work right now
trimmings gonna equal that easily
trimming Ruby a [ __ ]
yep so that's where I was headed with
this you guys everybody wants to come
work at the dispensary but keep in mind
after you turn in your application if we
do hire you there will be a lot of
things or much work you had a bunch of
people come in and apply today and two
of them came well-dressed clean
appropriate turned in resumes spoke
eloquently and will get called called
back for an interview the guy that
showed up with lunch Oliver is sure at 9
o'clock at night and was like half
sloppy drunk like I want to work here
give me the info he ain't gonna work
here no he is not he is not gonna wear
out there oh man he's not getting a call
back yeah we get dozens of people a day
and honestly we're gonna be hiring a lot
of people here soon everybody in
Colorado is expanding everybody it's the
industry's doubling this year it's gonna
double again next year especially if
other states don't get to legalize in
2015 and 2016 if it's only one more
state the industry's gonna triple at
least in the next two or three years
it's not fast three times the employees
my spot has I think I counted 20 there's
about 20 employees there were a couple
that didn't come to the meeting the
other day there are about 20 of us
full-time employed there right now and
we're short-staffed yeah we could
definitely use a couple people so turn
in your resume at the spot get your
badge yeah go get your badge that's the
first thing you got to do you guys go
get your badge and then come come apply
at the spot but if you do once you do
get the job there'd be prepared to do
some work it's not gonna just be playing
with weed and that was another thing I
wanted to mention somebody was talking
about well you guys are just hanging out
smoking dope all day no do we can't even
smoke tobacco on the property because it
might look like marijuana on the cameras
and we don't need that mess with the
regulator's yes we have to be I think
the rule is a thousand feet from the
premises before anybody is allowed to
smoke in near any dispensary is actually
what I think the technical rule is it
may not be true but that's I don't know
if there's a like you can't smoke in
public in like parking lots or in public
okay and as far as on the dispensary
premises we're specifically barred from
having any sort of consumption a lot of
yesterday by state regulation that
includes all employees yep there's been
just a number of dispensaries that have
been fined because employees had like
vape cartridge pens in their purses and
stuff we're not supposed to have I can't
have my rig in my car no while I'm on
the clock if my car is in the parking
lot at the dispensary sorry guys I'm
burping I just opened up a fresh drink
and I'm burping it up while I'm
recording here while I'm in on the clock
at the dispensary working I can't have
my fresh shiny green Toro rigged in my
case in my backpack in the car so that
when I get off work I can drive over to
Mike's house and dab him out I can't
have it there or if I'm going to a
concert or a comedy show after work I
can't have my rig in my car so I have to
uh I'm a medical marijuana patient and
sometimes my back hurts sometimes I will
have to no no no no no no if I choose to
if I choose that I need to medicate
during working hours I have to drive
home and take a DAB eat lunch and then
drive all the way back to work because I
can't bring my damn backpack add a break
to work like shaking his head no like
you shouldn't say that but people have
seen my periscope they know that once in
a while I've dad
airplane yeah by the time I get back to
work it's like a [ __ ] 30-minute drive
back to the middle of the desert really
commuted much further that's good I know
more shitty jobs it's a good drive to
come on to music and just jam out cuz
it's a fast Drive it's mostly highway
miles so it's legit all right let's put
the show back on the damn road no we're
not allowed to smoke at work we're not
allowed to medicate anyone near the
building if you think about it it's when
you go to the liquor store like is the
clerk drunk like when you go to the gap
like fair point the kids probably dress
then I'll gap but like we go so far with
it at work that there's a special
protocol for employees buying we buy
stuff all day like every day there's at
least two employees that work that day
buying something but we've got special
protocol for it because if it's just
like in my car we can get a lot of
trouble for it oh yeah even if you go in
and you buy that diesel hatch what do
you have to do with it it goes in the
safe until the end of the shift and then
right at the end of the night like
whereas before we lock the front door
it's employees want to anybody buying
anything and then we all queue up just
like custody okay yep and then it all
gets sealed in an accident bag it's all
officials not even bring my backpack
like once in a while I'm gonna have to
bring clothes and stuff because I work
in the back I'm required by the
Department of Agriculture to have a
change of at least one change of clothes
like all the way down to the underwear
and socks in a locker accessible because
I'm handling pesticides and other
chemicals and things so I need I'm
required to have a change of clothes but
they're like bringing is little backpack
and stuff as you need to bring here they
don't we don't want backpacks and [ __ ]
coming into the building we don't need
it on camera
especially going to the back they're
like please just don't like yeah so I
pretty much take think about mine
because it never leaves the security
desk right yeah come on I come in and it
gets set on the counter and it comes off
the counter again when I leave I go into
the back and it's like a labyrinth back
there there's all kinds of nooks and
trained
there wouldn't be anywhere really to put
my backpack anyway so your locker it
wouldn't fit the lockers are only the
lawyers a team yeah they're per size so
if you got a purse that's I work on a
way off topic you guys really good
people that are not from Colorado kind
of like to hear our how our lives are
what's going on and since we're two
dudes that work it every day and are
just blown the [ __ ] away about how
regular it is how many uh so I heard
another person ask this and I thought it
would be interesting and I was gonna
talk about it in a future episode but
since you're here what's the breakdown
of people where they're from like how
many people are Colorado folk how many
people are from out of state and is
there am i talking [ __ ] when I say that
probably 50% of the people that come in
are from Texas is that true yeah fully
especially if we do a breakdown over the
if we're talking about like that a year
range okay usually half the people that
come through most recreational
dispensaries are tourists that's
statewide are places like Aspen it's
like 80 or 90% Wow
marijuana is crazy expensive up that we
get people from Aspen in our shop it's
crazy expensive in Aspen and they're
down in Pueblo because they were driving
through the area and weed Maps told them
to stop here go to the spot and they get
loaded up before they head back to their
city in Colorado where it's way more
expensive intercity nice but easily half
the people that roll through her from
Texas it's comes in bizarre waves like
I'm one day everybody from Alabama the
next day everybody will be from
Tennessee yesterday it was Missouri and
truckers we actually have a bus well I
don't know how they actually traveled
there were ten of them they come from
Kansas and they all come together and
they all would they always show up they
come about once a month there are ten of
them that show up it's like a field trip
this kind of happens way more often than
you'd think like families come through
today there was a girl with her
grandmother and her grandmother just had
a filthy mouth
after 30 Joe and the granddaughter was
mortified in there buying weed together
like it's we get [ __ ] like that constant
that's kind of neat
yep grandma and granddaughter buying
hers for there and they're all blown
away because we have marijuana stores
where you can walk in and just like
every other store there's a salesperson
there to tell you all about it the
biggest obstacle about the shop is the
security guard you have to have an ID
that says you're 21 and if you got that
go on in to buy some he goes it'll be a
second and he makes sure that there's
somebody back there and he goes go on
back he can go buy weed yeah and people
don't know what to think sometimes I
don't get to spend a lot of time upfront
because I'm supposed to be in the back
in the cave girl on the weed but
sometimes I got a venture up to the
front I got questions I gotta go find a
boss and now they're hard to find so I
just find myself in the bud room
watching and seeing what's going on and
a good portion of the people that I meet
are from out of state and they all see
the little board with the pins in it
like what's this I know I just gave
everybody in America like a weird all
right
everybody try to find a little spot we
had two from Michigan today when I was
up there the people I get somebody from
a different country at least once a week
this is people from all over the planet
they can we had a bunch of just gorgeous
girls from New Zealand come through one
day it was awesome that sounds fun like
just on the regular people from all over
the planet coming to Colorado to smoke
weed and they're coming through pueblos
I have to say that sometimes I go up
from there my piece of really beautiful
women in the waiting room holy crap yep
we've gotten way far off topic here you
guys this is not a spa that's some cool
[ __ ] does happen there listen I've done
a news article that I wanted to talk
about before we get there guys I wanted
to tell you what's going on in another
realm of my world I've been talking
about damsels dank if you have not been
keeping up if you don't listen to every
single episode come on what are you
doing I'm just kidding you can't listen
to everything I know I know there's
other [ __ ] to listen to do your homework
people Maya there's a suicide girl she's
a friend of mine if you're not familiar
with the Suicide Girls make yourself
familiar with that don't
don't don't look at the Suicide Girls it
won't maybe do girls are models and they
mostly are like tattooed and have some
piercings and maybe some dreadlocks here
and there is the word you're looking for
that might be with the word I'm trying
to fish out of my brain here thanks for
the help all these diesel dabs are
making my brain sticky anyway I've got a
suicide girl who's a friend of mine she
goes by dude it's damsel is her suicide
girl name she works with green and
healthy wellness a dispensary in
Colorado Springs that is now relocating
they are building the new facility so if
you guys are fans of green and healthy
wellness
stay tuned they'll be open pretty soon I
will be announcing the grand opening on
the show I think anyway so dude its
damsel asked me to develop a strain for
her right now I have got to I've started
three phenotypes three different strains
from seed that I'm going to phenotype
from for her two of those are now into
flower they are about 48 hours into
flower I think somewhere around there at
this point
so I in about nine weeks we will have
the first two test batches of damsels
DANC for dude its damsel my favorite
Suicide Girl damsel and I and a few
other Suicide Girls and my buddy the
grimy Gatsby and a couple deter people
and a few other folks Mike's giving me
the head nod like wait you said a few
other Suicide Girls the numbers are
looking good here we're gonna have a
tasting party it'll probably be in
Colorado Springs possibly Denver well
it's depending on how much herb there is
you may get a little sample you may get
a sample of what gets selected because
there will be things that she likes that
I don't like that I don't like that she
does like I think I said that the
opposite but there is the grower and the
breeder all like different things in her
for her we're looking for one specific
thing there may be something that pops
out of this search for us then we're
gonna keep it as nothing to do with her
yeah that's more what I wanted it for is
I wanted to get in on the pheno hunt for
an entirely different reason he's like
let's find Madison this party sounds
kind of awesome too yes the party will
be pretty
am fun from what I hear they know how to
throw a party John hunt is the Turk
gatherer I just did say that that is the
truth so they're in flower and like nine
weeks we should have some like nine
weeks we should have some damsels dank
two-sample it'll be a lot of fun I'll
keep you guys updated on how that goes
they should be here to take some
pictures and things pretty soon that'll
be really interesting I'll try to well
try to get damsel in the podcast before
too long but you guys since green and
healthy had to relocate without a lot of
warning they are [ __ ] busy yep
yes um let's see we've been gone 22
minutes do we want to read an article or
do we want to talk yeah let's go read
this news article I've got here because
I found this interesting and it's kind
of its kind of important maybe this will
help some people out and this will
definitely interest Mike Mike doesn't
know what I'm gonna read this will
definitely get your attention Mike the
headline says FDA issues warnings to
makers of legal CBD hemp oil products
let me go and find who it's by so I can
give them credit it's by Thomas H Clark
from The Daily chronic I found it on the
daily chronic we will read the article
that goes a lot like this consumer
should beware purchasing and using any
such products the FDA says the Food and
Drug Administration has sent letters to
several makers of cannabidiol oils
derived from hemp telling them to stop
making medical claims about their
products ability to treat disease many
sellers of the Hep A Scanner bidi all
products who advertise their products is
legal in all 50 states because they are
derived from industrial hemp have been
making claims that their products are
rich in cannabidiol and can be used for
the diagnosis cure mitigation treatment
or a presentation of diseases according
to the FDA the FDA which considers CBD
an unapproved new drug said these
companies are misbranding the products
and issuing false claims to consumers
often these products do not even list
their ingredients on the product label
the FDA said consumers should beware
purchasing and using any such products
it is important to note that these
products are not a lot are not approved
by the FDA for the diagnosis cure
mitigation treatment or prevention of
any disease in late February the FDA
issued several warning letters to seven
companies that manufacture and market
hemp oils claiming to be rich in CBD
by promising cures for conditions such
as cancer autism and epilepsy none of
which have been tested by the FDA the
companies who were issued warning
letters appeared to be violating food
and drug labeling laws in some cases
hold on throats going crazy here I'm
gonna take a drink this happens
occasionally we take a lot of grouse
where am i I'm right here in some cases
the companies could not even smell
cannabidiol or inflammation correctly
the FDA notes on the market for a while
and it's always been crap well one thing
that I wanted to get to is a lot of this
stuff is brought in from other countries
because now that we have got this market
they're doing kind of like what they did
with spice you know they see that this
CBD stuff is really popular and they're
just sending us crap it may be partially
CBD so if they can write that on the
bottle but then it's just other random
oils just as a filler so you don't even
know what you're giving these sick kids
you have to get I'll finish reading the
article and I'll try to remember where I
am with this rant the following
companies and products were among those
notified by the FDA then there are
hyperlinks here also you guys it was a
bunch of companies cancer herb tea ,
Florida CBD life holdings of Arizona
hemp oil care of California pure CBD of
Washington it was a bunch of them and
then it also says the FTD FDA also
conducted tests of some products sold by
these companies and found that in most
cases the products contained very little
cannabidiol or none at all and there are
some bullet points that show some of the
test findings I won't read them all
it says the FDA tested two separate
samples of ultra CBD sold by CBD Life
Holdings offer it's one ounce bottle for
$45 on their website or on Amazon of the
samples tested one did not contain any
cannabinoids while the second contain
only point zero two percent CBD all the
products tested by the FDA that were
found to contain some CBD the ultra CBD
products contained the smallest
percentage so you guys are paying for
stuff that doesn't even have any CBD in
it which is gonna make me wonder what is
in it
this is a big issue for a lot of usko
states that have passed Charlotte's Web
laws that allow for CBD only products
but they don't allow for you to get them
anywhere right essentially the law
requires you to come to Colorado or
another legal state by something and
then break a bunch of federal laws on
your way home by taking it home and then
yeah if you're able to smuggle at home
you can go ahead and then legally use it
but that's mildly insane and so when
you're googling and you see hey boils
[Music]
CBD oils what there's one package says
if you're lucky you're getting hemp seed
extract if you're lucky if you're lucky
the bottom layer of whatever oil some
company in China makes and decided to
bottle up and label it as THC or CBD oil
right yep so the article keeps going I
want to finish this up just so we can
finish the whole article it says the
warned CBD companies have 15 days to
follow the FDA to show the FDA how they
are complying with the warning letters
failure to comply to failure to promptly
correct these violations may result in
legal action without further notice
including without limitation seizure
and/or injunction the FDA warns medical
marijuana experts suggest patients
considering CBD treatment to instead
seek CBD rich strains of cannabis grown
in states that allow medical marijuana
such as Colorado who also require
independent laboratory testing of all
marijuana products so medical experts
are even saying what Mike and I say go
to Colorado get some lab tested facility
grown quality cannabis that's safe that
doesn't have any pesticides in it
because if it does it's been quarantined
and taken away like we're almost to
where we need to be regulatory wise here
in Colorado they're going the wrong
direction with their new regulations but
where they need to be adding stuff as in
pesticide testing those regulations
aren't up to speed yet because the
testing labs aren't in place yet because
the FDA will certify tests like it just
spirals right because of our dumbass
prohibition is everybody
- the show knows what I'm gonna say the
solution there is to legalize it yes
just do it already yeah and then the FDA
would already be overseeing all this
hemp seed extract [ __ ] you'd be able to
legally confidently buy CBD oil this
legit CBD oil you'd know what you were
taking or giving your kid or whatever
yeah so this is partially like to warm
people if you're buying this crappy CBD
oil you're probably not getting any help
for your ailment hey if you know if it's
like what if what if it's a placebo
effect if it's working and you felt
better what do you what do you think
sure they could do it in ER I don't know
cuz maybe they're taking some weird [ __ ]
I'm not telling you to take or not to
take any thats the truth if something
works it works for a reason yeah but who
knows what you're taking guys so the
advice here is to come to Colorado or
legalize it where you are fight for
legalization and my guidance is when it
comes time to legalize in your area
don't pass CBD only legislation no pass
cannabis like recreational or medical
cannabis use to where you can consume
flower tor you can make extracts where
you can consume extracts and edibles
make it all part of that because just
the CBD is only going to work for a very
small portion of the medical cannabis
community CBD doesn't do a damn thing
for me like I need my THC right right
and I have a CBD episode coming up on
the future and guys I know I keep saying
that but I'm putting it together there
are some episodes I can throw together
in like a day or two the CBD episode is
going to take me quite a while it's
going to be a series I'm gonna get
several people to talk on it and tell us
how CBD treats them but Mike is
definitely gonna be one of the people on
there already Doug is gonna be part of
that show Mike will be part of that show
we'll get a lot of people on there I
just met a few people recently that are
well-known in the CBD community so that
will help us out then we're finally
starting to get CBD CBD products real AB
reliably in the rec market I got out
some time I'm out notice that yeah I
was impressed we were talking to the
purchaser for the shop and he was asking
us what he asked us for guidance we
knows that were potheads he's like what
should I buy guys and he showed us an
order that he was able to get really
high CBD products and we encouraged him
to do that for the wreck shop so that
we've got that available for people as
well yeah come check it out you guys try
some CBD see what it does for you it may
help you out some people it's the
miracle for me there's nothing but so
like I'm saying don't go with the CBD
only because CBD only wouldn't do
anything for me it's the synergistic
effect is what we're searching for in my
opinion we need a little little bit of
THC to make it all work I think it's all
one one unified thing that's my opinion
so when it comes time to legalize guys
make sure you don't just do CBD I need
to give a shout-out to the author of
this article I like to remind you too it
was it was Thomas H Clark from the daily
chronic you guys be careful if you're
using an oil CBD products don't make
yourself sicker than you already are
know what you're using if you're buying
stuff from a shop and it doesn't have
lab testing start asking for it it's
it's just a matter of time until this is
just like everything else when you go to
a store and buy something you know what
you're buying you can look at the label
on it and know what's in it and be sure
that what's on the label is actually in
it because the FDA is testing this yes
yes well now we have the meed backing
you up will in Colorado the FDA is not
allowed to so we literally had to create
from the ground up our own meed they do
I mean that I remember when the first
testing labs were open the state didn't
give a [ __ ] that was the industry
demanding it patients were beginning to
demand it shops needed to know what they
were putting out and testing and back in
the day I was able to take my product my
finished flowers my hash to a shop and
have it tested there's discussions of
reopening laughs the caregivers I hope
so because right now they've lost the
rule so tight well part of the thing is
if the shops have them so overwhelmed
there are so few labs that are qualified
that right now if I wanted to take my
product I'd probably have to wait a
month anyway so they just disallowed us
to be able to do it there's one type of
testing and I honestly can't remember
what it is it's not potency but I can't
remember what that special
the test that we were hoping to get done
there's only one lab and it's in like
Durango oh it's a residual solvent test
yep you guys are looking for yeah it's
only for hash it's they can only do that
in Durango and so we're literally
discussing who we're gonna send it
Arango gonna draw the short straw and
drive like 14 hours across the state
it's 14 hours i'm ballparking okay I
might need a day off that'll be fun I
think steep hill Halen can possibly do
those same tests but I'm not sure I can
don't quote me there yeah that was a
discussion I overheard a couple of
months ago heard part of that today
actually we're talking about labs and
such today one of the offices awesome
too much talk about work on this episode
huh guys leave it in the comments sorry
it's what we did all day we've been gone
about 33 minutes dude I've got a couple
more things here that I'm gonna save cuz
this right here is gonna take a while I
wanted to talk about I'm just gonna give
it a couple of quick seconds here then
we don't have to get too much into it
ah you guys follow the UFC a lot I'm not
a huge UFC follower
I followed Joe Rogan more than I follow
the UFC but that's attached that's my
third degree of separation or whatever
you're gonna call it but there is
something that happened in the UFC that
as a pothead as a cannabis activists as
somebody who is part of the marijuana
community this got my attention there's
a UFC fighter who tested positive for
using cannabis who has been suspended
for five years five years dude his his
career has been put on hold is uh his
salary has been put on hold and they
also find him a hundred and fifty
thousand dollars for passing for failing
a pee test for cannabis I think that's
kind of silly I don't think saying yeah
dude that's his job that's what this guy
training has trained his whole life for
you know it's it's totally and totally
insane and there's a couple of different
reasons why it's insane like if it was
steroids this would be a little insane
like five years is an insanely long
amount of time it's not a
performance-enhancing drug like it's
been shown to be helpful and protect
against concussions and recovering from
head injury yes and kicked in the face
for a live ads his job yeah yeah like
there's a thousand different reasons why
this insane and I love uh I'm gonna
probably butcher her name so I apologize
because you for sure kicked my ass but I
think it's Ronda Rousey independently
went off during the press conference and
I saw that video oh yeah peripherally
followed this story but she went off for
basically the same reasons I did right
to misquote Ronda Rousey but to
paraphrase and misquote her basically
what she said was I have somebody uses
steroids and they're in a ring fighting
that potentially gives them the ability
to hit me harder and kill me but if they
are smoking cannabis that gives them the
ability to heal themselves they are
smoking a plant that was put here for us
to smoke and we were going to punish
people for it is basically what she said
I'm gonna [ __ ] it all up already told
you that I totally agree with Ronda
Rousey is absolutely on the money with
that there's a petition I'm not gonna
sign the petition I haven't signed it
yet but if you guys what if you're if
you're in the UFC do you think it's
wrong that this dude's been suspended
here's the thing they did give him three
P tests and two of them were clean and
this third one was not even necessary it
was by I've got a news article in the
screen that I was gonna read but I
didn't even want to get that far into
this but it says Diaz submitted three
urine samples on the ninth one prior to
his fight and two and the hours
afterward I'm really going quickly
through this of those three samples the
first and the third administered under
the world anti-doping agency protocol
and submitted for testing to the W ad a
accredited sports medicine research and
testing lab in Salt Lake City both of
those came back clean so that's the
world anti-doping agency you can't cheat
that pee test I don't care how bad you
are they see your wiener they see your
dick when you're peeing they watch the
pee come out of the head of your pee
hole like it comes they watch it into
the container and then they [ __ ] seal
it themselves they're wearing rubber
gloves and catching it for you basically
it's not the only reason I'm not an MMA
fighter was on the [ __ ] list
this is however the truth the 10:30 p.m.
test however was administered by a
separate testing representative and
submitted to quest Diagnostics Anan W a
DA accredited lab so that labs not even
accredited that test came back over the
threshold for allowable marijuana
metabolites resulting in the loan
positive test this company that tested
him isn't even accredited by the world
anti-doping agency and they did pass
there what the [ __ ] Las Vegas sporting
whatever you're called the Nevada
sporting and something commissioned I'm
not cool with you guys this sucks you
guys need to go just sign the petition
so that Nick Diaz can get back get his
career back five years for a UFC fighter
dude that would that's that's like half
of your career
you only get to go from your early 20s
until maybe 30 something unless you're a
bad [ __ ]
once you get the mid-thirties
testosterone starts to drop in you can't
take the punches is he gonna come back
like Tyson after prison the [ __ ] knee
blows out or something we talkin Philly
and chief of pigeons no people it might
be neat to see but I don't wanna have to
wait five years to see it fight for me
this is just another example of why
everyone needs to get involved and get
educated like this guy doesn't get to
fight for five years because he peed
dirty other people are losing their kids
because they peed dirty like other
people are going to jail because they're
selling people caught that people want
because we want to smoke a plant while
other people can drink some [ __ ] that
makes them drive like maniacs oh I can't
blame it on alcohol but yeah because
people want to smoke a plant we're going
to jail we're not allowed to have the
careers we want this dude can't fight
this is terrible because we all hang
back like we all get [ __ ] on regularly
alright I think that's enough for Nick
Diaz support that you guys I do Mike
thanks for joining me bro
didn't want to end on a down note know
what positive [ __ ] you got for us
take a phat dev and give your mama for
you that's my line bro it's worse [ __ ]
to go the positive thing is that we will
be back or at least I will be back next
Monday I'll have a whole nother episode
for you we're gonna talk about a
discussion with a stranger on Facebook
about is holding your smoke a good idea
he thinks you get hired from holding
your smoke that was his statement and
then we'll talk about other people's
theories including mine if you'd like to
be involved in this we will schedule
this for a time when Mike can return for
the podcast interesting like to get you
it's not gonna be the whole show but
that's there definitely you're gonna
hear my opinion on that so if somebody
else would like to come and be on that I
think that it's not a good idea so if
you think it's a good idea message me
I'd like your opinion email Jeff that's
right send me your opinion either way
holding your smoke when you take a bong
hit when you take a DAB when you take a
smoke off of a joint do you think it's a
good idea to hold in your smoke for a
few seconds how long do you think you
should hold in your smoke do you hold in
your smoke differently for your dab then
you do a joint I'll let me hear it do
you think it's you want to hold your
smoke or do you want to just in and out
how long do you hold it do you think if
you hold it for 10 or 15 seconds you're
getting higher let me hear your opinion
on that [ __ ] you can tweet it to me if
it's under 140 characters it's at G fyh
podcast if it's longer than that you're
gonna have to email me it grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
or of course you can hit me up on the
Facebook just find me it's a growth from
your heart if you're one of my friends
just [ __ ] text me bro it's so funny
when I get text messages about the show
I'm gonna your text message you can all
forget delete all my messages but anyway
I'm rambling now contact me let me know
what you think about holding in your
smoke that's what's coming up on a
future episode are you trying to think
about more positive [ __ ] over there
rattling through my brain about what
I've read about holding in the smoke
yeah there's multiple opinions on this
topic yeah we'll save that one we'll get
that out on another episode yeah let's
wrap up the show man I'm trying to think
of some positive [ __ ] we're here you're
here okay here's some positive [ __ ] did
you read that the CERN Large Hadron
Collider was supposed to open up two
black holes which is gonna open a
wormhole and the earth was gonna be
swallowed and we're all gonna die
that was supposed to happen on the 23rd
and we're recording on the 24th so guess
what we didn't die so that's a positive
note we're here first we'll destroy the
meteor again y'all be the hero in this
story
[Music]
II need something right now all right
we're gonna wrap up the show Mike and I
are [ __ ] chatty and high as [ __ ] yeah
diesel Debs yeah those diesel dabs made
me sativa eyed everything all right
Branagh thank you for coming and hanging
out taking an hour out of your day you
got a new baby at home congratulations
on that thank you thanks for taking time
away from that little guy to come hang
out with me I know what that's like
prying away from him right sure you will
wrap this up make sure you guys follow
Mike it's an emo Punk 15 on Twitter let
him know that you found him here on the
podcast he likes to know where the
followers came from whereas stalkers
arrived from sometimes it's easy to tell
like when it's 2:00 a.m. and I haven't
tweeted in a day and a half and it's a
story name in photo I can assume other
times I have no [ __ ] clue like Debbie
McNab erson just followed me I bet
that's from the podcast right nice
somebody's gonna make up a screen name
Debbie MacGyver sin and tweet me from it
it'll be really funny [ __ ] happens
because I really want to thank you for
listening to the podcast thanks again to
Mike for showing up I'll be back in
another week you guys I don't have any
sponsors for this month's podcast or
this month for the podcast if you're
interested in sponsoring the show send
me an email to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you need you can
sponsor the show we'll put your product
out there we get over 5,000 listens
within 48 hours so we can hype up your
product really well now that the show is
over you guys please go to iTunes
iTunes store search for girl from your
heart find the review section and give
me a five star rating please you know
we're worth five stars yeah I bought a
lot of toys sounds good
let me know you think of the show I'll
read your comments on a future episode
you guys um I already said to follow me
on all the social media don't forget the
show is available on iTunes and stitcher
and every single episode is always and
forever archived on I read genetics
Colorado com that'll never go away I do
apologize that the website has not been
updated in quite a while my web guy has
been occupied with school so we're just
gonna let him do that when he gets out
of school then he'll fix up the website
at school first I'm not gonna distract
him we're all about education here I did
say education what else do we got I
think that's all we got for the show so
until next time I need to give a huge
huge shout out to manager Spence in the
entire garden of Weeden crew big shout
out to my new rig she has been named
Juanita thanks for joining the family
Juanita she's a cute little Toro rig
she's beautiful she hits like a champ
she looks really good with the email on
her like you're quiet about that you
looked at it and looked away like a
[ __ ] don't hurt me to burn ature check
out Big Cartel darts burnisher Big
Cartel calm I'll go to Big Cartel Calm
search for burn ature and look what
they're making they're making coffee
tables they're making shelves they're
making tables I'm making all kinds of
random [ __ ] that you can think of with
the [ __ ] email built into it you guys
you can have an email built into some
random [ __ ] that one just made a weird
twinkling noise I hope that was your
phone it was alright that's cooler than
the email doing it cuz that wasn't a
feature that I knew about your new rig
does not have digital it was pretty cool
alright guys we're getting dispensed
thanks again for listening huge shout
out to my homie Mike for coming over
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff thanks again for joining me you
guys sitting across the table from me
once again is my good buddy white Mike
how you doing buddy the [ __ ] out I got a
couple of new rigs I've been hitting
them like a champion they're working
working be smooth try to transition just
dropping that [ __ ] to zero well thanks
for coming bro yeah do you work today I
did we kind of talked a little bit about
the spot last time we're not gonna do
that we were gonna talk about some other
stuff I just want to give Mike a big
thanks for getting here cuz I he's a new
father I know it's got to be kind of
rough pulling away from the kid so
thanks for showing up at this kind of
late hour on a Saturday night right
there's a couple of reasons out a half
away right now
we'll slap you around if you fall asleep
I may push the mic right in your face
and make you talk a lot because I keep
turning [ __ ] up and it's not gonna go
much higher so um let's see where do we
want to start we've got a lot of great
news articles to talk about you guys um
before I get too far I want to give a
huge shout out to my new friends at
elevate glass in Colorado Springs
elevate glasses on South Tejon I should
have the exact address in my hand I
think it's five I'm gonna say 512 South
Tejon it's on the 500 block of South Bay
hone there is a dispensary right there
altitude organic medicine and then
there's a tattoo shop and then right
next to that is elevate the glass shop
go there they've got great glass at
affordable pricing and they might have
super hot maybe you know that might be
one of the bonuses of why I like to go
there I can't confirm it or die yeah
mike has not done with me I've been
there twice and both times there was a
very lovely lady there ready and willing
and able to help me with all of my glass
needs
it was great I'll definitely be back I
got a new I think I talked about the
it's a mothership knockoff basically
that I got there about a week ago and
then just last night I went picked up a
little hitman 2 mini with the hammer
head on the inside and I had to grab it
it's got a yellow logo I've never seen a
hitman like this with the yellow logo
before and I thought it was super cute
so I picked it up and man it hits like a
Mack truck so I'm super impressed
it really does it's uh your collection
is growing by leaps and bounds in the
new wonderful was the first word that
comes to mind
nice I don't have as many rigs you might
think because well I got rid of a couple
through a place to make room for these
so that's the truth I'm not as much of a
rig junkie as you might think
buy a Master Shake yeah Master Shake was
fun slop he's got that shut up too
sloppy
make sure you guys check out oil MP and
arts on Facebook that's my buddy sloppy
it's his glass trading page if you're
looking for a new glass our artistic
glass functional glass at a great price
my buddy sloppy is now in the glass
business so make sure you support that
shout out to sloppy
all right so somebody sent me an email
let's start off the show with an email
from a friend this is kind of not
cannabis related and it's funny because
he starts his email this is from my
buddy Justin and now the email says so
this isn't really a show or growing
question just a matter of personal
curiosity what do you think of montes
yahoo do you feel like his music is
reggae or not or not really listen to
him just wondering doing fat dabs from
Justin G Justin dude I'll give you a big
shout-out you follow me on Facebook you
follow me on the podcast you follow me
on almost every periscope video that I
make I really appreciate your support
it's great to have a little cult we'll
listen to almost everything that I put
out I definitely appreciate you guys a
little following there that's freaking
awesome I totally appreciate that so
let's talk about montes Yahoo Mike's
ridden around in the car with me and
heard what happens when Matisyahu comes
up on the shuffle you gotta join in and
get out those freaky big boy dinky doo
doo eyes you gotta get there and get
going with him dude that [ __ ] is so much
fun I've learned to meditate while you
drive not just hold on yeah well kind of
where's yourself in there for impact and
then tune out and pretend like it's not
reggae all day you put yourself in your
happy place
oh they do play some reggae at work
alright so let's talk about how I feel
about Matisyahu um dude that's kind of
ah so one day my buddy Ross Christian
who was one of the guys it taught me a
lot about Rastafari I shot it to Chris
much respect
Ross Chris gave me a little CD with one
Matisyahu song I came home and listened
to it and I was like that is the [ __ ]
right there I just really liked the flow
like the music was good but I liked the
way it felt it just flowed really smooth
his lyrics were really smooth over
everything so I downloaded more right
and I loved it I found shake off the
dust of rise and I found whybut stubs or
what was available at that time so I was
driving from Pueblo Colorado to Lawrence
Kansas on a regular basis I had a band
out there and I was lived here and had a
band out there and then I travel back
and forth all the time to take care of
life I had a CD player in the car and
all of my CDs got stolen except for the
one that was in the CD player
to a bunch of people I know and it was
why if it stubs it was the wife at stubs
album so that's what I had to drive back
and forth to Lawrence Kansas and it's
about at an 11 hour drive depending on
traffic and depending on how things go
so that's 10 or 11 opportunities to
listen to that CD from beginning to end
both ways yeah I totally fell in love
with that album
dude shake off the dust rise came a
little bit later in my life I think I
got that one right after I got tired of
the Y right after the theft after
everything got stolen but yeah so I went
to Lawrence Kansas and showed a couple
of my friends I was like check this guy
out
and then we saw Matt Walker Russa and on
the first night at Wakarusa fest in 2005
I believe there wasn't anybody there
there's like 40 of us up front checking
out Matisyahu the second night there had
to be a hundred and fifty people there
the third night that place was packed
he took one night off it was like a four
night festival he takes a Saturday off
for the the Sabbath by the Sunday night
when he played it was packed you
couldn't even get in the yes over three
nights he just blew up like that so I
I've seen ma kiss I got to go see
Matisyahu on my one of my birthday's my
girlfriend took me to see him at the
Beaumont theater in Kansas City Kansas
of all random places when I lived in
Lawrence so yeah I got to see montes a
few times have seen her at the
bottleneck and Lawrence I've seen him a
lot but yeah that artist meant a lot to
me just from that time period it really
brings me back to that whole time period
of my life it got no water was my
favorite montes song and then
unfortunately when he came out with the
album youth I feel like he put all of
his life's work into the shake off the
dust arise album like all of his writing
for 20 years of being a person he put
into that and then he did check out her
life at Stubbs which is basically the
same thing just live and they're like
all right now you've got a production
deal in a record deal let's make an
expensive album and he was like oh [ __ ]
I almost like I don't I don't like the
new stuff as much as I did the old stuff
but that happens to a lot of artists I
feel the same way about spearhead kind
of goldish it was much better there's
something about music that whatever
drives you to create it
dyes weren't enough money lands on top
of it right that's kind of how I feel
about it like especially if you're like
an angry band that's where you see it
the most take all right you just got
like a twelve million dollar contract
why are you still angry right and unless
they really start buying just more
expensive heroin or something right yeah
where would we board with music this
we've really gotten off the rails this
is Cass but we're losing just a lot
about weed he knows so much more about
music I do know a lot about music yeah I
could probably do music podcast I've
played the drums for so long I can read
and write music and I know a lot about
music music playing and listening and I
also know about bands yeah we could do a
whole show about that cuz we've gotten
way off topic but where would we be
where would music be where would
musicians be if they didn't alter their
minds a little bit
The Beatles wouldn't never came up with
any of that [ __ ] if they didn't start
life would be very for sure the Grateful
Dead would not have been fun if I was
not tripping my face off I think there's
a great Lenny Bruce rant to that effect
alright so I want to put the show back
on track just a little bit we're almost
10 minutes in and we haven't talked
about weed at all hey Justin thanks for
the email dude you really like made me
time-travel in my mind when I read that
it was really reminiscing on those days
matisyahu's great he's got a great
message he's a positive dude he doesn't
use any profanity so it's good for the
kids he only talks about good stuff and
to pump your head and heart with good
stuff is always better than listening to
some negative [ __ ] that makes you want
to do stupid [ __ ] I don't listen to
things like it doesn't support anything
good for your mind so listen to some
montes Yahoo listen to some spearhead a
lot of people around here in tunak oh I
can't for some reason medicine for the
people but a lot of the hippy kids or
all the dreadlock kids are loving it now
so check that out if you need some good
positive music in your life all right
let's get on to something that has
something to do with cannabis do you
want to talk about let's see you want to
go I got three topics here they're all
equally important we've got the 30 shops
we've got recreational cannabis is now
legal in the state of Oregon should we
stir and
well alright that's our good news and
then we've got an article about somebody
getting shot so let's go bad bad good
let's end on a positive note this time
last night it was a down note we had to
come up with positive [ __ ] all right
well then let's start the bad bad if you
want to go worst first let me open up
Google here I've already got this
article saved where is it here it is it
happened again this year you guys it is
outdoor season and people people that
are growing outdoors are sitting outside
waiting for thieves the past two
weekends
over the past fourteen or fifteen days I
have heard of about seven or eight maybe
nine or ten outdoor grows getting stolen
it's that time of year people it is
Ripper season yeah or Ripper homey
season I hate it it's uh I've had a lot
of people in my world have just wrecked
winners because
[Music]
of drippers do they spend all summer
throwing their life into a crop and then
it vanishes before it's done you wake up
you go out there to water your plants
and guess what they're not there anymore
I saw something about a van get busted I
want to say it was in California that
was just packed full of plants that had
just been ripped on security cam footage
with people's faces and plans yeah right
now if you are in any pot group on
Facebook somebody has posted a picture
of some [ __ ] and it says this guy
stole my pot plants do you know who he
is it's all over Facebook right now
everybody is getting ripped off so it
happened in our town somebody let's just
get right to the news article here you
guys I've got it on the on the screen
the headline is you need something up
there bro yeah no no you need AB my
brain wants cigarette but if you have a
vape I'll let you fade in here but no
came unprepared came unprepared I
apologize for your lack of preparations
[Music]
we can't make a new father he came over
here it's like on a Saturday night
[Music]
running out of time to do things I've
been medicated we can talk about the
spot on the show headline says before I
get that far this is from Jesse Paul of
the Denver Post I thundered on Denver
Post calm it says Pueblo police
that's our town you guys puddle oh the
city of public Onorato the seven one
nine that's where we are
Pueblo police team shot after
burglarizing bird
burglarizing burglarizing was the word
that I couldn't say teen shot after
burglarizing illegal marijuana grow
investors investigators say Vincent
Durand the homeowner shot at the two
alleged burglars you got anything to say
Mike you look like you're about to speak
up I heard about this story the next
morning and yeah it's a horrible
incident everybody's going to jail
everybody both of the kids are gonna
being charged with burglary
the homeowners being charged with
first-degree assault that's what happens
when you shoot somebody who's running
away from your property okay all right
well let's read the article here it says
a 17 year old boy was shot early Friday
in Pueblo after authorities say he
burglarized a man's illegal marijuana
grow let's update the people why it's
illegal before we even go too far
because we are in Colorado everyone is
allowed to grow six plants of their own
every adult if you have a medical
marijuana recommendation from a doctor
you are able to grow possibly more
plants but in the city of Pablo within
the city limits of Pueblo it is now
illegal to grow any sort of cannabis
recreational or medicinal outside of
your home in your yard that is not in an
enclosed building greenhouses are
illegal it has to be like a sealed
normal building like a has to be like in
a fountain date building with the
foundation as part of the rule
it has to be so many square feet like
there are thorough rules that you have
to follow excuse me the dabs you you
can't just plant six plants in your
backyard anymore um they did away with
that a year ago statewide you just have
to have it in a locked enclosed space
but every city and county in town now
have their own little rules for the most
part right so here we can so his grow
was illegal and he's being charged with
nuisance violations if I remember
correctly a thousand dollars a pop per
plant
Wow yep so that's six thousand and city
fines plus he's got to destroy the
plants plus he's being charged with
first-degree assault for shooting a
teenager destroy them take him inside
it's just about time he has to destroy
them
small fires yeah he's got to cut them
down and they can't be out there anymore
but it's harvest time anyway yeah so
he's just got to chop him down now take
him inside but had this garden been
discovered by city inspectors or
regulators or if the neighbor called the
cops for whatever six months ago when
they were knee-high and there was no but
there he would had to cut him down then
- okay all right I'm gonna continue with
the article we just wanted to explain
why his grow was illegal since it is
Colorado that may be confusing to some
folks the article goes on to say police
say the teen showed up at a hospital at
about 4:15 a.m. Friday with a gunshot
wound to his right leg the juvenile male
initially stated he was shot after
leaving a party on the west side of
Pueblo police said in a news release
however it was later determined that he
had uh uh he and another individual had
jumped a fence into a yard on the 1600
block of Western 13th Street in hopes of
finding marijuana plants at an outdoor
grow investigators say Vincent Duran age
55 the homeowner shot at the two alleged
burglars striking of the team the
juvenile was treated released and taken
to the public services center where he
was booked on burglary charges police
say got imagine how that would suck dude
you gotta steal some weed or just a
teenage kid jackson Budd end up shot in
the leg at the hospital and then in
[ __ ] jail I have no yeah I don't
either
if the homeowner didn't kill him this
article has been all over Facebook
because our friends posted it to
Facebook and shared it and people have
commented [ __ ] kid got what he had
coming to them and people have commented
I woulda shot him again guys this is
cannabis I know this is your investment
I know this is your business
please don't [ __ ] shoot people over
weed you should be growing it legally
anyway it's legal here just follow the
simple rules and if somebody's trying to
steal those plants call the cops that's
what they're there for
that's why legalization is beautiful is
we finally get to use law enforcement
when somebody tries to steal our weight
yeah and we had a friend recently stolen
from who actually called and reported
his plants stolen and the cop asked him
how much was that plant going to harvest
you was it going to yield and he told
him how much of what would yield and he
said what would that cost you to buy at
a dispensary and he told him what that
would cost per ounce he called me and
got a price quote right it's on it be
this much per ounce dude and so on the
police report they values each plant at
what an ounce would cost at my shop and
now those people that will be caught
because they've got video of them
they'll be charged with felony theft
because they took over a certain amount
of dollars worth of product like the
beaut the real beauty of legalization is
that we can use courts and lawyers and
cops like the violence doesn't have to
exist there that's the truth even there
in your backyard they're stealing your
[ __ ] you guys you know make them run if
you've got a firearm pointed at them
don't [ __ ] shoot them as teenagers or
[ __ ] kids just flip the lights on I'm
not gonna run away there's a 17 year old
boy if you would have said freeze get on
the ground you could have called the
cops you could have dealt with it a
little bit better Reza dude shot a young
kid who was running away he was already
running away that's not cool nose on his
way out okay let's continue with the
article oh where was I - ran was
arrested on suspicion - first degree
assault and police say he'll also will
be issued a summons for the marijuana
grow he'll also be ordered to remove the
grow police say investigators say they
are searching for the teens accomplice
in August of 2014 a 13 year old boy was
wounded by a man after allegedly trying
to steal marijuana plants from a back
yard so you can see this is gonna happen
every year if we keep having these
illegal outdoor grows
just put it inside and put it inside
grow indoors nobody can see it if you're
doing it properly nobody can smell it
nobody knows it's there you can control
it you can grow year round right just go
get a carbon filter and a grow light and
i grow book read the book listen to the
show listen to the show I know the Sun
is free you guys but you got it in the
city of Pueblo it's illegal and if you
grow and it gets something like this
happens it puts a black eye on our
entire industry our entire community on
the plant on the movement on everything
somebody got shot over some weed because
somebody was growing it outside ok just
for the ballpark a decent little gross
setup for six plants is gonna run your
what the best gear 3 grand oh dude I
could set you up ready to grow for less
than a thousand bucks right but like if
you want with the best like three or
four Oh
25 how much would you pay to not just
sweat for six months eight months while
your plants are out back right if
someone's gonna steal your effort that's
the truth like for me it's definitely
worth more than a grinder tip and
if you think about it this way if you're
growing enough outside to make it worth
shooting somebody for it
you are doing your growing more than you
need probably maybe you're growing your
entire year supply I can't judge you but
think about the situation if you need if
you're growing that much you might be
asking for something if you're trying to
get greedy you might be asking you might
be inviting trouble if you're trying to
get greedy is what I think I'm saying
right this dude's gonna end up
harvesting enough weed to get him till
he's got to turn himself in to go to
jail like it sucks they decided to shoot
the kid trying to steal his weed and now
he's gonna end up in jail for it the
kid's going to jail for trash like it's
just shitty all around because this dude
wanted to skirt the law in a place where
it's legal
no let's change let's just change the
item being stolen from excuse me guys
sorry let's change this item from
cannabis plants to a car if it goes down
like this everybody's still going to
jail yeah but would you have shot at
somebody stealing your car
a feeling this guy would yeah okay you
know we had an incident in the city a
couple of years ago it got a whole lot
of press because it was particularly
brutal this guy kind of lived in the
middle of nowhere and had a trash pile
with a bunch of scrap metal in it and
people kept pulling up in the middle of
the night and stealing his scrap metal
so one night he got his rifle and turned
all the lights off and when the pickup
truck showed up the people climbed out
and turned flashlights on he opened fire
he killed one of them wounded another
one held one of them at gunpoint till
the cops got there it was looking at
like first-degree murder charges because
that's first-degree murder like you
can't lie in wait and kill people he
plays the [ __ ] an event like
I don't know it's just blow people oh
man this is gonna happen all over the
country just Oregon - its Ripper season
you guys don't like that's a big part of
growing marijuana it used to be because
it was illegal but it was always also
because marijuana is worth a lot of
money especially in places where it
isn't legal and if you can steal it from
someone your your cost is zero and you
can take it somewhere where you can sell
it for six eight thousand a pound so
people are gonna try to steal it and the
people that are gonna try to steal it
are [ __ ]
these guys are professionals story I was
told a story of somebody who got into a
greenhouse with a poly vinyl cover I
don't know exactly what that shit's
called the greenhouse covering thick
covering they cut a three foot tall slit
in the cover is two slit three feet tall
and they took every [ __ ] plant out of
the greenhouse did not leave a footprint
nor a leaf behind and cleaned the entire
greenhouse out these guys are
professionals there are experienced
rippers out there and they're at work
all for the next week or two just taking
crops that are finished alright I hope
you guys get your plants cut down dude
if someone comes to steal your plants
please don't shoot them don't go to jail
don't let your dogs out if you let your
dog out your dog bites somebody you
gotta put your dog down so and that
person may shoot your dog so just keep
the dog in the house like there's
there's really not a great option here
like that's one of the things that sucks
call the cops call the police you've got
I guess so huh or grow indoors we just
get shot for confronting some taggers in
the alley so I'm really kind of anti you
know doing anything right now other than
like bringing official that's what
they're there for just call the cops
yeah don't try to be a vigilante and I
always hated the not doing it because I
had weed and I didn't because I had weed
or smell like weed or just smoked right
yeah
just call 9-1-1 and say hey there's a
car upside down on the interstate why
don't you stop sometimes [ __ ]
all right guys gosh excuse my
throat-clearing I'm gonna give it one
good one I'll be done that was just
exaggerating I think I'm good though
that's the bad news
let's find some yeah not great news
this one we're not gonna talk about the
spot but guess what the spot will be
uses an example in the following this
bottle the spot passed all these tests
with flying colors we do not get any
violations everything is legit at the
spot we are champions so with that being
said the headline for this article is 7
Denver marijuana shops cited for
underage sales the byline is police say
they conducted checks on 30 Denver
retail marijuana shops on Friday I found
this article on the cannabis this erotic
article is written by Jesse Paul of the
Denver Post I actually first heard of
this Oh from our good friend Dave Mon so
shout out to Dave for putting me on the
case to find this one yep Dave's a good
dude nipples are sticking out Dave
police issued 7 citations for underage
retail marijuana sales during an
enforcement operation at 30 shops last
week officials said on Wednesday police
say they conducted checks Friday in an
effort to audit any potential underage
sales and found there to be lower
underage compliance rate to be a lower
underage compliance rate sir I read that
walkie we're disappointed said Lewis
koski director of Colorado's marijuana
Enforcement Division in a statement up
until now these compliance checks have
been a bright spot for the industry this
recent check drops compliance to 92% and
we're at 99 before [ __ ] [ __ ]
making us look bad the news comes as a
blow to recreational marijuana in
Colorado especially since the in the
roughly 21 minutes months since
recreational marijuana has been legal
stores mostly have been lauded for their
compliance owners and operators have
been praised for their handling of the
hot-button topic of underage possession
and consumption so in Colorado what
they're mainly worried about is this
weed being sold to people who are not 21
and also we being sold out the back door
of the dispensary that isn't being
documented if underage sales and product
and leaving a shop headed out of state
uh you know in bulk in bulk yes that are
are the two things that were really
really really seeking to avoid here they
call those the fatal flaws yep those are
the things that will trigger federal
intervention if they get out of hand
yes and I mean just in my world all of
the anti pop people love [ __ ] like this
like it doesn't matter that we only drop
down percentage-wise to inline with
alcohol and tobacco retailers like all
three of those businesses sit at about a
ninety two percent compliance rate like
ninety to ninety two and we're at ninety
two now thanks to this we were at ninety
nine thanks to Aspen [ __ ] [ __ ]
there were two shops in Aspen that were
busted a while ago after they were
busted pretty much every shop in the
state got a letter saying hey make sure
your ID check system is up to snuff
we're doing compliance checks we're not
trying to scam you like they're not
gonna pretend that they're 21 and show a
fake ID or something it'll be an under
21 ID and you'll [ __ ] it up that's how
you get stoned and in the state of
Colorado our IDs are vertical horizontal
yeah if you're over 21 it fits one way
on the card and if you're under 21 it
fits yeah so that should be obvious
because you have to look at the
verticals like I just had a family
member turn 21 and her ID so good for
several months so you've got to read the
date but how it's not hard
happy birthday I know who you are happy
birthday everybody go get a little flip
calendar with the you can't buy [ __ ]
here if he was born before somebody up
front who's trained and experienced in
checking IDs right we have armed
security checking every idea that comes
to the store and we turn away 65 girls
all the time because their ID expired a
week ago this is how strict our shop is
and I know you said we were gonna talk
about the spot but this is an example of
what should be done ah you gotta do it
right right now the fire inspector
showed up and the fire inspector said
hey I'm here to look in the back of the
building and the security guard said and
who are you and he said I'm the fire
inspector
security guard said sir can I see your
ID and he said I don't have an ID I'm
the fire inspector and the security
guard stuck out his head and said I'm
John on the security guard good to meet
you can I see your ID and the guy was
like I'm the fire inspector I don't need
an ID because I don't know who you are
you can't come in here and sent the fire
inspector away because he didn't have
proper identification he was in a fire
truck
but dude didn't have ID so we can't let
him in there that's period
I've yeah period that's the rule you
don't have ID you can't come in will
occur you could be Barack [ __ ] Obama
and I don't think we let you in there
unless you pull out that ID we had cops
come to the shop because the crazy guy
said we stole his wallet one day and the
security guard checked their IDs it was
really funny to watch all of the blood
tenders were standing there like dude
he's really checking their IDs it's the
third one in a row he's getting his
wallet out he's bought his driver's
license and given a dollar security
guard the AUSA's is crazy shout-out to
whichever security guard that was yep
that's a good job it's everyone that
comes in gets ID'd if your IDs expired
you can't come in and on all 21 you
can't come in yep every shop in the
legal industry needs to be able to do
this it's not complicated we make
vendors wait in the entry room if they
don't have them go back to the offices
you have to wait right here in this
chair welcome and then we make them wait
if they have a delivery for us and they
don't have their ID we handle everybody
else first
all right let's get back to this article
we were talking a little bit about the
spot we said we weren't gonna whereas
praising the rules that were followed in
Washington state by comparison which
legalized recreational marijuana at the
same time Colorado did but implemented
recreational sales six months later
several stores have been reprimanded for
selling to minors Kowski said despite a
lack of repeat violations at any one
licensed shop this represents a downward
trend in compliance that is concerning
that is very true
we've been at it for just over almost
two years now holy [ __ ] time flies there
was a lot of information in that last
paragraph there re stinging purposefully
restating businesses that failed to make
sure that they're back in compliance
where they need to be yes another piece
of information you might enjoy dear
listeners is if you're a tobacco or
alcohol retailer the fines usually about
ten thousand for screwing up an ID check
if you're a marijuana retailer
the first two penalties you face or
$100,000 fine and you can lose your
license $100,000 so it's 10 times the
fine if you screw this up as a marijuana
business that could close a shop yeah
that could absolutely close a smaller
dispensary that can shut it down a new
dispensary they could be gone yeah ouch
I know a lot of shops oh that would have
closed down in their first year that
would have closed down that Mike and I
worked we met each other well I don't
know we we became good friends through
that probably that would destroy
tomorrow they would yeah hundred
thousand dollar fine that woulda just
closed that place down and went there I
would have been hungry all right I'm
gonna continue with the article here it
says when reach my phone representatives
at 5:00 of the shop cited either
declined to immediately comment or said
they could not discuss the citations
because of ongoing criminal
investigations
obviously we failed in our mission to
keep people under 21 out of our shop
sent Ryan Fowler owner of the cited
store red eye relief I'm incredibly
disappointed I must say I like the name
red eye relief that sounds like
something I would have said I Drive by
two of these shops regularly when I'm in
Denver I almost stopped at one of them
the last time I was up and never just a
few days ago should have stopped doodle
at you feller said four employees
including a store manager were fired in
the citations wake he added the shop
will stop accepting vertical
identification cards and begin using
electronic verification to ensure there
are no underage customers so even if
you're 21 and you have a vertical card
they're not going to let you win
yep which is nonsense yeah you can fully
let in people that are 21 and you should
they're perfectly legally allowed to
shop in your business um same thing with
the electronic card reader if you're you
can't look at the day and see what it
says the electronic card reader I can
help you that's true it shows your age
actually when you slide that card reader
it shows the actual age yeah but if you
can't read a year can you read a number
at all that's true you guys there are a
few dispensaries if you come to Colorado
and you shop at a dispensary there are a
few that run your card through that
little card reader like they have at the
bar that thing does not save any
information you guys it does not save
any information it scans your ID and it
processes the information on your ID and
then it shows how old you are is all it
does a lot of people are paranoid that
that thing is showing your ID it does
not or that's keeping your information
it does not we're not allowed the
dispensaries are not allowed to track
your information the only thing that we
do keep track of is oftentimes
dispensaries will document what state
you are from and that is mostly for
advertising and just marketing purposes
so we're not keeping your information we
don't want to know where you live we
don't care we're out of room for records
we're sort of busy yeah like we don't
have time to even process that
information let alone compile it a need
or anything to do with it either all
right I'm gonna get back into this
article um where was I there we go we
were very concerned about this matter at
the healing house said in a statement to
the Denver Post we are 100% committed to
compliance in all aspects of the law we
have had no issues in the past and we're
taking this matter very seriously
officials say the citations for selling
marijuana to a person younger than 21
were issued at 7 separate businesses the
charge is a class 1 misdemeanor oh so
they could also face criminal charges
huh the person who made the sale faces
has already been cited was a criminal
criminal charge and they'll be going to
court for it no I know we said we're not
gonna talk about the spot but when you
walk into most dispensaries there's a
security guard up front checking IDs
then he sends you back to the budtender
who sells you bud Huson then he rings
you up
who's responsible therefore that the
security guard or the budtender you
should be checking an ID again worked
we totally asked if we're at all worried
about it we have a lot of faith in our
security guards we don't at all
tolerate the security guard not doing
his job correctly right there most of
those guys are there already goes the
whole company's ex-military everyone and
that company's event so they're used to
doing everything perfect when they have
to it work and so it's simply done
correctly every time we still ask from
time to time we've got a couple of
people that come in the shop that looked
very very young and they're both well
over 21 but they don't look it yeah and
so every time there's a new bud tender
there and even sometimes when you know
there's just a lot of people there and
we want everybody to be confident that
we're not selling under 21 people we'll
just it can I see your ID again real
quick man I'm sorry I just got to be
sure right because my butt on the line
true yeah you're way too pretty for jail
yeah it's like I really like you dude
but you're not worth out okay no or your
job yep this $40.00 sale is not worth
$100,000 fine and my job right yeah the
criminal charge I'm gonna continue with
the article and I just realized that at
the bottom of the article I didn't see
this when I skim through this the first
time all of the shops are listed I like
it so avoid them yeah or if you're not
21 go there dispensaries need to be held
accountable said Tyler Henson president
of the Colorado cannabis Chamber of
Commerce your job as an owner and
operator is to insure your employees are
readily trained that can't happen again
he added Henson said employers and their
employees need to understand at what's
at stake here
officials say the violations can mean a
license suspension a fine per individual
violation a fine in lieu of suspension
up to $100,000 and license reef occasion
and that sounds so serious when you put
it like that I mean think about it dude
what what did the one shop down here do
they got their license pole
my consumption on side consumers wasn't
like they were giving out dabs in the
bedroom no they had roaches in an
employee bathroom and it was enough for
them to lose to snore licenses underage
sales they haven't closed the shop that
I know of yet but I don't think any of
the cases that have screwed this up have
gone through that process completely yet
time will tell it's brand new yep
my guess is a couple of people are gonna
lose their license if you get stung
twice I would bet on it oh yeah twice
they should yeah yeah
so it says sanctions may also include
restrictions on the license police said
in a news release investigators say they
will file the cases with the Denver City
Attorney's Office which could issue its
own discipline raging from license
suspension to license revocation
according to the Colorado Department of
Revenue the marijuana enforcement
division has conducted 172 compliance
checks since January 1st of 2014 and
found 16 total violations so it goes on
to say Denver marijuana shops were cited
where citations were issued and then it
lists them it says the herbal cure on
South Logan Street the healing house on
South downing pure medical dispensary on
40th Avenue Laconte 's clone bar and
dispensary on East 7th that's over by
where they host the cannabis cup herbs
for you on East Nine Mile High Green
Cross those guys have a cannabis cup so
does Lakan tase there are a couple
places on here that have cannabis cups
that are professionals that have a
reputation that are [ __ ] up I don't
know how a [ __ ] some of these shops
messed this up red eye relief on South
Cherokee Street you know we can chalk a
couple of them up to a lazy employee or
somebody up at the front not giving a
[ __ ] and you just hand him an ID and
like they look I've been not old enough
and gotten into clubs just by handing
the bouncer an ID here it was my ID that
said I was not 21 and he's like oh you
got an ID here just hands it back like
you said some people are [ __ ] smart
enough to read an ID to figure out that
nineteen seventy whatever means you're
this how old
sometimes so we can give a couple of
those just to dumb employees some of
it's just brought one of them one or two
is probably just somebody let somebody
slip through just like I don't know what
it is but if you give that you know if
selling to people under 21 is part of
your business model you can go yeah
we're trying to set a positive standard
here and do things correctly we're
literally front and center on the world
stage
when other nations bring up marijuana
legalization as an idea or a concept
that they might want to pursue they
discuss what's happening in Colorado yes
we are the mom every now and then I hear
about someone from France or London I'm
coming through Pueblo and taking a look
at what we're doing here in Pueblo which
this never would happened five years ago
true there's no reason for any of these
people to be here very trial and be
interested in what we're doing what
they're coming here to see how marijuana
legalization works in practice
and if they see teenagers waiting in
line it's not going well it's not gonna
spread and it should that's the truth
all right you guys we've got one more
article that I want to get in we've been
going for close to 40 minutes we get
this one in here I like it the people
seem to like when I've got somebody else
with me they'll listen a little longer
so there's two of us I'll listen that's
good news time folks so let's start this
one off with a big congratulations to
we're gonna enters recreational arrow
with tax-free pot sales October first
documented the beginning of recreational
pot sales in the state of Oregon I've
got a lot of friends out there big shout
out to my Oregon crew the pnw crew hope
you guys are out there enjoying
recreational cannabis sales so I've got
an article once again from the cannabis
this was written by Jonathan JQ / and
Bob Seavey of The Associated Press
it's like a cool pair of names Cooper
and Bob CB yeah alright just when I
think I was gonna ready for another
debut say some really high [ __ ]
everybody celebrate organs recreational
cannabis consider my arm twisted yeah
I'll twist this we've got two rigs on
the table I'll let you hit the email and
I'll go ahead and take the one that
requires a torch you got a DAB over
there myself a medium medium dad hey
guys I want you to take a dab with me
first of all but then I want you to find
me on social media either Facebook or
Twitter or you can even email me you
want if you want but I want to know how
big of a DAB do you take do you take a
point one do you take a point two you
take a point three do you take point
four or do you do a [ __ ] half gram
dab tell me what you think I want to
know about it it's a girl from your
heart a hotmail.com you can find me on
Facebook it's girl from your heart or if
you want to search me out on tweeter
find me on the little tweeter it's at G
fyh podcast let me know how big of a DAB
you prefer to take so you're looking for
regular dab sighs not this one time my
friend dared me to take I wanna know
yeah yeah if you're about to just pull
off the dab for yourself if it's your
normal day if your dad but I want to
know what you pull off but your average
and then tell me how many of those you
take in a dab session also because if
you take a half gram and you only take
one of them then that's cool if you take
five point ones that's cool so I just
want to know how you do it
I'm just curious I myself like to take a
whole bunch of 0.3 like 0.3 is about
where I like to be and I like to take a
bunch of like about 6 or 7 of them
sometimes on a lunch break I'll take 3.3
ziz what I like for a lunch break I'm
gonna take a cab right now right now I'm
hitting the hit man let's do this
really well you don't remember how bad I
cost no cost
little cough so recently I picked up a
mother ship knockoff it really looks
just like a mother ship Klein but it was
thinner I think if the glass may be a
little thinner not that not so much the
go yeah maybe a little bit the glass way
too but the overall size of the rig the
cylinder going up this is thinner in
diameter okay maybe a little bit
shrunken of a ship but it was a fifth of
the price of a mother ship it's a great
rate so shut up to elevate in Colorado
Springs I know I've said that once or
twice this show but I've been buying a
lot of glass from them and I appreciate
the hookups this little hit man hits
like a goddamn truck I'm trying to act
like I'm not trying to choke and trying
to act like I've got my breath together
everything but guess what there's almost
no resistance is straight from nails
along oh that you just get a sometimes
you guys want to take a big dab it
sounds like Charlie Brown's the adults
in the sounds like after a big dab
sometimes it takes me a minute to dig
through that hole but I feel like I'm
back we're celebrating Oregon having
recreational sales of cannabis right
welcome to the club you're the closer
see the cool kids hostess this is from
Portland Oregon and it says excited
shoppers looking to score some of the
first recreational marijuana sold
legally in Oregon bought up baggies of
Bud early Thursday taking advantage of
doorbuster prices and other deals
goddamn that's such a poetic opening
line for a news article whoever wrote
this is majestic some of the more than
250 dispensaries that already offer
medical marijuana in the state welcome
to recreational users soon after
midnight just moments after it became
legal to sell to anyone who is at least
21 right Shango premium cannabis in
Portland a co-founder Shane McKee said
the first sale came about a minute after
midnight and many others quickly
followed I think it's not only
historical for folks in Oregon but
nationwide anytime people start selling
that as an alternative to alcohol or
tobacco he said in a telephone
Brad Suzman co-owner of Kanna daddy's in
Portland said more than 90 customers
bought pot in the first two hours at the
store opened at 7:00 a.m. so people were
out there at midnight buying weed out
there at 7:00 a.m. by and weed that's
pretty neat it's like when a new video
game goes on sale something like that
lines out the door people just buying
weed I'm torn with this story I first
I'm elated that another state is joining
the legalization ranks I'm glad they
they're celebrating I'm glad people came
out and that the lines were good a lot
of medical shops are converting so
supply might not be the problem it's
been another legal states which is
awesome but at the same time it's time
to knock off the shenanigans and step
all the way up into the legal industry
you got to put your best foot forward or
you're gonna [ __ ] it up for everyone and
there were a couple of things about the
rollout in Oregon that could [ __ ] it up
for most of Oregon half of the state has
banned shops period the other half of
the state allows a shitload and if you
look at a map it's like right down the
[ __ ] mountain range in the middle of
the state
the coast side approves in their shops
everywhere the other side of the
mountain range
not a single shop of course and stuff
like opening at midnight when there are
hours that you're allowed to open and
not allowed to be open and they don't
involve 12:01 in the morning
there's the Maine reporter covering
marijuana up there that I follow on
Twitter one of her colleagues was handed
marijuana gummies
outside of the shop waiting in line
doing news reports he was just handed
free pot candy pot edibles specifically
candy or [ __ ] band
so we're giveaways and it's not like
this stuff is its resources on day one
it's I mean it's a celebration
shenanigans happened there was a truck
driving up and down the street not at
all affiliated with the dispensary we
were waiting in line at on
the guy buying threw out bags of edibles
he drove buying gave out plants yeah I'm
90% sure it was somebody advertising for
another shop that was not at all getting
business right but it might have just
been one of us who had blown a stack
with joy it could have gone either way I
didn't get up close and investigate cuz
I didn't want to lose my awesome spot in
line right cuz by then I was halfway
through a two-hour line but there's you
Nana gets to be expected but it's day
four seven now or whatever whenever this
is gonna air we've had a week now
every ID gets checked every rule gets
followed if you've got a problem with
the rule get a lobbyist and get a lawyer
change the rules this day level so that
they work better for everybody
[ __ ] skirt it right different kind of
lawyers but yeah it's it's really
important now that if you're in the
legal industry that you step all the way
up we have to put our best foot forward
right now every state you guys every
state in every upcoming state this
applies to if the medical shops in
California had it all tried to put their
best foot forward ever
from 1996 till now it would have [ __ ]
legal a decade ago [ __ ] but I mean
just like in Colorado we had to deal
with dr. reefer the boulder city council
right now is talking about dialing
regulations back down to reality because
we've gotten rid of and I [ __ ] quote
the doctor refers to this world like
they're done now they're all out of
business talking about how they used to
own a dispensary you don't even know
that one of my buddies owned a shop
called doctor reefer in Colorado Springs
do you used to sell us a Hindu Kush
vaguely doctor reefer um there was a the
doctor reefer in question is the one up
in Boulder he had a twirling sign guy
and that's what he wanted bold it was
fired up about this is wildly
inappropriate twirling sign yeah we
can't have a twirling sign guys they're
specifically bad because of this buck
you can you can twirling sign for your
tax return place you can totally sign
for cheeseburgers
you can't whirling sign for El Pollo
Loco but not for cannabis
you can't your vape shop yep yep yep
all right we're way off topic here I'm
gonna give this article has more words
written in it and they say he says
customers told them they've been writing
waiting all their lives for a moment
like this expected to sell $60,000 worth
of marijuana throughout the day there
were no reports of arrests or other
problems involving the early sales in
the state most stores planned to open
later in the day Oregon is one of four
states that have legalized the sale of
recreational marijuana business began in
Oregon with far more dispensaries than
did Colorado or Washington State where
pot shops have been up and running for
more than a year Alaska could begin
retail sales next year big shoutout to
Charlo Greene foster buds PD exes you
might be going to jail you've been
following that story no she has not or I
have not her if it keeps getting raided
because as you said shops not till
whatever they're trying to enclose some
kind yeah Charlie take care yourself
beautiful don't end up in jail I need
you out there fighting the good fight
for us more omi foster buds in PD a
foster buds PDX in Portland had a couple
hundred customers since opening just
after midnight shop manager Ken Martin
said it's just been a steady flow he
said adding that employees repeatedly
refill jars with pot to meet the demand
two customers came in used to that
[Music]
number which Jarrett went in to keep
going I've watched it a billion times to
customers who came in had just turned 21
he said debut Fleming I don't know if I
read your name right Divya Divya Divya
Fleming of Portland the first buyer in
the keys store said the atmosphere was
upbeat for the launch of the new
industry it's the end of prohibition
said Fleming who uses the drug for many
medicinal purposes because if I ever
mentioned that I was the first person to
buy recreational cannabis at the greener
side dispensary in Pueblo Colorado I was
first [ __ ] anyway I'm pretty sure I
talked about that it was like way a long
time ago the store offered its first 25
customers 35 to 40% discounts and was
handing out soda coffee juice and other
refreshments McKee said many stores in
Oregon were trying to lure customers
with extended hours food giveaways and
discounted Maryland
Oana shoppers who have shoppe errs have
one more incentive to buy early and
often under Oregon law Papa purchases
will be tax-free until January the
savings of up to 20% that's a good way
to do it get people to come in and see
how it goes and then start charging tax
that's pretty nice
the one thing I really like about
Oregon's law is they're really looking
to kick the black market in the balls
nice
so no taxes for the first little bit so
you know it's the old street theory that
they threw at us in middle school in
there yep you get a taste the cheap you
want a free joint
welcome to the selection welcome to the
quality control welcome to the quality
increases welcome to the guy being here
on time we'll hit you in the nuts with
the taxes manana no more watching how
it's made for two hours doesn't look
like foot traffic none of that just walk
in have your mind blown with awesome
weed product and balance right all right
the article goes on to say store owners
say they're hopeful they can avoid the
shortages and price spikes that followed
the start of legal sales last year in
Washington and Colorado Alaska could
begin retail sales next year I think I
already read that huh once we're offered
a goodie bag with t-shirts but no free
marijuana
sounds like the spot another we'll have
a live band and 10% discounts several
stores have erected billboards in
Portland a shop in Maryland is
advertising on the radio I'm just trying
to basically stock up for maybe four or
five times with the normal volume would
be said Chris Byers owner of River City
dispensary in Merlin customers can buy
as much as 7 grams at a time of dried
marijuana flower and leaf the part
that's generally smoked plus plants and
seeds dried flower and leaf hopefully
there's not a lot of leaf in there yeah
basically buds is what they mean yeah
some of the people that write wheat
articles need to hang out with some weed
heads for the next year or so
pop infused candy cookies oils and
lotions will be available only to people
with medical marijuana cards as the
state works on retail regulations for
those products oregon has a robust
supply supply system that has supported
medical marijuana users and the black
market companies have invested in
massive warehouses in portland to grow
the drug indoors and southern oregon has
some of the nation's best conditions for
out
or cultivation Brewers don't face strict
regulations yet so the supply can more
easily flow into retail stores than it
did in Washington and Colorado still
there is concern summer has historically
been a time of marijuana shortages in
Oregon and most of the outdoor crop that
is ready to heart and most of the other
crop is not ready to harvest sorry I
skipped word there
indoor growers have had minimal time to
wrap up production because lawmakers
only approved the October first start
date three months ago and they had time
to get one quick crop in said Jeremy
Pratt
he said we kind of have a seasonal
drawing market here in Oregon said the
owner of nectar cannabis which has four
stores in Portland we have lots of
products in the fall and then it kind of
gets tight this time of year anyway
green oasis which has two locations in
Portland and more on the way has
prepared by trying to cultivate strong
relationships with growers it will
entice customers Thursday evening with
an outdoor bed and offer ten percent
discounts to those who spend at least
$40 Kohinoor Matthew Schwimmer said we
don't know if anyone else doing a band
and we thought it was a good idea to
give back to the community Schwimmer
said so that's the article you guys big
congratulations to the state of Oregon
they have now got recreational cannabis
sales it is tax free until January so if
you're doing the circuit make sure you
go stop in Oregon make sure you get
yourself a shout out to donuts you know
some recreational cannabis in the state
of Oregon you guys yeah make sure you're
21 and make sure they check your ID and
if they don't check your ID call them
out on it tell me that they're not
following the rules there's a [ __ ] it up
for the future if if you listen to the
show and you haven't had a chance to
legally purchase cannabis start saving
for plane ticket if you're 21 if you're
21 if you're 20
it'll just change the world when I think
of what I used to deal with to buy weed
like did what was just standard when I
was in high school and in college and
then in my 20s it was just a nightmare
especially in retrospect like it was
just life when it was happening it
wasn't that bad like I didn't mind
watching how it's made that much but now
that it's totally legal and I work in a
pot shop and it's just like picking up a
cheeseburger on the way home it's so
much better yeah if I was afraid of it
at first big it's so much better I can't
adequately put it into words well I came
from the black market and I was afraid
of all of this and it's I don't know
freaky to a lot of people it's a huge
change if you live in a non legal state
you worry about what do you I don't know
how much weed you buy but when half of
it is gone you start thinking about [ __ ]
where am I gonna get more wheat cuz
there's no reliable spot I never have to
think or am I gonna get my next bag of
weed because if I don't if I don't grow
it I can go to the shop in which I work
or I can drive to one of my other buddy
shops or I can drive to one of my other
friend shops or I'm also a medical
marijuana patient so I could drive to a
medical dispensary excuse me I'm trying
to burp I could drive to a medical
marijuana to shop and get whatever
cannabis I need in there so it is a
little bit better that way I made her
more available way more available it
made weed more advanced the innovations
that have come with this legalization
have been incredible so I like it I
think it's way better
I fear this much better legalization
it's beautiful we can do so many things
like it's not so like I never had
trouble finding pot before in my life it
never came up
I might have trouble locating good pot
or the same pot and it was always
horseshit whatever you bought like it
was never what they said it was just
you'd ask do you have any of this and
they go oh yeah and they'd go get a
handful of something different if you
like this is the name you said you know
um and you just believed it that was the
best you had hopefully you weren't
getting cheated and that was just life
now with there's ten stores within a 15
minute drive from both our homes
yeah and that's pretty much true across
Colorado with this yeah and you can go
to two or three of them and see what you
do and don't like if every shops got
different pricing every shops got a
different selection there are major
companies across Colorado where you can
kind of find their stuff everywhere um
sort of like Coke and Pepsi like you
don't have to go cheap with you store
yet she would choose Cuba choose
Incredibles there in almost every shop
at appear like there's a handful of
major edible companies that are
everywhere now I feel bad for the
delivery people that's a lot of
paperwork
um Dixie like there's a bunch of them
and it's just beautiful you walk in and
there's 3040 I mean sometimes only five
or six but there's a selection of buds
you get a look at them smell them you
get to know the price like it's not
weird that you drove for someone's house
and spent 20 minutes in the living room
and you don't want to buy this you can
just thanks and leave yeah if you know
why if you go to the dispensary you know
like what's in there you can leave you
don't have to buy anything there yeah
people ask me what the minimum purchase
is and it's like nothing if you don't
want any of this please you don't have
to buy like I'll show you around
everything and you can leave knowing
what's going on but and then go look at
a few other places nothing like half the
time when you do that I give you a
coupon book with everybody in the town
listed there you go like just something
to do for the day so guys don't feel
obligated to buy something if you're in
a dispensary and you don't like what you
see don't ever bet your money you work
for that you're not wasting their time
that's a store you can go in there and
do what you need to do if you're a
marijuana fan you're gonna like what you
see it almost any shop you go to
especially if it's the first shop you go
to I went I was in Colorado Springs
hiking one day and I had a friend with
me I had hash with me I just travel with
dads I don't really take flowers with me
we called you guys in art colorado
connoisseurs we called the buds
we're just call it flowers I didn't have
any flowers with me and somebody wanted
to smoke some weed and so we're driving
and I was like a look at dispensary and
we pull up dude I would not smoke
anything in that [ __ ] place there's
no difference on any of these strains
like it was yeah I just left I didn't
eat anything out of there
I've left mineus mini shop illest
some of them aren't up to par some of
them only still exist because enough of
the population legitimately had to stop
smoking weed 30 years ago because it was
too risky for him and only now that
they're retiring and that their kids are
grown are they getting out and trying to
buy weed again I mean for 30 years they
didn't know who to call yeah and we're
too worried about asking their friends
and neighbors about losing their jobs or
custody their kids or whatever you know
they just didn't but now they can just
pull up to a ship walkie and ask for an
eighth I talk to everyday have super
silver hair and huge smiles it's fun
I've been working outside of the shop
lately at my job that I've been doing it
just required some cleaning of some [ __ ]
that's taken about a week and I've been
out in the back with the door open and I
see a lot of people walk by because
there's a parking area over there and
they walk by me most of the people that
I see are older folks it's not a lot of
young punks buying weed it's older folks
that used to smoke back in the day like
you're saying they'd have kids that are
in college now like you see him come in
you see a 20-something college kid come
in with his mom or his dad and they go
buy weed together and I think it's
really funny to see that [ __ ] most of
the 21 22 year old people I see you're
on family vacation that's awesome yeah
it's a lot of fun we get a lot of
younger people too but definitely the
tourist economy is is retirees if you
think about it make sense if you're 22
there's no reason to fly to Colorado to
buy weed
except for the enjoyment of buying legal
cannabis and getting to see what the
selection and the hypes all about
because you know 30 people this we're
happy to sell you a bag of weed or at
least one or two yeah there's no reason
to come here and spend the money on the
flight for what you can do at home
already but if you're 65 there's still a
lot of risk you know
oh [ __ ] yeah there's none here and it
just blows people away I heard that at
least twice three times a week know
where I'm from this is this is really
frowned upon we would get in so much
trouble for this everyone would think
bad about us if they knew that we were
here doing this like please don't tell
my friends and family and it's like lady
you're from Georgia you guys if you come
here to get some weed don't try to take
it home smoke it all here smoke it all
here if you can't finish it call me you
can drop it off at my spot there are a
lot of locals that are happy to help you
finish the bag you over purchase it is
it is legal to give your weed away to
somebody who is over 21 if you've got
cannabis and you bought it in Colorado
and you're about to get on the flight
you're about to fly home or you're about
to drive back across the border stop at
the last gas station in Colorado before
you hit the border or [ __ ] while
you're at the airport you see some dude
with some dreadlocks someone who's at
work that's a good idea don't get well
unless it's me cuz I can take I can't
actually if they have dreadlocks that
last statement doesn't apply just
rephrase that okay so the guy that works
at McDonald's really wants your
unfinished bag of weed he could really
use that kind of charity and sort of pat
on the back but if you give it to him at
the drive-thru window he's gonna get
fired you were trying to do something
nice so have him meet you outside real
quick we've done for a long time let's
wrap up this show hey Mike thanks for
coming over dude you look like you're
beat by now you do thank you for
listening to the show I think each and
every one of you for tuning into the
girl free heart podcast episode number
100 is on its way I'm not sure what
we're gonna do yet I think we're just
gonna party I'm gonna try to get a bunch
of people on the show I might take a
bunch of big fat ridiculous dads I go
around table a bunch of coffin yeah
that's pretty much it a square table
with a bunch of coughing
I like it I like it all right you guys I
would appreciate it if you'd support us
on all the social media stuff the book
Twitter email you know all that good
stuff on Facebook it's just brought from
your heart on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast on Instagram you guys I use I
read genetics that's my seed company
I read genetics check it out on
Instagram I ordered about eighteen point
three thousand followers right now so
please jump in there I'd love to have
you as one of my followers have been
posting a lot of cool stuff and posting
pictures of a commercial grow that is
pretty damn impressive pictures are just
gonna get better and better as time goes
I'm just taking my iPhone using the
iPhone I've been taking the good camera
to work it and taking any pictures so
when I do that people will check they
pants alright um let's see I'll be back
on Monday with another episode gosh I
just realize how close number 100 is 99
and then after that is number 100 we're
gonna have to have a party yep yep Mike
you sound like you're beat bro let's
wrap this [ __ ] up donation button on the
podcast page check it out go to I read
genetics Colorado com click on the girl
from a heart podcast on the top right
there's a PayPal tab you can click on
that and if you feel like that this
podcast was worth a couple of dollars or
a contribution of some sort you can
throw in 50 cents you can throw in 50
thousand bucks or anywhere in between
they will all be appreciated I will give
you a shout out on the show but I'm
never gonna charge you guys for this
podcast but if you feel like making a
contribution I would love it the podcast
is always going to be free free free
free free free you guys the show is
available on iTunes and stitcher every
single episode will always and forever
be archived on I region etics colorado
dot-com I think that's it you guys
thanks to Mike for taking time away from
his kid big shout outs a little Davey um
big shout out to Mama and also big shot
with my ninja spins thanks again for
listening you guys until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
all right podcast rolled I want to thank
you guys again for listening to a long
block of old episodes I would love it if
you would email me and let me know what
you think about these old episodes the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to stalk me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on Facebook
simply search for the grow from your
heart podcast I hope everybody out there
has a great weekend I'll be back Monday
with a fresh new episode and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me