[Music]
Divac welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 241 of the
girl from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band cut leaves
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat to the entire mystic
group
Oh ladies and gentlemen I'm starting off
the podcast with the throat thing
already I apologize I'm gonna blame it
on all of the flour I've been smoking
that's right if you know me and if you
listen to the podcast a lot you know
that I don't smoke a lot of flowers we
call weed the buds that's known as
flowers in the cannabis industry if
you're in Colorado or a legal state
that's the flower
I don't smoke a lot of flower I like to
smoke a lot of concentrates I like to
take a lot of dabs but last weekend I
went to see fish and it's hard to sneak
a dab rag into a concert but you can
sneak a whole bunch in joints and a
whole bunch of weed into a concert so
I've been smoking a lot of flowers it's
been a little bit more convenient than
taking a DAB all the time but you can
hear what it's doing to my throat I do
apologize for that big shot up to this
lemon og haze I was bred by the ethos
collective ethos seeds mr. Kollin and
then I grew it at Three Rivers and then
I bought it as a just a patient over the
counter and I smoked a whole bunch of it
this weekend it was freakin delicious
also smoked a bunch of the true cush
what else did I have I had some bordello
and some blueberry headband they were
all quite delicious the bordello was a
little more mellow than what I would
have preferred but the flavor was on
point so once again I apologize for all
the throat clearing that you will hear
during this episode hopefully it fades
away once I start talking a lot I'll get
my voice going it will fade away I've
also got some water here I've also got
some frosty cold dr. pepper I'll keep
myself caffeinated and hydrated and I
will deliver the best show I could bring
you all right I've already been talking
about sea and fish last weekend holy
crap you guys if you know anything about
me you know that fish is my favorite
band on the planet it was up for debate
for a minute there it might have been
fish with a Grateful Dead for a moment
it may have been a band called mo but
you know what fish is my favorite band
one thing I've noticed you guys is I
don't I don't know any of the new [ __ ] I
don't know half of the songs that fish
plays anymore I miss the old stuff I
like the stuff when they wrote long
elaborate songs with a lot of great
changes now it's kind of straightforward
for for rock and roll stuff which I'm
not mad about
they had who don't want to work to write
all those other long songs but a lot of
the new stuff isn't for me I still had a
great time
fish did fish with the pH I did three
nights at Dick's Sporting Goods
it's the Dick's Sporting Goods field or
something like that no no it's a giant
soccer field in Denver
it holds a lot of dim people this place
was huge and they did three nights in a
row they did Friday Saturday and Sunday
man the concerts were great I went with
the always lovely always beautiful Jenny
Beth we drove up to Denver we got a
hotel we went saw fish the first night
my favorite song of the first night I'm
not gonna read you the entire set list
one of my favorite fish songs of all
time has always been tube I've seen them
play tube a couple of times live I got a
really cool version of tube the first
night of the Phish concert that's always
awesome of course if you know me you
know that I love Harry hood it's a
reggae style Phish song they played
Harry hood and then they played Harry
hood into cavern cavern the old stuff is
my favorite so of course I'm mentioning
the old songs cavern is off of one of
their first couple albums if they put
out off of a picture of nectar it's the
one with the quote whatever you do take
care of your shoes that was a great show
super happy with that Bayon chord with
the horse and to silent in the morning
into character zero
I heard them play a little note they do
those little teaser notes when a
musician picks up his guitar he's gonna
play a song you'd put your pedals to
your effects pedals are on the right
thing and then do a little noodling to
make sure it sounds right and then you
play the song I can tell by their pre
noodling what song it was gonna be when
it was the horse into silent in the
morning that's always fun calm that calm
the songs before they play them the
Encore was the horse silent in the
morning into character zero that was the
first night that was pretty awesome the
second night now I'm gonna go quickly
here with my favorites out of the
setlist the people that are fish fans
they listen to the show will appreciate
it the rest of you will just get to hear
some of my favorite songs on the second
night they started the show it's simple
I always thought that was cool
then they went into a song that I I'm
gonna admit it I don't know if I've ever
[ __ ] heard it before it was called
Martian monster don't know if I ever
heard that that might have been my first
time ever hearing that song like I said
I don't know any of the new fish stuff
anything after round room I am pretty
lost and before I don't even know a lot
of round room that's where they kind of
lost me I like I love that old [ __ ] I go
to see the jams and the old [ __ ] and I
go to see the build-up and then when
tray hits that [ __ ] pinnacle Note one
if you're a fish fan you know what I
mean he just goes to this place that's
what I go for I want to see that so the
second night they open was simple and a
Martian monster then then they did it to
me ladies you know when they played
[ __ ] Reba the crowd went wild Reba is
a super popular Phish song they did it
with the whistle if you're wondering it
was
then they did Sand limb by limb in that
set VIN chalk dust okay here's where it
got fun everything's right Flay go steam
chalk dust torture Mike song winter
queen what's the use week of pug groove
all is one giant Segway those all into
each other
finished up with slave to the traffic
light on court was the lizards and run
like an antelope I almost read you the
whole set list but damn that second set
was a [ __ ] heater you guys that was
fun
lots of jammin went on there the second
night of the show actually sat with mr.
Sean as a Reedy and his lovely uh I'm
not sure their official title but his
partner in crime is companion for the
night Miss Caroline thanks for hanging
out with us that was a good time and of
course I had the lovely and beautiful
miss Jenny Bethel on my arm we got some
pretty cool seats I don't buy the field
seats I don't get down on the field
right in the front just gets a little
too crowded it's a little too much a lot
of people are all [ __ ] up on drugs and
they're not super polite and it's not
that they're rude they're just [ __ ]
high out of their minds and they're not
paying attention that they're in your
space and spilling their drink on you
and stepping on your toes and I got a
pretty girl with me and I don't need to
deal with all that [ __ ] so we we chose
to sit in the stands and Sean happened
to be about two rows back from the
stands and he him and Caroline saved us
some seats so we got to eat some vegan
nachos in the parking lot and then we
headed into the fish show for the second
night that was great the first night we
just kind of floated around in the back
in the back of dicks there's an area or
you can just kind of stand there and
dance and there's not a lot of people
around it's not real crowded I enjoyed
that so I could get down and just shake
my dreads and swing my arms around and
be a silly hippie for a little while
when you're 65 and your arms are super
long you just feel like always bumping
into people at a concert so it's kind of
nice just to be in the back of the
second night we were kind of in the
crowd and then three quarters of the way
through the people to the right of me
decided they'd had enough they were a
little older than myself and they just
dipped out they took off so I had a lot
of space to the right side of me and I
stepped over and gave some other people
some room but that was pretty cool so
we'll keep going to the third night they
opened with a song not sure I'd ever
heard Buffalo Bill I'm sure I've heard
it somewhere
didn't sound really familiar but I knew
the words that was weird the moment
dance birds of a feather a couple things
that I'm not familiar with back on the
train which is always cool the wedge was
[ __ ] nice 46 days was not my thing it
sounded good not my favorite song
bathtub gin was [ __ ]
awesome then set to down with disease
then a couple other things meat stick
dude the meat stick Piper into meat
stick was pretty awesome
2001 opossum Suzie Greenberg Jenny
wanted to hear Suzy Greenberg all
weekend she's like I want to hear Suzy
Greenberg I wanna hear Suzy Greenberg
[ __ ] three songs up from the whole
concert she heard Suzy Greenberg so they
wrap up the second set with Suzy
Greenberg come out do an encore of waste
into first tube so that was Owen I kept
mentioning to Jenny I said they did not
finish down with disease because it was
more of down with disease that they
didn't finish there's a whole nother
verse and here I'm looking at the notes
to the setlist and it says on finished
so I didn't mention that the third night
Jenny and I were kind of debating on
where to sit because it's a huge venue
and she kind of wanted to have a seat
because she got pretty burnt out tired
over the weekend and it's it's just
convenient to have a seat and I was like
it was crowded and I didn't really want
to invade anybody space cuz it was a
little later when we got in Sunday night
and most of the good seats were taken
and I was okay with just dancing like a
hippie in the aisles and shoes what I do
and especially at dicks they got that
big hole ring area around there that you
could just chill in so I was like how
about we just go smoke a couple of
joints off to the sides there's some
seats down by the stage that you can't
really see the stage but you can hear
the music it sounded [ __ ] great we
smoked a joint during the opener during
down with disease and then we went up to
the top and just walked around and
started at the top and worked our way
almost all the way around the bowl and
then just worked our way back we went to
one end and smoked the joint went to the
other end and smoked a joint and we just
walked around the whole third or the
whole third night and just went and
grabbed seats during the break or when
we wanted to go sneak away and smoke a
joint or something so we just walked
around mostly and that was kind of cool
because we got to see a lot of different
weirdos the fish shows are filled with
weirdos and we also got to see the
concert from a lot of different angles
and then I got to walk around and enjoy
it the way I wanted to and then Jenny
also got to have a seat and rest her her
bones her knee was getting a little sore
which is understandable but anyway that
was our seating arrangement on the third
night let's talk about some of my
favorites man some of my favorite songs
over the weekend of course tube was
awesome rebo was [ __ ] amazing a limb
by limb was really cool contact is
always one of my favorites for some
reason the whoreson to silent in the
morning is not particularly one of my
favorite fish songs
hearing it live the way that they did it
was [ __ ] great they did a really good
job so good job fish had a great [ __ ]
weekend good job Jenny Beth thanks for
being a great fish date a weekend date
the fun little getaway with you had a
great time
let's see also I want to mention
something when I tat the Phish concert I
was in line getting some lemonade it was
probably the third night I able to
assume I don't completely remember yeah
I think it was a third night cuz we're
way off to the left over there getting a
lemonade had to be the third night
because that's where we kept smoking
joints was in that one seat over there
um yeah they didn't had so much so many
joints on me and they didn't even search
me to find one of them had joints in
every pocket was [ __ ] awesome as
rolling joints and filling them with wax
and filling them with butter with
batters with hashes was [ __ ] awesome
but anyway the third night I was in line
for a lemonade the non-alcoholic
lemonade they cost six dollars and fifty
cents it's basically a cup of ice water
they drop a [ __ ] lemon in it charge
you 650 whatever it was delicious it was
refreshing but I met a lovely young lady
who at first I wrote down Ashley and
then I second-guess myself in her set
and said her name is Amber I'm gonna go
with my first intuition and say that I
met a lady named Ashley but I don't want
to be wrong so that feels [ __ ] rude
so I apologize I'm pretty sure was
Ashley or amber it was a Phish concert
by the way and I did just get done
smoking age I can't take joint that's
why I was getting lemonade so I
apologize if I got your name wrong but
she recognized me she didn't recognize
me she's never seen me before she I was
wearing an IRA genetics t-shirt and I'm
a tall white guy with dreadlocks and
I've talked about it on the podcast
before and I've talked about being it
fish and she just turned around and she
said hey I don't mean to be weird but
are you Rasta Jeff from the podcast I
was like it's totally me and she
introduced herself and obviously as too
[ __ ] high to pay proper attention and
did my best I've got some ATD but she's
from she's from the East Coast and she's
trying to grow on the East Coast and she
had some questions about how to mimic
barometric pressure because she's
struggling with pressure and moisture
issues because everything is so
different from growing out there to here
and her teacher has left her she is not
with her teacher anymore her teacher has
moved to Colorado so she's
juggling to figure out some stuff so if
anybody's got any tips on how to mimic
barometric pressure I would love to hear
about that because I have no idea how to
do that but I had a great conversation
with her we hung out in line for a few
minutes until it was her turn to order
her drink and then my turn to order my
drink and of course miss Jenny Beth came
from the came back from using the
restroom so I got to introduce her also
it was funny cuz we were standing in
line trying to talk and for some reason
people decided that the space between
her and I between Ashley / amber / my
new friend they decided that the space
between us was the new walkway and we
were trying to talk politely and have a
conversation if people just kept [ __ ]
passing through like we didn't exist it
was really funny
I found it entertaining but she had some
great questions and it was really great
meeting somebody at a Phish concert
there were thousands of people there I
don't know how many I'm gonna say 10,000
people there and this young lady
recognized me and was polite enough to
say hi and I think that that's really
cool so that made my day it was really
fun getting a compliment and meeting a
podcast listener randomly I do I
apologize if I flubbed your name I hope
you understand it was a Phish concert
you know it would be really cool as if
you sent me an email or contact me on
social media and let me know if I got
your name right or wrong or anywhere
near what it actually is I'm gonna go
with Ashley cuz that's what I thought my
brain said at first then I was like no
you're wrong and then I second-guess
myself and said hammer but I'm going
with Ashley that's what I want to go
with maybe I don't know all right amber
Ashley let me know how closer how wrong
I want to hear about it I also want to
know about the gift I gave you I gave
you a gift
how's it going how's it doing does it
happened yet I'm curious let me know
alright so after the Phish concert Phish
concert was great after the Phish
concert Sunday the lovely Jenny Beth and
I headed back to the hotel and slept
like [ __ ] babies we were worn out
from a long fish weekend we had a ton of
fun we were exhausted from running
around on the Sun and dancing all night
we woke up we got cleaned up packed up
from the hotel and we headed to a
restaurant known as Sam's number three
delicious little [ __ ] eat spot right
there that was tasty it's marvelous I'd
recommend that we wouldn't hung out at
the guitar Center in Denver for a few
minutes there too the one on Colorado
just went and beat around on some
electronic drums for a few minutes
there's had some time to kill and we
were right near that area so just went
knocked around on some drums and then we
headed over to comedy
works where I got dad the Fuuka I got
super blaze and miss Jenny got super
blazed as well and we went to comedy
works and we saw mr. Doug Benson
that's right Doug Benson was doing
stand-up comedy most of the time when I
go see Doug he's doing his own podcast
which is called Doug loves movies which
is hilarious where he's usually got a
few guests and they play some games on
stage and people went prizes and things
and it's kind of interactive it's a good
time this show however was just stand up
Doug came out it was kind of a weird
setup honestly they introduced Doug and
he came out and did a little talking and
then uh he went he said so I'm the host
so now I want to bring out my opening
act
Jacob seroff and Jacob sear off I hope
I'm saying that right sear off sir off
sear off Jacob sear off came out and did
like thirty five forty five solid
minutes a [ __ ] crushing material you
guys if you want to be slightly offended
no matter who you are no matter what
race you are what sexual orientation
what religion Jacobs are off has got
something to offend you and I like that
kind of humor honestly so check him out
Jacobs serif si rof I check him out he
was hilarious he's a little Jewish guy
he's kind of got um man I don't want to
contaminate your thought process when
you see him or listen to him but it's if
if Ari Shaffir and Marc Maron made a
baby it would be Jacob Seraph that's
kinda that's kind of what I thought when
I met him ah
so I went saw Doug Benson on the way to
see Doug Benson I decided to listen to
the Doug loves minis podcast a few
minutes into the podcast he's like
Denver I'm coming to see Denver oh no no
he actually read my iTunes review and
Doug Benson said take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me at the end of
my iTunes review because I was smart
enough to type that in there and he
reads the iTunes reviews on his show but
then after he read my iTunes review he's
like Rasta Jeff I'm going to Denver and
I look forward to seeing Ross and Jeff
he comes to all the shows so that'll be
fun to see him there he totally gave me
like a longshot on his podcast that was
super cool
then we're at Comedy Works at the show
and Doug Benson reads tweets if you
tweet him before the show he will read
your tweet possibly during the opening
part of the show so he read my tweet and
of course I said
Doug Benson I'm getting I don't remember
the words I used I don't have my Twitter
open right now but I said I'm getting
lit up on dabs and dr. pepper before the
show and he read he asked me he goes
Ross to Jeff's here where's Ross to Jeff
and I was like whoohoo I'm right here
he's like what's up dude how many shows
have you been to and I couldn't think of
how many Doug Benson shows I've actually
been to I said about 10 but honestly I
said more than 10 honestly I think I've
been to closer to 20 Doug Benson
performances all of which were at Comedy
Works so he read my tweet he asked me
some questions he told me thanks for
coming he said it was our 10th
anniversary which means the gift is
paper and then he said I'm sure Rasta
jeff has something wrapped in paper and
then he laughed and he said I look
forward to seeing you outside dude
because he meant in the alley where we
smoke and then he goes I'm gonna give
you a [ __ ] he can't believe so Doug
Benson told me he was gonna give me a
[ __ ] and they need to started
laughing and then he said no I'll see
you out in the alley after you show and
then he said me and all my friends are
gonna jump you and wash your hair which
was slightly offensive but completely
funny and then of course miss Jenny Beth
tweeted at Doug Benson also so right
after that he said where's miss and I'm
not gonna say her twitter handle cuz I
don't know if she wants it advertised
like that I'm gonna be respectful sorry
but if you wanted me to say it I'll say
it on another show but she did not I
don't know if she wants or shouldn't
give me permission or anything please
Doug Benson's like so where's this
person and she's like I'm right here she
was pretty embarrassed and then he read
her tweet which was something about
seeing Doug Benson after a great weekend
thanks babe and she was saying thanks
made to me cuz she tagged me in the post
but Doug Benson was like so is that for
me babe and I thought it was pretty
funny so we both got our tweets read by
Doug Benson
during his recording Doug Benson
revealed that the show at Comedy Works
was being recorded for his next comedy
album that he will release on iTunes so
there is a good chance that myself and
the always lovely always beautiful
always charming miss Jenny Beth will be
on Doug Benson's new recording because
his new thing that he's doing he just
records the entire show and then puts it
out like a bootleg style like how fish
used to do and the name of the show will
be the date which was I believe
September 4th it'll be 9 / 4 / 17 Denver
Colorado will be the name of the album
so
I hope he puts it out because I mean I
got a lot of [ __ ] interaction and it
would be really cool to get to listen
back to that I had a good time so the
live album should come out hopefully
that happens I want to give a huge shout
out even if the album doesn't come out I
always have a good time when Doug Benson
comes only give a huge shout out to Doug
Benson I don't think he listens to my
podcast I listen to three of his five
podcasts I think there's five let's see
getting Doug with hi Doug loves movies
Doug Lowe's minis dining with Doug and
Karen there's the premium content on
iTunes then I do not pay for I apologize
then there's also premium content on
stitcher that I do not pay for it may
sound crazy but there's so much [ __ ]
free podcasting why would I pay to
listen to a podcast even though it's my
buddy Doug Benson there's no need to pay
for I couldn't listen to it if I did pay
for it there's so much goddamn content
anyway Joe Rogan's putting out [ __ ] 9
hours a week I'm gonna pay for something
but anyway ah Doug Benson puts out a lot
of content I don't think he listens to
my show I listen to most of his but
anyway huge shout out to Doug Benson he
always treats me just like a normal dude
we're buddies by now he's like what's up
dude and it's not even weird when he
sees me he interacts with me and just
like we've hung out a lot also huge huge
shout out to Jacobs her off the dude was
funny he hung out with us after the show
took pics with Jenny Beth and I smoked
some joints with us also always always
want to give you a huge shout out to my
friends at Comedy Works in downtown
Denver ah shout-out to the entire staff
everybody there takes good care of me I
don't know a lot of their names because
there are a lot of them and there's one
of me I know a few of their names but
everybody there takes great care of me I
appreciate it from the guy at the front
bar to the guy at the second bar to the
ticket taker to the guy that at the
ticket booth it gives you your tickets
to all of the people that seat you that
bring you drinks to the sound guy
everybody there always treats me like
[ __ ] royalty like a rock star I love
that place can't show them enough love
if you're ever in Denver go catch a
comedy show at Comedy Works even if it's
not a big-name act just go see some
comedy there are some rules when you see
comedy guys let me educate you there's
one rule when you see comedy shut the
[ __ ] up you're not onstage the only
thing you're there to do is laugh your
ass off so don't interrupt don't
interact shut the [ __ ] up here's some
jokes laughs that's the only rules for
comedy don't heckle don't be that guy
Comedy Works will kick you the [ __ ] out
if you heckle and interrupting be a dick
Comedy Works will make you leave all
right go see some comedy I love comedy
and also I want to give a shot it's my
friend Baker uh Baker you take good care
of me bro I appreciate you also since
I'm at it
gigantic huge shout out to miss Jenny
Beth for a great fish weekend
you're a perfect fish date perfect thank
you all right where are we were like 20
minutes into this and I haven't talked
about cannabis at all I've talked about
a smoking cannabis but if you'll notice
my throat has quit doing that thing I'm
gonna take a little drink right here I'm
moisten myself up oh yeah that was
[ __ ] deliciously refreshing all right
onna shift gears to talk about something
a little bit more serious I can't use
any names because of I don't have
permission and I try to be respectful
but I had something weird happened while
I was at work the other day one of my
I'm the boss and it sounds weird to say
employees one of my employees and that's
how it goes I it just doesn't feel right
cuz he's my friend also and I don't like
power trip and being the boss he's equal
to me I've just got the title of I get
the [ __ ] to-do list and spread it out
and he does the [ __ ] but anyhow one of
my employees applied pesticides and he
assured me that he used all of the
proper protective equipment and that he
took all of the proper safety procedures
and steps and that he followed the
standard operation procedure to a tee
which I know he does because he's a
great employee he's dedicated he's smart
he's aware and he's just that guy and
he's also been worker protection safety
trained so I know what he's doing or I
know that he knows what he's doing and
he knows the risks involved with what
he's doing
so my employee applied a pesticide to a
room he actually applied you guys you
can mix pesticides if they're compatible
you don't have to spray one thing at a
time you can put like evergreen and
maybe I don't want to tell you too many
trade secrets but you can put evergreen
and cease in the same container and you
can shake the [ __ ] out of them put them
in there with water like 15 to 30 mils
of evergreen and like
thirty to forty five millilitres of
cease and to spray that [ __ ] on your
plants it'll help ya you can mix it but
we will do multiple products at a time
um we've got a new product that we've
only used a couple times and this
employee has never applied this product
before he did everything correctly
however at some point he mentioned that
he did get a couple of drops of this
pesticide on his wrist area and he said
he immediately removed his glove because
it got past the glove it got higher than
the glove way so he removed his glove he
went to the sink area and he washed his
hand for a few minutes as directed then
he went back and put on his gloves he
dried himself off went by put on his
gloves and applied the pesticide as
planned he was okay later on that
evening his hand was turning a little
bit red and it didn't bother him he
sprayed around 3 p.m.
around 10:30 that night he sent me a
text message saying hey I'm having an
allergic reaction to that spray check
this out and he sent me a picture of his
leg with welts growing on it it looked
it looked like he had just welts all
over his thigh area it was bad it was
red and funky and it was a little
concerning so I was like dude we have to
address this first thing in the morning
it was 10:30 at night there was nothing
I could do about it at the time other
than tell him go to the hospital if you
feel that's what you need to do because
as his friend and his boss and his
coworker and some of their just cares
about him in general I was like dude if
you need to go to the hospital go your
job is safe like we're not mad at you
go take care of you because that's what
matters so he's like I'm fine it doesn't
hurt it doesn't itch you'll see in the
morning he showed up the next morning at
8 o'clock and I'm like let me see that
you're okay to work because I don't need
him there working if he's not in good
shape and I need him to go to the doctor
so that we can prevent why abilities and
get my friend safe again and healthy so
I make him pull up his shirt and show me
like cuz yeah you said that was on his
ribcage last night and I was like let me
see your ribs and his ribs are cool I
was like let me see your thighs were
cool arms were cool is like all right
I'll let you work man so we worked
throughout the day everything is fine
everything was totally fine we go to
launch at noon we come back at 1:00
o'clock he starts working around 2:00
o'clock he approaches me and he said hey
boss like it's coming back he's got
little welts on his arms that aren't
significant but you can see something's
happening
um I said we've got to keep an eye on
this if it gets any worse you're going
to the doctor and he's like [ __ ] I don't
want to go to the doctor which is
understandable you guys within probably
30 minutes of this conversation he came
back to me he said boss I got to go to
the hospital this dude had welts on his
ribcage area that looked like I had
whipped this [ __ ] out of him with a whip
for hours these welts came out of
nowhere and covered his ribcage area on
both sides
he had welts on his thighs he had welts
on his forearms his he's brown his skin
is brown I'm not being racist he's got a
very brown complexion he's a brown
person he's got black hair [ __ ] brown
skin he was red his skin was visibly red
you could see that his face was red and
I was like bro we gotta take you to the
hospital so I grabbed all of the labels
off of all of the bottles that he had
used and put them in a baggie and we
drove to the hospital with those labels
and we had to tell the hospital that my
friend had been exposed to pesticides
now it was really funny because they're
like what are you here for I was like
pesticide exposure they're instant
reaction was too freaked out they were
like did you bring it in here how long
ago did you change clothes are you
wearing the same clothes did you shower
and I was like my buddy was kind of
before that what they're checking in
they asked him they asked him like
height weight birthday address name
phone number and then they said do you
feel safe at home and he goes what the
[ __ ] and the nurse left she goes do you
feel safe at home and he goes yeah and
she explained that they have to ask that
because that may be some person's only
opportunity to say no so don't ever
laugh and I'm gonna ask you that [ __ ]
question because there may be one person
that says no I need some [ __ ] help
it's scary at home someone's doing [ __ ]
to me so that's what that's for don't
laugh but my buddy was thrown off by
that question so I had to kind of
interrupt and explain I was like dude
this happened yesterday at 3:20 my
friend went home he changed clothes
immediately he's taking two or three
showers since then he came to work and
worked all day and hasn't been near that
pesticide I was off on the day that the
application happened I haven't been near
the pesticide or the applied room at all
I was like all this [ __ ] happened
yesterday and they all took a big breath
and calm down they're like
ah we're about to put you guys in the
decontamination shower so me and my
buddy were about to get a shower
together it sounded like which would
have been super awkward we were gonna
throw into the decontamination unit
which would have been really a longer
story than this who would have been a
lot more expensive of a building what it
was luckily I was able to speak up and
tell him that wasn't necessary so they
ended up telling my friend that it was
certainly an allergic reaction to the
pesticide they're like and my friend
kept saying but I didn't get it on my
legs and they explained you don't have
to get it on your legs the stuff you got
on you your body is allergic to it you
had a reaction it's trying to move that
reaction around your body to deal with
it so he got these weird hives all over
himself these welts these hive looking
things all over his body they told him
to take a couple of benadryl and take
benadryl every time it started flared up
and he said it was starting to itch real
bad you could see him trying not to
scratch it and they also gave him a
steroid shot this said the steroid shot
would speed it up and help his body heal
and recover from it so I gave him the
next day off he's got three days off in
a row right now I called him today it's
been he had a full day without me
bugging him then I called him today and
he said that he feels just fine that it
flares up occasionally and it itches
when he does but he takes a benadryl and
it goes away so he's doing much better
so by now I'm sure a lot of people are
going why is Jeff telling us about his
friend [ __ ] up with the pesticide I'm
telling you this because my friend got
drops of the pesticide on himself just a
few drops you can see where the drops
landed on his skin and left little marks
you can see how much you can actually
see how much [ __ ] landed on him because
it gave him a tattoo it changed his skin
colour right there it's back now but it
temporarily changed his skin colour and
it messed up his whole body I gave him a
fever it made him a chi it gave him
welts and these weird bumps all over
himself these hive-like bumps and he
wanted to scratch them and I feel that
if he would have scratched them he would
have ripped something open and he would
have been bleeding and gotten himself
infected just by how bad they looked the
reason I'm telling you guys this is
because I want you to be more careful
when applying pesticides a lot of us
myself included we've talked about this
at the girl we've all gotten everybody
that grows that's been
doing this for a long time has all
gotten a little a little lackadaisical
maybe the word we are a little
complacent when it comes to applying
pesticides and or being around
pesticides I know I did a podcast a
while back about pesticide safety and
pesticide training we've all had that
training it might grow several times and
something still happened so I want you
guys to be careful then the next thing I
want you to do is think about what
you're going to do if you do have a
pesticide problem if you're exposed to
something and you've got an emergency
what are you going to do to help
yourself is there somebody you can call
is there somebody at home with you are
you [ __ ]
do you have an illegal grow if you're
running an illegal grow and you apply a
pesticide and let's I don't want
anything bad to happen to you I didn't
want anything bad to happen to my
coworker I may have said his name so I
have to [ __ ] listen back to this
whole thing and make sure I didn't say
anything say my buddy's name I didn't
want anything to happen to him but it
did and luckily I have a support team
that I can reach out to and say hey that
[ __ ] happened I need guidance they gave
me step by step instruction on how to
handle this for my co-workers safety for
my safety and for the company safety you
may not have that so think about what
you're going to do let's just say you're
spraying you got your pump sprayer
however you apply your pesticide it's
probably in some sort of a pump sprayer
you're pumping it something ruptures
that [ __ ] explodes and pesticide goes
I don't want it in your high let's not
even go that extreme
you just get a pesticide up the side of
your face you got it on your cheek it's
kind of dripping down your neck it's
enough to make you go off [ __ ] I just
got a bunch of evergreen on my neck what
are you going to do do you have a plan
are you gonna freak out if you've got an
illegal grow and you've got to go to the
hospital for this you need a reason to
be spraying evergreen you can't have
spraying it on my weed plants so think
about all this stuff have the number for
poison control handy it's a regional
number I think I don't want to give you
the wrong number just google poison
control on your phone and you will have
the right number there's one number you
can call and they transfer you to the
correct region it's actually what
happens so have the poison control phone
number on your phone
if you've got an advanced phone you can
talk into it and you can say call poison
control so if you need help your phone
Siri will call poison control for you
they can give you advice on what to do
don't be afraid to call 9-1-1 if you've
got pesticides in your eyes you're gonna
need help you're going to have to call
9-1-1 wear some goggles when you're as
soon as you pick that bottle up you
should have goggles on because maybe the
lids not put on and you go to shake it
mesh it flies in your eye
you haven't even applied it yet you
haven't poured it yet you've already
[ __ ] up
you needed goggles then get the goggles
early so know what you're gonna do if
you do have a problem you need most
pesticides I can't speak for every
pesticide most of them if you get it on
your skin the thing you need to do is
rinse for 15 minutes wouldn't be a
problem
just rinse that area for 15 minutes if
you've got some antibacterial soap scrub
that [ __ ] on there get that pesticide
off of your skin it's better to rinse
too much and wash too heavily then just
to be lazy and leave some on there so
get in there and rinse that [ __ ] off if
you see anything like a welt or anything
like your skin raising or turning white
or changing colors maybe consider going
to the hospital and getting looked at
it's gonna be expensive but your health
is priceless okay luckily my coworker
was able to take some benadryl and get a
shot he didn't have anything too serious
please don't put yourself in my
co-workers position I know I've been
ranting about this for a long time but
it was scary my buddy was already [ __ ]
up from pesticides and then I was
watching him just have a [ __ ] nervous
breakdown because he was so scared of
what he may have done to his body and
what may happen to him at the hospital
it was not a fun experience for anybody
and it was quite expensive luckily it'll
be covered because we have a great
company workman's comp handles that sort
of [ __ ] but if that was you at home and
you had to pay for it out of pocket or
through your insurance you're gonna have
some explaining to do and it's gonna get
expensive so I'm gonna say it again have
a plan if you [ __ ] up with pesticides
have a plan know what you're gonna do
you need to clean yourself you need to
get the clothes off of you if it's on
your clothes you need to shower if you
feel like you need medical attention
don't be shy go get it okay
it's always best to have somebody around
when you're applying pesticides always
use the proper equipment goggles all the
time from the minute you pick up that
pest put the goggles on then pick up the
pesticide bottle have gloves on at least
those six mil six millimeter thick
nitrile gloves at least wear those
you're supposed to wear something twelve
milliliter 12 millimeters thick when
you're handling a pesticide a lot of the
pesticides need something thicker wear
those thicker gloves wear long sleeves
wear pants definitely cover your [ __ ]
feet make sure that your feet are
covered all the pesticides gonna fall to
the ground and you're gonna walk in it
the bottoms of your feet are some of the
most absorb absorb I don't know the
proper word the bottoms of your feet
absorb a lot they're able to it's the
most absorption II I don't [ __ ] know
pick a word right there it absorbs the
most the bottom of your feet your
genitals your eyes in your mouth your
palms that's where you can absorb a lot
of stuff so don't go walking around in
pesticides cover up your feet if you're
applying pesticides always always always
follow the re-entry interval rules on
the bottle it's on every bottle also
here's something to think about if
you've got a home grow if you've got an
indoor grow and you don't have major air
circulation you need to give extra time
for what's called a ventilation period
when you apply a pesticide in a room it
becomes basically a vapor if you're
using a paint sprayer or a pump sprayer
you've turned it into little vapors and
it's floating around the room you have
to allow two hours for a ventilation
period for that vapor to dissipate and
become tool and essentially it needs to
land that fog in the room needs to go
away so you've got a two hour
ventilation period before your reentry
interval starts so a lot of the products
we're using have a four and eight a
twelve none of them should have a
24-hour re intro re-entry interval if it
does you're using some major [ __ ] you
may want to reconsider that but follow
those rules carefully and wear your
personal protective equipment if you
have to go in there early please take it
seriously you guys I've seen very minor
effects of things going wrong with
pesticides and it was a scary situation
I don't want it to happen to anybody I
don't want it to happen to
you I want you to be safe one thing I
would recommend is before you apply a
pesticide read what to do should you
[ __ ] up so that you don't have to be
struggling panicking having a freakout
possibly have [ __ ] in your eyes and then
trying to read a bottle to figure out
what to do read it before also should
you need to go to the hospital I don't
want you to have to but you may have to
you guys this this [ __ ] comes up I had
to take a good friend to the hospital if
you have to go to the hospital take the
labels off of the bottles don't take
them too far into the hospital before
you tell somebody which you've got
because they're gonna want to put it in
a safe container so you don't spread any
of that pesticide around the hospital if
you can if time allows take a shower and
change your clothes anything you were
wearing when you applied pesticides take
it off rinse your body thoroughly put on
fresh clothes that aren't contaminated
with pesticides then go to the hospital
so that way you don't contaminate the
hospital with pesticides also you don't
contaminate the people that help you the
doctor the nurse the triage nurse the
delay Tia check in the security guard
the takes your knife from you I just
don't contaminate them with pesticides
also pay attention to pesticides I
encourage everybody to read all of the
labeling on all the pesticides you were
using I encourage you to use all the
proper equipment that you need for all
of those pesticides do not take any of
it lightly and please be careful with
the pesticides you're using outdoors do
not [ __ ] up our environment so that you
can grow some cannabis all right it's
not worth it that all of the land is not
yours just that one plot that you're
growing on and that spray that you're
spraying is affecting the entire world
and it's not fair so please be
respectful if you're spraying pesticides
outside no matter what you're doing with
this pesticide please be careful please
respect the [ __ ] in that bottle it's not
a joke all right I feel like I've been
[ __ ] giving you guys a lecture for a
long time I'm gonna stop doing that for
right now
all right podcast world I've been going
for close to 40 minutes I did have a
couple of emails I've got two emails
about the same topic they're both about
getting into the cannabis industry and
folks moving to Colorado
we got one person coming from Georgia we
got another person coming from Florida I
actually hope they are both okay since
we've got a [ __ ] tremendous hurricane
down there whippin everybody's ass you
guys I hope you're well I hope you're
able to listen to this podcast to help
you and your families are safe
hope everybody down in the south is safe
I hope everybody and the West is safe
from the fires everyone in the South is
safe from the floods ah that I send
[ __ ] love and light to everybody in
times of struggles right now because the
natural disasters or whatever type of
disaster you've got in your life I
[ __ ] send you some JA love but what I
was saying was I'm gonna read some
emails on the next episode from folks
from down south they are both coming to
Colorado or looking to come to Colorado
to get into the industry so we'll talk
about how to guide them into doing that
a little bit if you'd like to send me an
email to read on a future episode I
would love to hear from you it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com also if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast you can contact me through grow
from your heart at hotmail.com speaking
of product reviews I do have a box from
my friends at Pio grow they sent me a
great product to try out I have been
away on vacation seeing fish I came back
from seeing fish to find out that my
coworker had a pesticide problem and
then today I'm recording hopefully over
the weekend I am able to set up the
device that they sent me I'll play
around with that over the weekend I'll
get it set up and running for the week
and then hopefully within the next few
weeks I'll be able to give you guys a
full report and a full review and I'll
be able to report back to my friends at
Pio grow I'm sure they're looking
forward to all of my words all right you
guys you can tell my voice is starting
to burn out I would appreciate it if you
find me on all of these social medias
check me out on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast if you'd
like to see my cannabis photography on
Instagram
I am Irie and erskine etics I RIE
underscore genetics
check me out there I've been posting
pictures of the new storm shadow strain
I made there are pictures of plants from
the commercial grow for pictures of
plants from my personal grow lots of
great photos in my opinion I think
you'll like it
I read genetics on Instagram i RIE
underscore genetics click follow I would
like it what else do I got for you
patreon if you would like to support the
podcast financially you can do so by
going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart I'm not trying to beg for
money I'm just making it an option for
those people who would like to
contribute
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
for all the information that you need
big shout out to everybody who's been
contributing to patreon I truly do
appreciate you that helps me cover the
cost of my website every year it helps
me buy new little covers for the
microphone so that when Mike comes over
he doesn't have to spit into the same
microphone cover that granny was using
we get to switch it up keep everybody
healthy so that's what your funds are
going for paying for the podcast mostly
and I do appreciate it patreon.com slash
grow from your heart I hope you guys are
enjoying the throwback Thursday episodes
that I'm making almost every Thursday I
put out a long block of old episodes my
reason for doing so is because on iTunes
and stitcher those feeds only hold 100
episodes that means that the most recent
100 shows are there and all the old [ __ ]
falls right out of the feed so I've been
making long blocks of episodes to make
those good episodes available once again
so new listeners can go back and hear
old content once I get caught up I'll
stop doing it the good part is I'm
putting old episodes up on YouTube
YouTube will not limit how many shows
I've got so if you check out YouTube's
search for the girl from your heart
podcast you will find I think there are
approximately 75 to 80 videos up on
YouTube now I do plan on making more it
just is time consuming and I'm a
hard-working young man so don't have a
lot of time to sit here and make YouTube
videos but I'll get them up so that you
can enjoy them ladies and gentlemen I
think you can hear my voice cutting out
it's starting to go so it is time to
wrap up this podcast I want to give a
huge shout out to Big John I got your
email and I appreciate it and I also
want to give a huge shout out to
everybody who is volunteering time to go
rescue people from floods volunteering
to go put out fires I appreciate you
guys also we need more people like you
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug
[Music]
tell me am I in time to watch that
no one Silla see are you
[Music]
the
is returned
Jiali people see the Emperor
Eli Adashi one is returned
[Music]
pointing desire give your home Forge a
kingdom
oh just once oh come oh come now
[Music]
Oh
take fat davit give your mom a hug for
me
alright Rasta Jeff let's not drag my mom
into this and I'll see you soon I assume
I ass