yo in a podcast world
it's Rasta Jeff and it's Thursday so
that means it's time for another
throwback Thursday episode of the girl
from your heart podcast before I get
into the block of old episodes let me
make a quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any promotions any contests
or any giveaways those have all expired
there are currently no contest no
promotions no advertising or no
giveaways also let me update all of the
social media if you want to find me on
Twitter you can find me at G f YH
podcast on Twitter on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast and if you'd like to send me an
email
it's drove from your heart at
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen I hope
you enjoyed these chunks of old episodes
so here we go the throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
if you're a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff sitting across the table from
me today is our good buddy white Mike
how you doing bro I am great good I may
have fallen asleep on the couch for a
couple hours so when you got here I may
have been a little bit groggy but I
think I've got my [ __ ] together by now
naps are good for your health naps are
really good for you take a bunch of dabs
eat a bunch of food then you wake up on
the couch one more time Wayne right
feeling all refreshed I'm doing great
man thanks for coming today bro
happy happy - I think the listeners like
having you one because we get a lot of
listens with your hair guys before we
get too far I wanted to give a big THANK
YOU shout out to the mystic roots man
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew they let me play their
music on my show they don't ask me for
anything in return
that's super kind of that make sure you
guys support mystic roots in my opinion
Katherine Ramirez is the most beautiful
woman in reggae so make sure you check
that out big shout out to the coot or
the mystic roots canton coot from the
mystic roots pancetta so we've got some
cool [ __ ] lined up today to talk about
the first I want to kind of brag about
my good-ass weekend Thursday I think I
recorded uh since this Thursday Israel
vibration right yeah we talked about
that so uh Saturday my phone is too
close to the recording yeah by phone get
out of here we don't need you for a
minute
Saturday we I went up to Comedy Works to
go see our good friend Doug Benson again
for probably the 15th or 20th ish time I
went to work full disclosure well thanks
for uh keeping the shop on lock and
holding everything down while Rasta jeff
was up seen Doug Benson somebody gotta
hustle the truth so uh I didn't have
anybody to go with me Saturday I thought
I had some plans they didn't work out
the person I wanted to go with me was
unable to go Saturday so I went up there
and I had two tickets
and I walked up to the line and there
was another dude by himself walking up
to the line looked kind of confused
holding like his printed ticket and [ __ ]
I could tell he was a noob - comedy
works that he'd never been there and he
was trying to figure out the Comedy
Works lifestyle so I watched him fumble
around and I started conversation with
him he lit up a blunt we smoked a blunt
there in the part in the line at comedy
works and then he goes man he asked me a
question about comedy works I don't
remember what he said specifically and I
go oh no worries man you could totally
do that here you'll be just fine and as
we walked in he went to get his ticket I
go man you don't even need your ticket
you gonna sit with me tonight he goes
what do you want to sit front row bro
and he goes no you're [ __ ] me and I
go yeah man I got two front row passes
let's go sit in the front row and so
anybody that knows me that listens to
the show I'm gonna brag a little bit
I've got two lifetime preferred seating
passes for Comedy Works in downtown
Denver all I've got to do is let them
know that I'm coming and I will be
seated in seat 12 which is the front two
seats right there in front of the stage
right where the comedian's are spitting
and drooling and sweating and sturdy in
the face and making fun of you and
putting you in part of the show if the
be part of the show section made fun of
every time I sit there if I sit there so
it's great in the front don't love to
make fun of me so I took this new dude
that I'd never met until that day he was
having kind of a bad day up until then I
was like Brooks come with me we'll go
sit front row and he sat front row in
here the time of his [ __ ] life dude
he laughed his ass off you gave me a hug
at the end of the night was so cool
thank you I shout out to my buddy Merlin
if you're listenin bro it was good
meeting you man that was a good time so
after the show we go meet Doug Benson I
get stoned hang out with Doug Benson
actually it was really cool because it
was a Doug loves movies podcast and
Harlan Williams was a [ __ ] guest
Harlan is one of my favorite comedians
that was [ __ ] awesome Pete Davidson
or Davison from Saturday Night Live was
another guest and Doug's friend and a
comedian I've seen several times Jeff
Tate was the third guest so hung got
stoned with Jeff Tate doesn't smoke pot
but he hung out with us and Doug Benson
definitely smoked got stoned with a
whole bunch of cool ass people in the
crowd and then I drove back to Pueblo
actually at the mellow mushroom it was
still hungry so I also ate at the chee
behind because
my head and I'm a fat [ __ ] so that [ __ ]
was delicious drove home and when you're
in food country you gotta stop and get
some yeah when you drive past both of
those restaurants you're like well I'm
eating here there's just no stopping it
oh that's my friend Tiffany over at the
mellow mushroom thanks for a delicious
meal that was awesome he took good care
of me great waitressing I liked it
so Saturday Sunday did it all over again
I had a beautiful date Sunday she was
able to go with me Sunday went up there
and saw Doug Pinson do stand-up comedy
he tore it the [ __ ] up that was amazing
he made fun of me a little bit both
nights so that was cool two days of Doug
Benson hanging out with Doug Benson
the second night he treated me it was
not even like some celebrity and his fan
hanging out Jeff Tate walked up to me
and asked me a question he had a
question for me because I I was part of
the show at the end of the show they
play games and they play a game called
the last man standing the thing is
somebody the audience names an actor and
then the participants in the game have
to name movies that that actor has been
in until they run out yeah we just keep
going back and forth until Doug knew
that I listened to the podcast so he's
like Rasta Jeff will definitely have a
name for us we'll go to him for a name
in just a minute so he let me give him
the name when it came time to it I said
I have two names in my head do you want
me to give you two of them any pick one
he goes nope just give me one and we'll
do it I was like all right so the name I
gave them for the game was Philip
Seymour Hoffman because I mean he's got
a lot of [ __ ] movies it was really
good they liked it a lot of fun with it
so after the show Jeff Tate walked up
he's like who was your other name bro
forget the guy's [ __ ] name and I had
it like in my head right at that moment
for when he asked what I forgot NYX I
knew my time was up and I go I forgot
dude you know yeah but I always forget
his name and I said he played the
president in mocking and before I could
say Mockingjay he goes oh [ __ ] Donald
Sutherland dude and hit me on the
shoulder
so that dude knows his [ __ ] movies
Jeff Tate knows his movies real well
shoutout to Jeff day they made me feel
like a friend guys treat me like I am a
homie now when I walked through Comedy
Works I get high fives
I didn't even walk me to my seat anymore
like you're you know where your [ __ ]
seat is go have a seat enjoy your night
right
yeah do Comedy Works is awesome ice to
go there on college it's I mean I love
going to music shows but some music
crowds are [ __ ] yep the crowds have
evolved into [ __ ] that want to shove
their way to the front and spill their
beer on you and just be a disrespectful
dick and don't appreciate the show and
they kind of ruin some concerts for me I
started enjoying sitting in the back and
getting high as [ __ ] a long time getting
older but comedy shows they don't allow
any of that pushing and shoving [ __ ]
they'll kick you right out if you heckle
so you're sitting down the whole time
and you can order food and they bring it
to you so comedy shows have been kind of
my new go-to thing for a date or for
some fun it's really great stick girl I
see a pretty girl smile at a comedy show
shoutouts my date I don't think you
listen to the show but you know who you
are the wild cousins comedy shot at all
the Pueblo comedy crew much love much
respect all right we've been talking
about everything but cannabis on this
podcast for the past 10 minutes I'm for
some let's talk about cannabis actually
cookies let's take a quick second here
do you realize what I just asked you I
do serve people in places they were
probably just smacking their smth
smacked my damn head right now girls got
cookies and gorilla glue just sitting
there ready to smoke yes you guys and
it's not even flowers it's the most
beautiful hash you've ever seen yes but
when you do make sure that you include
some sort of law or allow you to have
some sort of consumption place where
everybody can gather and smoke cannabis
because that's what we missed here in
Colorado and right now we're struggling
to get those types of rules in place
wonderful yes but before you do let's
make a decision here would you like the
Girl Scout cookies or would you like to
go with the gorilla glue only because
right before we started recording we did
yes we did all right
it was quite wonderful but I coughed for
quite a bit hope will give you a little
dab Mike's kind of that's the truth you
don't have to take a DAB that's
comfortable for you Mike just said that
he had some news to share I'm gonna make
Mike share his news before he takes this
dad will be your reward reward that is
waiting for you and I'm gonna dabble you
tell us about your news so I got a text
a few days ago from a local friend of
mine in the industry down here he's
always been kind of a step removed like
he's not an owner of a dispensary or
anything like that but he got me a text
and he had a licensing hearing you
needed he wanted me to attend and he
received his special use permit to open
a cannabis museum slash consumption
location here in Pueblo County is this
somebody that I know yep look for that
coming
so a cannabis museum during the
licensing hearing his description of it
would be a marijuana themed Hard Rock
Cafe would be the closest business that
he could related to that everyone's
familiar with so when you sit down at
your your booth with the marijuana
product you bring yourself there will be
stuff on the wall that's like marijuana
was originally outlawed and it out it
out it out like historical stuff and
they've hired local historians like
professional historians that do this for
a living
Wow and are currently researching
cannabis because there isn't a local
historian who expert
word lost my focuses I suppose I could
qualified but I didn't know that we need
to come to somebody all the schooling
will be great useful but then they need
to come to somebody involved in it right
to get it sure they've got a college I
like us on the team and if they don't
I'm gonna be that person on the team for
them if at all possible Rock Cafe if you
will I'm sure it's got a name but I
don't I don't honestly remember it but
yeah that should be coming here earliest
estimates first of the year
knowing how these things go sometimes
I'm gonna say bye in the spring we
should have a place to go and enjoy some
cannabis out in the public you know what
was in a business that be in the city of
Pueblo or in the county of just into the
county just into the county all right
come on city of Pueblo you guys want
that damn tax money but you won't let us
have anything in the city the Pueblo
County passed rules and regs for public
consumption shops a while ago there's
only been one other applicant that I
know of to try and they [ __ ] it up so
hard it was painful a lot I think I
remember hearing about that huh I was
really pissed that they did it because
that said everybody back it's like six
months
ouch alright guys so you heard it here
first our buddy Mike reported on it Mike
is our correspondent now suddenly
reporter Mike live from the field Mike
you in a DAB you want a free dab for
such a wonderful report on the show here
there will be prizes marijuana I like
the word cannabis there will be a
cannabis museum in the county of Pueblo
here before too long that is really cool
Mike said something about public
consumption I am going to humble myself
I'm going to eat a little bit of crow if
you will on this show never said eat
crow before I get the phrase and now
that I've said it I understand where it
comes in perfectly I've never said that
I've heard it and thought that's a weird
phrase but it just came in perfectly so
shout out to the phrase eat some crow
it's got its place recently I've had
I've had beef with a couple of people
personal issues childish [ __ ] that's
stuck in my mind and they recently
through a harvest festival here in
Pueblo Colorado and their event was
completely [ __ ] successful they
crushed it they had a public consumption
event three blocks from my house on the
Main Street of our town our town is
called pueblos this should happen on
Pueblo Boulevard
they smoked hash and weed and had a
miniature cannabis cup basically in
their parking four minutes from my house
I did not attend it because like I said
I was seeing Doug Benson and that was my
priority then I know where they're they
don't off huge Spence and Jesse cleaned
house Spence won six awards and Jesse
won first place Jesse's outdoor grape OG
beat I don't know if I'm supposed to say
that that [ __ ] was outdoor but Jesse's
possibly outdoor grape OG green house
beat a greenhouse properly beat a bunch
of indoor weed so shout out to Jesse for
his victory shout out to Spence for six
[ __ ] Awards dude home runs you know
I've got I have had personal issues with
those people and it's my choice over
possibly business issues that we're
legal involving a store even though
we've got a little bit of beef we don't
get along we don't see eye to eye on
[ __ ] everything we're all in the same
community they pulled it off and proud
of them
I'm gonna give them a shout out right
here shout out to Terry shout out to
[ __ ] Ryan you guys did it you see
that big old [ __ ] played a crow right
here at the [ __ ] grocery cart a
podcast I'm [ __ ] feasting on it you
guys I'm saying it out loud they did it
I'm proud of him
nice work you guys no sarcasm like I'm a
smartass and I'm [ __ ] I'm straight
face right here good work you guys like
I've never gone to one of their events
for personal nor my personal stupid [ __ ]
and I'm a stubborn [ __ ] something in
me if I don't like you for something
you've done in the past and probably not
gonna like you in the future but I see
them trying to make progress I've tried
to work with those people before and we
just butt heads and so I've kind of
separated myself but I'm gonna get over
it
and I'm gonna go there next eBay because
they crushed it this time
all right so I had to man up there for a
minute I feel better all right Oh Mike
you look perplexed you've got a weird
look on your face nerds I wished I would
have gone to that like that when I heard
how well it went I was bummed that I had
to work all weekend right yeah I
couldn't wish that I would have gone
that's fully the first time I felt about
one of their events and they finally did
it right from what I hear you gonna try
haven't heard about any blowback from it
either nothing has really nothing
nothing wrong yeah well it's been
several days it's Wednesday now it's
about to be Thursday so nothing's gonna
happen all right so I was gonna say I
was gonna try not to miss any Doug
Benson shows at Comedy Works I'm gonna
try to get as many as I can because if
you tweet Doug Benson he will read your
tweets during the first 20 minutes of a
show that's what he does he just reads
tweets and makes fun of people and so uh
I just tweeted at him hey Doug front row
again feels like home
and so he read a bunch of tweets and he
goes this guy back here says where's
whatever my tweet her name and he's I'm
over here it was his tweet says I'm Way
too high ha ha ha speaking away - hi
raasta Jeff's in the front row again yes
rhasta Jeff's been in the front row in
that seat for the last 18 Doug Benson
shows he hasn't missed a show yet though
so funny I'm gonna try not to miss any -
it's gonna be a good time if the
listeners out there want this experience
the way to do every Doug Benson show
it's just there's a way to do this go
bananas I think that's the club in
Cincinnati baby if that's see like I
almost want a Google a juleps I'm gonna
take [ __ ] 30 seconds - we might pause
it we might not let's see we're gonna
have Siri do it
yeah I've been a dog fan for a long time
I guess we'll see I just ask Siri
where's the club go bananas live
stand-up since a [ __ ] Maddy bro up
such a comedy geek go bananas give this
a lot of vodka I do I love comedy comedy
is one of my favorite [ __ ] things I
alright because we've been rambling on
for like 20 minutes let's get on to a
topic here we've got a couple of things
in the news that we could talk about um
I read an article I'm not gonna read you
the article because it's forever long
it's way too many words long but I found
this article on a website called The
Guardian Mike also read it we'll be able
to discuss it without reading it here on
the show and we'll be able to paraphrase
a little bit for you guys and tell you
what it's about essentially um they're
talking about an influx of people coming
from across the country to Pueblo
Colorado because Pueblo Colorado for the
size of the city that we are and for our
economic development in the amount of
cannabis jobs available we are the most
affordable place to land when you come
from out of state would you agree with
that Mike we routinely ranked is like
the cheapest city in Colorado right if
you anywhere smaller you're pretty much
[ __ ] there's a hundred thousand people
here which is just about perfect for
coming to a city that's not too
expensive trying to get a new star the
cheapest cities in the u.s. its Denver I
[Music]
was part of this story in like a back
room since I've met with all the players
about this topic but don't spill too
many of those beans I won't
[Music]
we're not gonna beat but we'll talk
about it so they're saying that all
these people moving to Pueblo Colorado
are beginning to put a burden on our
resources here we have a resource called
Posada which is a nonprofit organization
that helps families I get there some
themselves on their feet if something
happens to somebody here in Pueblo they
can go to Posada for example there's a
guy in this news article that hurt his
foot something fell on him and broke his
foot and he can't work for a little bit
so he's going to Posada to get a little
bit of help maybe I don't know what
they're given and possibly some food
probably some cheese just to keep him on
his feet while he's unable to work but
they're saying that those resources at
Posada are being strained and the people
are coming from all over the nation to
come work here and they're not prepared
like you look like you got something on
your mind already you're stewing but no
it's so what they're getting at is that
legal marijuana is creating a huge
homeless problem in Pueblo Colorado
right and it's not like causing good
hardworking Americans who got hooked on
marijuana to become homeless it's
attracting homeless people in other
areas to pueblos apparently and the
article goes on to say people that work
at Posada and a couple other agencies in
town saying that they've had huge
increases in people seeking services
from them whether it's housing vouchers
or food stamps or medicine bank medicine
vouchers or help with medical problems
Posada especially has been pretty vocal
with the press down here in Pueblo and
then it's spiraled nationally when the
anti pot groups picked it up and started
pushing it other newspapers started
picking it up
the one of the problems caused by
amendment 64 is more homeless people
coming to Colorado because of our
marijuana laws and just that idea never
really made sense to me until I realized
that it's not illegal to be homeless
most places but it is illegal to have
pop most places right
and homeless people have huge rage of
substance abuse and if if you're
homeless consuming substances is a way
to deal with some of the miserable
conditions in that lifestyle absolutely
so if you can move to a place where
they're not going to chase you around
and throw you in jail for having some
weed why not be there and when that's
combined with a number of other things
that are happening at the same time like
legal marijuana here everybody's talking
about how many thousands of people are
working in the industry and how much
money it's making no one's talking about
what it takes to get an Emmy D badge so
that's something I was gonna touch on a
few minutes when you're homeless
and there's a new it booming industry I
mean it's he was been doing it since
humans started doing anything we moved
for to where there's work especially
when there's no work and we're just
coming out of a depression like a
national depression where works hard to
come by everywhere especially in our age
demographic remember all those articles
about people than their 30s that moved
home after college right I'm not saying
me but a lot of them got degrees unlike
internet stuff those jobs are all taken
up that should kind of failed but not
failed but I mean it's just gotten so
much easier to make a webpage that that
guy that you used to know how to do it
isn't and I have a theory that that's
gonna happen to the weed grower or to
I'm gonna do a whole report on that here
on the podcast in the future so yeah
those those people are now in the weed
industry making a pretty solid living
yeah um so there's a lot of reasons
homeless people are at our people on the
break of being homeless or moving to
Colorado and I mean I've said it a
countless times like come if you want to
come here that's great but come prepared
right like come prepared is one
seriously that's the iton on this
[ __ ] paper come prepare them that's
huge and a lot of people didn't like
winning your kind at the end of your
road financially an opportunity wise
wherever you live
and you hear about Colorado and
everything that's going on here all the
stores all it grows I mean you figure at
least I can get a job trimming right I
can sit in a room and cut Leafs off buds
all day I can surely do it in scrubs
like I'll move there and do it but no
one knows what that takes right you guys
if you're going to cut in come prepared
that's definitely the thing come here
with a little bit of money cuz it's
gonna take a minute to get a job in the
weed industry you have to get before you
even come here research a Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division support
badge if you're coming here for work in
the industry definitely know what it
takes to get a job in the end you're not
gonna get a job trimming for you may get
a job trimming for your cousin or
whatever but that shit's not gonna last
long it's not gonna that's not going to
sustain you it may sound a fruitful
right now but trimming for your buddy or
trimming for whoever's got this girl
option option for you it's not gonna
work unless it's a legal business
there's a lot of a lot of people that
have lived here or have recently moved
here with kind of a plan and gotten a
job that are growing their legal six
plants and they need help trimming and
they'll call you and you can trim for
them for like ten hours once every 90
days right yeah you need to work for
like five of those people if you want to
try to pay rent that way right
and you're not gonna find for others
right when you move here I hate it that
the trimmers I use go trim for other
people if you're not trimming if you
don't need a mad badge that's probably
not a job that's gonna last for very
long right now they're cleaning up
illegal grow operations they're getting
rid of all of that [ __ ] here in Colorado
it's going away so when things are legal
the illegal stands out like a sore thumb
true very true that's something we've
talked about on the show so research
getting your marijuana Enforcement
Division support badge if you've got any
drug felonies in the last ten years
don't even think about coming to
Colorado to get a job in the industry
they're not gonna give you a badge if
you don't have the badge you can't walk
in the door we can't let you behind the
counter you can't go in the gross space
you can't trim you can't deliver you
can't sweep the parking lot like I swear
to
god he's get on the website it takes two
seconds google colorado meed badge and
it'll come right up our security guards
are badged with their security service
like train with their security they wear
their security guard badge and their
shirts for their security and they're
gone all day long but they're also
wearing a marijuana enforcement they
have to have that [ __ ] to work there so
they had to go spend an extra it's like
150 bucks for that badge just to work
there so you guys if you can't afford a
hundred and fifty dollar badge and if
you can't qualify for that badge don't
come here please because I'm not talking
[ __ ] to you I'm not saying don't come
here you're just gonna be stuck you're
not gonna be able to get in the industry
you're gonna be relying on resources
here you're gonna make it just kind of
makes it look shitty if you can come
here and do something you're invited
come on if you're if you're able if
you're willing if you're ready if you
can trim if you're able to get the badge
we'll take it but honestly here while
we're on it the boot for requirements
are no drug felonies in ten years no
felonies period in five it's kind of
[ __ ] up that you could have like
killed someone and like with your car or
something five years ago five years ago
and get your badge before the guy who
got busted with an out or what is it two
grams of concentrate in most places yeah
yeah it really is but so no drug
felonies in ten years no felonies in
five and your student loans and your
child support need to be in order yes
now what in order means is you you means
you have to call them and set up a
payment plan and make one payment if
you're already paying on it you're legit
you're already paying good order you're
fine but if you've been ducking child
support for urge student loans for a
while you got to stand up call Sallie
Mae and start making payments you know
all they want is a receipt and tip that
you're paying I had to do it like I had
to go show him that my student loans
were in good order I do is get a thing
from both long companies it was really
easy I filled out I printed the
application online I printed it at home
I filled it out it took me like 30
minutes to do it whatever you know it's
just like a thick job application but
really thorough
yeah and then they give it to the FBI
who checks it so you can't just lie and
while they're checking a better smartest
[ __ ] they take your paperwork
running it then they call you back while
it's being ran and they fingerprint you
they take their sweet [ __ ] time
fingerprinting you so that if there is
anything wrong with your paperwork and
they if you're illegal if you've got
warrants they'll come and get your ass
right there oh yeah I wondered why it
took so long it seemed like the tech was
brand new and yet it took her 74 tries
to get my index finger oh yeah that
finger that laser reading finger printer
is hard while they were there yeah they
don't [ __ ] around so one thing I was
gonna say and this is gonna sound like
really rude as [ __ ] go and take cash
when you go to you the license place oh
yeah they do not take a check or a money
order you gotta know it's 150 I don't
want to quote the prices right now
because they change all the [ __ ] time
yep I paid 150 for mine was that a big
echo I didn't hear it okay I've got
these headphones on it's not a hurt echo
recording oh you guys I know it sounds
great to pack up your whole life and
come to Colorado and enjoy the
dispensary and smoke some legal cannabis
and it is it's amazing I have a plan
have a plan it's not as complicated
deep-sea fishermen we've got your
[ __ ] job here - Adam thought he was
gonna come here and grow some paw and be
the king [ __ ] of the [ __ ] world and
I'm not talking to [ __ ] about Adam Adam
is making it but Adam is not buying
whatever CD came out last week
he's Adam is not going with us to dinner
I work construction with them all yeah
if you fight for you can make it but
come here with a plan save up some money
find a job find a place or two that you
want to see to rent you have a plan yes
or don't just show up here with a u-haul
truck in three dollars in your pocket
cuz you will be homeless in like four
days or my option for you which I
recommend what you're gonna think I'm a
dick but ah save the energy that you
were gonna use to move here and use that
energy to fight for a legalization where
you
just push that over yeah just do that
right where you are just gather a bunch
of people ah get a bunch of like-minded
folk it'd be cool if you can get all the
smokers around but I understand a bunch
of potheads sometimes you don't want the
potheads to go to City Council with you
there's a couple guys you just want to
leave behind
we've definitely had more than one
walk-up I shoot themselves and everybody
else in the foot and it sucked
yeah some of those guys you just leave
behind but try to get an intelligent
group of people put an ad on Craigslist
in your area say hey I want to fight to
legalize cannabis let's start a
legalization group and you guys get
together and you make a petition put on
the ballot for your community policy
[Music]
advocacy groups for your areas what you
want to find and then join that [ __ ]
then do what you can
everybody's got their own gift in life
and if you want to fight for
legalization you have to find where you
fit in find what you can do my niche is
this podcast my niche is making seeds my
niche is growing like a [ __ ]
my initiatives taking care of my
patients and paying attention to what
works for them medicinally and adjusting
my grow schedule and micronutrients and
my gross strains to work for my
individual patients medical needs which
is an arc to tell you the [ __ ] truth
to draw enough weed for Mike and enough
weed for Doug and other people that I
supply and have the right strains at the
right times for these people it takes a
little bit of scheduling and a little
bit of foresight so whatever you do
you're a construction worker and you
look
move here and do construction and smoke
weed and the evenings have as much of a
[ __ ] plan about what you're gonna do
in life as Jeff just laid out right
there it's like what he does is his
niche like at least that much you should
be getting online and like oh you know
I'm a car salesman and find a dozen car
dealerships looking for employees before
you even consider moving out here yeah
call them contact them send them your
information let them know you'll be here
whenever looking for a job yep long
before you move out here the people that
moved out here with just a hope and a
prayer most of them have had to beg
people for money so that they can haul
their ass back home and that has to suck
unfortunately a Colorado has become be
not what you know but who you know state
if you want to be in the cannabis
industry right now there's just so many
rules and regulations and the tiniest
[ __ ] can cost the shop ten thousand
two hundred thousand bucks that you can
lose their licensing because you did
something that half the people that walk
in our doors every day assume we're
doing constantly so gaining that level
of trust and a job interviews a
[ __ ] absolutely and if your main
sales pitches that you've been hired for
a decade like just don't try like come
here and do whatever you've been doing
to make a living if it's selling weed
don't move here because we got stores to
do that now I get to look at a lot of
job applications because anything that
goes for the grow department the job
applications get passed to myself and
another guy you would not believe some
of the verbage that I see in job
applications like list your skills dog I
could grow the sticky-icky fire dog I
got hydro skills with the Z and [ __ ] and
we honestly we throw those applications
away I bring a resume look professional
it is the weed industry but it is called
industry its business we're trying to
better our business we need to make
money so we can improve our business we
can open more stores
it's just how business [ __ ] works
don't come trying to talk like you're a
cool gangster and try to impress us be
professional legal comes with rules
illusions and expectations you're gonna
be wearing a lab coat if you work next
to me in the grow I know that sounds
ridiculous we were at a lab coats bro
we've got a different lab coat for each
room I need to know that you're
responsible enough to wear this lab coat
and room a and know that you need to
take that son of a [ __ ] off and put on
another lab coat before you enter room
be aware enough to actually care about
cross-contamination yeah yeah we need to
know that you can read the warning signs
when we use a pesticide and we put up a
certain do not enter sign or whatever
gear is required to enter this room we
didn't know that you can read that kind
of stuff even the salespeople if I make
a real simple mistake I can get the shop
shut down yeah oh yeah anybody anybody
that works there pretty much with the
badge if we do with the law if we say
the wrong [ __ ] the store can be closed
any minute yeah and we're under camera
you guys you guys think we can hang out
and smoke pot and be chill know it's
busy as [ __ ] all the time there's no
chairs where I work there are no chairs
in my work area I'm always standing up
but also we're under camera from every
angle and all times you're on two
cameras no matter where you are in that
building there are two cameras covering
that area I cannot scratch my ass in
that building without being seen if you
do something really funny you can go to
the office and ask for the footage like
immediately cuz it's available I've had
security that was three rooms away make
fun of me for but Craig is on camera to
the point where they can read on my car
outside the parking lot with the camera
yeah that's how [ __ ] smooth those
cameras are they were reading VIN
numbers on cars like people really don't
understand the level of regulations
those cameras go up at a hundred feet
all the way around the perimeter of the
building all the way like a hundred feet
seriously I'm not even kidding we go all
the way to the street and [ __ ] that's
when you hear about a dispensary getting
robbed in Colorado you hear about the
arrest the guy who did it like an hour
and a half late right yeah oh boy and
it's funny because if somebody smokes
anywhere near the building our security
guards damn near run outside with their
gun in their hand you cannot smoke on
our premises
but if you cannot smoke anything
anywhere near our dispensary guys we
can't have I've mentioned this before
excuse my burping we cannot have I'm a
medical marijuana patient and I cannot
have my any of my medical marijuana
products in my private vehicle on my
work shift in my car parked in the
parking lot at the dispensary
I have to wait till I get home I have to
drive home and dab hard after work
because I can't have this [ __ ] there
anything that might be seen as odd
consumption could cost the shop its
license right we can't carry our
beverages ah I can't as uh as a guy that
works in the back I can take my bottle
mine but my Dr Pepper after lunch I can
take that back to the back of the
building but they will not let me take
my drink into the bud room when I go
visit Mike what I'm chatting him up what
I'm taking a pee break
Mike if you say you were a customer and
you spilled that [ __ ] in a jar weed
I couldn't even charge you for what you
just ruined because you're from that's
shitty oh and so if you're from Texas
and you spill your your water into it
sharra weed the Scottie house is a weed
in it the shops gotta eat a lot of money
hey that's my job ouch so can you take
your water bottle back there anything
only if it's got a lid okay just a water
bottle and then like keep it well the
[ __ ] away
pretty sure I've seen a couple of water
bottles back by that window well alright
cool so yeah it's strict you guys what
I'm getting at is there is no hanging
out smoking pot being lazy having fun
the only time I get to groove and have a
good time is when I'm pushing a broom or
a mop like I will catch myself shaking
my ass cuz I got mean we played we
played loud music in the back and
there's good music up front most of the
time so there's good music going on is
one of the best parts but the only time
you get to chill out and have fun is on
launch breaks horror sometimes we have a
little team meetings and [ __ ] which are
fun but it's hard work working at a
dispensary
if you come here to work in the industry
be ready to put in work put in work yeah
don't never stops yeah should I go in
nine ish just depends on the day so
between 8 and 10 just depends on
honestly how busy we're gonna be what
I've got to do I know what I've got to
do right now wish I was gonna take but
sometimes we leave there we've left at 7
o'clock before we've done it at 9:00 in
the morning we've got an 8 and left at 7
[Music]
you can't close up there until the time
in the back we can pretty much work but
we just got to finish the job there's a
lot of [ __ ] to do in the best sometimes
it's just what happens in the legal
industry like there's work to be done
and it's got to get done by somebody and
politics a lot of work what a planning
planning for us in the back people come
here with just the craziest expectations
and it's [ __ ] a lot of people if
you're one of those guys that quits a
job all the time if you're one of those
guys who can't show up on time if you're
one of the guys that makes excuses
you're not gonna make it in the
marijuana time yeah you gotta look
professional you gotta take care of
yourself here you guys this may sound
like [ __ ] but this is the truth for
every one dude that is hireable there
are seven women that are hireable that
are way more attractive than you so if
you're a dude and you're trying to get a
job in the industry you gotta get your
[ __ ] together because women sell more
weed so it's already a an uphill battle
for a lot of you dudes clean up yeah
always resume resume
all right you [ __ ] um let's see we've
been going for 40 minutes holy crap um
so this is like the longest news article
summation we didn't even different
places with this I like this podcast it
felt right um so just to get slightly
back on top let's do the thing that
pisses me off the most about this whole
legal pot causes an increase in
homelessness nonsense is like one of the
big reasons Puebla is experiencing a lot
more homeless people right now looking
for services or people on the brink of
being homeless
Services is because all of the cities
around us
currently bust homeless people out of
their area that's the only way they've
got to deal with it if Posada could have
anything they wanted right now it would
be millions more funding so that they
could send everybody back home and
there's a small reason for that like if
you send everybody home hopefully
they've got family friends people in the
community that they know and can make
contact with to help them get back on
their feet like somewhere where they're
tied to the community a little bit
rather than here where they're strangers
to everybody right but most places are
just like hey guess what I hear this
place it the way that you probably can't
get back to without a lot of help is
banging you should go there here's the
bus ticket there for free bro they've
got like everything you need um I had a
guy asked me for a ride that one day and
I probably would have told him no except
the place he was asking to go was like a
block and a half from where I was headed
and I took a look at him and he looked
totally [ __ ]
but like recently like his clothes were
clean but he looked like he had the
worst day after the worst month ever and
I was like all right dude I can give you
a ride to where I'm already going I've
like got like 150 pounds on you even if
you pull like a real [ __ ] loaded
weapon on me I've got this especially in
a car like if I can reach you it's I win
and his little story just wrecked me
like he had a serious medical condition
he was in Albuquerque and they were like
dude didn't you hear
Pueblo got it for you they've got like
free services for you with your [ __ ] and
I'll take real good care of you and the
community is gonna love you and they'll
get you a house and a job and [ __ ]
get you on your feet and this is Pueblo
they're talking about we don't got [ __ ]
off for anybody
unless you're looking to invest a couple
of million dollars in a numeric form
like what I don't got what you're
looking for it's cheap to live - we've
got the Colorado unemployment rates like
four point something it's one of the
lower and the lowest in the nation but
Pueblo unemployment rate is like five
and a half or six like a good point and
a half higher than the rest of the state
and when you magnify that times the
amount of people that are in the state
like it's a huge huge chunk of the jobs
like there's a lot of people that came
here looking for work that are just
[ __ ] [ __ ] out of luck now yeah cuz
they came with no plan but we're trying
to pin it on legal pot when there's like
30 different reasons homeless people and
people about to be homeless ready to
Pueblo you can Trancas the cheap like
the third cheapest city in the US and
expect that [ __ ] not to have
concentrations which varies in every
newspaper in the country you know what I
did not plan poorly huh this dab don't
get it let's do this you guys I'm gonna
hit the dab I'm hitting the [ __ ] hit
man the sampson hitman combo collab reg
highly-educated d nail on it that runs
to the gmail from emo tech shout-out to
giddy up task let's do this keep going
while i dad don't worry about Posada
oh I don't have anything against Posada
except there being nuts on this issue
they're getting national press talking
about how it's all marijuana's fault and
then if you read the article you'll get
about 3/4 of the way through when they
mentioned like other cities busting
homeless people here and straight lying
to them when I put them on the bus Don
Pablo's great and up level being ranked
the cheapest city in the u.s. tons of
people moving here sure that 3 or 4 of
them are gonna get jobs in the marijuana
industry only to find out that we don't
take felons
I mean multiple multiple that they just
don't publicize any of the requirements
anywhere outside of this podcast
basically right yeah so that's your
public service announcement you guys
make sure you google that [ __ ] make sure
you can find out if you're even
qualified to work in our industry and if
you're going if you're coming here to
run an illegal industry I'm not even
trying to be a smartass I was deep [ __ ]
into the illegal cannabis industry I can
admit it now I could talk about that you
know what I had to get away from it
because it wasn't gonna work much longer
I was gonna go downhill trying to stay
on that side of the world now I've got a
steady job everything is legit it's much
easier you guys it's much easier and the
illegal industry is going away you can
see it crumbling here those people that
are too stubborn to come to the light
you can see them struggling and
dwindling and falling off I saw it a
couple of years ago the people I knew
that we're living right on that the edge
but between the black and the white
market like the what you'd call the gray
market the more stores that opened up
the harder it was to compete with them I
mean the guy that had one strain for you
in March come July would show up a seven
by December there was a selection hash
in his bag too and by January it was
just too much of a [ __ ] hassle
regardless of the selection because you
could just go to a store and pick right
like you never had to hang out and not
seem like foot traffic or any of that
meet somebody somewhere how much how
many episodes of how it's made would
never have been watched
if we could just buy weed in stores
Deadliest Catch what I've never been
viewed Yeah right viewership on a lot of
[ __ ] would go way down if you didn't
have to hang out with your weed dealer
for two hours so you didn't seem like
you were there buying weed this dude is
just really really bored and a lot of
his friends come to visit for two hours
at a chunk I guess yeah like it's just
so much more convenient even when you
get to the shop and you're like really
that's the price [ __ ] taxes like you
start wondering how much your time's
worth like how many hours that I spent
sitting on the couch listening to
[ __ ] because I was
by a bag of weed and that was the best
way down because every weed dealer wants
to show you his new thing that he bought
with your money but you did you redo man
anything but more [ __ ] Deadliest
Catch yeah I don't know why used to get
stoned and watch the [ __ ] out of
Deadliest Catch that's really weird it's
it's fun which one's gonna get squashed
by a crab cage next I'm gonna write
myself a note here this is not show
related watch more Deadliest Catch no I
record another podcast and have a
Deadliest Catch story that I want to
tell on that podcast this weird dream
story on this podcast I mean this shows
almost a [ __ ] hour long I got my
wisdom teeth removed and they gave me
vicodin then I took too many of them I
fell asleep watching Deadliest Catch
okay that's like the main setup here I
woke up in a dream that I caught
somebody trying to kill people on The
Deadliest Catch boat and I murdered him
cuz he was trying to kill me and in
self-defense I killed him on the [ __ ]
cuz he killed everybody else on the boat
but then I realized everybody on the
boat is dead but me I think I did this
[ __ ] and I'm all covered in blood the
boats all covered in blood so I gotta
get the [ __ ] out of here then I wake up
and since I took too many vicodin before
I fell asleep I woke up I didn't really
wake up I'm still dreaming but I was
physically sitting up in real life but
in dream life I was still in my boat and
I saw blood all over my house and it
took me a good I don't really know but
I'm gonna say like three or four minutes
of like shaking my head around and
walking around my bedroom going why is
there blood everywhere what the [ __ ] is
happening and then finally the blood
faded away and I woke up don't too many
fight
don't do too many vicodin kids that's my
it's my [ __ ] theory but I had my
wisdom teeth taken out they [ __ ] hurt
dude that [ __ ] sucks okay I was kind of
listening but while I was listening I
had a thought okay let's hear this has
been rambling is [ __ ] so if you're still
listening I'll go ahead and pay to send
you a sticker pack or some [ __ ] if you
tweet me I like it when you ramble all
right you guys and then tag [ __ ]
drove from your heart podcast in it as
well so you have to if there's a whole
bunch you a whole bunch of people still
listening and I get a shitload of tweets
about it
I'll we'll pick like three and I'll pay
to get shoes
we got stickers we get plenty of
stickers I don't know that they'll what
they'll be but we've got stickers I've
got so many sponsors and vendors and
friends that we I've got really cool
some grassroot stickers I read genetic
stickers I Heart dab stickers we got
plenty of stickers so it's Nemo punk 15
you have to tweet at Nemo punk 15 and @g
fyh podcast with hash tag I like it when
you ramble yep and then I will contact
you to get your mailing information yep
all right you guys don't forget to do
that [ __ ] stickers it's free stickers
it's free stuff for listening this long
because this is kind of what everywhere
yes they do since Mike Mike's giving
away [ __ ] I'm gonna wrap up the show
before he starts giving away more [ __ ]
[Music]
thank you for listening episode 102 you
guys holy [ __ ] yeah whoa this is weird
you guys we need some sponsors for the
show glass they do not sponsor the show
but you know what they keep me dab the
[ __ ] out since we're doing shots like
that also shout out to highly educated
titanium task rock what's up homie big
ol fist bump and also since we're there
shout out to see furniture company for
the emails also shout out to emo tech
for the other email those all those
companies together keep me Dad the [ __ ]
out you guys I use those companies
products on a daily case Pelle case you
know the Pelican case we're listing fun
[ __ ] in the room
dr. pepper no they don't pay us dude
stop none of those people pay us for any
of that they're delicious without them
we could not do this that's true that's
a little baby how's that yeah product
review what I would like you to do is
sue me a product that you want us to
review it'll send it back to you if you
want if you want us to keep it sure as
[ __ ] we'll don't worry but I'd like you
to send us some products Mike and I will
unbox it here on the show we will review
it and we'll talk about it on the show
we'll be honest check it out we'll smoke
hash they're almost smoked weed through
it that is the truth we'll let the world
know and then we'll send it back to you
if you want only knows how big and wide
dis audience ranges right it could be
neat send us your products guys mostly
looking for cannabis related stuff but
will pretty much review anything you
want to send us that is true that is
true we like hats and shirts of [ __ ] to
definitely if you got some pen Dee's
that you need mourn and seem on
Instagram
shout out to ghost cat glass this just
became the [ __ ] shadow [ __ ] the BT
wars over here find me on all this
goddamn social media sites I'm on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast I'm on
Facebook girl from your heart on
Instagram you guys it's I read genetics
we're almost in nineteen thousand
followers get up on it get up on it
don't forget you guys the show's
available on iTunes the show is
available on stitcher and every single
episode is always and forever archived
on I read genetics Colorado com that is
my website they'll never take that away
from us let me apologize about the
quality of I read genetics Colorado calm
that is under construction my friend is
a college student we work on that when
he's not in college let the man get an
education that's first and when he's not
there he'll come over and we'll work on
the website go to school Tony
do your thing don't worry about it we
got your back brother all right if
you're in a position to hire somebody
who needs to work like a couple of weeks
a year I like it when you ramble yep all
right you guys I'm gonna wrap up this
show thanks again to Mike for coming
thanks to everybody for listen and what
the hell does tickle my arm
let the spider thump the guy that scared
the [ __ ] outta me over there that was
curious so high your body cares about
your dreadlocks again just tickled that
was strange anyway you guys weird AB the
[ __ ] out I hope you had a lot of fun
with us hashtag I like it when you
ramble get your sticker pack
[Music]
what's a podcast world a true Boy Rasta
Jeff coming to you live from the car on
Interstate 25 that's right I just left
the champs trade show I thought it'd be
a good idea to jump on the microphone
and do a little bit of recording while
it's still fresh in my mind so today I
went to the Chams trade show in Denver
it was a beautiful Drive it takes me
about two hours to get up to Denver
it took me about another 20 minutes to
find a good parking spot anyway I got a
good parking spot I messaged a good
friend of mine who had a pass for me we
met up and he got me a pass for champs
he gave me a high-five and told me to
have a good time he had [ __ ] to do so he
sent me on my way and I headed into the
Champs trade show you guys I am failing
you right now because I seriously don't
know what champs stands for champs is an
acronym for something I don't know what
it means
ch a.m. PS it means something about
glass and tradeshow because what it was
was a trade show based on glass cannabis
and it's some of that [ __ ] set for
tobacco use only but tobacco and
cannabis smoking accessories I saw
so basically it's all your [ __ ] that is
available at all the head shops that you
go to depending on the quality of your
head shop but it was all there all that
plastic shitty Chinese smoking
accessories stuff was all there all the
shitty Chinese knockoff glass was there
all of the shitty knockoff nail
companies were there but also some of
our good friends were there you guys I
got to visit the Hitman booth if I was
man if I didn't walk away from the
Hitman booths today I was going to spend
a lot of money with hitman they had two
rigs that I was really interested in
they had the mini they have the new I
forgot they call him - call him a sundae
stack or something like that it's not
the sundae cup but it's this little
snack thing the mini stack holy [ __ ]
they got they had water in it let me
pull through it that thing felt like it
would hit like a champ unfortunately you
guys there was no consumption in this
venue we were not allowed to smoke any
type of cannabis we couldn't dab there
was actually somebody pressing out rosin
dabs he had a rosin press if you know
about rosin it's made by squishing your
buds between two heated surfaces using
parchment in the middle as a way to
catch your hash he was pressing out
rosin right there for you so you could
bring your nugs and get him squished is
what they were calling it some people
were taking dabs of that right after
they would squish it although it was
frowned upon and if you got caught they
would escort you out of the building so
anyway I met up with the hitman crew I
fell in love with a couple of rigs they
had a mini sidecar rig with a blue label
the Blue Label was beautiful it's my
favorite color
my exact favorite color blue
unfortunately I just bought the same rig
with a yellow label so I could not bring
myself to spend another 150 dollars on a
rig although one hundred and fifty
dollars on that rig was a steal I just
didn't want to buy a copy of a rig that
I have already God did not make sense to
me anyway so I had to walk away before I
bought the sunday stack and before I
bought the blue mini sidecar
they had a bunch of great rigs at the
Hitman booth also I made friends with a
bunch of people
I also got to bump into our crew with
oil slick Josh Boyle slick and the oil
slick crew was there in full force they
sent me home with the sample of the I
forget the official name of it I've been
calling it the bond condom it's actually
a it's basically a condom you put on the
mouthpiece of your bong so that if
you're at a large party or an event you
can swap those out so that not everybody
has to get the do we call it the cup
cough or the hook flu so they gave me a
couple of those to check out right
across from our friends at oil slick was
our good friends at handmade apparel big
shout out to the entire handmade and oil
slick family thanks for coming out to
Colorado thanks for showing everybody
how to run a booth hit champs cuz you
guys do it right you guys are great
people great people in the industry
great service so you guys make sure you
support oil slick and handmade apparel
and also hit man glass also I made a
little stop at the highly educated
titanium a little booth there and I
picked up a couple of highly educated
titanium products task was not in the
building but he had his uh his cronies
work informally do a great job so shout
out to those guys make sure you support
highly educated titanium I know it
sounds like a big bunch of shout outs
but I was at an event where there are a
bunch of vendors you guys so these guys
took care of me they're our products and
I support so shout out to all of them so
uh it's basically you guys have to be a
swap meet of supplies for your head shop
and I saw every kind of pipe in bong and
hash rig and nail you could imagine
every type of hash container you could
imagine there was not a lot of growing
accessories or gross supplies or
anything like that it was all basically
aimed at supplying your head shop with
good quality glass so I've got a list of
people here that I got to hang out with
today before I even open up the list I
don't even need to think about it as I
walked out of my car I walked up to no
soon as I walked into the event I was
greeted by a guy by the name of Scott
reach he walked up to me and shook my
hand asked how I was doing you guys that
is rare dankness one of the most popular
seed companies in the world right now
for Scott to walk up and know who I was
kind of blew my mind to tell you the
truth I got a few feet into the building
and then I ran into the man himself the
kosher stoner adam mca' doshas our good
friend adam hill big shout out to Adam
mill it was good seeing Adam hill I got
to hang out that him for a few minutes
have a quick conversation
Adam was hungry so he took off we were
supposed to link up for turps later
we'll talk more about that I ended up
having to drive home I don't I didn't
have to drive home dinner was at 7:00 it
was seven o'clock we're still at Hunt's
house taking dabs I figured we want to
go in to dinner till 7:30 which means I
would have been there until 8:00 I don't
know I've been there till 9:00 maybe
9:30 it's a two-hour drive from there
they would have put me home around 11:30
or midnight I couldn't deal with that
I've got to work in the morning so I had
to split out from dinner
but anyway shout out to John Hunt shot
it's a Hannah Miller shot at Oh Carly
big shout-out to everybody who invited
me to dinner I apologize for not being
able to make it next time guys for sure
I went to champs today on a whim I
wasn't even supposed to go to champs
this was a poorly planned trip but I'm
gonna call it a hell of a success you
guys so I was walking through champs and
I spied one of the most beautiful women
I have ever laid my eyes upon the lovely
Miss Charlo Greene was in the building
if you guys don't know who Charlo Greene
is she is a cannabis activists activists
from Alaska and she's actually the lady
who was known for saying [ __ ] it I quit
on the news she was at champs and she
was here in Denver
oh my gosh you guys usually I am cool
calm and collected I must move
[ __ ] I'm not afraid to talk to
anybody I'll walk up to anybody and say
hello I'll walk into the restricted
access area and act like I own that [ __ ]
I'm not a shy guy but for some reason
when I saw Miss Charlo Greene something
inside of me [ __ ] melted ah
hey guys charlo is more beautiful in
person than she has ever looked online
on Facebook on the internet on Twitter
on Instagram whatever you saw her on she
is even more beautiful in person and her
personality is sassy and stunning so I'm
walking toward her and she spotted me
and she reached out and put her hand on
my shoulder and said hey you and she
knew who I was which was kind of weird
I've stalked her on Facebook and said
hello but she has no reason to know who
rhasta Jeff is so I was a little excited
by that that made me a little spellbound
it made me feel like a high school boy
so I stopped and I asked her if I could
give her a hug and she said oh of course
and we talked for a couple of minutes
and you guys I went stupid I did not
have [ __ ] proper to say to that
beautiful lady I couldn't decide if I
wanted to just be like a normal dude and
talked to her or if I wanted to go into
like business guy mode or if I wanted to
be podcast guy my brain fluttered that
woman is beautiful oh my god big
shout-out to Charlo Greene if you listen
to this yes I'm gushing over you you're
the most beautiful damn woman I have
seen in a long time holy [ __ ] blew my
mind honey she's tall you guys I'm six
foot five of course she was wearing some
heels but she is tall hold on there's a
cop right next to me he might pull me
over yes I am talking into a microphone
while driving down the interstate this
cop is right next to me you guys he's
like staring at me he's like what are
you doing I didn't pull me over that was
awesome
okay anyway Charlo Greene I'm six foot
five Charlo Greene of course was wearing
some heels but she was nearly as tall as
me I posted a selfie to Instagram and
you guys will be able to see if you
check that out check it out I read
genetics on Instagram she is tall and I
said damn honey you were tall and I put
my arm around her we took a selfie cuz
I'm a big girl and I love it and I said
me too and I went silent I was like well
I've got a shop down in Pueblo you
should come check that out and if I see
you at the party later tonight we'll dab
and of course I'm not going to the party
because I do have to work in the morning
I was really thinking about going to the
party but uh I can't it'll kill me I
will hate life tomorrow and I've got to
be a productive dude I've got [ __ ] to
handle trying to be a grown-ass man so
let's see I've got a list of people that
I wanted to make sure I gave a shout out
to we covered hunt hunt john hunt you're
a bad [ __ ] you are the Terp
gatherer you are may you're the brother
dude here the man I like it
big shoutout much respect to John Hunt
the Grammy Gatsby that's my boy that's
my partner in crime I like hanging out
with that dude he he kind of encouraged
me to come up to champs he let me hang
out he kind of encouraged he kind of
made it happen it's your fault you let
me hang out at the house afterward and
stop and take some tabs at the Turf
station thanks for let me come to the
dojo bro I appreciate it shout out to
hunt also shout it to Adam ill
don't know Adam hill you got to learn
about animal animal he had a podcast I
don't think he's doing that he's now
working with be real on be real TV
so Adam Hill the guy that goes whoa make
sure you check him out he's cool that's
my homie shout out to Adam Hill Terp
champ who else we got on the list I'm
driving you guys we got hit man we got
oil slick we got handmade apparel we got
highly educated titanium we gave a big
shout out to Charlo Greene god I just
want to take a second to think about
that one shoutout charlo alright also
big shout out to Tim and Zak and the
entire crew from New Mexico you guys my
friend Tim is from New Mexico he's part
of the New Mexico medical marijuana
movement my friend zach is a patient
today I met their grower and another one
of their friends I can't remember both
of their names one dude was named cedar
the other guy his name was left in my
head it was a normal guy name honestly
possibly Tyler but it's been a while and
I've taken a few dabs his name is left
my head I apologize it's [ __ ] rude
but shout out to those guys they were a
lot of fun to hang out with they got me
into the event we got to hang out for a
little bit and I will probably see them
on their way home because I live between
Denver and New Mexico so stop in and
take some dabs you guys I can't wait
let's see dude I bumped into a young man
by the name of Tim Martin Tim Martin is
the host of the John Doe radio show if
you don't listen to the JD our John Doe
radio show give that a listen yes I am
shouting out another cannabis podcast
but we are not competing we're friends
we do totally different shows they're
from Denver I'm from Pueblo we have
different views on things we agree on a
lot of things but I'm just saying it's
two totally different shows there's no
competition I fully support what Tim
Martin is doing Tim Martin's a great
dude Tim and I actually talked about
doing a couple of shows together so in
the very near future I will be traveling
back to Denver I will be on the John Doe
radio show stay tuned for that I'll let
you know what it happens you can listen
also we will get Tim Martin to come be
on the growth from your heart podcast
you guys know that I've got the zoom h6
I feel like I can take the show anywhere
I did not record anything today I had
felt rude I didn't even think about
taking my gear in there because it felt
rude walking around I just wanted to say
hi to my friends and hang out
and not be that interview guy in the
future I will do that if there's a
two-day event I'll walk around one day
and be friendly I'll walk around the
next day with the microphone there's
more fun just catching up with the crew
this time you guys so big shout out to
Tim Martin make sure you guys support
John Doe radio I don't know where to
tell you to go look for that it's
probably on iTunes the conversation that
him and I had today leads me to believe
that his podcast is on iTunes all right
who else do we owe a shout-out to you
guys I bumped into a glassblower he's my
friend he's from North Carolina he now
resides in the great city of Pueblo
Colorado
he's a glassblower that is on the rise
on Instagram he is known as at barefoot
glass
his name's Will he's a great dude make
sure you support that guy I am going to
get him and his friend Blake on the
podcast we were gonna talk about
glassblowing the glassblowing industry I
plan on having that dude on the show
that is going to be great so big shout
out to my buddy will at barefoot glass
for hanging out with me entertaining me
for a few minutes at the event that was
a good time always good to see we'll
what up well hope you listen bro shout
out shout out to your bro that I met
also I want to remember that his name
was Blake but like I said earlier that
was several hours and several dabs ago
I'm trying to get you guys my review of
champs well it's a little bit fresh in
my head and it's also filled with
shoutouts one more important shout out I
was walking through the event and I came
across a young man who calls himself Fox
extracts what up Fox I hope you listen
to the podcast it was great meeting you
and your lovely girlfriend and your
puppy big scratch to the puppy on their
tummy scratch that dog Fox is a lot of
great [ __ ] coming up with CBD you guys
we talked about something for about a
minute and it had me completely
intrigued Fox is now in Colorado he's in
Colorado Springs one time this week and
I am going to do my best to link up with
him and get him to talk into a
microphone for you and share you some
ideas that he's got he's got some
amazing [ __ ] happening I cannot wait for
you guys to get to hear it so I think
that's all of this shout outs I've got a
guy gave me an edible to try but I'm not
going to do a shout out on that or any
review until I'm able to sit down and
look at the packaging and eat it right
now I'm driving on Interstate 25 going
about 70 miles an hour there's nobody
else out on the interstate it's just me
it's a Wednesday night it's pretty
I'm actually driving through monument
right now shout out to the city of
monument and shout out to that cop that
didn't pull me over a few miles back I'm
full-on talking into a microphone and
that cop did not pull me over
that's pretty killer so let's see I
think I've done all these shout outs I
apologize if I missed anybody
it's nothing personal big shout out to
Adam hand for throwing me a pin big
shout-out to everybody that I hung out
with today I apologize if I skipped you
I want to move on to this next part you
guys I was gifted from a vendor a jeep
in mini disposable is called the Jeep in
disposable vaporizer it's got a battery
already in it you're supposed to use it
until it dies and then you're supposed
to throw it away so it's got
instructions of press the button five
times to turn it on unscrew the
mouthpiece lows load with your desired I
think it said essential oil as what it
said on the packaging and then it said
screw on the cap and then it said press
the button and inhale so I was gifted
this it's a yellow Jeep in disposable
it's the concentrate version I have
followed the instructions i unscrewed I
loaded I turned it on I screwed it back
together now you guys we were going to
press the button and we're going to
inhale and we're going to see what kind
of drawers we get off of the Jeep in
disposable let's check it out right now
here we go
so it's dead silent I know it's shitty
for podcasting but I loaded it with New
York City diesel live resin that I got
from Spence from the garden of Weeden
big shout out to Spence and it tastes
really good but honestly I didn't get a
bit of smoke it's lighting up like it
should let's try this again let's give
it another Pole
so honestly I just got some hash in my
mouth which tastes really good but
there's no smoke and it's not working
the way that you would really expect a
hash pen to work I packed it down
properly it comes with a little uh a
little pokers he can live resin in my
mouth I came with a little poker so that
you could pack it down in there and it's
packed down in there it's pressed
against the coil I've used plenty of
hash pins in my day and this one so far
two hits in I'm ready to throw it out
the [ __ ] window if I hadn't loaded it
up with some decent New York City live
resin it would be out the window the car
by now so what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
hold it up right to where the hash will
melt into the coil when I press the
button and I'm gonna let it melt for a
couple of seconds I'm doing that it's
lit up it seems to be doing its thing so
now I'm hoping that I've melted the hash
down gravity wise into the coil and I'm
gonna hold it to where it you know what
I mean right it's where the [ __ ] hash
is melting into the coil while I hit it
I'm gonna give it a give it a third try
and we're gonna see how this goes so
excuse me for one second you'll get more
silence but I'm gonna try this hopefully
we don't end up with hashing out my
throat while I'm driving
no smoke and a little more hash in my
mouth so we will try this again on an
episode at home when we're in the house
to where we're not driving in the car
trying to do this but so far the
disposable Jeep in I find it to be a
fail I think you press it five times to
turn it off let's see one two three four
or five they flashed and went off I'm
gonna set that in the seat next to me
next to the microphone case and we're
gonna say fail on that for now you guys
got to take a quick drink so I have a
bunch of chunks of wax stuck in my teeth
you know live resin in my mouth so we've
been going for a few minutes give me
just one second I'm gonna set down the
microphone all I did this out but I need
to take a drink hold on I got because of
that pin I've got melted wax in my teeth
hold on here we go
[Music]
all right I might edit a few seconds of
that out I apologize guys I'd take a
drink there's nothing like having hash
smeared across your two front teeth that
was weird
all right so where was I I was talking
about the champs trade show right you
guys champs trade show was at the Denver
Convention Center it was free they make
it seem like you need to be some sort of
a vendor or have some sort of a license
to get in there but honestly I don't
have why do I have an LLC in [ __ ] but I
walked up and said hey I'm here and they
said what company are you with
and I said I was with my buddy Tim
didn't even say anything I said I'm with
organic ax and they looked at Tim and
Tim's with organic ax and so they said
what's your name and I said Rasta Jeff
and she wrote my name on a little tag
and handed it to me no questions asked
it didn't cost me anything champs is a
free event if you're in the industry if
not all you gotta do is have a good
reason to be there and tell them that
that's why you're there if you have like
a wholesale license or something like
that you can definitely get in if not
you've got a friend that has a way to
get you into champs if you want to cook
want to go it's free which is a good
thing because it's not really worth a
whole bunch of money to walk through
there if it was like a five dollar
ticket I wouldn't complain I was a cool
event there's nowhere to sit down it's
illegal to medicate in the building it's
illegal to consume cannabis in the
building you can't even hit a vape pen
they did not like that of course like I
said there were a couple of people
taking a couple of rosin dabs but they
would have been escorted out had they
been caught um it was a great event it
was fun I had a good time the best part
for me honestly was linking up with a
bunch of people from the industry I
would up Anthony would have Johnny be
sorry I forgot you guys I did not mean
to skip you I apologize we spent some
time together hanging out and I almost
[ __ ] spaced it you know why because
our conversation was just friendly and
natural it wasn't something that had to
be documented it was just a good
conversation which I love so shout out
to also uh Jonathan Kent yeah Jonathan
dude and and Dan that's who was with
John yeah they a whole bunch of people
saw me I was I saw them it was fun
hanging out that was my favorite part
was meeting up with people and shaking
hands and seeing everybody was a really
really good time so it's a great place
to go if you're in the industry and you
know a few people you can buy a lot of
great glass at very great
counted prices I saw some beautiful
beautiful glass but you guys honestly
I'm not into buying really artful glass
lately I've been buying what they call
production work and functional glass is
just clear and hits like a champ I hate
it when I spend hundreds to a thousand
dollars on a nice rig hold on I gotta
put the microphone down here cuz the car
just gonna be one second alright I just
didn't want that car to see me talking
into the mic
I hate it when you spend a lot of money
or your friends spend a lot of money on
a rig and you can only put like a really
certain amount of water in there because
one drop more it splashes it in your
mouth and one drop less it doesn't perk
right I found that to be really annoying
on a custom-made piece so I buy
production pieces that are clear and I
think they hit like a [ __ ] champ you
guys I think there's nothing wrong with
having a clear rig you don't even need
to spend a lot of money on a rig you
guys you could have spent 40 bucks on a
really nice rig today and been set up
you could have got a highly-educated
titanium male and a carb cap for a
really good price champs is a great
place if you're looking to come up on a
rig or two or if you've got a wholesale
license it was really the place to buy a
whole bunch of [ __ ] alright so also shot
at the grass roots grass roots was there
set up in style yeah so for a free event
it was really a good time it was a great
day in Denver it rained a little bit but
they didn't slow anybody down most of
the vendors that I really appreciated
seeing will be at the Cannabis Cup in
Denver or excuse me I'm burpin they'll
be at the Cannabis Cup in Denver in
April if that happens there's rumors
that that may not happen I'm not gonna
start talking [ __ ] about it on the show
but there have been rumors that that
won't happen let's hope that it does
most of those vendors will be available
and present at the Cannabis Cup in full
force if there's a cannabis cup in your
area I bet those vendors will be there
make sure you look out for oil slick get
an oil slick pad keep your table from
getting all [ __ ] sticky check out hit
man glass hit man makes really good
glass that hits like a truck every
[ __ ] time when you get a new glass
what do you need you need a new nail who
do you go for for that you go to highly
educated titanium you get yourself a
nail I like a domeless nail on a carb
cap I think that's the way to go
then you need some cool ass t-shirts who
do you get your t-shirts printed through
you go to handmade apparel there's
another car on the highway let's just
get behind them in crew
for a little while so they don't see me
talking into a microphone yeah guys I am
driving on the interstate we're now
approaching Woodman Road in the
beautiful city of Colorado Springs
Colorado let's see I've been recording
for 22 minutes I should pay attention
more to the road and the recording but
I'm the only one out here other than
this guy in front of me gonna get passed
by a truck here we go all right
so yeah I've got a bunch of great [ __ ]
planned for more episodes you guys I'm
just gonna put this out as a Thursday
episode or oh yeah bonus Thursday
episode this will not be your Monday
primary episode
I just wanted to ramble for a little bit
while I was driving see if I could
actually do a car podcast never thought
of that before now that I've got this
nice gear I felt it would be necessary
you guys I've got an episode coming up
Monday I think Monday we are going to
talk about ways reasons why your
cannabis is not top-shelf in ways that
you can improve your cannabis and make
it top-shelf I wouldn't take a whole lot
foremost do you guys just upgrade your
grow just a little bit it won't cost you
money it will cost you more time energy
effort and attention which we all should
have I've got an episode about CBD
planned I think I have an episode with
Fox planned I have an episode about
blowing glass and the glass industry
coming up with our friend will and I'm
going to try to get a whole bunch of
grow lessons planned out so got some
great [ __ ] in my mind you guys are gonna
love it I want to thank you guys for
listening to this short car episode I'm
gonna get off the microphone I don't
have anything else left to say I
appreciate you guys I love you guys
every day like my own adopted children I
will be back Monday with the full
episode don't judge me by the quality
this episode you guys have recorded this
in the car while driving after the
chance trade show in Denver so until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 104 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber here at cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friend is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I'm - thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to the mystic
roots fans for letting me use their
music on my show
big thanks to Cab
back in the studio you guys and I
putting this episode out as a regular
Monday episode so good morning hope
you're having a great Monday
sometimes Monday's can be a real [ __ ]
so I hope I make it a little bit better
with the fresh episode of the girl from
your heart podcast if it's not Monday
for you whenever you're listening to
this I hope you're having a great day I
hope you've got a fat joint rolled hope
you got a blunt roll have you got a DAB
ready have you got a fall packs
look you got the vaporizer filled up I
hope you got something going on maybe
you're eating some edibles maybe you're
using some cannabis lubrication or
possibly a cannabis suppository whatever
it is I hope it's working great for you
I hope you're working in the garden hope
you're driving in the car whatever
you're doing I'm hoping that I'm making
your day a little bit better thanks for
joining me guys I'm back in the studio
last time I was on I did an episode from
the car and I did a review on the Jeep
in slim disposable vaporizer
I used the concentrate version you know
when I was in the car I gave this thing
kind of a shitty review but let me tell
you that was a preemptive strike I got
home and I looked at it a little bit all
I had to do was passion pack the hash in
a little bit harder press it down and
heat it up a little bit and it actually
gave me quite a few fat rips so I'm
going to what is it called withdraw my
my shitty review of this product and I'm
going to update it I'm going to give it
like 4 out of 5 stars for a vape pen
that's disposable this is probably the
best quality we're gonna find so like 4
out of 5 stars because for a DAB
wacks hit or a concentrate hit I prefer
a rig you need a rig for five stars but
it's a good product if you're in
Colorado and you're picking up some
concentrates and you need something to
smoke it through these little yellow
vape pens that you're gonna throw away
when you're done I think these are an
affordable and economical deal so I
apologize for the shitty review my
updated review says it's a quality
product all right so the whole nation a
shout out everybody in America this is
for you guys
Halloween just passed and guess how many
people reported finding cannabis laced
candy and their children's Halloween
basket nobody that's right there were
zero reports of cannabis laced can be
given out for Halloween this year so a
big shout out we did the same shout out
last year but I wanted to do it again
cuz you're doing a good job you guys
please don't ever give children animals
anybody cannabis infused candy without
their knowledge if your pets using it
for medicine I'll do that with
discretion I can't judge you there they
do make medicine for your dog now it's
infused with cannabis but don't do it
just to get your dog [ __ ] up that's
rude you guys keep us on a good streak
keep the recreational cannabis going
well for us
alright so shout out so you guys I was
at the champs trade show if you listen
to the other episode I'm sure you heard
about that but I was at the trade show
over the weekend I was actually during
the week there's a really tight-knit
really close little community that
travels around to all of the cannabis
shows and they set up their booths and
they take great care of the customers
and the community and they really
represent the cannabis movement the
cannabis product movement the cannabis
industry and a positive light I just
want to give a big shout out to all
those people they know who they are I
don't need to point them out
specifically if you were part of that
cannabis movement that comes to the
events that goes through the events that
is part of the product development the
advancement of the products if you're
there show in your face if we see each
other and high-five each other and don't
even have to talk you're part of the
crew that I'm talking about if we see
each other and just nod at each other
because we've seen so many tons seen
each other so many times you're part of
the crew I'm talking about you guys make
these events happen and we kind of rely
on you I've noticed a bit I find myself
hovering and lingering at those boots
that you're there all the time because
we've become comfortable we've become
friends and you guys are also leaders
and you're teaching the other boots and
the other vendors how to do it so a big
shout out much respect to the family
that travels around and does all of the
events and supports each other supports
the movement it's really great to see
you guys every time you show up you're
welcome in Colorado all the time if you
ever need anything when you're in
Colorado let me know and I will do my
best to accommodate you fully much love
and respect to the whole cannabis
community and Industry and also big
shout out to all the people that come
and learn and meet me at greet me and
shake my hand and high-five me and ask
me questions and thank me for my
breeding big shout out to all those
people I really enjoy going to those
events it's really a refreshing time all
right so you guys let's get down to
business here is the topic for the show
today
I've been bumping into people and
they've been talking about why some
people are able to take their cannabis
to the next level and some people are
stuck growing it's not mid grade but
it's still not stellar cannabis so I
thought that I would write down some of
the reasons why your herb not yours but
some herb is not what we would consider
top-shelf product and then we could talk
about a few ways on how to improve that
and get your herb up to the top shelf so
let me work on my list here I got a
couple things written down all right you
guys the main reason I find the cannabis
is not able to be considered top shelf
product is because it has been over
fertilized a lot of people are thinking
that they can add more fertilizer and
feed it more and you're gonna get better
product but actually what you're doing
is you are pumping it full of nutrients
that are gonna affect the flavor it's
gonna be harder to flush that stuff out
in the end everything that you put into
your plants will affect the flavor
another big reason that I find a lot of
cannabis is not able to be considered
top shelf product is that it was not
properly flushed you guys your cannabis
plants need to be flushed for a minimum
of 10 days preferably two full weeks
before harvest so 10 to 14 days before
you plan on cutting down your plants you
need to start watering it with just
clean water pH and about six five get in
there just fill every pot
the whole pot with water so that it's
dripping out of the drain holes a little
bit do that 14 days before harvest and
then let it dry up just like you
normally would and when you're gonna
water again make sure you water it until
it drips out of the pot a little bit and
you don't want to give it any nutrients
for the last 14 days if you're an
experienced grower there are a few
things you can add at the end there but
I wouldn't recommend too many things
unless you really know what you're doing
that's this is where you're really going
to start affecting your flavor so be
careful at the end make sure you flush
for at least 14 days you can go longer
you I don't think you can over flush if
you feel like you start flushing about
14 days before you think you're gonna
harvest and you feel like those plants
can go a few more days don't worry let
them go a few more days they'll be just
fine and they will taste even better let
them finish up let them ripen up let
them flush out let all the nutrients
come out and you'll be okay hey you guys
you may see some yellowing hope for some
yellowing that means you're flushing it
properly that means that you're getting
all the excess nutrients out of the
leaves that are stored in the plants and
you're gonna flush that right on out
that means that there aren't extra
nutrients left in the soil that the
plants eating it means it's eaten all of
its food and it's getting cleaned up and
it's almost time for harvest now I want
to take a step back and say over
fertilization and not flushing are both
possible even when you were using
organics you guys organic nutrients can
still burn your plants organic nutrients
can over fertilize your plants be
careful when using organics you can add
the wrong I mean think about the way
that stuff smells when you're working
with some organics it literally smells
like a pile of [ __ ] if you over
fertilize it they can make your buds
taste like a pile of [ __ ] it is very
possible also not flushing I hear a lot
of people say they don't have to flush
because they used organic nutrients you
need to flush if you're using if you're
using your own like super soil and you
know that you don't need to flush
because you've been flushing the whole
time you're an experienced grower and
you understand that but if you're using
the bottled nutrient or some sort of
organics or those amended soils you're
going to need to flush you guys so make
sure you flush even with organics make
sure you don't over fertilize even with
organics and this can make your cannabis
better if you're using a bottled
nutrient start with about half of what
they recommend on the ball
about half of the dosage rate and then
if you see that you have a deficiency
move up you can correct you can always
add but you can never subtract from what
you fed your planets all right
so don't over fertilize and do flush the
next thing that I see that makes
cannabis not able to be top shelf is a
really poor trim job you would not
believe how much very well grown
cannabis I have seen that would have
been top-shelf
if the grower would have taken just a
little bit more time to make sure to
take all those little tiny leaves off
yours we don't want to see any leaves
when we're looking at the buds we want
to see trichomes we want to see resin we
want to see just just bud so we don't
even want to see any stick at all just a
little tiny stick that sticks out at the
bottom of the bud
that's all that we need so when you're
trim and make sure you take off all
those little tiny pointy leaves get in
there and clean that [ __ ] up cut all the
little sticks out cut your sticks off of
the big gigantic buds and trim your weed
to look like just buds look at a
magazine look online look what good
quality bud looks like and trim it up
like that if you can see an obvious leaf
on there get in there with your scissors
and clip it off get in there to some
nail and knock that off trim your we'd
like connoisseur grade weed and it will
be top-shelf alright
and also wear rubber gloves you guys
when you're trimming your cannabis make
sure that you wear rubber gloves and in
my opinion top-shelf herb is hand
trimmed and not machine trimmed if
you've got machine trimmed bud that one
a cannabis cup I'm impressed ah let's
see what rubber gloves you guys whenever
you're touching these buds whenever
you're touching a product that
somebody's going to smoke make sure you
wear rubber gloves we do not want to
smoke your skin oils I don't want to
hear your skin oil or your skin moisture
sizzling my dab that's just so gross so
trim your weed wear gloves and use
scissors not a trim machine is something
I want to stress alright so another
thing that quite often deters people's
cannabis from being top-shelf product is
a very poor cure a lot of people are
trying to speed dry their cannabis you
guys the slower your buds dry the better
they are going to taste the better they
are going to smoke think about your goal
our goal is to
eventually grind up this bud and either
roll a joint out of it or pack a bowl or
stuff it in your vaporizer or most of us
nowadays are going to stuff it into a
tube and turn it into BHO or a lot of
your gonna freeze it and turn it into
ice wax or something but anyway let's
think about what we're trying to do
eventually most of us are gonna grind up
this herb and roll a fat joint out of it
then when you smoke your joint you want
it to smell good you want it to taste
good you want it to get you nice and
stoned but something that you really
want it to do that you don't think about
is that you want it to burn nice and
smoothly you want it to burn evenly you
want it to burn and make a nice white
ash you don't want it to burn into this
hard black charcoal looking thing that
hard black charcoal that's in the bottom
of your bowl when you're done or that
your joint turns into that's nutrients
that weren't flushed out of the plant
anyway I'm backing up a little bit but a
lot of times a bad cure will make your
buds not burn properly when you're
curing your buds you are removing excess
chlorophyll from the plants you are
removing a water molecule from the THC
which makes the THC more psychoactive
you are also pulling chlorophyll which
is making the plants taste better
making your buds taste better so a
proper cure and not a speed dry is very
important of proper cure will definitely
affect the way that your buds burn
slowly drying your buds will suck out
all of that chlorophyll and it will suck
the moisture out slowly and your buds
will burn very nice and smoothly they'll
be nice and sticky and they will burn
very very well I've got an episode all
about drying and curing I'm gonna pause
right now and go see exactly which
number it is it's either 35 or 36 let me
pause for one second and go see what it
is so that I can tell you to listen here
we go okay guys it's episode number 35
go listen to episode number 35 of the
girl from your heart podcast and learn
all about properly drying and curing
your cannabis actually when it was
episode 35 it was called I grow culture
but it's still on the same feet guys its
episode number 35 and it's titled number
35 drying and curing so go check it out
it's a the formerly known as
culture podcast that now known as the
drawer for our podcast it's in the same
feed go check it out
I feel like I'm way off topic let's get
back in the game here we are talking
about a poor cure is what makes your
buds not top-shelf because they don't
taste good and they do not burn properly
you guys it is very possible to have
nice sticky buds that are properly dried
and cured that will burn like a champ
stink up the whole [ __ ] neighborhood
and get you high a [ __ ] that's your goal
so listen to the episode learn how to
properly dry and cure the buds um
another thing don't try to speed dry
your weed you guys do not speed dry it
cut it down hang it upside down and let
it dry properly that's what that's gonna
give you a huge advantage also here is a
major contributing factor to why I feel
like a lot of people's buds are not
top-shelf you guys people really love to
cut their buds way too early what that
[ __ ] grow let it finish just because the
packaging on your seed package says that
those seeds will be done in 60 days does
not mean that you have to cut them down
in 60 days get yourself a nice scope get
some sort of a scope where you can
magnify the size of your trichomes to
where you can see how many of them have
turned opaque how many of them have gone
cloudy and how many of them are amber
when you start seeing about 30 percent
amber trichomes is when it's time to
harvest you guys a lot of people are
just cutting weed down way too early
they're trimming it like [ __ ] there's
speed drying it and then they're trying
to get top-shelf prices for it and they
feel bad and they feel let down when
they're not able to sell their product
for a top-shelf price you've got to let
it finish you've really got to let it
finish it doesn't even taste right it
doesn't get you high enough and you're
not even getting the right weight if you
don't let it finish that last week or
two is really where it starts packing on
weight on a lot of strains so let the
weed grow longer quit cutting it too
early and it will really improve the
quality of your buds like I said get a
scope start watching the trichomes quit
paying so much attention to your
calendar and pay a little bit more
attention to the plants I understand
you're on a schedule but the plants are
the boss here and if you want a Plus
top-shelf bug
this is what you're gonna have to do all
right so don't cut too early now also
you're going to have to pay a lot more
attention to the room we can tell I can
tell by looking at the finished product
if the room got too hot or if the room
got too humid or if you had some sort of
bug infestation or if there was some
sort of struggle a professional grower
can tell by looking at your finished but
what the problem was off your buds are
airy and fluffy you probably got too hot
in there if the buds have this weird
texture to them they probably got too
humid in there I can spot bug damage on
those leaves that you're not cutting off
I can see the spider mite marks on those
leaves you guys so pay a lot of
attention to the room get good control
of your rooms it's all about the
environment you have to set up that room
to have proper air flow you need air
exchange you need to get the old stale
air out of there and you need to get
fresh air in so that that plant can
breathe you don't want to be trapped in
a stale humid ass closet all day neither
do your plants so and they also don't
want to be too hot if you get the plants
too hot they start Fox tailing the buds
start getting wispy it's just like in
the summer time you guys you guys you
know what I'm talking about when it gets
all hot your junk starts swinging down
all low is just trying to cool itself
down the plants will do the same thing
it starts spreading its legs all far so
that it can get some air and it starts
Fox tailing that's from too much heat
you guys so if you get your grow room
under control you will be able to
produce better cannabis get the bugs
under control you guys if you don't have
bugs on your plants your plants don't
have to spend all their energy fighting
off these predators and they're able to
use all of their energy into producing
delicious tasty trichomes and resin and
terpenes let the plants focus on what
they're supposed to do alright so pay
attention to the room get the room under
control is the point of that part right
there so another reason why a lot of
cannabis that I see cannot be considered
top-shelf cannabis is because the grower
basically forgot the general rules of
growing he forgot to think about his
lights his air his water or his soil he
just kind of got off
times as growers we get complacent we
get cocky we get egotistical we get
overconfident we get ahead of ourselves
that [ __ ] happens and sometimes that's
when you start worrying about something
that is really obscure and then you
forget about something that was really
basic you're trying some new trick
that's really gonna improve the crop
right this new trick is gonna make
everything [ __ ] magical it's gonna be
amazing but as I did that I forgot to pH
the nutrient solution before I water it
something stupid like that you guys just
pay attention to the basics pay
attention to your lights pay attention
to the air pay attention to your water
and pay attention to your soil and
everything should be cool of course pay
attention to the plants look at the
leaves every day for bugs do all that
stuff but remember the basics you need
good lighting if you don't have good
lighting you can't grow quality buds you
can grow quality bud under a small lamp
I wouldn't go you know you can use it
250 you're not gonna grow cannabis cup
winning buds underneath the 250 watt
light you may do okay under a 4 you've
got potential under a 6 but I really
think if you're gonna grow cannabis cup
winning top-shelf a great buds you need
at least a thousand watt light at least
1000 watt light and you don't want to
try to put more than about a 4 by 4 or a
5 by 5 floor pattern worth of plants
underneath there you want your canopy to
be nice and tight under that thousand
watt light the light is the main
nutrient for your plants that's what the
plants want more than anything so have
enough lighting and also make sure you
have the right spectrum that's super
important don't forget about that air we
sort of discussed air before ah don't
have too much humidity don't have too
much heat try to find a way to replenish
the co2 by replacing the air in the room
very often your water I've mentioned
this make sure your pH in your nutrient
solution before you're feeding it to
your plants make sure you're checking
your PPM's
make sure you're using good quality
water if you can start with reverse
osmosis water that would be ideal
make sure you remember to check the pH
you guys a lot of people or simply have
overlooked pH balancing their water
before they add it to the solute to the
plants you want that about six five ish
depending on what strains you're running
on how far into flower you are but make
sure you've got your nutrients measured
properly you're not over feeding the
plants and you've got them pH adjusted
your soil you guys you got to use a good
quality soil you can't be packing your
dirt too tight you need some aeration
you need some air in there you need some
drainage in there use good soil don't
overlook that type of stuff those are
the basics that you guys need to pay
attention to that you may have forgotten
that sometimes I forget I'm guilty of
this as well this is all small things
that I'm trying to remind you about so
don't forget the basics of growing and
we can always refer to the old rule
called laws lights air water and soil
never forget those and then of course
you got to add love in there because I
think plants grow with a lot of luck you
gotta love the plants so another way to
improve your cannabis and this is gonna
sound like I'm just trying to make a
sales pitch here but you need good
quality genetics you guys unless you've
got a top-shelf cultivar and I'm gonna
I'm gonna branch here you guys quit
saying strands it's not a strand we
don't smoke different strands we don't
grow different strands we grow different
strains and if you really want to be
difficult and technical they are known
as varietals and then if you really want
to be an [ __ ] you would call it a
cultivar so a specific phenotype of a
specific strain would be a cultivar but
I digress use good genetics you guys
grow a good strain if you're stuck on
growing that strain and you can't get it
to be what you want it to be maybe it's
time to buy a pack of seeds and run
those seeds and find zi1 in there that
does what you need maybe you're simply
held back by the quality of the clones
you've got that could be your issue so
use good genetics do some research get
some seeds from a reputable breeder I am
not sponsored by the dank team.com
currently they do not pay for any ads
but I can fully recommend my friends at
the dank team.com they have reliable
seeds I used to say it all the time you
can get rare dankness mile hike an
adventure Sin City sour seeds those are
just a few of the people that I would
recommend of course I read genetics if
you can get your hands on it get
yourself some good quality seeds from a
reputable breeder I do a Fino hunt find
the best one out of there
you and maybe that will help you improve
the quality of your cannabis maybe it's
just that clone that you're growing
isn't going to get any better maybe it's
got maybe its potential is only 17% of
THC no matter what you do to it it's
just a genetic thing my genetics say
that I'm not gonna be able to jump six
feet high no matter what I do I can't
jump high I'm a white I'm a white man
they can't jump it's just my genetics
sometimes these plants aren't gonna go
much further than their potential so get
good genetics hey guys we talked about
lights air water and soil but what we
got to think about is do not overlook
the vegetative stage of growth from day
one when you get those clones when you
crack those seeds from the very
beginning of the grow you are working on
the quality of that cannabis you may
just say hey it's a veg I can just put
it under these weak lights I don't need
a lot of good air I don't need to feed
it good so a good nutrients but really
good teenagers and good kids make good
adults so why doesn't the same [ __ ] work
with plants I think you need to take
really good care of those baby plants
because that is the beginning of
everything you need to create a nice
root zone you need to create a nice
thick stalk you need a nice node
structure you need nice strong supported
branches
you need nice topping you need nice a
nice canopy you need nice pruning just
take very good care of the plants in the
veg phase and you will be very prepared
for happy healthy plants when you go
into the flowering stage so pay more
attention to the veg phase I think a lot
of people overlook the vegetative stage
of cannabis growing so that's a way that
you could definitely improve the quality
of your cannabis alright guys I've got
one more thing that I really think would
help improve the quality of your
finished product and it will also help
improve the quality of your concentrates
if you're a hash maker something you
really need to do is clean your grow
room okay
make sure that the floor is clean make
sure that the tops of your light
reflectors are dusted off make sure that
the air conditioner gets cleaned make
sure that all the blowers and the carbon
filters the tops of them sometimes they
collect a little dust clean those make
sure that your carbon filter covers get
cleaned occasionally hey guys you gotta
go in there and clean up if you've got a
shop vac with a good filter on it get in
there and shop vac the corners clean the
[ __ ] out of that grow room because every
piece of dust and particulate that is in
the air will end up sticking to your
plants if you've ever taken a picture of
a cannabis plant and there's a little
hair in there you understand exactly how
bad anything and everything will stick
to your cannabis plants while they're
growing you'll never be able to get the
hair out of it you'll never be able to
get the dust out so clean up the grow
room if you've got long hair if you've
got a beard think about keeping that
[ __ ] out of the plants to do what you
can I can't talk too much [ __ ] I've got
dreadlocks that go almost to my knees
I've got to wear a big ass hat just to
go in the girl room so try to be
sanitary try to be clean try to be dust
free try to clean up all that [ __ ] all
of that stuff is going to stick to your
buds all that stuff is going to end up
in your finished product all that stuff
is going to end up in your concentrate
so just think about all the dust and
whatever that is its soil and whatever
else you're dragging around in the grow
room that's all going to end up in your
finished product alright guys so I'm
gonna do a quick recap I've gone through
my list let's go real quickly if you
want your buds to be a little bit better
than they are maybe you could
I'll pay more attention to your feeding
maybe you could flush a little bit
better you could possibly trim up your
buds a little bit better you could
probably improve the quality of your
drying and curing method which all you'd
have to do is listen to episode number
35 and that'll give you huge steps on
how to do that you could probably let
your plants grow a little bit longer pay
attention to the harvest date that would
help you out
you could probably pay more attention to
the room and dial the room in a little
bit better you could probably work on
not having bugs another good way to
improve the quality of your cannabis is
to remember the basics remember the
fundamentals of growing another huge way
to improve the quality of your grow is
to use quality genetics from a reputable
breeder another good way is to not
overlook your veg phase and of course
clean up the grow room and then of
course we've got a little side note here
that says good lighting so make sure
you're using proper lighting and also
you guys good nutrients good quality
nutrients will get you a long way make
sure your plants are properly fed there
are a few things that I think would work
with every feed regimen if you wanted to
add dehydrated coconut water and also
yucca extract those things will
definitely improve your cannabis with
almost any feed regimen if you're going
hydro you're gonna have to figure out
how to add those to your hydro regimen
it's a little bit different but if you
got a soil mix going on those things
that definitely make your plants taste
better if your plants are burning and
making black ashes you're probably over
new training / nutrient tting over
feeding over fertilizing that's what I
think I'm trying to say and you're not
flushing properly so work on those
things you guys that's all I've got for
this episode I'm gonna start wrapping up
the show I will be back in about I'm not
gonna do a midweek episode so I will be
back Monday for you I've got a couple of
few things planned I'm trying to link up
with our friend Fox he's in Colorado
right now he is a busy man he is elusive
I've chased him down for a day and it
was hard to find him so he did not
record with him yet but we will in the
future if everything goes my way you
guys I'd love it if you found me on the
social media I am on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast we are on Facebook it's grow
from your heart on Instagram I use the I
read genetics Instagram page we're
almost at night
thousand followers to be really cool if
you clicked on that and put me up there
at nineteen thousand followers that'd be
really cool
so follow I read genetics on Instagram
you guys I think that's all I've got for
you this week I want to thank everybody
for listening I want to give a big shout
out to my ninja Spence until next time
you guys take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community at
number 105 your source for cannabis news
education and conversation through the
intro but it's alright we're he's also
known as on Instagram on Twitter I'm
looking for the news article that I had
tagged here but of course uh refreshed
something weird happened here recently
in Colorado Snoop Dogg has signed a deal
with Live Well a dispensary here in
Colorado to produce a strain of cannabis
and market this cannabis under the Snoop
Dogg name and live well that sounds like
a really cool thing but wills looking at
me and shaking his head kind of to the
side kind of like if you guys have heard
the show in the past we've reported
about Live Well putting a whole bunch of
shitty-ass pesticides in their cannabis
if you come to Colorado and you shop it
live well you'll be disappointed because
it's pretty much like going to the
shittiest street dealer you can ever
find and buying the shittiest dirt weed
you can find for way too much money and
it always seems old like old weed yeah
just old and it's probably because
they're using pesticides of low quality
so I think it's really weird that snoop
has come and done a deal with the
shittiest they've got the reputation for
being the shittiest dispensary in
Colorado soups publicist or publishing
or public people should have done a lot
more research on this [ __ ] this is a
little more work and I'm also curious I
am NOT a law expert but snoop is not a
Colorado resident how is snoop able to
participate in a Colorado cannabis
business I'm very curious about that so
if you guys have some insight on that
Mike if you're listening please tweet me
or come be on the show and we will talk
about how snoops able to do this this is
this is kind of wack you guys the
shittiest dispensary here in Colorado
and I'm not just talking [ __ ] if you're
in Colorado and you go to live well and
then go to almost any other dispensary
go to the spot dispensary go to green
and healthy wellness when they reopen
here in about two weeks you will see
quality products fared to live very
quality yeah green and healthy is only a
trip station is only medical so I
apologize all right so I wanted to talk
about that for a second we got past this
we did not even need any help from the
news article Snoop big fail bro if you
need some good weed come hit me up for
the dispensary and I'll show you how to
grow and I'll show you how I grow and
will produce some quality buds for you
will do it will make a strain for you
called doggystyle let's talk a little
bit about blowing class dude you brought
some great looking pieces with you man
the piece right in front of me is is
that called Illuminati or is that this
is haterade okay that's a good that's a
good random question where do these
names come from big last night the color
of the glass yeah whoever the company
that makes it or the person that pulls
it okay each one there's like glass
alchemy Mountain glass arts and then
tapi tubes en el burro here in Denver
okay just bunch of different companies
that pull different colors and they name
it whatever they want there's a few that
go across the board like blue Stardust
is one that every company most likely
has okay but then there's a few I can't
think of any off the top of my head but
that are just specifically a company
made them okay yeah so is this a common
color or is this
it's a pretty common one yeah right all
right so what's the difference between
haterade slime and Illuminati Illuminati
is UV reactive aluminum caps just like
Gatorade pretty much little bit more on
the yellow side probably all right in
California Florida
yeah the east coast has got a glass
scene popping up it's everywhere there
now glass galleries all over the place
it's really funny I go to glass events
and I don't even will and I hang out we
are friends through the garden of Weeden
we don't really hang out in on our own
but we always illusions glass galleries
we ran into each other at champs oh
[Music]
that's the best person that could call
right now hey Maddie come be on the
podcast again we get so many lessons
when you're here but we run into each
other at glass places glass events all
the time so we're birth of both huge
glass enthusiasts which is kind of great
so this is why tea glass why tea glasses
his name I don't know his actual name
don't even know there's an underscore
anything but you look up whitey glass
you'll find him feel good he's healing
the Klein game pieces with this weird
spout on the back that's called the
client this is a client Klein there's
like a recycler it's the new kind of
cool recycler that everyone's liking as
opposed to the old triangular shape
shears is more of an internal one even
though it's not technically internal
with the the drains and the drain in the
back everything I really like the way
those types of rigs hit I've been a
little Klein and I love the way that
they're awesome they're awesome
all right so shout out to whitey glass
that's a sexy piece dude tell me more
about this rubber duckie looking at this
little birdie right here this is a
comber dling this is number 38 in the
series just kind of a little of how many
I'm not sure on that sweet little
everything that's fresh yeah it's pretty
cool series Calvin Mickle's Calvin
Mikkel is his name of a puck type base
which is hollow and functional that's
where the perk is sitting he's got a
donut which functions as the basically
the head of the bird it would it's got a
beak what color's the beak the beak
looks like green Stardust I think this
one is Stardust he's got a couple of
white wings that are attached to the
base and then now you got a little club
banger on there little quartz banger
we're gonna talk more about the bangers
here in just a few minutes one of my
notes is all about the banger remind me
the artist on that one that is a calm
combo combo
alright so shout out to combo glass you
guys make sure you check out all these
artists on Instagram we're gonna talk a
lot about artists make sure you go check
them out I'll list off some of my
favorite artists towards the end of the
episode I'm gonna ask will some his
favorites also so we'll definitely give
you some [ __ ] to look at so next up is a
glorious piece what is this piece here
on the front call this disc collection
it would be called a cab when it's
connected like this alright it's a
little die crow iguana cab this piece is
made by mongrel glass Jack Jack is his
name Jack our chart good good friend of
mine from actually back in North
Carolina close to two years ago and then
everybody else from the town of Dixie
came out here all the surrounding areas
all the cool stoners are just moving to
Colorado
everybody from North Carolina is coming
out here it's really funny to see but I
love it you guys are so the North
Carolina people are some of my favorite
friends to hang out there they're a
different breed of folk they're more
open they're kinder than more polite
they got more time southern charm but
not that southern exactly
it's alright dude this piece what is
going on with the piece here ten of my
favorites this is called the Safari
special okay it's a really big really
big bass with a tiny little mouthpiece
try it out in a minute
oh yeah he did it's like it's kind of
hard to talk about it over the
microphone without you people seeing it
but it's got this giant basically
showerhead perk in it it's got like
seven holes it's [ __ ] trough like
oh they can hear that yeah yeah it's get
a nice function couple of leafs on the
inside with some flower implosions
attached to the perk it looks like
somewhere that Ariel The Little Mermaid
we wanna kick it totally looks like it's
got some ah so it is this a banger
hanger with this officially be this I
would call a banger okay all right well
we're on that subject about bending her
hangers I'm gonna give it another shout
out to my uncle glass here because he
was one of the first in my opinion to
start using this and he even posted
about it a while ago was when before
even bangers were a thing it was emails
when he nails were a big thing he was
one of the first people to start going
back to the original female joint as
opposed to the male joint that people
are using for dabbing because he noticed
the trend of people using attachments
and drums and everything so he I
remember him making a post about it and
everything about you know I'm thinking
about making transition back to just
this blah blah blah and he was one of
the first people in my opinion to really
you know I was confused when I first saw
him going back to the female joints I
was like what's happening here how do I
put my nail in this [ __ ] like this is
new and when I saw the bangers the club
bangers we're gonna have to talk about
bangers and have to define
I wrote down the word banger so this
piece we're talking about you guys I
know we've been talking about this piece
for a long time it's got a really fat
base and then it's got what did you call
this one cab
die crow cab with an iguana molt super
colorful iguana on the front see the
life in the back of the seat of life
sacred geometry in the background and
when you spin it around in the back
there's like a mid with the flower and
two leaves around it and then it seals
up and coming out of the clear sealed
part is three pieces of bamboo the
taller piece is the mouthpiece and then
it's got two beautifully detailed leaves
go just one one beautifully detailed
leaf coming up the side it's pretty
fresh looking piece that's that's a
really stylish looking rig yes one of my
favorites for sure I can see why yeah
does it hit well with that skinny
mouthpiece oh so we got to give
shoutouts to mongrel to combo and I
forgot all the time these names down so
that we can give a huge shot at at the
end to make sure all these glass blowers
get a bunch of love all right so what
are these three of your favorites in my
collection yeah oh yeah these are
problem three my favorites in my
collection for sure I've got a couple
more Klein's got a couple more pieces by
him I've got the wyoming angler but
these are like my daily drivers I work
with more the functional clear so since
we're talking about your glass under
brag about my new rig I've got this
Hitman over here it's actually hit man
Sampson collab it's got basic yeah yeah
it's got a basic hitman sidecar design
but then it's got this sweet bro what do
you call that color greenish turquoise I
like the clear glass that's made by like
a like a brand that's known like hitman
because I have nothing against these
rigs but when you buy one of these the
functions sometimes is questionable
definitely I've seen friends of ours
spend
thousands of dollars on a rig and if you
put four milliliters too much water in
it you're gonna get in your mouth and if
you put five milliliters too short you
get a dry dab and you choke for days I
love that these production rigs that are
made the same all the time I love that I
know what I'm getting when I buy them
and if I break it I can write I don't
want to break it but if I do I can
replace that fairly easily go to the
hitman store which is illusions around
this much this is a proto or well that's
a great piece you guys I'll take a
picture of it and I'll put it on my
Instagram I just promised that so I have
to do it which means you guys need to
check out my Instagram I'm running down
insta so you guys got to check out my
Instagram I read genetics there are
pictures of these rigs on there why am i
ringing that's so weird that the MacBook
is ringing
decline that [ __ ] all right so if you're
on a podcast put all your [ __ ] on
airplane mode that's that's my advice to
you where the shits were walking about
rigs right all right dude Brighton for
bringing thousands of dollars let's talk
about because I can hook the titanium
nail up to the email the nails that I
use are usually titanium they go onto a
mail joint that points up you drop the
nail onto there or you put your other
dome type nail inside there like our
buddy was talking about this dude
decided to flip back to the female joint
because he saw the trend of accessories
and what we're calling bangers coming
out so there's a guy everyone calls him
qwave but I think it's actually
pronounced quad and I don't I'm not even
sure I go back and forth qwave is more
comfortable quad sounds a little fancier
yeah so anyway there's a guy named qua
made what we call the banger it's got a
male joint that goes into your rig it's
got a female joint and then it comes
straight up and then it curves out to
there are multiple different
available you get it at 90 a 45 probably
other angles as well but then it's got
just a basic it looks like a small it
looks like the lid to your chapstick but
it's clear it's made out of quartz so
you heat that [ __ ] up and then you let
it cool and you drop your dab in there
and the theory and I believe it is that
the quartz is giving a much cleaner more
flavorful hit from your self yes
compared to the titanium and I really
agree with it my problem is I'm a little
clumsy and I I'm gonna break that and
you got to keep that a little bit
cleaner with the tie you know you can
get it real dirty and then just get it
hot and hit it with a little brushes for
the grill even almost a little steel
wool steel wool type things right and
get it fresh and clean but with a banger
once it gets dirty it's a it's dirty and
if you want to keep it clean you got to
do the it's got a q-tip in it every time
for every use q-tip Texan so that's a
banger you guys basically a bangers made
out of course a lot of remain out of
glass I don't see a problem with davon
Adam the glass piece but it's not gonna
taste as good it's not gonna last as
long it's gonna break after heating and
cooling so long the quartz is better
quality if you can use anything quartz
art I definitely one of the two yeah the
Halen honey holes are great if you're
going for something made out of quartz
the Halen troughs are amazing those are
awesome
the quaff Boehner banger nah cops are
cool if you trust your artists news
vendor trust where your stuff is coming
from China that's where I was
no China glass it's made by little kids
that aren't using proper protection is
there a difference in the glass it's
really hard to tell but yeah there is a
definitely difference in there's quartz
qualities and the Chinese manufacturers
are definitely gonna be using much lower
quality cords as cheap as they can face
cheap as they can find because it's just
some douche over here trying to make
money just exploiting the market um and
you're definitely gonna find lower grade
Chinese made court is gonna be much
lower rate than american-made just like
titanium exactly you sound like a bunch
of snobby douches when we talk about
getting a quality nail but that's your
health you're heating this
- I don't even know how many degrees I
don't have to burn the [ __ ] out of
yourself and you're putting your
medicine on there you're putting your
hatch on there and you're smoking
directly into your lungs so whatever is
in that you're you're gonna dab it if
it's something that puts off some sort
of gas or has an oil on it or some kind
of [ __ ] you're gonna dab that right
along with your Earl so get a quality
nail that's super important to me
definitely yeah some q-tip tank with
your banger and clean it out with a
q-tip right well you don't even heat it
the in theory is that if you get the
good you get a good temperature where
it's not too hot so you're done dab and
you get your good temperature you got to
do it pretty much immediately after you
grab a q-tip you wipe the inside there
should be like a little bit of not a
puddle but some wetness in there you get
it quick enough it'll clean it out look
good as new you're good to go you don't
even got to heat it up like this now for
example I was trying to do it this is
the nails a couple weeks old now all
right you know it's still but on this
one you can see I have it in the q-tip
check - but that's not gonna that's also
gonna like burn it and heat like it
burns it a little bit so the q-tip tech
is definitely like the ideal I guess
it's just I saw you saying something on
Facebook about q-tip tech the q-tip
q-tip tech it's these new q-tip holders
as what I find hilarious $300 glass
holder in there's there's some janky
ones you'll see going for like 150
dollars and it's literally it's
literally a shot glass for you people oh
it's a shot glass that a glass blower
made and put some color on and some of
these guys are putting absolutely no
time into it you can tell and they put
him up Rotch and they go for like 150
there was one I will say the one that
started the whole hype on it was a a
two-stroke and sleek collab that they
posted and I think they kind of posted
it as a joke originally and then they
and then they got a ton of hype behind
it and so they decided to auction it off
and they went for $2,200 holy SH and I'm
not don't get me wrong I mean this [ __ ]
was amazing these two-stroke and sleek
are phenomenal glass artists and their
work goes I mean their work is expensive
but at the end of the day it was it was
a shot glass q-tip holders what they
were selling is the thing to hold q-tip
yeah damn exactly but but this whole
q-tip holder thing blew up overnight and
it's insane you can do something with
that kind of money
hell you can do a lot of communities
$22,000 so 2222 okay a lot of people
listening right now though fix their
whole damn car alright so how long ago
did you make your first q-tip holders
before it got popular ah
honestly like I didn't make it as a
q-tip holder when I first started by one
of my first after a month about being on
the torch I was working with shaping to
make many tubes and I started making
shot glasses a slice little Doug Jarvis
that was what we what I was calling him
and my shop mate was calling me again
Doug jars you know yeah yeah which is
what they are and then I took it home
and I was like oh look I could put
q-tips in these uh-huh it's a q-tip
holder it's a headache you too Porter
and I had a buddy come in town and I was
showing he was like hey dude hoodie
q-tip older haha and we joked about and
this was a solid two months ago maybe
month and a half even like and I think
there's a bunch of Instagram five weeks
old on my Instagram you can see it on
the table its I'm not lying
well q-tip not trying to be that guy but
you know um and we me and my buddy joked
about it like oh that's so stupid like
haha like head a cuticle order that
would never sell like that's just
another like if it did haha and sure
[ __ ] here we are a month and a half
later with $2,200 q-tip holders and
talking about the podcast
I hate jumping on the hype train like
that I'm just not I don't like doing
that
but it's whatever hashtag q-tip tech
hashtag q-tip holder tech $2200 YouTube
and Instagram and so much after this
uh-huh so much stuff all right so we
talked about q-tip Tech ah I should have
asked you a long time ago but the
conversation was fun who are some of the
glass bowlers that inspired you that got
you into glassblowing this guy right
here mongrel ass okay definitely like my
biggest he was my biggest help getting
involved in everything personally from
where he went to high school we didn't
go to the same high school but we in the
same County and I had a lot of mutual
friends in high school didn't know each
other in high school we both ended up
living in Asheville after high school
and I hit him up so I knew he was blown
glass I was came in
I'd love to come check out studios it's
cool you know blah blah blah he was like
yes sure went down the studio a couple
times hung out with him hung out them at
his house a couple times you know got to
become pretty decent friends with him
bought some flats from him and then he
ended up moving out to Gunnison with
Brian's glass glass who's working with
Berserker who was phenomenal and he's
he's a beast you guys definitely got a
look at Berserker check out the dogs
that he makes the bullet split screen
really close my bad yeah it's okay same
crazy noises but he Jack showed me a
bunch of things on torched a couple
years ago there's about three or four
years ago now I guess
Kevin touches them over the years then I
wanted to start doing it and he gave me
all the information I need to do has let
me come out to his studio here check him
out so he's deadly my biggest eye he
told me my first torch actually biggest
he was done my biggest help getting into
glassblowing and as far as guys that
like you know inspire me and motivate me
and everything I mean you seen you seen
going he's definitely she's phenomenal
he's one of my favorites
Tom right here definitely my favorite
like sculpture artist or like I sort of
schoolgirl artists but his birds are
just phenomenal I love him I was real
big into elbow for a while when the
elbow I mean I was on the elbow bubble
for a while but then everybody was
everybody was definitely won't say it
pop but it definitely deflated a little
bit salt of course he was one of my
favorites back in the day
you guys check out salt that's a crazy
dirty [ __ ] yeah yeah and then um one of
the with the books my gosh I cannot
remember the name right now I'm tripping
slipping he's two books there uh yeah
it's really before glass was a thing
that he smoked smoked out smoked Volume
one and two um their books full of glass
artists and everything it was before
there was really a glass scene type of
thing it was just kind of like this was
how you found there was no Instagram
this was later these were the heavy
artists at the time and anybody in that
book - I can't really member anyone
specific this was a while ago
but that what those books definitely
were like whoa sparked you a little bit
stuck in your mind all right
yeah and degenerate art documentary that
was the biggest I think I watched my
freshman year in college and I was
already into glass that's what we
watched it but we were more into me my
roommate had a bunch of roars we had
like roars and 5150 AMG's much straight
tube rippers that movie changed my life
and it opened me up to Mai's the scene
of glass I had no idea even existed I
was like holy hell this is crazy like
this is nuts did you get to meet Bob
Snodgrass man he's the man he's the do G
[Music]
any any interest in glass or art or just
culture in general it's a really it's
just a great great film if you're into
cannabis culture and yeah looking for
something that you want to watch that's
not just we like if your girlfriend's
coming over and you want to watch
something else
it's not just another movie it's awesome
and it's really cool with that one
because that was only four years ago
that that documentary was like produced
and made and um let out and it's just
crazy to see how far they've last
industry the market has come from 2011
to 2015 we're in 2011 you know kind of
underground scene that like right there
was nothing on it really until this
documentary came out and then um you
know like at the time
documentary I believe Scott Debbie his
most expensive piece of time was $18,000
like that's that's a crazy amount of
money obviously for a piece but now
Scott Debbie is selling pieces for I
mean eighteen to twenty three thousand I
mean that's nothing out so what I wanted
to ask you what makes a market do that
kind of [ __ ] what makes an artist and
the market jump up and down and then
like we said earlier elbow the guy that
makes a dyno rigs he shot up huge for a
little while and then one day everyone's
just selling their elbows on Instagram
for stupid chena what makes [ __ ] Gor
like that in the glass market well I
definitely think what happened what
Instagram definitely helps I mean
Instagram is a huge part of like who's
doing you know what's who's what in the
glass world I guess if they've got you
know lots of followers on there people
are gonna think they're like oil
brothers for example Matt Bogle and he's
he's good he's really good but his first
rig that he put up for sale it was a
little coil pot of green mini rig and it
sold for like eight hundred dollars at
auction and it was like his first rig
that he ever sold just cuz yeah it was a
hype thing but I guess with the market
what happened was like everybody all of
a sudden started getting into it and it
built really fast like it went from
nothing to something like in a year
mothership prices worth quadrupling just
because I really don't know what it was
it just be kind of like it people
started finding out about it I guess it
wasn't all of a sudden an underground
thing that it was like you know people
had instagrams they get to show their
stuffs people were buying more stuff
okay and then everyone when the market
peaked everyone was like oh man like it
kind of like a stock market almost is
like a stock market crash and you want
to think about it like that where you
know everyone's like I sell sell sell
buy buy buy right yeah and you know when
mothership is like now's the time to
sell the mother ships and so everybody
sells their ships or I guess elbow in
this example everybody had the Brawn
toes and they were like buying them for
I bought mine for $2000 for example I
bought it from illusions $2,000
brand-new sold it about six months later
for $1,700 and I struggled selling it
for that enos and yeah and it was
usually like before that had no problem
I definitely bought mine at the peak of
the the peak of the height yeah it was
like right when I came down for vacation
for the first time for a movie
yeah sweet love that thing yeah but uh
but I think definitely people they see
what the rigs are going for retail wise
and so they're like okay that's retail
I'm gonna they put a high price on it
and he goes for a little bit more and
then eventually it's gonna build up to a
point and then people are gonna be like
[ __ ] that I'm not paying that anymore so
the price will start going down and then
all of a sudden everybody starts to sell
their rigs trying to oh [ __ ] I got rid
of this now while they're still still
worth something and then that and itself
decrease depreciates the value a little
bit yeah so full interesting it's funny
to see the mothership hype I saw the
mother ships goes roller coaster one rig
the same rate went from 12 to 18 to 24
to 28 to 32 and now they're about 18
dude there was a time when you could see
it I mean clear clear ships we're going
for like 9 K 5 K new ships one just sold
for $35,000 for the new trifecta it's uh
so mothership is known for the Klein the
Taurus and the fab egg and they combined
all three into one rig sandblasted it
and put some crazy if you want to see
some crazy blasts you guys excuse me I'm
all choked up I'm getting something in
my throat here now if you want to see
some nice crazy glass some high-quality
glass go I just hit hashtag mothership
mothership appreciation mothership glass
any of that mothership glass you find it
will impress you that's amazing [ __ ]
especially those elites and everything
there's a clear ones you guys are three
thousand dollars each eighteen to three
thousand eighteen hundred to three
thousand dollars the colored ones are
starting off about four you can get a
mini for little minis for twelve yeah
yeah just the mini with a little sweet
anything that's not a yeah that does
look like 1800 for just a rig no buckets
wink at nothing like that it's just all
hype on names - oh yeah holy crabs how
long is it gonna take for you to climb
your way up to the top there oh wow I
don't even know that's like it if I ever
get up there that would be awesome but
uh it's just really a matter of I mean
it's kind of one of those who you know
what not it is definitely a lot of what
you know but it is a little bit of who
you know to and who you can sell to and
I'm lucky enough we're starting out I
have friends from likes I used to manage
a shop back in North Carolina a headshot
back in North Carolina for a little bit
and so I've made a little bit of
connections through that and I have a
friend who just opened up a shop in
North Carolina transparent dreams on
Instagram about you guys North Carolina
I think wants to check it out and then
some of my old co-workers have opened up
shops so I've had outlets to put my
glass into nice from from the get-go
which is really nice cuz I've had one of
my shop mates you know he's definitely
he said some workshop mates not shopping
anymore
he had some trouble selling his glasses
he's been doing it for two years and
he's like you know he struggled selling
cases and I'm here like two months and I
was flipping flipping mini tubes out the
door and he just yeah it's just a lot of
a getting networking and marketing for
sure I got to hit one of your mini tube
team wheaton 7-10 now that's our buddy
Big Mike garden of Weeden crew time
through team weed night mates yeah
that's a nice shirt I like that 13
weeding I made so many good friends oh
yeah over 30 minutes now dude thank you
for taking some time out of your day
before we go let's give some shout outs
and talk about some of my favorite glass
blowers I'm I don't buy it I like to
look at it let me learn about that I
don't pay the money but I do appreciate
the art coil
there's his monkeys and his little
bananas that whole little series is just
very very cool very I don't say
simplistic but some of some of the more
simplistic stuff that he does is some of
my favorite stuff it's fossa also if
you're into that simplistic [ __ ] if you
like that real it's real stylish but
real simple SD Rhino or lino rhino
one of my favorite condenser on
Instagram check out SD riots at SD rhino
on Instagram one of my favorites and
also Bertoni bold color and of course
there's Darby home and yeah so I'm gonna
go back down this list we're gonna give
a shout out to mongrel class mongrel at
mongrel I think it's mongrel glass on
Instagram there you go and then combo is
they just called over there underscores
in there as far as I know it's just
called but I think it is and whitey
glass and then if we're gonna talk about
glass you guys make sure you check out
hitman glass dougie for support hitman
glass those are some homies of mine
berserker blitzkrieg you Xin elbow salt
and of course Bobby Snodgrass you guys
check out Bob Snodgrass started at all
if you want to blow glass if you want to
be a glass blower you need to go check
out anything to do with Bob Snodgrass
yeah make sure you check out the movie
the name is leaving my head regenerate
art degenerate art pipe classic movies
on YouTube to pipe classic on YouTube is
there a good YouTube channel or a way
for people to go learn how to blow glass
this is a great one Revere glass on
Instagram I'm sorry on YouTube they have
a whole channel and that is how I got my
start into it that's how most people
these days are getting started do they
have like 50-something videos and it
each one's a little how-to video to do a
different little you know different
technique or something and they're
they're pretty cool dudes dustin Revere
and Kevin foot I'm actually guys that do
it or the chair I didn't realize that's
what they did yeah they have a couple
different things they do and there's
pretty cool big shout out and thanks to
those guys for teaching people all the
[ __ ] that they know because that is a
huge art oh yeah I wanna give a big
shout out to somebody who will never
hear this but my buddy Ian ah I'm not
gonna say his real name but he's in he's
a glassblower he's not on instagram he's
not even like that he's kind of he
doesn't want notoriety he just wants to
make glass and be a glass artist but uh
that dude tried to teach me how to blow
glass and it wasn't his fault that I
couldn't learn it was totally my fault
there I'm good at several things and
blowing glasses definitely not one of
them I got a fiberoptic
bird I burned my foot I don't know how I
burned my foot I don't know what burned
me burn my damn foot I am not meant to
people that can shout at the e'en for
trying to teach me and shout out to the
raging glass crew that tried to tolerate
my dumb ass like two attempts to realize
this is not for me and you gotta get in
that fire yep in itself is expensive too
that's a big thing that people a lot of
things I think a lot of people don't
think about is sometimes you can get
like a rod of slime like a just a couple
ounces of slime just a single little
collar rod can cost like 15 bucks yeah
yeah and then how many Rhino they
breaking they killed sometimes when you
make a how many what percentage of your
work will break in the kiln you know on
a good day like I'll get like 20%
breakage but on an average day it's like
50% so just be like not just like in the
kiln but it'll like it'll break while
I'm making it or it'll a piece of it'll
break have to make a new piece like my
base will break cuz acute angles will
kill ya if you have an acute angle on
glass when it when it cools down it
cracks if the seals not perfect there's
air pockets there's just so many little
little things that go into it cools down
quicker than one piece if it's too thick
it's crazy those little details are the
things that the China glass exactly the
proper anneal cycles they don't use
proper seal so you could you know some
of their seals you could just push it
with your thumb and it'll fall off oh
[ __ ] if you can support American glass
if you can support a local artist
support a local artist I know I buy a
hit man glass but there's a reason for
that and Dougie is my homie they kind of
support what I do I support what they do
and they support the community yes he
puts back into the community so he does
support the chalice festival it's gonna
be freakin huge this year's gonna be
awesome
shout out to Doug for everything he's
been doing for the community I love it I
support it
supports us it's also dude cool ah man
so let's wrap up the show do don't think
you can for coming do you have anybody
you want to give a shout out to anything
you want to say while you're up he's
recorded and being put on the sloppy
told me to tell you to give a give his
mom a hug he gave your mom a hug you
were invited Olympian well - who's got a
solid little bit of a head ease for sale
nice glass you guys check out our buddy
slop support the community definitely
tell him that you heard about him to the
door from your heart podcast and see if
I can earn some commission or something
on this Blake my shot mate Blake stay
cheesy glass on Instagram he's been a
huge huge help ever since I started
blowing glass guess I should have talked
about him earlier but he's taught me a
good bit ever since I got into the
studio here in Pueblo nice yes big shut
up like I mentioned the champs you seem
like a cool bro I wish you could been
here but next time we'll get you on and
maybe you'll be able to tell us a little
bit about how to do that you guys will
get him back here in a couple of weeks
we'll set up another podcast here in two
or three weeks well then come talk about
how to blow glass just 30 minutes basics
you know we're not gonna get too
in-depth because if you burn yourselves
I'm not responsible either as well there
is we'll just make sure you know that
you mustard maybe it's just a what's
that called a [ __ ] [ __ ] bowl it
works make sure you support all the
social media stuff make sure you fall in
find me on instagram under I read
genetics make sure you follow at
barefoot glass as if you want to see a
whole bunch of great Glasgow fall all
the people I mentioned before I'm sure I
said it several times you're probably
done hearing it I'm not gonna read all
that stuff that I normally read because
you
probably tired hair and if you probably
know it all by now so I'm just gonna
wrap it up like this you guys thanks
again for listening I want to give a
huge shout out to my ninja spits shout
it's my guest for joining me until next
time take a fan dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
yeah what a podcast world it's your boy
Rasta Jeff coming to you with episode
number 106 of the girl from your heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation you guys I'm
coming to you with another show from the
car you guys have been traveling back
and forth between Colorado Springs and
Pueblo quite a bit lately and it's an
hour drive each direction so I've had a
lot of time to think and I have
definitely had some time to do some
recording so here I am on the microphone
traveling on the interstate it is
Wednesday November 18th I plan on
putting this episode out on Thursday the
19th so this is just gonna be a bonus
episode and I hope you guys enjoy it I
want to make a very special announcement
while I'm here you guys as of yesterday
around noon I am no longer involved with
the spot dispensary I have severed all
ties with the spot dispensary I'm not
employed by them I am not affiliated
with them and I am not advertising for
the spot in any way any longer so I want
to say goodbye to the spot dispensary I
don't work there anymore it was fun but
I've got to do other things with myself
I have no hard feelings or ill-will or
any hatred anything toward the spot I
just need to move on sometimes there are
other options in life that you need to
follow or need to pursue and that's what
I'm going to do with myself so that
being said let me make one more huge
announcement as of today around noon I
am officially the lead cultivator at
Green &amp; Healthy wellness in Colorado
Springs Colorado that's right you guys I
quit a job yesterday
and I've got a new job today so big
shout out to hunt and the Grammy Gatsby
and the green and healthy wellness crew
a few weeks ago as about two weeks ago
when the owner of green and healthy
wellness gave me a call and he said hey
bro do you know anybody that would be
qualified to run a large grow
and I said yeah what do you need and he
gave me a nice description of the job
and he told me what would be required
and I said you know I think I want that
job and he was like no way and I was
like not for real I want the job because
I'm not happy with what I'm doing
so we talked about it for a couple of
weeks I drove up and checked out to grow
I've spent a lot of time in the grow I
spent a lot of time with the crew and it
is a go you guys this is where I need to
be I need to be working a green and
healthy wellness with hunt with damsel
with Randle's I need to be there it's
part of the team so team dreadlocks is
getting a little bit stronger shout out
to green and healthy wellness for having
faith in me and giving me the
opportunity to be the lead grower you
guys I'm going to be the one producing
all of the medicine for their medical
marijuana shop and Colorado Springs so
if you're a medical patient look forward
to we should have a harvest coming down
mid-february ish is what I have planned
in my vision so around March around
March first to st. Patrick's Day ish we
should have some Rasta Jeff grown
flowers available for the medical
patients at Green and healthy wellness
in Colorado Springs Colorado now I want
to kind of elaborate here you guys I
want to let you know why I quit the spot
and let you know what's going on because
I don't want you to think that I hate
the spot or than anything
shitty happened I've been at the spot
since the middle of July and we have
been building and getting things
finalized and there is no sign of having
plants in that building for at least
another month or two and I am not I'm
not a plumber I'm not a construction
worker I can do basic things but I've
been trying to find stuff to keep me
busy for 40 hours a week in the spot for
the past month and there's nothing to do
and without plants in there I've been
going crazy you guys the building is not
ready for plants they're not ready to
cultivate I was expected to be there and
perform so it was hard to be there every
day with nothing to do it was making me
super anxious I was making me bored I
was spending way too much time on social
media because I was bored at the shop so
when my buddy hunt called and said hey
we need help here at Green and healthy
it felt like the right thing to do to
jump on and be part of the team
at the spot they run hydro it's a big
huge hydro setup I am NOT a hydro grower
I am a soil farmer at the green and
healthy grow we're running three gallon
pots of soilless mix with plants already
in the building there are plants there
waiting for me so Friday I'm going to
move plants to the flowering room and
I'm going to give them a little bit of
time to veg in the flower room in their
new home and about 10 to 14 days after
that I plan to flower the first crop for
green and healthy wellness so I'm
leaving a facility that will not have
plants until my first harvest at my new
facility is finished is what it feels
like and I'm in it to grow you guys
that's what I'm here for I want to grow
and produce quality cannabis so I had to
make a move I had to make a huge move
this is an hour drive to and from work
every single day but you know what it's
a soil garden with my homies there's a
grimy Gatsby and dude it's damsel and
John Randall's junior so in my mind this
is the right decision sometimes you got
to just you got to make a move that's
scares you you got to make a move they
put you on the spot you got to make a
move that breaks you out of your routine
and I feel like my life has really been
routine for the past couple of years and
shaking myself up like this really puts
his lights a new fire under my ass so to
speak it puts fresh ideas in my head I
find new inspiration I meet new people I
go new places I really improves my life
overall when I put myself in a
uncomfortable position when I break out
of my comfort bubble and put myself in a
position where I'm not exactly sure how
this is gonna play out it always works
very well for myself so if you guys are
scared to do something if there's
something you're thinking about doing if
there's a big change in your life that
you're thinking about making all I can
say is grab your balls and do it just do
it don't be afraid success is scary but
once you succeed and you see what it's
like to succeed and not fall down from
that all you're gonna do is want to
succeed more and more and more your
goals are gonna get bigger your dreams
are gonna get bigger your abilities to
reach those dreams will get bigger right
alongside all of that so if you're
afraid of something don't be scared you
guys you can [ __ ] do it and what's
gonna happen you're gonna try and you're
either gonna succeed or you're gonna
fail
if you fail you're gonna be right where
you are you're not gonna go backwards by
failing because trying something is
going to give you skills you're gonna at
least be trying something you're gonna
feel better and if you succeed holy [ __ ]
you just succeeded it's something you
just open a new door to your life you
just have a new thing you could do or
somewhere else you can go and what is
that gonna do that's gonna be a building
block for the next places you can go and
the next things you can do so if you're
scared if you're stuck in your comfort
zone if you're stuck in your little
bubble you guys all I can say is snap
out of that and try to do some new
things I have some faith in the world
have some faith in yourself have some
faith in life even if you're not a
spiritual or a religious person you can
have some confidence you can have some
some I guess faith is what you need to
have and don't have fear of failing your
life if your life is good right now and
you try something and you fail you're
still gonna have the life you've got
nobody's gonna take it away from you
because you messed up trying something
new and anybody that does talk [ __ ] to
you and disrespects you because you
tried something new and you failed they
are not your friend your friends are
gonna support you through your failures
your friends are gonna say man that
looks like a challenging task to try to
do and I'm proud of you just for getting
off your ass and trying it because 75%
of the people that are out there
wouldn't even have gotten off their
asses to attempt what you just failed at
so don't be afraid to fail you gotta try
some [ __ ] you guys I guess that's my
inspirational talk for the day that was
my announcement for the day I am driving
down i-20 5 on a beautiful damn
Wednesday it is so gorgeous out here
there's not a cloud in the sky I can see
for a hundred miles I can see Pikes Peak
I can see the wet mountains it is such a
gorgeous day so guys get outside suck up
some sunshine the winter is coming we
should talk about how to prepare your
girl for the winter I guess pretty soon
here so that's some good [ __ ] to talk
about you guys I'm getting out of here I
feel like I'm rambling into this
microphone I hope everybody has a
wonderful day smoke some great cannabis
smoke some good hash love one another
don't be afraid to reach your goals and
until next time you guys take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 107 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a professional
grower if you're an old-school smoker or
a hard court dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or someone who's just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you I'm
your host my friends call me Rasta Jeff
wanna thank you guys for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band big shout out to Kat and the
entire mystic roots no matter what no
matter where you are no matter what you
hope you're smoking something tasty hope
you got a fat dab hope you got something
like that going on coming to you on
November 19th sitting across the table
from you joining us again is our good
buddy white Mike how you doing it a
[Music]
little bit we'll get down to business
how you doing bro all right thanks for
coming thanks for taking time away from
the youngster do you guys if you're
listening take your vitamins gold take
your vitamins take some emergency wait
nobody pays me those if you have a
vitamin company that would like to
sponsor a podcast yes shut up to good
health you guys take care of yourself
make sure you hydrate if you're dabbing
and smoking a bunch of cannabis or a
bunch of hash or eating edibles or
whatever you're doing you need to
hydrate drink more water most of us are
dehydrated anyway skip that soda drink a
bottle of water I know it sounds crazy
it's ludicrous
hydrate that's good for you it's really
good for you all right you guys I need
to mention something I put out an
episode number 106 went up on stitcher
on Thursday we actually went up today
Thursday the 19th and for some reason
stitcher is failing on picking it up
it's only got one second of the show
posted so I've emailed stitcher and let
them know that there's an issue usually
stitcher just goes
corrects it really quickly the show is
it's available on iTunes it's available
on my website I read genetics Colorado
comm um for some reason it did not work
on stitcher
it's stitchers problem I can tell
because it's playing on my iPhone it's
playing on my computer I just will not
play through stitcher so I apologize if
you guys did not get to hear episode 106
I made a very special and a very
important announcement I recorded
podcast from my car while I was driving
so it's one of those and you do want to
listen to it so if you're a stitcher
listener and you have not gotten to hear
episode number 106 with a very special
announcement I encourage you to either
go to my website or go to iTunes and
check out episode number 106 it's I read
genetics Colorado com click on the girl
free heart podcast tab it'll be right
there number 106 very special
announcement give that a listen I think
you will appreciate what I had to say I
do apologize for stitcher not picking up
the episode I've emailed them I just
gotta wait for them to fix it that's
pretty much what we can do all right I
gotta reach for my phone I've got one
more thing I want to talk about before
we start getting down to the heart of
the show guys I got a screenshot of
something um so we put a lot of work
into this podcast I take time out of my
day to take time out of my life Mike
takes time away from his family to come
over here and record Mike works 40
something hours a week in the spot so
getting him to come over for an hour is
actually a little effort I got an email
that makes all of our time all of our
effort worthwhile these are the emails
that really make it worth putting in the
energy so this came from somebody will
just call it Mike
oh and he says the podcast is great best
show I've listened best show and I've
listened to them all hoping you will do
more shows with longer content like the
earlier episodes I would like to see a
pest management episode and more BHO
shows I'm in Michigan and took a 10-year
hiatus from growing after cloning the
shoot out of super skunk seed smuggled
back from Amsterdam in 93 [ __ ] sure
changed since oh four had to learn about
hey he lists a bunch of stuff he had to
learn about and then he keeps going for
a minute he says I've listened to all
the grow shows Adam Dunn dude grows Kyle
kushman and then he says yours is the
best by far great mix of knowledge humor
and irreverence in a very easy to listen
to style I'm almost done real
to the entire series again great job
brother man I'll do a DAB for you signed
Mike dude that's awesome that is awesome
he says we are the best podcast not
trying to compete with anybody but if
I'm being called the best then that is
[ __ ] awesome I appreciate that Mike
thanks for listening to the podcast the
email is turned off over here this email
coil needs to be replaced but when we do
it dad the next step that we do is for
Mike and I've got I get plenty of emails
like that but it was time to read one on
the air and say dude check this out this
is what comes I probably get an email or
a text message or an Instagram message
or a Facebook message once a day saying
thanks for the podcast stuff makes it
all worth the time and energy and effort
that we do to put in this podcast thank
you guys for listening that's what I'm
trying to say it thanks for the email if
you want to send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I'd love
to hear what you have to say what I
would really appreciate is if you go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the review section give me a five star
review and type in a comment let me know
what you think of the show that would be
really cool what that does is moves us
up in the ranks and iTunes and that
exposes us to more listeners and then
more listeners will grow better ganja
more people will help us liberate
cannabis it's a good thing so give me a
little review let me know what you think
I would appreciate that all right so we
do have a real topic we want to talk
about here but I want to talk about one
more things it's since Mike is a little
familiar with this region of life I got
the privilege on Monday morning of going
to jury duty at 8:00 a.m. on a cold-ass
Monday cold right yeah you gonna be
there bright and early and it's [ __ ]
cold and it was so windy there's one of
the windiest days of the year that's
crazy you had a really nasty yeah
because the courtroom has skylight sort
of windows that are kind of tinted
behind the judge and they were changing
from black to baby blue to black navy
blue with the weather every like 10
minutes is like holy [ __ ] what's going
on outside and that was crazy so I had
jury duty and obviously I was not
selected I am never selected to be a
part of the jury I
down to when they start asking questions
and then like oh you can go home but uh
I went in there with a certain thing in
mind of what I was going to see and
experience and how I was gonna handle
[ __ ] and it was nothing like what I
expected no it's it's not at all like it
appears on television exactly and if the
chairs are just isn't comfortable as
they appear on television if not
significantly more so but other than
that very few similarities it was shitty
church pews it when you're in them it
feels like it was designed to punish
everyone that was selected significantly
yes so Wow the thing that stood out the
most to me I'm afraid of judges just
straight up a judge can say you are
going to jail and you get to do some
time in jail you get to go get butt
poked for a little bit and there's
nothing you can do about it if the judge
that resided over that courtroom was
cool as [ __ ] like I don't know the judge
personally but he presented himself
fairly I didn't feel like he was passing
judgment on anybody by the way they
looked he treated the guys in suits and
the lady in her sweat pants exactly the
same he was kind everybody who was
respectful and he was a human about
things I figured it was gonna be
rigorous in like the time everything
would be on a certain time schedule and
stuff and he went for a little bit of
time and he goes does anybody need to
use a restroom or anything can we wait
another 15 minutes and everyone's like I
can wait 15 okay we'll go in 15 minutes
you guys don't worry and he looked up
the clock oh sorry it's been about 20
minutes you guys let's go use the
restroom we'll take 15 and like he was
actually pretty cool so you know they're
at this point for the most part it runs
like it should like it's much more
functional in I don't know human that a
lot of people assume I know judges like
I've met many of them right there people
too that's what I said Mike's a little
more in that realm Mike has experience
in that side of life and I I'm the
dreadlock I've got dreadlocks to my ass
I got red eyes most of the time I try to
avoid those types of folks but you know
now that things are changing I'm gonna
have to mingle and rub some elbows with
those types of people the judge was very
fair I did not feel intimidated I didn't
feel afraid it was really cool it may
have given me
touch of faith in our system maybe a
touch more it's nice to know that
there's at least humans involved like we
seen it from just the juror selection
part she didn't kick us out they didn't
kick out the rejected jurors until all
of the jurors had been chosen so that
they knew that there were enough in the
pool and I got to watch the selection
process and I got to watch all of the
jurors be interviewed and then at the
end of that the two lawyers the
prosecutor and prosecution and the
defense passed back and forth a piece of
paper and they agree on which people are
gonna be the jurors and I was laughing I
was like it's like fantasy football for
the Warriors or something and they're
like I'll trade you the angry white guy
for the passive white lady and like I
could just see a negotiating guy like
he's too angry he's too mad he wants
this guy to go to jail before he's even
heard the case the last two times I went
the first time I got let go before any
of that started even I never even made
it to the courtroom they called it all
but like 20 of us and like the rest you
know like just no ceremony buddy we
didn't have to sign out or nothing they
don't care the first time I went that's
what happened there was a case that we
were gonna see that day and the lady
that was supposed to be in that case
committed another crime and it been
re-arrested was going to jail and was
gonna be retried for all of her [ __ ] so
she got me at a jury duty that day but
she [ __ ] up her life no the last time
they they got down to like 30 people
that they liked and they just waved that
the rest of us when I go home and so we
all got to go home at lunch which is
nice but it's oh my god friends that
have selected and served on juries and
it's a hell of an experience you know
since uh you guys if you did not listen
to episode number 106 I no longer work
at the spot dispensary I just wanted to
put that out there I quit the spot I
know work a green and healthy wellness
and Colorado Springs quick update yeah
quick update just since 106 may have
been unlistenable on some devices yeah I
quit the spot guys I'm sorry I had to do
that I work at Green and healthy
wellness I'm now the grower there it's
in Colorado Springs we're gonna crush it
shout out to hunt I don't have to work
tomorrow I think I'm [ __ ] to do wouldn't
mind being selected for a case it would
have been kind of fun it would have been
a very learning experience for myself
yeah
I hate to imagine it but now if I'm ever
in court I know how it goes
yep and I've got a little experience
it's I'm not gonna [ __ ] my pants the
first time um I want to invite Mike
while he's sitting here in friend me
we'll get a commitment out of you guys I
want you to come to an episode with me
about how to deal with you how to
conduct yourself with a law enforcement
oh sure whether you're being pulled over
whether they're coming to your home
whether you're in public whether you're
at a smoking event I'd like to get you
and we'll get somebody else on the show
- I have a good idea of who we're gonna
get on the show I think really it's
sloppy and you that'll make for a really
interesting show that's for sure yes
sloppy you're invited we have such
different exactly experiences with law
enforcement you guys on the show and we
can talk about how to deal we'll talk
about how to deal with law enforcement
and not get your ass thrown in jail all
right guys so I must have blown a couple
of dabs into the computer because as I
was saying that part about the judge you
totally just clicked recording here here
we got to a computer is to dab doubt
something went wrong that means that
we're gonna have to start running an
auxilary output from the the USB down
here or the mixer into the h6 and do or
record this [ __ ] in case that happens
again and then I can just keep recording
the h6 would have kept going nice yeah
or we'll go get a little Roland handheld
recorder and use the headphone out on
the mixer and then just run that into
the handheld recorder and that just
records onto an SD card so there's no
failure the age six would work
the handheld would work we'll do
something like that as a back-up plan or
we can just take a DAB when it fails and
come back a couple of minutes later and
explain that we just had a major
technical failure here yeah it's the
cheapest y'all were wondering like what
kind of equipment we're doing the show
is just got a pile of equipment that's
larger than your car well this is the
home setup this is where this is that
you can get the voice like there is a
cast that's what that's was for all this
home based versions pretty elaborate
yeah yeah yeah the to go version is the
size of a big cell phone basically yeah
when you record Morris's cell phone
maybe yeah Zack Morris is older cell
phone that's the truth we just went
[ __ ] Saved by the Bell on this [ __ ]
all right you guys the program crashed
we had to restart it I just
didn't had to restart that's the truth
that is the truth I just give it a
shout-out to the judge that resided over
that courtroom I felt that it was fair I
liked the way he treated people I don't
know how much of that got recorded but I
went to jury duty you guys it wasn't
that bad the judge was cool it was fair
I wanted to move on from that and keep
going while the computer is working guys
I'm recording but that's the truth if
you want more lessons are you let me
know what you want to learn about send
me an email to cross my heart calm you
can tweet me it's at g f YH podcast you
can find me on Facebook you can send me
a text message you can did you I that
way so I've got understand you guys
would like the listener that sent me the
email said that he would like more
lessons on BHO and he was like a
pesticide issue or episode we will get
our friend Sean over here as soon as I
can get him back and we will do an
organic pesticide management episode and
then I need to find ourselves some hash
experts and we will do some hash
episodes I'm not a hash expert you guys
that is not me Spence is a busy
[ __ ] so getting him to come over
here is gonna cost me like 50 bucks an
hour to get him to come record all the
time but we'll get a hash expert we'll
get him to come on the show let's get
down to the point of the show you guys
we've been going for 15 minutes and all
we've done is talk a bunch of nonsense
um we've been covering this a little bit
lately I've got three news articles I'm
going to read the headline too and then
we're gonna skip all of that and then
we're gonna go to the main article that
I want to talk about but this is kind of
a little bit of a build-up on the on the
website called the cannabis twitch is
where I find a lot of my news big shout
out to David Liguria and Ricardo Baca
for supplying the world with up-to-date
cannabis news from Colorado I found an
article this one was written on November
13th and it says pesticide edict ensures
fate of recalled Binford pot products
the byline is nearly 30,000 marijuana
infused products
over pesticide concerns will likely be
destroyed after Hickenlooper says their
public safety risk here's another
article just the headline you guys is
all I'm gonna read this one once again
was in the cannabis that says
denver-based lab 710 recalls pot
products over pesticides and then the
byline is in the state's 8th pot recall
in 10 months lab 710 concentrates calls
back two thousand three hundred and
sixty two packages of marijuana
concentrates and then here is the third
one that I want to read the headline -
it says denver issues this one was
written on November 18th once again by
ricardo Baca and David McCoy of the
cannabis it says denver issues 9th pot
product recall in ten weeks and the
byline is edibles company guys garden
issues its second voluntary recall in as
many weeks after banned pesticides are
detected in products because this is an
upsetting trend we've been seeing here
in Colorado in the commercial growing
industry okay use its I'd I really hate
that we're finding pesticides and final
product but I'm so thrilled that we're
finding pesticides and final product
like it's this weird duality yes this is
regulation working this is when you you
go to the store and you buy a product
you know there's not pesticides in it
and now the cannabis is legal were a
year or so from having all of that
testing in place so that you know
there's no buck [ __ ] there's no
pesticide there's no mold or mildew
you're just getting delicious
concentrates so it sucks that they're
finding it but it's awesome that they're
finding it right because now we can stop
it we can start teaching the growers and
the grow facilities have to stop using
these products I much in the future I
predict that the Department of
Agriculture is going to create a
pesticide class for the cannabis
industry they're gonna have to do it
it's gonna have to happen they're going
to have to make their own regulations
because that's who's doing this they're
gonna have to tell us what we can do
they kind of are now all that stuff from
the ground up like it exists in every
other industry but we're not allowed to
access any of the components that do
this
cantaloupe Roberta backhoe or right beer
because cannabis is federally illegal so
we're not allowed to federally test so
we can't find all the labs that are
doing the testing were created by the
demand the medical industry created here
like all of the labs that are up and
running around the state came from the
Medical Marijuana days and they weren't
state mandated the industry demanded
them it created them on their own and
when they deal with testing labs want to
apply for DEA licensing like they should
they all got raided so they stopped
applying for DEA licensing and just ran
a testing lab anyway with just without
that federal certification meaning that
they can't do like organics testing or
certifying or anything like that because
that's all federal right shun at this
detail Halen labs actually I don't think
organic testing is actually federal I've
been regulations for using that word are
okay that makes sense recently if you're
a legal marijuana business and you had
organics all right so let's talk about
this article a little bit you guys it
seems to be a trend in Colorado that a
lot of the commercial growers are using
pesticides that have been banned and
that sounds ridiculous but oftentimes
these products were sprayed on the
plants seventy days ago and these rules
came into effect twenty days ago so you
can't retroactively lis unsprayed your
plants you can't go back and that's
basically what we're seeing plants that
were harvested six months ago and turned
into other Earth's sold off and turned
into other products like edibles and
concentrates you know I didn't in two
months ago I didn't account for the time
from so you've got to grow these plant
they got a veg they've got to flower
you're looking at 90 to 120 days there
it's got to be harvested they've got to
be trimmed and dried and cured you're
looking at another two weeks there isn't
your 140 days ish
somewhere between 120 and a hundred and
fifty days by now right that's engineer
math right and then the product has to
be picked up by the infusion company the
MIPS whoever's gonna turn it into
something the processing facility I mean
then you've got drying and caring too so
that's what that's what got us to about
a hundred and fifty yeah we're still
rolling on almost 200 days for under 200
days to
50 yeah before it's even processed okay
but I mean it wasn't standard practice
for the company buying the product to
lab test it again right and that's one
of the things that these recalls are
starting to create is the first company
to really fail that was the first big
policy change they announced was we're
gonna test everything that comes in now
because that's how this happened
yeah they process really nasty stuff and
we probably dab some of it it could
happen and you guys a lot of people did
none of these recalls have been issued
because people got sick or anything like
that it's right industry-wide they're
all voluntary when they're going through
and doing lab testing when one of their
products fails they just do a massive
recall on anything with that serial
number which is admirable because that's
a lot of money that these guys are
losing
that's tons of money tons of money I
just measured money and weight tons of
money yes dollar amounts and weight so
these plants could have been sprayed 200
days ago and the rules just were put
into effect whenever 30 days ago 45 days
ago and so it's not like people are
[ __ ] up on purpose it's not like it's
ignorance it's just it's just timing of
laws in a lot of the places something
that I want to mention is all that weed
used to smoke back in the day before we
had dispensaries it was being sprayed
with some [ __ ] there was something at
worse than what's happening in these
dispensaries on your wheat you've smoked
it before it's quality control is one of
the first things legal marijuana created
as a side industry and it's been a
beautiful thing you know I saw quality
go when medical came real popular around
2010 quality skyrocketed yep there was a
huge competition for quality buds and
then around 2013 2014 the quality
started going away and the quantity
started popping up everything looks the
same
everything looks real similar I'm gonna
try to uh to make that different in a
green and healthy wellness we've got
some fun we got we got fire genetics and
I know how to grow so I'm gonna try to
bring that quality back to the Shelf
clean and healthy wellness can't wait
yeah I keep looking back at the
recording software to make sure we're
getting what we're saying because we
can't afford to try to do this all over
again that was weird right
alright so we're talking a lot about
these tainted
this brings me to an email or an email a
news article I wish there was an email
that would have been great this one Mike
sent this to me from the Denver Post
right on Mike for finding us the good
news the headline is Hickenlooper issues
executive order to declare tainted pot a
threat to the public the byline is any
marijuana grown with unapproved
pesticides would be removed from
commerce and destroyed once again the
articles from David McCoy and Ricardo
Baca and it goes a little bit like this
I need to take a drink cuz I have dried
up then I'll read you the article Mike
say something impressive okay basically
this story just to save Jeff the effort
of reading a long letter from the
governor any marijuana grown with an
unapproved pesticide is now a threat to
public safety just sort of by default so
any but any grow that's got a not
unapproved pesticide use going on and
that grow is currently scrambling to
figure out new pest management protocols
because the rule in this that's gonna
really throw shockwaves through the
industry is right now cannabis is
federally illegal and to sell a
pesticide in the United States you
needed a federal certification and
approval I mean your product has to be
tested for all kinds of stuff because
it's being sprayed I'm god-knows-what
around God knows who so it every
pesticide comes with a lot of really
specific rules about how they can and
can't be used and what they can and
can't be used on and cannabis right now
isn't on any of those labels and what
the governor just said was if cannabis
isn't on the label specifically you
can't use it to grow marijuana legally
in Colorado and nobody's gonna put
marijuana on there or cannabis take on
just because it's illegal yeah there is
a caveat there's some some pesticides
have
they're super safe you can use them on
anything and they have it a standardized
phrase for that that'll be on the label
and if the pesticide carries that
specific use designation then it can be
used on cannabis so it's not like we
can't use anything in this industry but
I guarantee there are countless grows
around Colorado that have been using
stuff that's perfectly acceptable for
tobacco or flowers or food and has been
used on cannabis for a decade or more
around the country everywhere just as
common practice right there scrambling
right now to figure out what they're
gonna replace that product with it's
gonna make a huge difference for a lot
of growers so there's a timeline here
and I will read part of the article you
guys might trying to sum it up for us
but I'll read a bunch of it there's a
timeline off to the right of the artist
that's what I was thinking about a
little bit of hydration so that helped
out there's a timeline here and it says
on September 7 months after marijuana
holds post post tests find pesticides
and products that was on September 7th
September 8th Denver recalls mahatma pot
extracts containing unapproved
pesticides and then on the 18th denver
issues two more recalls and it keeps
going ah let's see
colorado proposes stricter rules pot
products made with unapproved pesticides
recalled on October 18th Colorado puts
what that's not a real word
it's just abbreviated stuff on industry
to use pesticides that are safe on pot
and then on the 21st Nature's cure of
Denver recalls pot products containing
pesticides and it just keeps going you
guys so they're a bunch of incidents of
these pesticides on cannabis we're gonna
keep seeing it and then they think it'll
taper off in the middle of next year
it should by by summer of next year by
spring of next year all this [ __ ] should
be settled everybody should be
well-educated on what they can and can't
use all the tainted herbs should be gone
some of the problem here is we don't
have enough testing labs so if you are
looking to invest in a fun sized
business call us we want you to be able
to test for residual solvents and hash
we need you to be able to test for
pesticides and flowers we need you to be
able to test for molds and pathogens and
our flowers we need ecoli testing in the
buds yeah we need all the to hood
testing reliable potency testing yep we
need it all alright let's read part of
the article I know Mike tried to sum it
up but it goes like this
Governor John Hickenlooper on Thursday
issued an executive order telling state
agencies that any marijuana grown with
unapproved pesticides is a threat to
public safety and should be removed from
commerce and destroyed the order is
Hickenlooper 'he's first word on a month
old controversy over pesticide used to
grow cannabis and a more aggressive
approach then half a dozen recalls by
denver health officials have put on
thousands of contaminated products some
of it later allowed back into commerce
sorry you guys that was hard to read
there's a really long since that whole
paragraph is one sentence and i didn't
have a good rhythm sorry I made it
walking for you after but it definitely
[Music]
that's the truth the order effectively
immediately was a result of a
collaboration with officials from
several state agencies the Department of
Agriculture Revenue and Public Health
and Environment among them and provides
much-needed clarity on the use of pet
use of pesticides and how agencies
should treat them according to a joint
announcement a joint announcement right
pesticide is applied to a crop in a
manner that is inconsistent with the
pesticides label and the crop is
contaminated by that pesticide it
constitutes a threat to public safety
the order says the order says agencies
agencies should use all investigative
and enforcement authority to end the
threat including but not limited to
placing contaminated marijuana on
administrative hold and destroying
contaminated marijuana pursuant to
existing law industry spokespersons
spokespersons God my words are hard
industry spokespersons could not be
immediately reached for comment late
Thursday the order comes from Denver
Post stories that showed how potentially
harmful pesticides barred for use on
cannabis were still being applied and
fought at high concentrations in
products sold to customers if the Denver
Post is taking full credit for this
executive order that's what yeah that's
what that sounded like thanks - papers
love it when they can say we reported
something and then change
and did a state level because of it and
so this is a huge feather in their cap
they've just been buying up random
product to dispensaries and taking it to
testing labs who's gonna say that the
westward started that part of it they
the westward in the Denver Post both
hammered the edibles industry a couple
of years ago over potency issues and
then they started doing contaminants
test or the poster - doing contaminants
testing and it's definitely sent
shockwaves through the industry it's
definitely caused change to state level
so they're running around like they
scored cuz they [ __ ] scored and they
kind of did it's been a good smack for
the legal industry I think like there
was a little bit
of shenanigans like we brought a lot of
the black market stuff with us and
eventually we were gonna step up enough
to where we had to play by the same
rules everybody else did and we've
passed that point in Colorado now
significantly and so a lot of the things
that happen at every employer are now
gonna be happening throughout the
marijuana industry and some of that lab
testing some of that's recalls and it's
about time it happened is it is all
right I'll keep going with the article
it says where was I I wanted to give a
shout out to Claude the Candyman we're
talking about edibles shots to Claude
the Candyman
dude you're on an adventure of a
lifetime you're probably not gonna hear
this podcast but uh Claude is taking a
personal vacation and I've seen his
facebook pictures the dude has never had
a bigger smile he's making a life change
Claude I'm proud of you bro big shout
out support sweet stone candy so it goes
on to say the post also identified how
state laws that barred views of certain
pesticides were not enforced and the
testing requirements for pesticide
residues were sent aside and then it
says a threat to safety Thursday's
bulletin specifically mandates state
agencies to determine any off-label use
of a pesticides a threat to public
safety and ensure that the contaminated
products are quarantined and destroyed
oh that's a bunch of hash and pot you're
just gonna watch it just destroyed I'm
wondering how high the animals the day
the fire department used to just put all
the bales of wheat and the fire they
still do that all over the place and
every now then they [ __ ] it up and get
the whole town really high yeah but I
don't know maybe I think it's just gonna
get blended with dirt is what it's
probably gonna happens with it that's
kind of what happens at a dispensary if
you run a soil grow and you gotta throw
leaves away you do like lasagna you do
leaves dirt leaves dirt smash it up yep
all right the article goes on to say
Thursday's bulletin specifically meant
no way I just read that part that is and
that is a stiffer approach in the
quantity quarantines and recalls Denver
health officials have put on marijuana
products contaminated with unapproved
pesticides in most cases the products
were allowed back into commerce once
tests confirmed as to
residues were at levels lower than
what's allowed on other consumable crops
Hickenlooper zorder appears to leave no
room for trace amounts and recalls for
the destruction of the affected plants
and any derivative products zero no
trace elements so if they used any
pesticide they'd find it on there pretty
much bye-bye to your whole product line
if they use some of this stuff I mean
years ago they could be destroying
breeding stock or I how we this is most
of the recalls are stem from a couple of
bigger grows that wholesale off dried
flower to other companies to make
edibles or hash with and so that's it's
the people that bought it that are now
issuing recalls is they go through and
they're like wait [ __ ] we bought 80
pounds of that and we make chocolate
bars so we threw that 80 pounds in with
a thousand other pounds we bought and we
made butter out of that and then we made
edibles and now we've got to recall all
the edible batches with those serial
numbers on its huge ripples through the
industry ouch we're gonna see lab
testing at every level we're gonna see
the labs triple or quadruple the number
across the state to handle all the
testing that's gonna have to take place
I wouldn't be surprised to see little
spike in price of a buck or two for
whatever this [ __ ] cost because yeah
it's gonna play into a I'm happy to buy
stuff in the legal industry because I
know that stuff's coming out yeah yeah I
don't have to worry about what's being
sprayed on it or what's still in it man
you just made the greatest argument for
legal prostitution yep yep alright we've
a company could destroy any affected
marijuana voluntarily or face
administrative actions by the state to
force the destruction according to a
policy statement issued by the Chiefs of
the three state agencies involved there
is no pesticide specifically approved
for use on marijuana because the
chemicals are regulated by the US
Environmental Protection Agency and
cannabis is illegal under federal law as
a result there have been no tests to
show how pesticides used on marijuana
could affect consumers or whether their
use is safe but state agricultural
officials have allowed certain
pesticides to be used on marijuana crops
only if it would not violate the
restriction on the products label it is
a violation of federal law to use a
pesticide contrary to its label you guys
this applies to you and your homegrown
this applies to you and your greenhouse
grow any pesticide wants to be a dick it
can be an extra charge yep all you got
to do when you buy your your spray
products your pesticides kill off that
little booklet that's on the back and
read it there will be rules on there
there will be what you should really pay
attention to is the interval of reentry
if it says not to go in this braid area
for four hours you should probably stay
out of there for four hours take that
seriously you're not gonna notice that
you're getting sick from a pesticide
until you start twitching in five years
right like you really want to read those
labels yeah so where the heck was I
despite the prohibitions the post
revealed in its own testing that a
number of marijuana infused products
contained high levels of pesticides not
allowed for use on cannabis what
followed were a number of recalls issued
by the Denver Department of
Environmental Health after
investigations and to business is
connected with the post findings we were
at the last paragraph you guys go ahead
my kids downplay the other half of their
findings they found they tested eight
samples two of them came back pretty
dirty but the other six came back
cleaner than the lab testing dude had
seen anything in a while
nice so but that's not news well it
should be it should be but there's no
scare tactic involved in that right like
it's it's really unfortunate that the
there's a dirty product out on store
shelves but at the same time it's all
being recalled because we've got testing
labs no one else has
it's kind of a beautiful thing I'm such
a [ __ ] up way though all right you
guys I will try I'm gonna make myself a
note a list of approved I want to find a
list of approved pesticides which I need
anyway for the shop
we just we use basically one or two
products at the shop we've done a pretty
good pesticide regimen going on there
but uh I will get a list of approved
pesticides we'll talk about that on the
show when we do the pest management
episode that I need to work on I've done
a lot of episodes of like halfway
written you guys I just need to put them
together things have been really chaotic
in my world I've been driving the
springs like three times a week to talk
about getting a job and now I've got the
job so it's gonna be a lot of fun let's
get on to the last paragraph of this
news article so that we can get Mike
home to his little baby
it says although state officials have
been battling around pesticide rules for
more than a year there was no
enforcement until Denver health
officials quarantined more than a
hundred thousand plants it said were
improperly grown with pesticides the
state said could not be used the
quarantines came after Denver fire
inspectors found potentially hazardous
pesticides and marijuana growing
facilities during routine inspections
this year and reported it to health
officials it as I mentioned this on the
show
they found a eagle 20 in there and when
Eagle 20 is an eagle 20 or flora might
its Eagle 20 when Eagle 20 catches on
fire and burns the off gas that comes
from Eagle 20 is cyanide so that's where
the fireman fire department doesn't want
that in your grow yeah like know what
you've got in your grow know you've got
in your house this is all gonna get
alongs yeah you should read the label on
any product you're using anyway all the
time you should kind of be aware of what
you're putting into yourself into your
plants into your food feeding your dog
read the label alright last paragraph
you guys last small sentence in the
paragraph the state is amid rulemaking
that would strictly limit the pesticides
they can be used on marijuana only to
those whose labels allow for unspecified
crops that can be used in greenhouses
and that are not prohibited from human
consumption s decides allowed in tobacco
cultivation also would be approved
alright so any pesticides found in any
test of cannabis equals your cannabis is
now being destroyed
yep that's a huge move that's Mike said
it a minute ago it's gonna make prices
go up I'm just gonna send big ripples
through the industry there's not
everybody was growing with the stuff
that's being banned or was banned a
couple months back so it's not like
everyone has to change out but every
company that buys product does like it's
it's only a matter of time before shops
our lab testing everything that comes in
just as a matter of policy let alone
extract companies edible companies just
think of a product like cheap wood shoe
or Dixie link into the new Snoop Dog and
how much stuff they buy in process
writer snoops new lion or Rihanna's new
line I like there's [ __ ] every on his
new line yep what just been a meme on
Facebook I don't know I'm high and I
scroll through a lot of news yeah but
Willie's know Willie's got a brain
coming out like I just came out cuz
you're mildly famous for marijuana
you've got a [ __ ] brand of marijuana
coming out well since we're on the topic
own store you know what I was gonna say
is I want to see since snoop and I'm not
dissing you snoop snoop Dogg I [ __ ]
love you bro Snoop Dogg I'm from
California bro I grew up my cousin lived
in Long Beach I spent a lot of time in
the LBC Snoop Dogg actually went to
school with my I'm not dissing Snoop
Dogg he might be I listened to the GGN
he should listen to the growth of my
heart I'm reciprocity it's nice but yeah
but Snoop bro you signed up with the
shittiest [ __ ] dispensary in Colorado
like they are known to be the shittiest
the most [ __ ] dispensary that got or
is accused of handing out [ __ ]
edibles at the goddamn stage yeah they
just keep [ __ ] up left and right
so they also had a lot of pesticide
issues I'm curious to see if snoops
products have residual pesticides from
when they were made back in the day who
knows Wow yes you did that and since
we're talking about like celebrities and
things that are gonna have strains
coming out let's go ahead and toot some
IRA genetics horns here
over the past two nights I have been
harvesting the lovely damsels dank and
actually got harvested a few nights ago
it was finally dry enough to finish do
the final trim so damsels thank you guys
is jarred up and the curing process has
begun there will be a tasting party the
first weekend of December it's a private
party I would invite you but uh yeah all
the seats are full you guys but I will
let you know how it goes I'll try to get
damsel on the show shortly after that so
that she can talk about her new strain
that I made for her she likes it I can't
wait till this process is over so I can
finally get some details because all
I've seen is pictures and some jar
samples that's pretty much what I've
what I've shown anybody right and I want
to dig through all of those over there
there are ten it made it to the final
round for damsel to choose for up so
whichever one of those ten she likes the
best
we will work with um she's human and she
may reject all ten of them that may not
be what she wants so and this might just
be round one yeah exactly and if that's
the case then I just did a really cool
female hunt I found at least three
keepers you never end a bust after a
good feed on that's the truth you know
you guys listen to the episode I did
about Fino hunting I don't remember what
your number it is but make sure you
check the website look it up there you
go it's super easy to do yep go to
iTunes go to draw eye region etics
Colorado calm look for the girl from
your heart podcast tab scroll through
every episode so we've covered the
Hickenlooper article you got anything
else you want to say while we're on the
air bro
not especially you just like shout out
to everybody there's a lot of changes
with people in my life this week like
you change jobs but you're not alone
there I've talked to a whole bunch of
people that are going through big change
right now so shout out for people trying
to do someone makes me that's gonna make
him happy yeah that's the truth don't be
afraid of a little bit of success that's
what I said on episode number 106 that
nobody got to listen to because that
your failed us I apologize so let's
start wrapping up to show you it's been
40-something minutes - whatever I have
to edit out because of the little tech
issue in the middle email a specific Gro
questions yes please do that if you want
to learn stuff about anything
email it to me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you can tweet me it's at G
fyh podcast find me on Facebook check
out the Instagram you guys I use I read
genetics on Instagram we've got 19,000
followers when I get to 20,000 I'm gonna
start doing some giveaways so get on
there follow me
join that [ __ ] do it do it I like it I
like it when you ramble people will get
you here next week yeah that's uh since
I've got Mike here Mike you have got to
scroll through Twitter and find that
I've got it there were like four people
who has tagged this appropriately within
the time line so if you will you're
taken care of if you count how many
people there are
we'll put envelopes on the table and
then we'll email them or they need to
send us their addresses so that we can
mail them stickers you know who you are
direct message me or at Nev upon 15 or
or you can grow from your heart to a
trusted Jeff for 20 yep just direct
message that in Twitter or over Facebook
or whatever and we'll get you your
sticker back mail now yeah we'll get
your stickers to you we didn't know if
you guys are awesome I got such a big
grin every time one of those came
through it's a good hour of just smile
and hashtag I like it when you ramble um
so you guys - what's up let's put it
into that now so that people can't jump
on Moss No Mas that is over you guys
what's this dropping this will come out
Monday which will be the 23rd ish Monday
there's something something yeah the
Monday
come on calendar you got to go faster
2013 I was correct so Monday the 23rd
the hashtag I like it when you ramble
sticker pack sweepstakes is no longer an
offer but if you really want some
stickers send me a tweet send the tweet
to I'm giving you so many different
Twitter addresses to talk about now send
the tweet to @g fyh podcast follow the
podcast we'll figure out how to get you
some stickers one way or another you do
something for him but it won't be
anything real crazy something like that
yeah I'll probably make you follow me on
Instagram where does rambling hashtag I
like it when you ramble tomorrow is my
mama's birthday my mom doesn't grow weed
but happy birthday mom you got to send
her love either way I guess that's a
good way to wrap up the show right yeah
you guys make sure you follow us on all
the social media I'm sure you've caught
all the the names and places by now make
sure you follow my kits at Nemo Punk 15
on Twitter search em out follow them do
you want to advertise your Facebook
group what we're here yeah might as well
I haven't mentioned it until now but
[ __ ] it follow me on Facebook if you
like it's pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws just punch that in your search I'll
come right up I've been getting a lot of
feedback on that lately shit's been
blowing up lately because anti-pop
people have taken notice and are serving
you're really pissed when I link their
stuff and debunk it and it's led to some
really hilarious little prohibitionist I
don't know attempted trolling I suppose
describing it's funny cuz it's sort of
like
if a small child decided to lecture
calculus at you like it doesn't matter
how passionate they are like they're
never gonna get it right you're not
gonna learn anything useful it's just
this weird thing that I mean to be
against pot at this point in history is
to have failed to do your homework and
that's just where the argument starts
yeah
poor Randy Randy Randy i slayed you so
much so much passion
poor little troll Randy and I done
slayed you so many times and you just
keep coming back for more
I need someone who likes to we have got
trolls on this podcast that listened
religiously so if you need a meme you
call them to action and we will get you
some memes right yeah the anti pot
community learn to meme like a week ago
and it's stuff that makes you want to
put your head through a wall so that you
can help them with the mean more I just
don't have the energy all the time to
[ __ ] debunk nonsense cuz there's a
lot of nonsense this is way off topic
you guys but I like it when you ramble
and I hope you guys were listening still
shut it if you are Facebook has murdered
me over the past week with all of the
change your profile picture to a French
flag and all of this and everybody
talking about who's a terrorist and who
is not that is burnt me the [ __ ] out I
didn't even look at Facebook the past
week I find myself shunning news and
social media after events like this just
because of all that like the event
itself is bad enough all the hate in the
fear and the idiocy and the ignorance
that led up to it's bad enough but then
the [ __ ] that comes after it's just so
much worse right yeah yeah Facebook just
makes me want to smash my head into the
wall lately so I've been avoiding that
sorry if I haven't been returning your
facebook messages and all that stuff for
the past week you guys but once all this
stuff stops on Facebook once we go back
to talk about football games and stupid
[ __ ] I'll be back yeah it's a little too
intense right now I have to go unfriend
people because of some of the [ __ ] that
I see dude I'm not gonna tolerate some
of it like I'm not gonna get all
political and get my opinion going too
much on here this is a weed podcast but
damn some people get really really
ridiculous really really quickly when
people are afraid they do really really
crazy insane things and that's what's
going on right now is there's a lot of
fear out there people are just diving
into it because it's easy there is a lot
of fear you guys don't buy into the fear
find the truth I know that's hard to do
in the world right now there are a lot
of clouds plus the ones weren't blowing
but you got trying to find the truth
search for the truth the truth will set
you free
yeah and calm the [ __ ] down the people
that I see been the main thought going
through my head the last two weeks is
just like dude calm the [ __ ] down yeah
like you need to Debs in a nappy-nap
like that's what your life needs hey
Bernie if you're listening to the
podcast bro we're snappy nap Bernie you
need a DAB in a nap but we're still
friends bro even though we had 12 hours
like gots to drive around your kids new
car see if you guys didn't catch on
Bernie's about three foot two I think
he's a great guy that's why I don't feel
bad picking on him because he's actually
a good dude that's why I'm giving him a
shout out and saying even though we had
a heated conversation on Facebook and we
totally disagree on some [ __ ] I agree
that we disagree and you're still my bro
he's a marine and so he's thank you
thank you and all the combat vets cuz if
we didn't have vets that signed up to go
do [ __ ] or people that signed up to be
Marines and army guys and Air Force guys
you and I would get drafted bro because
we're big like even when I was a
teenager and I had friends that really
could think I'm gonna go sign up for the
Air Force I was like I would die twice
like that's so not me though you've
played black ops with me you want to be
in the military with me know if I throw
if I get flashbang 90% of the time it's
cuz I threw the flashbang
it's tight pants lots of running that's
so not me it doesn't set the desert the
desert nope not me I don't look good
weapons are loud
I'd miss everybody on purpose bro like
there's a terrorist and I just kind of
fake aim and Adam shoot next to him to
scare him away you sure the sirens just
now I did that was crazy
I came through my headphones all right
you guys we are totally rambley we're
totally off topic I said happy birthday
to my mom that was last note that I had
we're gonna start wrapping up the show
and I thank everybody for listening Mike
dude thanks for coming hae-jin if you
listened to the show thanks for letting
me borrow your husband for an hour or
two sorry I sent him home highest [ __ ]
but I appreciate you let him come over
and spend some time with me and record a
podcast the listeners really appreciate
him on here
hey Davey if you listening but I hope
you're feeling better yeah all right so
we rappin to show you guys if you want
to visit the website hit the PayPal
donation button that would be super
awesome but I'm not gonna beg you for it
what I'd really rather you do is follow
me on Instagram it's a vital piece of
equipment is down right now y'all so if
you wanna send a donation go to I read
genetics Colorado com click on the girl
from a heart podcast tab on the top
right there's a PayPal logo click on
that PayPal logo it'll take you to
PayPal you can throw a donation my
direction I would totally appreciate it
and give you a shout on the show it's
not necessary the show is always going
to be free free free freedom I want to
share my knowledge my love for cannabis
with you for free but if you want to
make a donation I'd love the [ __ ] out of
you we would buy a new coil for the
Gmail things would work out and you'll
never have to hear the torch coming
through the microphone you notice we we
didn't dab because the torch is just so
this is what you dab with the torch
that's what you guys like a plane taking
off exactly all right we're on rambled
the [ __ ] mode so we're going to Mike's
we're gonna take some more dabs we're
gonna hang out be Bros for a few minutes
I want to thank everybody for listening
to the super long episode I want to give
a shout out to Danielle good luck in
Denver hope everything goes your way
[Music]
like what you doing fool and I was like
I'm gardening like you want to go to
lunch and I was like you know we went
had pho it's [ __ ] delicious
quality little shout-out to yeah
shout-out to spend to Manny and
shout-out to fo it was really good on
that note big shout-out to my ninja
Spence until next time you guys take
fat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
feeling
Oh
boom the wicked
[Music]