[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 243 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right good new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always you need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast they
thinks the cat coup and the entire
mystic roots crew ladies and gentlemen
this podcast is brought to you by our
friends at vat19.com that's right if you
need new regular or feminized seeds
check out the dank team com the Dane
team com carries alpha chronic can
adventure rare dankness I read genetics
gauge mean genetics and many more
trusted brands if you're looking to
expand your lineup or start fresh from
seed I highly recommend the dank team
dot-com alright before we get too far
let me make an apology I put up a
throwback Thursday episode and for some
reason stitcher did not grab it so I had
to repost it I know a lot of you folks
look forward to the throwback Thursday
episodes a lot of people tell me that
they get them through their long work
day I apologize that stitcher failed to
grab that I did repost it as soon as I
was notified I shot it to my friend that
let me know that the episode failed I'm
not sure if he wants me to say his name
on the podcast you know what I've said
his name before shoutout kelvin thank
you for helping me out for letting me
know that stitcher did not pick up the
episode what happens you guys I put the
episode up to my website and then
stitcher and iTunes and all the other
services grab it and they post it for
some reason stitcher has been missing
all of my episodes they don't grab it
appropriately I have to go back and
repost it specifically for stitcher not
sure what's going on I've emailed them a
couple of times they take forever to
respond by the time they respond I've
already corrected the issue myself I
will keep an eye on it and I will keep
the the episodes coming and keep it
issue free on stitcher for you guys
thank you for everybody that listens on
stitcher I do appreciate it one thing
that sucks about stitcher there's not a
lot of good ways for you to leave
comments you can leave them on the
episode you can leave them on the pay
but it's hard for me to find it I have
to go search each episode nothing
notifies me that I've got any review or
a comment there on stitcher so it's hard
to find them but I appreciate your
comments and reviews leave them I look
forward to it speaking of comments and
reviews I want to start the podcast by
reading the most recent iTunes reviews
let me turn down the music and get right
to it ladies and gentlemen if you want
to leave a review a rating in a review
on iTunes simply go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart a podcast halfway down the
middle there's a little icon the girl
from your heart podcast it's a red gold
and green flag with my face on it click
on that then somewhere towards the
middle of the page there's a spot that
says ratings and reviews click on there
so far so far you guys I have gotten 65
ratings and they are all 5-star ratings
it looks like 55 people have left
customer reviews so far they've all been
satisfied listeners I would appreciate
it if you go and leave a rating and a
review and I will read your review on a
future episode alright let's get into
the first review and it goes a little
bit like this
this one says let's see this one is from
a person that calls himself Spanky one
two three four five six eight seven and
they left this review on August 31st and
it says [ __ ] gnarly show main stay
black ah okay
I'm white as [ __ ] but I'll stay black I
know what you mean I got you I'll stay
black a man I'm [ __ ] gnarly show I'm
glad you appreciate my [ __ ] gnarly
show we would get along I can tell just
because you left such a cool comment so
thanks for listening to Spanky ah I'm
glad you appreciate the [ __ ] Early
Show mane and I will do my best to stay
black ah
next review was left on September 12th
one remiss just in time this was
yesterday a September 12th a person by
the name of mangled remains hey thanks
for putting your mangled remains
together enough to listen to the podcast
and leave a review the review goes like
this thank you for doing a more grow
oriented show heard your show called out
of the herder show called out of the
dude grows podcast today and absolutely
enjoy it first episode I listen to was
about scrog found it very informative
you sir have gained yourself another
listener hey mango remains thanks for
listening thanks for subscribing and
super huge thanks for the five star
review and the good rating I appreciate
it
men also while we're at it big shot it's
my friends if the dude groves podcast
there's another podcast about growing
cannabis called the dude bro show at
Scottie and the dude and they hang out
and they talk about recharge a whole
bunch and they talk about growing
cannabis I'm not able to listen to that
show as much as I would like to but I do
catch a few episodes here and there and
it's a great podcast if you're all
caught up on girl from your heart
podcast episodes and you're all caught
up on the spliff podcast I recommend you
check out the dude growth show it's a
really good cannabis related podcast
there are friends of mine we are buddies
I hang out at the dude grows cup every
year with those guys we will do a little
partying together we may do an episode
together in the future great podcast I
highly recommend it but let's get back
on track here
hey mangled remains and Spanky one two
three four five six eight seven I
appreciate your iTunes reviews I
appreciate the five star ratings and if
anybody else wants to leave a review I
would appreciate it big shout us in the
mystic roots band letting me play all of
their music on the podcast they've given
me consent written permission and I
appreciate it
alright those are the two most recent
iTunes comments I appreciate you guys
for leaving them let's move forward with
the podcast last week I teased that I
would be reading emails from a couple of
listeners from down south so I've got
those emails in front of me I'm just
picking randomly which one goes first
this one's on top this email I'm looking
to see if they use a name ah nope they
don't use a name so it goes like this hi
my new friend I live in Georgia my wife
and I are planning to move to a greener
state next May or June
most likely Colorado I have some family
in the springs and I have lived there
before Colorado Springs is about 45
minutes north of me it is a military
town it's not a bad place they are one
of the few towns or cities with actual
smoke clubs that's where the canna
Canyon is that's where the dab lounge is
it's where a lot of these smoke places
are so Colorado Springs is not a bad
place this person that goes on to say I
want to get into the industry growing
eventually I currently have little to no
experience I
have kids so an illegal grow is not an
option I have sis I have inspected and
consulted a few local growers with basic
problems but I like an experience I make
up for in knowledge and research skills
I'm trying to be as proactive as
possible without getting any charges
that's very smart of you especially
since you said you've got children in
here so that's a cool way to do it
you're going to other folks as Gardens
and learning in there then you can leave
and not be part of anything that goes
wrong should anything go wrong pretty
smooth move ah then you go on to say I
read listen learn I have no college but
I feel like all information is locked up
in books not buildings my question is
what advice would you give an uneducated
family man with nothing more than a deep
passion for marijuana and a lot of
determination that wants to get in to
the industry then you ask a couple more
questions but we're off to a great start
the first thing that you're gonna have
to think about um can you get your badge
everybody that works in the state of
Colorado marijuana industry the
regulated industry it's a marijuana
enforcement regulated industry everybody
that works there has to undergo a
thorough background check if you want to
there are three levels of badges there
are support badges there's a key badge
and there is an owner badge each badge
cost more money to get an owner badge
you actually have to be a license holder
you have to own the license of the
business to get a key badge
a key badges for somebody I've got a key
badge a key is for somebody who has got
keys somebody who would make decisions
there has to be a keyhole a key badge
person on premises at all times if there
are other people in the building if
you've got somebody with a support badge
there has to be a key badge in the
building around them at all times so a
key badge is ideal if you're going to
move into the industry and plan on
having any sort of AA management
position or any sort of authority within
the CRO you're going to want to get the
key badge the support badge is how you
get your foot in the door the trimmers
are only required to have a support
badge blood tenders are only required to
have a support badge but you were
limited on tasks and duties and jobs you
can perform which means you are limited
on income you can receive
of course as you move up in the cannabis
industry you're paying creases
drastically from a trimmer to a grow
tech to the lead cultivator to the
consultants to whoever else you've
gotten the building there are a lot of
people that you guys there are lawyers
there are consultants there packagers
there are advertising people there are
accountants there's payroll there are a
lot of people in different departments
but as you move up you certainly do make
more money so the support badge is a
good start the key badge is where you
want to be so the first thing you need
to do Google how do I get my Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division support
badge or a key badge google it it will
take you to I think it's the marijuana
Enforcement Division website there will
be a page in there with about 10
questions and it says if you say yes to
any of these questions you are not able
to get a badge I do not remember the
technical parts off the top of my head
if you've got drug felonies within like
5 or 10 years I think that excludes you
if you've got felonies within the last 5
years of some sort that excludes you
there are just certain things that will
exclude you you need to have your
student loans they don't need to be paid
off you need to be showing progress that
you're paying them I pay child support I
had to show that my child support is
current and that I'm not [ __ ] up my
child support and once I provided a copy
of that like oh yeah all your stuffs
current and here you go here's your your
badge I got my badge because my
appointment was at 10:00 in the morning
and I had my badge by 5 o'clock that day
it was finished if I wanted to stay in
Colorado Springs I could have picked it
up I had the mail it to me because I
didn't want to stick around in Springs I
didn't have anything to do I drove home
and just had to mail it but they got it
my appointment was at 10:00 it was done
by 5:00 and ready for me to pick up so
that's how long it took for me to get my
badge it's not that hard if you've got
stuff on your record you may have to
bring paperwork you may have to show
that all of your court records that all
of your obligations for court have been
completed if you were required to do
classes or pay fines or do whatever you
need to show that that's been done if
you've got any sort of court cases all
of it needs to be tied up or shown that
you're handling it responsibly so first
thing I would do before uh the next line
and the email is what can I do until we
move the first thing look and see if you
were even L
eligible to get a badge if you've never
been in trouble before you're just fine
if you don't have any outstanding debts
any student loans anything like that
child support bad taxes you'll be just
fine if you've got some fuck-ups in your
in your past you may need to check out
what you need to do to correct that so
that you can get the badge the next
thing you can do until you move it seems
to be like you're on the right path
read read a lot of books about growing
cannabis read the most up-to-date books
about growing cannabis whenever a new
book comes out about growing cannabis
read it go back and read all the old
books about growing cannabis read all of
Jorge Cervantes grow Bibles read all the
Ed Rosenthal books read all of the Greg
Greene books there are so many authors
in my head that won't come out right now
because I'm trying to say them as soon
as I quit thinking about authors they'll
all come to my head I would for sure
recommend DJ shorts new book DJ short
just recently put out another book one
thing I would recommend I said Greg
Green a moment ago I would recommend I'm
pretty sure Greg green wrote the
cannabis grow bible he also wrote the
cannabis breeders Bible I would heavily
recommend those books also I would
recommend podcasts not just mine I would
recommend a lot of cannabis podcasts
there was a show called free weed free
weed is part of what inspired this
podcast free weed was a pretty good show
there was some great info to come out of
that podcast the thing I didn't like was
if you asked a grow question if you said
hey I've got spider mites the host of
the show wouldn't teach you about mites
he wouldn't do much about it he would
say we'll go buy this product and spray
it which yeah that's cool but all that
does is make money for that company and
then later on on the show he would say
also this podcast is sponsored by the
company I told you to buy the product of
earlier and I felt it was a little
shifty nobody pays me to tell you to use
a product I don't use a product because
somebody pays for it I use a product
because it works and then I like to
teach you guys about why you're getting
that problem like if you've got spider
mites I try to tell you where they came
from how to fix it what the problem is
what to look for I don't just say go buy
some [ __ ] and spray it I kind of try to
teach you a long-term prevention that
other podcast was just like go buy some
[ __ ] because I'll get a kickback for it
and I didn't think that was cool but
listen to that podcast free weed there
will be some nuggets in there they have
some
panels from the High Times Cannabis Cup
the feature great growers and great
breeders and those shows will be the
most informative that will give you the
most usable knowledge other than free
weed I would recommend the spliff SPL
iff the spliff podcast hosted by Miss
bone Ellis
she's taking a little break right now
which gives you plenty of time to catch
up on all of her episodes she will teach
you a lot of things that you may not
even think about wanting to learn she
opens up my eyes to new ideas on
cannabis and cannabis usage all of the
time you don't only want to learn about
growing you want to learn about the
other end about the use the medical
effects you want to learn about Terps
learn about all of that stuff bo will
teach you that the dude grows podcast is
a great podcast also there's a podcast
called the Adam Dunn show if you are
looking for really long podcast the Adam
Dunn show can be three hours long
without any trouble I personally haven't
listened to the Adam Dunn show in quite
a while because it's such a long show
and I've got so many podcasts to listen
to and it kind of I noticed if I listen
to too many weed podcasts it affects my
show and it affects my voice in my
podcasting style and I don't want to rip
off anybody's show so I kind of put up
blinders and ignore their shows and
listen to bone ellas because we're on a
totally different path of podcast ideas
she talks more about the consumption and
the that part of it and I talked more
about the production so I don't feel
that her show contaminates my mind very
much but I feel like free weed and the
dude grow show and the Adam Dunn show
can kind of contaminate me it's like if
I were a comedian I wouldn't listen to a
lot of other comedians too often because
I wouldn't want to start sounding like
them like if I did comedy right now I
would just sound like Joey Diaz and
[ __ ] all those people it's like music
you just start saying I don't want to do
that to my podcast anyway let me get
back on track with the [ __ ] I was saying
that Adam Dunn show I think it's hosted
by Adam Dunn from th seeds of course I
think the co-host when I last listened
was Mitch Inasa who has worked with a
lot of big names in the industry he's a
very well-respected guy I respect him I
appreciate his work Mitch brings a lot
to the table for podcasting he writes
great papers he speaks well he's got
great presentation
stays on top of the cannabis industry so
he's well informed of what's going on in
the industry and socially and culturally
within cannabis and he's also just a
great dude
so it's good to have Mitch on a podcast
and also sometimes mr. Michael Holly
also known as bike is on the podcast and
then they have some amazing guests being
up there in Denver right in the heart of
Denver when events come through
everybody goes and stops at the Adam
Dunn show they've had chem dog on there
that was one of my favorite episodes the
dudes from Dark Horse have been on there
a lot of Miele has been on there if you
know anything about Miele Jensen DJ Nick
attea has been on there Tim Martin drops
in occasionally so the Adam Dunn shows a
great podcast I would say listen to all
these cannabis podcasts also I would say
scour the internet forums for
information but be very careful what you
believe there will be a lot of [ __ ]
on there let the forum's spark your mind
and then search whatever you read do the
research and see what you can learn from
that because I will see [ __ ] in a forum
and I'll say this is such a cool idea
then I'll go wait some dude on the
internet wrote this who knows who wrote
this it could be a nine-year-old little
kid it could be a 50 year old guy it
could be anybody it could be all made up
you never know so every time I read
something I want to go google what
they're saying from seven other
directions and see how this works why it
works if it works what could go wrong
just go scour the forums get some ideas
and then just start reading on your own
and figuring it out from there also what
can you do before you move keep doing
those consultations if somebody else
around you is growing go check out those
grows just be around as many grows as
you can also be around plants they don't
have to be cannabis plants if you're
working with plants you're learning
about transplanting you're learning
about watering you can tell how much
water a plant will need be in a
greenhouse if you can be in a greenhouse
or wherever be around plants working
with plants most of what we do in a
marijuana grow in a cannabis cultivation
facility is basic horticulture things
that would happen in other plant
production facilities if you're
producing tomato plants or tulips or
whatever
a lot of it is the same [ __ ] something
else he could do learn about insects and
insect control a lot of people don't
know enough about how to take care of
insects one thing you can do go to the
Colorado does Google allowable
pesticides in Colorado marijuana and it
will be the Department of Ag as the
website you want to find Department of
Ag will have a list the Colorado
Department of Agriculture will have a
list of products who are allowed to use
in marijuana Enforcement Division
regulated grows learn those products
think about which insects are going to
infest the crops that you plan on
working in those are spider mites thrips
white flies fungus gnats powdery mildew
is always an issue those are basically
the things you're gonna run into think
about all the basic bugs you're gonna
get in a grow indoors then learn how to
combat those pests with the things that
are allowed on that list and get good
strategies because not enough people
have strategies for that so if you come
in you're like dude I know how to take
care of these bugs with the products
you're allowed to use it's impressive
people may like that on your resume so
that's something you can learn one once
you move your next question is what to
do once we move once you move here get
set up before you move move to an area
with a an abundance of facilities if you
want to be a grower find an area with a
lot of grows move to that area Denver
has a ton of grows Pueblo has a ton of
grows Colorado Springs has a ton of
grows those are all the three major
cities Fort Collins not so much Boulder
not so much they have some but not as
many those other three major cities they
have a lot of grows it's one of those
cities apply and be aggressive have a an
impressive resume prepared look
professional on your resume yes it is a
weed job you're trying to be a grower
but still we need responsible people we
need people with a good resume now one
thing I want to say
this may sound like a no-brainer but
I've seen people post things on social
media that let me know that I need to
correct this do not go to a job
interview with cannabis if you show up
to a marijuana Enforcement Division
regulated facility with your own
personal product you are breaking
marijuana enforcement division rule you
are breaking laws you are putting that
facility at risk you cannot bring
product your own personal product into a
facility that is highly illegal do not
do that also as as the lead cultivator
of a facility if I'm hiring you as a
grow tech to be my backup guy I don't
want to see the product you grow that's
not gonna matter too much I've got that
part under control what I want is
somebody that can show up on time
somebody with a solid work ethic
somebody that is willing to learn one
thing if you know too much about growing
and you're trying to work at the
facility that I run chances are I may
not hire you because I'm concerned that
you're going to come in and try to
reinvent my wheel we've got a very good
system at Three Rivers myself and a
couple other people have devised a
really good system from clone to harvest
it works very well there's a lot of
money invested in the rooms and the
systems and the procedure we can't
change that because the new guy thinks
he knows how to grow weed better than me
and all the people that have been there
and designed the whole pattern so we
need people that are moldable people
that are willing to learn people that
are willing to listen people that are
willing to take command from somebody
who may be younger than them I see that
to be a problem in some facilities I had
a boss who was younger than me
and he had a hard time telling me what
to do and I'd be like bro you're the
boss tell me what needs to be done I can
do it some people don't like taking
orders essentially from someone younger
than them be just be receptive be open
and be willing to start as a trimmer you
want to be a lead grower 90% of the
people that start off in the Colorado
marijuana industry start off as either a
budtender or a trimmer that's your way
in the door show us that you can be that
we've got stacks of applications on my
desk in the office there's a stack of
applications taller than my water bottle
and I just go through them and I throw
half of them away nope not qualified no
they wrote something stupid in their
application nope
so show me that you can be on time show
us that you can be a hard worker show us
that you can list
show us that you're trainable show that
you've got initiative and that's how you
move up in the industry so once you get
here apply be aggressive have a good
resume and then if you have any special
skills like if you understand pesticides
put that on there if you can take any
sort of basic horticulture classes put
that on your resume this person asks is
there any online certificate programs
that may benefit my cause not that I'm
aware of there is a bud tending school
here in Colorado I don't think most
employers care too much about it you'll
have to understand a system called
metric ami TRC I don't unders I don't
remember what it means marijuana
something something tracking something
you'll have to learn that so be able to
use computers put on your resume that
you understand how to use computers a
lot of that stuff will come into play
we need organized people you've heard me
talk about this on the podcast if I cut
clones I have to get a sheet that is a
clone created sheet when I cut clones I
write down the month okay so let's say I
cut five durbin poison clones I write
down Durbin poison five clones from
mother plant number five nine four two
and I'm just making up numbers which
shows that I took those clones from
plant number five nine four two and then
I've got to write that down then when
those clones go into dirt I've got to
write down on another sheet five driven
poison clones into pots from mother
plant five nine four two on August 13th
and I've got to write all that [ __ ] down
and then so be organized be an organized
person put that in your resume if you're
organized try to be an organized person
so once you get here just apply and be
aggressive
don't drop off your application and
forget drop off your application ask for
the person that does the hiring hey can
I speak to a manager that always helps
the manager walks out and sees your face
have your badge attached to your shirt
so that your name is right there now we
see your face with your name now we've
got a resume in our hand we say hey you
didn't sign your email or I'll use it
right now we'll just say hey my new
friend from Georgia that says that on
your application says it on your badge
and I see your face I've got three
things to connect you now I know all
this information goes to this name this
face in this body it helps out so go in
there ask through the manager manager
will come out or they'll to the other
manager doesn't give
[ __ ] give the two a budtender either way
be polite drop off your resume and/or
application call call back and bother
them and see if they've seen your
application or resume or drop in go in
there and check when you go in
here's advice when you go in to check on
your application don't shop also make it
a separate visit go in there and buy
product or go in there and check on your
application don't do both because then
it looks like you just dropped in to buy
weed and you thought while you're here
you would check do those on separate
trips all right so go in there and be
aggressive call back let them know you
want the job because we've got so many
applications that we you might want to
remind us that yours is in the pile so
just call back bother them let them know
just like any other job be aggressive
and get the job what kind of skill set
are employers looking for to new hires I
think I touched on this for a little bit
some of them can be on time someone that
is honest someone that can take
direction some of it is willing to grow
with the company the cannabis industry
is in its infancy right now and we are
growing rapidly the people that are here
right now are pioneers if you stick
around you'll be something huge in the
industry if you are inclined to move up
if you get in now or in the next couple
of years you will be a leader in the
future if you are so inclined so we're
looking for hard workers who are
dedicated and who want to learn and want
to grow with the company and be part of
the team for years to come and also we
need people that are willing to follow
rules you guys we've got millions of
dollars in licensing we can't [ __ ]
around we can't lose licensing just
because people want to play games that's
one of the most important things all
right I want to thank you for that email
you didn't sign your name I do have your
name at the top of the email but I'm not
sure if you want me to say that so thank
you for the email I appreciate it
he ends the email with thank you for all
you do you're very welcome thank you for
the long email that helped me get a lot
of great material and then the end the
the message with PS I'm a big fan of the
podcast so go hug your mom my mom's not
around right now next time I see her
I'll give her a big hug for you
and you know I'm gonna take a fat dab
all right let's move into the next email
this one is from a person who calls
themself a silver Gooch not sure if I
want to kind of curious what silver
Gooch means I kind of don't want to know
what silver Gooch means let's
read this email it says hey Rasta Jeff I
found the podcast a few months ago and
have been listening to the episodes
constantly love the show your podcast is
one of the best I found so far with the
ton of simple to understand knowledge
for both hobbyists and professional
growers keep up the amazing work dude
that's exactly what I'm aiming for I'm
trying to give you easy to understand
easy to comprehend information for new
growers and professional growers so I'm
glad I'm hitting the nail right on the
head there
thanks for the huge compliment to start
off that's always a good start he goes
on to say I'm a recent college graduate
living in Florida well congratulations
and also you guys down south I hope
you're okay I hope you're able to listen
to this maybe I'm [ __ ] up by putting
out this episode right now maybe you're
not gonna get to listen to this I hope
you guys are okay down there in Florida
and Georgia and then he goes on to say
with a degree ize graduate living in
Florida with a degree in accounting and
have been a greenhouse manager for a
hydroponic farm for nearly three years I
have been meticulously watching any and
all attempts at legal as it legalizing
both medical as well as recreational
cannabis in our state however I am NOT
optimistic the way things have been
going yeah it doesn't look well for
Florida right now but eventually every
state will be legal that's that's my
hope he goes on to say after losing my
father a few months ago to cancer let me
stop and honestly say I'm sorry that's
[ __ ] terrible losing anybody sucks a
father has to be the worst watching
somebody go to cancer must be miserable
so do send some love to you for that he
goes on to say it's completely changed
my outlook on the way that cannabis is
handled today in our society after
everything that has happened it is only
strengthened my resolve to become a
breeder in order to help others get the
specialized medicine that they so
desperately need no it's terrible that
it took something like that to make you
change your outlook but I'm glad you're
on Team cannabis now and I'm proud of
you for wanting to be a breeder for such
a good reason there's a lot of people
breeding for the wrong reasons and for
selfish and personal reasons and it's
good to see more people growing from
their heart breeding with love even if
you're not there yet you've got the
right thing in your heart and that's
what we all need so you're going the
right direction I goes on to say with
that being said my question is this how
would you recommend getting into the
industry in new emerging States or estab
especially with former agriculture and
secondary education now in the last
email I read I talked about getting a
badge if you're not able to get a badge
you can still be I think you can still
be the accountant because you would be
an outside contractor you would not
actually work for the dispensary you
would be silver gooch personal
accounting or silver Gooch business
accounting whatever you called it and
then you would be hired it would just be
a service and be like going to Walmart
Walmart doesn't need a badge and I can
go there and buy supplies
I think I'm not certain that that's how
it works but that may be the loophole
perhaps if you're not able to get a
badge I don't know anything about you
but I'm just saying since you've got
that college experience there that may
be another way in for you your question
is how do you get in the same way that
I'm recommended in the other email take
the steps see if you can get a badge
then move to an area that Scott grows in
your area then apply heavily and then go
and make sure those people have seen
your application with all of that green
house experience I'm sure you've applied
pesticides I'm sure you know how to
water plants you probably know how to
take clones make sure you put that on
your resume and list everything you've
ever done especially stuff like if your
pesticide application certified in your
state write that down if you've got any
certifications any trainings even if
it's like an OSHA training everybody in
my growers worker protection safety
train which is a pesticide training that
looks really good on a resume I know how
to program the Gavita master controller
that is just one sends that adds to my
resume I am well versed in the eye
ponics the link for system controllers
that looks good on a resume any of the
program or any of the equipment or
training programs that you have taken
make sure you include that on your
resume and that will help you get into
the industry
so he goes on to say more importantly is
it unreasonable to set my sights on
becoming a grower / head grower /
breeder and living on that pay any
knowledge or contacts would be greatly
appreciated um so yes you can you can
live decently being a grower I should
not reveal what we pay
I had three rivers it just doesn't seem
appropriate
but the growers do make a livable wage
my friend one of my co-workers is all my
co-workers are my friends one of my
friends he's got a decent truck he lives
on his own he's got his own place and he
does all right he eats well he smokes
heavily and he lives off of being a grow
tech wage which is the I think he goes
trimmer and then grow tech and then in
our facility its trimmer grow tech and
then there's like a couple management
positions after that so he's just in the
second position and he's doing all right
I am the head grower and I obviously do
okay I've got a decent car I've got a
pretty big house I do it you can live
off of those wages I don't know how
lavish of a lifestyle you've got you may
not be rolling in the Mercedes you're
not hitting the strip club every night
you're not popping bottles but if you
live a modest life you can live off of a
grower head grower salary very
comfortably very easily a breeder unless
you are an established breeder with a
reputation there's not a lot of need for
a breeder in a commercial facility
nobody is making seeds right now other
than a couple of specialised facilities
and they've it's basically the owner is
the breeder and that happens I'm a
well-known breeder in Colorado I've got
I am i read genetics is my breeding
company my seed company it's available
at the dank team.com if you're
interested ah and I don't make any seeds
in a commercial facility that just
doesn't make sense right now eventually
there are talks at Three Rivers and I
will build a breeding facility together
and I will breed seeds in there and
those will be available exclusively at
Three Rivers but like I said that's just
in talks so don't look to make too much
money being a breeder being a breeder
would be something that you would do
more and your personal grow on your
private time and then
you'd grow those seeds out and then you
would want to get those if you want to
make any money being a breeder you've
got to get those seeds out get them
known it takes a long time to get
established and then honestly right now
everybody is a breeder and people either
want to buy from rare dankness DNA
genetics all those guys that are winning
swamp boys stuff like that or they want
free seeds so it's hard to be a breeder
and make any money off of it right now I
do okay with the Huayra genetics line
but I'm not rolling in money for my
breeding project at all your best bet is
to start as a trimmer work your way up
is a grow assistant become a grow tech
then prove yourself as a lead grower
which sounds like you've got the the
potential if you've got three years in a
greenhouse you've got a lot more
experience than a lot of people so make
sure you can get a badge get out to
Colorado apply it as many places as
humanly possible do whatever you have to
do to apply it places get interviews you
get interviews just like you do with any
other job you bug the management you go
there you do what you need to do you
call you call you call I recommend you
don't shop and check on your application
at the same time once you do get an
interview dress sharp yeah it's the weed
industry but we need clean people we've
got a clean facility yeah I do have
dreadlocks but I keep them clean I wear
clean clothes to work we don't look like
a bunch of bums I didn't go to my
interview looking like a bum look decent
don't look like an orc al Humboldt
trimmer wook look like a presentable
person this is a real business with the
million dollar license show up Dress for
Success be there to win with the rest of
us and we'll hire you so come to the
interview looking like a champ be
prepared be ready to learn don't act
like you're the best grower on the
planet because everybody says they're
the best grower on the planet we're
gonna hire you to trim if we hire you
you're gonna start off as a trimmer
don't lie say I can trim real slow or I
can trim real fast maybe now is the time
for you to start trimming other people's
crops if you've got friends that need
help go trim that weed even if they're
not gonna pay you it may pay off in the
end if I've got two applicants that are
both applying to be trimmers and you've
trimmed to five plants and the other
person has trimmed to zero you've
already got an advantage because I don't
have to teach you from ground zero I can
say let's see how you do this and we'll
adjust your trim to our trim and then
we'll get you up to speed we expect for
trimmers once they're there for three
four maybe five weeks we need
at least a pound a day per trimmer out
of you I've got a guy that can do two
and a half pounds there's a guy at
another facility we're associated with
that does nearly four pounds a day it's
not the tightest trim in the world but
he does a trim of nearly four pounds a
day you guys so and that's the plants
are dry they've been hanging up they've
been due leaf they're dry then we're
trimming them and that's what counts is
that day when you open up that bucket
with the whole plant then you start
going these guys were pulling one two
and four pounds per person per day so
start trimming don't lie on your
application if you can drive a forklift
a scissor lift any type of stuff like
that if you've got any electrical or
HVAC training all of that type of stuff
is helpful also list all of that on your
resume all of that on your application
all of that stuff will help you out any
computer skills any sort of technical or
mechanical training you've got plumbing
all of that stuff we use we use a lot of
plumbing we ha we have a plumber that's
there frequently we've got an
electrician there frequently our HVAC
guy is there frequently if you've got
any of those skills that's useful if
you've ever used a co2 machine and know
how to run co2 and set co2 alarms list
that if you've got if you've got rescue
skills list that if you know how to wear
a respirator if you've got a respirator
fit test and a respirator training from
OSHA
and if you've passed the physical to
wear a respirator list all that because
that saves us money
we don't have to pay a hundred and fifty
bucks to get you respirator certified if
you yeah stuff like that listen all of
that sort of stuff on your application
anything you can think of that makes you
more sellable to an employee still works
in the cannabis industry so list all of
that stuff I think I covered most of the
basics on how to get a job in the
cannabis industry it's just like any
other job you guys you need to get your
marijuana Enforcement Division badge
that's your first step make sure you can
do that before you even start thinking
about coming to Colorado make sure you
can get your badge if you come here and
you can't get your badge
you're [ __ ] you can't work in the
industry and you got to figure out what
to do your family's here you're here and
you ain't got [ __ ] going on there's a
lot of people that did that and it makes
us kind of look bad to tell you the
truth make sure you can get your badge
then apply your ass off and then go get
a job you're gonna have to start as a
trimmer or a budtender don't be afraid
to start at the bottom and work your way
up people move up quickly
people jump from facility to facility in
this industry a lot there's a lot of
weirdness and it's a new industry and
people are stoners and people don't take
it seriously so people get jobs and
they're like cool I'm the new grower and
then they [ __ ] it off because they don't
take it seriously we fire them then we
move up a trimmer to agro tech but I got
my job honestly because the manager that
was in my facility was removed from the
management position and I was the next
in line that was most experienced and
had leadership skills I showed
leadership skills from day one and when
our old manager laughed at like hey
people turned to me and they said hey
boss man what do we do when the manager
didn't show up for work the next day
they just everybody turned to me so
start off at the bottom just like I did
and you can move to the top just like I
did you guys alright let's wrap up this
email there's one more short paragraph
it says again thank you for taking the
time to read this your podcast has
taught me a lot about not only cannabis
as a plant but also how much we can help
each other with just a little bit of
kindness now what a great email I'm
sorry that you had to lose your pops to
cancer that's got to be miserable but
I'm glad you're on Team cannabis and I'm
glad you're doing what you can to help
other people and when you guys come to
Colorado both of you I hope I get
another email saying that you're around
so that we could take some dads together
or we can smoke flowers I know you guys
may not have dads as much as as we do
here in Colorado I'll [ __ ] you up if you
can take some dads let's do it if not
I'll roll a fat joint
we'll get stoned and hang out and talk
about podcasting and talk about getting
you guys jobs in the Colorado cannabis
industry also I really like the part
about where you say my podcast is taught
you not only about cannabis but how much
we can help each other with just a
little bit of kindness that is [ __ ]
awesome to hear that people are catching
on to that and picking that up just for
my little podcast about cannabis a
little bit of subliminal messages never
hurt take care of one another be kind to
each other
have each other's back especially you
folks down south especially folks in
Texas everything that's going [ __ ]
haywire right now everything's on fire
everything's under water
I certainly hope everybody is okay you
guys whatever you believe in whoever you
follow whatever you love if you're into
Jesus if you're into Buddha if you're
into Rastafari whatever it is I'm not
picky you do your thing but please send
some love to the people that need it
right now
the world is going [ __ ] crazy there
are a lot of people in turmoil send some
love and light out there again I don't
care who you pray to it doesn't matter
to me as long as you do it as long as
you mean it send some positivity out
there as long as you're praying for good
[ __ ] as long as you're not trying to do
terrible [ __ ] I'm cool with you I don't
care what you call your guy I don't care
what color your skin is it doesn't
matter just send some love to the people
that need it and the shitty times right
now all right
this email wraps up by saying stay white
eyed smiley and live life Irie growers
love you know I will stay smiley and
always Irie forever I want to thank you
guys for those emails that was great
thanks for the great content thanks for
helping me get people into the cannabis
industry now here's where I'm gonna kind
of sound like a dick Colorado is getting
full you guys all you people that are
thinking about moving here the traffic
is getting horrendous rent is getting
high everything is getting [ __ ]
crowded everything is getting more
expensive I would love for you to come
here and participate and join us in
legal cannabis and the beauty that these
mountains have to offer and all of the
[ __ ] seasons you get to see here I'm
from California we had spring and
summer.i in Colorado we get every season
highlighted really well we get a huge
winter we get a summer we get a fall we
get a spring we get all the seasons come
come enjoy them if that's what you want
to do but I would recommend that you
work on legalization where you are if
you can't come here and do what you can
to legalize where you are my hope is
that eventually every state will be a
cannabis legal state hopefully one day
they'll just there won't be legalized
states it'll just be legalized cannabis
in the United States of America
statewide you'll be able to travel from
California to New York with your bong in
the car with your weed in the car and
nobody will give a [ __ ] unless you're
hitting it of course that's not cool but
you could have it you have it in the car
and that's what matters I need to be
able to drive from here to California
with my hash and my rig in a container
that is locked and sealed so that I'm
not consuming on the road and have it
safe and not have to worry about going
to jail just because I'm carrying my
medicine with me to keep my head right
that's what I think I'm not trying to
say don't come I'm just saying if you
can't do what you can to get it legal
where you are because if everybody keeps
coming here we're gonna have a bunch of
states that aren't legal everyone that
wants cannabis is just coming to the
going to the places where it's legal you
got to fight for your own place some of
you need to fight for your own place
stick around get it going there
I invite you here if you want to come
here come on let's [ __ ] ran here
we're having fun but you can also stay
where you are fight for your own place
just an idea but you know what as long
as you're on Team Green as long as
you're fighting for cannabis I don't
care where you do it let's just legalize
it everywhere do it here do it there
just be on the same team as me and I'm
cool with you I'm not picky about how or
where you do it don't be a [ __ ]
about it though and don't don't be a
black eye or an eyesore on our community
kind of try to be responsible be an
adult about cannabis wherever you do it
all right because I'm [ __ ] rambling I
want to thank you guys for listening to
this podcast thanks for listening to
episode number 243 of the girl from the
heart podcast before I wrap up the
podcast I owe a huge thank you to
everybody who's been contributing to
patreon I've got some great patreon
contributors they've been at it for
several months now I appreciate each and
every one of you if you don't know what
patreon is patreon is a way that you as
a listener can financially contribute to
the podcast I'm not trying to get rich
off of podcasting although it would be
nice that's not my goal I want to help
you guys grow better cannabis I want to
help you legalize cannabis nationwide I
want to be a good spokesperson for
cannabis that's my job here what I'm
asking for funding for is to help pay
for my website to help pay for these
little fuzzy things over my microphone
just simple stuff like that
the water bottles that I buy for the
guests when the guests come over just I
want to help offset those costs if you
don't want to help I'll gladly do it out
of my pocket because I love podcasting I
love cannabis and I love you guys and I
want you to grow better cannabis and I
want to give you free help there are a
few people out there that do want to
contribute they can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to
contribute will be right there
and I appreciate your contributions and
once again I'll use those contributions
to pay for the website which is where I
host the show which is how you're able
to listen for free so once again big
thanks to everybody who has contributed
to patreon also I would love it if you
guys follow me on all the social media
check me out on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast you
can find me on twitter at g f YH podcast
you can also follow the at Rasta
four-twenty account also you can check
out the IRA genetics account on Twitter
also I would love it if you follow me on
Instagram I have got just over 15
thousand followers on Instagram I use my
seed company name we've talked about
that on the show a couple of times my
seed company my breeding project is IRA
genetics on Instagram it's Irie
underscore genetics I are i underscore
GE and ET ICS i re underscore genetics
on Instagram I post a whole bunch of
cannabis photography I just posted a
picture of storm shadow a few minutes
ago a storm shadow is White Widow cross
to the arize that plant is covered in
trichomes it's already got a bunch of
likes it's already got several comments
please go check it out get me a follow I
would appreciate it also if you've got
something to say you're not into the
social media you can email me or if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast you can reach me through the
email also it's grow from your heart and
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen on
YouTube I've got 85 videos posted I
would appreciate it if you check me out
on youtube if you want to hear the old
episodes episodes 1 through 20 are on a
playlist from another channel and then
21 through 85 are available on the
growth from your heart podcast YouTube
channel I would love it if you check me
out there also
damn I sound like I'm beggin for a whole
lot of [ __ ] at the end of this episode
do what you want to do if you don't know
I still love you thank you for listening
you guys I'll be back Thursday with a
throwback Thursday episode and then I'll
be back Monday with the brand-new fresh
episode I want to thank you guys for
listening to this podcast
thanks for the emails I truly appreciate
it I look forward to your emails I look
forward to your iTunes reviews and
comments I look forward to hearing from
me on Twitter I look forward to you
following me on Instagram ladies and
gentlemen I want to give you a huge
shout out to my friends at new
millennium nutrients and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
sitting in the mall and son I'll be
sitting under even come watching the
ships role in then I want to roll away
[Music]
sitting on the dock of the bay watching
that time
sitting on the dock of the bay
I'll let my
look
so I'm just gonna sit on the dock of the
bay
watching the time sitting on the dock of
a
[Music]
wastin time
here resting my bones and this
loneliness won't leave me alone
just 2,000 miles I roll just to make
this stop my home now I'm just gonna sit
at the dock of the bay watching the tide
[Music]