yo in a podcast world it's Rasta Jeff
and it's Thursday so that means it's
time for another throwback Thursday
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast before I get into the block of
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any promotions any contests or any
giveaways those have all expired there
are currently no contest no promotions
no advertising or no giveaways also let
me update all of the social media if you
want to find me on Twitter you can find
me at G f YH podcast on Twitter on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast and if you'd like to
send me an email
it's drove from your heart at
hotmail.com ladies and gentlemen I hope
you enjoyed these chunks of old episodes
so here we go
the throwback Thursday episode of the
girl from your heart podcast hey
everybody rhasta Jeff here before I
start the podcast I want to send love
and respect to all of the victims of the
Planned Parenthood shooting and I also
want to send a huge thank you to all of
the law enforcement that helped rescue
those people thank you
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 108 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to the mystic
roof man for letting me use their music
on my show big thanks to cat coop and
the entire mystic roots crew also you
guys this podcast is brought to you by
our good friends at hitmen glass hit man
glass made in America by Americans when
I'm shopping for a new rig I like to
know that what I'm paying for is going
to give me a nice fat dad and you know
what I can always rely on hit man glass
don't trust your dab to a rig made in
China by a Chinese child without proper
eye protection or adequate pay buy
yourself some glass made in America by
folks who dab as hard as you is a huge
part of the cannabis hash movement I
support hitman glass and be sure to
check out the chalice festival in
California go follow hitman glass on
Instagram search for hitman glass Duggan
give them a follow and be sure to visit
hitman class.com
today you guys start as we record I'm
hitting my hitman eseries sidecar this
is my first hitman rig and I have been
impressed since my first rip out of any
hitman rig I can remember the first time
I hit a hitman I hit a hitman sidecar
with my homie Hank we may have been in
his car buddy Hank for introducing me to
the world of hit man glass I have not
looked back since then
you guys I know everybody likes a nice
custom rig a nice colorful rig made by
some fancy artist it's always great to
have in your collection
but sometimes you pay a bunch of money
and you go to hit that rig and when you
put water in it the first time you go to
draw through it you get water in your
mouth every time you try to take a dab
you get water in your mouth because the
water level has to be just at this
awkward level to where when you hit it
you get water in your mouth where you
can put a little less water and not get
any bubbles that never happens with
it is always going to hit like a [ __ ]
truck so I recommend hitman glass let's
uh let's quit rambling about glass and
let's take a dad you guys today we're
gonna hit the Hitman eseries sidecar
I've got a highly-educated domeless
snail I'm gonna heat this sucker up
we're gonna do it old-school I'm gonna
use a torch and not use the email today
in two different locations I don't have
the email right here but I'm heating
this nail up getting it nice and hot we
were gonna take a dad together and then
we're gonna get on with this podcast so
you guys ready I hope wherever you are
whatever you're doing you're smoking
something tasty let's take a DAB
together this dab you guys goes out to
hit man glass and the entire hitman crew
let's take a DAB here we go yeah that
was my first rig and I love the way it
hits my first hit man rig and I love the
way it hits to the hit man crew carb
capping and freestyle rapping you guys
have got a whole bunch of stuff that I
want to talk about in this podcast so
let's get down to business a little bit
um I need to mention that my Instagram
account the IRA genetics Instagram
account was at nineteen thousand
followers and Instagram shut that thing
down so big middle finger to Instagram
for that follow my new account
it's ireon Durst or genetics so I've got
a new account going I've been posting a
few pictures I've got close to a
thousand followers again excuse my cough
so please go support the new I region
etics Instagram page it looks like
they're out to get the entire cannabis
community what I read today was as long
as you don't post pictures of yourself
using cannabis you can post pictures of
your plants and of your rigs and of your
hash and of your buds
you just can't post pictures of yourself
smoking is what somebody tried to tell
me today and you know what it seems true
because the accounts that are getting
deleted or people smoking and the counts
the accounts that are still there they
don't have images of them smoking so I'm
gonna try to stick with that I'll just
be posting pictures of plants pictures
of me at work pictures of stuff like
that but I won't be posting dab videos
and dab pictures to Instagram anymore I
apologize
so um yeah make sure you follow the new
I region attics Instagram also I want to
send a huge shout out to my friend Sam
I'm not sure if you want me to say your
whole name on the podcast but Big Shot
it's my friend Seb from Australia you
guys have been talking about the
donation button on the podcast page if
you go to the website I region etics
Colorado com go to the podcast tab there
is a PayPal button on the top right that
is a donation button and every donation
you make goes directly to my PayPal
account you guys our friend Seb from
Australia sent me a nice donation and I
really want to give you a huge thank you
shout out dude thank you
that was amazing that's a huge
contribution I absolutely appreciate it
it did not go unnoticed
thanks a lot if you guys want to make a
contribution I would definitely
appreciate it I'll give you a big ole
shout out on the show I will be your
Facebook friend I would alright so big
shout out to our buddy Sam that is super
awesome of you I super appreciate the
contribution let's see one more thing to
mention absolute number 106 you guys I
put up episode number 106 a couple of
weeks ago and stitcher failed to grab
the episode it would not play on
stitcher but since then it has been
fixed so if you are a stitcher listener
you can go back and listen to episode
number 106 it's kind of an important
episode if you're uh if you hang out
with me if you listen to me and you feel
like we're buddies since we've become
podcast friends episode number 106 is
kind of important it tells you a little
bit about what's going on in my world I
think you should listen if you have not
so that is available on stitcher now
let's see there's a whole bunch of stuff
I want to cover you guys um dude so
everybody knows I quit the spot
dispensary and if you don't when you
listen to episode number 106 you will
learn that because that's part of what
106 is about I no longer work at the
spot dispensary I am now part of the
green and healthy wellness team I am the
lead cultivator for the green and
healthy wellness gardens in Colorado
Springs big shout out to my boy hunt
he's got trust and faith in me and
understands that I am able to run this
large garden by myself and produce the
quality of cannabis that they expect on
their shelves so much respect to the
green and healthy team much respect to
hunt but let me get back to what I was
saying I quit the spot recently I just
wasn't working for me nothing personal
against the spot
it just wasn't they don't have any
plants yet and I'm a pot grower so I
needed to be growing and that
so I quit but c-spot held a contest or
maybe a raffle it wasn't really a
contest what they did was anybody who
spent over $50 in purchases got their
name entered into a raffle to win two
tickets to the Grateful Dead concert at
the First Bank Center just a couple of
nights ago it wasn't actually the
Grateful Dead they called themselves
dead end Co it's most of the members of
the Grateful Dead but the bass player
and the lead guitar player and the
keyboard player are new guys because
well the guitar players dead yeah
Jerry's Jerry Garcia has been dead for
several years so they had John Mayer of
all people replace him
they had Oteil Burbridge replaced the
bass player because Phil lashes out with
bladder cancer and if you know anything
about the Grateful Dead you know that
they just have an issue with keyboard
players their keyboard players seem to
die for some reason so this time they
had Jeff Jim NT on keyboards but so when
the spot had this raffle to anybody that
spent fifty bucks could win these
tickets by being entered into a raffle
our good friend sloppy who has been here
on the podcast actually won the Grateful
Dead tickets
um sloppy didn't put down his phone
number anything he simply wrote sloppy
on the on the raffle ticket so our good
friend Mike is the manager over at the
spot dispensary Mike called me and he
said hey bro sloppy one these Grateful
Dead tickets how do I get ahold of him
and I texted sloppy and I said hey bro
you won these Grateful Dead tickets and
sloppy said cool take those tickets and
have fun bro so sloppy the man my homie
sloppy what's up brother I love you bro
sloppy threw me two free Grateful Dead
tickets so I got to go see the Grateful
Dead on a Tuesday yeah I get to go see
this version of the Grateful Dead on
Tuesday and I think it's great because I
quit the spa a week ago and I'm still
getting perks and hookups from the spot
so showed up to the spot for the free
Grateful Dead tickets I had a great time
and also a super huge shout out to my
boy sloppy when I told him I had
Grateful Dead tickets he didn't even
hesitate he was like those are yours go
have fun so big shout out to sloppy I
love you bro I shout out to Dave I was
good bumping india over it the Grateful
Dead show that was kind of a fun
experience and also big shout out to
Rachel is good seeing you there it's fun
watching you blow big ole vape clouds
through the whole show but ya see the
Grateful Dead and I think it's kind of
neat that the job I quit a week ago kind
of in a roundabout way gave me free
tickets to go see the Grateful Dead that
was ironic in my mind but uh the
Grateful Dead holy crap that was such a
good show um they're at a whole new
level of playing the music is refreshed
I said it a minute ago and you guys
probably scratched your head and said
what John Mayer plays for the Grateful
Dead now yes that happened um a few
years ago John Mayer did something
stupid and I don't pay a lot of
attention but he said something stupid
somewhere and it messed up his musical
career and people did not like him so he
kind of took a little hiatus and went
away for a while and while he was
finding himself he discovered the
Grateful Dead and discovered the
Grateful Dead music and the way of the
dead and the community and really got
into it and somehow ended up playing
guitar for the Grateful Dead now and you
know what at first I was skeptical
because John Mayer is not my style of
music at all he's uh it's like girl
music it's like teenager music in my
mind and yeah I know I'm a prick because
I'm really judgmental about music but I
gotta say when I saw John Mayer playing
with the Grateful Dead he nails it he
gets it perfect he does everything
exactly the way it should be done his
tone is perfect he does not overplay the
dude knows how to play a guitar he can
sing you guys he's sing a few tunes and
they sounded perfect I loved it great
show so if you guys get a chance to go
see any Grateful Dead shows if you're a
Grateful Dead fan I definitely recommend
you go check it out I get there early
have a good time enjoy it a lot sing big
shout out to my buddy Gibbs I took Gibbs
with me to the Grateful Dead show and we
had a great time haven't seen Gibbs in
quite a while so it was a wonderful time
hanging out with my brother Gibbs at the
Grateful Dead show showed us the entire
deadhead family I'm gonna keep moving on
with the podcast I feel like I'm really
rambley today so I hope you guys are
into that I've got an event coming up um
on next weekend it's the dude it's
Gatsby Invitational um everybody knows
that I bred this strain of weed for the
lovely Miss dudettes damsel if you guys
aren't following dude it's damsel on
Instagram you're missing out make sure
you go follow my friend dude it's damsel
she's the manager at green &amp; Healthy
Wellness she's an alternative model and
her Instagram pictures will put a smile
on her face but I did breed a strain of
cannabis for our friend damsel and we
are having an official tasting party at
the dude it's Gatsby Invitational on the
fourth and fifth of
a month so I will record I will do my
best to record with damsel and get a
little bit of that onto the show but
what we're gonna do is Daniels bringing
a few of her friends from out of town uh
hunt myself and a couple other dudes
will be at the event we've rented a
house in Manitou Springs it's a private
party of winner we've rented a house and
we're going to have a tasting party I've
got ten jars in front of me I'm gonna
crack one open right now just for fun I
got ten dog jars of herb that I drew for
the lovely damsel it smells so we're
gonna have a little tasting party and
Miss damsel is going to decide which of
these phenotypes gets to be the
selection that will take the name of
damsels dank and then we will get a
clone into the shop and we will start
growing damsels dank at green and
healthy wellness in Colorado Springs and
it will be available on the shelves
it'll be a little while but we'll get it
there and the whole world with a medical
card will be able to try it hopefully
eventually Colorado Springs will wake up
and start allowing recreational cannabis
sales and that way we can make Daniels
tank available to the entire world that
would be awesome big shout out to hunt
for putting me in touch with damsel and
also a huge shout out to the lovely do
dats danzel hey Britt thanks for giving
me the honor of being the breeder chosen
to create a stream for you I understand
how important this is to you and I'm
gonna get it right for you trust me all
right
so the next thing I want to do is a
little grow lesson this will be a very
simple lesson um I was watching a
facebook argument the other day and
people were arguing over a plant being
male or female and I thought I just come
on here and just make it really clear
and simple and we'll talk about what a
male and a female plant look like okay
when it comes time to determine the sex
of your plants there are a few ways you
can go about doing it the main way that
you can do it is to just flower your
plant if you've got a plant and you put
it under 1212 which is 12 hours on and
12 hours off of light and you need full
darkness in your dark cycle you guys you
need complete darkness uninterrupted for
12 full hours if you can see anything in
that room in the dark cycle it is too
bright you need to make it darker
there's if there's any light it's not
dark enough that is not considered dark
if you can see your hand in front of
your face it
is to light in there the only lights
that you can have in a grow room during
the dark cycle are green LED lights or
those green coiled florescent lights
those will work for you need green light
in your dark cycle green lighting during
the flowering cycle does not interrupt
the flowering photo period because the
plants are green and they do not absorb
green light so so by putting any plant
into the 1212 period you will actually
induce the flowering stage in about 10
10 to 14 days ish you'll be able to tell
if your plant is male or female
by signs that it shows and we'll talk
about those here in just a couple of
seconds you guys you can flower a plant
at any size it doesn't matter how big it
is what's gonna happen is it's gonna
flower when you put it into 1212 that's
what's gonna make it flower but what I
always recommend is that you take a
clone from every seed that you grow when
you start a plant from seed please take
a clone from it you never know you might
be growing the most amazing strain
anybody has ever smoked it may be the
perfect medicinal strain for the every
for everybody on the planet for the
entire population it can cure every
element you never know and if you didn't
take a clone oh you're gonna be so mad
at yourself about that hey guys there's
one strain that I grew that got away I
could not get it to clone and it was
some of the best cannabis I've ever
smoked and I'm a little mad at myself
that I couldn't get it to clone but I do
have more seeds of it so hopefully I can
find that phenotype again anyway when
you grow so grow a plant from seed right
and then put it under 1212 and it will
flower I'd always recommend taking a
clone so take a clone now you've got a
plant that is grown for a little while
and you've got a clone
you can either flower out that original
plant that has been growing and that way
you've got a little bit of product to
show for yourself and you've got
something to smoke and make it worth
your time or you can flower out that
clone as soon as that clone that you
took starts showing roots you can switch
that light to 12 12 and that clone will
flower and in 10 to 14 days you'll have
a little tiny plant with either male or
female flowers coming out of it and
you'll be able to tell if you've got a
boy or a girl but at that point you can
either throw away that male plant that
you've got that's in the bigger pot or
you can put that female plant into the
flowering room and start making buds out
of it or keep it as a mother plant keep
taking clones off of it
and have that strain around forever so
take clones you guys and then you can
either clone that original clone or a
flower that original clone as it routes
out and then you can see what you've got
or you can flower that original plant
either way it's gonna do the same thing
and you will know what you've got please
take a clone I can't stress that so also
you guys the plants will show sex if you
let them pre flower if you leave a plant
in a pot for long enough to where it
feels like it's starting to get root
bound and it's reached its space I had
space constraints in that pot it will
actually start to flower on its own some
genetics will just panic and start to
flower on their own that way and they
will show you what is called a pre
flower that's just the plant showing you
that it's reaching maturity then it is
ready to go that it's hormones are built
up that it wants you to switch the
flowering cycle so simply waiting for
the plant to pre flower is a good way to
determine if you've got a male or a
female but then you do waste a lot of
light and a lot of nutrients and a lot
of space and if you're a productive
gardener sometimes you just can't deal
with that that's why I recommend cutting
a clone and flowering out that little
clone and seeing what you've got it's a
lot easier to waste a little bit of time
under a fluorescent light than it is to
waste time under that big thousand watt
high pressure sodium lamp or you could
have been running a useful crop so take
some clones flower amount see what
you're working with and now it feels
like it's time to talk about what to
look for when your plants do start
flowering so that you can tell if you've
got boys or girls basically I'm gonna
call it an intersection but and a node
where the two nodes separate you've got
your main stock coming up and then
you've got the little intersection where
the branch comes off to the left and a
branch comes off to the right ah
right about there your plants are either
gonna grow balls or hairs and I know
that sounds really general but that's
the most simple way to describe this
you're gonna get a pair of balls growing
out right there at that intersection or
you are going to get little hairs if you
see two little hairs sticking up those
are your female plant parts those are
actually the parts that if you were to
spread pollen in the room the pollen
would land on those little pistols those
are called pistols and those pistols
would slide the pollen up into the ovule
which would absorb the pollen which
would then pollinate your plant and then
it would produce seeds so
if you've got those little hairs you
have got girls if you've got those balls
you've got male plants and unless you
plan on making some seeds and doing some
breeding it is time to get those boy
plants out of the room and honestly if
you're listening to this lesson and
you're learning about how to determine
sex please do not breathe cannabis yet
please learn a lot more about plants
before you breed and I'll touch on that
in a minute I'll try to remember to to
mention why
so if you see balls get those plants out
of there also here's a good hint the
male plants I'm a breeder I've been
breeding plants for a long time I've
been growing plants for a really long
time one thing I really notice is the
male plants grow much much taller if
you've got a plant that's just taken off
it's just getting really really tall
it's got a real thick fibrous stalk
that's probably a boy I would just count
on that don't get so excited that you've
got this one plant that grows like a
son-of-a-bitch it is probably a son of
that [ __ ] it's probably a boy you're
gonna want to get rid of that in the
future as soon as you flower it you
won't know pull the males as soon as you
can you guys um if you got male and
female plants flowering next to each
other by day 14 that male plant is
getting ready to drop pollen I've seen
them drop pollen around two weeks into
flower the second to third week that's
that male plant is really gonna start
spitting out as pollen your female
plants are gonna be just ready to take
pollen at that time so you're gonna end
up with a seated crop if you don't pay
attention and get those boys out of
there if you leave those boys in too
long they'll see it up the entire room
very quickly it just takes one quick
little pass of the fan to spread that
pollen through the whole room and then
you've got a pollinated crop you've got
seeds everywhere so pay attention check
every single day get the males out of
there be diligent about it don't relax
stay on top of that [ __ ] get those out
of there all right so it feels like I've
talked enough about male plants and how
to identify them let's talk a little bit
about hermaphrodites because
hermaphrodites can really confuse a new
grower gender Maronites can confuse an
experienced grower or hermaphrodite is
and there are a lot of words for it
you'll hear people call it a hermie or a
herm it's a hermaphrodite you guys it is
a plant that has both male and female
sexes and it will show them hopefully
very early in flower and unfortunately
sometimes you don't see it until like
week eight on a nine meat plant and then
it starts showing a little pollen sack
and then you're like gosh [ __ ] I got to
cut this plant or gonna pick this pollen
sack
you start panicking but let's talk about
hermaphrodites when you see a plant with
male and female parts coming out of it
during flower you've probably got
yourself a hermaphrodite
oftentimes this happens in regular
breeding and it often happens in
feminized seeds this is something that
just happens I breed regular and
feminized seeds a lot of people try to
hate on feminized seeds for
hermaphrodite um if feminized seeds are
made correctly they will not be
hermaphrodites you guys they will they
will be good seeds um I've gotten more
hermaphrodites from regular seeds than I
have from feminized seeds and I'm a
breeder and I run a lot of seeds so I
don't blame it on the feminized seeds at
all I think it is just something that
happens you get males you get females
and you get hermaphrodites there's a
whole goal of this plant it's whole goal
is to reproduce itself that's what it
wants to do it's a horny plant its a
horny male it's a horny girl they just
want to find another plant they want to
make seeds so that the seeds can drop
into the ground and those seeds can
happen again next year
this whole plants goal is to just
reproduce sometimes it will do whatever
it's got to reproduce and one of its
failsafe backup plans is to become a
hermaphrodite
so sometimes that happens now I've said
that that can be a trait that is just in
the plant that can be in the DNA of that
plant it can be that plant can be born
as a hermaphrodite but sometimes
hermaphrodites are caused by environment
or mistakes if you interrupt the dark
cycle during the flowering period I
talked earlier about how you have to
have that complete 1212 photo period
with 12 hours of complete uninterrupted
darkness if you wanna if you interrupt
that you will cause your plants to
hermaphrodite if you seriously if you
open up that door and left that light on
for six hours during one dark cycle you
will start to see male flowers pop up in
your female flowers you'll see it happen
and you will have a seeded plan
it happens like that that is the kind of
thing that can cause from Afrin ISM a
lot of the Kim dog and COO strains if
you push them too hard with nutrients or
just give them a little bit of stress
somehow if they get bugs or powdery
mildew they'll hermaphrodite on you just
in a survival method that is something
that that plant wants to do just to make
sure that it gets to carry on with its
race it just wants to keep going on with
its life so hermaphrodites can be really
confusing [ __ ] does happen like that in
the grow room that's your job as a
grower to be aware of it and to learn
how to identify it so if you see pollen
sacks and pistols on the same plant
you've probably got a hermaphrodite
it is not worth keeping you need to get
rid of that plant no matter how good it
looks no matter how sweet it smells that
plant needs to go now if your plant is
well into the flowering cycle and you've
got big old chunky buds and you're
starting to see these pollen sacs come
up these little male flowers they look
like little bananas you guys it just
looks like maybe a piece of rice or just
it's a little tiny tiny micro sized
banana popping up out of your plants
it's a little male pollen sack this
little male flower coming out of your
female plants oftentimes that stuff will
happen late in flower somewhere between
week seven and nine if your past week
seven or past I'd say past week seven
and you see those you've got a decision
to make any time before week seven you
guys if I see that [ __ ] that plant is
dead I just murder it I've got a veil
ability two more plants I've got access
to seeds and clones like you wouldn't
believe so I'm a little picky I'm not
afraid to euthanize a plant sometimes
[ __ ] just has to go if it doesn't work
for my grow room sometimes a certain
plant and your environment that's it
called a phenotypic expression the plant
will express that it is not happy with
your environment and it won't work for
you and you just got to get rid of that
plant grow a different plant but if you
start seeing those bananas popping up
around week six or seven or eight you
have a decision to make if they're
popping up around week nine it's not
that bad because you've only got a few
days left most plants are gonna go about
nine maybe ten weeks if you've got a
plant that you're ending up week seven
and you start seeing little manners
popping up you want to figure out if you
want to keep that plant going is it
worth risking the rest of the garden
maybe sometimes those little bananas are
sterile and they don't produce pollen
sometimes one of those can rupture and
it will pollinate the plant that that
banana
is on and it will pollinate the plants
all around that plant as well sometimes
it can pollinate the whole room you guys
it doesn't take much pollen to create
seeds and so now you'll have seeds in
all of your plants so you've got a
decision to make do you want to try to
eliminate the plant do you want to risk
it or do you want to try to get rid of
those bananas well you can do to those
little male flowers you can mist them
with water because water deactivates
pollen so just miss to the plant with
water and then get some tweezers and
pluck out those little manners if you're
around week eight week nine just pluck
those out if you want to if you're in
week nine just leave it there and don't
touch it until you harvest and you
should be just fine
if it's popping up at week nine it's
probably sterile but sometimes it's
scary and you don't want to risk it
around week seven or week eight you
might want to pluck them out it's up to
you that's when you have a decision to
make but if you're a breeder
do not ever breed with a plant that'll
make a hermaphrodite little pop up a
little male plant around week seven
eight or nine don't do that because then
you're gonna breed that hermaphroditic
tray into something so make sure you
pull out they're hermaphrodites keep an
eye on that that's that's a decision
you're gonna have to make that's gonna
happen at some point in your grow career
you're gonna see a female plant popping
up a male flower at week eight and
you're gonna panic but don't worry it's
not the end of the world
you can either pluck out that male you
can let it grow or you can just destroy
the plant it's up to you you can always
turn those seated plants into really
good hash I think plants that are
allowed to seed make better hash than
plants without seeds you don't get as
much hash sometimes but I think that the
high is better once you allow the plants
to make seeds and I only know that
because I breed and sometimes when I
breathe there's material left over well
most of the time when I breathe there's
material left over you have to separate
the seeds from the actual bud and we
will run the bud material and turn it
into BHO and I like the seeded BHO
there's no seeds in the pho but I mean
it comes from seeded materials seeds are
removed then we run the material the
seeds are packaged and grown and then
the material is turned into hash and
that hatch seems to get me a little bit
better of a buzz that's my opinion
I talked earlier about new growers not
breeding and hermaphrodites are a little
bit of why let me touch Juan why I said
please don't breed if you're a new
grower breeding takes a very selective
eye you need to understand what plants
you're putting together and if you're
putting a plant a plant needs to be
properly tested before it's bred I have
talked about how I stress test a plant
before I'll breed with it I'll take a
girl plant and I will try to piss that
plant off the best I can and see what it
takes to make that plant hermaphrodite
or die or stress or whatever and I make
sure it's not gonna harm on me and more
importantly I make sure that the progeny
the offspring the seeds that come from
that female plant I make sure that
they're not going to hermaphrodite on
you so you have to have a plant you have
to stress the [ __ ] out of it you have to
have a properly selected male the I for
a male selection is a skill I plan to
have a conversation with other breeders
on this show about male selection so
we'll give you a heads up on that
but selecting a male is definitely a
special skill selecting plants for
breeding is a it's a skill it's an art
and if you're not experienced with the
plants you're using you may breed some
[ __ ] and then you're gonna have a
bunch of seeds and you're gonna give
those seeds out and you're gonna grow
those [ __ ] seeds and it's going to
the whole idea of breeding cannabis is
to improve the genetics to improve the
race to make the plant better and if
you're breeding [ __ ] into it you're
just watering it down and you're
spreading genetics that are a waste of
time there are a waste of people's
garden space when they could have been
growing some usable medicine that would
have worked for them so I'm not dissing
any new growers I'm just asking you
please don't try to breed until you're a
little more familiar with the plant if
you have to listen to a podcast and
learn how to sex your plant then you're
not ready to breed and I'm just being
honest with you learn slowly and then
when you're ready to breed I'll be here
to help you out I'm not trying to get
rid of you I'm just trying to be honest
with you that's the truth how to grow
and then we'll learn how to breed he had
learned ride the bike before he could do
wheelies brah alright it feels like I've
been going on for about 30 minutes let's
see look at that you guys I went 29
minutes and I didn't even make any notes
I didn't look at the clock that was a
great episode I feel like I did a good
job I hope you guys
enjoy listening to that little lesson on
how to sex your ganja plants I want to
start wrapping up the show you guys make
sure that you check out my favorite
glass company hitman glass make sure you
support a hitman glass go to hitman
glass comm make sure you support a
hitman glass Dougie on Instagram make
sure you support all the hit fam there
are a ton of hitman glass makers you can
follow them all on Instagram if you'd
like to check them out and see what
they're doing in the shop you guys hit
man's got it going on
they've got hitman farms they're
producing their own line of concentrates
in California they make glass they make
clothing they've got nails it sounds
like they're now doing sales and
distribution of fine smoking accessories
so you can get your hitman glass smoking
accessories at hitman glass com make
sure you check that out make sure you
put a little note on there let them know
that you learned about them from the
girl from your heart podcast is they can
know that you're listening to the show
also check out the chalice festival if
you're gonna be in California this
summer
you want to go to the chalice festival
it's a music hash and art festival put
on by Doug Ephraim hit man glass Dougie
is a hash enthusiast he is a dab kid
Doug's got styled Doug's got class you
want to go to a festival thrown by mr.
dougie right on to dougie thanks for
helping out the community and huge
thanks for being a supporter of the
podcast
I truly appreciate it alright it's time
to wrap up the podcast you guys I want
to thank everybody for listening I'll be
back in 7 days with another episode if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast but if you've got a product
you'd like me to review send me an email
let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you do need you guys
now that the show is over please go to
the iTunes Store
find the girl from your heart podcast
find the review section I'll give me a
little five star rating type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will give you a shout out
and read your comment on a future
episode if you've got something you'd
like to say you can find me on all the
social media I'm on Facebook let's just
grow from your heart we are on Twitter
it's @gf wih podcast I am back on
Instagram I mentioned earlier that they
deleted the IRA Genetics account from
Instagram I am bad
it's Irie underscore genetics so follow
me there if you want to check me out on
Instagram and of course you can always
email me it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you guys don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is always and
forever archived on ira genetics
colorado comm since they took down the
instagram that's got me paranoid that
things can disappear from the internet
so if there's any ever a time that I'm
not on your whatever service you're
listening to if you're good if you've
got me on stitcher if you've got me on
iTunes if I ever disappear from there I
will always in forever be on I read
genetics Colorado calm and that is my
website they cannot take that away from
me babble on cannot control what I put
there so this show will always be there
I don't forget that there's a donation
button on the podcast page on the
website if you feel like the show is
worth a few bucks and you'd like to make
contribution contribution go to my
website it's I read genetics Colorado
com click on the growth my heart a
podcast tab at the top right there is a
donation button that goes directly to my
PayPal account you guys I'm never gonna
charge you for this podcast this podcast
will always be free but if you feel like
making a contribution it would
definitely be appreciated and I will
give you a huge shout out once again
shout out to our friend said from
Australia
dude I seriously appreciate what you did
for me that is awesome
so I hope to see you guys on the social
media sites I think that's all I've got
free this week I'll see you in seven
days big shout out to hit man glass
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening and until next time
you guys take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
nah
not solely buddies
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 109 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education a new
smoker for a veteran dabber cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys for
joining me
as always I need to send a huge
thank-you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band thanks for letting me
use your music on my show big thanks to
Kat ku and the entire mystic roots crew
hope everybody's having a great
afternoon morning evening whatever it is
wherever you are hope you got something
rolled up hope you got a fat dad but you
got a vaporizer hope you got an edible
in you hope you got something good going
on / getting turfed out in some way
shape or form hey guys this is another
episode that comes from the car but this
is a sort of a part - recently I did an
episode about ways to improve your
garden well this is a part two of that
episode more ways on how to improve your
garden I also include a little rant
toward the end I did have to stop
recording halfway through because I
arrived at my destination but I did
start recording on the way home so
there's a little cut in the middle but I
hope you enjoy that before I go too far
this podcast is brought to you by my
good friends at Hitman glass big shout
outs to the crew at Hitman glass make
sure you support hitman dougie in the
entire Hitman glass crew hitman glass is
made in America by Americans today we're
hitting the Hitman and Sampson collab
this is one of my favorite rigs in my
collection
I'd say a 6 inch tall can with a
straight up I love the piece where the
ball or the nail attaches goes straight
up it's got a mouthpiece that comes out
of the side it's got a beautiful green
worked base maybe a turquoise color in
there it's got a green hitman logo here
on the side it's got a green hitman
flame across the mouthpiece there I'm
gonna do myself a fat favor we're gonna
take a DAB and then we are going to get
into the part of the podcast where I am
in the car so I'm gonna start heating up
this nail I'm gonna let the music fade
in and then I will be in the car the
next time you hear my voice so I'm gonna
take a DAB make sure that's my friends a
hitman make sure you guys follow hitman
glass make sure you check out hitman
glass
call make sure you support him on
Instagram make sure you follow hit man
glass dougie there are a bunch of
members of the hitman fam if you type in
you'll find a bunch of great glass that
you would like to follow and you'd like
to see more of make sure you check that
out shut up the Hitman glass big thanks
for supporting the show yeah what's a
podcast world that your boy Rasta Jeff
coming to you with another episode from
the car I'm headed northbound on i-25
I'm currently passing through the lovely
town of fountain Colorado I'm on my way
to Colorado Springs I'm headed to the
grow it green and healthy wellness I've
got to go do the evening check we are
now in flower so I need to go check on
the plants just before the lights go off
I need to go make sure that the timer
shuts off appropriately make sure that
all the heating and cooling works the
way it should for the night cycles go
check out some clones anyway been
spending a lot of time on the road I
don't have a lot of time at home or
studio time the past week this weekend
was the dude it's Gatsby Invitational so
I spent most of the weekend in Colorado
Springs with the Graeme Gatsby family so
Springs with the grimy Gatsby family the
dude it's damsel crew and the Terr pecks
boys I recorded two podcasts they need
to be edited and put together from the
weekend but they will be out pretty soon
that should be episodes 110 and maybe
112 I might put another episode between
there you never know what I'm going to
do but I've got a couple episodes coming
to you from the house in Colorado
Springs where we hosted the dude it's
Gatsby Invitational a house full of
models and dab kids there's a pretty
good time I would have to say I would
recommend that you guys go to Instagram
if you're on Instagram go to Instagram
and search the hashtag dude its Gatsby
and check out some of the shots we took
there also check out some of the shots
on dude it's damsels Instagram and also
on the grimy Gatsby on Instagram and of
course you can check out my new
Instagram
I understand attics and Instagram is my
new page I did start a new Instagram you
guys I don't know if I've mentioned that
on the podcast yet but I am back on
Instagram trying to follow all of the
rules I've been told that you can't put
photos of yourself consuming cannabis so
that means no dab videos no fat joint
shots none of that kind of stuff and I
was told that you can't have contact
information on your Instagram so I'm not
going to put any contact information up
there just to keep us safe you guys know
how to find me make sure you go follow
the new Instagram page I was at 19,000
followers they took me down
I am already back up to about fifteen or
sixteen hundred by the time this airs
hopefully with all the shout outs and
things from damsel damsel from the
weekend I'll be close to the 2500 mark
anyway that's enough rambling about the
due dates Gatsby Invitational I really
encourage you guys to go look at some of
the pictures that were taken on
Instagram and we will also post a
podcast that tells you all about the due
dates Gatsby Invitational
what it is who was involved and why it
happened I've got a head at that down
it's a great show
we got stupid hi you guys so it'll be a
fun show to listen to anyways I'm
driving on the interstate I'm kind of
rambly let's talk about something I've
got a couple of notes here they're hard
to read cause I'm driving but I wrote
this down I've been watching a show on
Netflix a show called narcos it's a show
about Pablo Escobar and his drug empire
that he created I had no idea the dude
was so huge I knew he was huge but I
didn't know that this dude was super
huge this guy I've never seen that kind
of money nobody else has ever seen that
kind of money that dude was building
forts out of hundred dollar bills pretty
much that [ __ ] is awesome anyway
something that happens in the show
narcos narcos is on Netflix it's a 10
season or a 10 episode season I
recommend you watch it something that
happened recently made me chuckle I
wanted to come out on the show and say
that [ __ ] will not work so Pablo Escobar
is standing on the balcony having a
little thought time by himself he's just
thinking and reflecting and staring off
into the know where and then he turns to
the right and there's a ganja plant to
the right of him and it looks it's not
mature it's nowhere near done
and Pablo just grabs a little bud off
the stalk and pinches it off and gives
it a good smell and sticks it into his
pocket you guys that may do a little for
him but that weed is gonna suck
that plant was not finished you can't
just pick buds off of a plant randomly
it's not like an apple tree
you gotta harvest it you got to trim it
you gotta try it you gotta do it
properly so that was a little goofy but
everything about the cocaine about the
production the shipment everything about
cocaine seems to be accurate they've
talked about how they make cocaine how
they processed cocaine how they hide
cocaine all of that has seemed to be
fairly accurately done but when it came
to to growing a little bit of weed they
had no idea what they were talking about
on that show all right you guys I wanted
to mention that let's see I talked about
the dude it's Gatsby invitation I'm
trying to go through my notes here so
this podcast is going to be a follow-up
to a recent show recently I did an
episode that was aimed at how to improve
your crop once I posted that show I
realized there were a couple of things
that I really skipped things that I've
been thinking about that would
definitely help you improve your crop
that I should have mentioned in that
show so let me scroll up on my phone
here while I'm driving sorry guys you
gotta be patient with me trying to do
this safely more ways to improve your
crop we need to talk about the
importance of pH here that sorry we need
to talk about the importance of pH pH
stands for potential hydrogen pH is
super important for your plants when
you're making a solution when you're
mixing your nutrients in your bucket or
in your reservoir however you're mixing
it you need to adjust the pH before you
feed it to your plants mix up all of
your nutrients have everything in there
get a pH meter stick your pH pin your pH
meter in there and see what the pH says
it fits like seven it needs to come down
you guys you want your pH for your
plants to be somewhere between six and
6.5 I think you'd be much happier your
plants will look better they'll take up
the nutrients more properly the plants
will grow better you won't see as many
problems a lot of times a pH problem
will mask itself as a deficiency or a
nutrient burn so if you just go ahead
and fix your pH you have to fix the pH
of the solution you're feeding your
plants if you're feeding it nutrients if
you're feeding it water adjust the pH if
you guys are feeding it teas don't mess
with the pH of a tea because
tea is organic trying to add something
to bring down the pH of your tea will
probably kill off your microbes and
whatever you're trying to build up in
the tea so just let that go that'll be
fine don't stress too much on the pH of
your soil if you bought good soil at a
gross store your pH will be just fine as
long as you're feeding it properly pH
nutrients a properly pH solution so once
you're done mixing up your nutrients pH
and get some pH and get a pH pin stick
it in there and see what it says add
very little pH down if you're using a
five gallon jug it's not gonna take much
pH down to get your pH to drop massively
so check your pH pay attention to the pH
I see a lot of people skipping that they
think it's not important they think it's
not gonna mess with their plants they
think it's just one more thing to worry
about but it's one more thing that can
definitely improve the quality of your
plants alright so adjust the pH also
let's talk about the importance of
getting the whites close enough excuse
me gotta clear the throat there I see a
lot of people with their lights real
high in the garden if you're using
DeVita's you do need that 3-foot gap but
unless you're using double ended bulbs
there's no need to have the bulbs way
high above the plants if you've got the
type of hoods that are ducted and have
glass inside of them and if you're
venting them properly and the room is
air-conditioned you can probably get
those those light reflectors right down
on top of the plants really close you
want to get them there's a section that
comes off the bulb that is kind of too
bright for the plant and those those
illumines I guess they are that are
coming off the bulb right there that
spectrum is too much for the plant right
around the plant that 8 to 10 maybe 12
inch circle around the bulb but if you
get a little further about 10 12 maybe
14 inches away from that thousand watt
bulb you're gonna get optimal growth
right there if you can cool it and keep
it cooler you can get closer and pay
attention to the plants and see what's
happening but I see a lot of people that
have their lights way too far away from
the plants get your plants closer to
your lights you want to get that light
right on there nice and intense light is
the most used nutrient that your plants
will receive so make sure you flood them
with light and also try to give them the
appropriate light if you're in the veg
cycle you want lights that lean more to
the blue spectrum if you're in the
flowering cycle you want lights that
lead more to the red spectrum alright so
make sure you've got enough light try to
get your plants close to the light and
use as much as you can you guys you can
burn your plants with your light so pay
attention to that but get them close
it's what you want to do alright let's
see what is my next note say my next
note says co2 in Richmond I didn't write
a lot of notes about this but co2 in
Richmond if you want to improve the
quality of your crop if you want to make
your plants grow more quickly more
heartily and if you want bigger fatter
harvests add a little bit of co2 in a
Richmond to your grow room you can go to
the gross store and you can get tanks of
co2 and you can get a set up to
distribute the co2 properly through your
room you may have to rethink your
ducting in your ventilation situation if
you're gonna do that but co2 will
drastically increase the quality of your
grow maybe not the quality completely
but the harvest weight you will
definitely see a difference the ambient
air outside and in your grow room
probably contains about 400 particles
per million of co2 if you get an
enrichment system maybe a co2 burner
maybe some tanks whatever you decide to
do you're gonna have to think about that
one and talk to the guys at the hydro
shop maybe do some research on that if
you're gonna put co2 in your room you're
gonna need to think about how to do it
but what my point is you can get that
co2 up to like 1600 PPM's you can get it
four times what it is in the natural
environment and your plants will love it
those plants want to suck up the co2 so
you can add co2 to your grow and
would greatly increase your harvest
weight so what you're gonna add co2 and
you're gonna start getting bigger buds
something that really helps with all
gardens and something I'm learning now
that I'm running this giant commercial
garden is trellising you guys trellising
and like a screen of green method if you
can set up a scrog that is a huge way to
improve your crop you will give yourself
more canopy space more canopy space
gives you more room to grow more buds
everybody wants more buds also you're
able to get more airflow to the bottom
of the plants the plants like that I
think that a sprog is the way to go I'll
do a whole episode on how to do a scrub
when I'm in the studio and I'm not on
the road because I would definitely want
to pay a little bit of attention Spence
and I talked about it a while back but I
wasn't sold on the idea and I wasn't
exactly sure how to do it so I didn't do
the idea justice but you guys we will
talk about how to scrog on a future
episode all right so use some sort of
trellising system a screen of green a
net get those plants in there and get
them supported get them spread out that
would definitely help with your garden
something that I see a lot of people
neglecting to do that I think would
greatly improve the quality of your
garden it'll also save your trimmers a
lot of headaches you guys I think it
would be really useful for you to get in
there and lollipop' your plants a little
bit so what that means is from the
bottom of the plant up take off all the
branches that don't have a useful bud
sight there is that don't look like
they're gonna create a chunky bud just
cut those off about ten days into flower
you'll know where you're gonna have buds
if the light is not getting to that area
just pinch that little starter of a bud
just pinch that right off all those
little tiny sucker stems that are
growing off your main stalk at the
bottom of the plant that are gonna make
little shitty flowers then nobody wants
to trim cut that [ __ ] off of there and
that will allow that plant to use its
energy to produce bigger buds up top you
won't have all that crap on the bottom
you'll get better airflow a lot of
people say they want to use those bottom
butts for hash that's cool if you want
to do that if you're trying to grow buds
with bag appeal big fatty chunky Nuggets
cut that stuff off of there
and you will have better results you'll
have better airflow and then you won't
have to trim all that little popcorn
crap cuz that's what sucks at the end
all that just gets chopped up and put
into the hash pile anyway so do some
lolli popping get in there and clean all
the bottom buds all the just the bottom
crap off the plant before it even has
time to suck up the nutrients and suck
up the energy of the plant just get that
right off of there and allow that energy
to go up to the top alright so let's see
something that people really don't think
about that I think could truly benefit
the quality of your garden and the
health of your plants the overall health
of your plants it's wintertime here in
Colorado and the grow room floor is
getting cold
my personal grow is in a basement
something I would recommend to get your
pots up off the ground you guys get your
plants off the ground a really easy way
to do it if you can't build something if
you can't build a table I would
recommend getting like a 4 by 4 Botanic
hare tray and just build yourself a
little table that'll support the tray
and your plants just lift it up whatever
is comfortable for you 2 to 4 feet off
the ground usually about 30 inches is
the height people go 36 inches is kind
of high for me I'm tall I don't need it
that high so just get your plants up off
the ground the pot the floor is cold you
don't want those cold pots on the cold
floor
you're gonna water them the water is
gonna stay in the pot you've got water
down there in the root ball and that
water is gonna get cold because the
floor is so cold when the lights go off
at night so raise your pots up off the
ground I was gonna tell you a cheap and
effective way to do that buy an extra
pot if you're running a seven gallon pot
and you've got your plant in there get
yourself another seven gallon pot and
flip it upside down and just set your
seven gallon pot right on top of there
and you'll be just fine
so that's a cheap effective way to get
your plants up off the ground your
plants are gonna it's gonna look like
your plants are happier just one night
of having them up off the ground they'll
grow more quickly the buds will develop
much larger it'll taste better the
plants will act happier and that cold
floor will also describe disguise itself
as a pH or a nutrient problem you'll be
thinking what's going on with my crop
your floor is too cold and your plants
are pissed off you don't like to get up
in the morning and walk across a cold
floor in your bare feet that sucks so
don't make your plants do it get them up
off the ground and that may help you get
them a little bit closer to the light as
well I may have just put you in danger
of getting too close to the light but
that's some
that the trellising we're gonna talk
about in another episode we'll help you
out with
so get your plants up off the ground you
guys I'm in a traffic area so I can't
really look at my notes right now so
while I'm driving right here I'm just
gonna give you a huge shout out to hit
man glass because hit man glass sponsors
the show and there's nothing like taking
a fat out of a hit man ring all right
we're getting out of the traffic area I
can look down at the phone once again
and see what the next one is all right
here we go check your PPM's of your
solution when you guys are mixing up
your nutrients to feed your plants pay
attention to the PPM's PP M stands for
particles per million that will tell you
how much stuff is in the water or the
solution that you have created so if
you're using reverse osmosis water it'll
start off at 0 ppm s most tap water is
gonna come out fairly low the tap water
where I am at home comes out about 400
ppm s it changes seasonally they add
stuff to it but we're usually about the
400 ppm area you can feed your plants if
you know what you're doing you can feed
them really high I've gotten into the
2000s people tell me I'm crazy for
feeding my plants 2,000 ppm s but I'm
paying very close attention to what I'm
giving them I'm not doubling up on
anything they're getting a broad array
of nutrients instead of just getting
really heavily blasted with phosphorous
so I would recommend that you don't go
much higher than like 1200 PPM's when
you're mixing up your nutrients what you
can do if you've got a big reservoir if
you're using this is gonna be a little
harder if you're using a five-gallon
bucket because you don't get as much
wiggle room but if you're using like a
25 gallon rez or a 50 gallon rez from
the hydro shop fill it up maybe like 40
gallons if you got a 50 gallon or s fill
it up to about 40 gallons if you got a
25 fill it up to about 15 or 20 then mix
your nutrients the way you normally
would put your ppm meter in there and
it's gonna show you that it's too high
right now but all you got to do is just
run normal water or if you've got
reverse osmosis water just that normal
clean non solution mixed water to it
until it comes to about 16 or 1800 PPM's
and feed that to your plant you can mix
it up and then dilute it until it's at
the right dilution and everything will
be at the right ratios you've still
mixed the
Agro a the same amount of Grobe the same
amount of Cal and mag everything will be
the same it's just you've kind of
diluted it to a proper solution that
your plants are gonna love and then take
notes feed your plants the solution that
was at 1600 PPM's and see how they react
if you think you want to mix it a little
heavier next time and mix it up to 18
sheet it to them and see what they do
don't go too heavy don't go past the 18
pay attention to your ppm s but I think
that is something that will really help
you guys out this guy just passed me on
the ride going about 90 miles an hour
playing on his phone that's crazy [ __ ] I
can't talk too much [ __ ] I'm doing a
podcast while I Drive but still at least
put your phone down if you're gonna pass
me on the right all right guys I'm
coming up on the Fillmore exit I'm gonna
go handle some plants at the green and
healthy wellness garden I will be back
in the car in just a couple hours and I
will do more of this podcast and we will
all have a good time so hang out I'll be
right back all right podcast world I am
back at your boy Rasta Jeff I just got
done putting in about two and a half or
three hours in the grow I had to fill up
some reservoirs we've got three gigantic
reservoirs we've got a drip system set
up tour every about two and a half hours
the drip system comes on for about a
minute and a half and waters the plants
so I just have to make sure that the
reservoirs are fooled Fulda they're
filled and they are mixed with nutrients
improperly pH so I did that I checked on
the clones the clones look marvelous I'm
not really good at cutting clones in
rock wool but this batch is looking
pretty nice for me I checked on all the
plants the plants look glorious you guys
today is day two of flower they're
taking off I can see that they've
already started to stretch a little tiny
bit since yesterday I know that sounds
ridiculous but they have definitely done
some growth so I checked the tanks to
check the clones I checked on all the
plants the plants look happy they are
starting to flower they're not showing
but I mean they're starting the
flowering phase now and then I had to
tinker with the Gavita controller so we
got that working all set up those plants
are gonna be super duper happy now I'm
on the road headed south back to Pueblo
from lovely Colorado Springs it is now
dark the temperature has dropped
dramatically I am just now headed past
the which exit am i I hear the Fort
Carson the mesa ridge parkway fort
carson exit we're at mile marker 132
then
is relevant I'm just talking because it
is what's on my mind let's get back to
where we were you guys this episode was
about ways more ways to improve your
garden we talked about co2 enrichment we
talked a little bit about trellising I
want to talk about trellising for a
second
so trellising will go back to that
trellising is when you take like a net
like a five by five net with about
either four inch or six inch squares
spaces between the netting you got about
four inch or six inch holes in there so
I would take the net and just you got to
stretch it tight but build like a
five-foot frame or attach it to some
poles and just lay that right over the
canopy of your plants while you're in
avenge just drop that right over and
pull it tight and then what I do is I
grab the branches from the plants and I
make sure that one branch is sticking
through each square of that trellis so
this will it'll do a few things it'll
separate the plant it's where you don't
have a bunch of branches all clumped up
into one area which will allow more of
the plant to get more light it will also
work as a support for the plant when the
plant starts gettin chunky buds and the
plant starts getting taller and
stretching it's gonna need some support
so every branch will be supported by
this trellis so it'll also spread the
plant out it'll give you a little space
and it'll do it'll create what I call
the little grid you'll be able to grow
on the grid you'll have more bud sites
per square foot than most people because
you have gone and stretched out your
canopy and spread it out in this trellis
so in veg a couple of weeks before a
flower drop that trellis on and start
making the plants grow into the trellis
and get them stretched out the way you
want then I would recommend flowering
once they're all up through there you've
got a node coming through every part of
the trellis you're comfortable with the
height of your plants any guys if
something's getting too high all you got
to do is grab it and bend it down back
under that trellis and then it'll start
growing up again
Cannabis wants to grow up that's what
it'll do so if you bend a branch down
and stick it in that trellis it will
grow itself back up so after a couple of
weeks you put the plants in flower after
they've edged into the trellis and Grunk
grown comfortably then you put them in
Flour and then just a couple of weeks
after flower maybe ten days after flower
I would recommend putting up another
trellis maybe less than ten days maybe
seven days put up another trellis just
about eighteen inches
higher than that first one your plants
are gonna start budding and they're
gonna grow right into that trellis maybe
16 inches if you're at a home grow we're
doing a commercial drill we're going
about 18 inches to give them some space
maybe 24 just depends on how fast they
grow by then but you want them to grow
up into that trellis to where those top
colas have more space to lean they're
gonna kind of lean on those trellis
wires so make sure you pull the trellis
tight when you put it up there get it at
the right height to begin with pull the
branch nodes through that trellis don't
be shy be careful not to break them but
don't be shy to get in there and just
kind of reshape that plant make it go
the direction you want and then I'll get
it growing into that trellis squares and
then add the other trellis a little bit
into flower and then keep the buds
growing through that and you'll be able
to create more bud sites more buds more
harvest weight without adding more light
or without using more space in your grow
room and I find that to be a huge
improvement so something else I want to
touch on you guys this is a major
important factor that people overlook
they say that cleanly cleanliness is
next to godliness so something that
would really improve your garden you
guys just clean up after yourselves get
in the garden and clean up if it doesn't
need to be in there take it out of there
you don't need to have the broom and
dustpan in there overnight when you're
not using it if you've got a trash can
in your grow room make sure there's a
lid on it I would recommend taking that
trash can out of the grow room at night
don't have anything in the room that
doesn't need to be in there clean up all
that crap in the corner or whatever
you've got over there if it's your
nutrients if your if it's your notes if
it's your gear clean that up take that
out of the grow room if you've got
leaves on the floor get those leaves up
off the floor now here's something I'm
gonna kind of contradict myself with but
I think it's really important to have a
super clean grow room cleanliness will
keep bugs away cleanliness just helps
you keep everything more organized
it keeps healthier plants but here's
something that I'm gonna add to this
around week 6 or 7 your plants are gonna
start getting really sticky they're
gonna start producing resin the
trichomes are gonna get fat the plants
are gonna want to stick to everything if
you're a girl or a dude with long hair
you'll notice that every time you walk
past the ganja plants you leave some
hair in them
if you're a pot photographer you'll
notice that every time you try to take a
picture that one killer bud has got a
dog hair or a people hair or a kitty
hair or some kind of hair in it what I'm
getting at you guys is these sticky
plants love to collect everything and
you're gonna give them about 21 to 25
days of straight sticky collection time
they're gonna be sticky for three weeks
so in that whole time they're acting
like flypaper I just collecting
everything that's in that room so my
advice to you guys is try to control the
dust that's in the air in your grow room
try to control the particulates and hair
that is flying around that are flying
around in your grow room try to minimize
all of that stuff because it's going to
stick to your buds and end up in your
buds and these days most of the people
in Colorado in California in a legal
state that are producing a grow at least
half of the grows are being turned into
extracts which means they're being
blasted with butane they're being turned
into water hash they're being turned
into some sort of concentrate what's
gonna happen is you're gonna take so
you're in your grow room right and
you're not cleaning up after yourself
and you're mixing soil for your next
batch or whatever you do in there and
you get dust all in the air you get soil
all in the air all of that [ __ ] is going
to stick to your trichomes all of it and
then you're gonna smoke those plants and
they're gonna taste like dusty dirt and
then you're gonna extract it make hash
out of it and all that dust and dirt and
[ __ ] and dog hair is going to be in your
concentrates so I really recommend you
keep the grow room clean try to minimize
dust and hair in the air you can get a
carbon scrubber I just throw a tall
carbon filter on the floor point it
straight up put a blower on top of it
and just let put that sucker by your
door kind of near the door so that way
any air that is drawn in any particles
will get sucked up by your carbon filter
hopefully and also on any intakes going
into the room I would recommend putting
a HEPA filter over all of the holes or
all of the ducting into the room so
you're not bringing in crap from outside
I definitely don't recommend
bringing in air from the outside that
has not been filtered and treated for
temperature right now it's the winter if
you were to bring in it's gonna be
probably 20-something degrees tonight
I'm guessing if you're running your
lights at night and you bring in that 20
degree air over your plants you're gonna
cause powdery mildew issue you're
bringing in frosty cold air you're
introducing it into a warm draw room
environment that is a great way to
create powdery mildew situations so pay
attention to what you're bringing in the
room be clean that's my point you guys
every leaf on the floor is a spot for a
bug to hide every piece of crap that
you've got in there is another place for
a bug to hide it's a place for a mold
spore to start growing just be clean
cleanliness is very important in the
grow room all right guys I think that's
what I've got free four ways to improve
your garden for now all right guys thank
you for listening to another episode I
don't think that the car episodes are up
to my quality standards the sound
quality and the amount of attention I am
allowed to give a show doesn't seem like
it's fair to the listener I am going to
probably stop doing the car episodes if
I do a car episode it will just be
something ranty it won't be something
educational or detailed so I appreciate
it if you made it through this episode I
truly do appreciate it thanks for
listening I'll be back next week with
the dudettes damsel or the dude it's
Gatsby Invitational recap that features
the lovely dude it's damsel we've got
hot on the mic for a little bit of that
show and four other lovely ladies our
friend Chris from the clear jumps in for
a little bit it's a great podcast and
I'll have that edited and cleaned up and
ready for you guys by next Monday so I
got seven days to get that out for you
no worries at all you guys make sure you
check out our sponsors I don't forget
about hit man glass this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
Hitman glass hit man glass glass made in
America by Americans because I've said
it before when I'm shopping for a rig I
like to know that what I'm paying for is
gonna give me a big fat dab I don't want
to get water splashed in my face I don't
want to get a dried a because there's
not enough water in there guys don't
trust a rig that was made in China
by a Chinese kid with no eye protection
probably wasn't wearing shoes he didn't
get paid enough don't buy some glass
made in China you guys buy American
glass made by an American it'll make you
feel better a man's not only a glass
company you guys hit man
each part of the cannabis and hash
movement support a hitman glass and be
sure to check out the chalice Festival
in California
go follow hitman glass on Instagram
there at hitman glass dougie search for
hitman glass don't you give them a
follow be sure to visit hitman glass
dot-com today you guys as I'm recording
right now I'm taking dad's out of the
hitman and Sampson collab this is one of
my favorite rigs in my collection I've
got several hitman rigs this is one of
the top two I think this one in the e
series sidecar might be the favorite
we'll hit the next favorite on the next
podcast so you guys make sure you
support hitman class big shot at the
Hitman dougie big shot in the hole hit
fan the hitman crew much love much
respect much support I love being able
to rely on a sweet rig alright well quit
kissing hit man's ass for a couple of
seconds and move on the show much love
to the hitman crew guys if you want to
sponsor the podcast send me an email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to get your product on the
show if you've got a product you'd like
me to review send that to me I'll give
it an honest review right here on the
podcast we'll open it up we'll test it
out we'll see what it does we'll talk
about it we'll post pictures to
Instagram
speaking of Instagram you guys make sure
you follow the new Instagram they took
down the original one about 19,000
followers I'm back up to about 1,500
followers I'm not working as hard at
getting followers
I'm just posting pictures for fun this
time I posted a lot of great cannabis
pictures you can go ahead and follow the
new Instagram it's at ireon ders core
genetics
I read genetics with an underscore right
in the middle there make sure you check
that out all right I think that's what
I've got free this week you guys know
that the show's over make sure you go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the review section give me a five star
rating and after that type in a little
comment let me know what you think of
the show and you guys I will read your
comment on a future episode it's hard to
leave comments on stitcher but if you
leave one there and I see it I will read
your comment on the show but stitcher
isn't as sufficient with the comments as
iTunes you can also email me it's go
from your heart at hotmail.com you can
find me on Facebook under grow from your
heart I am on Twitter did I say that at
G fyh podcast because we're easy to find
there's a part that I skipped what
happened here my brain just melt there
you go guys don't forget to the shows
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on ira genetics colorado comm
you guys there is a donation button on
the podcast page on the website
if you feel like this show is worth a
couple bucks you can go to my website
it's called I read genetics Colorado
comm IRI e GE and ET ICS Colorado calm
I read genetics Colorado calm people
often ask me what the word Irie means I
Ria's our Jamaican word it means to feel
as blessed as you could feel I means to
just be as powerful as powerful could be
you know when you're sitting with your
best friend or your lady friend or
whoever it could be your dog or by
yourself when you're sitting there and
you just feel good the wind is blowing
through your hair you know got a problem
in the world right now everything just
feels good you're like yeah that feeling
that comes over you they're feeling Irie
that is right there so we got the Huayra
genetics also anyway go to I read
genetics Colorado comm click on the girl
from your heart a podcast tab at the top
right there is a donation button it's a
little PayPal button that goes directly
to my PayPal account you guys I'm never
gonna charge you anything for this
podcast this podcast will always and
forever be free but if you feel like
making a contribution that would greatly
be appreciated our friend said from Down
Under through down a few bucks a couple
of weeks ago and it was great timing I
definitely appreciate it so you guys I
said before we're on all the social
media sites make sure you check me out
there I appreciate each and every one of
you for listening to the show and
following me on any form of social media
you can check me out on periscope don't
forget about that one you guys I want to
give a huge shout out to my ninja spin
so thanks again for listening and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug
[Music]
yeah welcome back canopies community
it's time for episode number 110 if the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation grower if your professional
grower appear a new smoker or a veteran
dapper if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross
the Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my show big thanks to Kat and
the entire mystic roots crew what's up
everybody hope you guys are having a
great evening afternoon morning whatever
time it is wherever you are
hope you're hanging out getting some
turps in your head hope you're smoking a
fat joint hope you got a vaporizer
packed up hope you got a DAB ready hope
you get the he nail turned on eating
some edibles you might be smoking a
blunt that's like not my favorite but if
you're smoking a lot more power to you
do what you got to do get it in your
head give them Terps in your mind set
yourself free you guys this is gonna be
a great episode this is the episode that
I recorded in Colorado Springs from the
dude it's Gatsby Invitational there are
a lot of great folks in this episode
this episode features the grimy Gatsby
this episode features Chris from the
clear concentrates and it definitely
features a whole bunch of lovely ladies
before we get to that there's podcast is
brought to you by our great friends at
Hitman glass that's right hit man glass
you guys there I'm sitting over here
hitting V hit man mini sidecar with the
hammer head I grabbed this one because
it's got a yellow label on it and I
haven't seen a lot of hit man with a
yellow label I really liked it that it
looked fresh the hammer had Perkin this
thing you guys oh my god this thing it's
like a [ __ ] boss you know what I'm
talking about it I'm gonna heat this up
for a second Erewhon more rambling about
hitting
glass let's see what else do I have to
say brother summer take a fat dab to
some gorillas what is it it's a gorilla
glue live resin from the garden of
Weeden so let's take a DAB here but this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends at hitman glass I'm shopping for
a raki guys I want a rig that I know is
gonna hit like a truck it's not gonna
splash water in my mouth and I also want
a rig made by an American in America and
not made by some Chinese kid without
protective eyewear with no shoes and not
getting paid so you guys I represent hit
man glass my glass made in America hit
man glass is a huge part of the cannabis
and hash movement make sure you check
out www.montgomeryvillenissan.com
[Music]
for supporting the podcast you guys I
don't have a lot else to say let's get
into the episode let's a time travel
back a few days to Colorado Springs
it was a lovely snowy afternoon there
were a bunch of lovely ladies in the
house or a bunch of turfy dudes in the
house there was a table table covered in
great food and good hash and good weed
so as a party let's let the music take
us right into that part of the episode
and then I'll be back to wrap up the
show after that all right what's up
ladies and gentlemen it's your boy Rasta
Jeff I am here in beautiful Colorado
Springs looking out a giant window
looking at a lovely day it's snowing
like a son-of-a-bitch
it's gorgeous out there sitting across
from me you guys I am here at the the
dude it's Gatsby Invitational and
sitting across from me is the lovely
dude it's danzel how you doing today
[Music]
it sounds it looks like the weed that I
grew is working for the whole house for
four days now nice I like that I like
that well our friend Brittany is joining
us she's known as dude at snaps or her
real name's Brittany hey thanks for
being on the show I appreciate that
she brought four beautiful model friends
with her I'm just gonna go from the left
and introduce all the ladies sitting to
my left is Miss Amanda what do they call
you on Instagram there you go guys make
sure you follow her thanks for joining
us we're gonna talk to you a little bit
more later - I'm really high - I just
hide it better sitting in front of me is
my new friend Shayna she's a great
photographer you guys she's taken some
great pictures this weekend hopefully
we'll talk more about that everybody a
heads up make sure you check out
Instagram hashtag dude it's Gatsby and
look at some of the pictures that are
posted there you might enjoy some of
those position here is Tristan how you
doing I'm doing good good good what's
your Instagram handle so people can
stalk you while they're listening oh man
Tristan Renee is my Instagram all right
and how do you spell Renee in there no
it's different
Arion a real special you are special we
like it all right sitting way to my
right nish is this shy girl
do we call you Jacqueline we call you
Jackie Jacqueline please all right all
right make sure you follow her guys
she's taking some great pictures this
weekend thanks for joining me ladies I
really appreciate it yeah we're super
steps over here who's got to grab his
mic blow out his dad get his [ __ ]
together cough a little bit this is my
buddy John hunt how you doing brother
what's going down hanging out man this
is my buddy the grimy Gatsby this is the
man the myth the Turk gather the legend
thanks for joining me man hi hi
thanks for having me this is a gorgeous
house a gorgeous location some gorgeous
friends and family also in the room you
guys we're gonna do another podcast
after this and we'll feature this these
guys but also in the room
we got Jordan from turf backs we got our
buddy Dan from CCC 4:20 and to my left
my new friend Chris from the clear the
clear scientist dude thanks for jumping
in with all these guys here in just a
minute we may get the guitar out again
if you guys remember what happened on
that episode got a little sloppy so I've
got a bunch of notes here in the phone I
should probably open that stuff up and
start getting on it first before we get
too far I need to learn a little bit
about the dude it's Gatsby Invitational
do you guys want to tell me all about
that I'm sure so I've kind of been
organizing these like a few years for a
different company I'm gonna bring a
bunch of girls and photographers to
different locations and we would make a
whole bunch of art and have a really
good time and there was kind of an
excuse for all of us to get together
even though we are spread across the
country and I thought why not do that
for cannabis products and for businesses
and so we kind of jet I kind of ran the
idea pestilent and he was like that
could actually happen it was kind of
just an idea wouldn't it be cool I
really just wanted an excuse to bring my
friends somewhere and watch them run
around naked but make it a real thing
and
and lots of hard work and planning and
some sweet sponsors later and a lot of
these guys here teaching me how to be a
boss you have to be a boss before I met
you I mean I think lifestyle marketing
and kind of like content creation in
general is something that numerous
businesses whether big or small are
utilizing in different aspects and so
with you know the the GG fam and
different kind of aspects and I actually
met damsel at one of those shoots before
giving a cannabis class to like the
photo shoot and kind of doing some
cannabis consulting but with the people
that are in the room now there's a
massive imprint and footprint so to
speak on like how social media and
social engineering and lifestyle
marketing comes to be very effective and
so it was kind of a double-edged sword
with bringing the right people together
but also getting the right brands and
what brands were part of the event this
for this one we have all kinds of
different companies seem to be obviously
some of the stuff we've been putting in
the air for the week Apothic came Papa
Canada came through with a bunch of
great holistic topicals that we've been
using and also having some great shoots
Terp x is an unbelievable sponsor that
not only is like done all other aspects
the clear concentrate as well as their
whole subsidiary of brands about that
popcorn
[Music]
huge you know Chris coming out in person
is a blessing in general just having out
the scientists of the mats mats that can
cover that coffee table right there that
we're staring at green and healthy
wellness we had some places there that
we shot at and saw what was going down
with that there are other ones
a huge success we brought out a bunch of
veteran models and a veteran
photographer and girls that are really
used to like pitching in and doing their
shirt at work and helping out and we all
get along really well but we know how to
work really hard to get the job done so
it was a lot of work and a lot of play
and we just had a you know a really
great group of girls that are really
good friends spread across the country
and when we get together it's like
nothing changed so it's been awesome we
keep talking about friends from across
the country where is everybody in the
room from family ok machinae I'm from
Boston Bob students of the country
nice meeting in Colorado Kristen I'm
from Long Beach nice it's kind of my
neighborhood from Bellflower I'm from
Chicago but just moved to Phoenix 3
months ago
oh wow how's that for a change to ride
your bike more yes hardly and she looks
awesome doing it alright so one of the
things that we really such a big shout
out to the the dude that's hard for me
to remember the dude it's a Gatsby
Invitational that's a lot of words for
my stone s to remember but Jennifer
letting me be a part of that look the
snow is coming down again this is such a
great view shadows the people that let
us use this house yeah yes the dope
house so one of the things that really
made this weekend special miss Danville
actually we're gonna blame this mostly
on hunt a few months ago hunt put me in
touch with Miss damsel and she asked me
if I would breed a strain for her so a
lot of what's been going on this weekend
is we have all been smoking what will
become or possibly not become from what
the talk has been some things that may
become damsels dank so you've had a
little notebook in front of you have you
guys decided which is your favorite and
least favorites in such I mean I think
the overwhelming favorite is what ladies
before before okay
all right so before is the winner I have
in doing this but the one that's gone
first is always true the one that
everybody's gone nice I've got some more
before in the car all right so for the
people that didn't get a chance to smoke
it can you describe what you thought of
before since you got your notes right in
front yeah but the taste was a little
bit more I was like camping okay lots of
good times the [ __ ] love before the
[ __ ] can I call you guys the [ __ ]
for the length of the show and I'll stop
right after all right so did anybody
else in the room get a campfire
tastes like camping a roam about that
[Music]
you've been cooking the entire time I've
been here this the first time you
haven't been cooking well thank you I
appreciate it and you caught you say it
does kind of taste like campfire good
yes okay all right because when I think
you can't fire I think like when you go
camping and your hair smells like
campfire not like that
that's yes is hey what kind of dreadlock
joke is that mama grab a mic if you're
gonna talk alright so before I was there
a runner up the a33 alright I thought it
smelled like fruity pebbles a little bit
like black Gerry better tea sit a little
more diesel II but that one had super
sparkly chirps on it um and I described
the overall highest wave feels you know
and you're like Brian he's just like
start spraying in the kitchen nice yeah
this Way's alright so does anybody want
to know what was in these crosses I know
all the boys everybody did anybody try
any of the number the letter C tasted
[Music]
there were three there were from that
selection I didn't bring them so the way
I did this I ran I think I started with
20 seeds of three different strains and
I narrowed it down through the veg phase
and through flower I ended up with three
of letter A and I just labeled the seeds
so that nobody knew what they were I've
just this is Brandi this is Brandi this
is Francie three of letter A four of B
and three of seeds
Cesar Dukey just got rid of them we
don't need that it's crap I'm not even
gonna grow any more of those seeds throw
it all the way a sea was transformer to
day breaker from gage rain genetics
transformers inferno haze and Kim D and
then the what's the other one I said it
is sorry I'm lost now Kim D that's
infernal haze' and Daybreaker
Daybreakers Kim D and Joseph Oh G all
right yeah so many genetics in my head
that I get confused but the winners a
nerd I am kind of a Terp nerd I'll take
that a is space Queen crossed a grateful
dog I used a female space clean and a
male a reversed male grateful dog so
it's a feminized yes basically
is what that is so it's MySpace cool or
am i grateful dog that I made to sub
cool space Queen a real tall stretchy
genotype of the space Queen that's where
that fruity funky moldy smell comes from
as the space Queen and it's the Romulan
that makes it grow those orange real
orange pistols the real fingery calyxes
that's from Romulan okay so be the one
that everybody loves
everybody's guessed it so many times
accurately its lemon skunk from Arion
its greenhouse seeds lemon skunk its
ourian's from lemon man and then it's
crossed to the day breaker from cage
grain genetics with the Joseph o G and
Kim D in there so that's what that one
is lemon skunk and Daybreaker
needs a good name if it's so what I've
heard you might not decide that this is
gonna be the keeper you know they were
all super super good but I feel like
there's just another strain that I
compared all of my eyes to and there
were so many good what was the b1 that
was another really really good one
that's the lemon skunk Daybreaker cross
so all of the bees will be lemon skunk
today breaker and all of the A's are
grateful dog in space queen trash okay
so the ones that you guys really liked
we're gonna work on getting those on the
shelf at green and healthy wellness
it'll take a while we'll get there
before and before maybe even be one
across the room and when I said b1 I got
two thumbs ups on the b1 so there will
be some new stuff showing up at green
and healthy wellness you guys that'll be
a little bit be a couple harvest but
we'll make it happen
[Music]
they don't smoke like the Colorado folk
do they come and get wrecked and it's
pretty entertaining not making fun of
you I love it
the derby boys have just been smoking
all the B 1 and B for like champions
what would you write what are you
step ok so Jaclyn over here what's up
with that
how long is before so b-1b all of the
bees were very very similar growth you
could barely see a difference in them
they kind of stretch the lemon skunk
make some stretch pretty well they grow
real dense they grow real chunky they
take they could take 70 days these went
63 I think it could have gone another
week but I was pressed for time what
about Tom the a was done at eight weeks
finished at 8 weeks one of them started
to herm you could probably see it if you
guys are experienced wheat growers and
if you got one of the top buds you could
see her/him flowers in there it was just
so I can't I can't work I don't remember
which one it is I took pictures and
marked it down to the photos and stuff
but I don't remember off the top of my
head but I marked down which one was a
herb that one brought in the most the
most flower be one well be one brought
in just yeah there was most of them
there are little plants they harvested
about ounce and a half B one was about
two and a half ounces yeah I got another
roster on the microphone that's always
nice you know what your favorite strain
is basically damsel you figured that out
we're gonna cross something of mine to
that strain some of our friends in the
room actually have a clone of your
favorite strain they're gonna they've
given me blessings to work with that so
I'm gonna play with it and we're gonna
make you a new strain we'll do this all
over again what do you ladies coming
back soon I hope
all right yeah this is gonna take me
let's see 120 give me about a year like
because I know what I want to do I need
to get the clone that you want me to
work with and then I'm going to reverse
it I'm going to make it a boy it's a
girl I'm gonna turn it into a boy I'm
gonna collect pollen from it I'm gonna
put pollen on another clone of the same
plant then I'm also put pollen on like
nine other [ __ ] in the room yeah and
we're gonna have a whole bunch of stuff
growing perfection that is the truth and
we want to find your strangest for you I
appreciate that man what are we smoking
right now which one is this microphone
benign benign very sweet that's the
Daybreaker that gives it the musky
Daybreakers got some real OG Kush
influenced to it shoutout to gage Green
genetics I feel it's real important to
give shoutouts to the people that let me
breathe with their strains gage
completely encourages me to work with
his stuff so thanks dude the whole gage
green genetics crews not just one person
it's a group of people so if you guys
ever done a tasting party or anything
like this before
how about you guys over there
tasting party you ever done something
like this nice well thanks for being
involved with it hunt fist bump for
putting me uh we've revealed the winner
I told you what everything is we're
gonna do it again alright so I wrote
this down hey miss I'm and I see you got
your phone over there you've got a book
coming out a cookbook you talked about
it you want me to just cut that part out
give you a chance to shout out your
cookbook I I am finishing a cookbook
spired by this trip to quickly finish by
the 1st of January stay tuned
what's your cookbook called it's gonna
be called eat yourself in and you said
it's mostly for women it's you know it's
it's gonna be for everybody I think that
everyone should know how to cook clean
and simple so I know my budget so that's
gonna be so whether you cook for your
boyfriend a girlfriend or significant
other husband wife awesome so you'll
have it finished by the end of the year
and then how long to get it out
we'll do a Skype interview when it comes
out cuz you've cooked for the house and
I drove home like a satisfied man so
thank you thank you it was awesome I had
to make sure to shout out your book
catered to like vegetarians allergies
dairy allergies gluten allergies I mean
we have about five different food
allergies in this house she's managed to
cater to every single one of them
normally I won't heat somebody else's
house but when she was talking to hunt
about his gluten allergy and she said
there's no good job thanks for feeding
everybody nice I could tell you just
live in the kitchen just comfortable
very much yeah it's awesome I love it so
Brett what do you do when you're not
being a supermodel I am the general
manager for green and healthy wellness
so I you know you manage yeah I manage I
recently started helping out in the
garden I have a new appreciation for the
plant that I've been smoking for the
past 10 years because it is a lot of
work got my hair caught in there oh
that's the worst yeah sticky flytraps
[Music]
thirteen years of customer service
experience probably serves me well in
the front of the house so I do that and
I am I'm married and I have a dog and we
like to stay home and smoke weed and
make sure you follow her on Instagram
you know welcome home thank you this
view here is awesome it's known so
perfectly I like it you guys found the
greatest spot I'm glad we did a podcast
right here all right miss Shana can I
ask you what you do in your normal
everyday life but you're not being a
model okay so I bet it's much easier for
you ladies to pose and feel comfortable
in front of a lady photographer instead
of some creepy dude
we learned with our best experience she
really you know shoots body and she's
really good at directing and working
with to put out the lookbook cuz Shayna
killed it
I saw the unedited shots and the
lighting is great you made these ladies
look great good job they make it look so
easy
miss Tristan perfect I'm gonna ask you
next dismiss now people gonna stalk you
I might cut that out so that's about it
and then I ride my bike and I hike
motorcycle your Harley yes tell us a
little bit about the Harley I'm curious
twelve hundred Knights tear it's my
first bike and I've had it for just
about a month now nice it looks good on
you thanks for not being shy for a
minute oh she passed the mic that was
perfect
[Music]
that was four hours later we got our car
back easier
there's one that's like you know
[Music]
11 or 12 until like 5 in the morning in
the rest of the time as you all know my
phones on and we're going guys there's a
bed at the shop if that tells you
anything about life alright so I feel
like we've got about 30 minutes most
people listen for about 35 minutes
before they get burned out I'll put a
little intro and an ending at the end of
this show at the start and end do you
ladies have anything you want to say
since you got a microphone in your hand
a chance to say something to the world
[Music]
ladies thanks for letting me invade your
privacy can't wait for us to find the
winner yeah we're close you guys and
team green and healthy thanks real let
me be a part of that that's awesome I'm
honored definitely come down to West
4:30 Colorado Avenue and buy a bunch of
Terps and hang out and kick it and see
the new shop guys can always come meet
Miss damsel she's there a lot Kumi
damsels 430 West Colorado we'd love to
see you yeah go say hi to Halley also
[Music]
patients but you know will expand soon
and we'll see you there it's coming you
guys yeah Colorado Springs has to wake
up and let us do recreational cannabis
this it's not cool smoked herbs
that's true all right well since that's
starting we're gonna wrap up this one
we're gonna start a show with the turkey
boys over there cuz let's throw on the
vibe now ladies thank you so much for
joining us I appreciate it shut up - hey
Lee since she couldn't be here also big
shout out to John Randall's jr. alright
you guys I hope everybody enjoyed that
episode I want to thank you for
listening I want to thank everybody for
participating in that episode I want to
send a huge shout out to hunt and damsel
for making me a part of the dude it's
gatsby Invitational I also want to thank
damsel for giving me the opportunity to
create a strain for her and also a huge
shout out to the entire green and
healthy wellness crew for trusting me
and giving me the opportunity to grow
the product for the shop
you guys are trusting me with your lives
in your livelihood I do understand that
and I appreciate the opportunity and I'm
honored to be the new lead cultivator of
your place all right so you guys he'll
be back in another week with another
episode don't forget to check out our
sponsor hitman glass if you're looking
for some new glass for your collection
if you want a glass rig that hits like a
truck a glass ring that's not gonna
splash water into your face a reliable
rig make sure you check out hitman glass
com make sure you follow my friend hit
man glass Dougie on Instagram if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
podcast all you've got to do is send me
an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com and I will get you all of
the information that you do need you
guys now that the show is over please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the girl from your heart podcast
find a review section give me a 5 star
rating and type in a little comment and
let me know what you think of the show
and I will read your comments on a
future episode you can also check us out
on all the social media we are on
Facebook it's a girl from your heart
we're on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
and we're on Instagram until they take
us down again under Irie underscore
genetics so I read genetics on
instagrams where we are they took down
the original page hopefully they don't
take me down again I'll do my best
you guys don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
don't forget about that donation button
on the podcast page you guys if you feel
like this show is worth a couple of
bucks of your time go to the I read
genetics Colorado com what
I click on the girl from your heart
podcast tab at the top right there's a
donation button it looks like a PayPal
logo click on that throw in a few bucks
that goes directly to my PayPal account
you guys I will never charge you
anything for this podcast this will
always be a free show but if you'd like
to make a contribution
I would definitely appreciate it I'll
give you a shout out if you got
something you want me to say if you want
me to shout out an organization I'll do
that for you so I'd appreciate that I
already told you to check us out on all
the social media I think that's all I've
got for you once again big thanks to the
green and healthy wellness crew big
shadows are the Terp X crew that's all
I've got for you guys shut up linen
dispensed thanks again for listening
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom
[Music]
Oh
No
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 111 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower you're a new smoker or a veteran
daddy if you're a cannabis activists
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic Luke's band for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat and the entire Vista
groups crew
they turn down that music a little bit
make sure you guys support my friends in
the mystic roots band you guys hope
everybody's having a great holiday
season this will be the Christmas
episode hope you've got all your
Christmas shopping done maybe you're
listening to this while you're driving
to the mall to grab that last-minute
gift or whatever you got to do anyway no
matter what holiday you're celebrating
this season I hope you have a great
holiday if you're surrounded by friends
and family and some good food and most
importantly if you're surrounded by some
good turf so if you got a fat joint know
if you got a good dad maybe some edibles
you know how we do it here the girl from
your cast I hope this episode is part 2
of the dude it's Gatsby Invitational
this is kind of the guys episode last we
had the ladies this week is gonna be the
bros this podcast actually features our
friends from turf X and our friends from
the clear concentrate but before we get
to that part of the show this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
hitman glass is gonna give me a nice
don't trust you guys by folks who just
as hard as you and I is a huge part of
California I'm gonna let the music play
for a couple of seconds and I'm gonna
take a couple of fat dabs
when I come back I will be joined on the
microphone by the turf X crew and the
clear concentrate crew from the dude
it's Gatsby Invitational round two this
time it's more of the bros the ladies
have gone downstairs to quote-unquote
take shots [ __ ] probably 300 pounds
of people down there Daniel I known you
first from CCC 420 is where I think I
first discovered you yes for 20 the
Triple C for 20 you're coming back make
any emergence like the first nice
Congrats on coming back up see you back
on YouTube the YouTube misses you all
the weed reviews all the dad reviews
he's over here talking to my right it's
my buddy Jordan how you doing brother
[Music]
here at this beautiful house and springs
on the top of the mountain I can see all
of Colorado Springs through the fog
[Music]
very interesting my buddy Jordan he is
its GDP Inc on Instagram incorporated I
don't know why that is one of my least
favorite is Brian he's got a really
fabulous law my friend open the doors to
Chris and Brian the scientists are you
ready to talk about that on a podcast or
that's something we have to keep on the
down-low okay yeah you know if I ask too
many questions just tell me I'm out of
line and and so you can put you make the
solutions you say oh this this has got
five or ten milligrams per milliliter
solutions
a little test tube or some some
volumetric flask assembly measure
exactly it's potent and it works hunt
Lakes likes the doctor dr. pepper mix on
this matter we're gonna bring to the mic
or buddy hunt the Grammy Gatsby he's
hanging out in the room a little bit
about what happens when you have
consumed the mother's milk Addie like
this stuff immediate type of effect
where like you can feel it and if the
drink is potent enough within five to
ten minutes you are at you know pretty
much euphoria and it also can pound
itself or some sort of like multiplier
where it's like if there's 60 milligrams
in the cub it really feels like 200
milligrams and some batches in the R&amp;D
phase were extremely chirpy and
unpleasant and other batches have been
refined into perfection very nice very
nice thanks for your testimony kind sir
if you ever want to grab the mic just
jump in dude hang out over there enjoy
yourself squat up nice so I guess the
golden question is over an hour drive
home and it's snowing and it's gonna be
a bobsled ride getting down this
mountain where we are this place is
beautiful
but getting down tonight in the dark
dude how about the deer anybody else
experience the deer yes
that was some crazy [ __ ] I lived in oh I
grew up in a grew up in Ohio lived in
Colorado here for a couple years and
when we live down here in Colorado
Springs I mean I always knew the deers
to be pretty damn friendly and fearless
this [ __ ] was trying to get in
on the cipher I know you don't work on
deer bro clear can you tell me about the
clear a lot of my listeners this is
listen to people have listened to by
people from all over the world not just
people in Colorado or Cali a lot of the
people listening have a hard time
finding pot so it's a clear if you just
want to tell them kind of basically they
know if they probably know about shatter
and basic hashes from listening because
we want to give them an update on what
the clear actually is that'd be awesome
so clear is is a brand of product that
we you know made a couple started a
couple years ago in California and it
was sort of the first
I guess popularized a purified cannabis
oil that because it was always a nice
high clarity and like low color in in
the kind of were one of the first quote
solvent free companies you know existed
so people have their own ways of making
these activated cannabinoids decolorized
and Stephane so we don't really speak to
how we do it keep it always a secret so
other people do it and tell you how they
do it but as far as we kind of stick to
just a purification method and we have
our own particulars as to what machines
we use we build a lot of our own
machines and have our own processes and
things like that so kind of particulars
and we have our own like unique flavors
that we then blend back they're all
natural flavors that can range from
cannabis type flavors that have high
doping content to like you know your
standard strawberry or grape and you
know we have sort of a flavor department
that we you know pump out different
flavors and try to keep those flavors
derived from cannabis or other products
so they're all derived from other
products okay everything's natural none
of them are like all the flavors we you
know I've talked to you for a couple of
nights and I trust you I trust your your
judgment on that kind of product so far
you know great uses for products like
this we can use them for topicals and
edibles and vapor cartridge isn't
anything you can really want to you know
formulate right I hear a lot of good
things about the clear we'll have to get
our hands on some I think that's your
department yeah it's out there a few
people that have it is just in Denver
not in the springs yet so I got to drive
to Denver to get it green and healthy
wellness is interested I think
the boss is behind me laughing your face
alright I appreciate that
[Music]
everything that gets grown in that
facility has to be extracted so you know
have a lot of really awesome has to be a
pretty exciting month we are going out
to Illinois we are one of the first
operators to get up and running for
medical cannabis we're going out there
to extract their crop and you know help
get their processing operation going
help them with some of the you know
processing preparation and the brand
that's awesome we're not that's not
really a brand situation you know the
market in an Illinois is very small
that's more of like a consultation help
you know kind of do like a co brand
private label type situation where we go
out there and help create their brand
which is you know one of the first you
know they'll have some of the first
infused products available in the
Illinois medical cannabis market and
probably you know be some of the first
legal butane extractions to be diced in
that state if not the first we're also
going to be getting up and running in
Las Vegas which very exciting so that
right about when this comes out this
will probably come out in about two or
three weeks so right when this drops
well yeah hopefully that would be you
know two packs branded products backs
shatter vape pens things like that
throughout the Las Vegas market are
calif you know we originally came out
here from California and but be pretty
awesome because now California patients
will have access to the products that we
make again because Nevada has reciprocal
medical marijuana and you have a
California medical marijuana card you
can shop at a Vegas dispensary Vegas
dispensary alright go to Vegas take your
medical marijuana card go shopping get
some herb go get some tur packs at the
first of the year damn it out how much
of so you guys are talking about nut
runs all of the room you're growing has
to be made into Earl what percentage of
that and if this if I'm out of line just
let me know and I won't ask the question
how much of that product will actually
be sold as smokeable Earl and how much
will be sold to a vendor and turned into
something like a topical or an edible or
something you know it's we you know we
take pretty we take pretty good steps in
the grow to make sure that you know we
have really high quality to let people
you know experience the flowers but the
fact that we can take all that high
quality flower product and turn it into
extracts
you know we want to get as much of that
branded tur PEX awesome nug run flavor
on the market as possible
I'd say most of that product will be
sold as smokeable oil if we start
delving into other products and find
that you know it's more beneficial to do
things that way you know maybe work into
that now but right now the plan is to
just make five resin talk about live
resin for a minute I heard you say
something to a client earlier the bottom
line on the show people call me a hater
we backed up everything I've said you
know you know because of the way
everything it's amazing I think the main
reason why people like live resin so
much is because the color brings out a
lot of flavor the Terps are amplified
[Music]
pleasing as if it's cut down early
frozen and extracted true form you know
this yellow yeah yeah I've learned to
take the plants a little bit early if I
know they're gonna be oil actually looks
so much better it's definitely a
definitely a tactic that a lot of
alright these days I just want to go
around the room what's your favorite
screen to smoke as a flower and favorite
to dab that's funny I was just talking
to Chris about this my favorite was
always the SF vog and I haven't had it
in quite some time but uh that's my
that's the ultimate in flower and dab
for the San Fernando Valley
oh gee yeah it's gonna I'm gonna if I
ask a lot of people I asked 100 people I
bet 50 of them would say the SF vog and
probably 40 of them didn't smoke the
real one yeah
I'm sure you have I know Chris is
thinking about it already you want us to
skip you alright Brian favorite strains
really like smoking Jack your flower
okay and really any any African sativa
just love okay I really like those get
up and do things during your day when
it's done right it's done it can be done
so well I want to assume that Turpin
alene is a terpenoid
it is correct Chris one of the isomers
of Terp Terp Anil I can remember I
believe it's gamma has a very distinct
smell and is attributed to like D Jack
and XJ type smells and a lot of times
can be a very like overpowering note in
like a lemon haze or silver haze or
something like that very fairly common
in like hybridized definitely yeah Dutch
treat you can really that's I think like
if you're gonna get into terpenes that's
when you're gonna be able to pick that
flower flower strain we got that we call
Lemongrab
you know the common nice it's all you my
friend flower and dabbers uh that's a
flower you know just blunt swisher
Sweets a granddaddy purp call it a day
but you know granddaddy purp probably a
favorite but you know mainly more I
really love otogi Gigi's particular yeah
and definitely can I've been going
really heavy on like mainly OG cut OG
flowers I'll cook it up from that from
time it's a unique thing yeah
have that distinct no-good gorilla glue
man that's got different distinct break
it up and you get a little something
different you know compared the number
fours with the ones we got from the
homey I'm nonprofit out in California we
have not popped those just yet now that
we've got this new warehouse far enough
I think we're gonna check them out and
we have the cut of the gg4 so you know
I've grown a ton of gg4 so I'll be able
to recognize it a little bit so we were
talking about the granddaddy purple and
I said it's not my favorite I'm gonna
kind of diss your strain here but then
I've got the two guys in the room that
are gonna be able to explain to me why I
don't like it when I smoke granddaddy
purp snow matter and it's a lot of
purple buds do this to me when they're
dried and cured they taste like they are
still wet is that have you experienced
that or does that make sense to you that
it's taste like there's moisture in the
bud or I don't like the flavor of
granddaddy perps the moisture content
shouldn't be affected I don't think it's
actually moisture it just tastes like
wetness or different sort of like floral
top notes terpenoids things that are
like a little bit less like elucidated I
would think you linked to cannabis like
sort of spectrum relative to like the
symbol terbium so you've got like a
situation where like how they age and
how they oxidize is kind of dependent so
you may get that effect
some people might identify that physical
frost fresh as [ __ ] every time even when
he's driving properly you know
granddaddy perps a fickle fickle lady
you know what I mean purple Oracle
there's different fee knows and cuts
there's definitely one that's like a
little bit heavier unlike the cardboard
you're talking about a you know
[Music]
different color and I'm pretty sure nice
green grapes in my favor
all right the black cherry Kim is well
known for its purple but one of those
green phenotypes is amazing it's one of
the keepers yeah that's my only and it's
way out of the purple range is that
black sure you cam it Rose purple but it
doesn't taste like anything else purple
all right hey I wanted to ask you what
happened to why did the original Terp ex
Instagram get the kibosh what happened
there
what you do the suits came in and said
it's time to clean it up you guys are
going too hard few weeks yeah they
should be got so far as to get a hold of
somebody over there and they you know
told us can have certain information on
there that we really any sort of pricing
information nope no contact I'm opening
my Instagram right now to see if I've
got contact info on there because they
show me down at 50 19 K and I'm at like
1500 and I feel dumb well
[Music]
whities
it's not
[Music]
me for my god crack DM me for info
I've got leap DM me forget foe I'll get
you whatever you need
I just wanna post how's the Instagram
song ladies and gentlemen do you guys
have a band name are you just the
terpene yards doc butthole in the brown
stock butthole yeah that's a great segue
I think what has been demanded miss
damsel just walked by and wanted to hear
the butthole song is there such a thing
as the butthole song that happens
between you two what would it take to
get you boys to riff a little bit of the
butthole riff here on the show for me I
think you would probably take those have
to pause real quick and come back once
we see if we can tempt this young man to
sing some butt hole jams for us here we
go ladies gentlemen butt hole Jam volume
or live on the girl from your heart
podcast brought to you by Danny rolling
from our hearts right now remember this
is what you guys do did for
your life is less important than the Sun
have you ever seen a cute little
butthole it's highly inappropriate dad
you just wanted to me be painting a
picture of it and maybe do some other
things as well
put your tongue in
you know that we like to lick lots of
butthole
it tastes so good it tastes so sweet
tastes kind of like a coconut meat
[Music]
Haeju when was the last time you ate but
more recently than I care to admit
it's what a lucky guy
to have those bottle Terps for dinner
every night
I'm sure she will fight
[Music]
it shines like a diamond when you're
done cause it's so damn clean
is real
[Music]
if I don't lick it for a while I get
mean
[Music]
gotta blow off some steam keep it clean
you know
[Music]
who dream kinda tastes like a strippers
ass crack
I am piney
[Music]
if there's one thing I know in this game
yeah I heard Jimmy played that back
[Music]
Jimmy [ __ ] kills better than train
man all right so we've got we've gotten
a long time and I want to reward my
listeners everyone that's made it
through the butthole song that's made it
all the shamanic Sousa shenanigans let's
talk about hash we've got some amazing
hash artists here in the in the room
everyone's next we're all comfortable
we're all friends now what's coming up
with hash what's gonna be next we've got
clear hurts
we've got dissolvable dr. pepper Terps
that's the truth everyone's talking
Terps everyone talks Terps they just
really doesn't know it Terps means yeah
most people don't know what a teen
flavor we're gonna call it flavor
components flavours terpenes and
different flavors Terps and I think you
know got some people out there doing
some little terpene isolettes stuff like
that but I think the game's gonna be you
know sort of just keeping the essence of
cannabis so that everyone can experience
it in all the different formulations you
know it's like kind of more of an art
and cannabinoids they're a little bit
more stable and flavors are kind of like
our you know perfumers and people who do
that sort of extraction you know I think
hasn't quite matured to that level of
science and its kind of getting there
we're just now been given the freedom we
were a little we were prohibited from
doing that experimentation all right so
you feel like Terps are next you look
like you got something important to say
okay
a lot of people poopoo on that but it's
it's definitely real and we use it for
people using lavender oil and stuff like
that just in their bedside steamers and
stuff like that or whatever the
essential essence so if I mean it's
definitely real and so incorporating
that in the cannabis is pretty cool
keeping even that original essence and
so coming up with the different
extractions and trying to get just the
terpenes and then
get plants that produce a lot of
turbines and there's this pretty neat
information out there in theories on how
you can influence the turbine levels by
soil management in like environmental
controls and stuff like that okay you
know this isn't the only industry where
turbines are prevalent or where people
want the turbines from what we're
there's a lot of different things you
said that environmental factors play a
lot into my terpenoids and my soil I
know you're not you're more on the hash
side then you are the grow game from
what I understand about you could you
give myself and my listeners one hint on
how we could improve our Terps in our
garden one thing that we could just stop
doing or start doing it would correct
our Terps sounds good to me you guys
heard it here he's gonna read that and
find rosin rosin bro Triple Threat a lot
of my friends listen to this podcast
I've tasted one person's rosin that I
liked everything else tastes like burnt
popcorn
yeah I had one guy my buddy Tim came
through and he had some properly made
rosin I think he made it himself he was
the only one who had rosin that I liked
about that low Tim rosin from you know
you don't wax a sufficient dry suit or
any kind of other gets you away from
that bulk of the plant material and
that's going to increase your resin
quality you're gonna get a lot less of
the resin stuck in the plant material
and
overall just gonna be more of a pleasant
experience just kind of come up with a
reasonable sipped dry I sift or you know
if you can keep the moisture away you
know people are building out cold rooms
doing do go in the fold to full length
and so you can break that material down
get away from all that leaf there it is
okay so oh man that's a lot of work for
a home grower sometimes what's your
what's the most recommended way of
getting some dry sift out of that to
work it into rosin I mean I think you
can just kind of promptly break down
you know they got wrote at machine okay
they've got material that can that are
pretty efficient if you just can i rosin
my Keefe popcorn ER since we didn't use
plant matter taste right is a classic
comes any process true if it's key for
not what should I be doing with my
reclaim I've got a drop down it's
probably got thrown it away okay make
sleepy time sleepy time CBN heated up
make it in and then just dab it again
we've got a video going they said can we
season our nails with reclaim
yeah yeah why couldn't you bro yeah you
totally could if you're kind of like
upset with your buddy you know take some
of his oil and just kind of clean one
thing one thing I've seen I saw a
picture on the internet the other day of
someone who had smashed their fingers
song it was a girl because there's girl
fingernails you know low temp high
pressure situations and didn't get their
fingers out of the way and it was not
pretty sight it looked like you ran over
a banana yeah yeah most of you guys are
you stole your girlfriend's hair
straightener they're not using a
hydraulic press or anything be fair that
as goofy and stupid as it works actually
flower and a hair straightener is the
first time we tried it what was that
from the gorilla glue I don't remember I
don't remember your rosin virginity
unfortunately I think you think we're
gonna run into two just like any of
these other extracts is that with some
plants will be absolutely frozen you get
certain heats and [ __ ] with certain snow
and certain ones are fine so I think
it's a matter of like where do these if
it's all going there's five or six ways
to make oil and that's gonna leave
different spectrums of which plants get
the GDP maybe he gets pressed and
doesn't taste like so
right so whatever or maybe it's like you
really taste better when you get it
first I like the way you think my friend
yeah we got to get some GDP impressive
and then blast it and then make bubble
out of it and see if we can convince me
that I like that flavor
[Music]
all right well let's get it I'll grow it
will smoke it me too me too all of us
we're in agreeance with that just call
me on over call me over awesome alright
so we've been going for a long time our
listeners have probably checked out
around the butthole song so I hope a lot
of people enjoy the extra bonus hash
talk if you're paying attention that's
your bonus that's a big shout-out to you
cuz these guys are I've got some of the
mad scientist the forefront hash guys in
the room here he's brewing up if you've
got more knowledge you want to drop on
these listeners bro I will never stop
you we'll put a spotlight on you we'll
give you a microphone would you guys
like to wrap us up with another song
would that be possible
some dad talk and some drone from your
heart all right all right well you guys
start the riff and I'm gonna say thanks
everybody for joining me I appreciate
everybody for being on the podcast you
guys on periscope I'm gonna close the
video thank you for watching let's just
leave it on so you guys can hear this
point it over at this guy you can hear a
song thanks for watching on periscope
thank you for joining me playing guitar
before you get going mental
thanks for joining me follow the clear
scientists made her new friend in Brian
tonight learned a lot of great [ __ ] from
you already cannot wait to try the
mother's milk mother's milk water
soluble THC that won't taste like
anything just cause yeah sometimes
then of course Jordan thanks for coming
on the show and singing my favorite
choir boy
you know take what the Lord gave you I
appreciate each and every one of you
we go there thank you so I'll be back
I'm gonna let these guys sing a little
song where they wrap it up I will be
back to wrap up the show and say goodbye
in the official way I'm gonna set my
microphone down and take a DAB and enjoy
the song you guys thanks for listening
thanks for having us man oh dude thanks
a lot I appreciate the hash knowledge I
want you guys back soon enjoy the song
guys
we are growing from our hearts Rasta
Jeff his Jets are as long as I'm tall
and it takes lots of devs Buster Jeff he
is growing tips for the healthy these
days
[Music]
while Kaku Daniel plays guitar
I needed
[Music]
I needed tap so big strong out of my
bunk
Jeff wanted me to sing
those are my favorite
there's about ten titties
in his house
but unfortunately they won't let me take
off her blouse
[Music]
but they still have nice titties
we got a throw from
[Music]
from your heart
from your heart grow from your
[Music]
got a girl here
jerks all right guys if you stuck around
that long I want to give you a huge
shout out and I really want to thank you
for listening also a huge thanks to
Jourdan Dan Chris and Brian and also a
huge shout out to hunt from the Graeme
Gatsby and also damsel from green and
healthy wellness you guys threw a great
party and thanks again for letting me be
a part of that and also thanks for being
on the podcast
all right everybody I'll be back in
another week with another episode don't
forget to check out our sponsor hit man
glass make sure you follow hit man glass
on Instagram it's dougie also check out
their website at it man glass comm they
have tons of great glass available if
you were interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you've got a product you'd
like me to review send me an email it's
girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I'll get you all the information that
you do need now that the show is over
you guys please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for girl from your
heart
I'll find the review section give me a 5
star rating and after that type in a
little comment and let me know what you
think in the show and I will read your
comments on a future episode on you guys
I'd love it if you follow me on all of
the social media you can find me on
Facebook it's that girl from your heart
podcast you can find me on twitter it's
at g f YH podcast i'm on instagram i am
at ireon Durst or genetics on instagram
you guys I had to restart the account
I'm sure if you follow the show you know
what happened I had like 19,000
followers I woke up one day and I did
not have an account anymore so I started
a fresh account the tur pax boys say
that if you don't post contact
information that you should be cool and
your page won't get deleted so I am
going back route and hopefully I get to
keep my page at this time so make sure
you follow me on Instagram I post a ton
of great cannabis related photography
you guys don't forget to the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always and forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado com
don't forget about the donation button
if you go to you I read genetics
Colorado com click on the podcast tab at
the top right there is a donation button
that goes directly to my PayPal account
you guys I'm never going to charge you
for this show the show will always be
free this podcast is my gift to you but
if you feel like the show was worth a
couple of bucks and you want
make a contribution I would definitely
appreciate it and if you'd like I will
give you a shout-out on the show if you
make a contribution and you would rather
me not give you a shout-out make sure
you type that in the notes or email that
to me because I will give you a
shout-out automatically if you do throw
down on the PayPal so let me know if you
want to be anonymous I want to send a
huge shot it's my friend Jessica hey
Jess thanks for listening to the show it
was great to learn that you listen that
closely I definitely appreciate it big
shout out to Jessica and her crew you
guys I think that's all I've got for you
this week I want to send a huge shout
out to my ninja Spence thank you again
for listening and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
and execute
here comes the
[Music]
all right podcast world I want to thank
you guys again for listening to a long
block of old episodes I would love it if
you would email me and let me know what
you think about these old episodes the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to stalk me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
some serious
[Music]
you