[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 245 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated Abbot if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band for
letting me use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew
ladies and gentlemen you will not hear
me bitching about the heat in Colorado
for quite some time it's right it's
starting to cool off this morning it was
nice and chilly and this evening it's
getting a little bit cold I had to close
the windows I've had the swamp cooler an
air conditioner running every day until
yesterday or the day before it is
starting to cool off here in Colorado I
think I'm looking forward to the cool I
don't have to run as much air
conditioning you can run a few more
lights things get a little bit easier
some things get a little bit easier in
the cool driving sucks in the snow
that's the least favorite part getting
to and from work in the snow is kind of
a [ __ ] but I'm looking forward to the
fall winter season this year
you won't hear me complain about the Sun
and the heat at all for a few months
what you will hear me complain about
somebody keeps smoking all my damn hash
I keep buying this hash I got this SoCal
og might have talked about it on the
last episode I got this SoCal og
Apothecary it's so good that it just
keeps disappearing I don't know so I
gotta take a dab of it and I blow it out
and I'm like that was [ __ ] delicious
I want another dab it's just so tasty I
can't get enough of that someone keeps
smoking all my hash I'm pretty sure it's
me you guys I'm pretty sure it's me hey
if you guys know who's smoking on my
hash let me know make them [ __ ] quick
all right let's get serious ladies and
gentlemen this podcast is brought to you
by our good friends at the dank team.com
that's right
if you're looking for regular or
feminized seeds from trusted breeders I
can highly recommend avid anq team.com
that's right the day team comm carries
brands like alpha chronic mile high sin
city I read genetic scan aventure sour
seeds DNA genetics rare dankness more
and more the list goes on and on they
carry all the brand's you are looking
for so make sure you check out the dank
team comm for all of your regular and
feminized seeds means alright check them
out let them know Rasta Jeff sent you
alright you guys let's talk about what I
did over the weekend I'm gonna brag for
a couple of seconds before we get into
the podcast on Sunday I took my
beautiful daughter Maya that's right
I've got a 14 year old daughter she's a
beautiful little girl and I'll talk
about her a lot on the podcast cuz it's
kind of nutty yo damn business but I
took my beautiful daughter and my
beautiful girlfriend Jenny Beth to the
Denver Zoo on Sunday and we got to go
check out some animals at the zoo we got
to see the silverback gorilla
we got to see some lions we got to see
some Tigers we saw some bears oh my it's
a great experience I think we all had a
good time
we all had a bunch of fun we are some
twisted individuals I think we had more
fun making fun of the silly humans than
we actually had checking out the animals
at the zoo but that's just the type of
folks we are it was a good-ass time
shout out to Jenny Beth for hanging out
with my daughter and I also shout-out to
my Aluna for hanging out with my
girlfriend and I
I don't think Maya will listen to this
podcast but I love you kiddo I hope you
listen someday the zoo is a good time
you guys we saw a whole bunch of great
stuff a whole bunch of Greek animals a
whole bunch of great birds and reptiles
and fishes and other stuff of that
nature one thing at the Denver Zoo that
kind of tripped me out they are doing
zoo dinosaurs so occasionally you'll be
walking through the zoo and you'll hear
a roar a roar that confuses you if you
don't know there are dinosaurs at the
zoo this week because that's like what
the [ __ ] animal is that because it was
intense it was loud it was really Basie
and I could hear it from a long ways
away it was not a real animal it was a
dinosaur no people are going dinosaurs
what the [ __ ] that's what I said too
they're not real dinosaurs you guys
they're animatronic they will not hurt
you they are peaceful there are robots
there did you toll ah
but man how is that gonna confuse some
little kids because we're teaching
little kids at the dinosaurs burg years
ago and then they're gonna go to the zoo
and I gonna see dinosaurs maybe what the
[ __ ] all the books are lying
I got damn seen dinosaurs at the zoo
last week it's gonna be weird someone's
gonna go to school some little kids
gonna go to school they're gonna start
at school nothing big I thought
dinosaurs really no you didn't they make
[ __ ] you yes I did
it's gonna be weird there's dinosaurs at
the Denver Zoo you guys I thought it was
weird is that confusing the kids I
really don't know really don't know
alright so after the zoo I took my
beautiful daughter home and the lovely
always lovely always beautiful Jenny
Beth and I we got to go to servantes
other side and to see what I think is my
favorite reggae band I've called them my
favorite reggae man enough times that I
think I believe it I got to go see
Morgan heritage at servantes other side
in Denver I was a pretty good show we
showed up fairly early we got to see the
opening act they were called red sage
they were good but I don't know that
they were the appropriate opening act
for Morgan heritage they were a little
more like fortunate youth more on the
blaim side of things I kind of would
have fit in with the mystic roots band
not quite the roots rock reggae sort of
thing that you should have had opening
for Morgan heritage in my opinion but
hey it brought a different crowd more
people came that was cool
so Morgan heritage came on stage and
Jenny Beth and I walked directly to the
front of the stage the stage is about
waist-high Jenny Beth was directly in
front of the stage right behind her was
me protecting her from all the other
idiots up front there's something weird
that happens late at night when people
are up front at a concert you just see
everybody get this glazed look on their
face once the drugs and alcohol start
kicking in and they just go full [ __ ]
they think they can ram into you and
bump into you and push you over and it's
ridiculous and being six five and having
dreadlocks to my ass I can make it clear
to the drunk people that the space I am
standing in and the space I am
protecting for my girlfriend that is my
space and I will not move we're going to
hold our ground so you have to spend a
little bit of your time kind of claiming
your space and putting your elbows up
occasionally because people get a little
bit ridiculous but we had a great time I
protected the miss the always beautiful
always lovely miss Jenny Beth protected
her pretty well from the drunken idiots
she didn't get plowed into too much we
got to see the band up front it was such
a great show we were so close that I
could hear Peter Morgan's voice coming
out of him before it hit the microphone
and before it went into the sound system
and that man has an amazing [ __ ]
voice Peter Morgan from organ heritage
is one of my favorite vocalists ever the
dude's got mad style the dude's got mad
flow his voice is awesome he's got a
good vibe I just liked the way that dude
performs his brother Gramps Morgan off
to the right side of him my right of him
had B his left I guess mr. Gramps Morgan
I could hear him sing that dude's got a
deep rich voice he's got a big
infectious smile he just looks like a
big Jamaican teddy bear I just looks
like such a cool dude ah then mojo
Morgan on the other side of the stage
plays percussion he raps a few times
that dude's just always got the biggest
cheesiest smile on his face he doesn't
sing a whole lot he's more kind of a
kind of a rapper sort of a dude he does
his own little raps in parts of the
songs but I could hear these guys's
voices before they were hitting the
microphones and their harmonies together
their voices individually these guys
have some [ __ ] talent you guys they
got the richest voices
heard in a long time at a great time so
Sunday we see Morgan heritage we drive
back to Pueblo Monday I go to work kind
of dragon ass because Sunday was a long
[ __ ] night we didn't get home till
super late we didn't get to bed till
even later had to get up had to go to
the grow it did that might have been a
little silly might have been a little
bit loopy but I made the best of it got
some rest then on Tuesday I went to work
again after work came to the house and
got cleaned up a little bit and met up
with the always lovely always beautiful
miss Jenny Beth and her and I headed up
to Colorado Springs to the black sheep
to see Morgan heritage once again it was
a great show on Sunday um the opening
act once again was a great opening act
I cannot remember their name right now
project two three four project three two
four project four two three project and
the numbers ahead two three and four but
they were not in the correct order
project three to four is what I want to
call him not certain but project
something they were a good band I really
liked their style their drummer played
some really great fills other guitar
player was [ __ ] talented their bass
player held it down and the other guitar
player the rhythm guy man there were
he's played some really nice rhythms
with like really nice lead parts mixed
into the rhythms is really cool that
band was really cool maybe once again
not the appropriate opener from organ
heritage but music is music man if you
got an opening act to start the party
let's do it I think they were great
Morgan heritage came on stage and I
headed directly to the front of the
venue Jenny Beth and I were directly in
front of Peter Morgan once again all
night it was a great show you know in
the first night there were about eighty
to a hundred people in the venue I would
estimate and on the sunday show or on
the Tuesday show at the black sheep
there were maybe 25 or 30 people at the
show and the band still gave it their
all they still performed like they were
at reggae Sunsplash they performed like
they were at reggae on the river they
gave their full big show just like they
normally would
they played mostly the same set on both
nights with a couple of variations they
switched out a couple of songs I was
really happy to hear Moscow Square on
Tuesday that's just a good song it's
from one of their older albums which I
really love they did not play what we
need is love on the second show but they
did on the first show which came from
from the my favorite album of theirs
called more teachings the both those
songs came from
that one they opened both nights with
strictly routes they closed both nights
with reggae night ah they do she's still
loving me they do a big do Cielo of
course and a bunch of great songs in the
middle but there weren't very many
people there at the Tuesday show I was a
great show we were upfront once again
and there was a moment when the reverb
was so loud that I couldn't figure out
what was going on the singer would sing
into the microphone and then it would
take like this long fruit so he would be
like here is my lyric and then you hear
this much delay and then we go here is
my lyric here is my lyric here is my
lyric so he couldn't even I could tell
he was becoming frustrated by all the
reverb he couldn't hear himself I
couldn't hear him but we were so close
that I was hearing we're I was hearing
the stage sound in front of me and then
the house sound behind me and all the
sound was mixing it was really odd I
would have been better to back up about
10 feet just because of the sound of
that venue but I was so close that I
could hear feel and see the drums coming
off of the drums hear the sound coming
off the drums before they went through
the speakers and I was loving that I was
hearing the tone of those drums and just
watching that drummer I do not know the
drummer from organ Heritage's name if
that dude is bad ass I'm pretty sure the
bass player from organ heritage is a
toots Hibbert son or grandson he's young
so I'm gonna say grandson these kids the
basin drummer looks like 19 and 20 years
old those guys are barely 21 if they're
21 there's some young cats and that
rhythm section [ __ ] held it down and
tore it up those guys were great well
Morgan heritage has a new backup singer
they have a lady in the band a sister
Asuna morgan who i don't know why but
she has left the band I would assume
that it's a health reason I cannot be
positive I'm assuming it's a health
reason just from things I've observed
but una hasn't been with the band for
the past couple of tours that I've gone
to I see this man two or three times a
year she hasn't been on tour with them
for at least the past two years I don't
know if Jenny Beth has ever seen them
with una which kind of gives me an
indicator of how long she's been gone
but they have another backup singer
named Natasha who seemed a little bit
shy at first but once she gets in the
groove the girl really gets in the
groove and she's got a hell of a voice
so if you ever hear this you're doing a
great job don't be so shy I like what
you're doing
alright guys I saw Morgan heritage
that's my point I saw them twice and it
was [ __ ] amazing
if you ever get to listen to morgan
heritage i recommend it go for some of
the older stuff go for the more
teachings album then work your way on up
they have a plethora of varieties they
do they do roots rock reggae they do
dancehall reggae they do lovers reggae
they do some that R&amp;B kind of sound in
reggae they've got a lot of stuff to
listen to I really love Peter Morgan's
voice he's the high-pitched singing one
really love gramps's voice he's the
low-pitched singing one and then they
put the sister in there they all mix up
super well such a great vibe all right
you guys I'm gonna quit talking about
concerts that I get to go to cuz I feel
like I brag too much but I love music I
love comedy and I like sharing part of
my world with you guys so let me say
that let me wrap this up by the sand
this Tuesday night I get to shake hands
and hang out with Morgan heritage you
got my picture taken with all the guys
Thank You Jenny bets were taking a great
picture of us thank you to the black
sheep for throwing a great show and also
big thanks to Morgan heritage for a
great two nights of reggae music really
needed it reggae music is like an
attitude adjustment it's like a mood
shifter sometimes a guy that works too
hard and gets frustrated with the world
can use a little bit of an attitude
adjustment alright let's move forward
you guys episode number 250 is coming
holy crap I'm five episodes away from
episode number 250 honestly when I
started this podcast I was like I'd like
to get a hundred episodes under my belt
and then once I got like 50 episodes in
I was like [ __ ] I'm going for at least
250 episodes I'm almost at 250 you guys
let me tell you the truth I have no
intentions of ever stopping this podcast
I'm gonna do this as long as I can I
love doing this sometimes it's a [ __ ]
struggle to get behind a microphone and
spit out an hour or thirty minutes of
material every week I have to find the
time to organize the show I got to do it
I gotta sit here and talk it but you
know what I'm never gonna stop doing it
because I love doing it I love sharing
part of me with you guys I love helping
you with cannabis
I love getting cannabis freed up I think
we are I think I am dispelling myths
about cannabis I'm breaking the truth to
people I'm taking the fear out of
cannabis I'm teaching people to take
better care of their gardens and
themselves by talking about cannabis
maybe I'm helping people fight cancer
maybe I'm helping people take care of a
family member who is sick I love doing
this podcast because I know that every
episode I put out I hope at least one
person and if I'm just helping one
person with every episode it makes it
well worth my time and energy I feel
like I would be doing the world
myself a disservice by not sharing all
of the [ __ ] that I have learned with
people I've absorbed a lot and I've got
a good brain and I like to talk a lot
and I feel like it's kind of my
responsibility to put this out here for
you guys I love you guys I love cannabis
I love talking ass off
I love podcasting there's no reason for
me to quit doing this so I guess the new
goal I'm gonna say 500 episodes that's
kind of that's 250 more so let's say 500
and when I hit that we're gonna aim for
a thousand [ __ ] 750 I don't even like
that number that's just like a give up
number
you gotta get to a thousand Joe Rogan
made it to a thousand if Joe Rogan can
do it I can definitely do it then dude
puts out like three or four episodes a
week but he's at a thousand shout out to
Joe Rogan you guys I feel like I'm super
rambley I am gonna press pause on this
recording for just a brief moment I'm
gonna take a couple of gigantic dabs and
then I'll be back hopefully I'll be a
little calmer and we'll work on some
emails from some listeners ladies and
gentlemen join me for a dab and I will
be right back
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back I'm
well hydrated and well medicated I hope
you enjoyed the reggae music I hope you
took a couple of dabs with me send me a
tweet let me know what you dabbed I
dabbed some space [ __ ] and it made me
one Spacey [ __ ] send me a tweet let me
know what you're smoking at GF wih
podcast I'd love to hear it alright
let's get the show moving I want to read
an email on the last episode I read an
email about folks who wanted to move
somebody who wanted to move from Georgia
to Colorado and get into the industry
and they sent me a little bit of an
update I'm not gonna read the whole
email I don't want to read some of the
important parts it says hey I just
listened to 241 you mentioned reading
some emails from Georgia and Florida
listeners not sure if you were referring
to my email but I went back and read my
email I sent and I wanted to clarify a
few things I said I've been inspected
and consulted that sounded a bit
pretentious what I meant was I've passed
out a lot of info forward the people I
have helped come from the old Southern
school of thought that if it ain't broke
don't fix it these individuals are good
simple living people just trying to
avoid the trap life hustle I've helped
with bug helped with bug and efficiency
problems such as corn worms cow egg
deficiency salt lock in mother plants
hot zones and flour rooms different
plant training techniques and he keeps
going for a little while
anyway I wanted to read this guy's email
he says most of the info I have has come
from you sub cool and my book collection
due to forget an info from myself and
sub cool and good books you were off to
a great start he goes on to say I listen
to 10 plus hours of podcasts and ebooks
a day as I slave away at my structural
structural that's harder to say than it
looks structural steel fabrication job
so I have a lot of info and just want to
pass it forward I don't want to get into
the industry for the money but for a
better future for my family and most
importantly I feel the need to be part
of the movement to keep corporate
America from taking what so many before
us have sacrificed to give us that's a
good reason to want to get into it
because that corporate takeover is
happening it's becoming that way it's a
corporate industry now it's happening
quickly
he also says PS ARMA has been the worst
ripper ever lol thanks brother go smoke
a fat dad and hug your mom wait a minute
I think you're supposed to hug your mom
you're supposed to take a fat dabba than
you hug your mom for me I guess I'll hug
my mom for you is that how it's gonna
work
i hugs all around anyway dude I
appreciate that you wanted to take some
accountability and say hey I sounded
pretentious making it look like I'm some
sort of consultant I do die like the
accountability that's pretty cool thanks
for stepping up and saying that ah man
sorry that emma has ripped your crop
that's a [ __ ] anyway dude thanks for
the email if you're listening to me and
sub cool and you're learning from the
internet you are doing things correctly
keep doing exactly what you're doing
keep listening to the podcast I look
forward to your emails in the future all
right I'm gonna read one more email and
this is going to work us into the main
topic of the show the email goes like
this it says hey Rasta Jeff had a quick
question for you but first wanted to let
you know how great your podcast is hey
thanks dude
I read a lot of emails that start off
like that and every time it means a lot
to me I put a lot of effort into this
show takes a lot of time a lot of energy
so I do appreciate every compliment he
goes on to say or maybe she goes on to
say you are incredibly knowledgeable and
well-spoken
it is a goldmine for newbies like me I'm
glad you found me I'm glad I can help
you out the email continues to say my
main question is for someone like me who
isn't in a legal state what is my best
bet on getting high quality seeds I've
been doing a lot of research and
wondering about going with US banks or
an overseas one it goes without saying
that my main concern is discreteness I
think you met discretion but hey we'll
let you fly with quality and
dependability coming in right behind any
info or suggestions on this subject or
just tips for the beginners you can help
me out with would be greatly appreciated
you're the man hey yeah thanks for
trusting me ah because I've got some
info for you that you're going to
appreciate but the email keeps going it
says all so I just wanted to let you
know how I feel like we have become
buddies just from the short month I've
been listening to you being pretty
engulfed in stand-up comedy myself along
with Rogen's Joey Diaz and other
podcasts and being a Deadhead myself I
feel like we are cut from the same cloth
keep it up my man that's kind of cool
did you say you feel like we're friends
I have always felt that the podcasters I
have listened to
a long time usually comedians when I go
see those comedians I feel like I've
already developed some sort of a
relationship with them because I've been
listening to Joey Diaz until you've
listed Joey right here in the email I've
been listening to Joey for years I could
say probably five years solid maybe more
than that I honestly don't remember what
I've discovered uncle Joey but I've been
listening to Joey religiously every
podcast he goes on I listen to every
episode he puts out I go to any special
he does try to listen every time he
comes to Denver I'm there when I'm there
in Denver I've tweeted the guy enough to
where he recognizes my name he
recognizes my little Twitter icon uh he
we know each other now and we don't know
each other we just know each other
because I listened to him two days a
week talk about whatever crazy [ __ ] he
did in a tease and then when I see him I
tweet him enough to where he replies and
then when I see him it's like we know
each other it's really neat so man I
appreciate that you think we're friends
we are friends if you're ever around in
Colorado in my neck of the woods
hit me up let's take some dabs we're
bros now you're a part of the podcast
family dude ought to put me to say
anything about my podcast and then
include Rogen and Diaz in the same email
that's [ __ ] awesome that's a huge
compliment and then if you're a Deadhead
bro we are cut from the same cloth we
are we're we're family so let's smoke a
dad one of these days now let me answer
your main question your main question is
for someone like you who isn't in a
legal State what is your best bet on
getting high quality seeds
I of course recommend the dank team com
they are in America so you don't have to
worry about any customs type shipping
let me say this to keep myself out of
trouble
if you buy seeds from anywhere it is
your responsibility to know the laws in
your area if you have seeds and it is
illegal to grow them be sure that you
were only purchasing them for the
intention of collecting and preserving
those genetics if it's illegal in your
state promise yourself that you will
never grow those you're only buying them
to have them as a collectible so that
perhaps something goes down and there's
Armageddon and there are no more
cannabis seeds you could be the only one
on the planet that's got these seeds
preserved and it'll be like a historical
thing you're like a curator of fine
quality cannabis collectibles also maybe
one day your state will go legal and
that's what you're waiting for
that's
yeah so don't buy seeds with the
intention to grow them if you live in an
illegal State the dank team.com will
ship you seeds to be used as
collectibles
if you live in illegal states if you
leave them live in a legal state feel
free to grow them and see what comes out
of them you will be impressed and amazed
ah one thing that I've got to say I
don't know what happens if you get seeds
shipped to you and you live in an
illegal State and that package gets
intercepted I don't know what happens
with that I cannot be responsible for
that you may want to check with your own
legal counsel or somebody like that
figure it out before you do it and don't
find out the hard way because honestly I
don't know what could happen to you or
the sender I don't know I do know that
the dank team.com is a reliable vendor
they've got a lot of great brands and
they are in the States uh you asked
about discretion they will ship
everything to you
very discreetly you won't even know
what's in there and nobody will know
what's in there it'll blend in with the
rest of the mail quality I can assure
you quality is top-notch they carry
brands like alpha chronic mile high can
adventure sour seeds IRA Genetics rare
dankness DNA genetics there's a whole
bunch of good stuff on there uh your
next one is where you're looking for
quality and dependability I know that
people at the Dane team.com personally
there are friends of mine and they are
dependable trust me on that so any info
and suggestions I recommend the Dane
team com go check them out I'll go right
now go check it out and let them know
that Rasta Jeff sent you telling you
listen to the girl from your heart
podcast I don't know if it'll help you
out but just let them know cuz it may
help me out in the future alright I want
to thank you both for your emails if
anybody else out there has a question
you can send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
to answer your questions yeah since
we're talking about purchasing seeds I
want to talk a little bit about
expectations from a seed pack I believe
that if you have realistic expectations
when you buy seeds you will be much less
disappointed and much happier with your
purchase when the time comes to harvest
your plants if you think about it it
takes about a hundred and twenty days to
grow a crop of cannabis from a seed it
could take longer it could take a little
shorter depends on your style I'm gonna
say a hundred and twenty days maybe a
hundred and fifty days to grow a crop of
cannabis
that's four to six months to grow this
crop you probably ordered the seeds and
depending on where you order from it's
gonna take a week or two to get them
there so now you're looking at like four
months plus two more weeks or at
eighteen weeks
you probably shopped on the seeds for
like a week and thought what you were
gonna buy then in another week you had
to wait for a paycheck so you're looking
at like twenty four weeks from the time
you purchase from the time you decide to
purchase the strain you're gonna get to
the time you actually get to cut them
down so it would make a lot of sense to
do plenty of research and investigation
before you order your seeds instead of
buying some seeds throwing them in the
garden and then trying to figure out
what you're going to do with these
plants that you don't know what to
expect most websites that sell seeds
have very good description of what you
can expect from those seeds those are
mostly accurate a lot of people are
salespeople breeders want you to buy
their seeds so they will butter up the
descriptions just just just like any
other product so you have to find a
breeder that you trust and then you have
to find a seed line that has been out
for a minute that's been tested I know
everybody wants to grab the hot new [ __ ]
but sometimes it's better to wait a
little bit because sometimes when you
grab the hot new [ __ ] you find out that
it really wasn't as hot it was more [ __ ]
and then you've got a bunch of that in
your grow room and you're disappointed
you've gone and spent $1,000 on this one
breeder and bought ten packs of his [ __ ]
you know you got a bunch of crap in your
grow because he released stuff without
testing it he put it out too early
something like that so do some research
before find a reputable breeder find a
strain that gets your attention figure
out what you're looking for when you're
shopping for seeds there are several
things to consider do you want an indica
do you want a sativa what kind of
effects do you want do you want it to be
a mind racing thing do you want it to be
a body thing is this for medicinal uses
is somebody going to be smoking this
cannabis for a medical reason you need
to find a strain that works for their
medical condition hopefully they've been
shopping around in dispensaries buying
different strains hopefully you've done
some research and you know what kind of
works for them if you're a new grower a
new smoker a new medical patient you're
gonna have to do some research on what
types of effects you want from these
plants so think about if you want indica
or sativa or a hybrid or what type of
effect you're looking for if you're
going for the mind for the body think
about stuff like
to start then you're gonna need to think
about height do you have a lot of height
in your grow room can you grow real tall
plants think about the space that you've
got you've gotta buy plants you've gotta
buy seed that will produce plants that
you're going to be able to fit into your
space if you've got a short space you're
not gonna want super Silver Haze
if you've got a really tall space you
might want to put some taller Hayes's
some longer flowering plants in there
just depends on how much space you've
got think about that when you're
shopping for seeds don't get Hayes's and
sativas if you've got low ceilings if
you don't have a lot of room think about
how much time you want these crops to
take think about how much time you can
dedicate to flowering plants you don't
want to go buy once again you don't want
to buy a Hays plant that's gonna take
you 10 to 12 weeks if you don't have 10
to 12 weeks to flower something if you
need product sooner if you're a cash
crop er you want something that's closer
to 8 or 9 weeks if you're growing
because you want that head-ripping
sativa you might want an 11 or 12 weaker
but think about that before you buy the
seeds because once you've got them
there's no seed bank in the planet it's
gonna take seeds back from anybody you
could open them up you could have spit
on them gonna put other seeds in there
they don't take [ __ ] back all sales are
final
with all seed companies so be careful
also think about yields what do you need
big yields are you a cash crop er are
you growing for medicinal reasons you
yields may be really important to you
for a medical grower yields are
important but not as important if you're
growing for medicinal purposes you need
to worry that that specific phenotype
and we're gonna get to that the specific
strain has a specific phenotype that
works for the specific patient's
specific condition and that's one of the
beauties about growing from seed is you
can select that for your patient so
maybe yield matters to you yield matters
to everybody because you have to pay for
the electricity you have to pay for the
nutrients you have to pay for the dirt
you have to pay for all of that so
hopefully you get enough yield to make
it worth your time and your energy and
your budget how much work are these
plants gonna take something like and
trying to find some stranger Jilly bean
Jilly bean is really easy to grow Jilly
bean you put her in dirt you watch her
grow that's from TGA sub-cooled genetics
shout-out to my friends at TJ sub cool
see I could have used one of my own
strains instead I used a sub cool
genetics ah Jilly bean she's really easy
to grow you may need one stick in the
middle just to hold that top Cola up if
she gets real huge
if she gets real big branches you may
need a couple of sticks to hold those up
put a stick on there use a fuzzy tire
some plant tape or something just hold
those sticks the buds - the giant sticks
that's real easy Jilly bean is really
easy to grow something like my Bounty
Killer the Bounty Killer gets really
long arms and girls really really big so
she's a little harder to grow she's
gonna need more space she may need some
trellising she's gonna need more work so
think about what you're able to do can
you get in there and put these plants
under a trellis can you handle putting a
lot of stakes in the plants if you can't
be there a lot if you're just gonna set
up a hydro grow and leave and come back
every now and then when you need to then
something like Bounty Killer wouldn't be
ideal for you something more simple to
grow something that you don't have to
mess with a whole bunch cookie rec from
Ken Avenger I've got a phenotype of
cookie wreck that you don't even have to
water it water it once or twice and it
just [ __ ] lives forever I don't know
how it does it it loves to be bone-dry
it thrives when it's dry so something
like that something that they say hey it
likes dry in the description that may be
better for you so think about how much
work you're going to need to put into
the strain that you are purchasing if
you're buying a short stocky indica that
finishes in eight weeks it's not gonna
be a whole bunch of work if you've got
at all stretchy sativa that takes 12
weeks that's gonna be a lot of [ __ ]
work
and if you haven't grown a lot of
cannabis do both of those things grow
yourself an 8-week indica and then grow
a twelve-week sativa see what it's like
if you've got a small room and you
overcrowd yourself with that sativa and
you've still got four more weeks to go
you're looking at life going [ __ ] what
am I gonna do it gets stressful anyway
think about aromas and flavors the
descriptions of the aromas and flavors
are sometimes kind of fantastical I
would look for reviews on the strains if
you're going by flavors and aromas
sometimes the breeders will definitely
inflate the the descriptions when it
comes to flavors and aromas they'll try
to tell you that it tastes like
bubblegum coated in sugar coated in
grape juice rolled in pine needles and
by then you're lost your tongue doesn't
even know what the hell to think of I
try to keep my descriptions fairly to
the point and really quick but be
careful if that's what you're shopping
for also
and this is a big part of what I'm going
to talk about but read about the
phenotypes or do research on the seeds
that you're buying to see what types of
variation come from those seeds those
are called phenotypes see what types of
phenotypes are known for coming from
those seeds and what the numbers are
for getting those phenotypes I like to
use Jillybean a lot when I talk about
phenotypes big shout-out to miss Jill
and sub cool from TGA genetics but the
Jillybean I like to talk about her when
I talk about phenotypes there are three
phenotypes that you generally get from a
pack of jellybeans so if you pop ten
seeds
we'll see you get five males and got
five females to deal with you're
probably gonna have a candy store fee
know the orange vino and the one that is
just kind of in the middle that's just
basic it's the basic [ __ ] fee no it
doesn't really have a name it's not
known but that candy store and the
orange Fino are popular fee knows so you
could if you're gonna buy some jelly
bean you could go research what they
look like what they smell like you could
see pictures of both phenotypes you
could get very good description to both
phenotypes through the internet through
a little bit of searching I'd go to web
forums and just search for the name of
the strain and then type fee no
variations or phenotypes available or
common phenotypes and I'll start showing
you and you'll start seeing it and then
you'll know what your chances are of
finding that when it's kind of like
buying baseball cards you guys sometimes
we're all looking for that [ __ ] Mickey
Mantle and sometimes you find it you
just got to run seeds and you never know
what you're gonna get but if you do some
research you know how many Mickey Mantle
cards are put through how many packs so
you can at least think about if I buy a
10 pack of this drained what are my
chances of finding my keeper that I am
the phenotype that I'm looking for
you could probably narrow it down a
little by doing some research alright so
once you've decided what strain you want
to grow and who you're going to order
from there are several places to order
you guys but I highly recommend that
dank team.com they may not have
everything you're looking for but
they've got plenty of good [ __ ] on there
so check them out ah once you've decided
what you're gonna order and where you
gonna order from you need to decide if
you want regular or feminized seeds many
of the strains available now come out in
regular seeds and then shortly after
that they are released by the same
breeder in feminized form now if you're
not familiar with feminized seeds let me
tell you what they are when you grow
cannabis from regular seeds you have a
chance of having male or female plants
of course in the cannabis garden
if you're growing four buds you only
want the female plants you would remove
the males
a lot of people don't want to deal with
the male's so we have devised a way to
create plants to create seeds that will
only create female plants a lot of
people think it's [ __ ] a lot of
people think they're hermaphrodites I
understand how it works I can teach you
how it works
it is not [ __ ] they are not
hermaphrodites I can give you a brief
lesson on how I do it because that's not
what this episode is about but quickly
here's how it goes I take a female plant
I treat it with the product that I make
at home it is called silver thiosulfate
I treat the plant with silver
thiosulfate each strain needs a
different treatment regimen some plants
want to get hit real hard with a heavy
dilution some want to be sprayed more
frequently with a lower dilution rate it
depends on the strain you have to
experiment with that I will spray a
female plant with silver thiosulfate
that female plant will put out a
response the silver disrupts the copper
movement in the plant which creates an
ethylene reaction in the plant which
triggers the plant to produce male
flowers those male flowers will produce
pollen that only contains female
chromosomes
since my plant is a female there are no
male chromosomes in this plant so the
pollen that comes out is female I put
that pollen onto a female plant now I
have only used female genes so all of
the progeny the seeds will be female if
I did this correctly they will all be
females and I know what I'm doing so
when I do this it happens correctly
there's no witchcraft to it there's no
tricking the plant
there's no genetically modifying
anything this is just basic science from
triggering the plant by treating it with
the chemical you disrupt one part of the
plant to trigger a desired response and
I've done it several times I've
researched it very well and this is how
you make Femina how we make feminized
seeds how I make feminized seeds it's
how modern feminized seeds are made now
I will give you guys credit that say
that feminized seeds were all
hermaphrodites back in the day maybe a
long time ago when the FEM seeds started
yes the way they were doing that is just
turning on the whites during the
flowering cycle and they should be
asleep messing with the light cycle
messing with the photo period that will
definitely cause plants to throw seeds
those seeds do not have
only chromosomes those plants will have
a tendency to have intersex traits which
mean it'll be male and female at the
same time also known as a hermaphrodite
also known as cut that [ __ ] down and get
it out of my garden so back in the day
yes FEM seeds were made with a little
bit of shady shitty practices now we
understand what we're doing and
feminized seeds are made with science
with research and I believe in them and
trust in them so if you want to grow
regular or feminized seeds that is up to
you
many people are haters on feminized
seeds it's because they're not educated
but also a lot of people are haters on
feminized seeds who are very educated
because they feel like people breeding
with feminized seeds will cause problems
down the line and they feel like
feminized seeds sort of bottlenecks the
progress of cannabis bottlenecks the
evolution bottlenecks are breeding if
some folks feel that way I do not I do
take some responsibility by making way
more regular seeds than I do feminized
seeds try to counterbalance the damage
that I do by making FEM seeds if anybody
thinks I'm causing any problems I just
make way more regular seeds to kind of
offset that I don't see a problem with
FEM seeds I think it's really helpful
for a person who has here in Colorado
you're allowed to grow six plants
legally you can set up a grow wherever
you want in your house as long as it's
secure and you can grow six plants now
you want to have all six of those come
to fruition hopefully so six feminized
seeds would be the way to go instead of
throwing down six seeds and having three
of them become boys and now you got a
pool three your plants only got three
left it kind of [ __ ] you get all this
wasted space you thought you had six
that's where feminized seeds would come
in very handy so once you've decided
what strain you want and you've decided
if you want regular or feminized seeds
that's when you go ahead and make your
order go to the website of your choice
the dank team comm find the strains you
want then you make your order and then
you patiently wait for those seeds to
come in the mail if you're in a legal
state you put them in a safe you put
them in a safe storage container and you
collect them if you are in a state where
it is legal to grow cannabis you
germinate them and you grow them the
best you can all right now I want to
talk about expectations of a seed pack
and I've kind of talked about selecting
seed packs but I haven't really talked
talked too much about what you should
expect once you start growing your seeds
it seems to me like
a lot of people think that every seed
they plant is going to be a keeper a lot
of people seem to think that if they buy
a 10 pack of whatever strain is hot
today vit if they plant one of those
seeds it's going to grow and look just
like the one in the picture just like
the one that whatever breeder posted on
the website that you bought it from you
think it's gonna look just like that if
you plant one seed you think it's gonna
taste just like the one you bought from
the dispensary that one time you think
it's gonna get you high just like that
maybe maybe you're gonna get super
[ __ ] lucky and it'll be that way but
chances are it is not like that if you
buy a 10 pack of seeds and you plant 10
seeds and they're regular seeds you've
got a 50-50 chance of each of those
seeds being a male or a female um a
friend of mine message meet the other
day and said that he got some seeds from
me that I gave him and he told me every
single one of those seeds in that
package was a male so he got a bunch of
seeds and now he has zero [ __ ] growing
because they were all males it's really
rare that you get a hundred percent
males but it's possible it's also
possible that you get all females but
science says you got a 50-50 chance of
getting a male or a female from each
seed so let's say you pop ten seeds
hypothetically 50-50 chance happens five
males came out those got cold
those are pushed aside now you got five
to choose from if you see anything
acting funky early and veg when it's
still little I get rid of those if it's
ugly if it's not growing right if it's
slow if it's shitty if it's got a
problem I toss it why do I want to waste
space and time and nutrients money
lights air on something that is not
going to be what I'm looking for if it's
small and shitty it's always gonna be
small and shitty gonna get rid of it I
don't replace it with something better
so now let's say let's say you got five
females let's say one of them was just
growing a little little janky she's gone
now you got four now you've got four to
choose from
what does suck about seeds is there's
variation what is [ __ ] awesome about
seeds is there is variation yes you want
the one that looks like the picture that
the breeder posted up to the website
hopefully that's the one you get but
hopefully you get the one that grows
perfectly for your space hopefully you
get the one that smells just like you
want when you walk by it you go damn
that smells good hopefully you find the
one that gives you the effects you are
after if you're a medical patient
hopefully one of those four plants
that's left is the phenotype then when
you smoke it all of your pain goes away
or all of your anxiety goes away or
you're able to dance like Michael
Jackson or whatever your goal is
hopefully you get to finish those four
phenotypes and you get to smoke them and
one of them was the magic phenotype for
you that's the cool part about growing
from seed you get to find the one that
is perfect for you now let me throw in a
piece of advice here that is just kind
of random but it's something that I
should say whenever you grow whenever
you get a new plant if it's a clone if
it's a seed whenever you grow a plant
for the first time make sure you take a
clone of it because that may be the most
amazing herb you've ever grown and if
you don't have a clone if you don't have
a copy of that to grow again you might
be heartbroken it might be some of the
worst [ __ ] you ever experience I had a
plant years ago that I grew from seed
and I tried to take clones of it so many
times and none of the goddamn clones
would root I don't know why I wasn't
good at cloning back then but I took
enough clothes for at least one of those
clones should have taken root and I
should have that plant but they just
wouldn't root and I smoked that weed I
was like this this is amazing cannabis I
smoked it with my buddy pops I smoked it
with Kevin and pop said that that was
one of the top-five best
weeds he has ever smoked and that old
man is picky and stubborn and if he said
it was one of his top five it was damn
good wheat and I loved it and I don't
have it I'll never get to smoke it again
because I couldn't get a clone of it and
I'm sad about it I'm a little bit I'm a
little bit shook and broken up over it
so take clones of everything that you
grow if it's the first time keep one
clone alive find out if it's good find
out if you want to smoke that again if
you don't want to smoke it again throw
those clones away if you love it keep
that clone and you can grow it over and
over and over again turn that clone into
a mother plant you can take clones off
it off of it for years all right so I
want to get back to talking about the
variation and finding the phenotypes it
does suck that you have variation in
plants and it kind of depends
how far the breeder took that plant F
ones are gonna find a lot of variation F
- not so much F 3 it's gonna narrow down
by the time you're to the F 4 F 5 you're
gonna come out with fairly uniform
plants but you'll still find variations
in there
I like the variation so when you buy
seeds expect some variation don't think
you can plant one and it's gonna look
just like the one on the picture or
taste just like the one you smoked at
the dispensary you're gonna have to do
some work it's called a phyno hunt when
you're searching through those
phenotypes to find the one that works
best for you that's a Fino hunt an
experienced grower like myself loves a
good Fino hunt it keeps it fresh it
keeps it new you gotta keep an eye out
for the males you're excited it's like
when you're a kid used to get a box of
cereal and you [ __ ] first thing you
would do is go home and dig your arm all
the way into the cereal and could all
sugary I'm just trying to find that
prize and hope you got the cool prize
that was on the box that's kind of what
it's like when you grow from seed you
just can't wait to see what you get so
you finish out those four and then you
get to smoke them all and then hopefully
everybody in the room agrees quite often
there will be some disagreement
everybody will be like I really liked
number two and then somebody be like man
number four is the one and then be in
the grower you've got to decide do you
want the one that harvested the best or
tasted the best that's where you have
decisions to make try to keep maybe
maybe the one that harvested the best
keep that one around and the one that
works the best medically for you keep
that one around that way you can grow
the medical one for your medical head
stash and you can grow the huge
Harvester just to have backup buds for
when you smoke all that good [ __ ] maybe
you can smoke him together make it
stretch a little bit but the best part
is you get to decide you grew that from
seed you've got a custom strain now that
nobody else has got around you because
you've got that phenotype and nobody
else has it hopefully you've got
something brand new if you're a cash
crop er if you're a black market grower
that's the way to go then you've got the
new new [ __ ] that nobody else has
alright so when you buy seeds keep in
mind there's gonna be a little work
these are not Tomatoes they're not gonna
grow all the same they are not clones
they're not gonna grow all the same
they're not genetically modified they're
not gonna grow all the same these are
seeds there is nature happening here the
breeder can do so much work but we
cannot guarantee you what's going to
come from a seed weird [ __ ] happens from
seeds amazing [ __ ] happens from seeds
that's why I grow from seeds you can
grow something that nobody else has you
can find something that's way more
amazing than the last seed grew you can
keep growing more seeds
love it I love growing from seed so I
guess what I'm trying to say is expect
some work you're gonna have to grow the
seeds take a clone of that seed pull all
of the males from the room as soon as
you see them show and male pull those
from the room pull any slow or weird
plants get rid of those out of there
then you got to finish out the
phenotypes that you keep trim them dry
them cure them smoke them if you have
lab testing available lab test them if
that's what you want but I've talked in
another episode that lab testing isn't
always the way to go who cares what the
lab test says if you like smoking
phenotype a and the lab test says that
phenotype B has more THC who cares
keep number a it's the one for you
you're not growing for a lab you're
growing for your medicinal needs worry
more about that but smoke it finish it
get it lab tested if you want to make
some hash out of it
maybe if that's what you smoke see what
that does then choose the one that you
really like or choose the two that you
really like I'm not gonna make a limit
I'm not gonna limit you you can have as
many as you choose but pick the ones you
like get rid of the ones that suck for
you and then you've got clones
now you can redo it I like to kind of
narrow a ten-pack down to two or three
and then grow those two or three again
side by side and then I'll narrow it
down to two then I'd like to think I'm
to narrow it down to one but I always
get [ __ ] stubborn and keep two around
for a real long time and then eventually
I'll get tired of growing one and I'll
just I'll get tired to grow on the whole
stream honestly and I'll just keep one
of them around to have it in my library
and then I'll grow more seeds and then
I'll find something better than one of
it however many is in my stable usually
I got about twenty female plants maybe a
little more
so I'll grow some seeds and I'll see
what I like and if I find one that
really is better than one of those
twenty or however many mother plants
I've chosen to keep it whatever facility
I'm in if one is better than I will just
coal one like whatever the weakest link
is we'll get replaced by the new
seedling but since I'm so stubborn what
ends up happening is I replace that old
one with two like my two favorite new
phenotypes until I get bored of growing
that new strain until I start growing
something new and then I just tossed one
of them and put it in the basically on
the shelf for preservation with the rest
of my mother plants and then I will
decide if I want to breed to it or
whatnot once you start growing from seed
you may find yourself kind of becoming a
plant hoarder just wanting to pop more
seeds find that next phenotype see what
you can pull out of a seed pack next it
becomes a very
be addicting hobby a passion and art
whatever you want to call it growing
from seed is a really fun thing to do I
really enjoy I love growing from seed
way more than I like growing from clone
I like clones cuz I know what I'm gonna
get in a future episode we will do the
clone versus seed debate I will also do
the regular versus feminized debate if
you've got anything you'd like to
contribute to those debates you can send
me info I email me it grow from your
heart at hotmail.com or tweet me at GF
wih podcast I would love to hear your
side of the debate and you never know
maybe I'll use part of your email in the
episode all right you guys let's recap
and start wrapping up this podcast the
short story is if you buy a pack of
seeds grow that pack of seeds and don't
expect to find the exact one that you
saw in the breeders website you're gonna
have some variation if you plant ten
seeds and they are regular or feminized
I wouldn't expect all ten of those seeds
to come to fruition you may not harvest
all ten of those some of them may need
to get cold for random reasons you may
have a male you may have a hermaphrodite
yes regular seeds or feminized seeds can
be hermaphrodites you need to get those
out of there you may just have weird
weak plants you may have a plant that
grows way too tall way too fast you may
have one that won't grow at all get rid
of that [ __ ] so that you can have strong
healthy plants you don't want to keep
around something that's a piece of [ __ ]
so don't expect all 10 of your seeds
that you plant to come to fruition you
are growing that first round to find the
phenotype that works for you or your
patient or your style or your needs or
reaches your goal the first grow with
the seed pack is not meant to be really
a production girl you will have usable
material have usable product but it's
not a production run you want to find
the keeper then that's the one that you
want to do your production runs with
then you want to dial that one in learn
how much nutrients she wants learn how
much humidity she likes learn how long
you need to let her go maybe she needs 8
maybe 9 maybe 10 maybe 11 weeks pay
attention to that get her dialed in but
the first run is just to find that
phenotype that you're looking for
all right podcast rolled my throat is
telling me that it is time to wrap up
this episode I want to thank you guys
for listening to another show don't
forget to check out patreon patreon comm
slash girl from your heart if you were
interested in contributing to the
podcast patreon is the way you can do it
also I would love it if you stalk me on
all the social media check me out on
twitter at g f YH podcast you can find
me on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast on Instagram I use my seed
company name
we are Irie underscore genetics I RIE
underscore GE ne T ICS check us out
there I read genetics also you got any
questions if you've got a product you'd
like me to review or you'd like to
sponsor the show you can send me an
email
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you once again
thanks to everybody that send me an
email that got read on this show and
everybody who sent me an email in the
past I want to give a huge shout out to
my friend amber from the fish show and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
routinely do from
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]