hey everyone this is davon granny and
you're listening to the grow from your
heard podcast know what a podcast world
its Rasta Jeff and it's Thursday so that
means it's time for another throwback
Thursday episode of the girl from your
heart podcast before I get into the
block of old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any promotions any contests
or any giveaways those have all expired
there are currently no contest no
promotions no advertising or no
giveaways also let me update all of the
social media if you want to find me on
Twitter you can find me at G f YH
podcast on Twitter on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast and if you'd like to send me an
email
it's draw from your heart at hotmail.com
ladies and gentlemen I hope you enjoyed
these chunks of old episodes so here we
go to throwback Thursday episode of the
girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community is
time for episode number 112 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and
conversations
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran dabber if you're
a cannabis activists even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to see the
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show big thanks to
Kat
the entire crew right now you guys are
listening to a song called the doggy dub
it's off the album the constant struggle
make sure you check that out
also this podcast is brought to you by
our good friends at Hitman glass Tim and
glass glass made in America by American
what I'm paying for is gonna give me a
nice fat dad glass guys don't trust your
dad don't trust your dad to a rig meat
in China by a Chinese child without
proper eye protection or adequate pay
probably barefoot working all day with
no wages you guys buy hit man glass made
in America by folks who dab as hard as
uni glass is not only a glass company
dougie is a huge part of the canvas and
hash movement make sure you support
hitman glass and be sure to check out
the chalice Festival in California go to
hitman glass dot-com and also search for
hitman glass Dougie on Instagram give
them a follow sorry I'm coughing through
the intro because I'm already sitting
here hitting my hitman eseries sidecar
this is my first hitman rig and I have
been impressed since my first rip out of
this bad dog I picked this up in
illusions glass gallery about five years
ago this has been my go-to rig all the
time it's sitting right here in front of
me right now I've got the let's see it's
got the white hitman logo on the side
it's got the black flame logo up the the
stem piece where the nail goes and it's
got a big fat base on it it's got the
e-series perks of the perk has letter e
in it four times and it's got a hitman
highly-educated duality nail on it that
is my go-to rig that's probably my
favorite rig in the whole collection
until the new rig arrives we will talk
about that looking for a new rig go to
hitman glass comm Christmas a wonderful
Christmas I hope you got the gifts you
wanted I hope you gave a bunch of
wonderful gifts I hope you got to see
people smile at the gifts that you gave
them this is also the last episode for
the year 2015 so when I come back it
will be the year 2016 I'm going to put
together a checklist of things that you
guys should be doing like monthly daily
weekly monthly I'll get that out to you
at the beginning of the year but I'm
sure there's some [ __ ] that you were
missing sometimes we need a reminder
notes Christmas everybody I'm stoked for
Christmas feeling the vibe I wasn't
feeling the Christmas vibe I've been
working too much I've been busy I've
been on the go but I finally got all my
Christmas shopping done I got caught up
so I'm feeling the vibe I'm in a good
mood having a good day sitting here
taking dabs getting the show prepared so
let's get into it I know you guys would
prefer draw lessons but it's been a busy
couple of weeks and then I saw this news
article so there's gonna be a little bit
of news on this episode and then I am
going to talk about how I got into the
cannabis industry um I was hanging out
with a few friends that have known me
for quite a while and they're like dude
how did you even get into this I was
like well that's a podcast topic so let
me just say it into a microphone oh then
you guys can listen to the show so I'll
talk about that in a couple of minutes
before I get to the news article before
I get to talking about how I got into
the industry I want to give a little bit
of advice a friend asked me about foliar
spray he's actually applying silver
thiosulfate to his plants so that he can
reverse his females into
males and make feminized seeds and he
asked me one question about foliar spray
that I thought I should help you guys
out with a little bit when you were
spraying your plants whether it be
foliar spray whether it be pesticides
whether it be silver thiosulfate to try
to make male plants out of them however
you are spraying them I highly suggest
that you either spray right when the
lights go off or that you turn the
lights off while you spray there are a
couple of reasons for this but my main
reason for this is that you don't want
to spray your plants when you've got big
heavy high-intensity discharge lights
right above them because you're gonna
spray little bubbles all over your
plants you're gonna put this layer of
bubbles it's basically a bunch of
bubbles all over your plants if you want
a nice fine mist when you spray you're
gonna have bubbles all over your plants
plants are gonna be soaked and these
high-intensity discharge lights are
gonna shine down onto those bubbles and
it's going to work kind of like a
magnifying glass remember when you're a
little kid used to roast ants with a
magnifying glass I know not everybody
did that but a lot of the boys are not
their head going yeah we did that well
you're gonna do the same thing to your
plant the lights are gonna act like the
Sun the bubble is gonna act like the
magnifying glass and your leaf is gonna
get little white burn dots on it you're
gonna be really confused as what it's
from you're gonna think a bug ate it you
think you have a deficiency you're gonna
think something's messed up but honestly
what happened was you foliar spray and
the light made a little bubble on there
and it burned the [ __ ] out of your
plants so I highly recommend either
removing the plants from the light
turning off the light or waiting until
the light clicks off right when that
light clicks off if you've got a small
crop you should be able to get in there
and you should be able to spray that
entire crop in just a couple of minutes
and your plants won't even notice that
you kept them up for a couple of extra
minutes and that way you're not gonna
get any burns on your plants from the
light then you're not interrupting your
photo period and your plants are gonna
get all of the light that they should
have gotten throughout the day cycle so
I recommend spraying right as the lights
go off or if you need to turn the lights
off or if you must just remove the
plants if you're only gonna spray one or
two plants like my friend fred is trying
to reverse a female plant into a male by
spraying it with silver thiosulfate and
I would just take that plant into
another room I would almost take that
plant to another part of the house if
it's a home grow I would go out to the
garage and spray it out there because
that way you will not get any of that
silver thiosulfate on the plants that
you want to remain
so that's my guidance on that also Fred
let that plant that you've sprayed dry
before you return it to the grow room
with the females because you don't want
to spread that liquid dripping silver
thiosulfate on to any of the other
plants
all right so that's my guidance on
foliar spray or pesticide application
mainly don't do it with the lights on
cuz you don't want to burn the [ __ ] out
of the plants alright now I've got a
news article that I'd like to share with
you this one comes from the westward and
this article was written by Thomas
Mitchell make sure you guys check out
westward Calm the West Road is a Denver
newspaper like every town has their
little local newspaper the westward is
their little local like alternative
magazine newspaper type of thing make
sure you check that out if you're ever
in Denver it's a great publication you
ever want to know where all the cool
shows are where the good food is
whatever is going on that's the article
2 or the magazine to check out all right
the Westborough article goes like this
something's going on in Pueblo County
you might not notice as you drive
through the town which shook a big hit
during the steel recession of the 80s
and has slowly been coming back but your
nostrils should get a clue once you
reach the outskirts where the aroma of
cannabis hits you although this isn't an
unusual odor in Colorado these days the
pot industry is in full bloom in the
county surrounding Pueblo I wish I could
write my high school guidance counselor
a letter about this says Michael Cadwell
Director of Sales for the Los Suenos
cannabis farm as he sniffs above the
size of a football this is the way we do
it he says excuse my coughing you guys I
was taking some dabs earlier los sueños
is a 36 acre farm just outside the city
in Pueblo County it's one of the largest
outdoor grows in the country unlike
Denver County this one does not require
that commercial cannabis cultivation be
confined inside and a stroll through the
four fields planted with 55 strains
shows what a difference the bright
southern Colorado Sun makes plants here
grow much taller and heavier and they
need to be tied to stakes just to stay
upright a high elevation increase and
increase in ultraviolet rays tricks
tricks the plant into higher resident
resin production explains Erin Hovey
head grower at Los Suenos and the
natural sunlight is virtually year-round
he says still the area can get cold so
when the winter for winter frost hits
loose los sueños an outdoor growing
becomes unfeasible Hovey and his team
operate in four greenhouses a more
eco-friendly alternative to the light
warehouse setups in Denver you can have
a thousand lights in some huge warehouse
for massive production but that's not
what we're trying to do down here Hobie
says this is farming cannabis hope you
grew up in North Carolina where he
started growing marijuana outdoors as a
teenager
despite the objections of his parents
and local law enforcement he honed his
craft there before finding a legal
heaven Haven in Pueblo County where he
now matures nurtures I'm sorry nurtures
the lives of more than 10,000 marijuana
plants there's no playbook to growing
pot like this and there are no
guarantees with growing in the natural
elements but that's what makes it fun
Hobie says you can't be successful at
this without good help when the hail and
mold hits you need people who know what
they are doing Kogi is just one of many
Coloradans who moved to Pueblo to work
with the legal marijuana the locals are
getting in on the action too
more than 1300 jobs were created in
Pueblo County in 2014 by the marijuana
industry according to a study by the
southern Colorado Colorado Growers
Association a staffing firm that helps
people land marijuana jobs opened in
Pueblo last February at the same time
Industrial vacancies decreased by more
than 15% and marijuana related
businesses accounted for 36% of new
commercial building projects in Pueblo
County in 2014 according to the Pueblo
County Regional Building Department
folks are quickly realizing that the
cost of cultivation is a lot less in
greenhouses and outdoor says Pueblo
County Commissioner Sal pace who is
championed the marijuana industry as a
form of economic growth in the area we
have a very sizable rural rural agrarian
portion here sorry I've never read that
word before and I probably should have
when Coloradans voted to legalize the
growing and selling of recreational
marijuana they also agreed to allow
towns and counties to choose whether or
not to allow retail pot businesses
within their boundaries Denver already
the state epicenter of medical marijuana
quickly became the first retail
marijuana capital of the world while
much of the rest of the state struggled
over the decision of whether to accept
pot businesses and if so how to regulate
them but pace and his fellow
commissioners were keen on the idea of
an agricultural marijuana economy early
on and began issuing cultivation
licenses in 2014 in hopes of spurring
local industry there are now cultivation
licenses for 33 medical operations and
seven recreational operations in Pueblo
and Pueblo West County um let me clarify
for people that are not from Colorado
there were a couple things in that
sentence I want to clarify us is there
are now cultivation licenses for
thirty-three medical operations and
fifty-seven recreational operations
recreational and medical are grown in
completely different areas there so if a
grow applies to be a legalized girl with
the meed the marijuana Enforcement
Division they either apply to be a
medical grow or a recreational grow and
it's just the difference in licensing
it's how your planet count adds up it's
how your cannabis is handled so if your
medicine if the cannabis is grown in a
medical facility it can only be sold to
medical retail facilities if the
cannabis has grown in a recreational
facility it can only be sold in a
recreational retail establishment so
that's why they make the indication
there if it's recreational or a medical
marijuana facility and also they talk
about Pueblo and Pueblo West County
those are on the border of each other
and there are a bunch I think there are
14 or 15 dispensaries in Pueblo West
which is just a small short quick drive
from the city of Pueblo actually worked
in Pueblo West and I live in the south
side of Pueblo and it used to take me
just 15 or 20 minutes to get there so
it's not like it's a distance and the
city of Puebla does not allow any
cannabis sales within city limits so
everything that is sold is just in
Pueblo County and Pueblo West
all right I've gotten off on a tangent
let's get back to the article that says
all of the although the city of Pueblo
allows cultivation it's been more
guarded in its approach to sales
recreational pot shops are still under a
moratorium in the city until a public
vote on the matter in November of 2016
so residents need to purchase their pot
of at one of the thirteen recreational
shops in Pueblo County where retail
sales aren't illegal Pueblo City Council
is starting to come around on the
medical side however and the first MMJ
dispensary was in Pueblo city limits
opened in October bubbeleh natives
Stephen and Monique Duran who've been
together for 13 years started looking
into medical marijuana businesses
several years ago he started studying
medical marijuana after his shift at the
Comanche power plant while Moni became a
regulatory regulatory rules Wiz finally
after finding one of the rare buildings
in Pueblo that met all of the city's
Street stringent zoning requirements
through the marijuana operation which
include the location and a small council
approved industrial zone the Duran's
poured their savings into a lease for
the building which is now the 7-1 9mm J
dispensary
there wasn't map the city had for us in
order to meet the requirements and it
was very very limited we found this
place which meant all of them Monique
says right now it's us and one employee
running the store or just a couple but
we want to be the model for how to
properly medicate patients in Pueblo
there won't be many competitors
following that model though since zoning
maps the zoning map is so restrictive
that only a few more Medical
dispensaries might manage to find a
suitable spot within the city the
couples inspiration for seven one nine
came from watching Stephens sister
struggle through the difficulties of
multiple sclerosis and seeing how
pharmaceutical marijuana may keep
medication affected her this was just a
different person on the she was just a
different person on those meds says
Steven seeing what real patients have to
fight through was some strong motivation
now these homegrown owners are happy
with what they've created is coming in
the shop and looking around has two kids
from Pueblo who never really had much
sometimes it's like a dream Monique says
it's such a cool story and we hope to
make it a better one it's a big shot at
the Pueblo Colorado several years ago
like the article said this town was
falling apart when I used to tell people
that I'm from Pueblo Colorado they would
laugh at me they would not take me
seriously
now when I'm in Denver or Colorado
Springs and I say that I am from Pueblo
a lot of people are like oh you got a
lot of weed going on down there don't
you and so while we're starting a little
get a little bit of respect in the
cannabis industry so big shout out to
the westward thanks for publishing an
article about us I hope you guys enjoyed
it you guys I need to take a drink and
then I will be right back to talk a
little bit about how I got into the
cannabis industry hank
[Music]
alright you guys I am back I took a
drink as promised and as any good dad
would do I took a couple of fat dads
while I was off the mike
spared you the coffee into the
microphone uh what I was dabbing I want
to share this with you I was dabbing
where's the package here we go I've got
a little bit of Le cush it's le
confidential trust to some OG Kush but
this is pho wax most of the time I'm
smoking BHO most of the shatter and dabs
that you see available on the market
right now are made with butane this hash
was made with propane let me open up
some shatter that was made with butane
so that I can compare them side-by-side
and kind of give you a little a better
description of what I'm working with
here so the shatter most you guys are
familiar with shatter shatter is an
amber II colored sort of a honey colored
slab of shatter it's a little thin sheet
of real if I bend it it cracks like
it'll just pop off and some of it will
chip off and go flying away when you're
watching Jurassic Park all those big
slabs of like the amber resin that the
bugs are kept in that the bugs are stuck
in that is what shatter looks like in my
opinion I think that stuff looks like
shatter so compared to the shatter I'm
gonna open up this pho and take a look
this is propane honey oil it looks like
aa and it looks like a piece of soap
it's really lightly colored it almost
resembles since it's holiday time this
looks like a small piece of Amanda's
peanut butter fudge yeah if somebody cut
Amanda's peanut butter fudge perfectly
smooth I think it would look just like
this stuff
I just noticed that there was a kind of
a shitty technical difficulty with my
microphone so I apologize if part of the
show was subpar quality that is not my
style I'll do my best to fix it but I
just noticed if there wasn't something
working properly
so shout out to the failed cable pretty
sure it's just an XLR cable it needs to
be replaced not a big deal anyway I was
talking about this hash I'm picking some
of some of it up right now
this is much easier to handle and deal
with and work with and shatter shatter
is real sticky it'll stick to your
fingers when you break it it'll break
off when your fingers heat it up it gets
kind of goopy I'm holding on to this pho
and I would be able I am able to break
off little dabs for myself I'm able to
break off big ass dabs for myself and
little dabs for my friends it's much
easier to handle I just took a few dabs
of it one thing that I can really say
this stuff is flavorful it's got a
really sweet really dank flavor to it I
can't even properly describe the flavor
of it it's got a cushy flavor to it it
tastes the essence of cannabis is really
in the pho I was skeptical at first but
a friend of mine that works at just at a
dispensary she convinced me that I
wanted to try some of it so I grabbed
myself a gram and you know what I
approve so let me give a shout out to
the company here I don't usually do this
because I am affiliated with another
facility but I am gonna give a huge
shout out to the craft concentrates for
their la cush pho wax ah
the stuff is tasty and I do approve so a
big shout it's my friend Jessica for
convincing me to pick up a gram what up
Jess I appreciate the recommendation
good [ __ ] everybody buy some take dabs
of it I love it alright so I said I was
gonna come back and choke into the
microphone a whole bunch oh my gosh I'm
so sorry that was gross anyway I said it
was gonna come back and talk a little
bit about how I got myself into the
cannabis industry let me get into that
um I'm grabbing I wrote a couple little
notes here nothing major I just took a
couple little bullet points while I was
dabbing so I wanted to say that I was in
the cannabis industry illegally before
the cannabis industry ever existed you
guys I don't know how much of this I
should talk about or admit but we're
were beyond that right the statute of
limitations is probably gone if I admit
to any criminal activity anyway when I
moved here from California I was going
to high school here and our little crew
I was on a camping trip
somebody pulled out a pipe and we
started smoking and I was like nice some
weed Z&amp;C weed since I've left California
so we got stoned and then I was like all
right all my friends smoked weed that
means we're gonna have to find spore to
buy weed none of our crew really had a
weed guy yet and I knew that a couple of
the guys at school were hustling weed
but they didn't really there were some
racial tensions there in my school back
in that time the Mexican guys hung out
with the Mexican guys and the white guys
hung out with the white guys and we
didn't fight or anything it's just kind
of what those groups did we didn't there
was there's no reason for us to mix we
were over here listening to Green Day
and Nirvana and fish and they were over
there listening to I don't even know do
Cypress Hill is one of the things I
remember they listened to a whole bunch
of but anyway ah I was brave enough to
hit up one of the Mexican guys that I
knew sold weed I was like hey he could
sell me some weed he was kind of leery
about it at first but he's like yep she
have to buy ounces and at that time
we're just high school kids so announces
a little bit of a stretch so I made it
happen
I bought her an ounce and I started
hustling a little bit of that herb to my
friends and then uh those guys were
heavily connected and they were like
you're movin ounces you're gonna start
movin pounds now and they started
throwing me pounds for dirty dirty cheap
around here in this town I was had the
cheapest hookup on pounds around here
for a while until one day I was selling
a pound on the east side of town and a
couple of guys with face tattoos and
assault rifles walked up to my car and
they did not take my [ __ ] from me I was
so amazed but they told me that I was
not allowed to be selling my product on
that side of town that I was able to
sell my product on the north and south
ends of town but don't [ __ ] with the
east and west side and if they see me
again they're gonna take all my [ __ ]
from me and they sent me home nicely so
I kind of just became the street dude I
hustled the brick weed the Mexican brick
weed from a couple of friends that were
just flooding it to me so since since
none other white guys in my neighborhood
wanted to talk to these Mexican guys I
was just getting pounds from the Mexican
guys and just selling at all my gringo
friends and it was working out for me so
that's gonna where I made my break into
the weed scene that's how I learned how
to hustle all of that is a fictional
tale if you were involved in any sort of
law enforcement I just made that up
I'm writing a book and that is all going
to be in the fictional book I'm writing
all right so how's that feel all right
so then let's see I'm smoking and
hustling and doing my thing several
years go by
I learned how to grow actually I learned
how to grow
I had a guide that lived in the same
apartment building as me when I was like
7 years old and that guy was growing
wheat in his backyard and I would listen
to his conversations between my friend
Wayne and my uncle Eric and this dude
and they would talk about how to grill
weed I was like somewhere between 7 to
10 years old when I lived there and I
absorbed so much information from that
conversation that I felt like I was
destined to grow weed at some point in
time so we jump way forward into the
early 2000s I couldn't even tell you
exactly which year a friend of mine was
growing some weed I in Colorado and he
needed a hand and so I went helped him
out he didn't let me do a whole bunch
but he let me he exposed me to some
things so I learned how to do that and I
got good at that then I moved to
Lawrence Kansas that just for unrelated
reasons for musical reasons I changed
tube and chase the dream of being in a
band and went and played Lawrence Kansas
for several years travelled around the
Midwest but anyway a friend of mine
there had a place where we would play
music and one day I was playing the
drums and I looked up I don't know why I
looked up when you're playing the drums
your eyes just wander your eyes just go
places you get bored a staring at the
guitar players back all day guitar
players asses are all to you so I looked
up and I see this light coming from the
Attic and I'm like oh [ __ ] that's a
high-intensity discharge like they've
got an HPS light up there they're
growing some [ __ ] weed up there and
it's just like the crawlspace in the
garage a little storage area so I waited
for everybody leave except for the dude
that owns the place it was his space and
I go hey bro not to be an [ __ ] but I
got hit in the face with the grow light
a couple of times up there what you got
up there and he kind of looked at me
like huh weed smoke together we drank
together we're pros so he goes what do
you know about aggro and I was like I'm
I'm okay in a girl I've never been like
in charge of a girl but I've been a
helper plenty of times you know and he's
like well then come up here help me out
he's like I got a problem I need help
doing this and I'm gonna be out of town
for a few days can you take over I was
like sure so he goes out of town and he
ended up getting in trouble and he was
gone for several days way more days than
expected so I kind of took care of that
crop a harvest time came
and I was there through the whole
harvest I helped the dude pull down the
plants I helped him tram I got paid
pretty decently for helping him trim
some weed and this is in Kansas you guys
so I got paid a little extra because
we're really running a risk being in
Kansas the laws it was still completely
illegal and we were growing in basically
a jam space where we had a band practice
set up so we were begging for attention
every day with plants just right above
my head I could reach up and touch the
ceiling where these plants were sitting
on actually which would be the floor on
the opposite side so I got to finish
that crop with my buddy in Kansas I
actually brought some of that that we
grew what I got paid with I brought that
back to Colorado and shared that with a
lot of my friends here at my friend's
are like dude you guys kind of killed it
and they were kind of impressed with my
herb so I had to move back to Colorado
for some family reasons my grandparents
were passing I came to spend the kind of
final days with them you know it was one
of my good excuses to get away Lawrence
Kansas was [ __ ] me up you guys I
became an alcoholic I became a drug
addict I needed to get away from there
change my life and honestly I have not
drank since Lawrence Kansas not blaming
it on Kansas but once I left there is I
was able to get away from that lifestyle
and I feel like I'm way more productive
anyway I moved back to Colorado and I
get a you know medical marijuana card
and there's not a lot of weed on the
streets anymore and the weed that I can
find isn't up to the expectations that
I'm looking for and it's not as
available as I would like it to be so
again a medical marijuana card and I
told myself that when I got this medical
marijuana card I would quit drinking now
that there's as much cannabis available
as I want why do I need to drink right
so I go to a couple of dispensaries and
some of them were okay this was when it
was the wild wild west you guys this was
way different so I go to a couple of
dispensaries and I don't really see
anything that impresses me but I made
friends all over the industry and then
one day somebody told me hey there's a
new dispensary in your neighborhood but
it's kind of a private deal and they
told me that you had to call this number
first and then they would tell you where
to go and then you had to knock on the
door at the back of this building and
they would let you win so ah I get my
card ready I get my ID and I called the
number and the guy's like sure I'll be
home in about a half hour it's my house
just come knock on my door so I knock on
his door and he lets me and he's up so
there was an old health food store
downtown and it was a three-story
building
you have to walk up the back stairs to
the third storey and knock on the door
and this dude had an apartment up there
and he would ask for your ID in your
medical marijuana card then he would
have you sit on the couch and then he
would light up a joint and smoke with
you and then after you smoked about half
the joint he would bring out a couple of
different bags of weed I remember one of
the first ones he showed me was
chocolate chunk and then he had ak-47
Northern Lights there was another one I
can't remember I wish I remembered but I
remember the chocolate chunk got my
attention so he comes and shows me he
shows you these strains and then he only
let me buy a quarter the first time he's
like no I don't know you I don't know he
checked my medical marijuana papers - he
made a copy of my ID and my medical
marijuana card and sold me a quarter I
told me that I could come back every day
if I wanted we'd make friends and all
that stuff so I was kind of grabbed an
herb for other people I would go get
weed for the girl I was dating at the
time I would grab weed for my neighbor
there was a DJ friend of mine who needed
weed all the time and I was the only one
that really knew about this dispensary
in my group so I would go there every
day I would gather all my friends money
I'd go to this dispensary had ring the
doorbell I'd call him up I bring the
doorbell and then he'd let me in and
we'd sit on the couch smoke a joint he'd
saw me a couple of quarters and every
day I'd go he'd sell me a little bit
more a little bit more then you'd be
like so what are you doing this is just
for the people on my block the people
that sit in my basement smoke weed all
day instead of them smoking all my weed
I'm grabbing weed for everybody he's
like all right cool so one day I show up
and I can tell that he's overwhelmed
with work he was just completely slammed
we I walk up the stairs and I could see
that he's been carrying and shooting up
the stairs and it's all piled up by the
door and I can tell that he's getting
ready to transplant I was like you gonna
transplant some plants bro and he goes
yeah you ever done that before I was
like oh yeah I've transplanted a whole
bunch of plants in my life because I
have at this point I've been growing for
a little bit I've helped with a couple
other gardens and of course I got that
little lesson when I was a little kid
from my grower neighbor in the apartment
building so I was like yeah I can
definitely help you and he goes tell you
what come back tomorrow
come back at like 10:00 in the morning
and we'll do all of this tomorrow I'll
show you the grow and everything and I
was like cool so I go back of course I
show up a few minutes early and he's
impressed by that we smoke and get good
and stoned and then he shows me the grow
they had a bunch of lights this was a
third storey building that they had his
apartment was on the top story the
middle story was all the
and so he shows me to grow and he's like
we need to pot all of these pots into
bigger pots so I'm like cool let's do it
and it took me like I don't know maybe
seven hours to do all those he watched
me do a few and he's like [ __ ] this guy
knows what he's doing and he just went
out and did his own business it left me
there to do those pots I went up back up
the stairs and god I was like hey bro
these are all done he's like cool we
will pay you at the end of the week cuz
everybody gets paychecks at the end of
the week around here I'll have money
then I'll just come back at the end of
the week and I'll give you some money or
you can have credit at the store cuz you
shop here anyway and I was like I'm good
on Erb you know I've been buying a bunch
of weed I'm cool I'll just come back at
the end of the week and get money and
then nah so I would show up for the next
few days and I would go to buy my
regular quarter or half ounce or
whatever I was getting for the crew and
I would just bring cash for that but
then he would always have work for me
when I would show up you'd be like well
you transplanted those do you know how
to cut clones let's do this so we go
into the little room and we cut like a
hundred clones and he's like write down
how many hours you worked and we'll pay
you on Friday or whatever it was like
cool so throughout the week I work a few
hours and Friday comes along he's like
how many hours do you think you worked
and I was like you probably owe me you
know a couple hundred bucks or whatever
I came up with I don't remember the
numbers now he's like well here the boss
sent you this and he handed me a nice
stack of cash and I was like that's way
too much money bro he goes well we want
you to come work for us every week and
we want you here from like 10:00 to 5:00
every day and we'll pay you this much
every week if you just show up and do
the work I was like holy [ __ ] okay so
this dude was running the dispensary out
of his bedroom and I was running the
crow on the second storey and then he
would have to go run errands he would do
deliveries also at this time it was kind
it might have been illegal back in the
day but whatever that's already passed
ah he was going to do deliveries and
he'd be like hey bro people are coming
up to the store will you be able to help
them out I was like I got this and so
one night I'm helping we actually had
medical marijuana patients that would
show up these people were really sick
and we were a real dispensary so one
night there was an elderly couple came
and I'll never forget him this lady was
actually sick and we sat on the couch
and as I was having the conversation the
guy that was running this dispensary
showed up and he got to hear me explain
the differences between indicas and
sativas and he let me he got to hear me
tear gift for this woman I built a
relationship with her over a few minutes
and figured out what's wrong with her
whoa why is she sick how she likes to
consume cannabis what she's consuming
for how it makes her feel if in because
her sativas worked better for her what
the difference is between indicas and
sativas I spent 30 minutes talking with
this lady to make sure that I sold her
the right cannabis and to make her feel
comfortable it was her first time buying
cannabis from a store so this dude that
actually ran the place walked in and saw
me doing this and he's like bro you were
amazing at that I have no business doing
it after seeing what you just did with
that lady so he's like you were kind of
now the budtender guy oh there wasn't
the word budtender I don't think existed
at that point so he's like you were now
the sales guy you're gonna be dealing
with the customers and I've got this so
I would grow weed most of the day and
deal with the customers and then I
realized I was like we've got a
dispensary on the third storey I was
like why don't we have this down on the
first floor where everybody can access
it and they said that the city asked
them not to do that and I was like we've
got all the proper licensing um Monday
when I come in I'm going to move this
door down to the first floor and you
know we went to the second storey first
we moved we cleaned out an area and went
to the second storey so that you could
come into the first door on the bottom
story and it would be a little office
area and we'd greet you and then we'd
take you up to the second floor and sell
you buds we did that for a little while
and then I just kept getting braver and
ballsier I was like you know we got to
move this down to the first floor where
the handicapped people could come it's a
medical marijuana dispensary so we moved
it to the first floor and the owner was
really excited about what I was doing
he's like I love that you got balls he's
like I love that you can help the
customers he's like I love the way you
deal with things you know about cannabis
you can grow so he gave me a full-time
position ah
and eventually the guy that hired me
ended up moving on to open his own
business he wanted to open his own
dispensary because he was ah he learned
how to run it pretty much he saw
everything he needed to do he had a
dream of opening his own shop he didn't
want to work for my friend Tom shot at
the tom sexton and Karen Garnett they're
the ones who gave me a shot other than
Richard under Richard Richard is the one
that kind of told them to hire me but
then they trusted me with their shop and
gave me a shot so one day Richard left
there's a whole nother story on that if
you guys know me you know that story
there and I'm not ever gonna tell that
on a podcast
so Richard left one day Tom and Karen
came over to try to run the store I
pretty much had the store under control
I knew what I was doing I knew all of
our customers by first names I had a
young lady by the name of tree shadow
tree I don't know if you ever listened
to the show but I hope you do there's a
beautiful young lady named tree who ran
the front desk and also for a short time
there was a young lady named Chris Ann I
hope you hear this Chris Ann I miss you
and I really hope you get to hang out
play some music sometime I loved both of
those ladies but they were kind of my
Dora girl my door lady my greeters my
what do you call it reception is kind of
lady they weren't mine they were Z the
shops receptionist kind of person they
would check people in when they got
there they'd be like hey what's your
name let me see your marijuana card cool
we'll put you in line and then they'd
send it back to me they'd be like Jeff
your patient bill is heading back so
they'd come back and see me the owner
that originally owned the place would
show up every day and I'm kind of a
systems guy I make like systems and
procedures when you're running a
dispensary you've got to have like
procedures in the way that [ __ ] flows or
[ __ ] doesn't flow properly just like any
real business needs so I would set up
procedures and systems and nothing
against my friend Tom who owned the
place but he's an old southern boy from
North Carolina and he doesn't believe in
any sort of systems or order or putting
things here or doing things this way he
just wants to smoke a joint and things
happen the way they do which is
beautiful
but it doesn't work for business so one
day I had to get the balls and I had to
say hey Tom the best thing for your
business right now would be for you to
go on the mountain and grow the weed
that you grow and bring that weed back
to the dispensary and let me sell it and
you get the hell out of here he's like
you really think so and I was like I
love you but you don't know how to run a
business dude you're kind of a train
wreck when it comes to a retail
establishment and he took it very well
so he handed me the keys and he said
young man you got yourself a dispensary
don't do me wrong and he left and he let
me run that dispensary we ran that for
quite a while that's how I met our
friend white Mike that comes on the
podcast here I met Mike there I hired
Mike Mike was the first person I ever
hired the first time I ever hired
anybody is an employee it was Mike I
hired Mike to work as a backup bud
tender at metamour ministries dispensary
in Pueblo Colorado that's how we met
so I hired a few people the shop got
huge we were the only shop in town we
were the most popular shop in this part
of Colorado for a little while
we hired a couple more employees we
heard several more employees we had
Jordan and Andrea is backup bud tenders
and computer people and managers but
anyway I'm kind of getting sidetracked
here talking about madam R I'm
reminiscing in my own head
one day a city manager and a police
officer came in and handed us a cease
and desist letter that said we can no
longer serve cannabis out of that
location so we pretty much all of the
patients that were in the store we gave
them most of the product that was on the
shelf because we were now closed there
was nothing we could do with it I
remember I picked the jar of Sour Diesel
might pick the jar of Chocolate Chunk
Jordan picked a jar of what he liked an
Andrea picked a jar of what he liked we
took those jars the boss was like go get
a jar do whatever you want I don't care
what happens to the product we're closed
you can have the [ __ ] so the owner gave
us the product we gave most of the
edibles and all that like perishable
stuff to all the people did so when the
cop came in a bunch of people just left
they're like [ __ ] this and they got out
of there
but the people that snuck around they
got a lot of free products we just gave
all that [ __ ] away and then met amar was
officially closed that was the end of
that era I guess and that was my jump
start into the industry I'm gonna take a
quick drink of this frosty cold Dr
Pepper and I'll tell you the rest
well I'm drinking dr. pepper let me give
you huge shout out to my buddy John hunt
much respect much love John huh is
trying to quit drinking dr. pepper
I don't know why somebody would want to
do such a thing to themselves
alright I'm better I'm back ok so a
metamour ends up closing right um
everybody in this town knew who I was
from met amar everybody knew that I was
in the weed game that I was growing weed
that I had all the weed available so
everybody would started calling my phone
they'd like hey the store is closed
where can we get some herb um I was
still doing I had what's called a
caregiver grow the whole time I was
working at Meadow Mar I was acting as a
caregiver I had a personal home grow it
was completely legal and compliant with
the state of Colorado because I was a
private registered caregiver for five
other medical marijuana patients and
myself which meant that I was allowed to
grow plants for myself and them so I was
growing product for myself and my
patients but a lot of these people were
trying to get it from me
so there were a select few that honestly
I sold to shoot out of some weed to
those guys but I don't do that anymore
so I could talk about it but what I
really ended up doing was I was
caregiving and I was consulting and
teaching people how to be a better
caregiver so I would go if you didn't
know how to grow weed yet I'd go to your
house and I'd help you set up your Dro
I'd figure out how much herb you need to
grow how much space you've got we'd set
you up and then I would either get a fee
upfront or I would get a portion of your
harvest so that's kind of how I stayed
afloat there and kept myself real
popular into this cannabis industry
around here that and caregiving
as soon as I saw madam our start I'd
been breeding seeds and crossing plants
a little bit a little bit before now
before this time but when met amar went
down and realized that I needed
something solid because the consulting
thing was great but it's unreliable
people around here they say they're
gonna pay and a lot of times they kind
of don't want to pay
so I started breeding seeds for retail
distribution and that's how I read
genetics came up I was posting pictures
online people were loving my cannabis
pictures I decided to make an eye region
annex Facebook page and then I read
genetics really exploded I began finding
my seeds to a vent or distributing my
seeds to a vendor known as nature's
green remedies calm they are now known
as the dank team calm they might have a
little bit of my products available
right now as if you check them out the
dank team calm you may be able to get
some eye region attic seeds from there
so I started putting my seeds out I went
to a few cannabis cups and hustled
millions of seeds I've got millions of
seeds out in the planet now there are my
fault that I've given away and/or sold
so Wow I was noticing that I was getting
a little stagnant honestly I had the
podcast after after the seed company got
going I started doing a podcast with my
friend Wade we had a podcast called
seven one nine the blocks it is now
defunct ah but he was doing a podcast
one night I went to a comedy show and he
wanted to do a podcast after the comedy
show and he didn't have anywhere to do
it and I've got this sweet table and I
was like let's go to my house and record
it'll be fun so I did a podcast with
Wade and I honestly fell in love with
podcasting because of that but I did not
like the equipment that Wade had and I
didn't approve of the quality production
that Wade was doing and so I kind of
volunteered to help Wade get his show up
to par and I bought some recording I
already had some equipment cuz I'm a
drummer and a musician but I bought a
couple other add-ons for my equipment
bought a interface to make it work with
my macbook started podcasting fell in
love with podcasting with Wade we did a
couple episodes that featured cannabis
and then he got tired of hearing about
weed on his show so I made my own
cannabis spin-off and we're here now at
a hundred and twelve episodes holy crap
thank you guys for listening to me rant
this long and fit listening to 112
episodes so I started podcasting um then
there were a bunch of dispensaries
opening up in my area and I was watching
a lot of my friends in my age group get
really cool jobs at dispensaries and
just kind of looks like fun I missed the
meta Mar days I missed having coworkers
I was working from home and private
facilities and I wasn't having the
interactions with the social
interactions that I missed that I
desired so uh my buddy Kevin our old
friend Kevin that used to be on the show
he worked at the spot dispensary and he
kept putting in good words for me and
saying that they should hit me up and
have me be their grower because they
were having issues with their master
grower so I kept putting that off and
putting that off and then I decided I
started dating a girl named Angela and
Angela got a job at the spa and talked
about how much fun it was and so they
would have functions what's his name
afro man came out to the spa and we got
to meet afro man they did a few other
things that I went to as a guest with
Angela and I hung out and the spa crew
was a bunch of fun people I had a good
time with them we're all dirty minded
dudes and I had a really good time with
Rob and with Dave and with Vegas and
with the whole true I really got along
with everybody
so one day Angela said hey they want you
to come in and talk about a job so I
walked into the spot dispensary and
they're like who are you what do you do
I was like I'm Rasta Jeff I'm the owner
of Ira genetics I've been growing for
this long I've been breeding for this
long I helped found the only dispensary
in the city of Pueblo Colorado we got a
podcast with this many listeners I had
at the time an Instagram following of
like 15,000 followers which has been
deleted so I just threw down who I was
and what I did and they looked me
straight in the face and they said can
you grow hydro then I told him you know
I have very very little hydro experience
but I'm pretty sure I can learn it
because it's a cannabis plant I can
learn anything and they looked at each
other like they were impressed and they
shook my hand and they said how much
money do you want to make I told them
and they said okay and I kicked myself
in the ass because I should have shot a
lot higher since they didn't budge at
all they're like okay we'll pay you that
so that's how I got into a spot I
basically they knew who I was from my
buddy Kevin hyping them up and then
Angela told me that they were talking to
her and that I should go in there and
hit them up for a job so I went in there
and they gave me a job on the spot so
shout out to Kevin shout it to Angela
and shout it through the whole spot crew
even though I'm not there anymore I have
no ill will toward the spot it's just
not my spot for me they didn't have any
plants and I need to grow plants so that
puts me into the next phase of how I got
into the industry or where I am now in
the industry I guess
I worked at a spot for quite a while
they were having issues getting their
grow rooms up and running and up to par
and I was struggling to find something
to keep myself busy with for 40 hours
and I was on salary so I was expected to
be doing something I caught myself
cleaning [ __ ] in the parking lot one
time and I thought about it and I was
like not to be conceited but I was like
I'm a master grower and I'm pretty sure
I make one of the top salaries in the
building why am I here picking up
[ __ ] and not growing cannabis and
that really started to like eat at me I
was like I'm doing things like sweeping
up dead bugs and fixing hanging shelves
in the bud room was like I'm not here to
be [ __ ] Felix fix it or fix it Felix
from wreck-it Ralph brother that's not
my duty I'm kind of a cannabis grower so
one day I was at work and our good
friend hunt from Green and healthy
wellness sent me a text message and it
said give me a call as soon as you can
and hunt doesn't really send out the SOS
like that usually it's like what's up
brother let's take dabs and you're free
but he said as soon as you can so since
I wasn't doing a damn thing at the spot
anyway I pulled out my phone I gave him
a call he's like what's up brother and
he's like hey there's an issue with my
grower here and he no longer is employed
and I need a master grower and I was
like he actually was calling to ask if I
had a partner or a minion that worked in
my groves that I would donate to him so
that he could have somebody to work his
grows and I said you know what huh I
want that job and we agreed on a wage
and a starting date and about six weeks
ago it feels like I took over as the
lead cultivator at Green and healthy
wellness in Colorado Springs Colorado
right now the retail store you know what
by the time this episode comes out we'll
be just a few days away from the retail
location opening the new location is on
430 West Colorado Avenue in Colorado
Springs it's the old gas station
we call it the Terp station now we've
got some art in there
we had a professional artist come and do
some beautiful art on the inside the
building is looking really great there's
a lot of parking we will have a bunch of
great product around a February first we
will be harvesting the first round of
green and healthy wellness medicine
grown by myself rhasta Jeff put this
into flour I've been taking good care of
it so
it'll be ready pretty soon but that's
where I am now in the industry you guys
that's pretty much how I got in the
industry and that's where I am today in
the industry
I still breed seeds my next breeding
project will probably be making an f2
version of the strain arise I will also
add about four or five other females
into that selection there will so there
will be some arise f2 s and then a
couple of arise crosses that come out of
IRA genetics in the near future I do
intend to keep this podcast going as
long as people will listen I know lately
it's been a little bit unprepared but
that's because I'm working a lot of
hours at Green and healthy wellness
getting things put together there and
definitely adjusting to my new schedule
I'm getting everything back in order so
the shows are gonna get back to to what
they used to be I said that after
episode 100 we get back into the grow
lessons and I've been doing it a little
bit it's the holiday season so this
episode and the one next week are just
gonna be me ranting about stuff I think
next week I'm going to talk a little bit
about what I do in the grow room I'm
just gonna kind of take you guys to the
grow room with me we'll walk into the
girl we'll talk about my chores that I
do the things that I check we'll talk
about my personal grow and a small home
grow and we'll talk about the large
scale grow it green and healthy wellness
I'll try to talk about both of those I
also want to do a checklist of things
that you guys should be doing on a daily
weekly and monthly basis so those will
probably be the next two episodes anyway
I feel like I'm rambling on and on and
on
I'll keep this podcast going is what I
was saying I'm gonna keep breeding seeds
I read genetics will continue to come
out with new seeds I will keep breeding
my new stuff to my old stuff plus the
newest crosses that I find that I really
like will be bred into my lines I'm
gonna keep that going I will keep the
podcast going I will be at the cannabis
cup for most of the days if you guys are
coming to the Denver cannabis cup over
the 4/20 weekend I will try to be there
Saturday and Sunday and of course I will
do my best to make an appearance for
4/20 can I promise you anything with the
way the green and healthy wellness
garden goes that is a lot of work for
myself but I love every single minute of
it because there will be some
collaborations coming up in the very
near future I will be breeding some
strains with some other well-known
breeders I will be also creating strains
for some people who I can't even talk
about right now
people that you know their names you
might listen to their music you might um
you might watch their videos there are
things that you might do that we can't
even talk about right now but there's
some cool [ __ ] coming up in the future
so you guys I feel like I've rambled for
a good 45 minutes now Wow I just looked
at the time oh this is gonna be a long
episode I appreciate everybody for
listening to it that's where I came from
in the industry and that's where I am
now you guys if you want to be part of
the cannabis industry with me send me an
email I'd love to see what you got going
on I'm open for collaborations I'm up to
advanced cannabis and my cannabis career
email me it's go from your heart at
hotmail.com cuz I'm just wrapping up the
show I want to thank you for listening
I'll be back next year I will be back
next year with episode 113 we are either
going to do the checklist episode or
we're gonna walk through my ganja garden
and talk about my chores maybe we'll
combine that into one long-ass episode
you never know what rasta Jeff is going
to do I don't forget to check out our
sponsor hit man glass you guys make sure
you visit www.nasa.gov stuff the only
person that posts more stuff than hitman
dougie is Snoop Dogg is what I think
anyway
if you guys would like to sponsor the
show or if you've got a product you'd
like me to review send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I'll
get you all the information that you
need guys the show is officially over
and now that the show is over I'd like
it if you go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for girl from your heart
after that find the review section give
me a 5 star rating and type in a comment
let me know what you think of the show
and I will read your comments on a
future episode there are a couple of
comments saved up right now I'm trying
to get a few of them and I'll read them
all at one time but I promise you I will
read your comments on a future episode
um find me on all the social media I'm
on facebook I'm on Twitter Facebook is
grow from your heart Twitter is at G f
YH podcast if you would like to see
pictures of high quality cannabis
photography and also some pictures of
the grow it green and healthy wellness
and also some pictures of my walk ass
you guys I got dreadlocks down to my ass
a lot of people don't realize that a lot
of people say that my voice does not
match my face so go check me out on
Instagram you guys it's at Irie
underscore JH
nedick's i reaiiy RIE ireon discord
genetics on Instagram go check that out
I'd love to see on there and you want to
see what I'm doing trust me
correct if you've got something to say
you're not in all the social media you
can simply email me it's go from your
heart at hotmail.com I'd love to hear
your opinion I want to know what you're
thinking if you're listening to the show
I'm very curious
you guys don't forget that the shows
available on iTunes and stitcher and
every single episode is always in
forever archived on I read genetics
Colorado com don't forget that there is
a donation button on the podcast page on
the website it is the Christmas season
so if you want to throw a gift my way I
would definitely appreciate it you can
go to my website it's Ira genetics
Colorado com click on the girl from your
heart podcast tab at the top right there
is a donation button that goes directly
to my PayPal account I'm not begging and
I'm not ever going to charge you for
this podcast this show will always be
free this show I call it grow from your
heart because everything comes from my
heart this is free for you free to you
grow from your heart just like I am I'm
not gonna ask you for anything but if
you'd like to make a contribution my
PayPal account is right up there on the
website I would definitely appreciate it
I hope everybody has a wonderful and
safe and Happy New Year
if you get drunk and [ __ ] up please
don't drive get a cab get an uber call
me I'll give you a ride you guys if
you're too high to drive also please
take a cab walk stay where the [ __ ] you
are just don't get in the car and drive
and kill somebody kill yourself ruin
somebody's life please don't start the
new year off like that please I beg of
you just don't drunk don't get drunk and
drive don't be on drugs and drive if
you're gonna get [ __ ] up that's cool
just stay Park what a sober person drive
that's what lyft and uber and friends
are for so take good care of one another
this Happy New Year you guys I want to
give you a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah Happy New Year cannabis community
it's time for episode number 113 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write a feared new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a veteran
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots man for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots brood
yeah Happy New Year everybody hope you
guys had a great new year but peva made
some new year's goals if you haven't
made some goals for the new year you
should grab a pen and a paper and you
should just write down a few things that
you want to accomplish in 2016 and when
you get that feeling of accomplishment
you're gonna want to accomplish bigger
goals so just write down some goals and
get that [ __ ] done guys and also get
some [ __ ] in 2015 now is the time to
shake it off and leave it all behind if
you haven't forgotten about the [ __ ]
of 2015 it's time to take a big old fat
damn smoke a big old fat joint smoke a
Fat Boy
hit the vaporizer however you do it I'm
gonna take a big old fat dad but we're
gonna blow out all the [ __ ] of 2015
we're gonna start fresh here in 2016 so
we're gonna do that out of my my brand
new hit man short stack shove it to the
hit man crew you guys know me while I
buy a rig I like to buy an American rig
something made in America by an American
so I buy a hit man glass hey man glasses
made by dabbers these kids dab as hard
as you and I do hit man dougie is a dab
enthusiast he's a supporter of the hash
movement he throws a festival every
summer in California called the chalice
festival make sure you check that out
you guys I'm gonna hit my brand new hit
man short stack I don't think there are
words to describe this rig other than
[ __ ] amazing so I've got the email
hooked up I've got a big old glob of
cactus cooler from Terp X on the dabber
you guys take a dab with me and then we
will get on the show let's inhale some
positivity and love and freshness and
then we exhale we're gonna exhale all
the [ __ ] from 2015 let's take this
dab together you guys
[Music]
all right all right well I'm heavily
medicated now this will be a fun podcast
to the Hitman glass crew you guys make
sure you follow Hitman glass go to hit
man glass comm also make sure you follow
dougie on Instagram support hit man
glass glass made in America by Americans
made by guys who dab just as hard as you
guys I also wanna make a huge
announcement green and healthy wellness
is now open for business we are a
medical marijuana facility in Colorado
Springs Colorado we are at 430 West
Colorado Avenue if you have a medical
marijuana card we would love to see you
drop by pick up some tour packs
I'll pick up some Apothic ana pick up
some top-shelf flowers we'd love to see
you in there a big shout out to Britt
Carly Haley buzzy and especially hunt
the entire crew a big shout out
forgetting that place going I'm proud of
you guys drop in give us a visit what
else do we have for business
um these sticker packs remember a few
episodes ago we did a hash tag on
everybody who messaged us on Twitter and
used that hashtag they are going to get
a sticker pack a couple of nights ago
Mike and I sat here and addressed
envelopes and I will be stuffing
stickers into those envelopes and they
will go out Monday morning so when this
podcast drops those stickers will be in
the mail Monday the same day so by the
time you hear this the stickers are on
the way to you I've only got let's see
how many do I have here they're
addressed got one I've got two and the
third person already got there so I've
only got two so if you were involved in
that and you need to send me an address
send me your address to grow from your
heart a hot meal calm and remind me that
you deserve stickers from the hashtag I
like it when you ramble sticker giveaway
remind me I'll get to your stuff what
else do we got in I need to give a big
shout out to my buddy frosty I bumped
into my friend frosty at the candy
Canyon dad Club the other day
frosty I smoked that cush bud that you
gave me [ __ ] I was high that was awesome
thank you I smoked that this morning was
the first thing I smoked and made my
eyes little droopy made me want to be
nice and lazy for the day good wheat bro
I appreciate
it's always wonderful to receive the
gift of cannabis from friends it's super
great when your friends tell you that
they listen to your podcast and learn
how to improve their cannabis from
listening to the show and then they give
you buds that they grew so shot at the
frosty that super good weed dude I
really appreciate it you did a good job
well flushed well cured and super bleah
trimmed I like your work
man I got to give a shout out to
everybody at the canna Canyon I dropped
into the candy Canyon and everybody
there is super kind you guys when I walk
in everybody's like dab this dab this
try this I tried some live resin I tried
some butter tried some shatter smoked a
little bit of everything I had some
solvent list that's a full mil and a
little bit of everything the last time I
was there I really appreciate the way
they treat me there and shine that's all
my friends at the candy canyon a shout
out to camille shout out to everybody
over there i'll be doing an episode from
there really soon that features our
friend Fox Trax so keep your ears open
for that one alright guys so let's get
to the point of the show I've been
telling you that I was going to make a
checklist of things that you should be
taking care of in your garden so I did
that for you I've got a list of things
you should do daily weekly monthly
things you should do after each harvest
and also things that you should do
yearly there are a couple things on that
list so I think I'm gonna take a dad and
a drink while you guys listen to a
couple of seconds of reggae music and I
will be right back and we will get into
this checklist
[Music]
cactus cooler from turf backs if you've
ever cracked open a can cactus cooler
taking a drink it's exactly what this
hash tastes like it's kind of got my
mouth watering we're taking a dad that
made your mouth water usually your mouth
goes dry excuse me for coughing into the
microphone I was listening to a podcast
today and the co-host was just coughing
into the microphone err I really wanted
to turn off the damn show so I apologize
for coughing into the mic
anyway this checklist here we go this is
stuff that I feel you should be doing
every day some of this stuff will vary
if you've got a hydro garden some of
this stuff will be different if you've
got a soil garden some of this stuff
will be different based on the size of
your garden some of this stuff will have
to be done over a course of a couple of
days some of this stuff will have to be
if you've got a little garden this stuff
is just things that'll take you two
seconds so here is what I've got for
your daily checklist daily visually
check each plant for bugs molds or signs
of deficiencies or over fertilization
and correct if necessary oh you got to
get in there I walk in and I just pick a
random plant and I just pull a random
leaf off of a random plant and I flip it
upside down and I look at it I make sure
there's no bugs
I feel the leaf I can tell by feeling
the leaf how healthy the plant is I can
kind of rub on the leaf and tell I like
to pull the leaf off look for bugs look
for molds I look around the room see if
any of the leaves are yellow or crispy
or crunchy or if anything's happening
if you've got anything weird going in
there work on correcting it something I
should add anything that can be done
today do it today don't wait until
tomorrow you've got plenty of [ __ ] to do
tomorrow whatever you can do today do it
or you just keep adding [ __ ] up for
tomorrow and then tomorrow never comes
and then one of these days you're gonna
have a big-ass list of [ __ ] that you
never did you're gonna find problems and
you're gonna in your grow and you're
gonna know why it's because you didn't
do that list of [ __ ] that you should
have been keeping up on so try to stay
on top of your chores you guys that's
what I'm saying so check your plants
every day you should be touching every
single plant you should be putting your
eyes on every single plant get in there
and love them so the second thing on my
list here check to see if the plants
need water you can check visually I can
see if the plants look droopy at all if
they're starting to lean over if the
leaves are kind of hanging down they
need water or lift up the pot and check
the weight the standard way to do this
is think about it this way water your
plant water until it's full freshly
watered pick it up and see how much it
weighs that's its full weight when it
weighs half of that it's ready to be
watered again you need to pour in water
and get it wet again so second thing
check to see if the plants need water
the third thing I would do every single
day pull any dead leaves and put them in
a trash bag or a trash can that gets
removed from the garden area I don't
like to leave my trash bag or my
trashcan in the garden that doesn't make
sense to me I want to get that out of
there um one of the reasons being I
apologize for all the coffee and
cleaning with a throat that'll end here
pretty soon took a couple of ah the
reason I like to get yellowing leaves
out of the room as bugs are attracted to
yellow leaves bugs see yellow leaves as
a perfect opportunity the outer layer of
the leaf has been softened and they can
bite in and get to the juicy insides of
the leaves a little more easily and bugs
know that so they're attracted to yellow
leaves that's why your sticky traps are
yellow so get all the yellow leaves out
of there put them in a trash can put
them in a trash bag and get them out of
the room because those are gonna attract
bugs so get that [ __ ] away from there
the next thing I would recommend check
the clones in the domes for moisture
I checked the humidity levels in your
clones and check for roots and if you've
got roots to transplant them put them
into the next uh if they're going into
the next size Rock we'll put them into
there if they're going into cups with
soil throw them into there
have you got roots do whatever you need
to do if they need moisture or humidity
adjust that [ __ ] get in there and fix it
you can fix the clone domes really
easily so the next thing to do check the
temps and the humidity of the room and
adjust that if necessary you guys try to
aim for 40 to 60% humidity during your
bloom phase and then during the veg
phase you can be around 60 to 70%
humidity I wouldn't go any higher than
70% humidity and trying to have some air
flow along with that or you will get
some issues try to keep the daytime
temperature around 72 77 degrees I
really like 74 degrees plants really
like 74 some of the sativa is like to
get up to 77 during the day cycle during
the night cycle try to stay within 10
degrees of what your day cycle is so if
during the day you're getting 77 at
night you want to be at 67 or a little
higher don't go more than 10 degrees
swing from day to night so during the
day 72 77 during the night 60 to 65
degrees during your night cycle is what
I try to aim for another thing that you
need to do that a lot of people forget
to do and I can tell by your Instagram
photos sweep the damn floor all you
gotta do is get a broom and a dustpan
and a bucket and sweep the floor scoop
up that [ __ ] that you just swept up into
a dustpan dump it into the bucket get it
out of there and put it into a trash can
and get it out of the house all that
[ __ ] on the floor first of all it looks
terrible why do you want that [ __ ] on
your floor in your own room it looks
like [ __ ] get the leaves off there get
the dirt off there get that the I can't
think of what that shit's called right
now that white stuff that sucks to step
on the perlite get the perlite up off
the floor just sweep up you guys it's
not that hard every leaf on the floor
every little piece of debris that's a
good spot for a bug to hide if you've
got a problem with white flies fungus
gnats spider mites a fidex
that's another spot for a bug to hide
one little tiny bug can hide under a
leaf and lay so many eggs don't give
them the opportunity you guys fight the
battle at your advantage
don't give these bugs a place to go so
sweep the floor the next thing I would
do check any equipment check your hydro
pumps check the EZ cloner pumps check
your dehumidifiers if you're running
hydro check your mix pump in your
reservoir I know a lot of guys have a
big res filled with nutrients you just
put a pump in there to shoot the
nutrients around to check that pump make
sure it hasn't gotten clogged up those
pumps have little filters on them they
like to get gunky if you're using any
kind of feed system check that thing
make sure your sprinklers haven't gotten
clogged up if you've got an EZ cloner
check the water level in that as well
and refill it and adjust the pH so the
next thing you should do check the pH in
ppm levels if you're running any hydro
if you've got a flood and drain kit if
you're doing buckets or whatever check
your pH also check your ppm you need to
adjust your pH you need to adjust your
PPM's almost every day I've seen large
hydro Gardens need to be topped off
every day if not twice a day because of
water evaporation and plant productivity
and every time that water evaporates and
you add more water you've got to adjust
the pH so check that [ __ ] out all the
time every day if you can twice a day if
you can on that if you're running hydro
hydro guys may have a little bit more
work to do than a soil guys but we've
got a lot of soil and dirt to deal with
so the work will kind of math out I
guess I'm not sure I'm a real hydro
garden myself so I can't speak correctly
on that but it seems like you have a lot
of cleaning and a lot of maintenance to
do in a hydro drill so what's next I
prune and train the plants and shape
them the way you want them for your grow
space that's something you can be
working on every single day keep in mind
how you want those plants to be shaped
if the architecture correct since you
have sturdy plants try to use up as much
canopy space as you can with each plant
so prune and train your plants take off
all the shitty leaves take off any
little sucker leaves that are happen and
just get rid of that crap make the plant
cells all right excuse me so the next
step lollipop any small crap while
you're in flower all those little tiny
buds that are happening on the bottom
just crap cut that crap off you can
lollipop all the way up through week
four I've done it up into week five once
you get the hang of it you can really
get carried away you'll know what to cut
off you'll know what to leave so only do
it for the first couple of weeks I guess
until you get the hang of it then once
you've gotten a few crops under your
belt that you've ollie popped you'll be
able to do it up in a week four or five
without pissing the plants off I've done
it too late and caused from after nights
that's why I warned you to go light and
then learn how to do it so a lollipop
stuff take off all that small crap in
flower pull off any funky leaves while
you're there so the next thing that you
can do every single day you guys take
notes on everything you
Oh everything you do just write down
what you do I run a large grove for
green and healthy wellness basically the
owner of green and healthy wellness has
put me in charge of the grow what I say
goes he doesn't ask me any questions as
long as at the end of the harvest
there's our goal weight of quality flour
nobody's gonna [ __ ] with me and I'm
gonna reach that goal but the OCD person
in me the person that likes to be
accountable I make notes of everything I
do all day every day if I open up my
phone we could read exactly what I did
not exactly probably but I'm pretty
close to every step I did today from
walking in and checking the Clones
walking the roads and checking each
plant fixing the sprinklers like I write
down what I do every day just to keep
accountability and to keep myself
reminded of what's been done so that if
something goes wrong I can look back on
that look right here when I make this
stupid [ __ ] together I messed up also
you guys a good reason to take notes
this industry is expanding rapidly and
we're gonna have marijuana available in
every state before too long
when state start legalizing cannabis and
it's time to hire professional growers
you guys that took good notes of all
your grows you guys are gonna have a
portfolio basically an application or a
resume right there on paper you can say
look I took notes that shows that you're
organized it shows that you're
accountable it shows that you're
planning it shows that you're thinking
it shows that you're serious all the
other guys are gonna be able to say well
I grew this much weed in my mom's
basement and they're not gonna have any
pictures or any notes or anything like
that so you guys are taking notes you're
gonna have the advantage there so take
notes on everything you do I talk about
that a lot but it's something that I
think is really serious in a cannabis
grow what if you do something different
this time and it comes out perfect
you're gonna want to know what you did
the only way your dumb high ass is gonna
remember is if you wrote it down cuz
you're smoking too much good weed you're
growing too much good so write [ __ ] down
and that is my weekly or my daily to-do
checklist I'm now gonna move on to
weekly so this is nothing you should be
handling once a week I like to pick
Mondays and just kick Monday's ass I get
all the chores done on Monday and then
through the rest of the week you can
just focus on the plants and keeping
everything clean and doing all that
stuff so every Monday this is what I
would do I would start each week with a
well-planned feed in each room if you've
got a cloner
if they've got water in trays or in a
cloner dump that water out put fresh
water in there fresh nutrients whatever
you're using if you're using a and B in
the cloner or if you're using rapid
start or if you're using clone acts
whatever put fresh solution in your
cloner get it going fresh on Monday or
whatever day you choose to start but
once a week clean that sucker out and
get it going fresh also water all of
your veg plants feed your veg plants
with a strong nutrient solution on
Monday if they're little babies maybe
just some a and B they're getting a
little bigger maybe throw a little
liquid karma in there if they're getting
even bigger maybe they want some
potassium silicates and maybe some
cal-mag in there you should definitely
be feeding your veg plants a little bit
of ruin oculi also get those roots going
so also feed your flowering plants a
well-planned feed each week if it's time
to flush you need to start flushing and
that's another good reason to take notes
then you know when to flush if you guys
need help planning your feeding I did an
episode all about feeding your flowering
plants so episode number 69 will give
you a weekly planning a weekly schedule
of what to feed your plants while
they're in flowers if you want to check
that out that may be useful for you so
every week feed your plants a well feed
a well-planned feed the next thing I
would do every week is dust all of the
fans you guys those fans get dirty
I just dust the backs of them off if you
want to take off the screen and clean
the blades every week that would be
super cool of you your room would
appreciate it all of that dust is going
to end up in your dabs if you don't
clean the fan think of it that way the
next thing I would do
check the timers for proper time and
function be there when the lights come
on a couple of times a week I know you
can't be there all the time when the
lights come on but if you can try to be
there if the lights come on at nine
o'clock just be standing outside of the
room like 857 so that when the lights
click on you can hear it go click and
then you can open the door they can make
sure the timer is working and then be
there again when the lights go off so
just check the timers for proper time
and proper function every week I would
calibrate your meters if you've got a pH
meter you should have one of those
calibrate it get the 4 the 7 and the 10
solution and just calibrate that thing
once a week if you're a small time
grower and you have a hydro short hydro
store near you that you frequent
they will probably calibrate your pH
meter for you they'll be nice and do
that as a courtesy so calibrate your pH
meter you should also have a ppm meter
calibrate that as frequently as you can
at least once a week that can make a
huge difference in the quality of your
flowers if you're measuring something
and your meter is telling you that it's
at seven but it's actually at five and
you're adjusting to get to six five
you're actually gonna be adjusting down
into the fours and you're really gonna
cause problems so calibrate your meters
you guys the next thing I would do at
least once a week is check all your
blowers and fans and make sure that
they're not clogged or restricted in any
way most of the time this you can be
done visually you can look around the
room and see that everything is working
maybe put your hand if you've got a big
vortex blower just put your hand on the
outside of the vortex blower and feel it
vibrate listen to it you'll know if some
shits wrong but just pay attention to
that stuff if it's clogged up that could
be a fire hazard if it's clogged up that
is going to cost you electricity because
that fan is spinning and you're not
getting blowing out of it but you're
using electricity because it's spinning
and trying to break free from that hair
clog or whatever you've got in there
those leaves that are clogged in there
so just check those out guys before you
go sticking your fingers and any blowers
unplug them and give them a long time to
quit spinning they spin for a long time
and just the natural force of those fans
spinning on their own weight that's
enough to put a nice cut on your finger
so watch your [ __ ] fingers those
blowers I've cut myself on a blower
before it sucks more than you would ever
know take it from me there's blood sweat
and tears in my garden and that's where
the blood came from so the next thing
you guys visually check the ductwork
and make sure that everything is sealed
up we're blowing a lot of pressure
through these ducts or the ducting
connects to the lights where the ducting
connects to the blower where the ducting
runs out of whatever room you're using
just make sure that all that stuff is
sealed also clean your air stones if
you're making any kind of tees or
running any hydro or if you've got
cloners with air stones or if you've
just got water sitting there to get
bubbled to get the chlorine out clean
the air stones you guys those things get
murky sometimes you might just want to
throw them away and replace them they
are not that expensive if you've got a
few bucks just go buy new ones
the next thing clean your dehumidifier
or a humidifier filter in Colorado we
probably don't even have a dehumidifier
in most rooms we use a humidifier in
some places but clean the
filters they get funky that she gets
dirty anything that has water running
through it frequently needs to be
cleaned it'll get gross just clean your
[ __ ] if you're running hydro clean out
your reservoir every week to ten days
and start with fresh water and fresh
nutrients well like I keep saying water
that sits around that gets old gets
gross shit's able to grow in there
things can call an eyes in there you
don't want that you want fresh stuff if
you're running easy cloners do the same
flush out those easy cloners I talked
about that a minute ago just dump it out
fill it with fresh water fresh nutrients
pH it and get it going all over again
your plants will love you for it you
don't want to drink old funky water do
you like you don't even leave your dog's
bowl sit there for too long without
putting fresh water in it don't do that
to your plants all of your plants
they're family too so something you're
gonna need to think about weekly you
need you need to dispose of your grow
room trash carefully when the trash man
comes you're gonna I would wait until
the morning and take the trash out till
you when you know he's coming don't
leave that trash sitting out there on
the curb overnight if it's out there on
the curb your trash is accessible to the
public and it is legal for police
officers neighborhood kids hungry
homeless people curious neighbors
whoever private investigators anybody
can walk up to your trash and look
through your [ __ ] and they can take it
if they want those guys stole my trash
yeah they can do that but your trash is
fair game if it's out there on the curb
and if you've got a whole bunch of
leaves in there and you live in a state
that is not legal to produce cannabis
you could have a crime that could be
evidence to the crime right there so be
careful dispose of your grow room trash
very carefully if you're doing a large
grow take it to the dump yourself the
guys at the dump don't give a [ __ ] just
take it to the dump have it in big trash
bags just go drop it off they don't care
that you're dropping off weed leaves
those guys have their own business going
on so uh dispose of your grow room trash
carefully another thing I would
recommend doing weekly look around the
grow room look on the walls and the
ceiling and the floors and look for any
mold or moisture if you've got
condensation happening somewhere figure
out why that's happening correct it if
you've got any mold I've seen blue mold
form on the walls and grow rooms I've
seen little green mold form on the walls
grow rooms clean that [ __ ] up get rid of
it use h2o to use bleach use peroxide
use something strong if you want to go
organic do that do your thing but clean
that [ __ ] up that is unhealthy for you
it's unhealthy for the plants figure out
why it's happening and resolve the issue
to make it not happen once you've
cleaned it you've got to figure out what
caused it and stop it from happening or
it'll just come back mold is a [ __ ] you
can clean mold I saw somebody clean mold
off of a wall they had a spot this is
about the size of a quarter maybe a
50-cent piece and she scrubbed the mold
with bleach and hot water and she called
me the next day and she's like come over
here I want you to see this and I walked
into that mold and formed into like a
four by four square it just grew that
much in like 24 hours it was so
ridiculous so if you've got mold figure
out what's causing it clean the [ __ ] out
of it you may need to call a
professional eventually don't ruin a
rental home growing weed I apologize for
clearing the throat so much in this
episode but I've got a whole bunch of
good dabs from the Terp station so shout
out to chirp ex you can blame all the
throat clearing on Jordan that sounded
grosser than it was meant to but there
we go so that's everything that you
should do in my opinion stuff that you
should do weekly I'm gonna move on to
things that you should do monthly if
you're running hydro or if you have a
feed system I recommend that you clean
the lines out some way who recommended
it to me I remember who said it Shane it
was our friend Shane Shane recommended
that you use an air compressor to clean
out the lines of your hydro system to
blow out any clogs so if you've got a
feed system he's got a hydro system
clean that [ __ ] out if you've got little
sprinklers clean those out if you've got
drippers clean those out just you might
have to hand poke them you might have to
get something pokey and just hand poke
each little hole out by hand but you
need them clean so clean the [ __ ] out of
those monthly clean your air conditioner
filters that's something that needs to
be done monthly also test your smoke
detectors you should have smoke
detectors in your grow rooms yes you
don't want that [ __ ] burning down if it
catches on fire you want a heads up so
test your smoke detectors replace the
battery if necessary that should be
obvious there's nothing like a beep beep
all the time when you're growing and
batteries trying to die it's the worst
sound ever I don't know how anyone can
live with that another thing you should
do every month
the glass in your reflectors you guys
this may need to be done more or less
often depending on your style if you're
spraying in there if you're using a
foliar spray that shoots gonna probably
end up a little bit on the reflectors
unless you're careful if you're spraying
bug sprays it's gonna end up on the
light reflectors clean that glass just
clean it out if you can slide the glass
out clean the inside sometimes your
carbon filter blows a little bit of
carbon in there just clean that stuff up
you're paying for the light to shine
it's taking electricity the light is
shining don't put a dirty lens between
the light and the plants that you're
trying to put the light on it just makes
more sense to clean it you're paying
full price no matter what you do so
clean that [ __ ]
and speaking of paying full price the
next step these may sound like no
brainers but pay your electricity and
water bills every month you guys you
should be okay running a whole bunch of
electricity and use it a whole bunch of
water but the first time you miss a bill
they're gonna come [ __ ] with you they're
gonna knock on your door they're gonna
want their money and that's when [ __ ]
can go wrong so pay your bills don't
ever try to ditch out on a grow bill
don't ever steal electricity you don't
ever steal water just pay your bills it
should be a no-brainer most of the
people who listen to this show should
already be doing that but don't ever
steal if you do get caught stealing
electricity or water if the government I
think here I was told that they're able
to charge you threefold for what you use
so if you use a hundred dollars in
electricity and you get caught stealing
it they can charge you 300 dollars just
because you stole it so pay up front
don't be a dick it's well worth it all
right that's my stuff you should do
monthly I'm gonna move in two things
that you should do every harvest every
harvest you're going to need to dispose
of your sticks and leaves that you have
left over there's gonna be a bunch of
sticks and a bunch of leaves and a bunch
of trim not the small trim you want to
make a shout of that but like a bunch of
trim crap that you don't want laying
around you need to get rid of that like
I said don't go throw-in that in the
trash and just leaving it out there you
might want to wait for the trash guy to
come you might want to find a friend who
has a construction site and get
permission to throw your trash in there
don't go using someone's dumpster
because if you get caught doing that
bill that's a fine for throwing your
trash into somebody else's [ __ ] and then
they'll want to see what you threw in
there and then this cops looking at you
and your big-ass bag of weed leaves and
then you're trying to figure out a story
so figure out a clever way a safe way a
smart way to get rid of all your
sticks and leaves also dispose of or
compost or recycle all of your soil
carefully you don't want to be in the
backyard dumping out your old pots and
then your backyard ends up full of
perlite and it's all white and speckly
and the dirt doesn't look right you
can't be that guy so you have to figure
out a way to either dispose of or
recycle all of that soil that you use
recycling soil isn't as hard as you
would imagine it just needs to be
remanded and kind of stirred around and
then you can definitely use that soil
again so I figured out a way to do that
I've done a little bit of talking about
that on the show I'm still experimenting
with it myself so once I get good at it
I'll do a full episode on recycling soil
I made a little note about that so we're
gonna have to learn how to get rid of a
bunch of dirt you're gonna have sticks
and stuff get rid of that you're also if
you're running hydro you're gonna have
rock wool cubes or you're gonna have
those hydroton clay pellets I hate those
things
you're gonna have to get rid of that
[ __ ] too somehow I'm pretty sure you can
recycle the rock wool cubes the hydrogen
pellets you can rinse them off and use a
beginning and clean them but eventually
you got to throw those away because they
get funky so don't just go throw don't
go throwing those into your trash make
sure you get rid of those safely and
smartly smartly a word I think so
it is now also clean your pots you guys
every harvest you should clean your pots
you should also clean your hydro trays
if you've got a four by four botanic
care tray or one of those four by eight
trays you should clean those things
you're gonna think I'm crazy but here's
how I recommend you do it I throw it in
the truck and just take them right to
the car wash and just line the pots up
against the wall and just spray the [ __ ]
out of them it's Colorado here everybody
knows what you're doing just go spray
your [ __ ] down nobody cares the hydro
trays lean it up against the side of the
truck spray the [ __ ] out of it throw up
the back of the truck take it home if
you're in another state that may be kind
of weird but if cannabis is legal just
take them to the car wash and hose them
down don't use any soap don't use the
car washing soap don't wax them just use
hot water on them with the high-pressure
thing just spray the [ __ ] out of them it
works really well so once you got your
pots cleaned I recommend you clean the
room thoroughly from top to bottom I
said earlier use h2o to use bleach use
hydrogen peroxide there are a thousand
other products I could say to use but
use something to get in there and
sanitize the room don't just clean it up
sanitize it
our good friend Mike helps me out when
it's time to clean the room Mike and I
dress up in our little let's get clean
suits it's basically just our shittiest
clothes we have put bandanas on our
faces put our hair and crazy hats go
down in there and just clean everything
and by the time we're done you can eat
off the floor of my grow rooms when
they're freshly started it is so
gorgeous in there since I'm talking
about Mike gonna give him a shout out we
recorded a podcast last night and the
recording sounded like [ __ ] something
went wrong in the recording software and
everything sounded like robots sound
like r2d2 and Darth Vader and b8 having
conversations so I just deleted that I
apologize to Mike for that podcast never
making it to the air but you know he'll
be back Mike you'll be back bro I'm
sorry that did not work but anyway so
thanks for coming and let's get back
into the show sanitize your room every
harvest that's what I was saying I also
clean the floors and the walls in the
ceiling you guys wipe them down scrub
them down the ceiling gets funky you're
in there it's humid you're in there
spraying pesticides are in there Spring
foliar sprays so that puts moisture
everywhere then it gets humid water
rises the ceiling is gonna get funkier
then you're gonna assume so just scrub
it you'll think it's clean you'll hit it
with the rag and you realize it is not
clean the walls
obviously same thing with the foliar
spray same thing with the humidity and
the floors everything lands on the floor
you spilled nutrients there even walk in
there it's just filthy clean that [ __ ]
also inspect any seals you've made if
you've sealed up any windows or doors or
anything like that if you've put
caulking somewhere recaulk it if you've
taped it retaping
also if you've put up I put up hepa
filters so if I've got a wall between
two rooms and I'm pulling air from one
room to the other I just go to Lowe's
and buy those little square HEPA filters
and I just cut them kind of close to the
shape I want just staple them to the
wall I replace those every time every
harvest also I try to because they get
dusty they get dirty but they keep all
the funk out of the room so just go
ahead and replace those that's always a
good idea just those little square HEPA
filters you can find them at Lowe's if
you can't find those just use lucky any
kind of filter will work for is just
better than having the hole where the
air is moving open you just want to put
a filter over there to catch
Derr ernie bugs or anything they may be
trying to move around try to migrate
from place to place alright
so yearly here are a couple of things
that i think you should do every single
year as a grower oh I forgot to mention
every harvest um that little sleeve that
goes around your carbon filter take that
off and clean it and put it back on and
good luck not getting carbon everywhere
the next time you turn on your carbon
filter there are tons of tricks on that
here's what I'm talking about when you
use a carbon filter every time you move
it you jar the carbon inside and then
you put a blower on there if you plug in
the blower to start blowing the air
through the filter just to use it and
then all that carbon you've just stirred
goes flying through all of your lights
and into your grow room you've got to
get you got to figure out a smart way to
catch that carbon what I do is I blow it
into a I've got a it's a what is it I
know what it is I can't think of the
brand it's a Crown Royal bag because the
Crown Royal bag will let the air out but
it'll catch all of the particulate
that's coming through so I just put the
ducting into a Crown Royal bag and hold
it and plug it into there for a couple
seconds then I just pull that off and
seal it up and I've caught all the
carbon in there so that's a trick a
really weird random trick to keep all
the carbon from blowing out that little
cover off you guys it comes with the
sleeve take that off clean it it looks
like [ __ ] when it's all dusty anyway you
want that white and clean clean it up
put some OxiClean in the water get that
sucker white again
so yearly here's where we are yearly
replace your carbon filter the guide the
hydro shop swears to me that my carbon
filters are gonna last two years they do
not there was a guy replacing I what's
it called a transformer in my backyard a
couple of weeks ago and he told me sir
smells like you got a skunk back here
there were no smokes back there that was
a little bit of grateful dog crossed a
space Queen and it was stinking up the
whole neighborhood because my carbon
filter needed to be replaced I've got a
new one sitting there now as soon as I
rebuild the room I'll have a fresh
filter the neighbours will quit smelling
the candy scented skunks so replace your
carbon filter they only last about a
year another thing that you should do
every year you guys have your fire
extinguisher checked and replaced or
charged they've got a little red yellow
and green gauge on them you want it all
the way in the green if it starts to get
too yellow it's not reliable anymore you
need a new fire extinguisher in either
either need to go get it charged or just
buy a new one they sell them at Lowe's
they sell them at Home Depot they're not
expensive there hopefully you never need
it I really hope you never need it but
if you do you want it fully charged I
always have a fire extinguisher near
your Dro I've got one I've got a veg
room I've got a flowering room there's a
fire extinguisher hanging on the outside
of my flowering room have it on the
outside if something goes if you hear
that smoke alarm and they're going off
grab the fire extinguisher check the
door for heat if it's stupid hot you
have a decision to make do you want to
open that door or not open that door hit
that [ __ ] with the fire extinguisher
that you've already got in your hand you
don't wanna open the door to run in
there and find the fire extinguisher in
the smoky hot fiery room so have it on
the outside but I really I prayed a job
that you never have to use your fire
extinguisher but I'd rather you have it
and it work and I'd rather you be safe
then this thing fail on you so I've got
another fire fire extinguisher right
just outside the bedroom also just
that's where [ __ ] can go wrong there are
a lot of why it's a lot of electricity
just want to be a responsible grower try
to be responsible so get your fire
extinguisher inspected and replaced once
a year and I think that's all I've got
for the checklist you guys I really want
to thank all my friends on Facebook I
posted to Facebook asking for some
updates and a lot of people contributed
so many of you that I'm not even gonna
try to list everybody so shout out to my
facebook community that helped out I
truly appreciate that there's some
things I did leave out I understand that
things got left out here you'll need to
work on a pest management system you'll
need to integrate that into this
checklist somehow if you don't see any
issues you can simply spray once a week
with an organic application whatever you
want to use I use as a max if there's no
problems I just use like since I travel
from so many gardens I hit my plants
once a week with that as a max when
they're in veg just to make sure that I
don't bring anything home from all the
other gardens I play in if you see any
issues in your garden you may need to
increase the frequency and the potency
of whatever you're spraying maybe change
the active ingredient to of something a
little bit stronger hopefully you don't
get any pests if you're doing something
preventative but that's something you'll
have to work into this regimen here as
well there's also gonna be a point in
time or you're going to need to change
your lightbulbs we did another episode
on that every bulb is different every
garden is different we talked about swap
your thousand watt HPS bulbs about every
one to three harvests I've heard people
using them for a full year I've heard
people using them for a while it's like
I said earlier when your bulbs start
diminishing your eyes won't notice it
but your plants will and you're still
paying for all of the electricity if
you've got a thousand watt bulb and it's
like six months old it's probably only
putting out 60 to 70 percent of its
output but you're paying for one hundred
percent of that thousand wants to be
running so go upgrade your bulbs it
doesn't cost that much money if you
think about how how much herb you're
gonna grow from a fresh bulb the
difference the cost of that bulb should
definitely be worth it so that's what
I've got for you on a checklist of
things that you should be doing in your
garden don't be shy to send me things
that I missed if there's something you
want to add to this if there's something
I did wrong let me know I want to hear
from you no matter what you've got to
say send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you can find me on twitter it's at G fyh
podcast you can hit me up on Facebook
it's simply grow from your heart podcast
if you know my personal Facebook you can
find me there if you know me you can
text me you can call me tell me whatever
you want to tell me about the podcast
but I'd love to hear what you think of
this garden checklist if there's
something I missed let me know we'll do
a part to make sure you guys check out
the next podcast
it will feature kabuki Jay Fox and it'll
be recorded live from the Canon Canyon
so big shout out to kabuki J Fox of Fox
tracks and the canna Canyon in Colorado
Springs don't forget to check out our
sponsor you guys hit man glass big shout
out to hit man glass I've got a brand
new hit man short stack I really can't
do this justice if I destroy if I tried
to describe it with words on a
microphone it's five disc perks stacked
on top of each other and they are welded
together with what's called a Jesus seal
there are three Jesus seals holding each
perk together the discs are actually
donuts and there is a tube that goes
down the middle and it's got a hammer
head so there's a down stem that goes
into the rig it's got a hammer head perk
when you smoke through it the water goes
up through each disc and then it goes to
the top disc where there is a drain that
goes down back to the bottom through the
center I know I just confuse the [ __ ]
out of your head but
post a picture of this day Instagram so
that you can check it out a huge huge
shout out to my friends a hit man glass
make sure you follow them on Instagram I
let them know that you heard about them
from the girl from your heart podcast we
would all appreciate that you guys know
that show's over I would appreciate it
if you go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the review section give me a five star
rating and after that type in a comment
and let me know what you think of the
show and I will read your comments on a
future episode I know I haven't done
that in a while trying to save up a
couple and once we've got enough there
I'll go and read three or four or four
or five comments and we'll share that
with you so I'd appreciate if you go and
do that what that does is that exposes
the show to more people it'll move us up
in the rankings more people will see the
podcast more people will listen more
people will grow better cannabis and
that's the main goal here is just get
more people to grow better cannabis yeah
you guys don't forget the show is
available on iTunes stitcher and every
single episode is always in forever
archived on I read genetics Colorado
calm don't forget about the donation
button on the website you guys on the
top right if you go I read genetics
Colorado calm click on the girl from
your heart podcasts tab at the top right
there is a donation button that goes
directly to my PayPal account I've said
it before I'm never gonna charge you for
this podcast this podcast is always
going to be free but if you'd like to
make a contribution I would truly
appreciate it if you're curious where
your contribution goes it goes to paying
for the hosting of my website it goes
through things like new microphone
covers I try to have microphone covers
for the guests because they do this kind
of stuff the microphones when they're
talking because they're new so I try to
have a cover for each guest if they
don't have to go rub in their face on
another person's mic cover I just think
so that's gross water bottles for all of
the guests but mostly it goes to
covering the Bluehost website which is
where I host or the Bluehost hosting fee
which is where I have my website which
is where I host this show there's a
hundred and thirteen episodes up there
so it does take a little bit of
bandwidth anyway I'm just letting you
know where that goes I'm not begging if
you'd like to contribute I would
definitely definitely appreciate it and
give you a big shout out on the show
send you a couple of stickers let's see
what else do I have for you make sure
you listen next week you guys will have
foxtrax on I think that's all I've got
please follow me on instagram Irie
underscore genetics on Instagram I don't
give you a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening and
until next time take a phat dad
and give your mama
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 114 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right up here a new
grower if you're professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a veteran Davor
if your cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to say the
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show big shout out
to cat kun the entire mystical roots
crew
I also want to send a huge shot that's
my friends at hitman glass this podcast
is brought to you by our friends at
hitman glass hitman glass made in
America by Americans you guys know what
I like to say when I'm shopping for
glass I like to buy something that I
know is gonna give me a big fat rip and
it's not gonna put water in my mouth
when I try to hit it I like to buy a
hitman glass you guys support a hitman
glass visit hitman glass com make sure
you follow my friend dougie on instagram
at hitman glass make sure you send him a
little message let him know you learned
about hitman glass from the grow from
your heart a podcast he would appreciate
that and so would I so big shout out to
hitman glass today I'm sitting here
dabbing off of my semi new it's fairly
new to me be a short stack from hitman
glass this thing hits like a champ I got
the short stack here it's the little one
with the 14 millimeter joint on it I've
got a highly-educated duality nail on
there we have been pulling dabs of lemon
G from turf X and it has been a
wonderful day so big shout out to hitman
glass I appreciate the support make sure
you guys check them out so this episode
is a wonderful episode guys
this episode features my friend kabuki
Jay Fox
he has a company known as Fox Trax he's
known for the hashtag run CBD we're
going to talk a whole lot about CBD so I
think you guys should get out a notebook
because you might learn some [ __ ] and
I'm gonna let the music play for a
couple of seconds oh you know what
before I get that far I want to give a
huge shout out to my friends at the
canna Canyon this podcast was recorded
live at the canna Canyon the canyon
canyon is a private social club if
you've got an ID this is your 21 and
over and you've got a few bucks you can
drop on into the Canon Canyon sign up
side a member agreement and you can hang
out take some dabs with us you can smoke
some flowers with us it's a really chill
environment the place is classy as [ __ ]
I will have the business on the podcast
here real soon in the meantime check it
out you guys it's at 1507 West Colorado
Avenue in beautiful Colorado Springs
Colorado there's a sign out front that
says the can of Canyon I will be easy
for you to find go check it out
I'm gonna fade out the music for a
couple of seconds and I will be right
back with our friend kabuki Jay Fox
all right welcome back ladies an
gentlemen we are here at the Cannon
Canyon in Colorado Springs we find the
address we are at 1507 West Colorado
Avenue in Colorado Springs we are at a
really cool place you guys this is a
place where adults 21 and over if you've
got an idea in a few bucks at the door
you can come in and you can hang out and
you can take dabs there are people from
Colorado here that are kind of heads in
the scene somea Colorado's finest is
here Colorado Springs is finest is here
and actually we've got people here from
Texas hanging out taking dad's being
beautiful there are ladies here there
are dudes here there are more ladies
than men here yeah it is pretty rare for
a cannabis club so big shout out to the
hey take care of yourself leaving the
club right now is my good buddy Jason
Margulis have a great day buddy
be safe on the road he's out of here so
sitting to my right I'm gonna introduce
the man the myth the legend mr. kabuki J
Fox how you doing brother I'm great I'm
excited to have you here I'm excited to
be at a club in Springs where we could
just take some dabs we're gonna be doing
shows from here a why I feel like does
this place has a great vibe shout out to
Camille for inviting me here after the
whole like a VIP when I show up I
haven't turned a doorknob here every
time I show up somebody opens a door for
me it's a great place big shout out to
the club so uh our friend Fox here I
know you mostly as Fox I'll probably
clean Fox's most of the show that's you
are who I refer to as my CBD expert if
I've got a CBD question I usually call
you up so Wow I guess what I should
start with is can you tell my listeners
a little bit about what CBD is okay
CBD just like THC is a compound
in cannabis that is non psychoactive so
let's say tea is a psychoactive compound
which obviously gives us a great feeling
CBD is a non-psychoactive cannabinoid
that has different qualities that THC
doesn't have okay and I mean it's it's
one of 138 found in cannabis and it's
like you know we're 138 cannabinoids 130
Wow I only know of maybe 12 or 13 so THC
is the one that we all love it gets us
high it displays you said there is no
psychoactive effects to CBD no there's
more for effect right you know in high
doses you can get kind of like an
elevated euphoria but it's nothing like
a psychoactive effect where you feel
high CBD being in Colorado we're blessed
to have absolutely available I'm not I
don't smoke a lot of CBD myself it
doesn't do anything for me I am a
medical marijuana patient but I don't
need the CBD so I try to save it for the
patient's trip we did talk about it on
in one episode we'll talk a little bit
later about the effect that had on
myself but I want to hear more about so
why are we going for the CBD it what
does it really do for you why are you so
enthusiastic about CBD if it's not
psychoactive okay we've got plenty of
time okay so in the long terms of it
when I was young you know I lost a child
that's that's why I'm here and that's
why raise awareness
I lost my second child epilepsy I was
very young what happened
I had no idea about epilepsy at the time
literally it took me by storm there was
a good seven-year period where I had one
two very confused place it puts strain
on every relationship around me all that
I continued to focus on at the time was
cannabis and I had no idea that it would
bring me round circle to something that
I dealt with and not really knew about
what had gone on until I met a parent
going through something similar with
their nonverbal autistic child who was a
cannabis patient in their state they
started telling me all about the wonders
of how CBD is working for them but they
have problems getting at problems
obtaining at the CBD that they were
getting was tainted and making their
child sick had random [ __ ] in it
absolutely we didn't know much let's say
this is two years ago that I you know
contacted other parents oh we didn't
know what we know now and what is
available now it definitely wasn't them
yeah I've seen you come a long way I've
seen you uh the hash that you brought
today is amazing how much of that did
you make oh absolutely
actually the rest of them are from
companies that I love to support craft
concentrate as well as viola live resin
and some wonderful full mouth
extractions from natural mystic
caregivers blueberry cherry CBD you know
I like to mix it up man you know usually
if I run something it's out of my garden
and its first donated to the patient so
it's very limited on the you know right
that's drops that I have should be so I
rather just you know I luckily in a
great place where a lot of our friends
there in the community in the industry
and they're killing it at what they do
so I'm happy to support any
I like the way you do things I've been
watching you on uh we should let people
know how they can follow you on social
media how can they find you on Instagram
and Facebook on Facebook EJ Fox and on
Instagram I am at Fox tracks fo x TR ace
TCS go check him out while we're talking
you guys go make sure you stalk him a
little bit excuse me I'm confident the
microphone he gave me a big ol fat to
have some solve unless a few minutes ago
and I'm still us a little bit from it
that's a bear Mountain glass for the
gorgeous what colors exactly studios
custom one of one raindrop and purple
lollipop climbed up it's a Klein but
it's kind of a climb so he calls the
decline does so that's what I've kind of
been it's gorgeous thank you so much I
get a lot of compliments Ortiz almost an
egg sort of a feel to it as well with
the way that it's hollow there he
absolutely almost like a hollow honey
jar of sorts if you guys follow me on
Instagram it's Irene underscore genetics
I will post a picture that I took a nice
picture of you guys
and I'm sure you can find it on Fox's
Instagram we'll take it we'll take a pic
of that and take a pics of pic of us
together so man that's why you've got
the passion now I understand what put
passion into you that's why you came out
of nowhere and you're winning also
congrats on the cannabis cup thank you
so much it's funny that Jason who is
actually here it was my material that I
grew he ran it we ran it together on a
you know wonderful unit that he had I
think so and then okay Caleb over there
got the oil and cranked it out into the
award-winning chocolate bar that it was
funny that you had all those people in
the room I'm kind of in a room full of
rock star good work you guys definitely
you can there are a few left on the
shelf down there at
the candy Canyon come by they'll tell
you how you can get ahold of those
definitely try the peanut butter is very
yummy my favorite was the banana what
was that a banana something you gave me
yes yeah that was the the entry okay
the banana cream that was so delicious
walked around just whoa for the rest of
the day it put a little slowness on my
day you know the oil that we used for it
it came back testing out at 71.3% CBD
okay ten point nine five percent THC so
really strong seven to one so when we
cranked out and did the math that he
dosed it out it came out to like 160
milligrams to that bar and I mean it was
almost the perfect ratio for just
literally having the calmest day we come
we gave some in donating stem to some
autistic patients that were having some
rage issues pediatric nonverbal so
obviously you know it's hard to gate
stuff like that and the results that we
were getting back from the parents were
almost immediate saying just from a few
chips of this chocolate bar they were
getting calming soothing effects so that
was really helping with those oh I can
see there's no way that I could be
rageful or angry after eating that thing
walking around day 2 of the cannabis cup
just in mellow bubble around beautiful
alright so you said really help the
autistic children with their rage what
other things to CBD help with CBD is a
new your protectant anti cancer so let
me pause for a second when I say anti
cancer we all know that THC kills cancer
cells CBD freezes the cancer cell in its
tracks so it can't progress or grow any
further but it will not kill it no anti
cancer is freezing it at bay its best it
basically causes cell death in the
mutated cells and so that the tumors
can't grow anymore but they're okay if
you use a conjunction of a high CBD high
THC regimen with cancer you're bound to
basically stop kick freeze and kill
those mutated cells and
you know get back to a healthier you
know way of living yes so CBDs in your
protection so obviously it's very
popular with epilepsy and other
neurological diseases Asperger's autism
children on the spectrum
Crohn's PTSD anxiety it kind of goes on
there's almost anything that an adult
would be suffering from pretty much I
don't even take any form of aspirin or
any I mean I have completely separated
all that with different regimens of CBD
and THC in just a healthy cannabis
regimen you know okay endocannabinoid
system is very important and we all as
medical patients have our own
deficiencies in those systems CBD is one
of those all around protectants it's the
vault it's the multivitamin of the
cannabis you know world I like that you
make a sticker out of that yeah Centrum
sticker it does so much and in different
variations and ratios that can help so
many different things I mean Parkinson's
cerebral palsy nerve damage it goes it
goes on and on I mean it literally the
in CBD itself there's other spectrum of
cannabinoids CBN CVG CBC you know that
all have different medical attributes
that aren't psychoactive kitchen high
kind of things these are one of these is
an anti-inflammatory one of these is a
antibacterial one of these is a bone
regeneration you know I make a CBG cream
for a couple of patients that have this
rare disease called Keene box disease
which is where
is basically dying and I came up with
the salve that literally supplies
immediate relief for people that have
had the surgery we have that pain I'm
trying to make that more readily
available that's amazing that's amazing
that should definitely sway some of the
people I encourage people that don't
know a lot about cannabis to listen to
my show so that should sway them to
believe a little bit more in medical
marijuana and the uses as practical uses
and then we're not just in this just to
get as high as we possibly a lot of us
are and get rekt but part of my regimen
all the time I don't just advocate in
you know see what we do with the
genetics and you know the breeding and
just everything in general I needed you
know I literally I know I'm happier with
productive person I don't have going
through some of the things that you know
I've gone through at a young age you
know that kind of you know it weighs on
you a little bit you know and so it it
gets hard sometimes literally as soon as
I started enriching my cannabis diet
with CBD I've noticed a wide spectrum of
problems that I was having day to day
really kind of just have more control
over I don't really I don't let it get
to me anymore and I just find myself
being incredibly more productive when
you have it in my system the same way
about THC and I'm glad that we can sit
here and Wonder for THC one of my
friends team Landon
[Music]
but yeah he cured his leukemia with THC
strong cannabis though he started with
the realm of caring which is obviously
known for Charlotte's Web and the yeah
but the CBD oil which he actually wasn't
even using for the most part I mean they
used it as a supplement because they
noticed it was stopping what the chemo
is doing but they made it very they were
very adamant that TV is what killed and
stopped his leukemia and you know it's
been I think over six months since he's
had a clean you know bill very nice yeah
absolutely no or stay chemo anymore
state for scheme oh I'm sorry no more
all the tests have come back completely
negative you know there's no signs he
still maintains a healthy regimen Ciera
maintains as his caregiver and we
oversee you know all that and I've seen
what both sides of it does so at the end
of the day though we advocate for are
different compounds are different
cannabinoids whole plant cannabis is
what I think the full spectrum the
synergistic effect play this episode for
me guys put them put them up by the the
iPhone I let him hear this Judy yeah did
Colorado Springs is Sony we were talking
a minute ago about how the medical
community here has united because we
don't have recreational so we don't have
that there's not as greedy of a vibe in
cannabis it's beautiful it's all
peaceful no one's got a problem we got
people up there whipping up dabs for
them they're pressing a frozen just
hanging out it's so peaceful it's great
I love it hey guys come on down to the
candy cane and get a dad with us one of
these nights you told me we talked a
little bit before we hit record you guys
got comfortable took a bunch of dabs
together but you're telling me that you
made extracts before you even grew yes
just being a process process I hate
saying I mean I values what you're doing
but
understand the term where we were
whatever the case was it started one way
and it started becoming clear that we
couldn't control you can only control so
much of what you make things it's all in
your starting material absolutely and I
wanted to start controlling the type of
medicine that I was making instead of
just processing other people's material
I mean because it's hit or miss you have
some people that put their love and
their everything into their material and
it shows when you end up pulling it out
and sometimes out the case flora my and
everything else exactly what you mean
that's the most wonderfully nice yeah so
you know certain processing the oil
found out that I kind of really love
doing it got back to you know my roots
and chemistry and just little things
like that and then and seeing what
people are doing with distillation even
a few years ago and then things like
that yeah and seeing how we're coming
along I mean we're still a budding baby
industry in the can of chemistry world
oh yeah I agree with that yeah it's
amazing to see what we're doing now with
technology that's been around for a long
time and now we have these wonderful new
ways and freedoms to apply these new
applications so it's great to see what
these guys are doing and people are
coming out with new extraction
techniques whether it's in the solvent
list world or whether we're using you
know solvents or whatever the case is
and it's exciting to see what are some
of the things you make I've seen you
make a bunch of different types of Seco
products through the list of what you
can do so we made suppositories for some
patients we've made dogs CBD biscuits
we've also one-to-one treats for the
cancer you know some older you know some
rural canine friends have you know fatty
tumors or whatnot at all absolutely you
know so we do what we can and start
coming up with solutions solutions to
try to help those patients
you know I have a few myself so from
there
bombs different ratios of capsules for a
wide variety of ailments from you know
everyday
cannabis regimens you know for a normal
medical patient to an extended hospice
patient where what we do at that point
is make them as comfortable as we can
and we're you know these patients are in
the excess of taking anywhere from a
thousand to three thousand milligrams of
cannabis a day to comfortable you know
because that's what you can do so and
you're able to produce then reliably
perhaps we do we make per patient it's
specifically per so there's nothing -
the sad that I've talked about the CBG
salve and then any collaborations that
we've done with friends like Caleb or
anything like that are things that are
even close to being mass-produced
everything is small batch everything is
individually made per patient we've done
saline and cannabis saline infusions as
well as for those children that have to
feed through tea tubes oh wow
we've done thinking of everything yeah
we've done some medicated lubricants as
well we've done those work yeah
absolutely
shoot obviously different concentrates
water extracted butane extracted what's
the white CBD stuff I've seen my friends
seemly I didn't have a company called
land in South Hutt and they work with
the lab here in the states that produces
this hemp derived 99.5 seven percent I
CBD isolate Wow and at first she started
telling me about it and I was very
skeptical and I wanted more information
and then we got in touch with the lab
and I found out that they were using you
know American sourced hampt and they you
know they kind of walked us through the
process of you know did this lading and
then you know crystallizing
you basically you know it's I know just
made it sound like it's a simplified
process but it kind of is you know it's
just a matter of getting the right
material you're gonna you've got a chem
background so the pond with the rocks of
time but what catches really catches and
throw a lot of trial and error you this
industry is all about
absolutely trial and errors your friend
and I mean that's how I do everything
and I really you know we try to focus
and don't get anything out until it's
right and we in the series of things I
can really only think of one little
thing that we've ever gone through and
you know you're making edibles for
someone I learned my mistakes and
putting flaxseed in there because some
people are very susceptible to that
allergy but other than that like I can't
think of you know what we make has
really helped a lot of people across the
board for all the different ailments we
stay away from alcohol extractions as
far as our so any alcohol infused
textures or anything like that just
because we mostly started with pediatric
epileptic patients then trace amounts of
alcohol could the medications that they
have to take for the most part even
trace amounts of that kid effect and
totally just give them a huge variety of
complications with their medication and
I've seen you know it's also it's very
hard on their digestive systems and so
yeah children that are going through
chemo children that have autism children
that have epilepsy all have compromised
immune systems and compromised digestive
systems in their own way so one of the
problems that I've seen with pediatric
patients using ours so is that they have
problems holding down that medicine so
start going around and promoting you
know different carrier oils different
you know ways of taking this you know
non solvent or solvent extract and
decarboxylate and you know putting it
into a healthier carrier oil for these
children what's an example maybe copper
coil coconut oil and if someone is
diabetic and they want to try
there's always ham seed oil which is the
healthiest I mean it's protein juice
it's it's absolutely wonderful for you
so I always say hemp seed oil first if
not avvocato Isle grape seed oil is
another wonderful example of something
you can use those in coconut oil but you
know a lot of people are very happy with
coconut oil if it works and you know it
works yeah a lot of people are on the
coconut oil cake it seems to be real
popular lately my first question is with
that is if they're Crohn's patient or
diabetic I asked them right away
and you know we just I transparency is
everything you know true knowledge you
know this knowledge is all open source
so the more you can be open with the
patient and explain it to them the more
they leave knowing at the end of the day
the better it is in the long run you
know have you thought about going to
dispensaries and maybe to medical shops
and teaching the bud tenders this sort
of stuff or do you think they I
absolutely think there's a really
important part and people bartenders
specifically getting some form of
education because a lot of them I'll be
very blunt I say this a lot of them look
at it's just a job you know a lot of
them come in looking at the retail job
there's a lot of retail aspects to what
it is because it is a peel a
point-of-sale system but at the end of
the day you're dealing with medical
patients and what you're providing what
you're helping sell is we want to be
taken seriously like a medical industry
like we're trying to take the time with
the medical patient is required I don't
think anyone ever got too mad at a bun
tender for knowing too much like proper
information about their meds
I've been a budtender and I've annoyed a
few people with my weed nerd skills so
people just don't care for what they
want are therefore just what they want
but there's curious patients that come
in and they have genuine like like real
questions about things that they don't
know so it's wonderful to have somebody
there that knows what they're talking
yeah they can just make them feel more
welcome and more often or not you build
wonderful business relationships with
your patients and they feel comfortable
coming back and getting you know their
medicine from people that actually
and care about what there at the
restaurant where the guy remembers me
and remembers oh you like this last time
you just want to go back where you build
a relationship and our treat is like
customer number seven for today you
don't make a Rick Simpson oil type of
Prada I do I literally will infuse I
mean the oils that we make in comparison
are either infused with hemp seed oil
the Tincher percent okay or we crank the
ratios out with raw beginning hemp seed
or grape seed oil or coconut oil and
we'll use that as the carrier and we've
seen I can get the dosage almost down to
similar to what it would be and your
body's gonna love that what are that
black sludge is super hard for about
nauseous and change colors that stuff
raw and I don't understand how they can
do it it's you know so we're just trying
to find better ways of easier ways for
this to get into our system and
healthier ways Rick Simpson was an
innovator for what he did but right now
knowing what we know about NAFTA and the
process and I mean you were we're at a
different place now medically so we know
better and we should provide that to our
page right and I like your integrity on
that we kind of got sidetracked we're
talking about you uh you started making
hash before you started growing so how
did you end up because you weren't
satisfied with the material that was
around right that cookies trip a lot of
the CBD fire that was coming out was
looking like grass clippings or it was
really bad I'm not sure plants are hard
to grow no the CBD heavy plants are not
as easy to grow as some of the more THC
or sativa or indica
as a breeder in the grower I recognize
that heavily I don't like ced dominant
plants so here's the thing as a girl
that started out just girl you CBD
dominant plans the first time I pop some
seeds that would cheesy dumb and I was
like this is really easy you'd had the
curve now and the curves that I had to
deal with for CBD for growing the CBD or
not what I was dealing with it growing
you know some very wonderful TC genetics
that I had been gifted and I was just
like your ratios will be affected
severely if there's any sort of stress
during the vegetative state whatsoever
because that CBD is already there in the
vegetative state before before it's been
flipped or anything you know glad you
said that people often completely
overlooked their veg state people will
build a grub I've watched people build
$10,000 flour rooms and spend six or
eight hundred bucks just fixing up a
shitty old bedroom to make a bed space
like come on let's do that cuz that's
like you said that's where the plants
start stage of life you're going from
seed you obviously want to wax your
tapper you want to make it strong
adolescence before you put them hands
and every time something happened I just
call one of my friends debug looks what
I'm going through please you know and I
want to think I just wanna say this now
and if it's okay if I shot them out
always offer chronic gene my friend
Clancy has been one of the most stand-up
guys that I know I free CBD seeds in my
bookbag from him right now that I'm just
remembering so I'll gladly donate free
CBD seeds to anyone that wants them
right now I hope people in this room
heard though no legit yeah I'll gladly
say it again but yeah
he's been a wonderful wonderful friend
and Josh from the plateau labs a good
dude she had every breeder every person
that I've talked about what I'm trying
to do is CV has been completely open
source with me and helpful and any
little thing that I it's literally
fast-tracked me so much that it's a
blessing you know it's I am completely
grateful for the knowledge that's been
dropped on me because it took me from
trying to provide for my patients and
struggling to knowing things that I just
would have never grasped before you know
like I said it's I'm truly grateful for
it but yeah I started as an extractor it
just took one of my friends getting
screwed over basically for me to say you
know what dude I'll girl for you yeah
there you go yeah became very public
about it and when I first started
growing my problem was people hoard
these or they were hoarding these
strange right so it was like well let's
share them let's you know let's pull cut
and you know give them out and I you can
only help as many people as you can get
this cut out to you which is something
I'll touch into later but my main source
was you know okay well let's make this
happen so my time in Cali people were on
this crazy cookies craze I was going
from noir cow to SoCal and brilliant
Southern California you know hits at all
no progress whatsoever in Northern
California so I fell in love with a
wonderful plant called star tsunami and
I met an amazing group of breeders in
the Emerald triangle that changed my
life
some they were already caregivers for
some of the children in the state going
through cancer these men showed me what
real compassion was at the very starting
point when I was in this industry and
blessed me with some genetics and
knowledge and play me in the right
directions of things for what I wanted
to do or something
Ringo there's a lot of them you know
they know if they hear this they know
they are
they're the kind hearted people who
don't do this for the name they just do
this for the sake of continuing to push
cannabis forward you know for Jacob but
they've got my respect absolutely all
right so these people in NorCal you find
this crew in NorCal and you follow up
with them you find sauer tsunami yep you
start growing nowan yeah started asking
questions started doing runs with the
plants specifically then people started
talking about this plant this you know
because at the time even california
there was such a hype about Colorado and
Charlotte's Web and what it really was
and all these guys in California had no
clue so when you had these strange
popping up like sour tsunami and they're
like oh well it's just like sour tsunami
no and then you had Harlequin popping up
in the upper side down by Oakland and
that was one of the stronger three two
one two two ones they're like no it's
nothing like Charlotte's Web and then
this ac/dc plant started come around you
know and people just started comparing
them because no one knew there's all
these new strains are coming out from
Colorado is that a Colorado strain the
ac/dc no okay all right it started in
Spain from what I believe from where I
understand it started in Spain and
somehow made its way to California and
then from that's just from what I
understand from what I've been told you
know as far as their colorado CBD
strains you know r4 r5 the rule 5
as well before you you know the work
that natural mr. caregivers down here
[Music]
absolutely wonderful natural mystic
Ferreira one of the only shops that
really focuses heavily on CBD absolute
three or four different kinds of
top-shelf flower that are CBD dominant
it's actually one of my favorite places
in the springs to go to foresee buddy
fire because you know I support any
place that will put good CVD products on
leisure and I know the growers there I
know Joey pretty well well so many
questions you were talking about a labs
that getting your stuff tested you have
a lab that you prefer there's a friend
of ours that has an independent lab and
he really does help a lot of people with
low-cost testing and does his part to
help you know Colorado law has made a
little hard for caregivers patients
parents to have their meds tested
because obviously most labs are forced
to deal with people that have MIPS
licenses whatever the case is so there
are those few independent people who
have taken upon themselves with their
own dollar to provide a place where
patients can have their meds tested and
there's actually a place like that down
here in the springs I don't have all the
information so I don't want to worry
that's all right yeah Nate knows who he
is and he's definitely killing it down
here so once I get more information I'll
gladly pass along your way and we can
share it sounds great yeah we'll get it
out yeah he's the one who did the
testing for the cannabis cup actually
that Caleb and I did he's done some
other testing for the oil that I've done
before and and the numbers of OHS come
spot-on to the point where if I go
somewhere else and I feel like my
numbers aren't right I go to Nate
because you know that's I can count on
that
so so the cannabis cup is coming up it's
January you guys really calling out 2016
and it sounds so weird to say that do
anything for the cup this year there are
some few plans for the cup I'm keeping
myself open right now the way that they
split up so cow for the two weekends is
a little confusing so honestly that is
widely kind of backed out of doing
anything so quickly but I had some
things going obviously you know with
whatever happens in Denver we'll have a
showing out and there is something in
California that is calling my attention
that you know a few people reach out you
never know you what collabs you might
see Shawn out to queen bee extracts by
the way oh is the CBD winner for okay
doing great things out there in
California to support the chalice
festival you guys use a sponsor the
podcast looking forward to seeing what
will come to fruition between now and
first yeah yeah five days this year it's
gonna be Saturday Sunday Monday Tuesday
there's one more day it's either the
Friday before or the Wednesday at the
end there because for Denver because
4:20 is on something like that Tuesday
or Wednesday so they're just stretching
it out it'll be great you know that the
emmy has their feelings about how
cannabis events should be and what they
are Colorado they have a huge opposition
to a lot of the way that these events
are run what's your two cents if I can
ask personally on how that goes here for
people like us you know that obviously
have companies and promote within as
well as the people who enjoy these
events wait does what it does for me as
I work for a immediated dispensary so I
can't take my seed company and set up a
booth because I'm affiliated with that
dispensary so closely that I'll be find
my dispensary will be find if I'm there
selling products or giving products out
yeah yeah oh my god what do you get your
meed badge that's part of what you sign
but I feel the dispensaries this is
Colorado we're allowed to smoke everyone
there's 21 and over it's in an enclosed
area we should be able to go and set up
a booth and show our wares just like any
other industry we have beer festivals
where I'm not gonna name any beer brands
but whatever brand a B and C bring their
beer truck they said a beer they serve
it to people all day they show blocks
whole blocks of downtown Denver we're
doing this at a private event area at
the name of the place the Denver Mart
yes there were renting a place we're not
even doing it in the city blocks I think
that dispensary should be able to come
set up a booth and bring smoke and smoke
you and I out and everybody out they
should say this is our flagships train
this is what we grow come check us out
you know being an independent caregiver
on the other side of it I don't
necessarily have to answer to them but
at some point you know we cross paths
and things are mentioned so it's
interesting for people that are running
within that model in Colorado and how
that affects us for trying to actively
promote an events like this you know
without being threatening whatever the
case may be finds in your business
clothes a big enough fine green and
healthy is a small small business just a
few of us and a large enough fund would
end us that would be the end so we have
to be pretty careful on that we're
officially open yeah this will come out
we're open today but this will come out
like two weeks so we'll be full-on
yeah he will he'll be back to give you
guys a review on what he thinks are the
perfect rigs there and some stuff you'd
want to see awesome I took some notes
but I think I've gone through them and I
loved how cool Colorado Springs is we
don't have one of these in Pueblo so
this is kind of there there may be one
but it's real low-key and I haven't gone
there yet it's open yet so I'll go check
it out this is chill I like it it was
just hanging out have a good
conversation taking dabs it's cloudy as
[ __ ] in here just let us come hang out
and do a podcast maybe I can get
Camille's attention to come say hi it's
gonna bugger she's being social she's a
great poster I love it yeah I'll be here
a lot more often
I brought we've been going for like 40
minutes you got anything else that you
want to throw out to the world about CBD
while you're on a microphone you will be
back on the show you know I started this
company because obviously something
happened to me you know somebody that I
couldn't help my goal is to help as many
people as I can
because if you know that feeling of not
being able to help someone but then are
put in a position where you can why not
right you know and so every day I
encourage people to learn something new
about cannabis I encourage people to
take up a cause that's close to them it
doesn't matter what it is no matter what
it is for me it's epilepsy awareness and
I will talk about it and so my face
turns blue and
no more about epilepsy than you did
before we start talking
I wondered a lot today I'm really glad
so that being said like that's my main
focus with everything that I do I feel
like there are a lot of people out there
doing it but if you do need my help you
let me know
sounds like a great way to wrap up the
show one more big shock to the canna
Canyon show that's everybody here just
all the people to my left and listen to
this ridiculous podcast thank you guys
I'll be back to close the show bro
thanks again for coming we're gonna take
some tabs now you guys I'm hit stop
recording here we go alright that was
number 114 I want to thank you guys for
listening I want to think kabuki Jay Fox
once again for coming down and doing a
podcast with me I also need to send a
huge thank you to everybody at the candy
canyon for the hospitality
thanks for let me doing a show there
make sure you guys check out the candy
candy and I pull it up the itis right
now it is at 1507 West Colorado Avenue
in Colorado Springs check them out if
you're 21 and over and you have an ID
with you you do not need to be a medical
patient drop in say hi let them know
that rasta Jeff from the girl from your
heart a podcast sent you also make sure
you support our sponsor hit man glass
make sure you check out
www.mcamillionaire.com this show with
some fortunate youth the song is for a
friend of mine I want to give you a huge
shout out to my ninja Spence and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 115 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me starting the show
off try not to cough already big shut up
the Hitman glass for helping us with the
cops over here as always guys I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band so
letting me use their music on my show
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew hope you got a Fed
joint rolled up I hope you got the email
on I hope you got a dad out maybe you
got the vaporizer going you're smoking a
blunt in the hood getting down across
from me is my good friend Carlos thanks
for joining me Carlos how you doing man
I'm doing great
to my left over here is my buddy Alan
how are you man great to be here I'm
gonna start the show off with a question
what is your favorite way to consume
cannabis Alan I still liked it all
Jordan like an old joint doing the big D
from Broadway wellness who sold me my
very first real tab rig there's the
first canvas cup when I first got that
involved quickly from bongs
right into the hash take like half gram
dad out of a nice hit man rig which
that's a good way to work into this
advertising here shot it's my friends a
hit man glass when I like to buy a new
rig I like to shop in an American store
and buy an American product I like to
buy a rig made by an American person not
a Chinese kid with no protective eyewear
Chinese kid not getting paid a real wage
I don't want something made in America
American hitman rigs are made by dabbers
these guys dab as hard as you do Big
Shot that's my buddy dougie at hitman
glass make sure you follow at Hitman
glass Dougie on Instagram and also visit
www.un.org/webcast
right you guys want to go to the child's
festival with me in California it's over
the 710 weekend so let's go out to
California get down at chalice I'm
trying to get out there this year you
never know what could happen in Rasta
Jeff's world I want to give you a huge
shout-out to my friend Rob from the sour
seed company Rob I hope you're doing
better bro Rob had a health scare he was
supposed to be on the show tonight we
will get him back in the very near
future Rob take good care yourself
brother much love from everybody at the
table much love from the whole I read
genetics and girl from your heart the
whole team the whole true dude get
better man that's scary you told me that
[ __ ] I'm sincerely worried take care of
yourself everybody here's got this ombre
look on their face now we went from
having fun and taking dabs doing oh [ __ ]
what's wrong with wrong yeah so we kind
of put together an impromptu show I
called my friends over I was like dude
my guests bailed come on help me on the
podcast so we got Carlos we got Alan
here we're gonna talk about a few random
things before I get there I have to let
you guys know the stickers from the
hashtag I like it when you ramble
Twitter or campaign whatever that was
called those stickers should have landed
at your door if you participated in that
check your mail you should have some
stickers I've got an email I want to
read it's right here I'm prepared to you
as I promised somebody send me an email
it says hey now just wanted to drop a
note and say how much I loved episode
112 or how I got into the business
awesome great story looking forward to
the growth focused shows this guy also
says is waiting to hear if he gets hired
for a job in Illinois so dude I really
wish you good luck on the job in
Illinois and man thanks for listening
and thanks for the kind words about
episode 112 I really like hearing from
the listeners it makes all the effort I
put into this show super worth it all
you guys got to do is say thank you I
really appreciate it if you've got an
email you'd like to send to me it's a
girl from your heart at hotmail.com
I'd love to hear from you you can also
find me on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
since I'm telling about the email the
last episode was all about CBD we had
our friend
from foxtrax come on to talk about CBD a
friend of mine told me that that episode
made her cry
I'm sorry and you're welcome if it's
making you cry we're doing something
right right yeah if you've got questions
from the CBD episode I encourage you to
email me those questions and I will get
Fox back on the show and we will do
round 2 of CBD first topic that I wanted
to bring up on social media lately there
have been a lot of crazy pictures have
you guys seen the picture of the super
clear shatter the super so actually
nature put a puddle of water on the hood
of somebody's car and then it got really
cold outside and they picked it up and
they carried inside and held it in front
of them back of in with glass with
gloves on it took a picture of it to the
social media and that's just a piece of
ice everybody when they saw the vak oven
and the rubber gloves everybody on
social media just went oh [ __ ] look at
this it's [ __ ] it's for a few days
but then they went everybody it's just
ice so shout out for full and everybody
I should have pulled up so if you guys
were blown away by that super clear hash
that was held up a few days ago on
Instagram a lot of people reposting it
was all over Facebook it was all over
the social media that was frozen water
you can make hash that clear it's easy
you're doing it in the freezer right now
probably the right part of the country
is everybody's bubble that was just a
piece of ice so another social media
thing that has been really catching a
lot of attention lately there was a
glass convention in Las Vegas just
recently was it in Vegas anyway there's
a glass convention a an industry
convention or a mothership rig
bacon and Scott Debbie collab sold you
guys I want you to sit down before I
tell you how much this rig sold for if
you're driving you might want to pull
over if you're at work put down your
knife somebody bought a hatch rig for
101 thousand dollars you believe that
[Music]
you said that okay let's open up that
floodgate I'm gonna say this on my
podcast about five thousand people are
gonna listen to this and I'm sure at
least 100 of em are gonna send me dirty
emails that rig is really ugly you know
I'm sure many other things comes weed
but it's got a gaudy ass bass the bass
is this so one thing I should mention
this rig is covered in moons and if you
turn the rig around slowly it goes
through the phases of the Moon is
something that Debbie pointed out Scott
Deb you shout out to Scott Debbie and to
Sagan glass it's great work you guys I
just think it's ugly it's my personal
preference obviously enough people love
it so don't be mad at me for thinking
it's ugly a lot of people somebody paid
one hundred and one thousand dollars so
it's obviously not one person loved them
way more than I hated it he loves it one
hundred and one thousand times more than
I dislike it I just think it's ugly but
it's poorly planned
the base is god-awful ugly it's got
moons glued to it on the base that's in
this odd shape it looks like the base
was just they made the top and they're
like well we need something big enough
to hold this up now so they made that
gaudy base and then they put a I think
the color would be called Stardust black
Stardust Faberge egg and if you guys
know anything about glass
the Fab Age is the artwork it's the way
to go but they made it out of a color of
glass you can't see through so you could
barely tell that it's a fat bake it
looks like a grenade it's exactly what
it looks like actually okay I've got a
picture here on my phone somewhere I
posted it up to social media so it
shouldn't be too hard to find we will
pull this up for you to take a look at
but it looks like poorly planned and
then it looks like they just glued moons
around it to give it the moon vibe that
they were looking for and I said that I
wanted to buy it and just glue a rocket
to it just to complete the whole space
look there was the image right away so
you give me a minute to find the image
because Facebook likes to do that thing
where it jumps around
I promise here we go this is a rig that
somebody paid a hundred and one thousand
dollars for it's insane it's beautiful
it's got some great colors to it but it
looks like something that les claypool
or Tim Burton would have put together in
my opinion for a really clean sleek
smooth tight baller status look the rigs
are gorgeous and clean and perfect and
flawless and this thing's doesn't come
close yeah I like that
Allen's not really into the glass scene
he doesn't he hasn't mentioned anything
about glass and the time that I've known
him he's looks cool he just does he
already knows that that doesn't fit the
mother ship motto mother ship I'll give
you guys a shout out though those new
racecar seamed rigs are the bee's knees
bro
there are a couple of those that I
really really love I feel like I'm doing
too much pulling up stuff on the phone
here but I'll show you guys these
racecar rigs because they are beautiful
and I can do editing if any of this gets
carried away
hitman our mothership these rigs I'm
gonna try to describe it now since I'm
pulling it up so they took a normal
tourist rig which would be clear and
they have used yellow glass on one
portion and blue glass on another and it
looks really sleek and it's super smooth
and they call it the race car series
this is a Cline and where the Cline
function happens they used clear glass
to make a window so that you can see the
water bubble image that is actually
pretty cool yeah I really love the race
car series glass they do not like that
expensive piece but I really love the
the race car series so I apologize is
that I don't know how you made that
happen I should probably stop talking
about mothership since I'm sponsored by
hitmen glass by yourself all right so we
all agree that that rig was way
overpriced right does financially well
we're all kind of in the the legal
cannabis industry yeah what's uh what's
the most money that you would find
acceptable to pay at this point in your
life that's reasonable hey guys I want
you to send me a tweet to @g fyh podcast
and tell me right now if you're gonna
buy a rig what you would find a reed to
be a reasonable budget are you in the
hundred and one thousand dollar range or
are you over here like Carlos with one
hundred and fifty dollar great Bob I'm
using a hitman III sidecar in front of
me this one so I bought this at
illusions glass in Denver and this was a
five hundred and fifty dollar rig at
that point in time
ah it's natl think it's worth that at
this point but it was at that time in
front of me here is the shot at the
Hitmen glass once again this one on
their website is 800 for the short stack
yeah if you won that lottery I'm glad
you came here and recorded a podcast
before we checked out your Powerball
numbers because if you won that I would
not have seen you tonight yeah all right
so uh something that I wanted to talk
about since everybody at the table is
into the legal cannabis industry you
were kind of making I should we should
back up and talk about kind of how we
ran into each other I have known you
since I was the budtender at met amar
such a long time but we closed yeah you
were one of our first patients that
would come in sometime buy medicine from
us yeah when you came did you come in
when it was in the apartment upstairs I
did okay so you got to see it evolve
from that guys couch we don't talk about
that guy's name on the show we leave
names out to protect the innocent we
went from that guy's couch and then it
went to the middle floor and then we
moved it down to the main floor and
busted out and went hardcore for a while
2008 is when that shop was really
booming used to shop at the dispensary
they which Tom sex and pretty much
handed the keys to me and it was like
here you go run the shop so yeah since
then we've both gotten into that shop
was legal quasi illegal was such a gray
area we called it the wild wild west I
was growing urban the house and Tom was
growing herb at the house and we would
take it put it on the shelves and then
customers would show up with a backpack
and you know I just need to talk to Jeff
they'd send him back and they'd come
talk to him and they'd be like look at
all this weed I grew do you guys want to
buy it and so we just buy it if it was
good enough and they wanted a reasonable
price we could buy the weed from them
and put it on the shelves at that point
it days the good old days yes I think
the herb was a little bit better back
yeah and I work in a large scale grow
it's a different type of thing it's a
totally different monster the airflow is
different the temperature one of the
things I've noticed about everything is
that commercial growers are just oh my
god there just seems like I can't
believe how weed back in the day was so
much better and it was just people
working with almost no budget compared
to people have a lot of that is because
the passion the industry evolved the
rules evolve to where only people with a
million dollars can play in the cannabis
game right now you have to have a
million dollars to get involved in the
cannabis game to have a legal shop and
to grow a grow that supports that shop
to be able to open and have a clean
environment to build your grow and a
retail environment and to hire a staff
and to get product and to get insurance
and to get security security is so
expensive to open any type of anything
marijuana Enforcement Division regulated
every square foot where people can go
needs to be covered by a camera if
there's a doorway they want a camera on
both sides of the door so that if they
look at two camera views on the monitor
they can see you leave one room and
enter the other room flawlessly there
can be no gaps in your travel on the
cameras so it cost you a million bucks
to get into the industry nowadays and
what sucks about that is people like you
and I we have heart we got mad heart you
know what I mean we've been doing this
before we should even admit we were
growing in our on and so we've got heart
we don't have a million dollars because
we had to hide we had we were drawing
weed we weren't going to college we
weren't running a car dealership we
weren't doing whatever these other guys
are doing so we need to make our own
money and now that we've got it your
headphones alright no good I'll tap them
and they'll start working no just one on
alright guys don't ever buy the hero4
headphone amplifier from livewire if
you're a guitar tuner and they offer you
that give them a dirty
can buy the one that's $20 more
expensive it'll be well worth your time
guys that's my recommendation all right
so we're talking about this industry if
you don't have a million dollars you
can't get into the cannabis industry but
Louis and I Carlos and I have mad
passion we wouldn't be able to buy a
shop right now and set that up because
we've been growing weed and living like
that you got to kind of hide when you're
a cannabis grower back in the day we
couldn't have all the money that we had
so we had to hide that we couldn't go
open the store so we couldn't talk about
how'd you make this money I grew weed so
the people that are able to open shops
now are guys that have had other
businesses that we're doing other things
and no offense to those guys but they
don't have the heart that somebody like
you and I have about the industry we
work in this it's a business to them if
they have an accountant and a lawyer and
then the master growers are the guys
that are supposed to go grow their
employees so what I was kind of getting
out a little bit is right now mastered
growers and head growers I'm called a
lead cultivator as my official title I
hated the word master grower so we
changed I'm a lead cultivator I'll lead
the cultivation team we're making hella
good money like we're being paid fat
chunky salaries as lead cultivators in
this industry right now people that have
been at it for I've been growing
cannabis for over 20 years I've been
involved in the cannabis industry or the
cannabis scene for Wow 25 years I have
to think about that messin with weed for
25 years any guys there's a big
difference between being like a weed
grower and a cannabis giver caregiver
and being in the industry if you're not
paying taxes on it you don't have some
kind of cannabis meed regulated license
you can't say you're in the industry in
Colorado see I do this in the industry
you're a grower you're underground
get on paper come join us it's fun pay
taxes do it correctly but so what I'm
saying is the people that own the
industry they have all kinds of money
now so I think that people like myself
that are making good money we better
stick to it we better make a fat resume
you guys that are trimming making I know
trimmers that make anywhere between 10
and 20 bucks an hour if you're making
good money trimming start documenting
how many hours you've been trimming if
you're using a trim machine if you're
using the satellite if you're using the
Ripper
document how many hours you use on that
put that as part of your resume if you
know how if your applicator certified
that goes on
resume because in the future this is
gonna turn into just a basic job
unfortunately people like Alan said over
here it's a business that owners aren't
gonna want to pay the next set of
growers my salary the people that come
after me they're not gonna get paid what
this group of growers are getting paid
it's gonna start tapering off because
what I think creates a high dollar
product is an illegal product since it
was illegal it was highly in demand but
there wasn't any supply now it's legal
we could grow the [ __ ] out of it we
don't have to hide why are we charging
so much for it it's only for production
once we catch up with production which
won't take too long we're building their
greenhouses going up every single day so
once we catch up the production I see
prices going down and then the producers
are going to start being paid less and
less trimmers aren't gonna get hired on
for 15 an hour anymore the industry is
gonna taper off it'll be any other
agricultural Hills find more temporary
they have been going on it probably but
getting back to the leaf cultivator like
any industry I do will believe that if
you can show someone that you are worth
your money you can get a higher wage for
it if you can go in there and you can
increase production and show them that
you can do it you can bring it up 10 15
20 percent you'll still have a
competitive edge over someone else
absolutely able to present that
absolutely you make good recommendations
of absolutely documenting your history
and what you've been able to accomplish
and it's gonna make a lot of differences
as this industry does change that works
and in any industry document what you're
doing have proof it's just harder in the
cannabis industry but as we're revolving
a lot of guys like us we're ahead of the
game so stay ahead of the game and
document that stuff don't get stuck in
your bubble and write down everything
that you're learning and that goes on a
resume if you can eat like I said if you
can use the satellite that goes on your
resume if you can use the obidos that
goes on your resume if you can run a
sweet leaf extractor that goes on your
resume because eventually you guys
you're not gonna so Alan brought up a
good point you can impress them and you
can jump in and make a few a few more
dollars on your salary but a lot of
those guys a lot of those jobs are taken
by guys like us I've got a jump on it so
it's the next wave of people all the all
the rock stars are kind of doing that
now you're gonna have to be a badass to
get that kind of a salary in the future
I think
my opinion yeah I agree with you on on
that a lot it's still gonna come down to
networking to ivory and other industries
networking was important you have to
have those you know those crossover
relationships but nothing like this
industry of I've ever experienced the
word so I use the word incestuous it
really is you have to know someone a lot
of instances to get I get in the door
now I was pretty fortunate I was got
hired on I've always been in the
industry about well eight months and I
think I've been badged and I've worked
at a couple other facilities starting at
the ground level literally and I did
walk into one place and with my
crossover skills and my resume I was
able to get in there but I've had to
work and hustle to learn this industry
oh yeah but it does matter a lot on if
you can name drop a little bit I think
it helps a tremendous amount more so in
this industry I can completely testify
to your statement I would not be in the
position I'm in if I weren't I earned it
honestly
I earned I earned the spot but if I did
not know grimy Gatsby if I wasn't tight
with hunt like I was I would not have
found my spot where I am
he was my homie from before he had a
spot and when things went wrong he
called me right away like you can grow
yeah so get out and join the industry I
mean that's kind of what that you were
bringing up you know if you're gonna
join some other clubs or or anything
like that some social groups that are I
think just getting out and getting your
badge versus get your badge that's a
very first thing we did a brief episode
on how to get your badge I should do a
complete in depth episode on how to get
your badge I'm gonna make a note of that
here we're gonna do this in the phone
here since it's right here
episode about badge alright guys I'll do
a full episode on how to get your badge
I'll do a little update thing for you so
you guys are new kind of fairly new to
the legal cannabis industry can we talk
about what you guys are doing or is that
would you like to keep some of that
quiet for now well I won't mention who
I'm with because you know I don't think
it's okay the thing but yeah I'm just in
quality control trimming if you will
okay but you know it did really those
you'd mentioned dropping the mass
grower and lead cultivator the trimmer
is the last well not the last person but
one of the last people to see what that
products going to be like when it gets
out there yeah you get your dis turn
into more of a quality control issue in
the industry I think - you hear that
forward-thinking you guys that's
something we need in the cannabis
industry you're not just a trimmer you
were a quality control you're inspecting
my life buds that I handed to you to
trim your the last eyes they're gonna
look at them before we put them in a jar
and customers touch them so you have to
be inspector quality control before
thinker if you're gonna come join the
cannabis industry just like just like
you saying you're not just trimming it
you're not staring into the buds all day
you are making sure they are beautiful
so that when I put them in the jar and
the patients come in they go oh who trim
that black cherry Kim I want to smoke at
all especially on the hand trimming you
know really is a it's a fun it's a fun
skill to learn I mean it takes a lot of
technique and it can be boring but I
mean you have some great conversations
over the table you meet such a wide
variety of personalities in the industry
yeah people so many different be me that
have been yeah I've been out doing other
industries real estate for 20 years
I actually find that I'm always the
minority of the table everybody's a
little crowded it's starting to get the
rents going up it's getting a little bit
full they have an abundance of labor for
the market so it is competitive you know
so work on your skills and work on work
on getting to know people in the
industries where someone will give you a
chance then like every other thing show
up and do your stuff you know it's not a
place where you just sit around party or
I think there's a lot of people who want
to get into the industry because they
think it was like high school
whereby this sits around the topes
around a table or something it sounds
like that but I'm the lead cultures
business and I will send you the [ __ ]
home if you're playing with your phone
we go you're standing over there in the
corner like it's cool take a couple of
pictures it's a huge garden it looks
great take a couple of pictures I
understand but take your pictures right
before right after your shift well you
can walk in and take them or finish up
take them but don't push phone every 20
minutes to take a picture don't text
your girlfriend all the time just do
some [ __ ] while you're in there walking
around smelling plants and your fingers
and there's work to be done there's 300
plants in 85 lights in one room and I
called you over for a few hours of work
I need you to work not play with your
phone so if you're in the industry
appreciate your position start taking
notes of everything you do document all
that stuff make sure you're getting paid
a fair wage kind of pay attention to the
way that the market in this industry is
going and make sure that you are getting
a competitive wage and bring it to your
employer's attention that you can now
run an obidos you can now run a
satellite make sure that all that [ __ ]
is noticed make sure you're getting paid
for what you're doing if you're coming
to join the industry I would say get a
key badge you don't even waste time with
a support badge you're worth more money
with a good match yeah all right so
we've been going about a half hour you
guys want to take some dabs we're gonna
smoke some of this lemon gee I should
ask a question to get you guys going but
I didn't think of a good question yet we
already talked about so what do you
think of this will concentrate scene
where did you come from Wow so you've
come a long way in just a year see this
guy's a go-getter he didn't sit on the
couch and [ __ ] around
that's what I would encourage everyone
else out there that's gonna do this you
know treat it like it's a job you know
it's uh yeah it's certainly using a
product that's always been associated
with you know good time so we want
everybody to get the medicinal help out
of it that they need and with the REC
you know people that just want to use it
for enjoyment that it brings us but when
you're on the job it's a job you have to
make sure that all of those other
components work or it'll be a
short-lived industry cash register has
to come out right at the end of the
night there you go yeah do that if
you're too high so what do you think of
this whole hash scene the way that we
all just smoke shits on a hash or was it
like that at all in Arizona or is that
just kind of a Colorado thing well you
know what I didn't I wasn't in the
industry down there so okay I tell you
how much how much people were what they
were doing you guys enjoy it up here
[Music]
he's come across as very well-spoken and
very intelligent so far let's let him
continue that reputation on the show we
turn into a bubble I'm heating up the
highly educated this one's the duality
male you know I do have to sell you
stuff when I participated when it wasn't
legal as a younger man I had one of the
old Hobbit bongs that I used to smoke my
wonderful ex-wife
now she's wonderful cuz she's an ex
awesome I love you the glass where they
have here I mean to sit here you don't
have to really smoke to appreciate the
art or the craftsmanship in it you don't
have to do that it is really
pardon me you can see why someone who
asked the budget may spend the money all
here on one you know art is subjective
and it it's not jumping back to what
we're talking about earlier and what I'm
sitting here looking at what you have on
the table I mean there's three beautiful
pieces well thank you to hit man's and
then a piece from elevate glasses
changed like what maybe the last ten
years I remember just going into the
glass shop it was kind of like so so you
know and then now this seems like the
glass shops there's something about
being a grower I caught myself falling
into it when you harvest do you have too
much money for a minute and like any
young guy that has too much money and a
big ego and [ __ ] going on you gotta go
buy something and I don't do the gold
chains I don't do rims on my car and the
thing I like to do is smoke hash and
listen to good music so I've got a
slammin stereo system I got really good
headphones on and I've got really nice
hash so that's every harvest I would go
buy something ridiculous like this was
one of my first good harvest to hit and
we were talking about that was like a
harvest that I drew this one here I just
drew some extra herb I was like I'm
gonna set up this room and that extra
room bought me that rig was pretty much
what I pulled out of there extra you
know so stuff like that we're gonna go
buy a rig instead of buying rims and
gold chains and if you've gold chains
and air jordans of your thing [ __ ]
Rock em I'd rather have a hit man rig in
come hit my rig I like skate shoes and
Dickie's it's nice and easy for me
what's the new one that you got there
this is called the hit man short stack
and we're hitting a little earlier so
shun it again to hit man Dougie shot it
to Ryan a hit man glass hey Ryan I got
the rig I was supposed to tell you when
I got this do that email but thank you
it's kind of clogged up we should clean
it that's something I could talk about
how to clean your rig that is a good
chunk
there's probably a half gram of just
buzz stuck in there yeah that's just
that's a very intricate piece to be
trying to I'm gonna have to dissolve it
really well with rubbing alcohol
isopropyl alcohol just fill the rig up
as high as you can with alcohol let it
sit for a few then pour a little bit of
kosher salt in there kosher salts real
rough and then shake the [ __ ] out of the
rig cover the holes of your thumbs and
shake the [ __ ] out of it don't drop it
do it over the carpet dude over the
couch if you feel like you're clumsy and
just shake the [ __ ] [ __ ] up real good
and then rinse it with hot water a few
times let it cool off things I noticed
is if you give it a decent one about
that what that piece is a pretty
intricate but nice and streak free when
you're done cleaning Carlos got the
headphones in the mic will have you back
on for another show and I'll have like
stuff written down for like 33 minutes I
you got anything else that you want to
say - no let you guys know now that the
show is towards the end when this comes
out within 48 hours of this episode
being posted 5,000 people will download
come out on Monday by Tuesday at
midnight 5,000 downloads so a lot of
people are gonna hear all the stuff into
the show to tell people how many people
[Music]
no I don't have anybody represent always
encourage people to be responsible make
sure you get out there and support the
people that are supporting this industry
you know whatever it is if it's a
politician make sure that they have your
interest at heart and get out there and
support those guys doing that there you
go that's very wise words I don't think
both you guys for coming this is a great
show you guys good conversational show
get robbed get well soon banks I need
you on the show I'm gonna have Rob from
sour seed on in a very
soon episode we're gonna talk about
selecting males for breeding that should
be a very fun episode two good breeders
we may get rusty from Canada venture if
he's available he has to travel an hour
to get here but if he can come if we can
all match up we have three well known
seed breeders here I will answer some
questions if you guys have questions
about selecting a male email it to me
grow for me harder hotmail comm we'll
talk about that um I think that's all
I've got for you let's start wrapping up
the show I'm digging for that paper that
I read at the end
you guys are selecting a male get the
wheel cool all right
you guys thank you for listening I'll be
back in another week hopefully Rob will
be better by then if not he'll be here
in two weeks no pressure Robin love you
broke it
get well soon you guys everybody send
send a good vibration to Rob he needs
some love right now yeah don't forget to
check out the sponsors I hit man glass
big shout out to hit man dougie the
show's over you guys please go to the
iTunes Store search for the girlfriend
heart podcast give me a five star rating
and type in a little comment let me know
what you think of the show and I will
read your comments on a future episode
if Rob doesn't make it to the next
episode I'll read all of the comments
and emails on the next episode I'll get
us caught up talking about the email
address and the Twitter account the
whole episode hotmail.com
and on twitter it's @g fyh podcast don't
forget the show is available on iTunes
and stitcher and almost every episode is
available on I read genetics Colorado
comm something went weird on the website
a few of the episodes are gone like
episodes 1 through 27 or something they
kind of disappeared don't worry I'll get
them back up there I will fix that I
don't forget that there's a donation
button on the podcast page if you go to
the website I region etics Colorado com
click on the growth my heart podcast tab
on the top right there's a donation
button that'll go directly to my PayPal
account you guys I'm never gonna charge
you anything for this show it's always
going to be free free free free I just
cuz I love you but if you want to make a
contribution I would definitely
appreciate it
go hit up that PayPal tab I'll send you
a shattered on the show if you want
questions answered you will definitely
get top priority I will kiss your ass
to stuff oh I'm on all the social media
I've said that a bunch of times followed
the new Instagram account you guys it's
I understand attics help me out I'm
almost to 30,000 again shallots manager
Spence thanks again for listening until
next time take a fat dad and give them a
hug for me
[Music]
all right podcaster all don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you