yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 249 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write up your new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to cap - and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen remember last week
I was complaining about it raining for a
solid week I would like to upgrade my
complaint it has been raining for two
solid weeks here in Pueblo Colorado if
you're an outdoor grover here in the
southern colorado area the struggle is
real this year I feel bad for you but
you know where there's no struggle right
here at this dab table right here at
this recording area that's right I am
smoking some flow wax from our friends
at concentrates supply company groan I
had Three Rivers of course where I'm the
lead cultivator if you know me you know
that I've got sort of a love-hate
relationship with the flow plan I've
been growing flow for probably ten years
my first or second legal medical
marijuana grow contained flow plants
that's how long I've been growing flow
it was a gift from a friend I took it to
the garden I took clones of it I
flowered some out I kept clones
I took a mother plant and I have had
this flow flying around for probably 10
years I say I've got a love-hate
relationship with flow there's nothing
wrong with flow it's got a very unique
smell and that's what I love hate is the
unique smell of flow part of flow smells
amazing to me part of flow smells
terrible to me it just kind of depends
on how it comes out and what part of the
flowering period you're in one point
that smells great
then it turns into this thing that I do
not like part of it could be because I
grew it for so long that I would wake up
in my house my entire house would smell
like flow I would go to bed and my
entire house would smell like flow I
would leave and pull up into the
driveway and when I got out of the car
the first thing I would smell would be
flow a lot of people are like you have
big problems dude but sometimes that
same smell forever that she gets on your
nerves and you just want to not smell it
and I couldn't get away from it so I had
like a love-hate relationship with flow
and I would refuse to smoke it for a
long time I'll grow the [ __ ] out of some
flow because I grow for a dispensary and
people buy the flow so we got to have
the flow but flow is not my favorite to
grow or smoke but then I was at the
dispensary and I grew this material and
they said hey we turn to some of the
flow into wax do you want to smell it
and I put my nose in the little jar I'm
doing right now
and my mouth just went yeah I'll take a
gram of that
and I did an episode called follow your
nose and I was totally correct when I
smelled this I wanted some and as soon
as I got home and dabbed it I said to
myself you should have bought more of
that because it's got a really great
high to it it just kind of it kind of
mellowed me out a lot of dabs make me
super rambley and super chatty I know it
sounds like I'm rambling and chatty
right now because I'm doing a podcast by
myself and I'm the only one here to talk
and I'm explaining how I feel and [ __ ]
so I do sound rambley but my thoughts
are much slower much more controlled
than it would be how to smoke some Jack
flash or platinum tangi or something ah
it's a pretty damn good high off this
blowback so I enjoy this I'm nice and
relaxed I'm sitting down on my chair
nice and mellow
I made some solid notes here it kind of
descrambled the eggs in my brain that
gets scrambled sometimes when I take too
big of a dab so great job to my friends
at CSC for the great work on the flow
and also a big shout out to all of the
growers at Three Rivers yes I'm the lead
cultivator so I am Tooting my own heart
a little bit but I am just the lead
cultivator there are other guys that do
a lot of hard work I do get hot and
sweaty but these other guys they bust
their asses so shout out to the entire
grow team at Three Rivers and big shout
out to our friends at concentrates
supply company of course the trimmers
are included in all of that everybody
from the gross staff to the trimmers to
the metric folk to the compliance people
shout out to everybody at Three Rivers
and of course at CSC you know I believe
it was CSC I'm not certain but one of
the concentrate companies sent us an
email saying that our material yielded
the most concentrate that they have ever
gotten from a batch of material so we're
doing something right at Three Rivers
they're doing something right over at
CSC concentrates good job this flow is
amazing I'm also digging the Cindy
Walker which is Cindy 99 with white
Walker in there and I've also got some
blueberry headband great work but I'm
loving the flow of the flow is you know
I think this batch of flow may have
restored my faith in my fascination with
flow I might be back on the flow train I
might smoke some more flow more
frequently now that I've tried this
alright so let's talk about something
else that's cool from the grower at
Three Rivers we have two lab tests
everything that we grow everything that
we grow is tested for potency and it's
also tested for molds and yeasts to
microbial testing so we send everything
out before it can be sold at the store
it all has to be sent out that all has
to be tested the results have to come
back then we can sell it the test
results for some of our strains have
come back pretty impressive lately and I
want to brag about our 31 percent THC
test result on presidential Kush we did
not breed the presidential cush that is
not my project of breeding but we did
grow it and we tested at thirty-one
percent THC I'm pretty proud of that
that's a pretty good number most strains
that you're gonna find in a dispensary
they hover somewhere between the 22 to
like 29 is high 27 is kind of where
you're gonna find him mostly 22 to 27 in
that range if you get over 30
that's impressive 31 is super impressive
the highest that we have seen is 35 I
don't think I've ever seen a higher test
which was of course the arize the tested
at 35 in a fraction that was grown at
organic a'that was bred by myself um so
yeah I just wanted to brag on our whole
crew and our genetics and the Janie tech
that we're using over at Three Rivers
we got an official lab result at 31.6%
you know back in the day we got a test
from our ecto cooler strain there was a
little higher than that but everybody
thought that it was a fluke so everybody
kind of dismissed that and we're just
gonna celebrate the 31 percent we're
gonna take this 31.6 seriously and we're
gonna brag about this one so big shot
it's everybody at Three Rivers let's see
what do I want to touch on next you know
what I got to do I got to remind you
that this podcast is brought to you by
our friends at the dank team that's
right if you need to add some new
genetics to your lineup if you need some
regular or feminized seeds check out my
friends at the dank team comm that's
right the dank team comm carries brands
like alpha chronic mile high sin city
can adventure IRA genetics the callee
connection DNA genetics and many more
trusted brands so make sure you check
out the dank team comm and let them know
you're listening to the grow from your
heart
podcast all right speaking of new seeds
let's talk about my most current
breeding project that's right on the 1st
of this month I started a new breeding
project I put a few plants into flour
I'm running one light in a very small
room with a very small amount of plants
let's see what's in there I've got a
chem 4 there is a rise there are two
different phenotypes of arise arise
number E and a rise number 8 there's an
no cooler in there there's strawberry
fields we've got a kosher cush there's a
flow there's a grateful dog there's a
Zack Hayes space [ __ ] and of course
hell's og they're all in the breeding
room together they're all going to get
hit with pollen from my arise mail that
a rise mail is known as King Solomon ah
let's see the Kim for I've made Kim four
seeds before with Solomon ah they don't
have a name I only made about 30 of
those so I never let any of those out
arise Ian a rise 8 of course will make a
rise f two seeds ecto cooler I have
never bred the ecto cooler to the arise
before what I'm thinking is gonna happen
is we're going to get really tall really
dense really stinky really resin covered
buds with a very unique flavor the ecto
cooler has a very unique flavor the
arize has its own pungent smell I think
when you mix the two we're going to find
some great progeny the Strawberry Fields
is in there Strawberry Fields has a very
strawberry candy light kind of smell
kind of a soft a hint of a strawberry
instant sort of a thing I think we'll
create some really tall tropical
flavored strawberry type sativa buds
Wow the kosher pushes in they're kosher
cush from DNA genetics it's a great cut
of kosher cush my goal with the kosher
cush cross the kosher doesn't put out a
lot of weight it produces a bunch of
really small buds I'm hoping maybe we
can increase the yields on the kosher
cush maybe put a little more funk into
it kosher is already a great strain but
I think adding it to a rise we're going
to increase the production just making
an overall plant all together flow is in
there flow makes when you cross flow to
a rise that makes a strain called prana
prana is an indica sativa hybrid with a
very unique aroma the smells that come
out of that plant are amazing I produces
big fat chunky colas what's next the
Grateful dog when you cross grateful dog
to an arise male that creates a plant
called the morning dew morning dew is as
close to grateful dog
as I have released in regular seeds a
long time ago I released grateful dog
and feminized seeds it quickly became
very popular but I quickly sold out
because I am NOT making more feminized
seeds for a long time there's no plan in
my future to make feminized seeds so
that morning dew was as close to the
grateful dog that I have
in a regular seed what else do we have
on the list here Zack Hayes let me tell
you about Zack Hayes Zack Hayes is
Strawberry Cough crossed to killer clean
and it was made for our friend Zack
Hayes from New Mexico who was part of
the organic a dispensary Zack Hayes
unfortunately passed of cystic fibrosis
so he had a strain named after him
long live Zack I'm going to cross the
arize - Zack Hayes hopefully I can get
those available for you at org antica
and Albuquerque so if you're a medical
marijuana patient or if you knew Zack
there will be a way for you to get your
hands on the Zack Hayes seeds big up -
Zack much love miss a little buddy
alright what else do we have in the room
space [ __ ] space [ __ ] is Mike Ross of
grateful dog to space clean I took my
favorite space clean female and I
pollinated it with the grateful dog
feminized pollen this mate was made
years and years ago and I never released
it I kept this one to myself it
basically almost every plant that I grew
from there came out very similar to
space Queen it looks like I just made a
space queen cross it didn't show much
grateful dog in there I'm hoping to kind
of mix that weird and mango funky flavor
that space Queen creates with that gassy
funky tropical thing that arise has and
I'm really curious what that's gonna do
the space Queen stays short and squat or
the space [ __ ] stays short and squat
and branches out a whole bunch a rise
likes to grow real tall and as real
branchy so I may have created a beefy
ass plant with a bunch of stink all
right what else is in there hell's oh
gee I have crossed hell's og to arise
before and that makes a strain called
Hellfire og since it starts off with an
OG Kush as a mother that female puts
that really it just gets a lot of a
hell's OG fuel and funk and dake nests
and then you put the arise in there
which is golden go and Daybreaker now
we're gonna I'm gonna go back a little
bit day breaker is chem D and Joseph og
so I'm putting chem D Joseph og and
golden goat to another cush plant it's
bringing out a lot of great cushy
undertones and some have like a lemon
cush some of them are real greasy some
have a smell of like lemon pledge with
cush on it and then some have like a
weird it reminds me of like lava soap or
some kind of soap that I can't quite put
my nose on
but it's got a great aroma to it my goal
was the hell's OG does not produce very
well it's kind of a tall lanky skinny
shitty plant like a lot of oh jeez and
the arize is just a stocky really robust
plant everything that breeds to that
comes out with more production so I'm
trying to increase the production
increase the structure of the hell's OG
and it is working so that's what's in
the breeding project right now all of
those will of course be hit by the arize
male there are only seven or eight days
into flower right now they need about 21
to 25 days to get into bloom before I'll
hit them with pollen then from there
they're going to need five to eight
weeks for those seeds to harden up I'll
go pull seeds occasionally from certain
plants and see if they look like they're
ready the flow finishes really quickly
those seeds come on quick for some
reason the hell's OG those seeds seem to
take a really long time to harden up so
it's all about the plant it's all about
timing things it's all about having a
goal and it's all about paying attention
to what's going on so if you're gonna
breed have a goal don't just throw some
plants in there have an idea what you're
gonna do know what you want to create
anyway that's a look into my breeding
room thanks for joining me I let's see
what do we want to move on to next let's
read a message from a listener if you
listen to the episode last week I talked
about how to talk about cannabis with
your kids how to address your cannabis
use with your children a lot of you live
in places where dare is trying to set
your kids up to snitch on you I think
that if you hide your cannabis use it
looks like you're up to something I
think if you talk to your kids about it
and tell them what's going on you have
built an honest relationship with your
family and there's no reason to hide
[ __ ] when you hide things it makes you
look like you're hiding something you
might be acting just a little bit
differently because you're hiding
something and the kids are so receptive
that they're going to see you acting
differently and they're gonna know
you're hiding something so don't hide
[ __ ] don't lie to the kids when you hide
things you have to lie when you lie you
have to lie again then you have to hide
that line then you gotta lie again and
it's just a [ __ ] shitty web and you
don't want to start that with your
children tell the children the truth
anyway
a listener sent me an email and I don't
know if they want their name set on the
air so I'm going to keep that private
but he knows who he is and hey bro we
need the session soon I know you live in
Colorado I know you're kind of far from
me but we do need to get together in
session also brother great work on the
drum videos on Instagram I see you
playing the drum videos I'm a drummer
too
we need to get together in Seche and
play a little bit of drums are you
bringing your drum kit to me or am i
bringing my drum kit to you that's the
question anyway let's get into this
message it goes like this thanks for
making people aware of the wretched meed
background check it's kept my family
struggling since we've moved here I'm
still trying to find a good lawyer to
file suit with the meed I really think
the ten years is ludicrous
it ruins the chance of any young felons
getting a badge ten years from the
moment you turn 18 is 28 so anyone with
any charge under 28 are out of the
industry then if it's 10 years from that
it puts you at 38 years old if that
makes any sense now at one time they
didn't allow felons at all someone filed
a complaint and a lawsuit and they
changed it to 10 years I believe if they
changed it to 10 I can get them to
change it to 5 allowing me and thousands
of other others that are stuck on
welfare in Colorado I think he's saying
that would allow them to get a job in
the industry which would be taxpaying
citizens with a badge I know I'm
preaching to the choir but you if if you
have any lawyer suggestions I would
appreciate it
the recent parent podcast was great okay
so now I just caught up to the part
about the last episode so I mentioned on
an episode that you should find out if
you can get a marijuana Enforcement
Division badge before you move to
Colorado if you want to work in the
legal marijuana industry in Colorado you
have to get a badge you cannot come into
a facility without a marijuana
Enforcement Division badge
you can't touch product you can't do
damn near anything you were a visitor
without that badge so to get that you
have to pass a thorough background check
there are a lot of things that could
screw you on getting that badge if
you've got a felony within the last 10
years or if you've got a drug crime
there are a lot of things that can
really mess that up I don't remember all
of the specifics I'm not gonna search
right now but if you are planning on
coming to Colorado to work in the
cannabis industry go to the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division website
and see or if if you are even eligible
for a badge there is a list of things
it's about ten or twelve bullet points
and it says do any of these apply to you
and if you say yes to any of those there
is a good possibility you were banned
from working in the marijuana industry
for the time being until your time
period comes up or until you can get a
lawyer to fix all of that [ __ ] for you
so be careful if you're coming to
Colorado that's what he's talking about
this guy wants to find a lawyer
to help him file a suit against the meed
in the state of Colorado to reduce the
ten year period to five so if anybody
out there is a lawyer anybody wants to
lawyer up and help this guy send me a
message it grows from your heart at
hotmail.com and I will connect you guys
and you can go you guys can start
working on this and get more people able
to work in the industry now here's the
part of the message where he talks about
we talk about children he said the
recent parent podcast was great we had
social service called on us
in Kentucky sorry I'm scrolling through
the message there we go and social
service is called on us in Kentucky over
moving here they came in and evaluated
me and my wife and concluded that if we
did use cannabis it was not affecting
our children in any way we were very
lucky it could have gone badly more
people need to educate the kids hell
educate the whole country Cheers
thanks for the show hey brother you're
very welcome for the podcast thank you
for the great message thanks for
reaching out to me I did ask for input
on the last podcast I said hey if you've
got some input on this let me know so
hearing back from you is great thank you
I'm glad I was able to remind people to
check on the Med badge before they come
here and I'm glad I've got people
thinking about keeping the kids safe
you guys Babylon is out there
programming your kids to snitch on you
the DARE program wants your kids to
snitch on you be very careful
hey thanks for the message dude I hope
we get the sesh some time soon maybe we
can meet up in the springs or something
alright I've got another message I want
to read that came from Instagram it goes
like this Rasta Jeff hey buddy no names
if you read this anyhow I can't get
enough of your real grown OBS approach
I've learned a lot from you and you're
helping me to make some incredible
medicine I quit drinking alcohol almost
two years ago quit taking
pharmaceuticals for back pain and
anxiety and quit smoking cigs about ten
months ago
thanks to cannabis congratulations man
that's [ __ ] awesome alcohols terrible
pharmaceuticals are terrible and
cigarettes are the devil so I'm proud of
you for quitting I meant I'm glad I'm
helping you grow good cannabis to get
away from that stuff and take better
care of yourself the message keeps going
and it says like this I don't use iTunes
or I'd give you a well-written five-star
review hey Thank You Man
that still means a lot to me he says
consider this I digress I'm high on some
homegrown Jack Herer right now
I wish Jack had a higher CBD content as
it is I find it to be a wonderful
medicine in certain areas
have you ever bred with Jack um I
haven't bred with Jack but I've read
with Jack flash I haven't grown the
seeds out yet and then he goes on to say
or can you recommend a strain very
similar to Jack but with a heavier CBD
medical side I highly respect your
opinion that's why I'm reaching out to
you directly
too much conflicting infective liking a
few of my photos gave me a lot of
confidence that I'm doing something
right hey that's pretty cool that Jessi
likes your photos on Instagram you were
definitely doing something right now as
for conflicting information that's why I
do this podcast I wanted to write a book
I realized that a book would evolve
almost every week in the new cannabis
industry and then I also knew that there
was a bunch of [ __ ] out there on the
forums that was making people ruin their
grows so I wanted to put out a way to
teach people how to grow with just like
you said in the beginning with no
[ __ ] with no jokes with no tricks
with tried-and-true methods that
actually work in home grows and large
scale horticulture so thanks for the
compliments there now let's talk about
strains that are similar to Jack but are
a little bit higher in CBD now a strain
that may surprise people that often has
a lot of CBD in it is Alaskan Thunder
[ __ ] Alaskan Thunder [ __ ] is thought of
as a sativa it grows really tall
reaching colas it has like a really nice
minty sandalwood sort of a flavor it
kind of depends on where you get it who
grew it but it acts more like a sativa
but I have seen test results from
Alaskan Thunder [ __ ] that have tested
tested with impressive CBD numbers
another strain I think you may like may
be penny wise penny wise is a kind of a
sativa growing plant it's got a nice -
Teva high but it's also got plenty of
CBD in there now another really popular
high CBD strain is ac/dc ac/dc has a lot
of CBD but it's also got THC it's gonna
give you a nice head buzz but you're
also going to get that relief you're not
gonna get bogged down a couple of other
really popular CBD crosses are Harlequin
and canna tonic you can find those quite
often in Colorado I'm not sure if they
are available in your area
many of the strains I listed are
available in seed form you can probably
find some of them at the dank team.com I
can't guarantee what they've got
thing that I have noticed is in my
opinion CBD works better as an edible I
find it to be more effective smoking CBD
comes on quickly but it doesn't last
very long in my opinion maybe something
you might want to consider keep growing
the jack keep smoking the jack
but maybe add a little bit of CBD edible
or CBD teacher to your regimen and that
may be the way to go to help with the
relief if you want to go extreme and
grow a plant that is really heavy and
CBD and won't do much on the THC side I
would recommend Tora Bora from DNA
genetics it's not the best plant to grow
it does not produce very well but it
does put out very good CBD medicine
it'll have a nice cherry flavor will
have kind of a cushy aroma and the CBD
effects are very strong so that's Tora
Bora from DNA genetics all right yeah I
want to thank you for the message you
said not to say your name but hey thanks
I'm gonna go follow you on Instagram
right now and I would like to know if
you find some medicine that works a
little bit better for you ladies and
gentlemen if you want to send me a
message the best way to do it is to
email me and grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you I
would love to read your messages on the
show let's get into one more email
before we wrap up this episode this
email goes like this it says what's up
just started listening to your podcast
and I've learned a lot thanks for doing
the podcasts for us hey you're very
welcome the email goes on to say I
listen to your sea of green episode and
got some great info I'm planning on
using the scrog tech since myspace is
very limited I recall you saying that
you use this method as well I'd love to
hear another more in depth episode on
your methods pot size transplant before
a flower and plants per square foot I'm
planning on growing Cindy 99 using the
true living organics method the Rebbe
sells c99 f for that he says we're good
with this growing method that should
work pretty well in that method by the
way any tips for small grow spaces
Thanks and keep it up well I'm not going
to do a whole long episode on scrog
again because I kind of covered most of
it in that first episode let me get
right to the point with your questions
you said you want to know more about pot
size now since you're doing a small area
you actually included your area you say
that it's two by three and a half by
eight so you've got two feet wide three
and a half feet deep and eight feet tall
that's not a lot of space to wear
with but that's plenty of space for a
small light maybe you've got a 400 watt
light in there hopefully you've got some
airflow in there maybe you've got a 600
watt light with a whole lot of airflow
that's up to you but pot size in a space
that small I would probably do 2 or 3 3
gallon pots and just spread them out
really far or maybe do one 5 gallon pot
if it even fits in there that's gonna be
a tight fit if you can get those square
pots one 5 gallon pot in there would fit
spread it down real real low and just
keep that plant as short as you can get
it every time it grows up Bend it back
under that trellis net and keep it low
another thing you can do if you want to
go smaller pots you can do more plants
in smaller pots and you don't have to
veg as long the thing with more plants
is you have less veg time with less
plants it takes more veg time you're
just gonna grow one plant longer to fill
the space or you'll grow more plants for
shorter to fill the space so if you want
to do rock wool cubes do like the 4 inch
rock wool cubes maybe do 1 2 3 like 4 do
maybe like 16 rock wool cubes in the
whole room or maybe do like 12 or 9 4
inch square pots or 9 6 inch net pots it
kind of depends on how often you want to
water how many plants you want to run
how many plants are you legally allowed
to run is this an illegal grow there are
things like that to think about so in
your space I would say 2 or 3 3 gallon
pots or a whole bunch of little ones
transplant before a flower like I said
it just put them into the 3 gallon pots
or maybe 1 5 gallon pot I'll use a good
aerated soil using quality soil mix use
good nutrients plants per square foot
let's see that's kind of up to you if
you just like I was saying earlier if
you want to do a whole bunch of little
ones you could do like 30 little tiny
rock wool cubes or you could do 16
bigger rock wool cubes or like 9 6 inch
net pots or 3 3 gallon pots or one 5
gallon pot or maybe 1 7 gallon pot would
fit in there what this is gonna do is
it's gonna make a difference on how
frequently you have to water it's gonna
make a difference on how long you have
to veg and it's going to make a
difference on how many plants you have
in there those are some of the things to
consider when you're deciding this so I
feel like I may have kind of just told
you figure it out but you kind of have
to figure this part
that's something you're gonna have to
decide do you want to veg longer do you
want to veg shorter if you want one big
plant do you want multiple strains
that's one of the fun parts about
cannabis is that you have a little
wiggle room there are no solid rules on
what you've got to do okay what I would
probably do I'm looking at it I'm trying
to picture this size of space I think I
would do four three gallon pots and I
would be sure to do all the same strain
I would grow them up about like until
they have a few nodes you know when they
start making that node where the one
starts taking off at the top I would top
them take that main top node out of
there now you got a nice even plant I
would start trellising them out then and
spread them out real wide now you've got
four plants that are probably like ten
inches tall they're nice and bushy put
them under the screen get that screen
set up about ten or twelve inches above
the top of the pot and just start
spreading them out as wide as you can
instead of letting that plant grow up
make it grow out and then let it go up
from there and then if you have another
screen up you can use the next screen to
support all the buds that you're going
to create they'll start falling over use
the next one as like little supports
forms for when they start tipping you
just have this little little rows of
buds everywhere it'll look beautiful so
I hope I gave you useful information I
know I just told you figure it out do
what you feel best with but I would do
four three gallon pots and put the net
about ten or twelve inches above the pot
use for the same strain let those plants
grow all into that net keep bending them
down bending them down keeping them low
I do some go and pop and twist the stems
do a little bit of super cropping in
there and make sure those sticks are
nice and strong let move the nutrients
around real well and then when you've
got that screen filled in let it grow
straight up just a little bit and then
flip it into flower and I think you will
be completely happy with your results
again I know I left a whole bunch of
wiggle room in there I didn't give any
steadfast answers but this is some stuff
that you get to play with I did say I do
the four pots three gallons run those
Cindy 99s in there are these seeds
feminized or are they regular if they
are f4 as it says here they're probably
regular seeds plan on pulling out some
males so here's my opinion if this is
possible for you however many seeds
you've got grow all of them in that
space in small pots put them in a six
inch net pot and if you've got a ten
pack run all ten of them when they get
big enough to take a clone take a clone
from every one of them and label it like
make plant a plant a plant
eat plant be go label all your plants
and then take a clone and label that
clone plant a clone a plant be clone be
and then grow them you're gonna find
some boys throw the boys away throw the
corresponding clones away now you've got
a bunch of girls to finish finish those
girls find the one you like the best
you've got a clone of that over there in
the cloner or hopefully it's in a pot by
now and rooted but you've got a clone of
the good one so now you can grow as many
of that as you want next time so maybe
start with a whole bunch of small pots
find the one you want and then run four
clones of that one in three gallon pots
next time that may be the strategy I
don't know if you've got room to keep
clones I don't know if you have room to
keep that and the good one is a mother
plant I don't know what your options are
it sounds like you've got very limited
space but if you can dedicate another
very small space to keeping a clone and
one keeper mother plant you would have
yourself a small perpetual grow all
right you didn't say if you want me to
use your name or not on the episode so
I'm going to be respectful and not say
your name but hey thanks for the great
email thanks for asking questions if
you've got more specific questions about
scrog Anor if you need any help please
feel free to send me another email of
course it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
everybody who has a grow question I love
helping my audience out all right
podcast rolled my throat is starting to
tell me that it's time to wrap up the
podcast I'm sure you can hear it in my
voice I'm getting a little raspy ladies
and gentlemen the next episode is number
250 I'm super proud to have made it this
far I do promise you that I've got more
grow lessons coming I know the last
couple of episodes have been weird
topics not mainly based on growing but
I've got more grow stuff coming for you
ladies gentlemen please keep the emails
coming like I said a moment ago it's
grow for me hard at hotmail.com also let
me mention something I had a couple of
messages and a saved folder that I
really wanted to read and I don't know
what happened but I updated my iPhone
and I feel like my saved messages folder
disappeared I don't know where some
messages went so if you feel like you've
sent me a really good email and I didn't
read it on the show feel free to send it
to me again I may have lost it I may
have missed it I don't know what
happened feel free to bombard me with
your emails about the podcast cuz I
would love to get your message on the
show I don't want to miss anybody I've
got a lot of emails stacked up here I am
working my way through the pile alright
ladies and gentleman this is the part of
the podcast where I remind you about
patreon if you felt like this podcast
was worth a couple of bucks
your time and you'd like to contribute
all you need to do is go to
[Music]
patreon.com/scishow
that helps me deliver this podcast to
you for free if you're unable to
contribute keep listening
I still love you I just know there are
people out there that do want to
contribute and help the show so for all
the information go to
patreon.com/scishow on tape I truly do
appreciate your help and support
also if you contribute to patreon and
you've got a question that you'd like me
to read let me know on patreon or let me
know through email that you've
contributed to patreon and send me an
email and let me know say hey I just
contributed on your patreon campaign and
I have got an email that I would like
you to read on the show and chances are
your email will get moved right to the
top of the list also if you've already
contributed to patreon and I have not
read your email let me know and I will
dig through the pile and make sure
you're next alright don't forget that I
have put up the first 100 episodes on
YouTube that's right a lot of old
episodes are falling out of the feed I'm
doing the throwback Thursday episodes
I've done so many that those are now
falling out of the feed I've put the
first 100 episodes on YouTube the first
20 are on the old Agriculture Channel
all of the others are up on the grill
from your heart podcast YouTube channel
go to youtube search for the girl from
your heart podcast subscribe check out
the videos I think you will appreciate
the old content I would love it if you
follow me on Twitter it's at g f YH
podcast
also make sure you stalk me on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart a podcast and on Instagram I use
my seed company my breeding company name
we are Irie genetics I RIE underscore GE
and ET I see s give me a follow there
let me know you're listening to the
podcast check out my wonderful cannabis
photography I think there's something
there that you will enjoy ladies and
gentlemen if you'd like to say something
or convey a message and you're not into
the social media or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review or if
you'd like to sponsor the show you can
reach me through email it's girl from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
to hear from you that's all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in
just a few days with episode number 250
I want
give you a huge shout out to Tom Petty
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I'll take you
there's something I used to say she
don't give a damn for me let me get
[Music]
to be
[Applause]
[Music]
I woke up
so let's get to the point
the job
[Music]
[Applause]
some
[Music]
[Applause]
you