[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 250 of the
growth of your heart podcast your a
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right a peer a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
and the mystic roots man to let me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen across the table
from me covered in sweat bright red I
putting on his headphones and recovering
from a giant dab it's white Mike welcome
to the show bro hey man thanks for
joining me
yeah yeah you said too long you just
took a choker of a dab over there I uh
I'd be dying right now but I lo tempted
a little too far that's perfect cuz I
didn't need you tied to the intro the
show I used to that double bucket of
yours
oh the the thermal banger yeah I'm not
used to the thermal banger had I cooked
my regular banger that long I would have
taken a ridiculously hot dab and I did
yes it does take a little extra heat but
the dab you get off of the thermal
banger with with the bubble cap without
the bubble cap that thing's useless cat
Rex you uh
such a great great dab welcome to the
show brother yeah you took a nice sub
already davon over there that was some
massive cherries from our material out
of three rivers and process by CSC so
it's the critical mass and the black
cherry brandy gether it tastes delicious
thanks for the debut gave me so good
yeah yeah that's good stuff good good
job to our friends over at CSC I like to
start the show you always by letting
people know what I'm smoking on so today
we're smoking on the massive cherry
we're also gonna take some dabs of some
platinum tangi here in a minute we will
also smoke some start out pho wax we got
a whole bunch of good stuff yes we do
it's gonna be a fun party for some
reason I'm feeling a little I I don't
feel a hundred percent super good like a
weird migraine thing happenin I tried to
try to have some water and some snacks
and I shook most of it the dabs kind of
made it go away but yeah I haven't felt
100% today but we're gonna I noticed
when I as a musician I noticed something
you can feel like [ __ ] where you can be
too intoxicated or you could just be
having a problem but as soon as you get
your instrument going and the music
starts playing all that [ __ ] disappears
I want to hit play and heard the intro
music I know this what I mean yeah I was
like no my headache just kind of faded
away for a minute yeah so yeah all that
good stuff will make it go away
episode 250 like this is almost muscle
memory yeah but I'm not you know no no
that's not what I'm getting at but like
it's something that you do
love so yes as soon as you start doing
it your body remembers wise like you
enjoy it here's the podcast table we
know how to do this
throw some dopamine and a little
adrenaline actually to get you through
yes yes um so how do we want to start
episode 250 I want to start I just wrote
a note on my hand I've got a whole list
of notes and then I wrote one more note
on my hand ladies and gentlemen this is
episode number 250 welcome to the
podcast if this is your first podcast if
this is your first episode of the girl
from your heart podcast you've ever
listened to or if this is the two
hundred and fiftieth episode of the girl
from your heart podcast you've ever
listened to welcome to the show and
thank each and every one of you for
listening I am thank you so much I'm
stoked to have made it this far it's
huge to what you said it was gonna be
episode 250 I was like I don't care what
I have to do I have to be on that show I
think you were on the first episode
weren't you Oh No number one it was
Kevin Kevin is on number one and I'm
pretty sure I was on number two I wasn't
around quite yet all right I think I
don't came just a little bit later
my timelines a little fuzzy since the
head injury some stuff I remember it but
Dad all the pieces I've got fifty or so
hours a show on top of that in my head
just from going back listened old stuff
again on Thursdays how many episodes do
you think you've been on oh okay
nice nice um let's see we're recording
on ten seven seventeen I just want to
mention that for archive purposes I
don't know why I wrote that down but I
want to I want to mention that what day
ten said well you know what I wrote that
down on ten seven there's ten nine I
think let me pull up the look on Mike's
face when I said ten seven he's like oh
[ __ ] what happened I heard 10 17 and I
was like no it's the [ __ ] not no we got
a harvest too soon yeah I can't have
three harvests in their room I hate to
start a podcast with sad news but uh man
we lost rough week we lost one of the
greats
mr. Ralphie may one of the best
comedians on the planet in my opinion
Ralphie May passed of cardiac arrest
Ralphie may have been struggling with
pneumonia if you know Ralphie May he was
also quite large he had been cleaning up
his act he was eating better he was off
drugs all he did was smoke weed she hung
out with Joey Diaz and did
he shows in Las Vegas he was a resident
comedian in Vegas and they found him
dead
shallots Ralphie May I did get to see
Ralphie at comedy work South not the
small downtown club I think my first
Comedy Works experience but was either
Doug Benson or Ralphie may I not sure
which one happened first
but Ralphie mate was a great show there
was a heckler in that show and I've
never seen a comedian [ __ ] destroy a
heckler like that Ralphie may must have
planned he it was like he know that like
when you get to his status you've got a
few in your pocket ready right got
anybody who messes with you Jay he he
crushed that [ __ ] heckler rolled them
up into a little ball rolled them down
the bowling lane got a [ __ ] strike
and then took a breath and back to my
bit now and just [ __ ] crushed his act
just like he was like he didn't yeah he
didn't miss a [ __ ] beat Ralphie mate
was known as a partier Ralphie may like
to eat some mushrooms and smoke a little
weed one of my favorite Joey cocoa Diez
stories involves Ralphie baby I'm just
gonna summarize here because it's a
great story
hi and if you don't listen to anything
with Joey Diaz you should he's offensive
so be forewarned I hope you like it as
much as I do
Joey Diaz tells a story about performing
in a comedy club and a girl had cocaine
and if you know anything about Joey Diaz
and cocaine I think he was more into the
cocaine than the girl but this girl had
some cocaine and he took her into a
walk-in freezer in this restaurant and
he says I was eating a monkey he was
putting coke rocks in her vagina and
snorting them out and they got caught by
the manager he was smooth enough to
stick the bag of coke
I don't promote drug use but this is
what Joey does and he's a [ __ ] adult
so Joey
steals the cocaine and sticks it in a
sock and dips and he runs upstairs and
he tells Joe Rogan a rogue and I just
got myself in trouble I need to get the
[ __ ] out of here Joe Rogan hands him a
hundred dollar bill and tells him good
luck bro so Joey Di starts walking on
the street like you're gonna get the
[ __ ] out of here I'm not sure what I'm
gonna do and Ralphie May drives by or
walks by and he tells him Ralphie get
the car jack get the car and he's like
Coco I got [ __ ] to do and he's like get
the [ __ ] car jack and so finally
[ __ ] Ralphie gets the car and picks up
uncle Joey and they drive off and
[ __ ] Ralphie May rescued uncle Joey
that's one of their many stories they've
told together on the podcast but that's
a crazy
glad my life paths never took me into
their life paths because honestly like I
think I would throw myself down that
path a lot harder than is survivable I
got lucky I purposefully ducked pretty
much everything but weed in psychedelics
until I knew myself well enough to know
that anything that picked me up and gave
me a bunch more energy was something I
needed a [ __ ] away from yeah I don't
like those kind of feelings psychedelics
were my friend for quite a while of
course I went to a bunch of fish shows
and I'm a Deadhead and I'm into that
side of life so I've I've done my fair
share of DMT and more than my I've done
your share of LSD along with mine I've
done a lot of people if you never done
acid and you're not into it I did yours
for you you'll be just fine
don't worry somebody had that handle
yeah but that was like the 90s and early
2000s and [ __ ] so that's way in the past
but I never got into like the cocaine
and the other weird drugs like the
psychedelics I like to be [ __ ] whoo
and I don't feel like that I never
thought those were is uh I don't know I
never saw people digging through
dumpsters to get a hit acid you know
right that's not you don't get it what
are you gonna do Friday I'm gonna need
some acid we can do Monday I'm gonna be
back to a normal person and go to work
right I have to keep my job up so that
my apartment can still be mine yeah yeah
but when you're playing in the band and
they're paying you an acid then it gets
a little those lines blur I that's one
of the things that like non-drug
consuming people often don't realize is
that like 98 percent of drug consumers
you would have no idea consume drugs
right like beet because they just do it
occasionally recreationally it's not
something that drives their existence or
that they promote regularly everybody's
got a job everybody's got
responsibilities we've got a friend who
has a name that is a name of an
inanimate object and his name got
brought up today and somebody was
actually talking about the inanimate
object and somebody's like do you mean
this guy and I'm not no I'm an object
not person but it's funny that you say
that that guy's [ __ ] cool oh you know
him and they started talking about his
rampant drug use and I was like yeah
dude does a bunch of [ __ ] drugs but
you'd never know he goes to work he's
not a piece-of-shit drug user but and
that person had to think about their
what their
yeah you know what he does do every drug
on the [ __ ] planet but he doesn't lie
cheat or steal and he's not like
addicted anything he just does drugs on
Friday he gets really [ __ ] up every
Friday on throughout the week he
maintains a [ __ ] life but the only
one anybody ever discusses or that
anybody really sees out in public is
booze like everyone knows 50 people that
drink regularly fairly heavily but it
doesn't influence or [ __ ] up their life
in any dramatic ways like sure [ __ ]
might be a little better if they didn't
do that but they get up every morning
they go to work they come home they have
dinner on the table for the family they
go to bed they get up and do it all
again the next day they go fishing on
the weekends or to Little League or
whatever the [ __ ] and no one no one has
any issue with it because it's not
impacting anyone else yep just in a
negative way they're maintaining and you
see it all the time with regular like
that's why hey I was watching a bunch of
anti-pot videos yesterday so it's kind
of on my mind but why are you watching
anti-pot videos know your enemy okay you
have to know what they're talking about
so you know it's gonna pop up on our
radar is the shitty anti pop people are
railing about today is the stuff we're
dealing with in regulation 18 months
from now okay but they don't understand
it all the history here or the the
numbers involved in the number of people
involved um when you listen to him rant
as far as you can tell marijuana is
something we invented around 2000 like
99 2000 it just appeared we manufactured
this high THC cush yeah a bunch of
people who wanted to get rich off an
addiction for-profit industry just and
showed up with it and started marketing
the children
but the reality is it's always been here
through all human history cannabis has
been around countless drugs have been
around and for most of that time most of
the consumers have had other [ __ ] they
had to take care of all day and just did
so occasionally for enjoyment and we
went nuts with it 80 years ago and here
we are today because we were afraid of
Colored People raping white [ __ ]
that's a big part of it Nestle - money
money money and votes money and fear and
votes and control let us do what we want
we don't hurt ourselves
well some of us will meet ourselves out
right before we get too far hard left
people sorry about that that's around
I'll bring you right back on course
before we get too far this podcast is
brought to you by our good friends at
the dank team comm that's right if
you're looking to add some regular or
feminized seeds to your garden then dank
team comms where you can find alpha
chronic mile-high can't event your IRA
Genetics rare dankness the callee
connection you're showing me something
with a lotta Lotta labs Sin City while
you're ready this is all that I was
trying to repeat the old ad from the
early episodes but I'm not sure who's
still on there anyway a very reputable
and trustworthy breeders on there I
would highly recommend to get it highly
recommend at the dank team.com
do it up let him know Rasta Jeff since
you let them know you're listening to
the girl from heart podcast
they've got regular they've got
feminized seeds I highly suggest some
IRA genetics or some rare dankness or
maybe even some mile-high or you know
who's also really [ __ ] cool got some
seeds on there probably by now hopefully
sour seeds is available on there check
out sour seeds get yourself a pack of
sour see if they got that storm shadow
from my region etics that's a really
good cross that's white widow cross to
arise oh yeah Storm Shadow
just like the old school alright so
let's see we recorded recover Ralphie
May we covered the dank team ad bro look
how far we have gone 250 episodes did
you go I'm just been a rough week like
we lost Tom Petty we lost Ralphie May
yes Tom Petty got a shattered on the
last episode feels like I'm missing
somebody if I miss anyone so don't don't
make anybody else die with your Bobby
curses I don't know no I lost one of my
dogs this week too I'm sorry about that
week RAAA she's just been a crazy has a
heavy last couple of days you're talking
about to past week I'm talking about the
past 250 episodes bro remember when we
started this and it sounded like it
sound like this in the background won't
sound like that yeah yeah we didn't have
any compression everything sounded like
[ __ ] and now we got there was none of
these blinking lights to look at I
couldn't watch the green bubbles go up
and down with the level of my voice and
now we sound all smooth like we are NPR
and it sounds nice and crisp
even like big-name people that do
podcasting now when I listen to most
other shows like man they do Jeff doing
their sound yeah if your podcast is
recorded like through your phone or if
you've got a call and guessed half the
time I won't listen and I just can't
deal with it it's got to be quality
people want to hear quality people
deserve quality like dude honestly it it
didn't like neither of us are
engineering experts or [ __ ]
electronic equipment experts like you
you were in the band you know a lot more
about this than your average Joe but
[ __ ] google it listen to cliff
ravenscraft errs on the first minute
seeing shadows' okay well then that's a
good I was gonna talk about how proud
and grateful I am to have done 250
episodes do we start it sounded like
[ __ ] I figured you do like eight and
give it up we get like 5,000 downloads
every time I put out a new episode
within the first 48 hours of really
sending in a new episode I get about
5,000 downloads I bounce between super
proud of that number and super like
scared of that number don't be scared
does every now and on already sick dude
you've said some insane [ __ ] and like
5000 people downloaded that show at
least yeah um some of the shows that
we've done that we're super in-depth
some of the numbers you've told me I'm
like oh Jesus so you know the Fillmore
auditorium in Denver yep we filled that
twice yeah that's how many people heard
that twice that right like I never would
have said that on stage in a room full
of people but it's just you and me and
your little recording space like we're
so comfortable here at this point thanks
for joining us you guys I am grateful
and I'm proud to have done 250 episodes
so awesome I'm gonna keep keep bringing
you more great content I feel like I've
become a good ambassador for cannabis
I'm trying to be a good representative
for this planet and share it with
everybody in a good positive way so
thank you guys I'm proud of myself and
proud of all the guests and I'm grateful
and I kind of want to thank all of the
guests that have been on here but I
don't want to miss anybody so I don't
want to try to say too many names but of
course Mike Robb from sour seeds
everybody back in the day like Adam
Kevin and Jesse um Mike mentioned a
minute ago cliff ravenscraft if you guys
are into podcasting and you need help
getting your podcast going cliff
ravenscraft is a guy who calls himself
the podcast Answer Man if you go and
check out his website all of his free
stuff will improve your podcast it's
free I just check out what he does he's
kind of on a new thing he's gotten bored
with helping everybody get a podcast
going he's on a new thing but his old
stuff is still there and it will teach
you so much and it's all there's a lot
of free content he does want you to pay
for some I've never paid for anything
and I've learned [ __ ] plenty from
that dude there's a ton of information
that honestly if you're doing a podcast
regularly and you haven't started
looking for people like him to kind of
help improve your show this way that and
it's not like oh every 30 seconds do
something funny it's not that he's real
no there's a lot of really good
information on bringing together a
tighter show a more informative show a
better produced show how to get more
listeners based on your metadata just a
lot of tricks
yeah really should be he makes a
six-figure income off of podcasting he's
recorded more podcasts than anybody else
he was one of the first podcasters to
have a real podcast on iTunes
anyway that's cliff ravenscraft check
him out I highly endorse him thanks
cliff you'll never listen to my show
probably but thank you um a big big
support and of course everybody that's
been here is where I was the garden of
Weeden crew all of them sloppy when
sloppy used to come and kick it sloppy
was on the show but sloppy spent more
time on more episodes over there at the
dab table just chillin so sloppy's been
on a few times Joe has been here a few
times granny
um so many people have been here the
people that granny brought with her
every time all of the places that have
let me do a show in their location like
of course the canna Canyon shout out to
our friends at the can of Canyon because
I don't want to miss anybody shout out
to Addison demora he was on like episode
number two or three I dropped a clip
Addison I big shout out to addy addy
just lost his dad so big shout to Haddie
we gotta send him some strong support
also and people are falling lately this
is getting weird Jesus it's been a weird
couple of months man but I I owe
everybody a big thanks if you've been on
the show thank you if you listen to the
show thank you also
more people I need to give a huge thank
you to on episode number 250 everybody
who has ever sponsored this podcast
everybody from oil slick to highly
educated titanium to elevate glass I'm
not sure who else
of course the dank team they still
sponsored the podcast they still helped
us out you can get your IRA genetic
seeds at the dank team com make sure you
check that out they've got that they've
probably got the scarlet begonias which
is the redheaded stranger across to
arise I would look and see if they've
got that if they don't email me and
we'll fix it they should have a rise
also um may all the sponsors who have
ever our friends at PL grow systems big
shout out to PL grow systems and pretty
sure that's what they call it
I can see PL grow there's something over
the rest of the box I can't read the
name PL grow but shout out to those
folks for sponsoring the show and
sending us products to review the
grinder folks that have sent us grinders
to review everybody our friends at gmail
I emo Tech for the gene/l that I keep
hot all of the time big shout out to
everybody that sponsored the podcast I
know I said it want someone to say it
another time our friends at elevate
glass at 5:17 South Daytona and Colorado
Springs I owe them a huge shout out
anyway big big shout out to everybody
that sponsored the show I appreciate all
the support all the continued support of
course if you want to sponsor the show
send me an email to grow from your heart
at hotmail.com also big shout out to all
the haters I love each and every one of
you
also I need to give a huge shout out to
folks like oh we missed the barefoot
grower shut up - will what's up dude - I
didn't mean to miss you what a bunch
handmade how did I miss you guys I
apologize I just looked down and I'm
like I'm gonna drop a couple of names
big shout out to Kelvin Medina and rich
me Lohan and a few people like that you
guys know who you are
um but big shout out to my friends there
were a couple times when I was like guys
I don't feel good I'm sick as [ __ ] I
need help doing a podcast and Adam and
Mike and Kevin all showed up maybe Jesse
a whole bunch of people showed up one
night and we did a podcast I basically
sat here and looked at everybody and
nodded and ran knobs cuz I didn't feel
good but you guys put out a podcast for
me so thanks to all my friends that
support the podcast thanks to all my
friends that share the podcast not just
the people that come over to the house
and record not just the people that hang
out at the Dada table not just the
people that I work with that support me
but my friends out there all my social
media friends the people that I interact
with online the people that I don't
interact with
line on line but I tried to because I'm
overwhelmed with all that stuff
I've sent a couple of names I don't know
who wants the names set on the show
people but I feel like I don't want to
stop and go back to make a list Al and
he made some seed then he shared some
seeds with me I don't know if he wants
his name said but shout out to that guy
he knows who he is much respect Doug
Doug one of my favorite episodes I did
was with yeah old Doug is [ __ ]
awesome big shout-out to Doug Doug I
don't know if you listen dude but much
much love and respect there are a lot of
people that I want to mention but it's
hard to remember everybody's name all
the people that helped me out thank you
thank you so much you guys big shout out
to everybody of course I owe a huge
thank you to the always lovely always
beautiful miss Jenny Beth she's patient
she lets me get my podcast done ah there
she needs me
she needs my attention and it takes me a
little bit of time to get this done so
shout out uh what else we got all the
listeners that trust me you guys that uh
that you send me questions and you count
on me do you take city advice to take
advice you heard on a podcast yeah take
it into your own garden and try it on
your children your children exactly go
exactly ah I feel like part of what made
me start this podcast was I was reading
a bunch of [ __ ] on forums people
would say oh you've got this kind of bug
shake up a mountain Dew and spray that
on your leaves and they would mean it
and I've got good what the [ __ ] are you
doing I would people would tell me like
oh just grab this random thing out of
your house grind it up and dump it in
the pot and it's like what or somebody
told me half a jar of molasses per
gallon holy piss all you need for food
and it's like what what what's going on
it's something that grows yeah just pour
half into 1 gallon and half into the
other and make it hot hot water and then
stir it up and pour it into your plans
Wow and that was advice I was sincerely
given as though that was the trick they
were using to make their yeah a lot of
the things I would see online I would I
would see that just causing two more
problems yeah sure you just got rid of
your bugs now you've got sticky ass
Mountain Dew on the top so your leaves
now you're gonna get more bugs stuck to
bat and your believes gonna look like
[ __ ] that's gonna cause a more prompt
don't ever put Mountain Dew on your
plants you guys it was a terrible joke
don't do that [ __ ] but that's part of
why I wanted to do
Podcast also I wanted to write a book I
was like I'm gonna write a weed book and
then I'll say get book changes every
week I can't even do that weed changes
cannabis changes the industry changes
the rules change
oops I couldn't write a book every time
I'd write the outline I'd look up
something well that's wrong now I gotta
update this a podcast is cool cuz it
evolves every 7 or 5 days in my world
like an update you guys be like you
remember what I said six months ago
wrong new tech do this yep so we found
it a better way or a more efficient way
or cheaper way yeah but thanks to
everybody that trusts me because a lot
of people send me I've got you can see
all these emails are in this folder
people send me stacks of emails and that
means that those folks trust me they
know that the information I give them is
gonna be well thought out they know the
information I give them will be tried
and true and they know that ah I am not
selling them a product sometimes I will
recommend some [ __ ] there's some things
that you can buy that will help solve
your problem it's what you're gonna need
it's what that's the best way to do it
but I am not paid by any nutrient
companies I'm not paid by any pesticide
companies there's no money coming my way
from anybody right now honestly for this
mod you guys can hear it in the show
like if you listened to other shows you
can tell when someone's a brought to you
by cheeseburgers that's part of what
inspired this podcast also there was
another weed podcast bit in the first
half of the episode he would read emails
well I've got spider mites what do I do
and he'd he'd say well I would go to the
store and buy product a and then turn
off the lights and spray the [ __ ] out of
product and your problem will be gone
and then he would go on and act like the
show is natural and then 30 minutes
minutes into the show they'd go well now
we're gonna take a break and then the ad
would come up this podcast brought to
you by product a like oh is that why you
recommended product at the start of the
[ __ ] show because they paid you money
it was a fake email nobody had that
problem you made that [ __ ] up so that
you could pitch that product to make
somebody I don't do that you guys I
don't yeah I'm not trying to make some
money off of products oh I want you to
be able to do it for free if it's
possible I'll tell you what I use and
you didn't use that and it's not know
here's the tips and tricks that he's
using personally and it's in since
success with it's not getting
recommended because there's a percentage
on it yeah it's totally what I would use
like I mentioned like products like
grande Evo and evergreen and cease
things like that we actually use in
commercial cultivation facilities that's
what I would recommend all of the time
well it's today
we had a guy ask you what what do you
think about ladybugs
you gave verbatim the same answer I mean
not work forward but incredibly close
that you gave on the podcast three four
months ago yeah here's what we use
here's where you can get them here's why
this superior to ladybugs yeah because
in the Doozers blown away his eyes got
really big and I could see them like it
seemed to take his phone out and start
writing [ __ ] down yeah ladybugs are cute
you guys but most of them end up in your
ducting and in your shop vac ladybugs
are they're great for photography but I
don't think they're gonna do it get some
sworsky mites those are gonna do you
much better it's gonna do a lot better
work for you but thank you guys for
trusting me that means a lot to me and I
know that you trust me because you
continue to send me emails you continue
to interact with me you continue to
tweet me a lot of you continue to send
me messages on the Instagram and you
keep listening to the podcast so that
lets me know it's working thank you that
means a lot to me I do put a lot of work
into this podcast it sounds like you
just hit record and you talk but I've
got pages and pages of notes and
thousands of dollars in gear so there's
a lot going into it so it's good to know
that it's worth all the effort to you
guys sometimes we do just get really
high in hit record but the only reason
we're able to do that is cuz two years
of homework went into being able to do
that yeah this isn't gonna be one of
those shows where you need to get out
your notebook this is not gonna be one
we could turn it into one but it'd be a
real dick move it doesn't just hide it
at the end make it like any super tricks
no no we're not gonna do that to you
guys this is gonna be number 250 I'm in
it I feel much better you guys when I
started this podcast I honestly felt
like [ __ ] Mike's like dude if you want
to call it we can Mike there's no reason
I handed you hash the taste like cherry
I drink two bottles of water and the
second one has a packet of emergency in
it vitamin C in electrolytes and then I
ate a bowl of noodles and a handful of
snacks and that really put me back on my
game and then just getting talking
really got me gone I feel a lot better
now so thanks for bringing me back out
of my coma bro yeah but what I was gonna
say was since it's episode 215 were
chatting our faces off we're gonna take
a couple of fat now a couple of seconds
it's gonna take a couple seconds to get
to that cuz I know that's gonna
understand I can't see your list
just occurred to me that I wanted to I
send a huge shout out to all the people
that have emailed the show over the
years and all the people who were
thinking about emailing the show in the
future the last couple episodes like I
haven't been in over here on a show and
I can't even tell you how long bearaoke
Telus but I could get it to Barry shut
up Barry you're awesome man
I was so happy to get that tweet from
you I've been itching to get back over
here but the last couple shows that
we're heavy email-based
were really really good I loved the
parenting show and I know that's not a
show that dawns on you without that
prompt from the the listener and it's
not exactly I wouldn't have called you
and been like dude let's do a parenting
show right even though I'm a new parent
yeah I'm thinking about that [ __ ] all
the time I had a couple of friends who
are parents they're like what the [ __ ]
dude I should have been on that show yep
like and I know I know but I I know
sometimes I can't I can't get everybody
on the podcast all the time sometimes
honestly I want sure I know what day I
wanna record my goal is to record on
Thursday I liked it but sometimes it'll
be Tuesday night and I can't sleep and
I'll be [ __ ] it here we go and I'll just
get a record a show at midnight and I'll
just record it just because I'm in the
mood and I feel like podcasting is get
maybe maybe not everybody would feel
this way I feel like it's kind of like
music it's kind of like an art and if
I'm in the mood to do it I should do it
cuz it's gonna come out way better than
when I'm not in the mood I'm sure you
guys have heard well at least one or two
episodes and I'm like I had [ __ ] on
this episode [ __ ] phoning it in
[ __ ] you here's a show there's been a
couple of those there were a couple
shows were like we just couldn't trim
anymore yeah we needed a long break like
go and grab a bite to eat and come back
and get back to work wasn't gonna cut it
so we did that and then we did a show
and then we chilled for a little bit and
then we got back to work let the highs
uncross yep
let the hands on cramp and just sit in
show for a minute see I shot it to
everybody that emails us all we do
appreciate all of the interaction even
though I can't respond to all of you I
apologize dude it is I work a 40-plus
hour a week job plus I've got my eye i
am i read genetics i run that company as
well plus I've got the podcast plus I've
got my own personal relationships plus
I'm a father that should have been way
higher on that [ __ ] West I apologize
but I've got a lot going on oh yeah I
just feel like dude I'm getting emails
from one of the bosses I'm getting
emails from an applicant oh yeah and my
emails from the bosses never stop our
boss is we it's my kids bedtime plus 12
minutes so like I should be doing
storytime right now I am the lead
cultivator at Three Rivers and Mike is
the metric guy at Three Rivers so we
stay busy with emails from bosses he's
in front of the house I'm the back of
the house we meet in the middle and talk
about a lot of stuff all the time so we
do get a lot of emails we're involved
with every decision made well we try to
be involved with every decision made
with that business so we do stay
completely busy bleep well we do
interact I interact with as many of the
emails as I can so a lot of times I just
get at you when I'm pooping or falling
asleep or whatever I do what I can
I'm trying but I appreciate it it
doesn't go unnoticed I print most of the
good emails and how honestly when I come
over and join those shows it doesn't
help cuz let's try to do three emails
this show becomes like we got through
most of an email this show yeah you get
a little chatter you wanna get you high
but I'm good with that
hey it's working because like I'm gonna
segue into my next bullet point nice and
smoothly here this week on stitcher we
are ranked 595 fresh overall yeah there
are a lot of shows on stitcher I was
trying to research how many I in one
section I saw 25,000 in another section
they boast 40,000 shows like 40,000
titles of different shows are available
on stitcher I don't know which is true
if somebody wants to do the real
research and find out and tweet me send
me a tweet it's @gf wih podcast let me
know cuz that way I don't have to search
for it and I can put that energy into a
good show the part of that question I
like is that for your show it doesn't
matter so much if there are 20,000 or
40,000 because you're better than all
about 540 M
and also I was hyping myself up I was
like I want to be on that top 100 but
then I thought about like we're a
cannabis show like we're a very niche
I've got a very niche show here it
depends where you look at it the
cannabis consuming population is
somewhere between like 10 and 25% of the
population is like everybody's good yes
my real guess is that you'll take a
couple hits at a concert or yeah a few
times a year is closer to 40% but I mean
even then that's why I kept pushing it
it's not like other [ __ ] that where
they're pulling twenty million views a
week right the amount of people that
listen to podcasts and the amount of
people that smoke cannabis and the
amount of people that actually give a
[ __ ] enough about cannabis to listen to
a podcast that's kind of a small pocket
right well there but one thing I've
noticed my demographic is the exact same
on my Instagram feed as it is on my
podcast
most of the people are from Denver to
Los Angeles report hland and 80 percent
of them are men and most of them are men
between length 21 and 35 it's mostly
who's listening to my podcast so what's
up guys
hi ladies I don't have to leave you out
I got your female friends to listen to
the show
I get it I don't draw the ladies I'm not
a lady magnet that's alright with me if
they could see the Chewbacca costume I
think things would be different
anyway I was ranked we were ranked the
show was ranked not me as my podcast
who's number 39 and lifestyle and health
on stitcher radio yeah and number 39 and
the lifestyle and health category so
thank you guys for listening on stitcher
I appreciate it
also thanks for all the wonderful
comments on iTunes I still have not
gotten anything but 5-star reviews - yes
episode 215 nothing but five stars you
know what's what's uh what's awkward
about that they don't list you in a lot
of [ __ ] until you get a negative review
because like who cares about all these
positive reviews you have to get a
negative one to fall under their
algorithm nobody knows yeah yeah because
it's like you're just trolling now right
now I'm fake just beg for it
well maybe my hope five stars all around
you guys good doing it real I'm doing
keep the streak alive do we need to edit
that out
you just taunted a little bit please do
not do it because come on I like that
five-star rating that's awesome
um what else do I want to say Thursday
shows you guys are you listening to the
throwback Thursday episodes that I put
out every Thursday
I've been putting out what I call the
throwback Thursday episodes let me
explain how who what when where why and
how I'm doing all that what happens is
iTunes and stitcher hold 100 episodes in
the feed being that this is episode
number 250 that means there's a hundred
and fifty episodes that you don't get to
listen to because they're not in the
feed what I'm doing for you because I
love you guys
I'm making old episodes in two large
three or four hour chunks hey Mike you
got some smart action from his heart I
love you anyhow I'm taking old episode
really does give up his computer for
like six hours per Thursday show so we
can post that [ __ ] to all this all the
streams cuz it's three three hours and
change usually like it's yeah the long
show yeah it's usually like three maybe
four sometimes five episodes ever back
it's perfect yeah yeah and people that
have long jobs that are at work all day
they love it but I take old episodes and
I put them in chunks ah that way instead
of putting one episode in the feed I can
give you like four episodes put them
back into the feet and you can listen to
that old [ __ ] without knocking out a
bunch of new content you get to go back
and listen so that's what's happening on
the Thursday shows so all the Thursday
episodes are old ah there's something
else I want to mention and that but I
don't know which order to do this also
on YouTube I'm putting up old episodes
on YouTube because YouTube doesn't limit
how much content I put up by the time
this comes out there will be close to a
hundred I kept saying a hundred episodes
episode 100 is scheduled to release
within the next couple of days it's up
there it's in my YouTube feed but it has
not released it like 99 and 100 need to
come out but they're there so all I have
to do is wait for that scheduled time to
come out I've got them set up on YouTube
to do that so check out the girl from a
horror podcast YouTube channel the first
20 shows are on the iGrow culture
podcast channel remember when the show
is called I grow culture so when I first
started you guys the first at first 50
episodes we were called I grow culture
but there's apparently a
an educational program called
agriculture that teaches college-level
agriculture courses and they didn't like
my little weed podcast ripping off their
name though so we quickly changed that
to the girl from your heart podcast once
we add resistant once they said hey
we've already got that I was like a [ __ ]
I don't want your name I want my own
name I just didn't I googled it nothing
came up
yeah there was there's no no harshness
they just send a little things saying
hey by the way that's already taken and
we immediately started working on a new
name yeah and the next I was like on
episode 50 we'll drop the new name and
we did that so the first 20 episodes are
on the old agriculture feed 21 through
whatever 99 or 100 now they're like a
hundred and five episodes in that feed
but only the first 99 or so available
those are on the growth from your heart
feed on YouTube so search for that click
subscribe follow us there once I get
enough videos caught up I may put up
other random videos like other stuff
that's not actually podcast episodes I
may put that up on that channel just
pictures me doing random [ __ ] but I want
to get caught up first that's a little
bit ways away alright when I talk about
the Thursday shows I said there was
something else I wanted to mention this
is totally random if don't cheat that's
all I'm gonna say if you know me and you
were here when it happened or anything
like that
don't cheat because this is gonna be a
contest I've got a prize 11 [ __ ] at my
car d1 contest is over sorry [ __ ] oh
here's another contest I got another
idea Mike you get a prize it's a kick in
the dick oh here comes the magical radio
I do ever prize them and I'm not gonna
tell you what the prize is because it
depends on your location and your age if
you were here in Colorado it's [ __ ]
cooler than it is if you're in [ __ ]
Delaware but sorry Delaware you're
getting t-shirts on the Thursday
episodes during the intro music there
are several voices hidden in there
several voices yes there's a voice
backwards if you can tell me who the
backwards voice is I will give you a
prize also there's one that goes oh [ __ ]
Rasta Jeff in the house if you can tell
me who that is I will give you a prize
do not [ __ ] cheat if you were here if
you know don't tell anybody that's a
dick move don't cheat I want not
cheaters to win this prize
I have no idea yeah people are gonna
listen and maybe somebody'll know maybe
somebody'll figure it out 11 cat are the
answers those are the answers
it's and unless you have a friend named
11 and we do have a friend named cat but
that is not who we have a friend in 44
yes we do yes so I guess 11 wouldn't be
that strange of a name no 11 would have
been better than 44 if you know why he's
called 44 anywho but there's a prize and
then I'm not promising you what the
prize is but I'll send you something if
you if you nail one of those there's a
backwards thing if you can nail who the
backwards voices and then if you could
tell me who says oh [ __ ] and two chances
to win the world on the backwards ones
is it gonna be if you can tell me what
they say front words you get a bonus
prize cuz that's a [ __ ] challenge
there's the backwards voice to identify
identify what they said and then a
totally different voice says oh [ __ ]
Rasta Geoff in the house identify that
voice there's a prize in it for you and
is this mixed into all the interest for
the Thursday episodes or just one
specific that they got to go find um
it's uh I think I used the same one on
episode 240 let me I'm gonna look in my
phone you talk for a second about
something I'm gonna go look in the phone
here and we'll see which two episodes
they're throwback Thursday it's about
well they can't be too far behind I just
don't wanna be wrong on the number I
think it's 48 and for 248 and to 46 but
my phone's opening it up right now I
better turn down I don't want it to go
plan through the [ __ ] I was listening
to the Joe Rogan podcast with Whitney
Cummings on it last is what it looks
like I was listening to nice throwback
Thursday number 248 as the episodes ooh
what if I just play right now
don't don't but then that would give
okay alright then Mike said don't do it
you guys know you gotta got it you show
a little initiative if you want to win
the prize oh [ __ ] I'd go listen to that
yeah the prices match if you're over 21
you live near me the price gets much
[ __ ] cooler trust me yeah there's
some imaginary lines that limit prize
capabilities that's the truth that's the
truth
um well bullet point or a nice have um
my next bullet point is shitty so you
take a tiny flow dab on here you don't
want this
take that dab and then I will talk about
this bad news I've got and then we I
will take another dab after that okay
here is the rig do we want to pause and
dab no we'll just keep doing this isn't
number 250 we haven't done [ __ ] yet so
why are we gonna press pause for this so
this the plane engine sound that you're
about to hear that's the tourist I'll
turn down your mic just a little bit so
that you don't hear my cabin and
coughing too much over there
so um I'm gonna talk for a minute well
might gets a dad going for himself there
are a couple of people out there that I
want to talk about for a second I want
to send some love and some white and
some support and some words of
encouragement and a thank you and a
whole lot of stuff all at once many
years ago I stumbled across a guy known
as sub cool there's got they're called
sub : he runs a company called TGA
genetics the Green Avengers team Green
Avengers and sub cool and his wife I'm
not I'm pretty sure that's his wife
known as Miss Jill MZ period Jill miss
Jill are known for breeding some amazing
strains of cannabis I want to give Jill
credit because we're gonna do ladies
first
Jill bred a strain called Jillybean
you've heard me talk about Jilly bean on
this show a whole [ __ ] life you
haven't heard the name so cool in this
Jill but you listen to this show you've
definitely heard about their work and
things they've created so miss Jill has
created the Jilly bean
miss Jill also created Bryan berry cough
Bryan berry cough was made for Jill's
friend Bryan who had a it's not a
disease it's a condition a disorder
called ALS it's a syndrome is what it is
I try to be correct on those types of
things but he had something called
ALS which is a terrible condition
disease correct yeah he was in a
wheelchair and he couldn't control his
body completely and yeah it was it was
sad to watch but Joe loved him they were
friends from school so she bred a
strawberry cough she got Kyle kushman
Strawberry Cough from Kyle and they bred
space dude which is their space clean
male which is the equivalent of my King
Solomon arise it's their version it's
their plant it's not the same strain or
anything understand that's like I've got
the arize I got the space dude it's
thirsty
it's their main thing they bread that
and miss Jill bread that and made the
brine Barry cough for her friend Brian
sub cool
is famous because of mini strains Apollo
13 spacecraft on the way better the void
there are so many good strains that came
from sub cool team T Team Green Avengers
also does Doctor Who the nine pound
hammer a lot of those things are coming
from that camp in that crew you remember
how far we used to drive for vortex yes
I used to drive I live in Pueblo
Colorado there's a dispensary in
Colorado Springs called the clinic it is
at exit 102 or 104 which ones Colorado
we used to go all the way up to Colorado
Boulevard of New Mexico and Denver to
visit the clinic Denver yes and I would
buy all of the vortex hash they had all
that they would let me buy I would buy
all of it that vortex hash was [ __ ]
amazingly delicious there was a trip of
the van was like half-full and we were
all behind you for text yes
just so much just everybody go get the
limit of vortex I'll buy it and then
I'll give you guys a bonus for doing
this for me so anyway if you look at my
photography and if you look at sub
clothes photography it is very obvious
that sub cool inspired my gro style
inspired my photography inspired a lot
of things i pull from a lot of sources
sub cool being one of the main
influences when I started growing he was
just very available yeah he has a show
called the weed nerd where he will teach
you a lot sub cool is the weed nerd 420
on Instagram he's probably live right
now if you want to log on and watch he's
doing something some cool inspired me a
lot miss Jill inspired me a lot
sub cool taught me about breeding sub
cool taught me about growing some cool
the plush beary that I made black cherry
chem with came from sub cool these space
Queen that I made space [ __ ] with came
from sub cool kissing sub cools ass cuz
I love him he inspired me a lot without
sub cool and team green Avengers and
Miss Jill there would be no I read
genetics I would not be who and where I
am today without that inspiration and a
little bit of guidance we spent a lot of
time watching so cool shows and just
learning absorbing learning to think of
things at different ways the first few
times he interacted with me on social
media I didn't know what to do with
myself I was like how do I reply to this
and alike take a moment as I I don't
think he even realizes how much he
inspired me and how much he taught me
and how much I paid attention people
have called me mini-sub cool online
before like it's been a joke for a
little while but we're similar uh and
Ginny says I'm quite like some cool
which i think is funny anyhow what I'm
getting to you guys is sub cool and miss
Jill had a very nice home in California
and the fires destroyed [ __ ]
everything the wild fire in California
has burned down their entire house um so
far at this point in time sub does not
know if the safe that they closed just
before they left they contained all of
the TGA seeds that that safe could be
destroyed they don't know if that exists
or not they can't get back to their
house so this is ongoing as it's not
something that happened already it's
something that's happening yeah the
house burned down a couple of nights ago
they're staying in a hotel I don't know
how much is putting it all on Instagram
live so this is all basically public
info and I want to send some love out to
them it's basically what I'm trying to
gentleman you guys know what's going on
if you've ever so the sub can't get to
the house to find out if those seeds are
even alive you guys the mother plants
that TGA breeds with burned in the fire
all of their plants them their plants
are gone they cannot make strains like
the void vortex it's all gone it's gone
the mother plants that did that the male
plant that did that that [ __ ] doesn't
exist anymore so they're gonna have to
start from scratch unless one of their
friends has a clone of the space dude
because that was what did it all sub and
I were in talks of him sending me a
space dude that was just in that but
that was kinda just that hasn't all
evolved yet and we were gonna do a
collaboration together there's gonna be
a space dude clone here I would have it
I would have it to send back to him when
he gets on his feet
it didn't happen yet [ __ ] sometimes
timing is a [ __ ] sometimes nature is a
[ __ ] because if you've ever grown
anything from sub cool miss Jill team
green Avengers if you've got Doctor Who
9 pound hammer vortex space clean the
void plush Barry there's so many strains
at this high floors prayer that was
tough lesion orange ah there there he's
what's the one I'm thinking of time RAC
blood yeah it's time RAC is élisa élisa
strands that came out of
uga is just intense jackhammer so long
yeah yeah sorry you guys can hear me
shaking up my water on the mic sorry no
didn't see drink here if you guys have
grown any of that stuff you guys owe a
little nod toward TJ at least if you can
do anything if all you can do is go to
Instagram and message miss Jill it's at
miss at miss dot Jill if you search for
miss Jill with a Z you'll find there's
no I it's MZ Jill send them words of
encouragement Jill's having a rough time
with this
Jill's taking it worse than sub cool
subs of [ __ ] soldier sub will not
acknowledge that he's got feelings
because he's a big manly man honestly I
would probably be playing the same
[ __ ] role a sub cool he's powering
forward and trying to work through it
and not deal with it and it's working
for him that's the way men deal with
[ __ ] I get that Jill is not doing well
she's gotta feel the way through it yeah
and she's been in a hotel room for
several days like guys like I'm a guy
I've got dreadlocks and I'm kind of I'm
not pretty I can put on some shorts and
some shoes and tie my dreadlocks in a
[ __ ] giant knot and we can go do
whatever needs to be done
Jill's a woman she needs her woman think
she clean clothes she needs makeup and
[ __ ] she doesn't have any of that it's
not that the report they can't get it
there's a house burned down they're
staying in a [ __ ] hotel scraping by
literally imagine if you went to dinner
tonight like you and whoever you run a
Mickey D's and while you're gone mother
nature takes everything you own that you
didn't have with you in the drive-thru
yeah everything but your dog and the
pipe that you took with you buddy
I mean you know she's just been brutal
the last couple of months but the fires
in California are just the most recent
yet so my point is that [ __ ] sub cool
miss Jill I love you guys talk the dog
lovin bro I hope team tgia recovers from
this and I want to send huge love to one
of my my teachers one of the guys that
inspired me one of the groups that
taught me how to be the grower that I am
I wouldn't run a giant cultivation
facility if I didn't follow the weed
nerd so tightly for years so shout-out
to those guys I I'm down to help however
I can to get you guys back on your feet
if you listen to this I would love to
see you going again stay strong you guys
I don't want to watch you guys get
depressed and crumble through this stay
strong they're badasses you got a whole
bunch of support behind you I hope the
entire cannabis community all the weed
nerds if you follow some cool you're
known as a weed nerd so
we nerd he's the leader the weed nerds
so all the nerds we've got your back
I also shoutout to everybody out there
that's being [ __ ] displaced and
hampered and hindered and made miserable
by all these spires is a terrible
situation in California it's miserable
mindo dope is about to get burned down
also if you know these fires are headed
right for the ELMO triangle right now so
if they haven't already screwed with
people like they've completely just up
turn sub-goals world and that whole crew
they're headed for a lot of others I
mean it's gonna be a really really
really awkward October November December
this year they've been saying there's
too much cannabis in California do you
think this will even it out wasn't
between the mother nature all over the
place the fires in Cali the the humidity
and the moisture and the cold snap here
pretty much anywhere you grow cannabis
this year weather [ __ ] with you harder
in your last couple weeks of bloom
that's gonna [ __ ] with the overall
outdoor harvest this year coast to coast
Dave also in the last like two weeks
they've busted three pretty large
illegal crows down here in southern
Colorado they were doing the same thing
in California I saw somewhere in Oregon
they busted like the biggest one they've
ever busted it was thousands of plants I
mean there's been a lot going after the
crop at the end of this year who knows
what we're looking at it's been a rough
year for cannabis growers too much there
ain't no such thing as too much never
too much cannabis you know the the
outdoor grows they got busted here we're
all ran by cartels is what they're
claiming that's the headline but they
just say that okay um if anybody that
the gross speaks Spanish it's a cartel
grow until everyone's sentenced well
that's [ __ ] up it really is the latest
one they're they're pimping with ties to
Cuba and I've read 50 different news
stories on this kabuki is that your crew
what are you doing every single article
is just a word-for-word repeat of public
ounty Sheriff's Office Facebook post
about the bus
they're just every news agency in
Colorado from the Denver Post to the
cannabis to KOAT to KKTV all of them
copy you've paste the [ __ ] Facebook
post and call that reporting [ __ ]
lazy [ __ ] journalists do you wanna
I'm gonna take a DAB here do you want to
tell them about the guy that shot the
kids in his yard for stealing cannabis
last year um yeah there was a dude in
Denver who got his outdoor ripped by two
teenagers opened fire while they were
running away and he's headed to jail for
80 years
80 years did he kill one of them and
wounded the other yep killed one wounded
180 years for a cannabis plant you guys
don't shoot people if some few people
for your [ __ ] weed yeah grow more next
year you guys plant plant a couple extra
there are a lot of stupid rules in
Colorado and Washington and Oregon and
[ __ ] that you have to follow with
legalization but the one I don't mind so
much is keep it the [ __ ] locked up um
its ripper season right now I know two
or three people that got ripped and are
all wrecked right now because they got
ripped and they're mad and they're
hunting down people and they're on the
lookout for a [ __ ] vehicle and it's
like dude I [ __ ] told you to put it
inside and that I'm a cannabis grower I
was a cannabis grower before I should
admit being a cannabis girl I love
cannabis but that's the [ __ ] that is
keeping it illegal in places they're the
fear of that yeah yeah you know it's
these they're valuable plants you're
putting and you're just setting TVs out
in the backyard basically you know what
I mean like motorcycles a little heavier
you wouldn't create a can of spray paint
and spray paint on the front of your
house I've got ten grand and in cash in
the back poorly defended yeah you're
setting bags of money out there
essential yeah I've got gold bars on my
back patio just so everyone knows like
you're putting a cannabis plant in your
backyard that creates a smell every
single teenager that walks by your house
from early August to late October knows
you're growing every Ripper that's
driving up and down alleyways in
neighborhoods with one dude sitting in
the back of the pickup and one dude
going up to the doors offering lawn
service every now every couple houses so
they don't do shady all summer long
they've got a clipboard in the cab where
they're marking down two dresses with
outdoor grills they can smell then they
come around in October and they clean
your [ __ ] out and it's the most
predictable thing in the world it's one
of the main concerns everybody had under
prohibition you were worried about
rippers and cops in that order
yep and now it's legal and everybody's
like I don't have to worry about the
cops and they completely forgot that
they were a secondary [ __ ] concern
ten years ago and the rippers are your
real problem you don't want to bring
that criminal element to your world
one dude penned over by where I used to
live got shot to death in his front yard
because the three guys he brought in
from Oklahoma to buy his crop that he
couldn't move here decided they'd rather
shoot him and then pay for it like
that's part of the beauty of
legalization is we don't have to mess
with anything that [ __ ] anymore people
you want to narrate my dab it's a
quarter gram or so going into the
thermal banger with the Hitman sidecar
right beneath it it's a little too hot
because Jeff doesn't like pool dabs
can't waste it folks
q-tip texts for rich chumps below it or
fancy girls mmm Angie planted Angie yeah
it tastes delicious if you like a dab of
that yes who drew that that was us over
at Three Rivers that's our growth is
extracted by our friends over at the
craft delicious dad ah delish
the high doesn't like destroy me but it
tastes real it'd be a good breakfast dad
good breakfast I had the realization
that outside of this show I pretty much
just dab at work that's kind of a funny
thing to say that's kind of a funny
thing to say I just dab I got to hide a
[ __ ] podcast correctly I just do this
for just to [ __ ] heat the microphone
I'm an unsafe here are you sure you're
gonna be okay the nail so how many or
two butane how many times slash people
have tried to hit the microphone like it
was the pipe like I'm doing it was my
favorite yeah well of course I've seen
happen a couple of times the room was
full when I
I'm coughing from my dad you guys I'll
recover well Mike we've been going for
nearly an hour here I know you're
heating up add a bit about to take a DAB
and I'm gonna ask you a question before
you hit it since you've got a microphone
and 5,000 people listening is there
anything you want to say well you got a
microphone in your face and we start
wrapping up the podcast thanks for
listening everybody shoot us some love
on Twitter it's at nema 1-15 or at g f
YH podcast yeah we'd love to hear from
you keep sending us emails those make by
far the best shows at this point also
support Mike's Facebook page it's pueblo
for sensible cannabis i've dude i've
been slacking for that so hard on that i
haven't been inspired yet I've been
[ __ ] tired since we started this new
gig go inspire my queen between the new
job in the two-year-old dude I am just
racked Mike's brag do you guys send him
something even on the show anymore good
as I'm so tired
cinema washer to wash the sand out of
his vagina it's it's it's kicking and
prohibitionists are excited that Trump
in sessions are talking a lot of [ __ ]
and so they're coming out of the
woodwork a little bit insane a little
more in public which they kind of didn't
do for the last eight years they learned
it not to but they're kind of coming
back and forth and watching them talking
links makes me want to debunk so that's
what we like about you show me a little
love and that's all the encouragement
I'll need to dive all the way back into
a folks debunk Mike go do it go be mr. D
bunker alright you guys I want to thank
everybody for listening Mike I know
you're taking a DAP but dude thanks for
taking time out of your evening to come
hang out and be on episode number 250
happy to brother I'm glad to have you
here it was fun take your time take your
time away from the kid don't worry enjoy
them throw that carb cap around it's
just glass we'll get more from elevate
do that bubble cap rolls that's a safety
feature it is it is it just goes in
circles and won't roll all the way off
the table though you guys if this is
right where I shamelessly tell you about
my patreon campaign patreon if you feel
like the podcast was worth a few bucks
and you would like to contribute all you
have to do is go to a website called
patreon check out patreon.com slash grow
from your heart patreon will allow you
as a listener to financially contribute
to the podcast
no I'm not trying to get rich off my
podcast however I do have a proposition
coming up for you in a future episode
what patreon will allow you to do is
throw down a few dollars it does cost me
a few bucks to post to have a website I
host my podcast
on a website on the I read genetics
Colorado website don't go there it looks
like [ __ ] and it's embarrassing but it
does exist it's there it needs a lot of
love it hasn't been touched up in quite
a while I'm not a web guy somebody
reached out to me and we may do some
work in the future but that's not what
the topic is right now um anyway I have
to pay for that website to be there
that's how I host the show that's how I
give you the podcast for free I will
happily pay for it out of my pocket if
you think that you'd like to help out
send me a couple of bucks on the patreon
and that's what I will use the money for
also these little microphone covers that
I'm scraping it probably sounds like
[ __ ] in your headphones smells like
nothing which is a real pleasant change
yeah sometimes you know the orange one
that was here for like a year the one
that Wade used to use on the old seven
one nine podcast the other thing was
here for like a year yeah not like
homies mustache I bet it did unpleasant
I bet it did yeah yeah I replace those
and then I throw fresh water bottles on
the table stuff like that it's not free
to do a podcast I'll do it if I need to
you guys not bacon but if you want to
help out I totally appreciate it that
would help us all out we're on like the
11th little box the headphone jacks plug
into guys we burn through gear here and
not on purpose it's not like we're doing
anything crazy the high-speed Internet
to upload the podcast is a little pricey
but I mean whatever that's so huge Thank
You Man thank you I'm not begging you
guys I burped as I said that I am NOT
begging you guys but if you'd like to
throw down I would truly appreciate it
also somebody just threw down four
dollars and 20 cents on patreon they're
making a four dollar in twenty second
tribution that's cool as [ __ ] thank you
I appreciate that thanks to everybody
who has signed up on patreon that's a
mountain dew if anybody's wondering mike
has got an addiction that is not a beer
it sounded like a beer a lot um let's
see what else um if you've got a product
you'd like us to review or if you'd like
to sponsor the show or if you've just
got something you would like to say you
can reach out to me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com or you can find me
on social media simply go to Facebook
search for the grow from your heart
podcast you can go to Twitter and you
can search for GF wih podcast or
you want to get more personal you can
find me it's a trusted Jeff 420 of
course follow Mike on there it's a hat
Nemo Punk 15 right yeah okay I'm sorry
the number throws me off on I don't know
why it's number 15 also if you want to
start that was 15 when I came up with
that oh my god that's where that number
it gives Wow [ __ ] old
wow that is antiquity I wasn't gonna go
there my uh my Instagram you guys I've
got about 15,000 Instagram followers
check me out I use my company name its I
read genetics I RIE
underscore genetics GE nati C as I read
genetics on Instagram check it out if
you're into cannabis photography you
want to see what I'm growing what we're
doing over at Three Rivers if you want
to see pictures of my breeding projects
if you just want to see what I think is
high quality cannabis photography I
think you would appreciate my Instagram
like I said earlier the episodes are
going up on YouTube it takes me a lot of
computer energy to put those up but
they're going up there so check out the
YouTube channel if you'd like to I would
appreciate that do it
it definitely don't follow me on
Instagram um I almost never use that
platform I'm not good with it someone
one of the listeners I actually I've
been feeling a little guilty about this
so if you're listening now know that
nobody sent me a long message on
Instagram asking about California law I
saw it while I was on break at work and
glanced at it was like oh I need to
check that out research for a few
minutes and get back to them I can't
figure out how to bring that [ __ ] back
up on Instagram so please don't send me
stuff through there cuz I will lose it
and then feel guilty for months on end
but if that person is listening tonight
know that I've been feeling guilty
slightly for months and send that
question to me on another platform
I lost a folder of emails and there was
one in there that I was like ooh that's
good I want to do that on the show and I
can't find the [ __ ] folder I did an
update on my phone I want to blame it on
that but I don't know where it wife at I
screenshot at it or something it may be
I don't know but I told everybody I was
like hey if you guys if you sent me a
really cool email and you feel like I
haven't read it yet or a message and I
haven't responded focus in it again
whatever annoy me I only work if you
keep on me honestly I got so much [ __ ]
going on
that uh the open mouth gets fed I guess
is the way that goes yep yeah so if
you're quiet and you don't remind me I
might skip you and it's nothing personal
it's just I'm doing 10,000 things and I
might like it for thought you might
email us don't do much when they don't
get answered plants do a lot when they
don't get watered
snap no [ __ ] it's just that's how our
life's go man I've been playing that
game for three days at work like I have
25 things I want to do and need to do
and would like to do but I have to do
the 8 things that I have to do fryers
yeah yeah and being got being the grow
manager it feels like this guy working
on this this guys working on this trim
crew is kicking our I'm gonna put on
some gloves throw an earbud in now I'm
gonna run in here start doing this I'm
gonna mix up the water so that I could
do they as soon as I start filling the
water container the doorbell rings and
I'm like I'm gonna ignore it let
somebody up front answer it and they'll
handle it and no you [ __ ]
always walk somebody right to me hey
Jeff these guys need you and I'm like
[ __ ] I was there was a day that that was
happened to me real bad and for some
reason everyone that rang the doorbell
it wasn't ring they'd get up on it
really do remember that day so people
have learned that we have aggro and we'd
like to play our music kind of [ __ ]
loud and so some people yeah I know that
guy didn't but sometimes we've missed
people we've been in there and they're
like yeah I sit here and listen to your
music for like 30 minutes and I'm like
[ __ ] I'm sorry that's a family that's
been singing together for a hundred
years yep it's uh it's just crazy busy
so if we've missed you in any way just
send that again holler especially that
person who sent me a message on
Instagram like it seemed like a good
question it seemed like you cared a lot
about getting the answer I just only got
a chance to glance at it I only vaguely
know what it was about and then it
disappeared into an app I don't
understand
I got a similar message from somebody
asking me about Texas laws and I I don't
know anything about Texas law and I
thought I should research that but I
didn't do it and now it's lost in my
Instagram messages access law sucks and
then it just sucks kinda there you go
there you go listener who asked about
Texas that's what you get I guess no
Texas is one of the places that cops
have been busted doing body cavity
searches on the side of the [ __ ] road
because the cop is pretty sure he smells
weed there also the place where if you
make edibles with a concentrate say like
you put a gram shatter into a tray of
brownies they put that whole tray of
brownies on the scale [ __ ] pyrex dish
included and say you've got 30 pounds of
concentrate which they classify along
the same lines as heroin and so because
you made hash brownies with actual hash
you get rung up like you had six kilos
of heroin come on over the border don't
mess with Texas
no seriously Texas is not the place to
cannabis right now yeah their laws are
pretty brutal ah there are a lot of
cannabis refugees from Texas and
Colorado yes there sure are yep
alright Mike coughing from a dad but I
think it's time to wrap up this podcast
ladies and gentlemen see we didn't mean
to do it but we say we throw a little
informative nugget 250 episodes you guys
podcast thank you bro thank you when I
started I was like maybe I can do a
hundred shows I'd done nearly in a
hundred episodes of another podcast with
a friend and I was like well that wasn't
that hard but he did all the talking I
was the producer and coast
I had to chime in and honestly I would
sit here and wait for him to say some
dumb [ __ ] so that I could just zing him
the best I could was what I did on that
podcast but I had a lot of practice just
like I can do 100 episodes and I got to
100 I was like that doesn't even feel
like I'm started it feels
I have a rhythm now on a set on episode
100 I don't remember if it was while we
were recording her right before or after
someone was like I can't believe you did
a hundred and you were like yeah we will
do this again for 200 and we all kind of
looked around the road looks like do you
really think I'm gonna do this in I
understand yeah yeah but there's that
kind of look and I was like man he's
really on a roll though some of these
shows are really good some of them I get
it somewhat were rambling and talking
but meant it's a lot of work to put out
this podcast sometimes we just got a
play everybody has those days at work
weird I'm gonna put my thumb in my
button play with my phone all day at
work and hide in a corner everybody has
those days occasionally hopefully I
don't have too many but I mean we did
that on this show a few times but you
want now that I'm at 250 once I got to
like a hundred was like I'll do 250 no
problem I've got that weird OCD now dude
the goal is 500 episodes so if Rogan did
a thousand recently oh yeah he's in like
a thousand and twenty or something by
now but he does three a week and eats
[ __ ] a bunch of alpha brain and
drinks coffee man talk so much got a
good body Mike to take bohon with him
get to 500 and it will work on a
thousand let's do it you'll be here for
me even though you're getting grey up
there bro you'll be super great by a
thousand right you notice and I always
have a hat on yeah it's coming in
there's plenty of salt in my pepper now
folks I think we're gonna wrap up the
podcast with that one ladies and
gentleman
thank you for listening it's been 250
episodes I'm super proud I'm super
grateful I'll be back
I'm probably gonna put out a Thursday
episode as well ah three episodes this
week
you got to spoil the people and what
they want Gotti well now it sounds like
I promised it so now we got a Thursday
shows are easy to make I remember their
surprise for the person who I can dinna
[ __ ] who can't identify
oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house and it's
not me cuz I sounded just like that just
now it sounds just like that guy oh
shoot rusty there you go it's that
person identify that person also there's
a voice when the record spins backwards
there's a voice in there that goes
backwards and if you can identify whose
voice that is
you gonna prize if you could tell me
what they said you get an even better
prize depending on where you are he told
me charm no man it's nut Chun man I'm
still like a leavening cat I'm gonna
submit those answers officially folks
they're taking the cucumber boat wire
anyway cumber boat [ __ ] wire
[Laughter]
[Music]
I'm talking about your down as [ __ ] Oh
all right we're gonna wrap up this
podcast of the big old goofy grin on my
face I'm nice and stoned my headache is
gone I shout it to the platinum tangi
shots a mic for hanging out shout to
everybody for listening to 250 episodes
of the girl free heart podcast thank you
I appreciate it this shout-out goes to
all the people that listen to the
episode is what I had intended but I
feels like this shout-out should really
go to some cool so shot it's a sub cool
miss Jill and everyone in team green
Avengers
until next time take a fat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
music
Wow sometimes that's all the time it's
gonna be easy
I saw Mariana and get steal the wicked
I'm very good about myself a belonging
feeling good damn that's there from
there my smoke the marijuana yet stay a
Bon Jovi kids
[Music]
Oh
[Applause]
[Music]
I smoke the marijuana stay low we kids
down
[Music]
[Applause]
I'm feeling very good about myself
big uns I'm feeling good well and that's
the problem I smooth the marijuana yet
boom Dubi kids
[Music]
I went I got problem might um
domestically on my land is just one of
Tory would me my reminder I'm get down
still your bum the wicked
love inside that there you gotta find my
big mother
[Music]
you