[Music]
oh [ __ ]
Rasta Jeff in the house
[Music]
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 120 row from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
or a dedicated dabber the very cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band let him use
their music on my show big shout out to
you guys this episode was fun to record
I had a few people over
we had our buddy buzzy over we had Mike
over and our good homie sloppy was back
we did an episode about how to interact
with law enforcement in case you're
pulled over or in case you bump into the
cops out of public or a case the cops
come to your front door there may be
some useful advice in this one for you
before we get to the podcast and you did
give huge shout-outs my friends at
hitmen glass tonight I'm sitting you're
hitting the Hitman eseries side car
smoking Sumter pecks our death star got
some live resin big shot it's my friends
a hitman when I buy a rig I like to buy
a rig made in America by an American
that's why shop with hitman glass check
mine at www.wku.edu/oucampus summer make
sure you support the chalice
festival chalice hash music glass and
art to SoCal festival
do not miss it alright guys that's all
I've got for shout outs in advertising
so I'm gonna let the music played we're
going to get into the episode about how
to interact with law enforcement thanks
for listening
so what I think we have learned today is
that we need to sign like a an emergency
contact form for people and they come
over and take Babs I try to [ __ ] people
up over here apparently welcome back to
the show sitting to my left is our good
friend buzzy how you doing today my
friend hey y'all as well right on thank
you for joining me no problem awesome
over here kind of in front of me a
little bit off to an angle as our good
buddy white Mike welcome back to the
show bro thanks man good beer thanks for
coming over here even more in front of
me is our buddy sloppy how you doing bro
yo yo doing well thanks for coming I
don't get to see you often enough for
sure that's why I shot over here like
that
sloppy was on time if not early I was
[ __ ] impressed good work bro thanks
for coming for sure awesome we've got a
topic that we're gonna talk about
tonight I'm gonna tell a little quick
story yesterday I was at work and one of
my trimmers I will not say his name just
cuz I got respect for him one of my
trimmers called me and he's like hey bro
can you do me a favor it's like anything
for a bro and he said can you come pick
me up at the fire station and I was like
well what's going on and he said I got
pulled over and they gave me a DUI for
cannabis so they gave him they pulled
him over they had probable cause to pull
him over when they pulled it walked up
to the car there's a car wreaked of
cannabis because he's a trimmer
you smell like cannabis and my buddy was
like well I'm a trimmer and he's like
alright well get out of the car I want
to give you a sobriety test and my buddy
failed the test okay they then put him
in the cop car took him to the fire
station and drew blood at that point
they called me I my buddy called me and
said that I can come pick him up a
couple minutes later my phone rang it
was my buddy saying hey the state
trooper just said that if you look smell
or act high at all he's going to arrest
you so be cool if you're coming or I'll
call somebody else and I was cool I
hadn't smoked yeah it was really it was
like 2:00 in the afternoon and I don't
even think I smoked before I went to
work that day because I go to [ __ ]
early to smoke sometimes right
so in smoked all day I was crispy the
only reason my eyes would be crispy is
because they'd been up for too long
working you know in the
so I Drive over there and I call my
buddy I'm like can you come out and hold
on the cops gonna come talk to you
couple of friends in the car from work I
just brought everybody with me cuz I
didn't want to leave them there without
the boss so I put him in the car like a
field trip for the boys and took them to
the fire station you guys stay here
somebody record this so a couple of
people recorded the interaction on their
cell phone just in case she went sloppy
so uh I walk up to the cop and he's like
so your buddy
was pulled over for DUI he's too
intoxicated to drive I've got the
opportunity to either take him to jail
and keep him or I can release him to a
responsible adult who will declare
responsibility for him for the next
eight hours so ah I know the guy he's a
good dude and he's gonna come work but I
need to [ __ ] come work with me he was
on his way to work when he got pulled
over so I'll sign the paper so the cops
like I need your ID and he took my ID
and watch me write down my information
as I was doing it and ran my license and
[ __ ] because you're not wanted and I go
oh thanks I've never felt more unwanted
it was the cop I don't get Machado I
don't remember his name he was really
[ __ ] cool for being a state trooper
they had to give my friend a DUI he gave
us information on how to avoid getting
ourselves in trouble he said stuff like
don't smell like cannabis so strongly
don't smell like cannabis have expired
plates and do these he said there were
fifteen he didn't tell us what they are
he said there are fifteen things that
they look for as main keys and my buddy
hit nine of them so he definitely got
arrested but they let him go to me the
cop was really cool but I've been
talking about doing this episode about
what to do if you're involved with a law
enforcement I feel like my buddy handled
himself well he told them he worked in
the edge had to over you wouldn't got
that call exactly they didn't even tow
his car they pulled it off to the side
they asked us a lot of questions and I'd
quit when I was picking him up be the
cop asked
two questions and then he got friendly
with us and started asking questions
about the industry and work and at one
point I just shut up I was like oh I
don't want to answer any more questions
he tricked me
he's my friend now and I'm telling him
[ __ ] but it brings us to this episode
it's a really good way to segue into
this don't drive high because they're
looking for people in Colorado right now
it's the start this officer told us it's
the start of their searching for DUI
season all the troopers have recently
taken a drug expert class a lot of the
state troopers are now cannabis what is
talks
cannabis intoxication or impairment
experts or whatever so where they could
tell how high you are and this cop said
things that made me think he was serious
he knew stuff about my buddy being
intoxicated that I know about cannabis
like he knew that level he said your
buddy doesn't look high or act high but
when I interviewed him I can tell there
are things inside of him that are going
on that indicate that he's high that's
kind of [ __ ] like I was impressed by
it the way that he put it like all right
Jedi Master like right port medical
training I don't know but so let's talk
about some things that we could do to
maybe help ourselves out and not get in
as much trouble and maybe prevent
ourselves maybe hopefully walk away
without any [ __ ] handcuffs or maybe
instead of giving all the way taken to
the jail keep yourself in a situation
where they call Rasta Jeff and he gets
to come pick you up to sign for you so
let's talk about like if you get pulled
over
ah you've told me a your method our
friend buzzy over here he's told me his
method of how to handle himself when he
gets pulled over so I'm gonna go around
the table and I'll start I'll start with
buzzy cos used to the left you're
driving down the street you're on the
interstate you're driving a little weed
in the car but it's hidden you know it's
cool it's in Colorado a lot of these
people are gonna be like however many
percent where you are is really gonna
depend on what you should do before you
get the car also if you are driving with
weed regardless of where you are should
pretty much put it in the trunk always
know it in no way endorsing breaking the
law let me find you a straight brother
just do it right here onto this table
look I'm a ver MacGyver all right order
in the court I'm tapping the getting
pulled over you got those red and blues
behind you they're flickering in a car
and driving and just being a person they
don't know what color you are they have
no idea what you're doing
I don't know you don't even know you
pulled over up to the window shines like
right [ __ ] goddamn face and usually
he'll say something like yeah would have
the window rolled down before he gets
there okay all right both hands on the
steering wheel you want to be able the
cops should be able to see both your
hands this is to my method is avoid
anything possible be extremely
what the cop wants to happen him the
most desirable situation possibly
submissive to him or trying to avoid
paying money to the state was my goal
just keep your hands on the wheel he's
like place license registration say
that's in my glove box can I reach into
it
sure you go into it you get your stuff
out give it to him I don't know
different things can happen from there
okay so grab July he's like how you
doing you're like pretty good sir how
about yourself probably is what you're
polite dude license registration proof
of insurance he's gonna walk back to the
car hopefully he's gonna come back and
he's gonna say my friend buzzy you were
going a little too fast quit driving
like an [ __ ] in these parts I'm just
gonna give you a warning hopefully it
goes well so the key to it I think we're
all gonna have the same story be polite
to the cop
don't try to be know your rights but
don't try to invoke them immediately
when the cop comes up give him what he
wants until he's telling you start
[ __ ] with you like the important
thing to keep in mind here is that they
have all the power and can execute you I
mean not to [ __ ] flaunt it at all 999
times out of 100 or probably even more
than that you're gonna get annoyed
ticketed and sent on your way but you
that one time out of however many
they're gonna freak out shoot you in the
face or get pissed and drag you to jail
sometimes the cops are just great Rob
you take your [ __ ] don't leave me there
take your [ __ ] on the side of the road
like I want to continue in mind like
exercise your rights but do if you
follow the little script they're
expecting nine times out of ten you're
on your way in ten minutes
all right yeah yeah ten fifteen minutes
so I'm gonna take some too brother [ __ ]
I wore the same pullover you've gotten
pulled over you've gone through all the
[ __ ] our buddy buzzy over here is
handled but now when the cop comes back
with your license registration proof of
insurance he goes hey Mike uh kind of
smells like you got weed in there I
would like to search your vehicle now
what's the proper response at this point
I don't
I just I do not consent to any searches
there's just you keep repeating that
when they ask you to search your stuff
all right they need major probable cause
and they'll make [ __ ] up like you've got
Altoids that's probable cause excuse
that to cover their breath knew that
that's not probable cause about like
myself I work in a giant Gro I was
trimming plants that were six feet tall
today I had to chop I had to lean in
between two plants and chop plants down
and carry six foot tall plants if so my
shirt I probably break I've got trim on
me right now if I was coming from work
and I said you smell like marijuana I
work in the legal marijuana industry
that's just a side effect of my job it's
probably the probable cause to search my
vehicle though nah I'm sorry I would say
be strong on distinguishing the
different smells between smoked
marijuana and fresh marijuana yeah this
doesn't this is this smell that you're
smelling is work-related this is not
smoked marijuana is the smell of a plant
right at this point you're like they're
arguing about smells because you're not
slurring your speech because your eyes
aren't red because they didn't catch you
weaving so I is probably one of the
things we should put on the list to
avoid getting your ass in truth you're
sober right now
you can argue it this is a smell that I
picked up at work working while sober
I'm on my way home sober like that's
what you're smelling if you insist on
searching the car like unless they're
finding roaches in the ashtray or add a
break in a cup holder put your [ __ ] away
you guys yep you're headed on the road
yeah have it out of reach have your
Stephanie if you've got a locked
container that would be ideal that's
what they'd prefer to keep in the trunk
I think we were talking about that
earlier right it works just like booze
if you've got a 12-pack in the backseat
of the trunk you're fine if that 12-pack
is open and the 12th one was in your cup
holder no more sloppy little blonde he
never passed it to anybody what's going
on with you bro I've hit it four times
sir
I figured there's only two of us smoking
house thanks for coming some of my
friends just not wanna smoke can I just
see your face Hills all day they made me
this stone alright so sloppy yes I want
to hear about it I'm a cop I got the red
and blue lights behind you you're in the
car nothing wrong that you know of yeah
pull over I come up behind you how do
you handle yourself what are you gonna
do okay
so two different answers when I was
younger
cuz I have two totally different
perspectives on this that's why I got
you here from being an adolescent to
being in a dirt you know what I'm saying
like from going from you I told ya I
could die happy right now
[Music]
okay so when I was younger I was one of
those oh [ __ ] the police man they can't
do [ __ ] to me and I would you know
approach to the situation they'd pull me
over and I'd be like why'd you pull me
over this then I'd be really
confrontational towards it and then I'd
go to jail and that's what would happen
because I was being confrontational in a
scenario where I didn't need to nowadays
you comply you [ __ ] comply to
everything there are asking you within
reason like oh why why are you speeding
this keep like what buzz he said keep
your hands where they can see them my
goal is to make the police officer feel
comfortable like as soon as they walk up
to the window that should be your best
friend like all those teeth are mighty
white today sir you're looking real
sharp tonight close like it's nice and
sunny out really don't don't say the
phrase mighty white
[Music]
so without without putting myself out
there too much I was driving not high at
the moment going fifteen over and I had
weed on me this is back in North
Carolina or whatever and I got pulled
over and I had Colorado plates cuz I had
a rental car I'm going I'm going fifteen
over and I just I was like [ __ ] you know
what I'm saying like dude get out of the
car with his cowboy hat like he had his
badge was on the Hat so what happened
was I drove back to North Carolina I
brought a little bit of personal because
I didn't want to deal with no like
[ __ ] ratchet [ __ ] to get weed back
there [ __ ] that I got we now I actually
got pulled over in Kansas worst place to
get pulled over ever so he got out with
the badge on his hat and I was like oh
he's gonna shoot me and my dogs
I had two little puppies but so I'm
nervous I'm like [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] Colorado
plates and I remember right until he was
in my peripherals
I was nervous like scared and as soon as
he was that I sung to him he was I could
have sung him a hole disc I was so nice
to him and he asked me why I was
speeding I was the officer I've been
driving for like eight hours I saw that
there's a rest area up there I was
honestly just trying to make it there so
I can go to sleep runs my stuff now I
don't know how the police things work
but I'm pretty sure that when they run
my name in any state they can see my
criminal background I'm pretty sure it
goes from state to state so he saw how
perfect but the bigger stuff yes yeah
I'm sure he saw I had a record and he
treated me totally respectfully he
looked me he said I pulled you over
Tuesday were speeding and I wanted to to
really come talk to you because your
Colorado plates I wanted to see if you
have anything to hide from me but
obviously you don't have a good day and
then he left me didn't even give me the
speeding ticket and it's all because I
was I made him feel comfortable and I
was polite because fifteen over they
could take your license on the spot if
they really want to be a dick and we
were in Kansas and I had two pitbulls in
the car and after he left I threw up
because I was like oh my god
Juke yeah I really thought I was going
back to jail and I was like I hate life
they're gonna take my dogs but I could
have handled it like when I was younger
and been an [ __ ] and got my dog shot
and got [ __ ] tasered she killed
myself or thrown back in jail but I was
play that's what I hate I hate seeing
all these videos where they're like oh
that's that's police abuse that's police
abuse but the dude isn't doing what the
police is asking him like lay down on
the ground lay the [ __ ] down like what
why do you want to get DDT doc I just
don't see the point like they're
pointing like I saw a video that's all
video the police had a gun pointed at a
guy he had a knife and he lunged at him
and they shot him and people are like
unnecessary force you're a [ __ ]
hypocrite because if you have a legal
gun on you and I come and try to stab
you right now you're gonna shoot me you
[ __ ] so don't [ __ ] don't vitae it
on the police and and and when I say
[ __ ] I don't mean gay people's it'll
be all upside for sure don't be a little
[ __ ] [ __ ] about it don't be a little
[ __ ] like because if I try to stab
that because people are so hypocritical
because if they put themselves in the
same position they would act totally
different than what they're speaking and
I hate that because if you try to stab
me I'm shooting you if I have a legal
right yeah like stand in front of that
guy over the knife and I'll give you
half a second deciding you're shooting
[Music]
why didn't you shoot him 17 times there
was only 16 bullets Lebowski records for
all the people the real trick here
though is to just be calm and go through
the script that they're expecting and
that's really easy to do if you're not
doing something you're not supposed to
be doing like but a lot of people are
doing something we shouldn't be doing I
remember how he used to be in Colorado I
used to have to drive and go pick up
weed and drive at home all the time and
that was the time that I was most at
risk is when I just went and picked up a
new quarter
to drive at home and I made it real easy
on myself I threw it in a backpack when
I bought it I threw that backpack in the
trunk when I got to the car if I got
pulled over on the way home it wasn't
for speeding cuz I did my damnedest not
to break a single traffic law with weed
in the car I got pulled over plenty of
times with weed in the car and when they
walk up to your car to go good evening
officer and it doesn't stink like weed
the car you're fine they go oh I pulled
you over for this let me run your [ __ ]
oh here's your ticket have a good night
you show up the court you pay that [ __ ]
it's done click try the 105 on i-25
Rasta Jeff yeah control I also think
looking looking them in the eyes is key
yeah because you're something you're
like aftershave yeah be respectful like
like if you can be calm and confident
they don't wonder why you're nervous and
try to figure out why you're you're
freaking out and want to date through
your car the hardest part for me is when
they make you sign the ticket like
normally I sign my to my name like
you'll get a little motion but then you
get all nervous and your buddies
headphones taken upon us is this
connection here you're gonna slide
sloppy one time they're gonna make that
your real name you're gonna have to sign
everything as sloppy
it's my alias under the NC inmate
whatever it says sloppy I unfortunately
unfortunat I got arrested once and my
hats it's he brought it to me like I can
only assume that you're sloppy huh I
also had it on my own for a while you
had it on your arm for a while it's
covered up now that makes more yeah yeah
yeah so how did this dude have a tattoo
fight well I have covered all of my
gang affiliation tattoos because work
trying to be a good person Abra I'm
trying not to be a target one of the old
heads one day looked to me said all that
is is a bull's-eye for everybody that
doesn't like you and the police and I
said oh my god he's like what you walk
down the shirt you're just telling
everybody like you don't need to do that
[Music]
to do if you get pulled over now pull
the [ __ ] over as quickly as you can
safely pull the [ __ ] over keep your
hands where they can see them let the
cop come up he's gonna be like I want
you hit yeah don't flirt with a female
cop no that pisses her off so bad for
your stuff tell them you're gonna reach
for it I'm gonna reach for into the
glove box
ask them to reach for it can I reach my
glove box and grab my license insurance
I'm gonna reach in my pocket get my
wallet out now please
alright don't shoot me sir I recommend
everybody records interactions with the
police's as soon as you're pulled over
turn your cameraphone on places
somewhere or like you know for sure
because then like oh I mean why not at
least is there you a I don't want
everyone seeing me cry on periscope it's
an extra layer of protection for
everybody if you're lucky you live in a
place where the cops have cameras stuck
to their chests that they can't turn off
but when you drive away don't get all
nervous and do something stupid write
[Music]
something else I was thinking about
earlier today that I had to
realize as an adult is a not every
officer is a [ __ ] scumbag yeah I'm
saying by saying that every officer is
just trying to make your day worse is
basically being racist it's like the
same as labeling a racist doing so yeah
it's just JA pissed or some [ __ ] yeah
every fast-food person's gonna be an
[ __ ] and every cops trying to [ __ ]
you over because I've seen cool cops
I've interacted with wait cops who are
literally just trying to do what I was
younger like 24 25 ish my girlfriend at
the time worked managed a bar and we
would go smoke in the Holly
there was an alleyway that went one way
he could turn left or right to come into
the parking lot of the bar if you go to
the other way you'll go through another
area this cop would roll through and he
knew we were out there just passing all
the time in that alley cuz you just walk
right out of the side door of the bar
and go sit in this little area between
cars and smoke when he would come
through it flashes brights so we know
put our [ __ ] away and be prepared to he
wouldn't have to [ __ ] with us you know
he would just rather not see you smoking
or maybe he's got somebody else in the
car
smoke some weed sorry oh no I've just
had dozens of interactions with yeah for
sure I've seen that happen but if you
follow the script nine times out of ten
you drew out of there in 15 minutes tops
we never see we rarely see any good [ __ ]
about the cops on the news on the
internet on TV anywhere like that
because you rarely hear anything about
the good [ __ ] when people do good [ __ ]
like oh yeah that cop help that old lady
up it's this [ __ ] job you only see a
psychology class I learned about this
that's actually life period if you
notice like people talking about stuff a
lot or even the news it's never good
stuff because none even though it's
unknown you don't realise a good stuff
is happening all the time so that bad
stuff is a blip on the radar and that's
what you remember and reference to
because it's usually things are
copacetic so when something bad
Vin's it really sticks out and that's
what people want to hear they don't want
to hear like a hundred kids were saved
today they want to hear you know puppies
getting kicked off of a cliff people are
[ __ ] up man like they see bad stuff
and it it gives them I personally feel
like people want to see bad things so
they have a reason to fuel a unnecessary
fire to complain about why they're not
doing well or to use it to to why things
are so [ __ ] up this and that like yeah
especially like oh man here in America
like we are so privileged as Americans I
hate this whole anti-american thing
that's happening like people standing on
flags if I see you stand on a flag I'm
running you over at my previous I don't
give a [ __ ] like that's so that's a
great you wanna know why this yo this is
why this is why because no one is
fleeing from America you are not putting
your family on a door and pushing it
into the ocean to get somewhere else
like America is fine there's no there's
no death rage happening when it's
nighttime we're making a podcast we're
not having one of us make sure that
death troopers aren't coming to killing
everybody in our [ __ ] village like
you know what I'm saying I hate people
they're like Oh
America is horrible no you're able to be
the person that you want to be because
you're in America because being yourself
in other countries can get you [ __ ]
murdered like jarl weed this is probably
but that's about a half ounce
weed right here in most countries would
probably get your head cut off most 75
different kinds of food we could drive
our own vehicles we can we're okay
everybody in this room has varying
religious beliefs tattoo here I've got
dreadlocks you've got your symbols there
I think I have a good idea what you
follow and I'm sure you two kind of
linked up in the same similar sort away
from conversations we've had but in
other countries one of us would be
beheaded for what we all at one point I
literally asked you like how the [ __ ] do
you not get pulled over all the time
don't realize I've been told so many
times that my voice doesn't match my
appearance when I buy a lot of product
there and I also deliver products
sometimes to people there shopping and
they're like I recognize that voice they
turn around they look at me and they're
not sure if that dreadlock guy is the
guy from the podcast it's really funny
so the listeners that have never that
aren't privy I guess I'm six five and
I've got dreadlocks seriously too fast
my ass like mid thigh region almost to
my knees one of the really longer ones
goes almost to my kneecaps by now so
yeah I feel pressure from the police
sometimes the cop yesterday asked me he
said how long did it take you to get
those dreadlocks that long but like 11
years and he goes Wow commitment buddy I
was at the courthouse getting
fingerprinted for when I worked at a
dispensary everybody had to go get
fingerprinted and had to go take a day
off because it took them all [ __ ] day
to fingerprint me but uh cop in there
walked by and he goes great dreadlocks
bro
I was like it was a cop he wasn't even
being sarcastic he was like had a smile
on his face and [ __ ] so not all cops are
jocks some cops are cool but yeah I'm a
frickin so sometimes they feel some
pressure cuz that's just a big thing
going on now I could really just go on
about go on man well social media
warriors and stuff people who are like
just bitching about the world but not I
think that what we were just talking
about earlier like all like how ex
public executions and all that stuff
like I think that for one hour I think
that everybody should be made to watch
one hour of what's really going on in
other countries like a week one hour a
week of like show me like what's up in
Mexico show me what's up in Egypt like
show you was really [ __ ] up because
it's all about the source where are you
gonna get that material the [ __ ]
Internet has all of it it has people
being publicly executed by the good also
does it have the good as well as the bad
every was just referencing to the fact
that people [ __ ] about America okay
it's we are really okay here like I got
I just went to Cali Cali was awesome
first time ever in Cali amazing chef I
think someone like Cali but I got into a
debate with my friend there because
she's like an active feminist and stuff
which I support that's awesome but she
said that like women don't have a lot of
Rights here and they're really
restrained so on and so forth which in
some ways I do see like statistically
they get paid less and stuff I
understand but as far as freedoms of the
world women are really free in America
and and and I hate to say it but like in
other countries women are still getting
stoned too
for talking to males in public and we
got women running for president so like
yes things are different but like we are
we are Farley advanced in a lot of ways
I don't know if that sounds like weird
to say but like how can people find you
on Twitter angry to me if you want to
make sure all of the tweets about the
statements are headed sloppy I didn't
say anything about anti said I'm totally
for it there were some microaggressions
I also think that I think it's [ __ ] up
that it's [ __ ] up to be proud of your
heritage nowadays like like no but nope
nobody really doesn't nobody's like you
I'm Italian and they're like nobodies
with their roots everybody wants to be
guilty of cultural appropriation right
right it's a step away from being racist
it's almost it's a foot into the racist
category which it isn't
but then again racism is isn't it just
having pride in one's race isn't bigotry
the real problem like or something like
that like cause like it's okay I feel
like it's it's a thing like it shouldn't
be a thin line like everybody should be
proud of who they are like if you're
German be proud you're German if you're
black be proud you're black if you're if
you're Asian but you know what I'm
saying like but it's when you add hate
to it like oh I don't like these other
people because they're yeah but I think
that it's misinterpreted a lot like
people just see what they want to see
like straight up you could take any
story and make it good or bad and by
changing some like minor details
altering [ __ ] I've seen them do it two
people can read the same book and get
totally different stories where two
people can watch the same car accident
until two totally different stories
perspective business damn thing yep
watch the same fight I have two totally
different stories both people one
like beat the [ __ ] out of Jeff Jeff beat
the [ __ ] out of Mike he was stopping
them the whole time like both people one
man you know just like everybody is way
off course they do hashtag I like it
when you ramble so I talked about what
to do if you get pulled over by the
police guys behave yourselves don't
reach too quickly we all saw the video
the guy that reached into his car to get
his ID I got blasted by the police
cheese don't reach so quickly just chill
out
ask chill out chill out Tariq trying to
get a good recording whoever said that
is a genius sly high-five since you get
your hand up there you go high-five want
to record it alright so how about were
sitting here Mike let's go Mike first
this is your house I just gave you the
house we're sitting here doorbell rings
and I'm not even doorbell it's this one
it's [ __ ] this sound the cop
everybody's heart sinks when you hear
that [ __ ] police how do you handle that
take a quick look around the room and
make sure there's nothing laying there
that I wouldn't want laying out that's
just to have it from back when we was
illegal here right that's a good tip for
anybody that's not a Colorado so open
the door you know good evening officer
what can I do for you and then see what
they've got to say at that point like
nine times out of ten if they were there
and you were in real trouble they woulda
knocked like your door was exploded a
flashbang gone off he'd have an f-16
plans your head
oh if they're knocking they just want to
ask questions and so you've just if
you're not interested say you're not
interested come back with a warrant in
play we in the conversation instead of
back inside if they're like asking about
something that happened up the street or
whatever you want to talk to him step
out on the porch and pull the door shut
behind you sit there and have the
conversation should you almost lock
yourself out unnecessary all right they
can't open the door and go in for any
reason not legally a warrant like
without probable cause that like there's
a crime being committed insider that
somebody's in distress so what if the
cop says well Mike I'd like to take a
look inside as why because we believe
you did it
did what the thing that we're here to
accuse you of no I'd like to look inside
Mike I'd like to go inside if you don't
have anything to hide Mike there should
be a problem with us coming in and
taking a look don't you think I got
stuff to do have a nice alright Mike
thanks for thanks for playing along
would you like because you won you
played that perfect all the right
answers over there
it's you've got a lot of rights in
knowing how to exercise them is key grab
a pen or tie flex your rights calm I
think it is yes or just Google flex your
rights it's a series of videos put on by
the defense attorney out of Baltimore
who's really fun to watch on video and
it's really nice to know exactly what to
do and a law enforcement Google flex
your rights your rights right it's it's
awesome I meant to review it before I
came over but I got a kid now and the
microphone yes I read something the
other day that says that
undercover vehicles cannot operate
normal traffic stops in Colorado do you
know if that's true or not I saw a Chevy
Tahoe ish looking vehicle I don't wanna
be certain on the Tahoe it looks like a
Tahoe pull somebody over on i-25 the
other day while I was in Denver yeah
yeah I have I have somebody works at the
Honda dealership that said that he got
pulled over by undercover and they said
you don't have insurance and he said
you're not supposed to be pulling people
over in this vehicle and they let him go
but you know I know I don't never
believe 100% when people say so I was
trying and he was a car dealer he's a
mechanic okay car dealer he already
[Music]
don't smoke cigarettes guys you'll end
up sounding like yep that's exactly what
that is
we're having a podcast and here we go
it's the cops you open the door no no
first thing I do first thing I do
because I'm a pet owner I'm putting my
dog somewhere where they can't
aggressive towards the police because
[ __ ] that sound like crazy or nothing
but if they shoot my dogs in front of me
I'm catching some charges cuz I'm
swinging no regrets [ __ ] scary as [ __ ]
and they're so lovable but they're 90
pounds of pit bulls so I understand like
sometimes I forget that there's like
that cuz people like oh my god I'm like
get it their face but yeah I know I'm
putting my dogs up and then I I'm going
to answer the door as soon as I see that
it's the authorities I am stepping out
and closing the door like when you said
that that's exactly I I don't want them
looking in my house I don't want them to
have reason
while one of them talks to the other one
searches as much your house as you can
be lurking around oh there's a grinder
on the table or so I don't want none of
that [ __ ] get out shut the door
why are you here always be polite I I
contact I guess you have to be the hands
out of your pockets yeah for sure
that's it don't have your hands
all right here's altima question well
mr. sloppy
I'd like to come inside and take a look
why I just want to make sure you didn't
do it I really don't know what you're
talking about
you did the crime that we're here to
invent don't don't let them do anything
let them [ __ ] it in your house yeah and
honestly from from past experience even
if they have a warrant they're gonna do
whatever the [ __ ] they want cuz the one
time I was arrested was this exact
scenario I will not exact I stepped out
of the house I went to the gas station
to get a Dutch I was with my friend
Julian I think I've told this shut up
Julian yeah yeah shoutouts to kilojoules
and see he makes beats but no I think
I've told this story on the cast before
we we pulled up to the gas station it's
like half a mile from the house and mad
cops swarmed the car and get out and
they're like full tactical gear and
stuff
and they're yelling at Julian and I leo
mistaken identity I literally thought
that and then they looked at me and said
my government name and they had the
warrant they showed me the warrant I
read it I was in handcuffs I looked
through it I lived in a third storey
apartment one way in one way out told
them the door was unlocked said my
girlfriend's in there with my dog go
ahead just go in like you already have
all the paperwork at school they went up
there and still busted out every window
flashbang my girlfriend
you knock the door in and and I told
them where everything was and they cut
my cushions open broke my fridge
they found half a gram of marijuana a
bong and an unregistered firearm I
wasn't 21 yet I was three months away
and that was it and I told them the door
was unlocked to go inside and they still
blew that [ __ ] up like yeah if they have
the warrant
[ __ ] you if they don't have the warrant
get the [ __ ] out of my face like leave
me alone they've got the warrant they're
pretty much doing what they want to do
they didn't knock anyway they booted in
that [ __ ] door what it was was they
planned on doing that to me anyway and
then I went to the store and he was like
oh you took all the fun out of it [ __ ]
toys alright so we all know what to do
now if the cops come to the door step
outside talk to him be kind keep your
hands where they can see them if if a
cop asks for your ID you do not have to
present ID but it helps with the
interaction if you want to keep on that
like polite like I don't want to go to
jail side compliance just give me a
[ __ ] ID if you're not hiding anything
you can you can flex your rights but I
don't have to give you my ID videos
where you can really learn your rights
and some people really enjoy pulling the
mi detained with their YouTube channels
that are solely dedicated to people
harassing police officers with assault
rifles just to get a rise out of the
police thanks sir what are you doing I
can be here because of HB 41
my nunchucks and samurai sword and
butt-ass naked are fairly legal right
there depending on where you live in the
US like along our southern states
anything bordering Mexico they've got
random highway checkpoints where they
look for immigration documents and all
kinds of [ __ ] and a lot of that's
unconstitutional and it really pisses
people off and so people who know
exactly how to flex their rights in a
very specific living [ __ ] beaten out of
them and thrown in jail and go flex the
rights if [ __ ] massive checkpoints
and stuff it it's nuts
but exactly how to do that makes getting
pulled over really easy to handle like
you stay calm keep your hands in plain
sight walking down the street what if
you're just down on [ __ ] 4th Street
walking from one store to the other
that's kind of [ __ ] dark out the cop
walks up Tina's like hey you come here I
want to talk to you a cop just walks out
of nowhere or he comes from where he
came from you're in conversation you and
I were talking pops up bumps into us
excuse me boys I'd like to talk to you
how can I help you officer what's going
on I'd like to see your ID you reach in
your pocket
[Music]
I was just about to say that we saw you
guys smoking some weed back there when
you're walking I saw you [ __ ] reek
like we're going with tase you and hit
you with something and put you in the
car
that was the one and only benefit ever
smoking cigarettes that's what I always
smelled like and I like point to the
cigarettes in my pocket be like no sir
Marlboro and then go alright so when
does the why want to I want to search
your pockets Mike I think you don't
consent to any search I feel like I need
to search Mike I don't have any grounds
to detain you so I'd like to run your
name then I'll let you go you can go
because you're an ass Latino your stay
really calm and like if you're screaming
yes get on the ground
but if you just calmly I'm I'm sorry sir
I have somewhere to be am I being
detained
I'm not being detained sir I'd like to
go my free to go Thank You officer have
a good night you know good luck
investigating whatever it is so a couple
of weeks ago weekends ago two or three
weekends ago by the time this podcast
comes out it would be three weekends
there was an event called the frost ball
the frost ball was a local cannabis
competition where people grew cannabis
and entered their cannabis and people
were judging it and there was a party
where people were consuming cannabis and
the police came and they raided that
[ __ ] oh they they didn't rate it
the word they used was rated but they
came and shut it down but there are like
35 cops it's surrounded the place and
all swarmed in all at once and shut the
place down let's say word an event shoot
I have to change my event I was gonna
say the cannabis cup but as of the past
couple of days it does not look like the
Denver cannabis cup is gonna happen yes
a lot of places are not going to be able
to give that
[Music]
[ __ ] over there cost me six bucks an
uber over there dab the [ __ ] out of
walking around I've got I don't know
four grand to shatter in my pocket seven
grams good flower okay to carry that as
an adult in Colorado cop walks up to me
and wants to give me [ __ ] how do I
handle myself with this cop in public
and even had a cannabis event where I'm
gonna be [ __ ] with sorry I said
straight in public but it's at an event
we're all consuming he's like come here
I want to talk to you immediately like
stop moving my feet yeah just questions
just the am I being detained to my free
to be harassed that's how I not in the
mood to be harassed alright do you say
that to the cop it hasn't really come up
that I've had to run it like that since
I was a teenager like the good evening
officer how are you what can I do for
you like it doesn't matter if it's oh I
was speeding or oh we got a noise
complaint or oh it smells like weed out
front like if you started off that way
nine times out of ten just being played
and going like no I don't consent to any
searches now I've got stuff to do later
like
stephane guys what can I do to help like
sorry guys have a good night usually
that gets you through it five or seven
minutes
worst case scenario they go get out of
the car they search your car they find
the weed they write your check for the
weed you get home alright that sounds
reasonable sloppy standing up taking a
DAB no I like it so you don't bump the
rig on the mics you don't dab the
microphone like you did last time you
were here like even if you're about to
get in a bunch of trouble playing it
cool with the original interaction with
the officer assumed asurs you don't get
really injured during that and don't get
injured something I didn't mention
earlier that I should have totally
mentioned the cop that pulled my friend
over and gave him a DUI asked him how
long it had been since he smoked last my
friend tried to play mr. honesty and
told them a little too early I think I
think that played a part of the the
arrest
say yesterday like if that cops like how
long ago you're you're driving to get
pulled over cops like you well when is
the last time you smoked cannabis
yesterday yeah not today
before I went to bed like if you're
driving you're required to hand over
like license registration proof of
insurance but you're not legally
required to self-incriminate you're not
legally required to answer any other
questions dry snitching give them the
minimum amount of the information that
you need to give them you know let me go
on with your you're legally obligated to
comply you can get arrested for just
resisting like if the cop walks up and
you run away like the cop didn't even
say anything you just walk onto your
block or whatever it immediately turned
and ran and she chose to chase you and
rest you you can get arrested for just
resisting arrest got arrested for that
all charges got dropped it immediately
but I went to court a relation of mine
got arrested just for that he they were
climbing through the window of a party
while he was in high school
he put his arms out just to the sides
and went get out of my house piggy and
he got tackled and handcuffed and he
thought it was hilarious but he knew he
he'd survived it because after he was
tackled at handcuffed like he could do
and say what he wanted he was gonna get
bailed out in less than 24 hours anyway
like yeah I I was young on probation
walking with another friend that was on
probation and we had heard that if
you're on probation you're not supposed
to be with other people on probation so
these cops came up on us and I darted
and then I had a load of sack on me but
I threw it and then I got arrested and
as soon as I like I went to jail got
bailed out and then as soon as I went to
court he was like where are the other
charges and I was like what do you mean
he was like well what else did you get
charge from us oh I just ran because I
thought I wasn't supposed to be hanging
out with this person automatically drops
let it go bottom are right here nice um
so I mean that's a that's the easier if
you just come you know even if you're
about to get in trouble it's so much
easier to do with the court without the
why did you run away like why did you
live on a car chase yeah why did you
enjoy detective so-and-so with your door
don't do that type of it just don't do
that
you just play it cool I want to the mic
it was directed toward you thank you
thank you thank you give you that dr.
pepper state shadows to the dr. pepper
those 23 Terps right oh my god
sometimes I pour others raced in their
20 foul Oh interesting thing about the
place all right so if you're getting
pulled over by an unmarked vehicle would
you pull over or would you call it in
ah I'm a I'm a dude ah I can handle
myself I feel like for the most part I
got pretty good judgement of what a cop
looks like and when huh but if I I'm not
trying to be sexist here if I were a
small woman who wasn't his [ __ ]
wasn't six five and two hundred pounds
you know there's some girls you could
pick some girls up and just [ __ ]
carry him off yeah if I was that size of
a girl if you just call 9-1-1 and be
like hey cop it's pulling me over for
real am I really being pulled over like
I'm a tiny woman or I'm just in a
sketchy part of town or did I did I it
doesn't look like a cop car except for
the flashing lights in the windshield
911 oh for sure yeah if it's not don't
send people to pull over whoever's
trying to do it just sit there with your
windows up and wait every now and then
you'll see in the police blotter was
someone was arrested for but they pulled
over a cop immediately he was like
[Music]
robbing people like bless you that's
another thing would you do you think
that you have to roll your window down
all the way or can you just do it than
this necessary amount to talk and
exchange like is that being a douche are
you pushing the limit by not giving them
the full window like what are you trying
to prove
yeah I just roll it down to talk to him
yeah I mean yeah because if somebody's
gonna salt you they're doing it how can
I lick your ballsack today right like
that's why you play it cool from the
get-go so that the cop doesn't decide to
play it the hardest way possible
as they could just decide to arrest you
and come through that window no problem
like yeah just roll that [ __ ] down
that's why you put the weed in the
backseat or in the trunk
throw it in an extra bag or a backpack
so that your car doesn't stick where in
the road don't have a roach burning in
the ash trail and you get pulled over
yeah don't don't yeah don't smoke and
driver shadows um I man I have to get on
that don't smoke and drive you gotta be
careful with that road duis are not fun
if you do get [ __ ] and pulled over if
you can't [ __ ] get yourself a good
lawyer get a lawyer yes you can't afford
a lawyer get the free public defender
one or go to a law school in your area
nine times out of ten they've got a
third-year law student who would [ __ ]
love to defend the living [ __ ] you for
free don't believe what all your pothead
friends are gonna tell you and [ __ ] like
they'll hype you up they'll get you
scared they'll make you feel relaxed but
they're just there they are not a lawyer
take their advice don't take your crazy
uncle Larry's advice just go around
there tell them that you were this just
carry a fake ID all right so we've been
going for a long time thanks for
listening if you've made it an hour with
us that's that's Ernie yes it sure does
so does anybody have would you like to
shout out any social media or anything
anything that you want to say since you
got a microphone in your face and some
people is listening I'll start going
we'll just go to the left here you got
anything you'd like to say over there my
friend just take it out kind of quiet
this episode but it's all good
Mike had a lot to say it's cool I wasn't
trying all right
way Mike people don't get don't get
[ __ ] by being nervous how do our
friends follow you on social media you
can find
at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter or Pablo for
sensible cannabis laws on Facebook I
blow for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook make sure you support that
click it give it a like follow it check
out what Mike posts share it observe it
it's good [ __ ] you people should start
paying attention to politics do get
registered to vote this next year's
gonna be interesting in most states
I wonder if Randy ever listens to the
podcast poor Randy and his little
squared doll he suspects might not be
pre-approved somebody somebody share
this podcast with Randy let him learn
the truth
all right sloppy we're gonna move over
to you Mike thanks for coming again bro
you gotta take time away from your
youngster to come hang out with us
high-five your boy for me
nice sloppy sloppy oh how can all the
people listening how can they find you
on social media Instagram Twitter
Facebook however you want to do I am
sloppy nine one nine on everything
except for tumblr I think it's sloppy
brains
yeah sloppy brains I didn't make that
but somebody made it for me oh and then
ya dead god nine one nine as well it's
our music so should I check that out
pick it follow that didn't know that was
you if that's me boy nice alright
fifty miles to and from work every day
it's fifty miles each way 100 miles on
the road there's one exit where I go it
probably takes me 10 minutes just to get
on the damn on-ramp because the
construction in Colorado Springs right
now ah if you're in the left lane you
should be passing somebody if I am
behind you in the left lane I'm not an
[ __ ] see the left lane is for passing
yeah that Lane over there to the right
is for the slower moving traffic there
are big signs on the interstate it's a
slower traffic keep right that means
[ __ ] you if I'm riding your ass in
the left lane all it means is you're
conceited [ __ ] that's
don't flick your cigarette at me don't
give me the finger put on your damn
blinker and over and let it pass you and
I don't even care if you're going ten
miles over and I'm trying to go 20
honestly not to sound like like a like
[ __ ] it but the left lane is the go as
fast as you please and risk getting a
ticket link just radio and then get back
in the right lane as soon as you pass
somebody get in the right lane keep
doing it people be like oh you're
weaving a lot I'm like no I'm driving
correctly you [ __ ] idiot like this
says keep writing less passing truth
don't be that that's social justice
warrior that tries to driving is not a
game you're playing with people's lives
sometimes when people do stupid [ __ ] on
the and and I Drive a Prius nobody wants
to get beat up by the guy that was
driving the fries cuz then you got to go
home and lie you have to be like it was
six guys in a Jeep and it knows one dude
with a [ __ ] Bob Ross afro hopping out
here and whoopin your ass out the Priya
and then get back in there to Bob Ross
Prius driving away in all yours
[Music]
Adele it's hard to pull up in your car
goes we know that's where you're wrong
you don't hear the I have literally had
people in the car and then drove off and
they're like you started alright so
we've got a long time if you guys been
listening for this long I love all of
you we're gonna wrap up this part of the
show we're gonna take some dabs and I
will be back to put a tail on this
episode
alright guys I want to send another huge
thank you to our guests big shout out to
buzzy big shout to my Kenny huge shot at
the sloppy for joining us I want to give
you another thank you for listening with
this long episode I'll be back in seven
days with another episode I will have
Rob from sour seeds here we're going to
talk about selecting a male plant for
breeding it should be a great
educational episode I need to give
another shout-out to our sponsor big
shot to hit man glass make sure you
check them out WWWE bang glass comm if
you would like to sponsor the show or if
you have a product you would like me to
review send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com i would love
to hear from you please follow me on
twitter it's at g f YH podcast you can
find us on Facebook
it's just grow from your heart you can
also follow me on Instagram it's Irie
underscore genetics guys thank you again
for listening I'm out for this week I
want to give you a huge shout out to my
ninja Spence and until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 121 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education if you're
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated jabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Ross - Jeff I'm going to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I want to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band for
letting me use their music on my show
big shout to catch the entire mystic
roots crew
I also want to give you huge shout out
to my friends at hitman glass hitman
glass when I buy a new rig I like to buy
something made in America by an American
and that's why I support hitman glass
looking for a new piece I recommend you
check out www.montgomeryvillenissan.com
[Music]
and I will be sitting at the table stay
tuned alright ladies and gentlemen
welcome back I am back with our good
friend Rob from sour seeds how you doing
tonight bro how you doing man thank for
having me oh dude thanks for coming
taking this time out of your day always
I've been talking we're both busy cats a
lot of things on your head I'm impressed
too much you looking forward to the
cannabis cup
absolutely so this will be the first
time we've spoke about this on the
podcast the cannabis cup that was
planned for Denver over the 4/20 weekend
Denver said no they did not issue the
permits that were needed high times
response was to move the cannabis cup to
Pueblo Colorado yeah that's where we are
that is our location that is my town
that's where this podcast is recorded so
the pod cat no matter where the podcast
lands in Pueblo it will be 20 minutes
from my house at maximum that's I'm
pretty stoked on that we're gonna have a
whole bunch of cool people around here
we're gonna have a whole bunch of cool
[ __ ] to do I'm hoping to get a whole
bunch of cool people on the podcast
since it's nearby they can either come
here and record in the kitchen slash
studio podcast setup or I've got a
portable unit we'll take hopefully we
get a whole bunch of cool folks don't be
afraid to come you guys a lot of people
seem to be talking [ __ ] on Facebook
about Pueblo Colorado
all the people that are talking [ __ ]
have never been here well that's it and
I'm from Florida and I love it here so
that tells you something right there
yeah it's I landed here because the
research there you go that that's even
worse I landed here because the research
the one I got here I visited Denver I
didn't visit the springs I've been and I
was at South Wallenberg but I've been
all over for being here a short amount
of time in three years in a Colorado
it's a nice humble town you get to know
the people here they'll take care of you
yeah yeah Denver's too expensive Springs
is a kind of a military vibe I think is
a high-crime - okay yeah I've been
working Springs now and I see a lot of
wonky [ __ ] on my breaks honestly I see
some strange always going down in
Springs yeah yeah well there are a
couple of parts of Pueblo that I would
not go to but not bad you guys so come
hang out at the Cannabis Cup have a good
time sour seeds should have a booth out
there you know I'll be running around I
don't have a booth I will not do a booth
this year I'll have an IRA genetics
t-shirt on I'll be running around having
a good time that's a long ways away but
we're stoked about it the Cannabis Cup
is coming to Pueblo Colorado
I don't be afraid come see us we're
gonna do a little show about breeding
cannabis we want to do a show about
selecting a male plant
sorry we're both coughing over here I'm
taking some dad's Rob smoking a joint
what strain are you smoking on bro
in common the King Tut smells the most
kind of a it's gonna unique smell very
unique smell I don't even know how to
describe that ah it almost reminded me
of a specific turpenoid I can't remember
which one we decided it smelled like
anymore thank you for the heads up there
I can never remember the name of little
it's always the one that I forget the
herb smells like it's got a lot of
little oil in it anyway we're jokin over
here cuz we're getting high I'm smoking
some terrific's Sour Death Star wax
shadow to the turf ex crew all right
we're gonna do a podcast about selecting
a male plant for breeding if you're
trying to breed some seeds there are a
few things to look for in a male plant
so let's say you buy yourself a 10 pack
I would do it to ten packs if you're
trying to do a Fino hunt to find a male
but not everybody's got the room
try to do at least two 10 packs there's
power
numbers the more plants the better I
agree 20 to 50 is a good number right
you can usually find super plants in 20
to 50 just astounding keepers a standout
yeah and if you can't do that many at a
time just do them in phases do 10 find a
keeper out of that 10 do 10 more find
the best out of those 2 out of those 10
and then you got to stack up against
each other keep doing it until your room
is fooled in a certain eliminating [ __ ]
that's right I even sometimes a right
out of the gate you can kind of tell you
know you have those seeds that just look
like they're gonna have a hard time
they're gonna struggle and you can tell
whenever they open the show they have
the little tiny leaves or sometimes are
mutated or doesn't look as strong or
vibrant as the others I just go ahead
and Chuck as a breeder as somebody who
is I've read a lot of plants and if you
were looking for a male plant you're
going to have to learn to get rid of
some plants and not be too attached to
your babies be ruthless yes be ruthless
these are not humans these are little
baby plants and you are creating the
future of cannabis if you do not pull
those ugly little [ __ ] you are going
to ruin and [ __ ] up and you're gonna
[ __ ] the progression of cannabis yes
you are and we don't want to do that
we're breeding to improve the genetics
so if you have a plant you start a bunch
of seeds you got a couple that are kind
of wonky looking you got one with the
[ __ ] up leave don't be afraid to get
rid of it as they grow keep a good eye
on them um so before we get to that part
let's talk about what the male plant is
going to bring to our breeding project
when we hit a male plant with pollen - a
female plant that accepts pollen that
has pistols it's going to create seeds
that are going to have traits of both
plants what is the male mostly going to
bring to the table here I feel like it's
going to bring a lot of the pest
resistance and a lot of the vigor and a
lot of the shape that's it that's a lot
of what it is the hybrid vigor and
without that male side of the family you
really can't catch that true hard figure
like that um I always tell people all
the time you know you can't create you
know Halle Berry's by eliminating half
gameful I like believe but that people
catch on there all right so yeah we need
the male to bring that good structure
and
resistance I think a lot of the flavor
comes from Mama comes from the girl so
when you're looking for structure and
shape a lot of it is gonna come from the
boy so now we could talk a little bit
about what to look for in a male plant I
keep saying the structure I like a male
plant if you're breeding a sativa you're
gonna want one that gets a little bit
taller the males are always gonna win
you're when you're in veg the males are
always gonna start taking off a little
taller their goal is to get above the
females so that when they pollinate
their pollen falls down onto the girl so
that's a good hint well they're growing
in veg look for that one that's taken
off that might be a boy for you so
you're looking for if you've got a
sativa you want the one that keeps not
too tall and doesn't take off too much
because you don't want to make your
progeny skyrocket immediately but you
want to find the one that's the right
shape of you almost want to find what
you want your girls to look like you
want the boy to look the shape to be
what you want your females to look like
is what I think I'm trying to say so
fine look for that you want tight close
node spacing you don't want a whole
bunch of gaps in between your branches I
don't like it when a plant spits out
really long branches like Tahoe say the
oh geez that was about to come right out
of my mouth the og family the whole
family over there on that side even
grapes top row G and some of the other
ones that are hybrids most of them take
off because the boys like you're saying
the structure it comes from the male is
a perfect example Joseph the Joseph male
that gage uses everything they crossed
that great male by the way but
it comes out tall a lot of the times you
get mostly dominant phenotypes of
stretchy plants because the stretchy
stretchy with little popcorn balls it's
a dominant OG male and that's that's
what's going on there it's that
structures taken over the dominance from
that male plant in this do G dominance
and that oh jeez always the cushions
have always had had that dominance and
it really there's an Afghan heritage
it's just trace back it's recessive
Afghan genes that are really strong and
they're always gonna come forward and
breed true unless you find a dominant
gene from a different side of the family
that breeds just as hard like something
from blue dream for example good example
of a good breeding parent or white widow
used to be a really good breeding parent
I've spread to white widow with two
other strains and it does very well
that's exactly and that's what you're
doing at the time you take another s'ti
of genotypes from different parts of the
world Brazil South America things like
that and then diversifying them against
things like OG coaches which are
originally derivative Afghan places like
that they're mostly purged into
California East Coast places with
coastlines
and then out out a lot of the stuff that
started off in the Dutch genetics has
those real thin leaves because it was
all bred for indoor cultivation and
things like that and genetics Moroccan
genetics you see a lot of Spain a lot of
Spanish genetics that's where you see
the influx of that in Netherlands so I
want to give a shot at the gauge between
genetics since we were talking about the
grape stopper OG there those guys
finally took home a cannabis cup for the
grape stopper good work guys nothing but
love and respect free gauge grits m4k
mk4 and key play the whole true they
kind of help me get a little start in
the cannabis industry so much much love
much respect shutout for that so look
for something that doesn't get too tall
too crazy if you're looking for an
indica if you're trying to breathe it
into Camille find the shortest stoutest
[ __ ] dias one you can find probably
with those big fattest leaves you can
find the who that why there's dinner
plate leaves if you can camp out under
those leaves if you can almost make a
hammock under those leaves that'd be a
sweet male to breed with if you're
looking for a nice indica plant so you
want something with nice nice tight
closed note spacing so if you can find a
male plant you got a flower about you
guys
Ejim I'll start looking for note there
structure in veg watch what they do you
don't have to get them too tall take a
clone off of them label the clone that
matches the so clone a to plant a clone
be to plant be flower your plants out
see what they do if you've got females
and you're looking for males you can
just go ahead and toss the females or
you can finish them out have some buds
I will take my male plants and flower
them all the way out to see what they do
all the way to like 7 8 maybe 9 weeks
into flower I want to see if they're
gonna produce trichomes I want to see if
they're gonna produce a whole bunch of
pollen I want to see if they're just
barren some plants will only produce a
little bit of pollen as a breeder you
can see which pollen will be so there's
kind of grainy pollen I don't feel like
that pollens worth a [ __ ]
it's the pre pollen it's the pollen
before your plants actually start
busting out that real grainy dusty [ __ ]
I don't think that is good you want to
let that if you're gonna collect pollen
let that fall let that get away and then
collect that like it's about 14 days
into the pollen e pollination that's
about 10 to 14 days into when they bust
open that's when the really good pollen
starts coming out it's a little softer a
little smoother to the touch
plants fully mature in the flower at
that point hormones going over so if
you're playing is producing trichomes
and a whole bunch of resin and has the
perfect structure you want to breed with
that I like to rub the stem and smell
the stem of my plants my favorite thing
if it smells like puke it's a good thing
trash can and vomit that's a good to me
that's a lot of that when you smell that
stem and if he if the male you know
across the board and say you have a
bunch in a row from your phyno hunt that
you're doing put them all next to each
other sit down smell each one of them
side by side make sure you're cleaning
your hands each time via really good
profile what each one is doing usually
the ones it stinks the worst is the best
one yeah typically and then you judge
narrow it down by smell and then narrow
down by structure sight use all your
senses don't don't eliminate anything
you know feel free to take a leaf and
snap one off and taste the stem a little
bit if it's sour and tart tea is stuff a
lot of the times and you're using hardly
no nutrients at all it's a good thing
it's telling you I got a lot of terpenes
I got a lot to add to the table they're
definitely the bail is definitely going
to contribute to the flavor I think the
mama definitely over overwhelms the
flavor category but the male is going to
contribute to the amount of flavor just
use any old male you want to use the
best one you can yeah so if you bested
ten pack of seeds you probably find you
know maybe five males hopefully you know
five females five males oh you're gonna
toss two of those right away one of
them's gonna be funky
one of them's gonna be run so let's go
away now you got three I think that I
never used I personally know that I
never used that first plant to show me
male flowers I don't like to take that
first one he's too dominant I feel like
he's going to do too much to my breeding
he's gonna all the plants are gonna look
like that one if I've got three of them
I kinda would lean toward the third one
to flower if I've got five if I had five
males it worked well probably that third
or fourth one would be the one that I
would use I wouldn't go right for that
first one that busted out it's too
obvious me I always choose it honestly I
when I'm doing my breeding I always
choose it honest like like based on what
the mothers doing what I'm trying to do
if I'm trying to say like if I'm out
crossing like a blue dream or a sativa
or something close to it has a longer
flowering time and I want to come in
with an indica and actually shorten its
flowering time then then that's when I
would choose a male that it's bust out
first because I want to take that flower
and Tommy that's perfect thing good but
but if you say you have a little indica
dominant but you want to make it a true
hybrid and you want to make it go a
little bit longer in the garden say more
if it's a seven eight week and you want
it to go more like eight nine maybe
tennis or something like that then
that's you know another reason you'd go
with a long and don't be afraid to have
plants that flower for a long time you
guys I know nine ten and eleven weeks
sounds like scary flowering times but I
flowered plants for 14 and 15 weeks and
what happens is amazing once they get
that right that's far
Sour Diesel is a good example of that
going that long 10 11 weeks on it but
it's well worth it in the end I mean
you're getting a connoisseur product
that you can't gain anywhere else and
the testers also you the wrists for and
the harvest weights come through it
makes it well worth it but I had an
African land race that didn't have a
name and it grew colas
I couldn't down at week 14 and the coals
were bigger than my legs I think I think
it's the biggest complication with all
growers uh
young to old is patience yeah I think
it's the hardest thing we all have to
overcome just in life that's it in
general that's it alright I got to take
a drink I'm about to choke and then
we're gonna keep this moving
all right I'll let it that part out I
was gonna beat Boxster oh man you should
have thought have been French I might
not even edit it now since you're
beatbox and I might just leave that part
right there alright what else you want
to add to that but you don't anything
you want to add to - talking about
selecting a bale that we pretty much
covered I mean use all your senses you
know and breathe for a purpose that
that's is the biggest thing breed for
purpose I cannot stress nothing for
purpose at all because if it's good and
you want to bang it together with
something else that just looks good just
don't do it just because to do it or
don't do it because you got a cool name
lined up do it be do it for purpose do
it for purpose we see too much of that
in the industry every day that you get
you know create the strain come up with
the name lastly yes and if you do make
something and it sucks okay so let's say
you make a stream you take whatever
you've got this mail and then you've got
this prized female you throw pollen all
over it you let it go so once you
pollinate it's gonna take you you know
about six more weeks until the seeds are
ready maybe six or eight more weeks
before he can chop that plant down I let
the plants dry until they're crispy at
that point I just chop them down let
them get super crispy and then I just
rub them and the seeds fall out then I
go collect all the seeds then I blast
the material into oil honestly but so
then you gotta grow those seeds yourself
I would recommend you grow a hundred of
them just at least germinate a hundred
of them right away and see what they do
before you give any of them away to
anybody germinate a hundred of them veg
out at least fifty and flower at least
25 of them dry uhm kiram smoke em see
what they do if it sucks flush the seeds
down the toilet get rid of them feed
them to your birds it's human we all we
all make mistakes and you can only
control what you're doing so much it's
not its nature I would say nature you
can only control so much of what you're
doing the rest is left in her hands yeah
and sometimes things just don't want to
breed together I made a strain that
totally sucked it produced giant colas
that tasted amazing but it would not get
you high at all you could smoke the
entire crop and ooze no high at all my
main thing was a breeding we had one
recently that came out with a Dante's
Inferno
it was a big hit for a lot of people
because a lot of people do our
connoisseur smokers out there that like
I brewing things like Grinspoon and
other other strains out there that are
just absolutely 100% top-grade
connoisseur weed they yield like crap
you know Girl Scout cookies I mean it's
not a known for its yield it's known for
its power and flavor every sweet funk
taste oh that's it and you're not
growing that as a cash crop you know you
know a lot of the times you're growing
that for personal and if you do you are
growing for cash crop you have a lot
what are we even talking about to get us
nails but anyway I did have was
something I wanted to add to the RAL
terpenes breeding for Terps um one of
our perfect ones it's coming up now it's
gonna be one of our big frontrunner is
the s1 version of our blueberry fuel umm
this cut has amazing terpenes it soft
it's just all day it's hard to explain
it's really really hard to explain it's
it's got a little bit everything in it
and the reason that is is because when
you're choosing males and females and
you're doing that breeding work you know
actually look at the terpene profile if
you don't know and you can get it tested
spend the forty fifty seventy-five bucks
whatever it takes get it tested did you
have paperwork to back your stuff up if
you're in a legal state you should test
and the more widely it's becoming
nowadays do you have literally half the
country now we're 50/50 and it's taken
over and you should be able to get it
tested by someone somehow somewhere or
almost you know use your connections to
reach out and then get it done you know
it makes a big difference I mean you can
find out like a terpene profile and then
try to match it up with something that
absolutely would complement those
terpenes but doesn't have them like are
very fuel blue dream which is a good
clone only a good breeding parent breach
true breach solid it doesn't isn't it's
known the breach table I've read a
couple good strains with it you know you
can pop 100 200 seeds and you might get
wanted to harm ease out of it just
because it breached that stable and and
it usually takes the dominance of things
but when you breathe wood was something
like oh geez and Diesel's and things
like that you had a whole different
terpene profile that really complements
the blueberry muffin ears and the blend
and the creaminess of the Blue Dream it
just stands out and everybody creates a
whole nother animal
you don't even those people when he
smoked with him first tell him what it
is lastly they did never even what a
guest it came from blue dream that's the
thing look at it never would have
thought and taste it never would have
thought and it just peels him back he's
got you know diesels it's got oh gee
tones it's got blueberry taunts it's got
creamy tones in it and I think I've
smoked some of that with you before I
think you brought that last time and it
was definitely a tasty strain because
that was what you brought for me to
smoke so I've noticed everything I
breathed to the Blue Dream I've never
used it as a mail obviously because it's
a clone only and it's a girl but
everything I've read to it it has made
huge colas everything you put to it
that's it that's a - that's why we did
the og cross one typically was the DEXA
gaining a little bit extra you yeah
because oh jeez our lanky and stuff I
was trying to put more I bred grateful
dog to the Blue Dream and I call it the
Blue Heeler and my point was to put more
vigor to the Grateful dog just make it a
little bit bigger a little chunkier but
I'm not a fan of the flavor of blue
dream that it's grow its grow eat it's a
stripper weed it is it's real it's kind
of like a bland blueberry it's real
muffiny and real creamy it's like it
tastes like Jiffy muffins
[Music]
weird flashback yeah so I put that to
the Grateful dog and it made it more
pungent and more more piney and then it
brought out a bottom layer of fruit i
bred it to the king Kim cross the grapes
topper og and we call it the watts the
blue stopper but uh that one made it
much stinkier and that the kink in
grapes na / og made little tiny popcorns
and now it makes Spears since we put it
to the Bluejays
people all the time you know I've know
you've had I know it's been around for a
long time held 15 years now but don't
count it out as a breeding mother with
hybrids you know don't see blue dream on
the label and automatically turn it away
because you're probably passing up a
really really good cross I know a lot of
people that do not like blue dream at
all shadows of those guys they know who
they are
gonna see your names on the show what up
boys no no a lot of the nightmare lines
people fell in love with and things like
that the reason why they called it
nightmare where you think nightmare
dream I mean put two and two together
people didn't even know no yeah lynnie
Tom like now there's no blue dream in
there alright so something important I
should mention this is uh this is kind
of a breeding by eye technique here you
could make Eliel charts you could take a
whole bunch of notes you should take a
whole bunch a whole bunch of notes
either way but this is kind of just a
breeding breeding with love girl from
your heart sort of do it by your eye old
school sort of thing we're breeding with
a lot of experience here so I think if
you find a good male you're gonna want
to do a Fino hunt of at least 20 seeds
you're gonna want to find one with a
good structure you want it to look you
want it to have this shape that you want
the babies to have find one that makes
resin if you can find one that makes a
whole bunch of pollen if it doesn't make
enough pollen you're not gonna make
enough seeds find one with real close
node spacing find one that smells real
good
try not to select the very first one
that goes into flower and shows you that
it's a boy definitely do not use any
male plants that show any sign of
hermaphrodite male plants can
hermaphrodite also you'll see pollen
sacks you'll see little mail sacks
popping out and then right out of the
sides you'll see female pistols come out
yeah it's not those aren't nut hairs
[Music]
that will create lots of problems in the
future you do not want to breed
hermaphrodites that's right that is not
a good that's the exact opposite of what
we're aiming for so yeah and then pay
attention that pollen you guys and when
the pollen does start spitting you don't
want that first grainy sandy pollen you
want that the pollen will when you catch
some of it and put it in your hand and
rub it in the palm of your hand it'll
feel smooth and silky it'll feel real
nice and then when you leave the grow
room gonna have to hose yourself down
get a mister like a sprayer and spray
like a pump sprayer like you'd almost
used to pump pesticides get one of those
and just
bring yourself down and wash your hands
because tap water worked really great as
chlorine it's safe for everything plants
and there you go that'll deactivate any
palm that you've got on you and then if
you are going from that pollen room and
do a room that has female plants you can
always hose them down as you walk in
just hit them with the sprayer and they
won't receive pollen for a little while
just trying to prevent that pollen from
getting onto your females if you don't
want to breed because if you have a male
plant in the house or in the room or in
the facility with your females it's
going to try to get pollen everywhere
one thing I've noticed bro you can tell
me if you've recognized this
I've got separate breeding rooms I've
got an upstairs in the downstairs area
an area over here an area over here that
I've got a male in one area and females
in a totally different area I've noticed
when I've got girls and a flowering male
in the same house the girls get a little
stickier and they flower a little more
quickly do you think those girls know
there's a male around somewhere good
question that is a good question it goes
into some of my forte lighting and it
actually yeah they do
they know because of infrared lighting
okay let's use infrared lighting to see
around them that's why you have natural
spacing in the woods
that is why trees naturally spaced
themselves out naturally weed out
smaller ones below them and around them
and you typically go into the woods and
new pine tree forests and things like
that and they have okay so infrared
lighting plants know there's pheromones
I believe as well okay because well they
can take in co2 and they can they
breathe out carbon dioxide you know
there's always a constant intake between
oxygen and carbon dioxide battling right
and in a lot of their annual plants so
they built over thousands and millions
of years beyond this earth they have
built defense mechanisms to try to
breathe that is their purpose that's why
they're hermaphrodite honestly if
anybody remembers the first Jurassic
Park allegation say nature will always
find a way and then y'all said you have
eggs
that is why because nature will always
find a way and you're talking about
something that is on a total different
levels than what you think it's
mind-boggling to think how you know an
evolution sense how far ahead some
plants are then then what we are you
know we tend to think we are the kings
of the world you know weird sin of the
universe every day its weak but really
if you look at an ant if he was our size
he could lift your house right yeah they
can lift like 500 times in a natural
weight and it's writing this smile at
you in your house what it is you know
it's really more about perception than
anything you just push with all the
listeners how you perceive things it's
pretty much pretty well the whole plants
mission is to survive alright so you got
anything else so you want to add to this
podcast it sounds like we've covered
selecting a male I hope that made a lot
of sense to you we can do this better
than they can I really do I think I
think the people are going to show them
that we've held the put we've held the
state fair here for how long and
somebody we know actually made a good
point on social media that uh it's 11
days long 25,000 people a day yeah if
anybody can do a Polk County can do it
right we can host that many folks we got
enough hotels eating places that's it
because I actually plan to put together
a podcast I posted it up to social media
asking my local friends for a little bit
of help we're gonna put a podcast
together and be a little bit of a tour
guide for you I'm gonna find places for
you to stay places for you to eat things
for you to do gives you a little bit of
information about our town so that when
you come here you're prepared and then
we can all have a good time and take a
bunch of dads and be friends and you'll
have a good time with us it's gonna be
such a blast a lot of people talk a lot
of trash but look what's about to happen
here
the biggest cannabis event on the planet
is going to be here in our backyard
I think it's going
I know it's gonna be a blast cos I have
fun everywhere I go Spencer competing
this year I can't speak for Spencer Rock
boy what's up Nana everybody's doing
well over there we just gave Chad outs
two dogs on the podcast that's pretty
rad alright make sure you guys follow my
buddy sour seeds on social media how can
people find you bro
find us on Twitter you can find us on
Instagram or Facebook we have our own
website wwm I'll hide NGO which will be
changing over to us our C company calm
Mona calm we're gonna go eat Commerce
you can get our happens and get custom
links right tor right to our right to
our sites that sell our seeds bro thanks
for the hat pins you brought me a nice
little selection a happens I really like
the the dab scraper that's pretty nice I
appreciate that
man I enjoy doing it this just keeps
everything fresh man are your products
available on the dank team.com at this
time we gotta get you in touch with our
buddies over there talk to you make sure
you guys check out dank team comm let
them know that we sent you there's a
little bit of hydrogen etic stuff
available go check that out there's some
black cherry chem available up there
good by the way well thank you thank you
he grew some over to green and healthy
wellness it'll be on the shelves by the
time this podcast comes out very likely
be gone just made some of the best
concentrates I've had in Colorado dude
honestly I mean I take top-five updated
thank you just the flavors off you can
taste the cherry my two favorite thing
happens you see two strains and a
breather that's bread as many times as
we have you can see what it's gonna do
you're like oh if I put that it's an art
there smartest tree involved in it and
we're not don't don't ever let us think
that we're taking that away it's not
just pure science there's art to all of
the extractions growing breeding
especially absolutely it takes it takes
a good eye and a little bit hard you
gonna listen to the plants you got to
lay down next to them
listen to him gotta feel the vibe from
the plants help ya bro thank you for
coming out thank you for asking rolling
joints and smoking down ahead of joint
guys you guys fill your head with
thoughts while I fill my head with smoke
there you go people think I don't smoke
a lot of flower but I've been smoking a
lot lately yeah it was me I'm guilty of
that once you get to that level you just
hold on to a joint for a few minutes and
smoke it these are my years clean sober
do it guys two months almost two months
we mentioned that you had a problem one
night on the show and we didn't talk too
much about it I just said that you're
planning on coming but you had a little
issue yes yeah from smoking cigarettes
he smoked too much well I'm Wade you're
prepared and back in it getting there
all right some time with me you guys
we're gonna wrap up this part of the
show room and take a bunch of dabs I'm
gonna get a fresh drink and then I will
be back to wrap up this show all right
you guys that was a lesson and how to
select male plants for breeding I hope
you learned something I want to send
another huge thank you shout out to Rob
thanks again for joining me big shout
out to everybody and thus our seeds crew
I'll be back in a week with another
episode I'm putting together an episode
on how to get your meed badge so that
you can work here in the Colorado
marijuana industry legally I'm also
putting together a tour guide episode
the cannabis cup is coming to my
hometown of Pueblo Colorado so I'm going
to make an episode about places for you
to stay places for you to eat places for
you to avoid and maybe some fun things
to do before during and after the
cannabis cup while you're here so look
forward to those episodes I hope you
check those out don't forget to check
out our sponsor hit man glass visit hit
man glass comm also follow dug in
Instagram it's at hit man glass Dougie
on Instagram if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review send
me
email let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll get you all of the
information that you do need you guys
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the review section I would appreciate it
if you give me a five star rating
be honest click what you think after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comment on a future episode I would
love it if you would follow me on social
media you can find me on Twitter it's at
G fyh podcast on Facebook it's just grow
from your heart podcast and if you want
to follow me on instagram it's i reaiiy
rie underscore genetics I read genetics
on Instagram I'd appreciate it if you
give me a follow check that out click
like all that good stuff you guys don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and I read genetics
Colorado dot-com make sure you check out
all the old episodes if you're a new
listen or go back and learn a whole
bunch of great stuff if there's a drill
lesson that you would like me to cover
something you have questions about
simply email me girlfriend hard at
hotmail.com I will work it into a future
episode you guys that's all I've got for
you this week I want to give a huge
shout out to my ninja Spence
thanks again for listening until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 122 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friend is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff phone - thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
to cat and the entire crew
you guys sitting across the table from
me is our good buddy white Mike thank
you for joining us bro thanks for coming
man thanks for taking some time away
from the rig away from the job and
especially away from the new baby thanks
for hanging out big shout out to the
wife for taking some time and let me
come hang out thanks for joining the
podcast let's see where we want to start
I want to give a big shout out to my
friend John Anthony Moses I know you're
hanging out listening to the podcast
thanks for listening but I appreciate it
[Music]
the cannabis cup was supposed to be in
Denver on 4/20 supposed supposed to but
unfortunately the city of Denver
declined off the permit I'm not sure
exactly
Denver officials declined all the
permits they were either way they said
not gonna do it nope they had some
issues namely out-of-state dispensaries
handing out samples and what was
supposed to be 14 thousand people a day
actually being 35,000 people a day all
right Colorado where Mike and I reside
yes they claimed we were going to do the
festival on the 18th 19th 20th 21st
within that range those original goal
they put up fliers they put out some
announcements on their website they put
out some stuff on Twitter or Instagram
and Facebook oh [ __ ] the next weekend so
the permits have been entered
they've been submitted they're being
reviewed so far the city of Pueblo has
not said if they are going to allow or
decline the cannabis cup to happen in
Pueblo Colorado this episode will come
out in two or three days and I'm pretty
sure the decision will not be made at
that time so right now there is no
definite location for the high times
his Cup in Colorado and it if it does
happen it will be moved to the weekend
of the 22nd and the 23rd if it does
happen in Pueblo Colorado at all yeah I
read something today claiming that this
move was it was sort of an option B if
Adams County didn't go through and
they've been looking for bigger
locations than the Denver mark and the
location down here in public claims to
be able to handle the 25 or 30 thousand
people a day no problem so I'm not too
familiar with the location I thought
Denver Mart was great but of course when
I heard that it was going to be in
Pueblo I was awesome that shows a lot a
huge chunk of money out of going to the
cup really just want to go to the cup
yeah you gotta go and it's a multiple
day of vein I have to go just because
that's how I go to all three days or
have to go to all three days you gotta
be up there for you know paying top
dollar for hotel rooms right now it
never sucks and all the shitty hotels go
expensive if you think you're gonna pay
70 or 80 for a hotel those 70 and 80
dollar hotels are now a hundred and
thirty knows that 420 is a big weekend
in Denver and they cash the [ __ ] and
unfortunately a bunch of people have
already booked plane tickets they have
booked the rooms in the big complaint
about the cup in Denver was always that
the planning was sort of like a d-minus
like the roof didn't fall in like nobody
got squashed but other than that it was
kind of a [ __ ] well when they
change their mind that they weren't
going to do it in Denver and they
decided to move it to Pueblo a lot of
people were like yeah [ __ ] Pueblo we
sure do but then when they push the date
to a completely different weekend I'm
sure that a large portion of the people
that we're going to attend just decided
[ __ ] it they weren't even gonna try if
the cup goes off in Pueblo because it's
not at all a sure thing at this point
folks it's the decision comes down to
the County Planning Department and then
if they decide yes it can be appealed by
any number of people and our local
sheriff has told the press that if it's
approved he's going to appeal
um because he doesn't he doesn't have
any idea how he's gonna handle 35,000
cannabis cup attendees not because of
the number of attendees but because
they're attending the cannabis cup
something about the event makes it
special how we're going to be drive
we're going to be too high to drive what
I saw in a statement they're really
scared of DAV's yeah to the average to
normal person who's never seen cannabis
and sees me pull out a torch and heat up
a nail and do this crack like looking
drug I can understand the fear that he's
a police officer he's a sheriff he needs
to figure out what's going on with the
medical marijuana community and be in
touch with us and come join us instead
of be afraid of us and try to persecute
us and prosecute us right spend 10
minutes talking to any member of the
community a lot of big crazy weird words
but when it comes down to it I'm a
peaceful chilled out dude and I'd love
to sit down and have a conversation with
anybody who needs to be education that's
what today is there was there was a lot
of hilarity I think in this story if you
look at some of the reasons stated and
quoted that the permits wound up in
Denver were denied the two big reasons
that are cited over and over and over
again in the press are a woman jumped
out of her car like somewhere in or
around the cannabis cup where she had
just attended her was on her way it
doesn't really specify but like clearly
marijuana use doesn't cause jumping out
of cars I've smoked people if you know
me like colorado sold almost a buoy
those with we last year if it cost
jumping out of cars we would know 90% of
the people on the plane right like
that's not an effect we wouldn't see
four years down the road jump out of
cars I would have done backflips out of
buses by now right and there were 35,000
people a day at the cup and one woman
jumped out of a car like that exactly
like a fat related they forgot to
mention in the article that she took a
DAB and then she went and did a whole
bunch of Molly and then she drank
whiskey and then
jumping out of a car one of the time and
she was stone sober and fight another
boyfriend
so I was I was friends with the
boyfriend and they should have long
story I'm not [ __ ] telling it now
let's not go there but yeah like that
wasn't drug or alcohol related that was
I can't be in this car another minute
[ __ ] craziness longer so do come to
Colorado and he come to pleasure if we
do have the cannabis cup here please
behave yourself represent yourself as a
positive cannabis user a responsible
cannabis user be careful they're going
to be looking for people driving too
high but they treat cannabis like
alcohol if you're going to be leaving
the cannabis cup have your cannabis in a
sealed container if you can put it in
the trunk of your car put your rig your
dabber your carb cap your torch and
especially your product any product
you've got that smokeable edible drink
full if it's cannabis infused related if
you can rub it on your balls put it in
the trunk of the car if you don't have a
trunk if you've got an SUV put it in the
backpack zip the backpack up put it way
in the back of the vehicle have it out
of reach of the driver don't get
yourself a DUI or an illegal possession
of cannabis ticket because that is still
a possible thing here in Colorado
if this cannabis cup if it goes off in
Pueblo is gonna be under a lot of
scrutiny and honestly Puebla could use
the cup down here and I'd really like to
see the event do well if it gets
approved at all I would love to see it
one of the big complaints in Adams
County was out-of-state dispensaries
coming here and selling weed and dabs at
their booths some of them were doing
donation legal mumbo jumbo other people
were straight doing sales um at least
according to recent reports and yeah
that's a big no-no here which is why
none of our local dispensaries were even
handing out product at the cup I get
that the cup is supposed to be the
community gathering and celebrating and
having a huge smoke out but how you hand
out samples or what people bring to
smoke like there's a lot of rules around
that you need to know the law and please
try to comply with it like as much as
practice' Bellaire phul please please
don't [ __ ]
for us we've worked really hard here to
do this we've got a good thing going
come have a good time I'm not trying to
be a dick about it come when you're at
the event take dabs sure your dad's with
your friends give me a fat dad take a
fat dad with me high-five me let's take
some selfies let's get on Instagram
together let's snap chat at the [ __ ] up
but be careful when you're driving away
from there keep your cannabis safe keep
your eyes not red be able to walk the
line be able to pass the tests remember
we did the episode a little while back
about interacting with law enforcement
be prepared for that [ __ ] if you're a
nervous person don't be extra high and
nervous when you're leaving the cut for
an extra hour you know understand if you
take a couple dad's hang out for an hour
I went back and listened to that episode
the one thing I realized I meant to
emphasize and didn't was the easiest way
to not get in trouble with law
enforcement and to be calm and cool
during those interactions is to not be
breaking the law you know that's
something my buddy Lewis shoutout Magoo
he goes you know what you forgot to
[ __ ] mention was don't have [ __ ]
expired plates don't have your tags
expired don't have a broken headlight
and taillight don't be an [ __ ] to
have a tracked windshield he said break
one rule at a time this is advice goofer
[Music]
but that's an old lawyer joke is like if
you've gotta break the law break one lot
of time and it's [ __ ] true like if
you've got weed in the car and you ain't
allowed to have weed make sure that
that's the only rule you're breaking if
you're speeding you're asking to get
caught if you're you've got a [ __ ] up
car you're asking to get Congress in a
lot of states if you look like Jeff
you're asking hey hey and what don't
know some of the listeners to me
occasionally some listeners don't know
this when people meet me or they hear my
voice somewhere they turn around and
like is that you cuz I go to the gross
tour sometimes and people like dude
that's [ __ ] you you guys I am six
foot five and I've got dreadlocks almost
to my knees I am not even joking my
dreadlocks go damn near to my knees now
I can close them in the car door I used
to roll them up in the car window but
now they're so long that that [ __ ] isn't
even thought about yeah they're long
tell testify for me Mike he's [ __ ]
ridiculous
with a gentle weave they could be like a
legit hammock or blanket this one here
is big
around then my torch I've watched steals
things from other people's hands without
[Music]
the dreadlocks around a little bit and
then no one wants my dreadlocks in their
face and or their beers dancing room in
Colorado it's not that unusual to see
some dreadlocks it's really unusual to
see locs this long all right but yeah in
other states you're a walking
advertisement for a dude that's high
yeah oh you should see me try to go
through the the TSA going through the
airport right they inspect my dreadlocks
they [ __ ] want to squeeze them and
see what's in there honey yeah so uh
guys if you're coming be careful
look out at the cup have a good time I
will be there look for me I'm gonna do a
shameless shout out here since the
Cannabis Cup in Denver will not be on
the week of on the day of 4/20
everyone's looking for something to do
on 4/20 in Denver I want to give a huge
shout out to an event called the secret
sash the secret Center will be happening
at the Gatsby Gardens in Denver Colorado
on 4/20 and I do invite you to join us
for more information you're gonna have
to follow the secret sash colorado on
instagram search them out we will get a
website going there's more happening our
homie Adam ill will be coming out to
deejay or not to deejay to host the show
I apologize I think it's a good if
you're a fan of the podcast you might
know who I'm talking about and it is not
nicotine so I'm just gonna cross that
one off a lot of people might think I'm
naked tea coming to DJ an event but we
do not so big for the Grammy Gatsby big
shot of the secret sash we want to get
the secret stash packed up we want you
there come check it out all right so we
do have a topic for this episode it's
not just gonna be - hi guys taking dabs
and rambling that's the topic our friend
she calls herself that one mountain girl
sent me a message on Instagram and she
said hey you guys should do a message
about how to get your badge in Colorado
so big shot it said that one mountain
girl for listening to the podcast also
big shout-out for following me on IG man
today and today it happened to a lot of
people but I noticed several Instagram
account
got wiped the [ __ ] out the green and
healthy wellness Instagram account for
the shop buh-bye
the tur pax account for their hash
buh-bye I'm afraid to open mine right
now look if it's even there because I
mean that's my crew you know what I mean
I grow the herb for green and healthy
and then it's blasted by derp X and
we're all tagged in the same posts
disappears I'll just create a Rasta Jeff
Instagram I region etics Instagram blast
it down so I'll just make a roster Jeff
if it disappears all that you know it's
like to post pictures of what's going on
and interact with my friends my family
out there so big that one mountain girl
also also shout-out to my friend Jessica
she kind of encouraged me to write this
episode she is a manager at a very
prominent dispensary in the Colorado
Springs area big shout out to her and
her staff and her dispensary big love
big hugs but just was like you should do
an episode we had a friend doing this
going through the same thing and I was I
thought about my query to it Mike and
just both have one person so now all
they have to do is refer that person to
this episode welcome new listener if you
learned about the podcast by somebody
saying hey listen to that you'll learn
how to get your badge welcome thanks for
joining us I'm Ross - Jeff it was my
buddy white Mike we're gonna teach you
how to get your badge I took a bunch of
notes get your badge in Colorado and
this is how to get a Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division badge so that
you're able to work in a legal
recreational and/or medical marijuana
facility this could be a dispensary
where you're either rolling joints all
day where you're a budtender if you're
there's a million different types of
jobs sensories but be prepared to start
at the bottom of the ladder kind of
regardless yeah yeah like you must
recover two million bucks but anything
you're gonna do in there you need a
badge from the owner to the budtender to
the joint roller
due to paints the walls yeah to the
lawyer need a badge the guys that come
in and build the place have to get
either real badges or visitor badges so
all the people that work for the
dispensary the grows the processing
facilities where extracts are made the
facilities where edibles and drinkables
are made the places where topicals are
made even the testing facilities where
the cannabis is tested for cannabinoids
they all are required to have a Colorado
marijuana enforcement agent badge which
requires a thorough FBI background check
fingerprints and an intensive intensive
application process if you don't meet
the requirements you're not gonna get a
badge we'll get to that we'll get to
that so let's talk about the steps on
how to get this badge because if you
want to work in a dispensary this is the
first thing that you need to do and this
is really really important if you're
thinking about moving here to work in
legal we'd know this before you move yes
there's one step in here that you'll
need to know people who moved here that
didn't know how to do none of this and
don't meet the requirements and so
they're [ __ ] yeah or they're stuck
trying to get a job doing whatever it is
it was they were doing that they hated
so much they moved across the country to
learn working legal weed but they're
trying to set up a black market grow to
survive right and they're struggling all
right so the first thing you gotta do if
you want to get a badge here in the
state of Colorado you've got to find the
application online they will put the
application in the shownotes I'll put a
link to the application let me read you
the website address if you've got a pen
in paper or if you want to type this
into your web browser quickly it is
Colorado dot gov slash Pacific the word
Pacific yes Colorado gov slash Pacific
slash enforcement slash medical -
marijuana - occupational - licensing so
it's Colorado gov slash Pacific slash
enforcement slash medical - marijuana -
occupational licensing yeah yeah well
hopefully somebody type that into their
web browser
hopefully somebody got that wrote it
down I'll put it in the show notes but
that's where you need to go to get the
application that's where you start it's
not super hard to find if you just
by name right there are a lot of things
to filter through though it's confusing
and what you're looking for yeah it does
take a minute of reading and kind of
clicking around to find the actual
application that you need cuz they've
got like four of them post right and
you're looking for either a key badge or
a support badge and we'll talk about
that in just a couple of seconds I think
I made a note to talk about that so find
the application read and review the
application you'll get to a part that
says this marijuana occupational
employee application form is an official
document if you provide false
information on your marijuana license
application and/or do not disclose all
information the application asks your
license is subject to denial or
revocation and you may be subject to
criminal prosecution the marijuana
Enforcement Division will conduct a
complete background investigation and
we'll check all sources of information
you are advised that it is better to
disclose all information than face
denial revocation or criminal
prosecution
so guys they're not bullshitting when
they say that I know a guy named Tim who
has been waiting months and months for
his badge because they are doing a
thorough investigation they found some
stuff on his record they're contacting
the state where that happened there
talking to the actual judge that resided
over my friends case to find out if he
can get his badge or not it's been a
long time he writes them letters all the
time and they reply with we're still
investigating so we'll get back to you
so they're not bullshitting they were
gonna go through this they're not
kidding disclose your [ __ ]
so it says if you need clarification of
any of the following questions please
contact any marijuana Enforcement
Division office so it means if it's not
clear to you call them because and when
we get into the requirements in a minute
like we'll get more specific but really
just tell the truth
there's no fudge in this know the
requirements if you don't meet them
straight up don't try cuz you ain't
gonna get passed and if you do it's a
special crime this is the age of the
internet if you did some [ __ ] like just
write it down they really don't care as
long as it violates a couple of
requirements and they play those
straight up and down for the most part I
might hurt one person who didn't get
their badge and they tried to make it
sound like a big conspiracy it was like
nah dude it was that felony three years
ago oh yeah the disqualifying conditions
it's
these questions go like this have you
ever discharged a sentence for a
conviction of a felony pursuant to any
state or federal law regarding the
possession distribution manufacturing
cultivation or use of a controlled
substance including probation or parole
within the last 10 years even if the
conviction occurred more than ten years
ago
so that means have you been in jail for
any felony is that what that means
that's no drug felonies in ten years is
what that questions asking about like
you have to have completed the jail
sentence and any probation or parole at
least 10 years before you apply for your
Emmy deep edge so ten years ago ten
years let's be specific it says drug
felony yes so you had to have drugs
involved in your felony and it has to be
more than ten years ago if that happened
if it was nine years and 365 days
because it's [ __ ] leap year so
condition number two have you served a
sentence including probation parole
within the last five years upon
conviction for any felony even if the
conviction occurred more than five years
ago so once again if you're on probation
or parole five years ago or within the
last five years you are not allowed to
work in the industry so no drug felonies
and ten no felonies period in five or
probation or parole yep and the
probation of parole for many of those
felonies has to be got done at least
that many years ago and this one is neat
are you a licensed physician making
patient recommendations yep if you're a
doctor in the industry you can't be
affiliate affiliated with the dispensary
you're involved with that part of it so
you don't need a badge that makes good
sense I understand that rule kind of
makes sense and I really get where
they're going with the felony rule
they're really trying to play it so that
the state can say with all reassurance
that people who were dealing drugs in
the past aren't owning dispensaries and
an easy way to do that is to make sure
that anyone convicted of selling drugs
doesn't get to be a dispensary owner for
at least the first decade and yeah that
kind of sucks for people who got busted
back in the day and they're now trying
to be totally straight-up legal
but that's how Colorado wants to play
this position part they just don't want
you to be a doctor hanging out alright
number four says have you had your
authority to act as primary caregiver
revoked by the state health agency so if
your you were somebody's primary
caregiver as not under the Medical
Marijuana type of caregiver but as their
caregiver for somebody who's elderly or
disabled if that's been revoked you are
not allowed to work in the cannabis
industry the next question is are you
under 21 years of age you have to be 21
years old when you apply it gotta be 21
that's not too hard to figure out 21 the
next question says are are not question
but let me take a sip here hold on talk
Mike I don't know what the next question
is but I can guess student loans are you
the spouse or child living in the
household of any person employed by the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
so if you're working for both sides yeah
yeah if your mom
you can't be a regulator and a profiteer
that there's special rules to prevent
that from happening for a junkie years
when you join the meed now because a
bunch of people we're going to work for
the meed
going through training doing a bunch of
meed inspections for like three or four
months and then getting a job at a
dispensary for like ten times to pay to
be a compliance officer because they
could put on their resume a mediator it
was happening so much the meed had to
pass special like non-compete clause
rules that they have to sign contracts
when this is their job DVD now that's
pretty good and then the next one on the
last one are you a sheriff deputy
sheriff police officer or prosecuting
officer or any officer or employee of
the marijuana state licensing authority
or a local licensing
then the next the next little cups don't
get no badges the next little note here
says stop if you answered yes to any of
you of the above questions by Colorado
law you cannot obtain or hold a Colorado
marijuana occupational employee license
those are just straight-up you can't get
a license period
don't try we'll find it with the FBI
background check yep so if you heard if
you qualify under any of that [ __ ] that
we just read you cannot work in Colorado
in the legal marijuana industry you're
gonna have to go to California or
Washington or Oregon or maybe Michigan
or who else is legal now Mike where can
people go the legal states Oregon Alaska
there's 23 medical marijuana States get
online look at the laws in each one see
which ones you can still work or or or
or what you should really do better make
it legalize cannabis where you are if
you can't work in the legal industry
that doesn't mean you can't lobby on its
behalf that's the truth throw that out
there yeah you can you can do what you
can do for your area maybe you can't be
a grower maybe you can't be a manager
you can't be an owner but you can always
be a lobbyist you can be an activist you
can do your part in some way shape or
form that is for sure
so after it asks you all these questions
and you check no to them or yes to them
it makes you sign and it says I have
thoroughly read and understand the
questions above and understand that I
cannot hold a Colorado marijuana license
if at any time in the future I can ever
answer yes answer if at any time in the
future I can ever answer yes to any
other questions above that's weirdly
worded but it's crazy legal talk for if
the answer this change is like if you
committed a felony nine years ago in two
years past
oh god that felony conviction and all
your [ __ ] with it was over ten years ago
like you're good to go now
alright you can reapply or apply period
so then there's also an arrest
disclosure forum form if she says if
since turning age eighteen have you ever
been arrested served criminal summons
charged with or convicted of any crime
regarding the possession distribution or
use of a controlled son
you must disclose this information to
the marijuana Enforcement Division make
sure you get them all on there too cuz
oops I forgot that one looks really
[ __ ] bad they give you plenty of
space to list yep holy crap check any of
the following or professional licenses
you have held so it asks which licenses
you've had it asks if you've had a
liquor license or a lawyer license or
racing license a lottery license so it's
gonna ask you a lot of crazy questions
fill all of this out truthfully okay
so read the disqualifying conditions if
you qualify then print out the
application don't [ __ ] print it it's
like 10 pages of paper let's see several
pages the ones we read you verbatim are
the the automatic disqualification ones
if you start checking yes to some of the
ones we're talking about now that
doesn't automatically mean - no it means
you got some splaining to do okay yeah
the first ones were knows ya the first
ones are automatic knows it's it's a
felony in ten years or a felony in five
years a drug-related Trani in ten if
you're a cop or I don't remember what
the last one was copper doctor those all
disqualify you guys I'll DQ you
automatically but the only two of those
that apply to most of the people
listening to the show or the first two
alright alright there's probably a
couple you know I remember there was an
event that we did for the show we did a
live show somewhere the place doesn't
exist anymore but we did a live show
somewhere and we invited people to come
and I made flyers for the show right and
I put out flyers for the podcast to come
listen to wall people it was a smoking
remember because I used to sit in a room
with a number of members of law
enforcement every Monday night okay like
when this happened that I was keenly
aware of how many officers were in that
room every Monday night I put out flyers
to listen to the podcast at a smoking
event and somehow law enforcement found
the Flyers and thought that they were
like some sort of tickets to get free
weed at the event or something and so in
the next episode I gave a shout out to
the cops open that they were listening
because they had the Flyers and it said
listen I had a little QR code if you
scan do we take you down you can hear
the show so if you're in law enforcement
I appreciate you for listening I hope
you're learning the truth about cannabis
it's not evil it's not terrible it
doesn't ruin anybody that's officer much
respect for you thanks for doing what
you do alright so that's the next step
here we're gonna keep the show on track
Mike's got a DD today print the
application complete the application
that shouldn't be too hard so at that
point obtain any court papers that you
need any arrests disclosure forms
anything like that if you've got tax
paper forms that you need if you have
child support paper forms that you need
print all that find those papers then
you need to make an appointment the
Denver office in Longmont accepts
walk-ins in Grand Junction you need to
make an appointment in Springs you need
to make an appointment the phone number
is on the website I guess I could have
had that for you I do not I apologize I
failed you there so call and make an
appointment it's way easier to call and
make an appointment in steering's than
it is to sit there and wait for like
three hours in Denver that's what I did
in a kind of sucked you waited all day
in Denver yep I made my appointment for
Colorado Springs I showed up about 15
minutes early because it's hard to judge
i-25 so I got there about 15 minutes
early and the lady was like hey the guy
that was scheduled before you didn't
show up
Oh care are you ready [ __ ] yeah I'm
ready and it took her maybe an hour to
do the entire process she fielder
printed me interviewed me that's why
you're waiting all day in Denver is
because that's how long it takes right
and there's a lot of other people showed
up every day just relax when they're
fingerprinting you it's easy and you
know what if you've got warrants or
something if you're wanted in the state
of Colorado and they run your ID and if
you're wanted they come in [ __ ]
arrest you
yeah we really can't emphasize like read
the questions and the answers yes to the
first four or you've got like active
warrants out now don't apply don't apply
cuz I'm not even kidding they will come
arrest you if you're getting
fingerprinted they run your [ __ ] you're
wanted by the FBI there's a sign
this says unmarked or plainclothes
security officer on premises at all
times he will come and arrest you I
spent three and a half hours trying to
find the dude and I think I found both
of them they're not playing around read
the questions answer them honestly for
the secondary questions like child
support and student loans if you've got
any of those you know any of those
questions apply to you you're gonna need
to contact that institution like I had
to cut contact everybody I've got
student loans with and get a paper that
says my student loans are in good
standing rush means if you've been duck
in that [ __ ] for a decade you need to
stand up take the punch
mmm set up a payment plan start making
payments you only need to make one
payment same thing with child support
right if your child support is [ __ ] up
I was cool cuz mines legit but if your
child support is [ __ ] up they will
make you get a paper from your
caseworker that says that you're paying
and that you're doing what you can if
you had felonies 17 years ago or threw
over the deadline and you're good to go
you need paperwork from the court that
adjudicated your felony in the original
jurisdiction you gotta [ __ ] contact
the court to try and sense to you and
get the paperwork from them that says
you completed successfully and on what
date you completed for every [ __ ]
felony and it can be a real pain you've
got I mean I've talked to people in
Denver while I was waiting that had to
go to like seven different courthouses
to pick up stuff that they got between
two one or like 18 and 20 and then
they've been perfect for a decade but
they had still had to spend four days
driving between courthouses getting
paperwork so that they could then apply
to work in the legal marijuana industry
like have you [ __ ] together and some for
some of you that's gonna be a lot of
paperwork gathering if you don't have it
together the lady at the meed office or
the man the person that helped me was a
lady so I always think it's a lady but
the person that helps you at the media
office they will give you a list of
everything that you need after you fail
the first time yeah that's the first
step of the process when you get there
and it's your turn as they go through
your [ __ ] piece by piece and make sure
you have everything and when I got done
it was very clearly lucky you have
everything it's your first try Wow high
five that's gonna
you know I was well-prepared I knew
plenty of people that have yes so we
neither of us had an issue but we've all
talked to countless people that have no
idea what this process looks like they
even moved to Colorado moved across the
country unprepared and so knowing this
and doing it right is sort of essential
folks if you've got forty four felonies
you're probably not gonna exactly forty
four we call them forty four and that's
the only hint we're gonna give you so um
we're gonna keep moving when you show up
okay the next step is show up and
complete the damn interview comb your
hair if you do that if you got
dreadlocks fly them down cuz I'm gonna
make you take a little like a swatch on
the floor of or on the wall of material
where you're supposed to stand in front
of that shit's like five ten like what
those people are it was pretty funny all
right so when you show up for the place
when you show up for the interview
bring the completed application have
that [ __ ] filled out before you get
there bring your ID bring your court
papers and disclosure forms if you've
got any of those to bring with you bring
proof of residency if you don't have if
you're new to Colorado and your ID if
you do have an out-of-state ID that's
what the [ __ ] I'm trying to say if your
ideas from out of state bring proof of
residency that you do live in the state
of Colorado bring the phone bill bring
up [ __ ] cable bill bring the light
bill bring whatever you got this is this
goes back to column and they'll tell you
exactly what you need and this is the
time to bring up my ID since I'm from
Texas or Tennessee or wherever the [ __ ]
like bring it out and they'll tell you
exactly what you need supporting
paperwork wise if you've got felonies
they'll tell you what to what to ask the
courts for same thing with your child
support stuff they told me it's all on
the implications questions super
important they do not take cash bring a
money order or bring a check if you're
going to get your key badge and this is
where we'll talk about this part if
you're going to get your key badge it's
gonna cost you $300 if you want your
support
it is a hundred and fifty dollars my
colectomy is that wrong because I just
know it wasn't prices were right but I
think jumper takes cash I'm like 85%
somebody else that was helping me with
this episode will not accept cash and
the website says bring check or money
order so I'm pretty sure they quit
accepting cash just surprise me I knew
that only one office did and I could
have sworn it was Denver but I might
have taken the check I worked at a place
that had a lot of cash flow like we had
a lot of cash they've worked at several
places and just imagine how many
applications they handle at $150 the
badge minimum times 16,000 employees
imagine that much money in a box and the
office anywhere over a [ __ ] couple of
days that box is full of cash so I
understand just be prepared you guys
take a check or take a money order
just stop it somewhere that sells a
money order freaking Walmart sucks they
have money orders I think most Walgreens
will sell you a money order go to the
place now let's talk about the
difference between a key badge and a
support badge there always has to be a
support badge on premises
nobody can be in micro without a support
battery there has to be a red badge
which is the owner badge if they own the
place to get that one or a key badge if
you don't have a key badge if there's
not a key badge on premises nobody else
can be in there
none of the support badges can be in the
room so I find it advantageous to go
ahead and get that key badge because
then you're kind of more qualified to do
more [ __ ] you've already got more
ability to take on more responsibility I
made sure to get the key yeah and did it
help you do you feel like getting your
key badge helped you advance in your
position at the spot I think those rules
are more heavily enforced on the medical
side okay or maybe I'm just no I've got
to be the I'm the only support badge
several nights a week at work or my only
key badge that might be why I got
promoted yeah yes it was one of my
promotion it just makes you more
promotable so a support badge you can be
like a budtender you can be a trimmer
you can be a joint roller
you can in the gardens you can support
badges in starter badges like if you've
only got 150 to spend on a badge and you
know you're gonna be a trimmer for the
first year like tinder or a budtender
you can go ahead and get the support
well like we're not saying don't but the
key badge definitely gives you more
opportunities in the industry and if
you're one of those people that's moving
to Colorado with a degree in
biochemistry like you might want to go
ahead and get the support badge or the
key badge I'm sorry I thank you mixing
those two I was trying to figure you
confused me so sorry yes edge is the
more important one I was looking for the
distinguishing it says something about
on the application if you're going to
have keys and be in charge of employees
and have access to limited access areas
you should go ahead and get a key badge
so I recommend of course get the key
badge if you don't have the money for it
get yourself a support badge if you're
an ambitious ambitious person and you
feel like you want to move up if you're
gonna manage that [ __ ] get the key go
ahead and get a key badge if you want to
work with the grow team if you're real
enthusiastic and you can show that you
can do it get yourself a key badge we'd
love to see you move up in the industry
super quickly I knew I wasn't gonna be
on the bottom rung for long so I fully
got that one on purpose like I know a
lot of other people that did that too
and I know a couple of people who got
the support and have been kind of passed
over several times because they can't
meet some of those requirements that you
have to have the key for gotta have a
key badge on premises at all times gotta
be pretty much in the same room with the
support badges it doesn't even leave
them in another room so alright so if
you want to be like the cultivation
manager get a key badge you're gonna be
a trim team leader get a key badge maybe
even if you want to be LEED budtender
you might need a key badge because
you'll be carrying product back to the
storage room which requires a key badge
to get into or at least it should so get
your badge it's gonna cost money
decide which bad you want the next step
here you guys once you've got your badge
wait for it take a picture [ __ ] smile
for your picture look good in the
picture bruh that's the next step yep
you don't want to look like a dumbass
and then hang that picture any night for
the next two years
wear that bright green Colorado medical
marijuana Enforcement Division lanyard
picture on it it's so funny walking into
place original original green one bro
way to be og buddy emoji alright so once
you've got that that picture with your
cheesy a screen on it you got a badge
the next step is to get a job if once
you get the badge now you can apply in
the industry
yeah yes so think about what you're good
at or you did it bud tending are you
good at trimming honestly we keep saying
bud tuning and trimming those are the
ways into this industry if you want to
be a master grower most places have a
master grower you're gonna start
transplants he's gonna go will come show
me what you got and if you can follow
directions and do it the way that he
wants it done and also contributes skill
knowledge and care to the job you may
end up being assistant grower one day I
mean let you come help me pull leaves in
the garden one day you'll work your way
up and one day when I'm or not not me I
don't want to say the master grower or
whatever facility you work at one day
when he's sick or whatever he's got the
shits and can't come in maybe you get to
water the plants or whatever and you get
to learn how to become a gonna work your
way up one way or another Jeff and I
were both bud tenders like that's where
you start a lot of people start off as
trimmers that's where you start like you
can be almost anything in the marijuana
industry like we literally need every
profession I have played bud tender
manager fire hire and fire work I did
hire him firing I grew the weed I'm
still doing the growing I do the I do
some transportation a bunch of different
the Bob and like people need to people
every day that aren't prepared for that
idea they're like well I've been in
marketing for like 10 years and it's
like cool are you ready to trim some
we'd learn everything in this room and
what their different applications are
for different patients and and sell it
accurately and inform well-informed like
can you pull that off because if you
can't do that or be cool trim to show a
little weed like you're gonna have a
really hard time looking for dispensary
it's actively looking for a marketing
dude who's never worked in legal weed
before and doesn't necessarily know the
community the culture of the product the
clients like there's a lot you need to
know and you learn that when you start
as a budtender a trimmer it's a whole
etiquette it's a whole world to be
involved in a buddy of mine started as a
trimmer in like six weeks later he was
running a trim crew for like seven
different dispensaries and they just
cycled between them as they harvested
shout-out to Linus yep shoutout - like
he had a he struggles for a while find a
dispensary that would even take him on
as a trimmer and when he finally found
one he made sure to put it in his all
and now he's running a big ass crew and
they're killing it right now they've
done a good job I'm the same way we
moved up quick be motivated we're
growing so rapidly there are so many
people coming from around the world to
be in this industry that there are 50
people trying to take your job in this
industry every [ __ ] day green and
healthy wellness is a small shop with a
small no small location we aren't very
well-known yet we're kind of new we
don't have a large following I think
that's what I'm trying to say with a
whole bunch of words we don't have a
huge following but we get probably 5 to
10 applications every single day of
people that want to be growers trimmers
bud tenders whatever they can do they
like I will clean the toilets as long as
you give me a job in there yeah I see
some crazy I see a lot of people coming
in that are doing it right that are
ready to work that know the industry and
know how to sell their place in it and a
lot of it comes down to like knowing how
to pitch your previous work experience
because I sold weed for my living room
for the last 10 years you did an episode
before the cover like some of the
resumes you got to grow and how
ridiculous some of them could get put
together real resume like if you don't
know what that is google it yeah be
prepared cuz there's a lot of people got
in for the jobs that are available even
with this how fast were expanding
if you want to stand out at all you
gotta do all right now let's talk about
some of the problems that come with
getting a job working in the cannabis
industry the number one most obvious
problem to me is banking yep that's an
issue when you work at a dispensary or
as a grower and I can't speak for every
shop or every grow and this is something
that I probably shouldn't say too much
about but this is the damn truth when
payday comes you get an envelope stuffed
with cash everything is done in cash it
sucks
yeah you get a pay stub and taxes are
taken out and that you get is the same
but instead of a check at the bottom or
better yet a voided check that tells you
about the direct deposit you just got
you get a check stub folded up with a
bunch of 20s in the middle a bunch of
[ __ ] yeah you carry all these damn
twenties in your backpackers somehow to
the car it's not just payroll it's
everything like state taxes federal
taxes electric bills rent it's yes when
you get home you got to figure out a way
to convert all that cash into some way
to pay your rent so that is the obvious
problem luckily employees can usually
get back accounts it's smaller banks no
problem it's the businesses that really
can't get accounts but you've still
gotta transfer cash to bank right right
you got and that cash came from a
dispensary sometimes it stinks like we
we have a mutual friend whose account
was just closed because their cash
deposits smelled way too much like
cannabis yeah also one of the problems
we've talked about this a little bit on
the podcast another problem that can
happen if you work in the cannabis
industry is you're gonna get pulled over
you're gonna smell like a pound of
[ __ ] weed and the cops are gonna
harass you if you've got a badge a lot
of times they expect you to be a model
citizen because you've got the badge and
you know the rules is we're gonna be a
little more careful we're back to
putting your best foot forward like
don't stink like weed with your badge
last and also how because they're good
they're gonna as soon as they see that
[ __ ] or even the green lanyard that
goes with it they're automatically gonna
be thinking is this person high right
now behind the wheel do I have a DUI
arrest so don't be that person true also
renting is hard yeah hard when your
place of employment is green and healthy
wellness there's a stigma involved that
a lot of people don't realize I've got a
friend leaving the industry right now
and they were talking to me just this
afternoon that they're applying for jobs
that aren't in the cannabis industry and
he's real hesitant because he hasn't
faced the company the drug tests in a
decade
he's a budtender and a cannabis consumer
and passionate about cannabis really
enjoys that aspect of his life and at
minimum he's gonna have to give it up
until we compete clean and he wasn't
except necessarily expecting to leave
the industry this abruptly so he's not
prepared for that and so at best his ass
is gonna be out of work for a while
while he looks for either jobs that
don't test or what not but he's extra
hesitant because as soon as they're like
well what do you just get stopped doing
and he's like well I'm working on
marijuana industry for three years and
now I'm trying to get a job at a bank or
you know wherever the hell else yeah
they're gonna they're gonna be
judgmental for sure right so like even
if they don't typically drug test or
there's a lot of companies I work for a
bunch of them back in the day they just
threatened a drug test and the only drug
test they do is whether or not you show
up to get your cup they can't actually
afford to pay like the seventy five
bucks or whatever to test yeah yeah even
those companies are more apt to test
somebody who's coming out of the legal
weed industry it's just got that sense
to it so getting banking renting cars
renting a car is kind of a [ __ ] I
turn down I just bought a new car you
guys shoutout to my new car but also
shout-out to Mario Archuleta for the
sweet hookup in the new car I was
declined I've been getting stacks of
envelopes in the mail from credit
companies that declined my credit and
when you look at why it says
insufficient employment and I make a
[ __ ] ton of money not to brag about my
money but I make plenty of [ __ ] money
for the car that I bought and they just
didn't like it that I worked at her
dispensary they would call me while I
was waiting in the Ford dealership to
buy my car they would call and they'd be
like hey we've just got one question
about your employment what is this gah W
you are cats right on GH have you turned
to avoid questions for green and healthy
wellness like oh are you a weed grower
it's not the companies that don't apply
to this but like there's a statement
that you're gonna take on and you kinda
have to be ready to bear that cross it's
not just out in the world like plenty of
you got family that's like Oh [ __ ]
cousin Ricky working at the weed store
we should mention all the drug testing
talk the dispensary bond drug test you
noop don't worry but don't show up high
either
if there's too many [ __ ] rules to
come toast if we can't tell you're high
it's okay if we can tell you're high
you're in trouble don't be that high
[ __ ] problems working in the industry
our banking credit getting the car
getting a loan that kind of [ __ ] is hard
shout out to my friend Jessica I asked
her for guidance on this because she is
a manager in a dispensary she said the
first thing she spouted off what the
passion was [ __ ] sexism in the
cannabis industry this is she called it
a boys club and said that this is ran by
guys and she's a woman and it's hard to
be taken [ __ ] seriously by all the
men in this industry so ladies ah
when you come to Colorado your chances
of getting a job are nearly tripled of
what a guy with the same qualifications
are going to have the chances of that
same dude are gonna have of getting
employment I know that sounds rude to
say they don't
care what you'd look like if you're a
trimmer for the most part but if you're
a budtender automatically hot females go
to the top of the stack and that's kind
of true in any industry but it's really
true in the cannabis industry
unfortunately so you're gonna get hired
first at the same time everybody's gonna
look at your titties all [ __ ] day long
in the cannabis industry we are used to
growing weed in our basement we're used
to being a bunch of bros it's kind of a
boys club we should know this by now but
the grow environment the weed business
environment sometimes people forget and
it gets a little bit sexist a little bit
so yeah the rules the messes like kind
of apply to every other industry like
we're under so remind us myself after
one or two of those shout out to the
ladies that have taught us that there
are some sexism in the cannabis industry
be prepared for that a little bit
another huge problem you cannot consume
on site if you want to consume cannabis
while you're working at a medical
marijuana or a recreational marijuana
grow facility processing facility
anything like that you cannot do it
anywhere near the building you know go
somewhere else I don't care where you do
the cameras cannot see you people that
are leaving
go far away consume your medicine some
more far away safely that goes for
customers okay
don't do that get out of there also
something that I would mention is a pain
in the ass in the cannabis industry and
you may think I'm crazy some people can
make glam but there is so much tedious
regulation and so much pressure they
were way overboard with the regulation
and like just I watch people every day
grind up scraps of marijuana like stems
like [ __ ] that you wouldn't
even consider feeling bad about if you
threw away like it's just trash they
have to grind it with coffee and
shredded paper to make it
indistinguishable and unusable yes like
and when that you translate that to a
major grow the amount of like just how
you throw out the trash because a
majorly complicated process that will
reduce ridiculous I run the the big row
we are harvesting eighty five lights
worth of plant right so what we do I
will start a trash can where the
trimmers are and I'll put I'll harvest
the plant and I will put that pot of
dirt in the bottom of the can now
there's like a little bit of dirt in the
bottom and then as we trim the leaves
and a little bit of sticks will go in
and then I'll go harvest another plant
or maybe we've got old pots stacked up
and I'll pour some and it goes dirt
leaves dirt leaves and the sweepings in
there but you got a mix up that weed the
weed recognisable which is also behind a
gate and we still have had our [ __ ]
trash broken into torn out of the
dumpster they tear the bags open and
they destroy all that and I gotta go
[ __ ] sweep it up and put the trash
back in the goddamn trash can in the
morning when I get there so the
regulations are ridiculous I have to
everything's gotta be weighed a million
times everything and there are checks on
things also so it's a little bit
stressful on all the regulation all the
pressure is crazy
things have to happen at a certain time
things have to be done quickly you can't
wait for some [ __ ] in a big grow and
you're on camera from 9000 different
angles so don't ever think you're gonna
get away with anything the being on
camera on every square inch takes some
adjusting like I watch it all day at
work we forget there are camera or I
pointed out to customers like we're on
camera like we can see and hear
everything stop it hear everything you
try to get us in trouble like why it's
not [ __ ] asking how to take we just
axis look we can't answer you right yeah
stop asking how many views edibles which
you should eat is [ __ ] one and wait
two hours [ __ ] I told you twice they
get stressful
the rules always [ __ ] change I get
emails once a week with new rules rules
there's a special company that makes law
books and they're on there like third
marijuana book now Wow like you have to
buy the original book and then the two
addendum books so that's uh that's most
of what I've got that's stressful but
one thing that might can testify to
because he's a budtender mostly now the
consumer is so educated that they expect
a bud and and foe educated they think
they know what the [ __ ] they're talking
about that they expected but I hear the
phrase out of a lot and I hear good to
go even more oh it's a good and a bad
thing I'm blessed to be in the the
medical side of things I get a lot of
that too but honestly I see kind of a
truce a more touristy side of it and
honestly they just haven't had the the
culture of the community out loud and
proud like we have here in Colorado like
down in Texas in Arkansas for as long
the like you can really tell who who's
been in the community actively who
hasn't who's been like a marijuana
consumer in the total shadows like most
of their friends don't know they
definitely wouldn't talk about it in
public or on the news around the radio
so they've never heard anyone say sativa
before or indica it's just never
happened they've only ever read it and
just thinking about that kind of boggles
my mind a little bit so I try to pay
them a little bit but a [ __ ] when I
hear for like the 14th time on a
Saturday makes me want a [ __ ] [ __ ]
punch somebody but I saw the same thing
in the wine world like so it exists
other places people think they know a
lot and they acts naughty it's funny I
love the dispensary where the budtender
knows [ __ ] everything it makes you
feel stupid and doesn't realize that I'm
a breeder right like I love it when
they're wrong I was gonna shop the other
day in Denver and I heard wrong
information there was a strain labeled
wrong and I listened to the button or go
on for like four minutes about how it
was an indica wasn't really popular
sativa and I'm just sitting there
shaking my head as the customer gobbles
it up and I'm like dude look at the buds
like I can tell that's a [ __ ] sativa
just by the way the buds are growing
damn
stupid professional weed smokers alright
Mike thanks for coming to the show bro
yeah guys that's all we've got for how
to get your badge here at the state of
college some of the things that come
along with that particular key the
awesomeness
yeah shadow once again to that one
mountain girl and also a huge shout out
to Jessica both were huge contributors
to the show also shout out to the CD the
Colorado Department of Public Health and
Environment website for all the
information they gave me I want to give
a huge shout out to everybody who wished
me a happy birthday if it was on
Facebook if it was on Instagram if there
was on Twitter if it was here face to
face if it was a through text message
however it was thanks had a great
birthday the whole week has been amazing
we're still raging it has been several
days since my birthday it's actually the
4th now and my birthday was on the 1st
and I have finally eaten all of the food
and snacks that I was however have not
consumed all of the Chipotle gift cards
that I was given so yeah somebody gave
me a Chipotle gift card so I got that on
deck maybe that'll be my after work
treat tomorrow sometime I just wanted
[Music]
for my birthday if you fed me if you
took me out if he dad me out if you gave
me some solvent less hash that I pressed
into one giant [ __ ] dead big
shout-out if you dab me out with sphere
X big shout out also big shout out to my
friends at the can of Canyon I dropped
into a can of Canyon yesterday and hung
out everybody in there dad me out
everybody was happy to see me big shout
out to the can of Canyon if you're ever
in Colorado Springs and you need a place
to stop and kill a few minutes you want
to smoke down I always recommend the can
of Canyon it's on Colorado Boulevard
Colorado it's not hard to find if you
google the canna Canyon in Colorado
Springs you will get there tell Camille
that Rasta Jeff sent you that you listen
to the girl from the heart podcast she
will treat you like royalty that's what
I think I've got free this week you guys
I do have more episodes planned I'm
gonna do an episode with a bunch of
lovely ladies and we'll talk about women
in cannabis what else
anyway it'll be in the future anyway I
don't have to talk too much about what's
coming up my little notebook is over
there I'm not gonna reach for it my
gonna thank you for hanging out do do
you I do leave the little guy at home I
hope you didn't miss him too much while
you're here I'll let you get back to him
real soon yeah it's about that time but
it's good to be here man I heard an
episode a little while back someone
mentioned missing me on the shows yes
I'm trying to be here man its life got
crazy but this is still important to me
and I want to be here as often as I can
but that's not as often as I would like
right now so I apologize for my absence
and I hope you like me on the show
lately
those are buddy Mike emails like
repeated updates life exploded and this
show had to take a back burner for a
while for for a minute there it was it
was a big part of my extracurricular
activities and I just that is the most
important thing in your world as it
should be no but yeah a priority so
we're recording real late at night like
[Music]
we're scratching it out but I wanted to
be part of the show getting badges like
I've seen so many people [ __ ] because
they didn't know this information before
they made a big little bleep and I want
to really want her to be a part of this
show so yeah sorry for the Ramblas hope
you got the information you need because
knowing is back in seven days with
another episode I'm not sure what I'm
gonna put out for you in seven days I've
got a lot of stuff written down it'll be
great I promise you that make sure you
tune in make sure you check out the show
on iTunes stitcher or I read genetics
Colorado dot-com we do not have any
sponsors on this episode if you want to
sponsor the podcast or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review send me
an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I'm gonna give a big shout
out to a product called sphere X I was
able to dab this new role called sphere
X last night at the cannon Canyon I only
took one dab of it so far it's got my
[ __ ] attention so check that product
out if you're in Colorado if you've got
something you want me to review send me
an email grow from your heart I
hotmail.com I'd love to review your
product you want to be a sponsor we'd
love to give you a shout out on the
the show is aimed at a cannabis
community so if you've got a cannabis
product this would be the perfect Avenue
to show off your wares you guys I want
to thank everybody for listening
big thanks to everybody out there in the
cannabis community who's doing their
thing who's making this [ __ ] happen
you guys want to give a big shout out to
my ninja Spence and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with the fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me