[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 256 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band flooding means
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen I also want to send
a huge shout out to all my friends that
just joined me on Instagram live that's
right I've been doing Instagram live
videos occasionally and it's a lot of
fun it puts me in the mood to do a
podcast it gives me some ideas it gives
me inspiration it makes me
conversational it gets me started and
it's a great way for me to hang out take
a couple of dabs with my social media
following so shot at everybody who is
watching the Instagram live video I
appreciate the support and interaction
if you're not following me on Instagram
make sure you check it out it's Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore
genetics on Instagram that way you can
join us and watch the Y videos you can
participate you can comment maybe I'll
answer your questions on the video maybe
I'll answer your question on the podcast
I like to get inspired so join us check
me out there while I was doing the
Instagram video I was taking some fat
dabs of some what do I have here some
Kim for from concentrate supply company
and I was dunking it into this delicious
Kim for it's called sugar wax but it was
more like a slurry more like a SAP I
really appreciated the flavor of it I
dumped the Kim for a shatter into the
Kim for slurry and it made a really nice
dab I made a whole bunch of lung
expansion and it got me obviously you
got me super high and super chatty so
great work to our friends and
concentrate supply company for the
excellent concentrates all right I also
want to give a huge shout out to our
friends at the hell a dank seed Co if
you need some new seeds for your garden
go check out hella dank seed Co at dank
seed dot store or simply search on
Google for the hella dank seam Co they
have got some IRA genetics in stock
they've got bog seeds in stock go check
them out see what they've got available
also portions of this podcast are
brought to you by our friends in the
dank team comm make sure you check out
the dank team comm for brands like
archive can adventure mile high rare
dankness Sin City and many more trusted
brands so if you need some new beans for
the garden you've got two great options
they do different deals it will suit
your needs
do some google and do your research see
what works best for you shot us
everybody out there growing from seed
alright let's see what's next on our
order of business stitcher for some
reason you guys snitcher will not load
episode 253 I have reposted it several
different ways different times different
methods different plans of attack I kind
of know what I'm doing with my RSS feed
and I cannot get stitcher to load
episode 253 I know people are gonna say
change the file name I changed that file
name to something random and it still
would not pick it up I repost it at
several different ways iTunes would get
it pod feed would get it my website
would get it website would pick it up
but for some reason stitcher just did
not want to pick up number 253 I'm gonna
wait I emailed stitcher they always take
for damn ever to reply hey stitcher if
you're listening please help me out one
of my episodes won't load umm I'm going
to wait for them to reply hopefully they
will say something back I'll see if they
can fix it if they don't respond I will
go back to trying I've been overwhelmed
with stuff for some reason the throwback
Thursday episode didn't appear as it
should have today this morning I had to
go manually repost that at 4:20 p.m.
today I'm not sure what's going on with
snitcher I do apologize I will get it
worked out everything will be fixed as
soon as I can get them to reply I'm on
it you guys I'm trying but it's kind of
a stitcher thing I don't know what else
to do I think it's their service because
it works everywhere else it works on my
website which isn't anything fancy it
shows up in iTunes which is the main
podcast server it shows up in pod bean
it shows up in pod bay shows up and all
the other podcast services so I feel
like it's got to be a stitcher issue so
I apologize if you are a stitcher
listener I can tell that I'm missing
listens because my ranking is slipping
I'm usually at like a thousand or better
I'm usually somewhere between 600 and a
thousand and the rankings I'm not
anywhere near that right now so I got to
fix that I got to get Fichter stitcher
fixed I got to get everybody the
information and knowledge they need
people rely on me I apologize
one thing I can do to get it going while
stitcher is messing up is I can make
more YouTube videos so I've posted
several YouTube videos I don't forget
that like the first hundred and three
maybe one hundred and five youtube
videos are up on the grill from your
heart podcast youtube channel so if
you're not subscribed to the YouTube
channel go check that out
the first 19 or 20 videos are on the old
Agriculture Channel but there's a
playlist on the grill from your heart a
podcast channel the first 19 or 20 are
right there on that playlist click on
the playlist it'll get you there listen
to the first 19 or 20 then all the way
up to like 103 105 are
all right there on the girl from your
heart podcast YouTube channel I will
keep updating it until I get caught up
to current it takes a little bit of time
but I just did some upgrades to my
computer I honestly did some downgrades
I just deleted a whole bunch of [ __ ] now
the computer goes way faster it's gonna
work a lot better
so maybe now I can do more video editing
a little more quickly we'll get more
videos up for you guys
that's what I can do when stuff fails I
can find new ways to try to compensate
but check out the YouTube channel I
would appreciate that
alright guys let's talk about cannabis
I've been rambling on for like five or
six minutes and I haven't spoken much
about cannabis I try to keep you guys
updated on my most recent breeding
projects and I haven't spoken much about
it on a couple of episodes but I have
got I've got an arise male in a room
with several females my goal right now
is to make a few new crosses because
I've been inspired and I've got a few
new clones that I want to pollinate and
make a few new things we've got some
great ideas and I'm also going to
replenish some seeds that I've got
available commercially that are getting
low in stock so I've got some familiar
plants and some new plants in the
breeding room some of the familiar old
stuff is like ah there's a grateful dog
in there so that I can make more of the
morning dew there's a piranha in there
so that or I flow in there so that I can
make more prana there are a couple of a
rise females in there so that I can make
more arise seeds there's a hell's OG in
there so that I can make more of the
Hellfire OG but the new stuff that's in
there is what has got me excited and
probably you also I put a kosher cush
female in there that will be pollinated
by the arize I'm not even gonna try to
name that until I grow it out if you've
got name recommendations let me know
some Jewish names would be cool cuz I
call my male plant King Solomon and this
is the kosher cush there's gonna be some
Jewish attachment to the name maybe some
Torah relations to the name let me know
what you think also there's strawberry
fields in there
there's also a Zack Hayes in there if
you guys know anything about Zack Hayes
that's a Strawberry Cough plant bred to
the killer Hayes those were two of my
friend Zack Hayes is his real name was
Zack Hayes you guys mmm
the Zack Hayes was bred for my friend
Zack Hayes who actually passed away of
cystic fibrosis it was a great young man
he was a great dude he was a cannabis
patient he was a cannabis advocate and
he was just a great dude all around so
the Zack Hayes was bred for him our
friends at organic ax got me a clone of
that
I know I am putting pollen from my arise
on that and I will return a bunch of the
seeds to our friends of Arg antica and
we will see what happens with that in
the future but it needs a cool name so
if you've got a cool name for a sack to
arise let me know now that you know the
story there's also space [ __ ] number
three I bread space [ __ ] number three I
don't think many people I gave out a few
clones of that a while back I don't
think anybody's got it alive still space
[ __ ] number three is of course Space
Queen kind of a really pungent like a
rotten mango fruity kind of smelling
phenotype and I pollinated that with my
grateful dog and I made space [ __ ]
number three it was of course number
three because it was just the third seed
that I planted in the wine I labeled the
cups one two three I think I went up to
number eight and that was number three
number three and four were the keepers
three is the one that stuck around for
the long time also there is ecto cooler
in there I cannot recall the cross on
ecto cooler right now it's got some DK
in there it's got some other cool stuff
ecto cooler was bred by Tierra Rojo I
expect some great [ __ ] to come from the
arize - ecto cooler so that should be a
fun cross to come up with the name for
if you can think of any names for ecto
cooler to arise I'd love to hear your
suggestions send your suggestions to me
on Twitter I had G fyh podcast or email
them to me it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd like to know what you
think I should name those strains but
anyway all of those girls are in the
flowering room and the mail is dumping
pollen and it is just about pollen time
so probably when I'm done recording here
I'm gonna wrap up the dreadlocks and
something real nice I'm gonna put on
different clothes and I'm gonna go in
there and I'm gonna smack that male
around and make sure he gets pollen I'll
turn off all the fans turn off all the
blowers so that I have a little bit of
control over where the pollen goes I'm
gonna go smack that male so where he
shoots his dust everywhere
give him a good shake and then I'm gonna
take a butt off of them and just rub
that one bud of male flowers all over a
couple of females I'm gonna make a whole
bunch of seed that the pollination is
happening you guys that's what that's
what I'm getting at it is pollination
time I'm excited we're just shy of 30
days into flower with these plants that
means at about 30 35 days ish these
seeds will be ready that means I'll get
to take them out once the plants try up
I'll get to see what I have created
that's always the funnest part of
breeding is seeing what you have created
so that's a great way to segue into the
topic of this show
guys I like to talk about breeding a lot
and I'm known for a lot of my breeding
projects and my breeding work and when
people approach the subject of breeding
they seem to be overwhelmed they seem to
think that breeding is some sorceries
some magicians work you guys breeding is
the most natural thing that cannabis
plants can do that's what they want to
do growing cannabis plants without seeds
is actually the trick if you were able
to produce cannabis that does not have
seeds in it and that is quality and
smokeable you yourself are able to make
seeds for yourself if you're looking to
make a small batch of seeds I'm gonna
give you some advice on an idea that
I've got I have not perfected this we
are gonna work on this idea together I
am certain this would work for a small
garden we're gonna talk about what I
have called single pot breeding and I
feel like this could be a book but I'm
gonna give it to everybody right now for
free because I love you guys and I think
it's a wonderful idea so here's a great
way in one pot in one small space with
one light for you to create enough seeds
for yourself to play with and maybe
share a few with your friends and that
way you don't have to buy more seeds and
you can start your own breeding projects
and see that it's not wizardry that it's
something that you can do if you've
grown a crop to fruition if you've made
a plant live that whole nine or ten
weeks through a flowering cycle you are
able to breed seeds if you've got a
strong enough light you are able to
breed seeds it's not that hard so I am
gonna press pause I'm gonna clear my
throat real quick I'm gonna take a
couple of drinks I'll probably take
another dab and get my throat all choked
up again but I'm gonna press pause for a
second I'm gonna take a quick break and
through the power of editing I'll be
back before you can blink and then we
will talk about single pot breeding and
how you can make enough seeds with one
pot with one light in one very small
grow space stay tuned of you guys all
right podcast world I just noticed
something funny while I was recording
our friend Jesse sent me a message and
he pointed out that there is a vendor
who sells cannabis seeds online and he
claims to have a bunch of IRA genetics
seeds that are honestly sold out and if
he's got them they're rare [ __ ]
collector's items and you might want to
get on there but I know that they're not
what he claims they are because those
are simply not available he's way too
late to have those those probably don't
even exist anymore anywhere this guy
claims he's got heart of gold seeds this
guy claims he's got
grateful dog seeds he also claims he's
got tons of seeds from all kinds of
other vendors and breeders but it
doesn't seem like it's even realistic I
know he doesn't have my stuff he never
bought anything from me I know most of
where my stuff goes so what I'm saying
is that Greybeard seeds the ultimate
seed bank at Greybeard seeds com is not
an official distributor vendor
representative of Irene genetics
products in any way shape or form
they've got a picture of Jerry Garcia up
is their picture as their icon Jerry's
not part of their seed company don't
fall for this um I can't recommend that
you troll them and email them and/or
contact them and let them know that they
suck I couldn't say to do anything like
that because I'm a podcaster and this
goes out and I don't want to get myself
in any trouble so make sure that you
don't contact them make sure that you
don't harass them make sure that you
don't let them know that they're a fraud
just let them be ignore them and let
them continue as usual all right my
friends that support me and love me
please don't do me any favors by
reaching out to these people and
disrupting their business for being
completely fake because if I asked you
guys to do something like that it could
backfire and get me in trouble so please
don't do anything like that on my behalf
because I clearly did not ask you to do
so thank you guys I love you for all of
your help and support all right now my
main whole point of pressing pause was
to take a DAB but then I saw that Jesse
message me so now I'm gonna press pause
again now that I told you guys about
what Jesse messaged me and I'm gonna go
back in message Jesse that he needs to
come on the podcast and then I'm
actually gonna take the dad's that I
press pause to take so once again please
hold all right you guys I am back I am
well medicated I am hydrated I was kind
of poking around that website a little
bit there's not really a lot of ways to
contact them through looking at the app
on my phone or at their website on my
phone but maybe you'll you'll find more
anyway I was talking about single pot
breeding for those of you that don't
have a lot of space that you're
interested in making a few seeds for
yourself why not breathe in just one pot
if you're not into the one pot idea we
can also call it one light breeding and
we'll just say every time I say one pot
you just say three or four three gallon
pots however many you can fit under your
light now let's talk about light for a
second I don't like to breed under
anything I certainly wouldn't go small
than a 400 you could but it you're not
gonna make a lot of seeds they're not
gonna be a lot of viable seeds they're
gonna take longer if you've got a 600
watt light that's just about right a
thousand watt your golden thousand is
amazing six is good 400 will be
sufficient anything less I think you're
gonna make a lot of white seeds you're
not gonna get enough seeds just to make
it worth your time and effort it just
won't be any good for you I would stick
with the 400 or bigger the 600 is
probably your best bet if you're just
trying to breed for personal seeds no
I'm talking small spaces you guys a lot
of people out there growing in like a
five by five hydro Hut or maybe a small
closet or something that's why I say
single light that's why I got the idea
of a single pot what's to stop you from
getting one semi large pot like maybe a
seven gallon and putting three pot three
plants in that seven gallon pot three
small clones that are you know once you
put them in the dirt you've got six
maybe ten inches sticking out and you've
edge them up a little bit and then you
get them all about 12 inches tall maybe
8 inches 18 inches tall or so and then
you use like a tomato cage or three
sticks to spread them out or they're not
all growing straight up the center of
the pot you want to spread them out try
to give a little bit of space in there
maybe top them veg amount until they're
like 18 24 inches tall and then one of
those is your male one of the plants in
that 3 the trio of plants there is your
boy and the other two are your females
maybe you've got an indica and a sativa
in there it may be better if you don't
do a full indica and a full sativa
because your flowering times will be
wonky you'd want them a little closer
together but it will work it certainly
will work and you'll make enough seeds
for yourself if that's your goal but put
two strains that are similar in there or
two females of the same type and then
one male in there and flower that out
and that one pot and now you can make
enough seeds for yourself with one space
one light one pot now the reason this
would be helpful I've got a couple of
great reasons why this would be helpful
for you one reason maybe if something
goes wrong it looks like you've only got
one plant instead of having three plants
you're only gonna get in trouble for one
shouldn't something happen I don't know
how well that'll work for you but you've
only got one pot so you can only have
one plant right all right another reason
why this would be helpful is because now
you've only got a water one pot yeah
you've got three plants in there but
you've only got to mix up enough
nutrients in enough water to water that
one pot and if you're somebody that
works a lot if you're somebody they
can't be home constantly a
in gallon pot is gonna stay wet for like
3 maybe 4 days depending on your
environment in your small gross space so
that'll buy you time you've only got one
pot to water and it reduces numbers and
it saves you floor space cuz you don't
have so many pots in the floor you've
only got one pot and keep in mind that
eventually once you're done pollinating
you're gonna cut down that male plant
and it's gonna give you a little bit
more space in that pot so it will be
less crowded so you can probably fit
three or four plants in a seven gallon
pot you can flower it all in the same
pot under 1 400 watt light use very
little space and then you can make your
own personal seeds alright now let's
talk about the same thing but let's
change up the plan of attack in the
method just a little bit let's say
you've got maybe I like saying a 5x5
hydro huh those are very available and
it doesn't have to be a hydro huh just
whatever grow hut you can get get a
quality one or a small 5x5 space that's
kind of what I like for a one light
setup so let's let's talk like 5x5 hydro
Hut with maybe like a 400 watt light in
there maybe a 600 watt light you've got
a duct on top to get the heat in the
stale air out what I would do in a 5x5
Hut I would run a carbon filter I would
hang it from the top I would run the
ducting from the filter through the
light then I would run I would have a
vented light or a ducted light then I
would run the ducting up right out of
the top and I would set the blower right
on top it's on the outside of the Hut
just resting on the roof now and it's
sucking it's got ducting attached to it
and it's sucking the air through the
carbon filter over the light and out of
the top of the hut that way you're
extracting air that has been filtered
and doesn't stink out of the hut and he
will pull fresh air in through the vents
in the bottom of the hut while you're
pulling that old stale air out and
you'll also be cooling the light at the
same time so that one blower is serving
multiple purposes so carbon filter
ducting light ducting blower resting on
the top outside and then you're just
blowing that heat out now all you have
to do is get that heat out of whatever
room you're in that heat has to go
somewhere
but anyway so you got a 500 or a 5x5 Hut
or like a four or a six hundred watt
light in there if you don't want to do a
single pot here is another method that I
have discovered works very well you
could do this for breeding or I like to
do this personally for running new seeds
I make new seeds I've got a lot of them
and I want to grow them but I don't have
a whole bunch of space so I need to grow
some small plants but I'll do in that
situation is I will use very small pots
I really like to use 4 or 6 inch net
pots if you go to Amazon you can find a
5 or 6 inch net pots used for
hydroponics they're fairly cheap you can
get a pack of 24 for not much money at
all you can probably get free shipping a
pack of 24 if you use the method I'm
talking about you'll have enough for two
runs and they are reusable so it's very
affordable know what I like to do I like
to get the six inch net pots and I like
to fill them with a very aerated coco
like 50% cocoa fifty percent perlite I
fill it almost all the way to the top
and I'll put my clones right inside
there or my seedling I will sprout it
and get it all germinate it and I'll get
it growing and then I'll put it into the
cocoa and then I take em I get
Tupperware or Rubbermaid dishes from
Walmart or Target and they're only like
six maybe five maybe eight inches tall
it the most and they're just made for
like storing clothes underneath the bed
or something some of them have wheels on
them but I like to get them they're
about three feet long and then they're
probably eighteen inches wide and I like
to put five of the six inch net pots per
Rubbermaid container so I do a row a
three and a row a two and they fit like
three and then two they don't they don't
fit side-by-side they're not parallel
those staggered I'm sure you know what I
mean right so I got five per tub and I
do two tubs under one light so now I've
got ten of those in the six-inch net
pots and when I put them into the Coco
the first time I'll water from the top I
will water those plants with a lot of
mammoth microbes plus life from veg
bloom a little bit of veg bloom base
maybe a little liquid karma maybe
cal-mag if it needs it and then a little
bit of carbohydrates depending on what
brand of carbohydrates I'm working with
at the time but I'll add some carbs in
there to get it going but you want to
focus on the root development at that
time anyway I will water it from the top
at that time I'll put the clone into the
cocoa and water it from the top just
like normal get the cocoa saturated it's
been transplanted at school then I set
them into the Rubbermaid dish and slide
them under the one light now that's the
last time those plants get watered from
the top now I mix up a three gallon or a
five
gallon jug of water every Monday and
shake the [ __ ] out of it and divide it
in half and pour two and a half gallons
of water I tried to save some you guys
if I do the five gallon container I only
try to do about one and a half to two
gallons of water per Rubbermaid
container and I fill it up and it's
honestly I've got long fingers it's
probably a little more than up to the
second knuckle that's got to be an inch
and a half maybe two inches deep where
the water just sitting in there and it
works because those net pots have so
much space up top that they're still
getting air and they're not drowning
ah that water only sits in there that
deep for like an hour before all the
cocoa absorbs it it just wicks it right
up and then you've got like one knuckle
deep worth of water and that sits there
for a couple of days when the plants
just absorb all of that and they drink
it all up from the roots as the roots
get dry as the cocoa gets dry it wicks
it right up and keeps it going in there
and then I let that go honestly I can
water it on Monday or Sunday night and
then I can work throughout most of the
week and I don't have to add water until
maybe Thursday or Friday actually
today's Thursday and I put just a little
bit of fresh water on top to top it off
I watered it Monday it got dry up dried
up by Wednesday today is Thursday I just
added some fresh water on there so that
I'm not adding I didn't even add
nutrients today I just add in fresh
water that'll probably rock until like
Saturday or Sunday and then Saturday
I'll take the plants out I'll set them
on the floor and I'll take those
Tupperware dishes and clean them out
real good I'll just hose them out
outside in the backyard then I'll bring
them back in and then I'll remix more
water and then I'll pour that three
gallons and divide the three gallons up
by the two tubs and set them in there
and let it rock just like that under the
light and sometimes I'll do a small
breeding project like that if I'm making
new stuff that's often how I do it if
I'm running new seeds that's often how I
do it then I can do ten small plants
under one light sometimes you can do
even more if you want to do another
Tupperware dish and then you just veg
them for a very short time just until
they're you know like maybe eight inches
tall and then you flour them you don't
veg for very long and then that way you
can see what you've got if you're just
running a 400 watt light that's enough
space for that many plants you can see
what you've got you can see what you
made if you're running new seeds or you
can make plenty of new stuff I recommend
if you're gonna do it that way do a mail
separately put the mail in a sauce
and set him to the side because he's
gonna get eliminated once he pollinates
anyway so don't waste your space in that
Rubbermaid dish for the mail I just put
the mail in there and water the saucer
so that you could take out the saucer
eliminate him once everybody gets grown
real well and once everybody's
pollinated so that's a great way to run
a semi large number of plants in a small
space you could also do the same thing
with beer cups if you didn't want to
spend the money on the 6-inch net pots
you can fit more beer cups in the same
amount of space and you can use the
Tupperware container as your reservoir
as your base like I like to do is my
hydro table but that's if you're running
that many plants you have to worry about
the rules and the laws so be careful you
can fit a lot more beer cups under that
light and you can get them real close
together and grow them up till they're
about three or four inches tall and then
flower them you can see what you've
created
if you want to pollinate those at that
height you certainly can do that and you
can make a bunch of seeds from a really
short crop that's a way to do it but my
idea started with a single pot to stay
legal and get away from all the large
numbers but if you want to go with large
numbers just use beer cups make sure you
poke holes in the bottom so you get
plenty of drainage I like to use a drill
and I stack like five or six cups
together and go straight through the
bottom three or four times and then I
actually like to go through the side
right about I don't know maybe half an
inch up just go right through the side
of the cup four times so you have plenty
of drainage if you're gonna be filling
the reservoir and you're using the cups
you can't go as deep because you will
start to get root rot there's not as
much drainage happening not as much
oxygen you have to be careful it would
be a good idea to put an airstone to get
one of those aquarium air stones with
the two that come off and drop one air
stone in each reservoir of water to keep
the oxygen level in there high but if
you're using well aerated coco with the
net pots you should be fine if you're
using beer cups you certainly need
oxygen flowing in that water or it won't
get funky treat it kind of like hydro
measure your PPM's and stuff don't don't
overdo it and then I just let it flower
if you're doing brand-new seeds I like
to let new seeds go nine to ten weeks if
you're pollinating to make new seeds let
that go you'll probably have pollination
start happening if you're not touching
anything the pollen will start dropping
around day 14 go in there and smack the
plant one time around day 25 you really
have heavy pollination by then
wait until about day 65 to cut that
stuff down let it dry and you've just
made a tester bachelor seeds with one
light possibly one pot possibly a
Tupperware dish this depends on what
method you chose Oh something I should
mention it just dawned on me if you're
gonna do the the Tupperware method with
the water in there it is cold as [ __ ]
right now that you guys it's Colorado
where I am it's wintertime it's getting
cold even in the house the floor is cold
get that Tupperware container up off the
floor I just put something underneath it
or it's not touching the floor between
get it a little bit warmer that water in
there will get cold that will cause you
problems right now if you're in Cali and
it's not cold don't worry about it but
if you're somewhere like I am right now
starting to get super chilly
don't let that water get real cold you
guys it may sound like I'm
oversimplifying things but if you're
trying to do stuff for yourself in your
house and you don't have a lot of
resources it shouldn't be as
intimidating as a lot of people think it
is
you can breed just like I said under one
light in very very minimal conditions
and you can have great success don't
scare yourself
don't overcomplicate it don't overthink
things keep it simple stoner I think a
lot of people make mistakes in the grow
by overthinking they cause problems by
overthinking when people come to me for
advice on the internet and they're like
man this is going wrong I don't know
what to do I don't know what to do what
should I do
it's all dude smoke a joint go for a
walk and then come back and look at your
plants and the answer will come to you
you won't be so freaked out you won't be
so panicky you won't be overthinking it
you're just driving yourself crazy so
what we do with most of life honestly I
think try to overanalyze things
overthink it look too deep into things
you start [ __ ] up just see what you
see and accept it alright don't
overthink the grow it's not that hard
you guys its nature these plants grow
like I've said it several times the cush
grows on a mountain on a cush Mountain a
goat peed on it it got a bunch of wind
they got a bunch of rocks thrown at it
it was not a happy plant and it survived
that's where it happened it's where it's
all from Durban poison is from Africa we
have a Durban poison plant that won't
grow in the garden we couldn't figure
out what to do with it we quit giving it
water guess what it grows there from
random places with random conditions
they didn't come from place they'd none
of these plants were they didn't happen
naturally in a grow room in a sterile
facility they were on a mountain they
were in a John
they were in a forest they were in
shitty climates getting pissed on by
goats getting chewed out by bats random
terrible things were happening to these
plants and they survived so don't be
scared to take it and treat it like a
plant it's not a puppy it's not a dog
it's not an iPad they can take some
[ __ ] also you may kill some plants
in your time I have killed a lot of
plants don't get me wrong I've killed a
lot of [ __ ] that's how I learned to be a
good grower I only post really cool
things to Instagram I only tell you
about really cool experiences on the
podcast you guys guess what I've gotten
spider mites a lot I've had powdery
mildew before I've had bud rot I have
[ __ ] up trays of clones one time when
I was a new grower I got too stoned and
fell asleep and left the grow room door
open all night and seeded the entire
[ __ ] crop and heard the whole thing
so guess what you guys I make mistakes
don't be afraid to try new stuff don't
be afraid to make some mistakes and
don't be afraid to not treat this plant
like it's a princess it's a weed they
called it weed for a reason all right
I'd love to hear it if you decide to use
any of my new growing techniques I
taught you today if you're gonna breed
in a single pot if you're gonna breed in
several small pots if you're gonna breed
in the little tray and 6-inch net pot or
if you're gonna grow and the six-inch
net pots like I recommend it I'd love to
hear what you're gonna do if you have
any questions let me know you can reach
out to me a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I will answer your questions
personally I do have a lot of emails it
may take me a minute to get to them but
I'm doing my best to answer each one
personally all right you guys I want to
thank everybody for listening to episode
number 256 of the girl from your heart
podcast if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast or if you've got a product you'd
like me to review I would love to hear
from you send me an email once again
it's a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love it if you find
me on social media you can stalk me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast on Instagram it's Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore GE
and ET ICS I read genetics on Instagram
don't forget I do some Instagram live
videos it'd be fun to have you there I'd
love to see your comments love to get
your input see what you've got to say
I'm supposed to remind you again about
the email I keep writing down the word
email so grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
if you're not into the social media and
you'd like to reach out the email is the
way to do it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you guys don't forget that I
put out throwback Thursday episodes
every Thursday the reason I do that is
because iTunes and stitcher only hold
100 episodes in their feed and I've got
256 episodes out now that means there
are episodes people cannot find in the
feed I am putting old episodes together
in blocks of like maybe three maybe five
episodes it's usually about three hours
worth of content I mash them all
together and then I release them on a
Thursday that way you can go back and
listen to that old stuff the trick now
is that a lot of that old stuff is being
reposted and it's pushing the older old
stuff out so my solution to that like I
mentioned earlier is to put it up on
YouTube you can find the show on YouTube
the first hundred and three maybe one
hundred and five episodes are available
on YouTube simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast click subscribe
click like interact with me there I
would appreciate it also one more
request I would love it if you'd go to
iTunes and give me a five star review on
iTunes and click Subscribe also type in
a comment let me know what you think
about the show I may read your review on
a future episode if you leave in iTunes
rating and review alright you guys my
throat is burning out I want to thank
everybody for listening to this episode
I want to give you a huge shout out to
my friend Johnny Snipes and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
so young
and I can remember
[Music]
Oh
hola
[Music]
Jojo Jojo
Buju
[Music]
four cha-cha-cha
you