[Music]
welcome back campus community it's time
for episode number 258 to grow from your
heart podcast you're a source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right here at new grower liquor
professional grower here at news smoker
or a dedicated dabber the pure cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots been letting you use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots
ladies and gentlemen you ask and you
shall receive white Mike is back in the
house welcome to the show brother thanks
I left a moment so that everybody could
applaud that's why I was silent for a
moment in my mind Magister yeah
everybody was applauding if you did not
applaud heavily at that moment I will
allow you to rewind your podcast 15
seconds and at that moment I expect you
to applaud in your car that's off chance
to trick grabs the episode correctly
there's a 30-second back button ah poor
stitcher for some reason [ __ ] keeps
[ __ ] up I think we've got it all
corrected you guys for some reason
there's one episode but stitcher will
not take stitcher decided y'all don't
get it yeah I don't I'm yeah Mike didn't
get to hear it either Mike listens on
stitcher it will not they've sent me
emails like we fixed all your problems
and I'm like this episode won't go and
they're like sorry but count them
[ __ ] see those two numbers that are
next to each other that don't go next to
54 to 55 see the problem here but nope
it but we're not gonna come [ __ ] heads
because people do get to listen for free
so we're gonna just be like I'm sorry I
apologize that's one throwback Thursday
episode you will not get but when the
time comes when that number falls in
sequence I will put it in the YouTube
feed it will happen there right so
you'll get it that way I apologize there
are other ways to listen to it I'm sure
I apologize guys I don't know what to do
but this pitcher just pretty much gave
me the big purple middle finger to the
website and listen oh I don't know the
web sites a piece of [ __ ] that's
embarrassing that's why I say people can
find other ways to listen I didn't want
to encourage that
that piece of [ __ ] website being visited
listens just fine yeah you go there if
you like you guys it's not that bad
as far as 2:53 is concerned it's way
better than hey ah since uh since do I
mention on the last episode that I met
mr. jinx proof I couldn't tell you so
yeah just uh just a quick shout-out to a
few friends if you're not aware of jinx
proof
big shout-out to a breeder known as jinx
proof reader of the nine pound hammer
and several other award-winning strains
on notable strains jinx proof came to a
gross store in Pueblo West Colorado and
hung out
just hung on visited did a little bit of
uh seed exchange gave some advice gave
some talking drinks Rufus is a very
positive dude
jinx proof has an autistic son and they
do autistic autism awareness he's got a
very cool wife named Miss Rose he didn't
bring the son or the wife but he came
and hung out I want to give a big
shout-out to my friend dung beetle for
inviting me also it was random because I
was standing there and a dude walked up
to me he goes hey is this where jinx
proof is gonna be and I was like and he
goes how are you Rasta Jeff and I was
like yeah man that's me and is like dude
my name is Banksy Jesse and I listen to
the [ __ ] podcast what's up bro so I
met Banksy Jesse who comments on my
Instagram stuff quite a bit who I've
read his messages on the show before so
that was cool to meet him big shout out
I may have talked about this on a
previous podcast it feels like I also
met a dude who goes by the name of
paperweight seed so I met bag see
Jesse's brother also can't think of the
dude's name quiet guy cool do though we
had fun everybody kind of ditched us in
the corner when we were hanging out
having a little session but he's a cool
guy we got to hang out shadow our friend
paperweight seeds I got to make some
friends with some more some more growers
and breeders and also there was a guy
there whose name I can't [ __ ]
remember I feel bad Oh him and I hung
out quite a bit he had some great chirps
the songs it session it happens in
session yeah when you smoke out and meet
a bunch of people you're bound to forget
someone's name did I get too high to
enunciate I think you did we this could
be interesting
this is going to be a very interesting
podcast uh so I just wanna give a shout
out to all my friends for hanging out I
get the opportunity to meet jinx proof
jinx proof is a very cool guy very
inspirational person very positive guy
and it's weird because a lot of times
when you meet people that you see on
social media or that you've followed on
YouTube or whatever when you meet them
they're not what they're cracked up to
be
it happens a lot unfortunately you guys
I'm sorry I get to meet a lot of people
and a lot of people I meet her bags a
[ __ ]
jinx proof was cooler than I had
imagined he walked in and I was the
first person he saw and I just stuck my
fist out I go what's up bro welcome and
game on because hey brother and just did
his thing you know what I mean I walked
in just just like it was you or me he's
like so what's that been going on guys
where do I need to be how are things
going sorry I'm late
nice a normal [ __ ] dude and he hung
out and he talked with us and I let him
do all of his like meet-and-greet
business and [ __ ] and then I went talk
to him and
he's super cool super legit he didn't
smoke with us because we were smoking
dads and he's got epilepsy and he's
afraid of butane which I've completely
respected but yeah anyway shot it's all
my friends that set up the meet and
greet with jinx proof that was a great
[ __ ] time Mike mentioned how high we
were and why we're so rambly we got
dabbed the [ __ ] out on some star dog og
shatter from our friends at the craft I
picked it up at Three Rivers we smoked a
whole bunch of that [ __ ] on an Instagram
live video we were on Instagram Tyler
flavor way longer than we were supposed
to be we just meant to drop in and take
it dad we hung out for a long time got
rambley he got rambly but they liked it
when we ramble um let's see where else
are we in this Oh Charlotte all my
friends had joined us on the Instagram
live feed that was fun I appreciate that
I get a lot of inspiration for a podcast
stuff that I've written down so many
notes from those conversations that we
have on Instagram live and I'm gonna put
them into podcasts uh you may hear my
voice you guys I am giving over a head
cold at chest cold and nasty [ __ ]
situational gross get over it right now
you probably heard of my lungs too yeah
everybody in our cultivation facility
passed around this little cold like it
was [ __ ] the plague it got passed
around like a joint yeah it sure did
well it's probably got something to do
[ __ ] safety ah may have something to
do with all that [ __ ] but yeah I'm
gettin over it it's Friday night and I'm
finally recording this episode will come
out Monday as scheduled but I am behind
on my recording day it makes me a little
antsy makes me anxious
I apologize for sound and kind of raspy
and kind of shitty but I meant I could
get over here and be on the show that's
the truth and you've been asked to come
back so I'm glad that you're here bro
thanks for joining me what I was gonna
confess to however is being cold and
having a chest cold and having a sore
throat for a couple of days oh by the
way ah this is not an ad for any product
but if you take too much mucinex holy
[ __ ]
you'll feel better and you'll feel
better oh my god that was a [ __ ]
adventure a little bit extra mucinex and
a [ __ ] edible whoa holy [ __ ] yes and
most of that was the would you say 120
milligrams of THC yeah yeah so I haven't
eaten edibles you guys in over a year
you took a long I took a long edible
break a really really long edible break
and definitely since well before March I
was gifted some edibles and I decided
since I was sick and had a sore throat
there's time to much them so I got down
on a half godoh bar 860 milligrams of it
I was like I kind of feel like I might
be huh
so 860 more and I was like now I'm
[ __ ] high 120 milligrams had my highs
a little red and I was feeling a little
loopy and then they took a couple of
small dabs just to [ __ ] push me right
there and it got me I was pretty lit so
I'm kind of back on the edibles train
you guys I'm not gonna go crazy I don't
want to be the super edible monster that
I was for a while you guys it would not
be a feat for me to eat a thousand
milligrams in one sitting
oh that used to happen regularly once a
week once every two weeks I was hanging
out with some guys that like to do the
thousand and the 2500 milligram
challenge yeah once it started as a
thousand and within like a month it was
to 2500 well yeah cuz a thousand got
easy like you do wouldn't I've gotten
really crazy metabolism I could eat 120
milligrams and not be high in two hours
so a 250 and then I'm not high in two
and a half hours and then I eat 300 and
then I'm just super high for an hour but
it just didn't like it just all comes
through at once but once you start
getting in like the thousands II that's
when you start getting up like for our
high want to eat that 2500 milligram you
get these visions why I can do that to
myself with like 30 not the Vision Quest
but the bait for 3 hours sorry that the
iPad rang that might have interrupted
the recording I'm not sure no the iPad
rang though that's really weird I turned
off all the phones in the [ __ ] high
path sorry about that that's very
unprofessional it did a really good job
for the last hour it just dropped the
ball now we've got a it doesn't have the
little floppy thing like the phone does
on the side to put it all the way down
so I can't turn it down that's cool
we're just not even gonna edit that I
apologize that you guys got to hear the
iPad ring hands off
hey Mike where the [ __ ] were we on this
podcast edibles too many edibles too
many edibles yeah there's the numbers
you throw out or just insane to me like
I eat 10 is for like pain management
reasons or I really like 10 of THC in
Tennessee BD there's not an intoxication
that goes with that but the the pain
relief I get from it is really nice but
if I up the THC to 25 or 30 like I'm
having fun for most of the night I don't
I don't want any CBD in my mix um a
friend of mine gave me of one of the
hundred milligram doughnuts for my
birthday and when I half of that oh I
was ruined for like four hours
just like giggle high like laughing at
words bro ads roads don't get us started
on roads of our post though was the word
that I died on that night I learned in
Spanish funny I'm one of Davey's books
there's English in school that's pretty
cool man I'm glad you're teaching him
Spanish nope in the wife's at least
though and I've turned into a giggle
puddle and had to leave the room one of
these days when you're old you're gonna
hear the word listo and you're gonna
piss yourself and it's gonna be
hilarious
yep all right yeah well yeah you guys
don't go trying to eat 25 hundred
milligrams of edibles unless you know
your own tolerance
yeah like Mike said start off with like
30 50 go low and you can always eat more
if you can't uh those edibles that once
you eat the drugs the drugs is in yeah
yeah once you're spinning around wishing
he didn't do that you're spinning around
wishing you didn't do that alright that
I mention what we're dabbing on I did
we're smoking some star dog og shatter
we had some there's some bordello on the
table I'm gonna dab and then what did
you give me a dab of Mike it was it was
good you took some come for it before
yes come for him I'm dabbing on some I
can't remember the name of this one
Jackie's mission Jackie's mission that's
the CBD I took a dab of that one earlier
today I really enjoyed the flavor it
made me so lazy my knees and my lower
back don't remember that it's Friday and
it was a long hard week it was something
longer just cheered up chilled out yeah
a lot happened this week we were
productive we were quite productive good
job good job to everybody out there
busting
ass especially all the people out there
doing outdoor harvest season oh man
it's in full swing big time full swing
it's been a treacherous year for all the
tour goers yeah let's see what do I do
next I think I should do this this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends in the dank team.com that's
right if you're looking to add some new
genetics to your garden if you need some
regular and/or feminized seeds if you
want to add something new to the lineup
something new and unique so then nobody
else in the neighborhood has if you want
to set your part set yourself apart from
everybody else in town visit the dank
team.com the dank team carries brands
like rare dankness archive can Avengers
Sin City mile-high rare dankness IRA
genetics Sour seeds but there's a whole
bunch more I can keep going on and on
and on a whole bunch more trusted brands
that I'm sure you will enjoy I'm sure
you'll find something you're looking for
something that will fit all of your
needs at the dank team.com the dank I've
got a head cold da MK T EAM dank
team.com I'm sure it sounds like I'm
just going Thank You calm sorry it's
alright the dank team.com it's not you
their ears are high
your guys's ears need a [ __ ] cleaning
just kidding i listened to the podcast
well I've got a head cold I love you
guys so the dank team at is done Mike
you got anything you want to say before
I get into this email that I've got here
no blank look on your face jeez your
[ __ ] wheels just locked up there's
lots of stuff I could ramble at but I
want to see what what we got in the
email bin I'm kind of curious what
you're gonna rambling but I can read
emails anything just pick one and like
like as if it's the second email one
thing okay so today I saw this on five
different anti-pop pages that I follow
there was another recall today in
Colorado where some dispensary used some
pesticide that isn't allowed in
commercial use for cannabis in Colorado
when they sent their [ __ ] to be lab
tested it tested for that it got
recalled because of that the way it
works in Colorado is you can't send any
of the harvest batch out before the lab
test comes back
so all of that product was still sitting
on a shelf waiting to be sent to a
retail location like the announcement
was the system working was legalization
working was a huge point of legalization
being passed into law millions of people
are already spending billions of dollars
on marijuana the least we can do is make
sure they're buying a lab tested product
didn't know what they're getting in this
is the system working and I see five
different anti-pop pages like oh my god
it's not natural or safe this is a
marijuana fail and then on the way over
here I see that I can I want to say
Safeway had their burritos recalled for
Listeria and so when I get home tonight
and I'm gonna be like burrito fail not
Safeway is a dangerous corporation yep
no I'm just kidding don't employ that
wasn't one of the five things that
flashed through my head when you're like
what do you want to rant about ya know
it's a good thing Mike instead cannabis
got caught no I am pretty sure that only
recreational cannabis is tested for
pesticide is that accurate
at this point it's do you know the
requirements are for both but the
medical doesn't have to be submitted
until January one I believe okay we
don't have enough [ __ ] labs yeah
that's that's a whole other story there
if you don't know the the places that
test the cantaloupe and the chicken
wings aren't allowed to test the
cannabis because of federal licensure
the first lab in Colorado that got set
up to test cannabis applied for that
license and got raided
so the it's walkie we're still building
part of that system but all rec is
tested for pesticides yeah all
recreational cannabis so if you're
buying if you're coming from another
state and or shopping at the
recreational market your product has
been tested which is weird I think they
would have done medical first um they
wanted to but medical was already up and
running and had kind of built a stable
system before they passed any of these
rules and then they were lobbied heavily
by both the testing labs and the REC
owners the REC owners have a hard enough
time getting their lab tests turned
around and a reasonable amount of time
and they end up with
like sitting in a storeroom when they
want it sitting on a store shelf and so
they lobbied pretty heavily to not
require medical submissions or turn
around there were enough labs part of
that's because in the years since this
was done it's been like two and a half
years we've several more labs have
opened up for a while look in one lab in
Jurong go they could do one of the tests
yeah and we do [ __ ] send our [ __ ] -
[ __ ] Boulder
yeah we're in Pueblo and we have a
courier do it comes from Boulder and
then drives down all the way down to
Pueblo turns around five minutes after
he gets there and drives all the way
back to Boulder it's like the shittiest
drug deal you could ever imagine
yeah I get one gram of everything please
and then I'm gonna drive for three and a
half hours home yeah it's yeah the fun
part is just pulling a gram out of
everything that we harvested and then we
sit around at the Gro just kind of one
eye on our email waiting for Christmas
to show up when we get our test results
back yeah we've had some pretty nice
test results 33 s thirty twos got a
bunch over 30 the sauce right yeah we're
doing all right we're getting that
growth dialed in so shadow so the whole
crew out there if you guys are listening
much love and respect everybody that
helps out in the garden out there all
the trimmers everybody in the whole
building
appreciate everybody killing it lately
Thank You boys lady
well [ __ ] Mike you're here what's the
second thing on your mind what what
grinds your gears oh god I'm tired
there's so many different ways I'd go
with this how can you be tired with all
that how can you be tired with all the
Mountain Dew you drink the Mountain Dew
I drink is the only reason I'm able to
function at all okay I don't know you
see how insane I am up front these days
and you add a two-year-old to that like
it's a miracle I'm [ __ ] talking
English right now and not just gibberish
um what do you guys want to hear about
you want to hear about Maine's governor
vetoing legalization that passed by
[ __ ] popular vote
so in election and he just said nah it
passed the state legislature and Senate
had to pass rules and regulations
package isn't the governor said no today
in his statement about it he's he said
suffice other states that have done this
did so under an Obama administration
that was pretty clear that they were
gonna be hands-off we don't have that
anymore so I ain't gonna risk it which
is nonsense because if you remember
folks this was the governor who went on
national television elected politician
in front of a camera that he invited and
he says and this is a quote or as close
as I can get to a quote so I apologize
for the heavy racial / - undertones and
overtones but this governor of Maine
says we don't want to pass a law and
encourage d-money to come up here and
impregnate white girls with luring them
with drugs that's what his fear of
marijuana was at legalization and he
threw out a couple of names like D money
and I can't remember the other two D
money is the one that's stuck in my head
lightly racist not even slightly it's
it's ridiculous
like I don't know how he's still got his
job after going on TV and saying that
[ __ ] like six months a year ago well he
did where did you say it is the governor
of Maine Maine that's always still has
this job yep all nine people up there
don't give up buck no reason their dicks
off I didn't want to go vote on [ __ ]
though the lucky ones found a way to
move [ __ ] anywhere that doesn't suck
but yeah
sorry Maine you're gonna have to wait
quite a bit why quite a while longer for
a legalization apologize if anybody
heard that sniffle yeah I may have to
press pause here in a second I'm getting
a pretty good sniffle set up unless you
just want to talk for a few seconds I
don't know if they want me to do that
let's hit pause and grab fresh drinks
and [ __ ] buddy all right guys we're
gonna take a quick second I gotta blow
my nose we're gonna grab a quick drink
we may take a DAB we'll be right back
eleven kisses peace oh is that torched
Diane did I just dial
damn it quick I'll get it going don't
worry I could do this hello [ __ ] is
plenty hot oh [ __ ] hot at her tea who
needs it esophagus not you did you hear
record before after that oh right before
that it's nice right on the show oh my
god Liz if you didn't I'm talking to the
microphone porno
reason that stabbed superhot dab holy
[ __ ] thank you you're welcome
Mike just gave me a dab of his bordello
shatter the whole [ __ ] room smells so
good
oh my brain smells funny oh god it was
too hot one of the heat cooking me than
the hi face tingles lung tingles finger
tingles something burning in a work it's
like questionable is this a stroke or an
orgasm either way don't stop I like it's
a hot dab face in the O face equally
hilarious oh I'm glad you're laughing
yep it's fun to watch y'all gonna listen
to me choked for like five minutes here
in a second so get [ __ ] Redemption
what do you want - damn I don't be super
super hot what what are my options
pretty much chem 4 or the star dog you
know horrible weirdo I think I want a
bordello
we're gonna need some butane sir
listeners we love you you like it when
we ramble do you like it when we get
distracted and dab there's oh there
should be butane in there if not we'll
figure something out there's somebody on
their way here will make them acquire
butane for us in the meantime we can use
the email this perch may have all right
we're getting it going you guys uh when
the divers too sticky to get one dad so
you get four take all four of the dads
Mike I'm gonna dab all four of them guys
welcome back to the podcast we are here
we got hydrated my god nicotine I got I
got caffeinated we're doing just fine
now I got that crap out of my nose
thanks for listening thanks for
tolerating my head cold Mike thanks for
coming over and helping me put together
a podcast
[ __ ] you and I've gone too and a hundred
percent with my head cold here it's a
lot easier to ramble with two people got
to give the people's with the walk that
hissing sound is Mike filling up the
torch I should have probably turned down
his mic I apologize that's the tame the
tame brain all right so uh let's get
into an email we've been rambling a
whole bunch
all right so this one comes from
somebody who did not mention if they
want their name set on the show what up
Chris
such a great [ __ ] callback oh my god
that person probably doesn't listen they
probably hate us deleted all podcasts
off their phone and in spite all right
anyway our friar listeners sent an email
and said Rasta Jeff I know you're a busy
man but could you point me in the
direction of some short growing strains
that the dank team provides I've been
viewing strains on their website but
they don't show height stats on any of
the strings there you go all that sound
you guys heard was Mike not being able
to turn off the tour charge [ __ ] with
me the dog was just trolling me it did
it to me earlier it would not shut off
it's becoming dangerous anyway the
strains on their website but they don't
show any height stats on any of the
strains also a lot of the strains are
hard to find on other websites so I
can't cross-reference many of them to
find this out well I tried to get
through it without choking those dabs we
took have me choking let's see this
listener wants me to give them
information on short growing strains
available at the dev team so I did a
little bit of research they do have some
IRA genetics available
short growing now I'm not sure Mike's a
dying over there should I leave the mic
on or not we'll turn it down so that you
can hear him while you turn purple then
pale a little bit of sweat I think Mike
is kind of like my lease I add you guys
it's fun watching him change colors
might give me a thumbs up when you're
alive and we'll put your mic back on I'm
alive don't turn it on alright now I'm
not sure if you mean short growing
strains by like height wise or timelines
I'm not certain what you mean by short
growing strains when I read the question
the first time I interpreted it
interpreted the question has height now
that I'm rereading it on the show I'm
wondering if you meant time yeah do you
mean like some eight week plant some
seven week plants and night maybe yeah
or do you mean not as tall because I may
need to redo my research but
let's talk about I'm coming back folks
yeah I'm putting your mic back on I just
reached over to do that there you go
mics back you guys
hanging it back in hmm it makes my mic
sound better to it get a little echo off
that one he's lying he's not back in
he's lying back ish all right so uh
here's something that fits both
categories cookie stopper cookie stopper
some of the cookies stopper phenotypes
are done in like eight ish weeks 56 days
maybe 60 days and also they don't get
too tall ah
so cookie stopper fits both of those
categories another one prana prana is a
cross a flow and arise prana makes very
unique smelling plants they smell
amazing and some of them are done at
like 55 some are done at 60 some are
done at 63 days and they won't get too
tall Mike you all right bro I'm dead
tabs taking me places I can see it -
you're you weren't there for a moment no
I went somewhere else it was fun you
guys I wish I said cookie stopper I said
prana that I say the flow stopper no
stopper would be good for it doesn't
take too long to flower and stay sharp
another one that you will love that
everybody will love ah the morning dew
morning dew is grateful dog which is one
of my prizes one of my favorites cross
to arise which is another one of a lot
of people's favorites those are two of
my favorite strains I cry bread both of
them I crossed them together I call it
morning dew it doesn't get too tall if
there are some very cushion dominant
phenotypes in there that will give you
some big fat beefy cush it's got there's
some Kim D in there there's Joseph's og
there's a lot of great stuff in that
cross there's San Fernando Valley og
cush there's chem 91 there's a lot of
things in there that'll give you some
vigor you'll get some short but buddy
plants if you find the right phenotypes
so that's stuff for my region etics
let's talk about stuff from other
breeders Mike it looked like you had an
idea just if this is if you're talking
height or timeline if you're talking
high and you're really restricted shoot
us an email with some specifications of
your grow area and I know Jeff can come
up with three or four ideas to help you
out guaranteed on that guaranteed
but what things are still fluttering I
can I can see it yeah we can hear it a
little bit in you I'm sorry touch oh
you're good man we go you took a big old
dab you took click for from your size
dad yeah which is a one dad for a normal
girl but another string that I could
recommend it's no dab competition I'm
just [ __ ] with you another strain I
could recommend that is not from Ira
genetics but it is available at the dank
team comm is from our friends at La
Plata labs I would recommend the Durango
og that finishes it's got phenotypes
that finish in eight weeks you guys when
you're growing from seed you're gonna
find some phenotypes that finish earlier
some that finish later
find grow from seed if that scope I'll
get that earlier finishing one that
works best for you
finish it up that way [ __ ] you've got
what you need so the Durango OG will
have eight week phenotypes in there
here's another strain that I don't hype
a lot because it gets enough [ __ ]
hype on its own
tangey tangi from Crockett family farms
if you grow it up to be about I don't
know how high your tight restrictions
are but it's not it's not one of those
strains that stretch plants do what we
like to call the 21-day stretch for the
first three weeks of flower they really
like to take the [ __ ] off just the sky
they like to just start taking off tangi
doesn't seem to do it as badly as a lot
of other plants
Tangie kind of doesn't stretch for those
yeah tangi stays sort of low for you so
Stan G crosses strawberry-banana tangi
the taffy stuff like that was just Angie
and happy stuff like that'll stay kind
of shorter for you and they also the
tangent crosses don't take a real long
time to finish so that fits both of your
timelines that should be enough
recommendations for you Mike I'll put
your mic back on you look like you're
back on the planet I'm mostly good to go
you're on Animal Planet again bigs like
a cake but good to go baked like a cake
so those are some strains that are
available there's a lot of stuff
available from the Cali connection
you'll find some eight or nine week
phenotypes that stays fairly short
because they're cush dominant I'm not
exactly sure what you meant so let me
know if you want fast flowering or low
height because short growing has me
confused I did at first I thought one
thing and I read it again and I thought
another thing so let me know what you
think randomly I want to give a huge
shout out to my friends the
swings that's right plays I just saw one
fly by I really slay swings in a garden
recently and I just saw a swing fly by
here because uh yeah let's see hey to
our friend that sent this email we're
gonna call you height restrictions
thanks for the email let me know how I
can guide you more carefully I gave you
a few strange recommendations I would
like to get more specific and answer
your question more specifically Mike you
got any insight on that one no just let
us know which one you meant and we can
get you a better list of quick flowering
strains or a better list of short
strains or we can give you some specific
road tips to work with your space
absolutely uh you can trellis down most
plants put a little four by four or a
five by five trellis and add up like
just the square net I've seen so many
different methods yeah yeah but they
just let the plant grow into that and
then when it starts it'll grow up into
it and then just bend it down and keep
it weave it into that basically is what
you're doing to keep it low don't let it
go up let it go out and spread it out
one plant 5x5 I watched a guy every
morning he went out and he dipped the
top of his plant into the next loop of
chain link to the left yep in come
October it was just one long vine that
went halfway down his fence with little
Christmas tree buds coming off a big
pine cone or up yeah large pine cones
sticking off of each little spot yep so
instead of one giant glory bud sticking
up and touching the light you get a
whole room a whole 5x5 section I'm just
beautiful little buds little seven
grammars everywhere yep yep nice setup
all right so scrog it out keep him well
let us know how we can guide you a
little bit further oh let's see since
we're talking about seeds here's another
question about seeds he says hey Jeff
I've emailed before from Alaska about an
auto flower and you hooked me up with
the answer now I'm hoping for a two for
two it's been a little while since you
sent this I'm sorry I've got a ton of
[ __ ] emails but here you are I hope
you're still listening big shout out he
continues to say I'm interested in your
seeds and would like to know what strain
is a good producer and good flavor
I grow hi Oh to output deepwater hydro I
think I embarrassed myself
with my last episode about deep water
culture and hydroponics so I'll go ahead
and admit that I don't have a lot of
experience with that type of grow
situation but I do have a lot of
experience with strains that are good
producers and good flavor um good
producers anything crossed to the white
widow so Widow get Snuggie the look on
your face Widow kids noogie there's Mike
still - beautiful there's a white water
plant that my father-in-law of all
people grew that when people say white
widow I'm immediately flashed back to
that summer harvesting her like it was
just monumental the Storm Shadow cross
is what I'm talking about
from Ira genetics eye region etics puts
out huge are the Storm Shadow puts out
huge colas tastes really really amazing
kind of unique that's a good one so I
would go for the Storm Shadow that's
white widow to arise also there's the
cream the cream doesn't harvest as well
but the flavor is amazing I'm curious
what the look on your face means I just
I'm sitting there trying to think of
strains and my list is very different
than yours because it's generated from
different places and a totally different
knowledge base but um and then I
chuckled because of our friend 44 in
blue dream that's sort of what people
love about it is it's got a smell and a
favorite profile that most people find
pleasant and it harvest like a
[ __ ] another strain of mine
that's available at the dank team if
it's not available the dank team
available that I stutter on available
another strain you can get it at the
what's it called dank seedot CO or just
Google the hell a dank seed company and
you'll be able to find it but something
I recommend is called scarlet begonias
it's redheaded stranger to arise and it
will produce huge crops and it will
smell amazing so there's a few
recommendations for you I hope you find
something you like in that makes there
are two options to find seeds the dank
team.com
and the hell it ain't seed co just
google the dank team seeds or the hella
dank seed co and one of them will pop up
you'll be able to find what you need
there
opposite coasts so if you live on one
coast maybe that'll help you out with
shipping they've both got different
deals they both got different giveaways
check out their websites you decide
where to shop I endorsed them both I
want to give a big shout-out to the
person that sent this email I don't know
if you want me to say your name so I am
NOT going to but you know who you are
because you wrote this email to me in
May and I'm just now reading it to you I
apologize when my phone updated it wiped
out all my emails off my phone and I had
to go download apps for each individual
email address so if I've got yeah well
no then when I reloaded it on the app it
brought up so many [ __ ] emails I was
like I never even saw that so I printed
them off but I wasted like seven trees
I've got the emails and I'm reading them
now so this one came from May and I'm
reading it I apologize but hey I read it
I did it I'm gonna catch up there's so
many emails all right Mike you got
anything you want to add to the high
good producer and good flavor from I
read genetics seeds nope yeah I didn't
think you'd have any better insight than
what I've got available know that read
IRA genetics each part yeah they want
something from my line that's funny so I
would say the Storm Shadow and the yeah
those are the way to go some older stuff
that will be a lot harder to find than
those that that meets that definition
but the Capleton if you can get the
Storm Shadow [ __ ] dive on Bounty
Killer the battery kill is what I was
thinking I was specific I don't know
where that's available Bounty Killer
seats go get those it was laser your
standard movie theater straw with a
two-liter bottle on it is how that plant
built out there was just a [ __ ] [ __ ]
yeah
just insane nugget everywhere alright
let's see I've got another email I want
to read do it I'll ramble a lot through
it so I wish you luck it looks long it
is kind of long but it's quickened to
the point for being so long this guy
says hey Ross - Jeff you don't know me
but I know you my name is and his name
is not Slim Shady but I don't know if I
just named since my name is you don't
know me but I watched you throw your
trash out every Wednesday
his initials are ZD and he says and I
listen would you say his name was
sir just what was said okay yes Zed his
name is Zane welcome
Zain I am I listen to your podcast I've
been listening for a few months just
keeping up with the most current one
posted recently your podcast has
recently started to click with me one of
your latest GF wih podcasts you had set
out a correctly used weed terminology
like the phrase dabs instead of dab when
you talk about doing dabs I thought you
brought up a good point and it really
seemed like a move I would do too I
would do also in trying to help out my
weed smoking brothers now I feel more
like your brother to me than most and I
gotta say it's all because of this
badass podcast so keep up the good work
brother and let's work together to
educate each other about what we are
truly passionate about there's more the
email but I want to say I like these
emails when people tell me that they
feel like they're my friend because this
may sound weird but I'm not only a
podcaster but I listen to podcasts as
well
right I'm also a member but I listen to
a lot of podcasts and I listened to the
podcast hosted by comedians I don't
listen to a lot of cannabis podcast you
guys the reason I don't listen to a lot
of cannabis podcasts is because I don't
want to bite their style I don't want to
accidentally steal their voice I don't
want to contaminate my flow with yes
exactly
I don't want to become other people so I
try to keep my god shot at for friends
at the dude grows podcast great people
great podcast if you're not listening to
the dude grows podcast the dude grows
podcast just Google dude grows show and
listen you'll love it my favorite music
wherever you're listening to my show the
dude grow show is available there and
please message them and be like hey
Rasta Jeff gave you a shout out and
we're gonna listen to your show because
I don't see a compa to they put out an
episode every [ __ ] day if you've got
time to listen to all their spoken
please do I don't have time to put out
that much content I was listening to an
episode of there's the other day and
they were like just hit 500,000 no
biggie
coming at it dude if you guys could
cover my my monthly salary did I make it
the grower just know I know if my
listeners would cover my what I make
monthly like however I make on a good
month like with a little bit of overtime
and maybe a small bonus just pay me what
I expect to make in a month which I know
what I bring in
the podcast listeners could put that
together I'm not asking you guys to this
hypothetical this would be the drug I
would put out and you'd go full Rogan I
would put out four episodes a week of
new content and then every Thursday I
would still do a throwback Thursday I do
Monday and Tuesday and Wednesday and
then I put out a throwback Thursday
podcasts on her Friday seems weird I
don't think anybody would even [ __ ]
listen to a Friday podcast if you put
out a show on a Friday everyone's out
party and everyone's out doing their
thing nobody's listening to a podcast
road-tripping road-tripping okay maybe
maybe and then maybe a Sunday show you
know what I mean but I'd put out at
least four fresh episodes and a
throwback Thursday episode and I would
also do a lot of YouTube stuff I would
totally step up my social media game my
life game because that would be able to
you know what I mean I would patreon the
[ __ ] they multiply my content time to
plug patreon well I guess we'll do it
patreon since we're in the middle of an
email patreon is a service that allows
my listeners to contribute to the
podcast financially just a minute ago
Mike told me that his microphone cover
smelled like he'd been spitting in it
for too long no I said this one smelled
like one that hadn't been spitting yeah
that's kind of a freshie one it smells
like shoe polish or something doesn't it
no just most like synthetic fabric Geico
phone I got these black microphone
covers from China through Amazon I made
stunk a little bad it smells like no
Halloween costume yeah yeah I believe
them sit now for a while because it was
really strong but anyway patreon you can
contribute to the podcast by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
patreon will allow you as a listener to
financially contribute to the podcast
what I will do with your contributions
is pay for my website I region TEDx
Colorado comm which is where I host the
show which allows you as a listener to
listen to the show for free there are a
few people out there that would like to
contribute I would appreciate that also
what I do with those contributions is I
will replace these little fuzzy
microphone covers so that they don't
start to smell like sausage and bad
breath so that when other people think
of really dirty shows yeah well I don't
even know I was here for like well that
was 15 that was a certain person's mic
and he had a funky mustache and just
always rub his mustache on to it just
[ __ ] it up real bad but and I also buy
bottled water and stuff like that so I
would appreciate it if you want to go to
patreon and help us out I'm not begging
I'm just letting you know that it is an
option patreon
patr yo n.com / grow from your heart
check it out all the information you
need to be right there
since I'm speaking about patreon Calvin
Medina huge gigantic shout out in a big
fat hug thank you I appreciate all of
your support let's get back into the
TV's gonna say the loop back to the
email I one of my favorite things about
this show is that it feels like you're
when you're listening to it it feels
like I'm at the table yeah and I don't
know if that's because I'm often at the
table or if that's just the field that
everybody gets from the show or a lot of
people get from the show but I've been
listening a lot more now that I'm over
here less mainly to fill some of the
hours and work and stuff but makes me
feel like I'm getting out and doing a
lot more than I actually am I've been
listening to Joey Diaz on podcast for
years anybody that listens to this show
knows how much I listen to Diaz Diaz is
one of my favorites and from listening
to and also Chris Hardwick and also
proofs Greg Proops I don't listen to
proofs as much lately he's been on the
it every show is the same lately sorry
proofs I don't mean to say that but
you're every shows the [ __ ] same
lately please switch it up a little bit
I love you please switch it up a little
ah but I've seen I've listened to all
these comedians podcasts for so long
Doug Benson
[ __ ] how did I skip Doug Benson uh so
when I go to see them it's just like
hanging out with you there's no like
stardom it's like hey what up uncle Joey
and he's like what up [ __ ] and
[ __ ] wait together and we hang out
and like I take friends with me or I
take Jenny Beth away from here I've
taken other friends with me dudes or
females and some of them get jittery and
they get weird and they talk differently
than they normally would when I'm around
them like uncle Joey it's so good to me
and I'm like are you squeaking but are
you squeaking at uncle Joey you don't
squeak when you talk what the [ __ ] are
you doing
like people change and I'm just like it
what up Joey you I got it got some weed
you want to smoke it you got a number
dog [ __ ] spark that [ __ ] up [ __ ]
let's go right you probably spent a
couple hundred hours with that voice
next to you yeah yeah I know so when he
starts talking I know what he's talking
about like I relate to it and so when
these people what I'm getting to is when
people say that I'm more like a brother
I reciprocate that feeling I understand
that probably more than something
would I here's a really random story
that's gonna make me feel like a fanboy
I've been watching Chris Hardwick's and
singled out Harvick's an awesome
comedian funny dude I've heard him say
several times I want to play Red Rocks
Chris Hardwick is from Denver his one of
his wife goals bucket list is to play at
Red Rocks in Morrison Colorado he was on
the oddball comedy tour that one year
that played at [ __ ] Red Rocks he
walked out on stage and took a selfie of
himself and he goes I've always wanted
to [ __ ] do that I felt an odd sense
of pride
we were watching a friend me the Gleek
like you did it I was like I've got to
play Red Rocks man that's [ __ ] cool
and honestly horlicks one of the few
I've never met I've seen him I've seen
him do shows but I've never shook his
hand I've never he doesn't seem like the
type to hang out after a comedy works
and smoke a joint whether downstream
right right he's yeah he's different he
seems like he'd need to be out a plan to
go film a talking show right exactly
exactly got a record a intro to his
podcast then an airplane bathroom real
quick
yep yeah but but anyway I relate to it
because when I saw Hardwick up there at
Red Rocks I was like my bro Hardwick is
[ __ ] doing it right like so that was
cool so I get it you guys I do get it's
not lost on me and I do appreciate it
being recognized and known and
complimented and praised and whatever
the other humble words are for it hasn't
gotten to my head too much I still
appreciate it it still means wanting me
to get compliments I'm trying to stay
humble that's what I think I'm trying to
say anyway I want to continue with this
email because I'm making it really
[ __ ] long usually damn rambley one I
saw I I saw the length of the the text
on the page I knew this was gonna be a
good content link email folks oh man
there's an email that I didn't print
that I wanted to read anyway um I may
find it we may press pause and find it
here in just a minute
this guy says also I live in Colorado
and I represent represent my state
rights by maintaining my lucious closet
grow operation I need to branch out with
some new genetics and I feel confident
you've got the quality I'm looking for
um let's go get a slap or bro I could
recommend the dank team.com
or the hell a dank seed company that's
what I can tell you
then he says let's meet up and he says
he was gonna be at a comedy show which
already happened and we did not meet up
so I apologize for that mr. Zane hey I
do appreciate the email I'm sorry that
I'm just reading emails from September
that's not too bad
yeah but they were in this email box
that I did your phone eh yeah it was
like hey you don't get the Seavey's III
empathize uh I had a relative recently
get married like for my nuclear family
and your say that again from my nuclear
family nuclear will you define that for
me the mother father brothers nuclear
did I just use the word you're not for
me I don't know that I've ever heard it
used like that I'm I'm pretty high and I
was totally like focused on another idea
in my head I was gonna go find this
email where somebody said something but
okay not here but the for some reason
the family the email chain about the
wedding they use the email I haven't
checked since like Eddie and I high
school Oh and so at one point I got a
phone call from the family member that
it was like what the [ __ ] that's what
the hell are you talking about like I
have plane tickets past that I haven't
thought about it at all no like we'll
check your email and I open it up and
I'd like 208 unresponded I was like yeah
and that's why I'm not the white sheep
yep well I'm looking for this for the
Lost email that you found yeah but no
we'll just save it for another episode
because there are so many great emails
in here were at like 45 minutes there's
no need for me to go digging for this
other one I think I'm high as giraffe
[ __ ] I thought we're at least at an
hour and a half well we would be if you
hadn't taken a cigarette break Mike to
fair point
yeah yeah so how we gonna save the world
save it or take it over I don't remember
I think they're the same thing
you guys should really try this Mike are
you that lit I'm gettin there the CBD I
think wore off and so I went from like a
four to a seven in the last ten minutes
all right Mike I want to read this other
email because you're super high and
there's no reason to do it recording if
you're this lit and having that good of
a time and I'm having a good time with
you and I'm sure the listeners enjoy
listening to us but I have to dig
through my phone too
find it so what I need from you is like
a solid two minutes of just so box might
want me to sell boxes yeah get up on a
sofa okay so I got a fan reached out
through Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws Facebook page and asked me about
Texas medical marijuana law and some
tips about advancing the legalization
cause down in Tejas so I for the first
time ever looked up Texas is medical
marijuana law I hadn't even heard about
it I've been so busy that got passed me
in there law is like ten milligrams of
CBD less than half a milligram of THC
oil only like super bullshitty and they
were asking me what I thought they
should do to advance the cause and I
gave them the you can dig back through
the pile and find a whole forty five
minutes show on like going to City
Council and getting involved in local
politics and researching and going and
making a solid argument that we did for
a podcast and I kind of gave him that
spiel and I thought about it for a
minute I was like no [ __ ] leave like
you you you know a trade you work in a
trade save up some money and the more I
thought about it I'm like if I was in
that situation I would save up as much
as I could not bail like if it's
possible for you to leave a place that
sucks and join a place that doesn't suck
why not do it like and I'm thinking
about Maine right now too
and there are a lot of people that work
really hard if the easily the biggest
[ __ ] in that Square area just [ __ ] it
up for everybody and now your choice is
fight for another two to four years and
get back to where you were yesterday or
work for six months live on a tight
budget move out of hell and I can't say
I don't recommend option B if you live
in a place that's sort of in between
hell and heaven or hell in Colorado
feel free to fight a lot harder or maybe
think a lot harder about fighting then
moving but if you're in a place where
they're still doing roadside cavity
searches for I smell weed in the car
ladies like I wouldn't feel bad about
putting the rest of my [ __ ] in the truck
and in heading out with just me and my
bank account if you're going to do so
have a plan though definitely come up
with a plan like don't just run away but
it's not that hard to move across
country and start over especially if you
make a plan save up some money it like
more than a few months rent and look for
jobs in your area out wherever you want
to move and there's there's like 26
states that have medical programs you
don't have to go for a medical or for a
marijuana job just because you're moving
this is something we need lawyers and
bankers and well there's yeah people
that make tacos it seems to trip a lot
of people up they move here from another
state and they're like I'm gonna go get
a weed job and I'm like what are you
gonna do and like them I'm gonna get a
weed job in the week I'm gonna be in the
industry and like what are you gonna do
can you trim can you bud ten can you
[ __ ] grow weed I know I'm gonna get a
job in the industry though you don't
know no you're not you're gonna come be
a burden have a skill whatever you're
doing where you are you can do that here
but I don't have legal cannabis unless
you're a deep-sea fishermen we have your
job here yeah you know like no seriously
like it's and that's through the
continental United States and if really
like you're like I can't give up fishing
[ __ ] move to Oregon or Washington
they're on a [ __ ] ocean - yeah there
are places you can go that it's not
yours you know what I'm saying though is
don't be too stubborn and think just
because you're moving to a weed state
you have to go full-on weed and work in
the weed industry be a weeds to grand
person [ __ ] like you don't have to do
all of that you just move here and have
a normal people job and have access to
safe clean medicine by going to a
dispensary you could be discreet about
it
you can move here and never tell anybody
that you moved here for weed wedge move
here I hated Maine the cold and shitty
came to Colorado yep
we definitely need like Colorado's
expanding lots of people moved here they
need dentists and teachers and people to
iron their shirts and executives
it is that kind of show folks all right
Mike I wanted you to ramble so that I
could find this email now that I am here
dude I've got it it's a quick one but
it's great that looks like a full screen
of text it's an iPhone it's not that
long this dude wants to go by the name
collard greens so what up my G collard
greens the message goes like this how
deejay us to send you some growers love
from the great state of Massachusetts
what up you Masshole I've been to
Massachusetts had a good time went to
New Murray Street hated it but the rest
of Massachusetts was he says been
growing my own top-notch organic
medicine for at least a few years now
and I love everything about it well
congratulations on the continued
successful garden I'm proud of you keep
it going
he also says the most addictive part of
growing of cannabis let me rephrase that
slow my face down the most addictive
part of cannabis is growing it heard
about your podcast from Scotty real and
the dude a big shout-out to those boys
we just gave them a shot on a moment ago
- what made me think of the psychic and
it was coming he said I really credit
their podcast with my excellent
performance in my garden and now I get
extra details to polish my technique
from your library of listening here's
something really funny
at least I thought so I recall Scotty
and the dude catching flack for too many
f-bombs and they mentioned that you keep
it clean the first episode I listen to
you read a comment about your [ __ ]
cool show or something with lots of
f-bombs and the next episode had a butt
hole song listen to the episode I'm not
sure which one was the butthole song but
then he said that's really [ __ ]
hilarious not at all what I was
expecting to hear and I love you for it
earned yourself a new disciple my friend
anyway no secrecy about my name needed
not searching for cred but not hiding
either
keep on teaching from collard greens
collard greens I Love You Man or or nope
- man love you man
thanks for uh thanks for all the love
thanks for reaching out I think it's
funny for a little while um
when I first started podcasting I had a
dirty mouth I I was on another podcast
it was comedy based I was hanging out
with a group of folks that thought they
were comedians some of them were
comedians some of them will and will not
be comedians and some of them just
watched the movie
private parts so many times some of them
go hold a microphone for minutes and
embarrass everybody but some of them are
actually [ __ ] good you guys um I'm
just kind of being a smartass about it
but when I would leave that show like or
over when I would leave that show I
would come do this show with a bad
comedian attitude and I would just it
doesn't stop when you hit your you you
act how you're fed you know what I mean
so that comedy would continue throughout
my day and I would just come be a witty
[ __ ] and it didn't work on the show
but I would do it anyway and so there
came a point where I was like man I cuss
too much I'm gonna stop cussing and then
I want it I put up a swear jar to where
every time I said [ __ ] I had to put
money in the jar and we donated that to
a charity but then I was like you know
what that feels weird I say [ __ ] like I
I have a help to tone it down but it was
it got unnecessary after a point and I
would feel weird cuz I'd come over here
and you'd be doing a really good job not
swearing yeah so we'll eventually I
decided [ __ ] it I say [ __ ] I'm an adult
this is my podcast we can put the
explicit rating up on iTunes and all the
[ __ ] adults can listen nope
that's how it'll [ __ ] be so um yeah
eventually I did just drop the facade
and I like to be myself on my podcast
now it's a lot more fun honestly someone
run episode 100 I just got really
comfortable here with the microphone I'm
lucky enough to have been a guest on a
few podcast shout-out to my friend Tim
Martin and the John Doe radio podcast I
was lucky enough to be a guest on that I
was a guest on a couple of other shows
and then also I got to be a co-host and
producer of a whole nother podcast that
did we did close to a hundred episodes
before I parted ways with them they
wanted to do a whole nother thing and
the dude actually moved away from town
so I just ended that relationship with
that podcast but I got a very good warm
up started there so I was basically
comfortable when I got on this show the
hard part of this show is finding the
show's voice and the rhythm and what I
wanted to do with it I used to have
segments and weird [ __ ] but I think it's
better when we just started talking hang
out having the show when I was when you
first started doing the throwback
Thursday episodes I had completely
forgotten the segments and then the
first episode where you skipped a
segment I was like oh where
yeah I was expecting that it's hard to
keep all those segments going it's hard
to keep you all that [ __ ] happening you
know all right we got off on to a really
good ramble because of this email mm-hmm
I like it it's not not necessarily bells
[ __ ] bro yeah sure that's all the good
hash
I haven't felt well lately and I haven't
been able to dab hard Mike and I dabbed
a little bit hard and I think we got a
little bit lit up tonight it was a long
week I needed it it was a long week eh I
want to thank everybody for all the
emails they've sent me I apologize I
know I've got a bunch of emails from a
long time ago but I will get to them I
will try to do my best to answer all of
them big shot to our friend collard
greens for the great email I appreciate
it thanks for being a new disciple is
what it looks like he called himself I
appreciate it thanks for joining me man
your real disciples take people's phones
add the podcast to their auto download
and then put the phone back the Sam
yeah shot it's my friend Brett also
known as Mary's motivation Instagram
Brett will grab your phone and be like
hey you should listen to my friend
Jeff's podcast and he will put it into
your phone for you at it so no work on
your part just click the button that's
right all you got to do is listen and
then every Monday morning a little icon
will light up and it says hey yo roster
Jeff put out a new episode and you
should listen master Jeff masse hey you
guys are if you participated if you were
mentioned in the the episode the what
[ __ ] number was it 250 concepts yeah
where people got to win prizes and get
stickers send me your contact info I
will have miss Jenny Beth label all of
the envelopes and I'll put some stickers
in them for you depending on where you
are who you are and what you did you'll
get a different prize you're gonna at
least get a couple of stickers from me
who knows what the stickers may be
hopefully it's an IRA genetic sticker
I've got a really nice sticker pack I
can give to people gotta put them
together you'll enjoy it just send me
your address however I like the I'd like
it if you send it to me via email would
be the best grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
if you want on Twitter if you want on
Instagram send me your Instagram and/or
Twitter handle let me know where you
want where you entered if you sent the
correct answer and you feel like you
deserve a sticker pack even if you
weren't the first second or third person
if you at least sent me the right answer
send me your address we'll get you some
stickers I am gonna check [ __ ] don't
try to don't try to troll me right and
if you follow directions
that's right more likely to get your
prize grow from your heart at hotmail
life is difficult when you've got 42
different social media platforms to
monitor yeah and I'm a busy dude so it's
hard to go through all of them I'll
scroll through Twitter and be like oh
[ __ ] I had that message a year ago
people don't understand what we do at
work though they think we were smoking a
lot of weed all day and we talk to
people in the building that physically
see what we do all day that don't
understand what we do all day it's a lot
of work y'all yeah yeah everybody before
the podcasts and the personal life and
the family and all of that yeah the home
grow and the [ __ ] breeding projects
and the kids you know whatever else
everybody else has everybody that that
grow has something else going on
everybody yeah everybody all right Mike
we've been go for just about an hour uh
do you have anything to say well we've
got a microphone for your face and a
whole bunch of people are gonna be
listening um check out my social media
if you're interested it's Nemo punk 15
on twitter and pablo for sensible
cannabis laws on facebook I've been a
little uninspired with Pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws lately I used to
do a bunch of really long-winded
elaborate post didn't get like one
comment on them I'd get like 1500 2000
views but one comment in over the last
couple months with the new gig I've been
a little uninspired so keep hitting me
up on there rien spire me rien spire my
buddy Mike get him going you guys go
troll him a little bit hobo for sensible
cannabis laws get him fired up um we
mentioned patreon earlier I would love
it if you guys check us out on patreon
patreon comm slash grow from your heart
if you would like to contribute to the
podcast I would appreciate the support
not trying to get rich however if you
guys would like to pay my monthly wage I
would just be a podcaster and if you
want a lot more content think about it
so much I would do it I would do I'm
asking one person to do it I'm asking
the collective alright anyway that may
come true and I'd get scared too you get
that email one day and you're like well
[ __ ] I really like growing her I'll do
it I'll do it I'm getting old I'm also
I'd love it if you guys support me on
social media I'm on Facebook search for
the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast
you guys Instagram I'm all over the
Instagram its Irie underscore genetics I
RIE underscore genetics make sure you
check that out occasionally I will jump
on Instagram live and do an Instagram
live video where I will talk about a lot
of material that I plan on doing on the
podcast I get a lot of ideas for my
Instagram live audience I interact a lot
and it's been a lot of fun I can't do it
constantly I like to do it sometimes
after work after I've taken a shower I'm
sitting here taking a couple of dads and
I'm chilling out that's my favorite time
to do it so check me out on Instagram
live if you've got the option and/or
opportunity is lucky Instagram life you
always got a shot of me on video today
they got to see Mike a little bit today
and you know what why Mike looks like
that's harder to say people don't see me
it sounded weird when I said that anyway
if you'd like to contact us and you were
not into the social media thing you can
simply email me if you've been listening
you know by now the email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com onna
thank everybody that send me emails they
got read on this episode I want to thank
everybody that send me emails they got
read on previous episodes and even more
I want to thank people that send me
episodes in the future no episodes
emails damn dabs are wrecking my brain
yep I'm fried - I can't believe it's
we're only at about an hour it feels
like this was a really long show a good
show but it feels way long you took that
one dad Mike that means you time-travel
it did that bordello stuff me fun places
I think it did did CSCS just been
crushing my meds lately I'm loving it
nice also guys don't forget a lot of
videos are up on YouTube now I've been
putting more and more YouTube videos on
and I saw 100 yeah one came up this
morning - at ten o'clock one o 106 - 109
there's a lot of them there will be more
Alexia's [ __ ] with number Alexia get
the numbers backwards thinking about 69
96 96 you doing it all backwards that
way that's fine that's fine
awkward maybe some editing to be done at
the end of this podcast or maybe not so
kind folks it all kinds Mike is one of
those kinds you
we take any type around here we take I
resemble that remark ladies and
gentlemen we're getting weird so we're
gonna turn off these microphones we're
gonna take a couple of dabs yeah oddly
enough more hashes the answer to this
particular well I think food is my
answer here pretty soon
Chinese food I do not have Chinese food
oh so you shut your mouth whoa cutting
deep whitey alright ladies and gentlemen
um I will be back Thursday of course
with the throwback Thursday episode then
I'll be back Monday with a brand new
episode where we will talk about
listener generated content um I want to
thank everybody for listening Mike I
want to thank you for coming and hanging
out and get [ __ ] with me the look on
your face is great but I can see how
high you are it's amazing
ladies and gentlemen make sure you
follow Mike on social media so you can
interact with this high-ass i'm usually
less hi that's good I enjoy this this is
fun thanks for coming everybody
oh yeah for uh for listening listeners
if you made it this far I would high
five of his high five super high he
might even miss make sure you check us
out on the throwback Thursday episode
please let me know what you think about
those follow us on all the social media
listen to us on YouTube I apologize if
stitcher fails you guys have to beyond
my control I'm doing my best they keep
sending me emails that say oh well
that's all I've got for you I'm gonna
quit rambling I'm gonna give you a huge
shout-out to my friend bagsied Jesse and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
more than often I Drive so much it is
like my ass is my feet I see little
black furry running dogs and I'm
standing up in my seat I'm standing up
and my seats to avoid sleep driving
crashing and Diane can turn up the to
rest area next ride is my salvation
cuz I'm running on whew
I'm running on fumes I'm running on
[Music]
let's get heavy the window goes down on
my face let me get two beats keep my
eyes open until I get there then I'll
kick the back that [ __ ] seat gonna
kick back and efficacy scatter its
mother
cupboard and chunk maybe a short stack
Mountain Dew many Finns and camel lights
it's a boxer a soft pack
[Music]
boxers soft bad
[Applause]
[Music]
or the long my dollars is cheap for five
hours in the motel bed truck stop shower
is only five dollars I think I'll go
with them instead I'm going with that
instead I love it when it all runs
together you gotta think about where you
build all of the places and the weird
looking faces I love it when it never is
wake me when this song is
[Music]
and the windows here become the
paintings with a glass and the world is
the canvas it's a peaceful diameter it's
like two gentle arms it's hugging me and
there's a four points chair that hangs
on to change cuz an old back seat of the
Jeep
I don't mind shooting the dogs off do
you observe the world the ball observe
the world
observe the world
[Music]
son goes to China this guy comes alive
and those paintings a purple swirl lift
up the glass and you climb into the
color than you deeply breathing absorb
deeply breathe and absorb well I'm here
not there you know fair should be here
it would be nice if everywhere we're
here we would not have to leave or drive
a fly a hurry real fast or decide hurry
we'll fast or decide
[Music]
it's more than perfect I Drive so much
it's like my ass is my feets nice little
black furry running dogs and I'm
standing up in my seat I'm standing up
in my seats to avoid sleep driving
crashing and dying you gotta turn up the
tune
rest area next bride is my salvation
because I'm running on
[Music]
I'm running on few
I'm running on fear
you
[Music]