[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 260 of the girl
from Earhart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right a pure new grower if you're
a professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated Abbot if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic group band who let me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to cat coop and the entire mystic roots
crew
also I'm gonna give you a huge shout out
to all my friends on my Instagram live
feed I just did a nice little Instagram
live feed it took a couple of dads and
set some silly [ __ ] give a shout-out to
some friends thanks for joining me on
Instagram live you guys if you're not
following me on instagram its Irie
underscore genetics on instagram you
could jump in and follow the Instagram
live feeds the other day our good
friends sub cool the weed nur jumped in
there big shout-out to the weed nerd for
jumping in make sure you guys follow the
weed nerd
I was honored something cool is one of
the guys had taught me how to grow not
personally but through his wiener do x'
through his internet ramblings through
all his post through all his blogs
through all of his books there was
photography some cool inspired me
heavily
so for sub cool to drop into my
Instagram my feet and say what's up that
really meant a lot to me so shout outs
all my friends on Instagram live an
extra huge shout out to the man sub cool
to weed nerd all right let's see let me
open up this thing so that I don't say
this wrong I've got an email I was
talking to my friends at the dank seed
Co at the hella dank seed bank and we
have decided oh I've got it right where
did it go it's an email and it's right
over here
I had it up on my screen but I have a
lot going on here's a special
announcement you guys I'm going to turn
down this music and I'm going to do a
very special announcement you guys on
the podcast will hear it second my
friends on Instagram why I've heard it
first but you're gonna get some extra
details here here's my special
announcement I'm announcing the hella
dank green Friday sale that's right on
Black Friday Friday the 24th through
Sunday the 26th all I read genetics
seeds will be $30 a five-pack and if you
buy three packs you get a free pack of
Capleton cross to arise at the hell at
dank seed co google them or go to dank
seed co all the info you need will be
right there
once again I'll repeat that all I read
genetics five packs $30 a five pack by
three five packs
get one free five pack of Capleton
crossed to arise until this batch of
Capleton to arise runs out it doesn't
have a name it may have a fresh new name
by the time you get it but so far Capel
tend to arise doesn't have a name it's
the new freebie over it dank seed Co the
hell it ain't seed bank make sure you
guys check them out
Black Friday that starts the day after
Thanksgiving you don't
to go anywhere you don't have to go wait
in line they don't have to go fight the
snow you don't have to go fight the
people you don't have to go to Walmart
you get it a shop right in the comfort
of your own home in your underwear
taking the dab on the internet while
you're listening to this podcast alright
the hella dink Green Friday sale make
sure you check them out alright I think
that's all the advertising I'm gonna do
let's see what's next yes usually I'll
let you guys know what I'm smoking on
tonight I am smoking on I've got several
packages of fresh new concentrates here
what is this one this is the choco lava
from our friends at the craft this is
the panacea line I was really diggin
lead the chocolates a nice sativa it
gets me uh it's me nice and chattery
obviously and then of course I was
dabbing them from the craft I was
dabbing the star dog og I just finished
the last of that super delicious I wish
I had more so super huge shout out to
our friends at the craft the panacea
line is delicious I really love the star
dog I gotta quit telling you guys what I
like because it's harder to find some
stuff now I go places to get the star
dog I go places to get certain batters
and it's all sold out because I told my
friends about it on the podcast and they
all go there and they buy it before I
can get to it it's all good you guys go
enjoy I just got to find more sources
and got to spread the love a little bit
further send me a tweet or a Facebook
message or an email or something to let
me know where you're shopping and where
you're getting super turkey hash and
what kind of prices you're paying in
Colorado medical or recreational tweet
me it's at g f YH podcast you can of
course you can find me on instagram i re
underscore genetics on facebook go for
the girl from the heart podcast if you
know me personally send me a message
however you want you can email me girl
from your heart at hotmail.com
let me know what are you davon what are
you getting it I want to know what's
available that I'm missing alright let's
move forward a little bit I have got an
email from a listener I'm reaching for
the iPad here I've got it up on the high
pads screen this email takes a little
different approach it's not what we
always think about and talk about when
it comes to growing but it's something
that should always be in the back of
your mind it's something you should
always think about when you're
constructing designing or building a
grow room and of course what I'm talking
about is fire safety so I'm gonna open
and read this email
let me see whose name do I use I'm gonna
have to press pause and see whose name
I'm supposed to use on this we did have
a brief conversation but I'm going to
read the email it goes like this
dear Rasta Jeff how are you
today brother I hope your gardens are
looking good and then he says his full
name and he said I can read it on the
show so I'm gonna go ahead and say it my
name is Alex Robles and I discovered the
podcast about six weeks ago and I really
enjoy listening to you hang out and talk
about cannabis I completely appreciate
that man thanks for listening and uh how
many episodes have you listened to in
six weeks I hope you're catching up
he also says I'm having a great time
catching up with the past episodes and
appreciating the block of older ones
they helped me get through the
mind-numbing parts of the day and so
many tell me so many people tell me that
my long episodes helped them get through
a long shitty day so I'm glad I'm
helping you guys out thank you that
means a lot to me when I started doing
those long episodes I wasn't sure how
that was gonna land on my audience and
it seems like you guys enjoy it so
thanks for the compliments and I'm glad
I'm helping you out the email continues
to say I do fire suppression system like
fire sprinklers and such in California
for a living if I can ever help you in
this realm please let me know I heard
you talk about fire safety and an indoor
grow and I wanted to share with you what
I wrote about a product I used in my
closet and then he sends me a link and
he also says you can find me on
Instagram and he gives his Instagram
handle I'm not sure if he wants me to
give that out or not so I'm not going to
if you want me to bro send me another
message and I'll put it out there I just
don't want to flood your stuff out I
already said your real name you said I
can read it on the show it goes on to
say I want to thank you again for all
the great content and then he calls
himself grow learn teach you guys will
probably be able to find him on
Instagram if you search for grow learn
teach now I'm gonna click the link and
it takes me to an article that our
friend Alex Rowe and I'm gonna read you
this article and this will be very
beneficial for you he does talk about a
product I'm not paid to pitch a product
or anything I just agree with what's
written here and he happens to pitch
this product that is very useful to
almost any grower this may be helpful to
a lot of people in a lot of situations
so I'm going to read this piece that he
wrote it goes like this it's never good
when a fire breaks out in an indoor grow
but it's even more tragic when that grow
room is in our home I want to take this
moment to say something about fire
safety in an indoor home grow we've all
heard the horror stories of bad wiring
Catching Fire or the plant canopy
getting too close to a hot light and
bursting into flames we try not to think
about it too much because aside from
having a clean safe grow area and a fire
extinguisher handy there is very little
we can do when we do have a fire
I work on fire suppression systems for a
living which means I spend eight hours a
day talking about learning about
installing and maintaining fire systems
I know that a commercial grower has
options however for our community of
home growers options are limited because
our realities are different we need
simplicity because by definition were a
hands-on group that will do it ourselves
if we can mobility is a must when some
of us grow in an extra room closet or
cabinet that someone has that sometimes
has to be moved there's also the need
for stealth if we're growing our
medicine in a prohibition state for an
indoor home grow there are basically two
choices from what I've seen out there we
either have to get an overhead fire
sprinkler system or an automatic fire
extinguisher also known as an AF II and
then there's a picture here of an AF II
and it says an AF e this a if he has
been in service since 1993 and is
designated to cover 60 cubic feet this
little device it looks basically like a
really small fire extinguisher and they
took that fire extinguisher handle with
the sprayer off and it's got a little
pressure valve and it looks like a like
a ceiling sprinkler in an office
building like the fire sprinklers in an
office building and it looks like you
would probably hang this thing
horizontally I'm not sure how it be
mounted how it be used in the room but
it would go up high I would assume and
then it would probably rupture when it
hit a certain temperature in there and
then whatever is in here will put out
your fire is what I'm assuming from the
looks of it but it just looks like a
mechana stir like a fire extinguisher
with a different type of head on it
so I'm gonna continue it says growing
with fire sprinklers in the room some
homes some homes come with fire
sprinkler systems which is a great thing
if you have a fire not so good for the
grower in US and here's why the pros
they do an excellent job at controlling
and knocking down a fire that could burn
your house down the cons there's going
to be a lot of water to clean up when
the fire sprinkler goes off and unless
you're using waterproof equipment you
may be looking at a total loss
so if you've got a fire in your grow
room and your fire sprinklers go off
your lights your air conditioning your
dehumidifier and your crop will be
destroyed it goes on to say the water
that rains down will have some form of
bacteria in it because it's been
stagnant for so long yeah that water's
been sitting in those pipes
in funky it hasn't been filtered it
that's gonna be nasty-ass water that may
get you sick it's gonna ruin your plants
if the plants are flowering all that
stagnant water will cause mold that is
very true and who wants to smoke plants
that had bacteria-laden sprinkler water
on them that sounds [ __ ] disgusting
the article goes on to say when the
system goes off bells and alarms will
ring and first responders such as the
fire department and police will usually
show up you don't need that [ __ ] in your
grow especially if you're in an illegal
state and you don't need that anyway
so I'm gonna keep reading the article
excuse me for the throat clearing I'll
blame it on the dabs it goes like this
nothing in this chain of events sounds
like a good time but it could happen
when you're growing with a fire
sprinkler in the room then he says my
AFE lets me sleep better the thing I
found that gives me peace of mind about
this is an automatic fire extinguisher
these beautiful pieces equipment were
originally designed to put out fires in
boat engine rooms
they've been repurposed over the years
to be used in everything from flammable
liquid cabinets to server rooms and
other enclosed areas where water isn't a
good idea the ones I use are called fire
boys and are designed to go off
automatically when the gross space or
grow room gets to a hundred and
sixty-five degrees Fahrenheit or 74
degrees Celsius I have to get the cubic
feet which is the length times the width
times the height of the grow room or
space to make sure I get the right size
unit each one will have enough agent in
them to easily put out a fire in the
size room that it's designed for I also
have to think about ventilation about
the ventilation system when I'm talking
about this type of extinguisher with an
active or passive air exchange a high
temp shut off excuse me a high temp shut
off should be put on the fans these
extinguishers work by flooding the
Froome flooding the room with the agent
when they go off plus it stays active in
the air for a bit to keep things from
reigniting the intake fan could feed
oxygen to the fire which could allow the
fire to stay lit or reignite easier the
exhaust fan could suck out the agent
from the room before it's done its job
so you guys if you do install an
automatic fire extinguisher
it would be a good idea to put your
blowers on a turn off if the heat gets
to a certain now this sounds weird but
if it gets to 135 degrees and your
there's a fire in there and you need to
turn off the blower to quit feeding
oxygen in there you need to turn off the
extraction fan to quit sucking out the
fire extinguisher you should have those
on a heat shut off it's also a good idea
to have your lights on a heat shutoff if
the lights get if the room gets over 99
degrees then it hits 100 degrees the
lights should turn off until it gets
back down to 85 degrees and then come
back on that would be ideal you
shouldn't have something like that in
the grow just to prevent overheating and
to prevent fires so those are some
things you should think about along with
one of these automatic fire
extinguishers you need some heat
detection devices that will turn off and
on the proper equipment all right so I'm
gonna keep going
it says growers know when you have a
fire system it doesn't mean you're not
going to have damage when you have a
fire the system is only there to
mitigate loss if there is a fire you
will have smoke fire or water damage and
there is no escaping that then they show
a picture of a whole bunch of these fire
suppression devices it says current
models have a more environmentally safe
suppression agent than what was
available it says no system is perfect
and there's a good and bad to everything
fire boys are no different but they are
a lot better than any other AFE on the
market and here is why the pros they're
rated for Class A which is trash wood
and paper and Class B which is liquids
and Class C which is electrical
equipment so you can get the one for the
electrical equipment for your grow room
that may be the one you need there's a
lot of electrical [ __ ] in there that's
probably what's gonna go wrong
the next Pro is the suppression agent is
life-sustaining which means if it goes
off and you're in your grow room you
more than likely won't drop dead where
you stand the error will get a little
acidic but you'll be alive so some of
these agents could probably make you
super sick probably [ __ ] up your lungs
possibly kill you sounds like this one's
not gonna be so bad if you're there and
it does go off it goes on to say the
suppressing agent is considered a clean
agent and comes out in a fine mist it
won't leave a residue on any equipment
surfaces so there's no powdery film that
has to be cleaned off like with other
automatic fire extinguishers so it
sounds like they designed this stuff
mostly for like computer rooms and
server rooms and [ __ ] like that
tour if you do have a
and these things go off you could just
go in and basically wipe down everything
instead of having to get water out of a
room that sounds way easier to me it
already sounds like a good idea and
nobody has paid me to read this or say
this I just found this very useful I
like keeping my friends and my growers
safe and my listeners I want everybody
to be safe a lot of you may have
overlooked the importance of fire
control fire extinguishing that's why
we're doing this so I'm gonna keep on
going it says they come in different
sizes to cover different sized rooms
from 25 cubic feet to over a thousand
cubic feet
it also says no bells or alarms will
sound when these go off unless you set
it up to do so which is a great thing
like we talked about earlier if you have
a fire and some alarms go off some bells
and whistles start going off guess who's
coming the police and the fire
department and then maybe if you're in
the wrong place the de fuckin'-a you
don't want to get yourself in trouble
because you had a fire trying to produce
medicine so these may help you out it
also says they will ship to almost
anywhere in the world which is always a
plus here are the cons of using this
product here it says the clean agent has
not been tested on fruits or vegetables
much less cannabis if it goes off in a
room with the flowering plants in it
that bud is a loss in my opinion because
I just don't know if it's safe I would
agree with that if you do have a fire in
there and this little extinguisher goes
off and it releases its agent which is a
secret so I want to call it the secret
agent they haven't told me what's in
there yet but when the secret agent pops
out and gets all over your buds you do
not want to smoke that stuff I have
smoked the [ __ ] are not smoked I've
smelled the [ __ ] that comes out of a
fire extinguisher before there's a fire
somewhere I had to spray the fire
extinguisher that stuff stinks if it
smells anything like that I don't want
it near the buds if it does get on the
buds don't make hash out of them don't
smoke them dispose of them properly be
glad that you didn't burn to death be
glad that you didn't have a big fire
live to grow another crop all right
we're gonna continue it says where was I
Here I am you can't pull a unit out you
can't pull a unit out of one room and
put it in a bigger room and expect it to
work the same it won't have enough agent
to put out a fire in the bigger room you
can however pull one out of a small room
or out of a larger room and put it into
a smaller room no problem it also says
you can only get them through a
distributor you can't find them at a
hardware store so you may have to Google
find them online I'd also says I hope
this information encourages everyone
every one of you to think about fire
safety differently especially if you and
your family live in the house in which
you grow if you want more information
about different fire systems or how to
size and order a fire boy get ahold of
me and as always grow learn teach and I
found this at in my Grod comm is where
the the link took me and he has got a
lot of stuff up here getting started
from seed as a link nutrient Guyot is a
link I'm gonna click on this getting
started from seedling and just see what
it says and what it does Canada's plant
in the vegetative state part 3 oh look
he's gone he's made a lot of stuff you
guys hey ah go check out this guy's
website in micro comm he's done a lot of
work he is put in a lot of articles and
it looks like he's been at it for a long
time because some of these are from 2000
middle the middle of 2016 so you guys go
check out in micro comm hey Alex thank
you for for printing such cool articles
and being such a great cannabis warrior
I am marking your site and my iPad here
so that I can go back and visit more
frequently and see what else you've got
going on hey man thanks for the great
email thanks for helping me keep the
growers and listeners safe a lot of
people may not think about fire safety
you got to be cool about fire safety is
what I think the commercial says you
guys so thanks a lot I do appreciate the
email I do appreciate listener generated
content I ladies and gentleman if you've
got an email you'd like to send to me if
you've got an article you'd like me to
read it's got to be your article you
can't just send me some [ __ ] that
somebody else wrote and expect me to
read it this guy gave me permission to
read his article I do appreciate it
but if you've written some stuff and
you'd like me to review it and possibly
read it on the show send it to me in an
email let's grow from your heart and a
hotmail.com obviously my throat's doing
this thing I don't want to see her and
clearing my throat for 30 seconds I'm
gonna press pause real quick take a DAB
take a drink and then hopefully I'll be
right back thanks for listening you guys
all right podcast world welcome back
thanks for hanging on for a second there
while I fixed my voice before we get
back into this I owe an apology to some
friends of mine up there in the frozen
[ __ ] state of Maine on the last
episode Mike and I were talking about
Maine and Mike kind of said some things
about Maine and I kind of said some
things about Maine and Maine I owe you
an apology
I got called out on Facebook so Big Shot
it's my friends Nick shoutout to Amber
Maine's not that bad you guys are some
cool people up there I'm sure of it
because when we talk trash about him all
six of the cool people up there sent me
a message on Facebook shot it's my
friends in Maine all right let's move
forward a little bit I've been asked a
couple of questions recently about veg x
and what type of veg x I prefer
recommend in what type of veg x I use so
when your plants are in the vegetative
state you've got a lot of options the
main goal is to keep them vegging until
they're big enough healthy enough hearty
enough ah the shape you need them the
size you need them
make sure everything's topped and
trained and set up the way you want it
before you put it into the flowering
state now the way to keep a plant in the
vegetative state is by controlling the
light cannabis is a photo period
sensitive plant which means if you give
it enough light it will stay in a veg
state but when the light starts reducing
and you get a certain amount of
uninterrupted hours of darkness that
plant will go into its bloom stage
cannabis is whole goal in life like a
lot of us is to reproduce all cannabis
wants to do is drop pollen or get
pollinated that's its main goal it wants
to reproduce make seeds so they can grow
the next generation next year so you can
keep it into a vegetative state by
controlling the light if the plant gets
enough light it will not go into a bloom
stage as soon as that plant gets a long
enough uninterrupted dark period it will
start flowering it will go into a bloom
stage so we control the lights we
control the amount of time that the
lights are on and that the lights are
off so some plants are very sensitive
they have what's called a very sensitive
critical period if they get just a few
hours of darkness they will start to
flower some of them you have to go kind
of hard which is why we do the twelve
twelve then almost all plants will flip
at twelve twelve you could probably get
them to flip at fourteen and sixteen but
twelve twelve seems to be the universal
combination to get every plant to flip
eleven thirteen is also common but
twelve twelve is your best bet you'll
get the best harvest you'll see the best
production now I'm really gonna get off
topic here and get off on a side rant
but you'll notice outside when you
flower your plants outside they do start
to flower before you have twelve hours
of darkness outside that's because not
all of the plants need
12:12 that's just what we do indoors
because the light isn't as strong it's
just better it's better for commercial
production also here's something that I
will add when the Sun sets the Sun puts
off a specific spectrum that tells the
plant hey it's time to go to sleep so it
kind of triggers the plant to go to
sleep that's why things like sometimes
light street lights and things don't
disrupt plants outside sometimes they
will this depends on the plant this
always depends on the plant but
sometimes some small lights outdoors
will not disrupt your flowering period
because the Sun was so intense all day
it was like you're awake [ __ ] and it
was just beaming down on that plant and
is it's at there's the sunset I believe
in a globe that we got around earth as
the Sun set the curvature of the earth
creates a certain spectrum and I don't
understand exactly how this happens but
the curvature of the earth and the Sun
setting creates a spectrum of red and
that red spectrum I could go away into
that but I didn't read so I don't want
to be wrong I sometimes I need a little
reading to do a refresher
but the near red and far red and
phytochrome red words all come into play
right here as the Sun sets it tells the
plant hey it's time to go to sleep and
so that plant actually goes to sleep and
when the Sun puts it to sleep like that
it's way harder to disrupt that
nighttime period so outdoors yes
sometimes people say the moon and the
stars won't disrupt my outdoor plants
but that's not exactly how it works
they've been out there getting beat up
by the Sun all day they haven't been
indoors under a thousand watt Gavita
it's a big difference so let me get back
to what I was talking about I really
like to get off on a rant sometimes on
these podcasts don't I sometimes that's
what I think you're listening for
sometimes that's my favorite part that's
when I learned the most let's see so
we've talked about what makes them
flower what makes them flowers you put
them under twelve twelve you guys
outdoors the Sun will tell them it's
time to go to sleep [ __ ] it's time to
flower indoors you got to put them under
the twelve twelve they start going to
sleep veg times you've got a couple of
options here
um the options that you have for veg
time is 24 hours on your plants will
live if you put them on with 24 hours of
light if your lights are not very strong
if you're using t fives to keep some big
mother plants alive 24 hours may be the
way to go
if the plants don't get enough light yes
they may have a long light period but
also if the light is weak
they may decide to flower on you I've
seen people have big mother plants where
the insides get real bushy and leafy and
the inside will start flowering you got
to get in there and cut all that inside
[ __ ] out if you have more light that
won't happen so if you don't have enough
light instead of running an 18 hour veg
period put it on 24 hours that may help
you out you still need to get in there
and take care of the plants but a 24
hour veg time is possible it's not my
favorite
myself and a lot of other growers
believe that everything wants to sleep
my clones are on for 24 hours a day when
I cut my clones in their fresh I keep
them on for 24 hours the clones don't
get any sleeping period once they go
into a veg cup or a veg pot those get a
sleeping period and depending on where I
am and what I'm doing the veg period
changes so let's talk about a couple of
different options there's 20 on and four
off or 19 on and five off which are very
similar this is very common in a mother
room either 19 and 5 or 20 and 4 very
common in a mother room that's long
enough to keep the plants in a consonant
veg stage so that anything that gets
root bound or likes to Otto flower if
it's in doesn't get enough light those
things will not Otto flower on you under
a 19 or 20 hour light cycle but then you
get that 4 hours of sleep I feel like
indoors it takes them like an hour to
fall asleep if you're not giving it the
light cycle from outside if it's not
getting the Sun to tell it to sleep I
think when the lights just go off and
they're blank it's like what and it
takes them a few minutes probably like a
full hour to get to sleep so if you give
them 4 hours and they're gonna get three
full hours of sleep technically and
that's that that helps I think
everything that's alive wants some
sleeping time you'll see them grow a
little bit when they come back on even
if you just give them the four hours or
five hours of darkness you'll see growth
when they come back on that works very
well let's talk about the pros and cons
of the 24 hour time 24-hour lights on
the pros of that lots of growth things
will not auto flower if you've got
something that did flower you can bring
it back to veg with 24 hours of time the
con of 24 hour time it's always on man
you're always running your electricity
always running your gear your plants
don't get to sleep they start to look a
little frazzled the 24 and 19 5 are the
20 on and 4 off
the 19 on five off cycle pros and cons
here the pros to this vigorous growth
they get a little bit of sleeping time
as a con you saved some electricity you
save some cooling time you save time on
your bulbs make stuff all your equipment
will last for hours longer now every day
you get four more hours out of your gear
so that adds up to a few more days the
downside to that I think a little more
sleep time is better you don't get
enough rest time on your plants they're
just not as happy you can see that
they're a little bit stressed from other
plants this is cool but ah I think I
think a little less light time is better
one thing that I do notice the people
that use longer vege times when you go
in to flower your plants do flip a
little more quickly then people that use
a shorter ven chime because the plants
notice they're like wait it just went
from summer to fall I need to flower
they just jump in more quickly and we're
gonna talk more about changing flowering
from veg to flower do you want that dark
period or not we're going to talk about
that in a future episode so we've done
the twenty-four we've done the 19 and
five we're 20/4 periods the pros and
cons of those then here are my two
favorites the eighteen on and six hours
off that is a very good veg phase 18
hours on is plenty of time for those
plants to grow and suck up their
favorite nutrient their favorite feeder
which is like the plants want light more
than anything so that's 18 hours to
absorb light that lets them get a lot of
vigorous growth within six hours it lets
all of your equipment cool down you're
not running so much equipment the
electricity is not being pulled the
plants get to rest your bulbs get to
rest you get some dark time that's
always a good thing the plants get to
sleep they grow there's also sixteen on
and eight hours off that's probably the
last one I would recommend I wouldn't go
less than 16 because indoors
you're probably gonna start flowering if
you go less than 16 hours of light on 18
hours off so the pros and cons of the 18
and 6 you get some off time during that
sleeping time you can see the plants
grow they get more vigorous although you
are gonna produce more humidity in those
night times you're gonna have to find a
way to get the humidity out of there
that may get really humid in those long
night periods so those are vege times
that I would recommend the pros and cons
it's kind of up to you how you want to
do it where you are how much electricity
costs what your schedule is what your
rooms are setup like what your
lifestyles like just how your growth
fits into your current scheduling one
thing I can recommend maybe run your
lights at night if that's possible
because electricity is cheaper at night
it's easier to keep them cool at night
because you're not competing with the
Sun and then when the lights go off
during the day and the Sun comes up you
don't have to try to fight with a grow
light and the Sun keeping that grow room
cool you can run the air conditioning
anyway just to keep the room a little
bit cooler during the day and hopefully
nobody thinks anything's going on
because it's normal to run an air
conditioner right now it's wintertime if
you've got to grow you should probably
be using that grow now because you don't
have to pay for cooling it really helps
out in the winter but I'm off topic a
little bit veg times I told you about a
bunch of veg times and I told you
different applications of them at the
large commercial facility I keep the veg
room on it's on 20 on and 4 off
sometimes we do 20 on and 5 off we're
experimenting when you're running a lot
of lights in a large facility every
couple of hours helps when you have to
replace as many bulbs as we do every
keep everything cool with as much as
cooling as we're using every every hour
on the bulbs and ballasts ELPS is what
I'm saying so we experiment sometimes
it's four hours of darkness sometimes
it's five we're just seeing what works
best for us in my personal grows I do
like to use the 18-6 for mother plants
for my personal mother plants I do use
the 20-hour on and four hour off cycle
and for all of my clones the clones go
24 hours on so that's my personal setup
there one thing I've noticed and I might
have mentioned this I teased on this
just a little bit ago if you have a long
veg time the people that go 24 hours of
edge and they never turn the lights off
when you put the plants in to flower
those plants flower just a little bit
more quickly most of the time it'll take
10 to 14 days to see flowers turning if
you just went from 24 and then you went
to 12 12 you might see that change
happen in seven to 10 days instead of 10
to 14 that's one thing I have noticed I
wouldn't do the 24
in veg or the 20/20 on and for off in
veg unless you were only gonna veg
little plants for a little while if
they're gonna get bigger and start
branching out you want to give them some
night time let those hormones move
around let the plants get some rest let
your equipment get some rest
just think about how long you want a
bedroom if they're gonna be little you
can do 24 on and then when you flip them
they will really blast off alright
podcasts world I hope I taught you a
little bit about veg times I hope I
helped you choose how long you want to
put your lights on if you're trying to
get something to come out a flower and
go back to veg it's got to be on for 24
hours or it's not gonna go back I did a
whole episode about reeve edging plant
so if that's what you're trying to do go
search for that one let's see what else
did I want to mention oh here's
something I wanted to talk about I want
to know if you tip your bud tenders if
you shop at a medical marijuana
dispensary if you shop at a recreational
cannabis dispensary I want to know if
you tip your bud tenders how do you feel
about tipping a bud tender I'm curious
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com send me a tweet at g fyh
podcast find me on Facebook it's the
girl from your heart podcast I want to
know do you tip your bud tenders and
Cooper watts if you're listening I'd
love to get you on a podcast and we can
talk about if you should and should not
and how you should and should not tip a
budtender and maybe we can also talk
about some dispensary etiquette while
you're here Cooper Watts this is an
official invite I know you listen please
come be on the show
all right podcast rolled I'm gonna start
wrapping up this podcast this is where I
tell you about patreon if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
if you feel like you learned something
and you want to throw a few dollars my
way the way you can do so is by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
that's patreon.com slash grow from your
heart all the details you need will be
right there
I would appreciate the help I'm not
begging but a lot of people want to
contribute and I would appreciate it if
you do so also I'd love it if you follow
me on social media you can find me on
Facebook I've said it several times
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Instagram I'm IRA underscore
genetics I've been doing a lot of
Instagram live videos it'd be great if
you join me there I get a lot of podcast
inspiration there I go hang out and
smoke out with my friends before I come
do the show I write down questions that
the people ask and then I will answer
them here on the show
so join me if you've got a question
maybe that's a good way to get it on
there I'd also love it if you follow me
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast also if
you'd like to communicate with me
somehow and you're not into all this
social media stuff if you just want to
be old-school the easiest way the most
reliable way the fastest way to get me
to respond is probably through the email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
that's the best way to reach me if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast or if you've
got a product you'd like me to review
simply send me an email and grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
to hear from you I wanna thank everybody
that interacted with me on this episode
also don't forget you can follow me on
youtube there are about a hundred and
fifteen videos up on YouTube now simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on YouTube I will get caught up
you guys it takes a lot of time to make
those videos I've said it several times
we will get caught up once I get caught
up the videos will get better I'm trying
to do that when I get a free moment
which is not very often I want to thank
everybody for listening to a Monday
episode I'll be back Thursday with a
throwback Thursday episode make sure to
listen somebody told me those episodes
kind of sound like [ __ ] I know why I
know what's happening I will fix it I
apologize for those episodes sounding
muffled and garbled if they weren't
perfect I am going to fix that the
episodes from here out will sound better
big thanks to the person that told me
they didn't sound top-notch I'm gonna
fix that for you I appreciate it ladies
and gentlemen I do take all constructive
criticism I'd like to know what you
think about the podcast send me an email
girl from your heart at hotmail.com love
it or hate it if you got something you
want me to correct if you've got
something you want me to talk about
let's hear it I love the interaction all
right you guys I want to give a huge
shout out to my folks in Maine I know we
bashed you on the last episode a little
bit but I still love you guys shout out
to Nick shoutout to amber and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
music
feeling good d'marie wanna get say your
bone dobby kids
Oh another problem might um domestically
oh my gosh it's the marijuana hon get
the kids on love is the other day you
better find it
I'm a big man Apple my problems behind
me i smoke the marijuana and think about
the we kids
in music music music I smoke the
marijuana
[Music]
going down myself ah we got the phone to
make two donkeys make the rocking milk
cell phones we got a diesel regards to
know for the people we got the idea to
Raisa spoken get wiser to smoking
marijuana the wicked
[Music]
I'm still your bum the wicked
love is the day you gotta find I'm a big
man of whom or problem
you