[Music]
yo what's up podcast world its Ross -
Jeff with high region etics in the
girlfriend heart podcast I wanted to
drop in and remind everybody about the
hella dank green Friday sale at the
hella Danks seed bank that's right all I
read genetics seed packs will be on sale
for $30.00 a five pack plus if you buy
three packs of IRA genetics seeds you'll
receive a free five pack of Capleton
cross to arise so make sure you check
out dank seed store for the hella dank
green Friday sale
[Music]
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 141 of the
girl from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to see the
huge thank you cutouts my friends in the
mystic roof man for letting me use their
music on my podcast big shout out to cat
[Music]
happy Independence Day everybody this
episode will be coming out on the 4th of
July and I hope everybody has a great
holiday or had a great holiday it's
great that this episode came out on the
4th of July because this episode
features Steve de Fino it's a veteran
farmers Alliance and a couple of his
buddies from the CFC big shout out to
Steve and his friends for joining me on
the podcast make sure you check out the
veteran farmers Alliance make sure you
follow all my friends on their social
media we will mention their social media
feeds right at the beginning so I'm
gonna let this music play for a couple
of seconds and when we get back we will
be joined by Steve Dino John and Quinn
[Music]
joining me is my new friend Clinton dude
thanks a lot for fixing my SD card so
that we can record a podcast tonight
yeah no problem thank you do you have
any Instagram or social media that
people can follow while they're
listening to your lovely voice I do have
a Facebook on your Quinten Spitler
that's about it check him out if you
want you guys check him out while you're
listening not if you're driving though
don't do that across from me is local
celebrity kind of an arrow of sorts yeah
he's getting well-known you've been on
so many podcasts you've been in a couple
of publications ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the podcast my friend Steve
Dafina welcome brother that's going on
dude thanks for having me at the what's
this basement have a names is the turf
basement
[Music]
they smell delicious as soon as I walk
down here good job on whoever did that
as John John welcome to the show bro
hey guys follow Steve Daffy no on
Instagram it's Trey Sarah
Turks that's right check out some lovely
cannabis photography on there John how
do my friends find you how do my
listeners find you on social medias I
think it's stocky while they listen all
right
[Music]
truly underscore living underscore
organics he tries to be modest I just
have some bloody pictures on there truly
living or true living organics all right
check about you guys check him out on
the social media follow all my all my
friends here so uh Steve actually
invited me here to do this podcast
deceive you guys probably remember if
you listened to the show he is the
founder president chair dude main
veteran of the veteran farmers Alliance
my listeners that haven't been following
you give us a little description of what
the VFA does give him $100 in cash and
prizes we feed them we give medicated
cookies medicated barbecue ribs chicken
we're eventually gonna move to live
music but we give away genetics soil
nutrients just grow gear everything so
you basically hold big parties at
cannabis friendly venues and invite
veterans that are in need get them out
of their house to do right and in the
way it works is I get companies and
other organizations involved in they
make a donation to where it's it's what
they provide as a product to the
industry right and so they give it away
and basically you know we're gonna
probably have around forty thousand
dollars in genetics to give away
I mean it's serious that's amazing do
you want to list off some of the people
that are helping out with that event yes
take your time dude thank you for doing
what you do for the veterans and also
for being a veteran Steve as a veteran
which is what inspired him to be so
proactive for his fellows I'm sure we've
talked about it on the show but Steve's
got a hole in his back from taking an
AED right
if PFP I could you could hide a baseball
in there took about seven years to
really pull out of it lots of therapy
and then you know just lots of good
cannabis helps as well what's good
friends absolutely good just a good
support system is what was really
important for my recovery I'm proud of
you bro not to sound like a cheesy bro
there we go we got sour seed company
shout out to rob it's our seeds we got
TGA genetics shot at sub cool
we got homegrown natural wonders yeah we
got covert grown Jonathan covert that's
my buddy we got Levi west from pistol
possible these are all my friends
yeah these are good people man we got
Rocky Mountain seed bank there you go we
got David Wain Hughes see here we got
Thunder buds genetics we got pollination
elite genetics boner seeds neuro cow
nice all my friends are donating CJ yeah
let's see here's prison City genetics
there's Trk nurse consulting this terror
oh ho yeah
a suit here I always messed it up as
Phillip Phillip yes Phil hug follow him
on social media you guys yeah he's a
good guy smoking iguana
they're gonna be here we got veteran for
natural rights that's Matt Cail we have
the strong alliance we have under the
clouds there a glass shop here in the
springs cb1 analytics that's Nate we
have iron protection group they're gonna
provide security for the for the whole
venue sear the dab lounge which is
holding the venue to the table Dan's a
good guy see here we got dry sniff
Colorado Glenn he's gonna be doing like
a dry sift presentation he'll probably
give one or two kits away as well we got
tiger stripes heat company we got you
know our company that's something we're
gonna talk a whole bunch about here
pretty soon
oh you know I got Danny dang stir seeds
then we got nectar for the gods which is
sponsoring all the swirling nutrients
you shared some cannabis that you grew
with nectar of the gods
and I'll agree that was godlike it's
pretty good and it was that sunset
sherbet you gave me yes sherbert no I
smoked heart of gold and then something
else of course good job on the heart of
gold even girl the [ __ ] out of that one
for a minute what happens with that but
that sunset I enjoyed that more than the
heart of gold to tell you the truth the
flavor on that was so bold thanks man I
was I described it in my head as if you
take a purple laughing and hold it in
your mouth for a couple of minutes and
let it start to melt that's and think
that's kind of what that would taste
like on thank you I really appreciate it
I just love to grow cannabis it's just
my favorite thing in the world I wish
you could see Steve's face right now cuz
he just lit up like a
[Music]
it's gonna be Friday November 11th on
Veterans Day perfect it couldn't do any
better than that Friday November 11th
Veterans Day at the dadlabs rides
critters Colorado Springs what's the
address there do you remember is 15 32
North Circle I believe good job that's
our non-veterans yes it is $50 to get in
what that does is that goes to the
donation for my 501 to basically get the
application get the bylaws written get
it rolling and going and then and then
yeah then I can actually do a whole lot
more which is gonna be the next three to
five years farmers Alliance event at the
dab lounge make sure you guys come he
said it's $50 don't be scared you heard
of all of those companies that donated
products are the non veterans that show
up and pay the $50 entry fee eligible
for those raffles yes yes you guys i won
two prizes last time I want a jar of
lead and then my second prize was a
grinder so yeah you can't go any better
than that right and you walk you win
something you're happy
I got blazed out of my mind I had a hood
I got a hoodie from our friend Fox yeah
okay great things that's a good time so
you trying to raise money the
contributions will go to raise money for
your new 501k okay three or three see
how it goes it's been crazy I got so
much going on it's like now I got to get
this one like it's a what was looking
about I think anymore from a thousand to
eleven hundred and then I gotta go to
score and
they'll do all the help me with the
bylaws once that's gone and I just
wanted to all be legit for everybody
there's a cat nobody'll make hundreds of
thousands of dollars it'll be like 22
grand top everybody like that's all the
rest of the donations I mean that's once
we're having we have to establish people
to hire on to travel around and and help
put these events on because we want it
instead of doing two year we want to do
one every month so locations to get more
veterans and more cities eventually if
we take in once we start taking in a
large amount and it's like well I need
to start hiring people to start
expanding then their cap is 22 grand not
eight hundred grand okay now keep it
modest for people yeah it's like for the
veteran farmers Alliance or regular
organs and the whole point is if you're
coming to work like even me if I don't
even know if I'm gonna even take the
money but the whole point is it's it's
guys that need something to do its we
take them out we take that donation
instead of putting in our pocket right
the whole nonprofit what we do is we'll
take that we'll take them out on like
fishing trips hunting trips we'll take
him out on backpacking trips trips we'll
take them down to Peru that's more
therapeutic than any kind of guys come
out for a week and just reset hunt fish
camp veteran farmers Alliance camping
trip but it's on our own land so to be
private land you can come out and just
relax just decompress some guys need
that they just need a little quiet space
away from the fireworks I've seen this
episode will come out right before the
fourth of July you guys respect the
veterans on the 4th of July if you know
that somebody that lives next door on
your block is a combat veteran go ask
them if they're cool with fireworks yeah
please don't go somewhere else and watch
the show like don't go freak people out
I've seen a lot of stuff on Facebook
about it please respect the veterans not
agree with war but these are
you got to respect them either way and
believe it sounds exactly like it from
distance last year was the first year I
ever went to the fourth of July in eight
years it was like like man okay I can do
this and I just remind me a lot I was
like all right yeah that sounds like it
but I know it's not real I'm just my
wife okay okay I'm good I'm like I think
I'll be alright and that was kind of
last year about this time is when I
first started taking the steps to
recovery new or new freshly out of your
trauma right it's the word for it but
you know I just got tired of it I got
tired of being in my head all the time I
got tired of isolating I got tired of
being this [ __ ] [ __ ] all the time
and it just got to the point where so
I'm [ __ ] I gotta just do something
about this and my wife was gonna leave
me I was gonna lose my house I can't do
this so I just said [ __ ] I'm not
gonna be trapped in my head anymore and
we found a good therapist or two doing
EMDR and radio.com you guys you can hear
this podcast every Wednesday at 1:00
p.m. I talk radio but he runs my show on
his network so super friendly I need to
go hang out with Jay Jay if you're
listening invite me up I'd love to be on
your show
I'd like to come and do your show and
Lucy show on the same day and one trip
to Denver that'd be awesome
yeah Jay Z get really cool guy hanging
out with events the table this was the
best she's ever dabbed
[Music]
devack's no gran it's beautiful I can't
give you best I've ever smoked I can
remember one of my favorites the very
first in Denver and there's a bunch of
people I just walk in after work and
just drop on the maybe keeping your own
head straight sometimes there's plenty
of work for you
sometimes video games can you play
combat like my wife or kick em like go
away
[Music]
like put you back into the mindset it's
like I play with video games I had to
give them up completely popular I would
show up at work and my friends would be
like did you have to check this problem
the next time I move I got rid of all my
gaming consoles and I try really hard
not to put games in my new computer have
a bunch of likes I used to take all my
time and dedicate and Instagram it was
just it's it's like a one way over there
and really sure we jumped off the deep
end on this one but we got on a pothead
rant know what to expect when they
listen to this show hang out and
medicate and get away we jumped off on
fireworks we got a place for the
veterans to go get away from everything
and medicate properly and hang out with
other veterans and be cool what we're
doing now we have the funds to really
start looking I think that's okay that
makes good sense I admire what you're
trying to do that's awesome all right so
basically City Council limits car
Springs now and all of El Paso County on
a twelve plan count limit no matter what
so even if you have a medical marijuana
card from the doctor
is that up hold a bull in court oh well
if you go to if you go up to like Denver
quarter that's to the first cats cat and
dogs on this show
you lose in El Paso County you lose and
you lose in the Colorado Springs if you
get busting collar Springs you lose in
Colorado Springs you lose in El Paso
County until you gotta go up to Denver
you go through when I heard them start
doing raids I just pretty much cut
everything down I'm like okay you know
it wouldn't be a surprise to smoke maybe
maybe maybe two and a half grams a day
just to not run out so my buddy called
me because he knew I was frustrated
things like man you gotta call this
other guy he's like he will tell you how
to do it and get into the industry where
you can be legit a hundred percent and
you can operate to where you can still
help veterans you can help them in a way
where you couldn't do it before which
was I can recuperate the cost through my
labor right so I can do that and then
also now I can re what's what's the word
I would say I can like so basically I
can resupply the VFA with free cannabis
okay nations from the CVC right so now
we're all in-house this is going okay so
now we're keeping everything in-house
it's all quality controlled we know
exactly who grew it where it's coming
from is the the CVC going to be
regulated by the Colorado meed no okay
so what we're looking for is basically
it's a place where
we basically have a warehouse for your
six plants because a lot of people you
know cannot grow their plants whether
they can and just can't in their living
space or to do so so are the time we are
gonna provide a place for their six
plants and we'll take care of it for
them and it's just like babysitting them
and having them place to grow and then
we will return their product to them and
all they have to do is reimburse us for
you know our time and our costs and
through that we'll be able to help a lot
of people that would normally have to go
to another recreation to get a red card
after that we operate according to a
minute 6464 says is what we're doing and
for that we're we're not scheduled in
amendment 64 what it says specifically
is it lists out you know personal uses
of marijuana you can grow you can store
you can consume all of these things and
in the last section in that part of the
amendment it says that anyone can assist
you with any category so therefore you
can have somebody babysitting your
plants for you because they are allowed
to assist you in growing right and we do
so why not do this and this is a way for
us to be able to provide a service that
normally wouldn't be able to be provided
right and now you know with this service
being the way it's gonna be set up is
now we can take in people like we're
gonna take in five interns starting
beginning of the year for an entire year
we're gonna train five veterans up to
get into the industry to learn how the
process works through the meed by their
licenses to get into the meed get all
that paperwork done so when they're done
after that year we bring in master
growers like you or your boss or other
bosses from different dispensaries and
they get to see stats and paperwork on
these guys how consistent they were what
their testing
what the tests were on their on their
cannabis was and and basically you get
to cherry-pick and you get to figure out
who's gonna be your new grower and you
hire them on the spot
so you're making kind of a master grower
farm league right that's awesome
yeah like these guys I mean a lot of
these guys need a job or something to do
and we can train them as best we can and
get them into these positions to keep
them busy and in that way we're helping
the community even more and they'll get
to grow the plots for the veterans that
are giving you their plant counts right
and you guys are gonna train them right
you guys grow skills well thank you
literally just tether them to us we're
gonna just take them down the line this
is what we do this is why we do it and
it's not oh this is just it's in the
book and this is why no this is why we
do it from personal experience here's
the book for reference you know like
teeming with microbes teeming with
nutrients
those are good books for these guys to
read not the the grow Bible when you got
a one that has like 600 pages I mean if
you're gonna do it like that I mean
that's great but I'd rather read
something that's 200 pages and where you
got to look up [ __ ] and it's like oh wow
that's really amazing like you're
actually learning it's retroactive
instead of comprehensive instead of an
encyclopedia this is why it's green
because it works growing knowledge is
just your experience so we're giving
these guys experience and knowledge for
free and eventually a job hopefully out
of it that's pretty red right so maybe
one day across Colorado
there'll be veterans running these grows
or across the nation that's the whole
point once we go federal or really we're
really just gonna blow up with it
because now we're gonna be the only
training facility in the United States
that can train people and then send them
out anywhere in the United States after
one year the dogs make the buds smell
great
I mean that don't do that they can just
they can just take control of the
industry because they're some of the
most disciplined hard-working I've been
through three people in the girl
facility so far that I have have not
made the cut I think some veterans might
be the next work they need a prize he's
loyal he just he wants he wants to to be
a part of something team that knows how
to build a good commercial size grow to
keep everything that you're trying to do
sustainable I would say between Joe and
I we have it covered his wife we need a
building to come out surveil in the
concrete this whole last year I've been
focusing on Grover design and you know
maximizing yields through that so I
think that after a year focusing on that
we can create create the grow that we
need to be able to provide medicine for
these guys at the cheapest cost possible
it's good to see the owners and founders
and CEOs of agro be the people that are
gonna be in there get in there hands
dirty because too often in regulated
industry there are guys that own big
businesses that just want to make more
money and they buy into the cannabis
industry and then the growers are forced
to just have to face conditions and do
things that would have to compromise
their integrity and a grow often right
because the owner doesn't want to spend
the extra money to do it the way it
should be so it's good to see and I'm
not calling anybody out my my
I read a shopping list when it shows up
[Music]
down a shopping list and take a picture
of it and send it to him and then the
next day when he comes in all that [ __ ]
you need to love that you go to the
store for my brother that helps me out
get those co2 tanks filled they're
sitting in their room waiting for you
but facilities have a lead guy that is
just throwing dollars it's somebody that
we agreed I was employed by one facility
where all of the upper management were
snobs about hating potheads because I
was my lunch break I go and spend half
my paycheck and then I go home and enjoy
it and come back and yeah you shouldn't
be mad at us pause we're making a rich
bro we got that new Hummer
[Music]
you know you know necessities taking
care of and stuff but nobody's gonna get
rich out of this you know like the only
way looks like they really want to be
blinging rich almost any conditions yeah
you're good I got most of that okay
notice reliable and that's really it I
like it grow cannabis for veterans yeah
alright so how long until this will
realistically be going the collective
we're thinking that you can get the guy
to move the damn building right and if
that happens we're thinking we'll have
our facility built September early mid
September mid late September September
whatever plans first October in there
October's drop dead right now we're
waiting on a lawyer visit and buying our
business license for you know our
warehouse facility that we're creating
and after that we wait what was it six
to eight weeks for that license and then
we can start signing people up once we
have the the tax license and all that
we're ready to roll they do already have
a website up at Colorado Veterans Court
com Colorado veteran's collective comm
check them out you guys support that put
a bunch of clicks on their website share
it if you have a veteran friend a family
member if you're a veteran I'll share
that with other veterans go check it out
if you're a veteran you should be
friends with Steve Dafina on Facebook he
likes veterans of all shapes and ages
sounds weird I get a lot of weird
requests on Facebook and you can go to
contact us on our website at the CBC's
website and it will email one of us and
we can get back to you as quick as we
can and would you do contact them let
them know that you heard about him
through the girl from heart podcast
because we would all like to know we
like to know where the resources came
from and where things went and who heard
what that's a good way to trace things
back and then they'll know where the
relationship developed and then they'll
treat you like a VIP I'll take care you
no matter what absolutely was always
super kind of read that you saved the
day by fixing this D card so we're
so so basically to keep our costs low to
keep our costs low I'm gonna pass this
over to John because he's gonna read off
some of the main sponsors that are
helped us for the CBC these are for the
CBC to get you guys started okay from
these guys our first sponsor and the one
that makes this incredibly possible for
us to do and cheap for the veterans is
nectar for the gods steve has been
growing with nectar for the gods for few
years yeah like two years now and he's
gotten to know the owner really well yes
and he's been sponsored for a while by
them so we went to him with this idea
that we had and Steve emailed him or
Facebook to him and asked if he would
continue the sponsorship and he agreed
with it and so we were getting our
nutrients and soil for free which helps
us keep the cost down for the veterans
the reimbursement fees plan to be at a
hundred dollars at first and remember
this is recreational at a hundred
dollars first and every sponsorship we
get we can take that chunk out our goal
is $50 reimbursement because our cost
drops so do the prices because that's
what we're doing I know we're not again
open I hear fireworks oh I've had some
interesting neighbors all right and
let's see what else we got some seed
sponsors we got gonzo seeds
giving us this genetics we need
obviously we've been on talk radio on
Monday they enjoyed our time up there
and we will probably be going back those
guys are really awesome they're going to
have our commercials run on their radio
show cool
we got pollination Steve knows Ryan
really well and there they have some
killer strains and so they're gonna be
sending us some of their genetics to
work with CB one analytics Steve got in
contact with those guys and they Tuesday
and they're gonna be running all of our
all of our testing for us for free as
well so we can know exactly what we're
giving these guys very cool you guys
will have some Irish genetics in that
garden also for school guaranteed I've
got some high yielding stuff that you
guys will appreciate oh yeah we just
those we're able to keep the cost down
as best we can everything else we can
add on there we'll just be cutting off
and making it cheaper for these guys yep
every time we can chop at that price to
bring it down it's just a better vintage
for these guys so if I were a veteran
and I sign my plants over to you and
then I wait probably 60 or 90 days so
that you could pull my plants down and
get a harvest out of them for a hundred
dollars to start what realistically what
ammount of Medicine can I expect from
you on the size of the plants we grow
but I'm thinking three gallons three to
five gallon plants okay okay we'll keep
it on a pretty nice rotation for
everyone everything will be numbered by
patient and everything like that so
we'll be able to keep it constant and of
course you know the better we grow the
more we'll come out of each plant and so
eventually they'll be getting
potentially more that then they can
actually consume and at that point there
they can waive their cost
give their product back to us and that's
where we're gonna be able to start
giving away free product through that's
working really well for you there's no
loose ends where money or anything just
sits around we're always just trying to
give back as good as fast as we can well
it's like city council when they did the
whole 12 point count it really just
broke mo you know there's such a
ridiculous way to do it because nobody
at that meeting oh we've been over this
nobody at that meeting wanted that to go
through no not one person there's four
people that wanted to go through plus
the City Council members and that was
about 150 to 200 that were opposed to
that I watched that on the internet and
you couldn't even feel the vibe of the
room coming from the computer screen as
well yes four hours of testimony it was
13 minutes
that's not injuries part yeah right so
apparently somebody's gathered enough
signatures to possibly add this to the
ballot for this year and it's to limit
the percentage of THC in every single
product whether it's medical or
recreational at 16% 16 percent THC and
anything everything so the font rates
flower I'm flabbergasted how I would
have to get rid of every flower in my
garden
or five
[Music]
does that mean this slab of shatter
could only test it okay
pretty sure you're correct with the
flower I mean if it's from what I heard
last night it was everything and if
that's the point whether it's
recreational or medical it's gonna
destroy dispensaries it's gonna destroy
everyone that's just such a waste I'm
not a quitter but if you told me that I
couldn't grow cannabis over 16 percent
THC anymore I might quit I'd move yeah
yeah I just have to move the operation
somewhere else there's no way to really
I mean terpenes are great but the only
tip I mean in in in th he's great but
there's the combination of both Dave in
high forms that are perfect either one
and it's just gonna be you know
synthesized THC or it's gonna be wow
somebody trying to control the industry
I think I think they make so much money
in the black market like busting people
in the black market that they're trying
to revert it back a little bit so they
can just keep going after and just keep
yelling that each nail into the coffin
just to make it worse to make us
criminals again I'm kind of like
flabbergasted me you gave us this and
now you want to take it away and they
like it's like here take this just
kidding sex one I just made it illegal
in a different twist you can't grow at
home because you are just gonna cause
problems and now you can't buy good weed
at dispensaries so go home and grow your
good weed oh you can't do that yeah
no no yeah dream can pop all your pills
and I just hate to go back to all that
but it's like come on man right how many
people do you see when you're out in
Colorado Springs how many people do you
see that are just too high for their own
good on cannabis that are causing a
problem none a lot of meth heads that's
I wasn't trying to go there but how many
people do you see on a bicycle as soon
as the Sun Goes Down with a [ __ ]
headlamp on they're in every trash
everywhere you got a Dodge them on your
car right now
the ones that are the problem are less
than 1% but they're going after them and
then punishing the rest we want to be
able to support our community able to
show people that this isn't the black
market this is we just need to get rid
of just all these regulations just
trying to tie us down I mean yeah
there's there is too many plants in the
house I mean if it's too powerful for
the grid it'll burn the grid up I get
that you'll get a house fire
so whatever on that but there's people
that need 40 50 60 plants and that's
perfectly acceptable in a home there's
no reason you can't I mean especially
with kids that like parents that there's
one Li that has 19 different strings for
her child and it works and she can't she
loses those strains it's like she's
screwed and that's the kid that kid
needs that and I mean it's it's pretty
powerful to be able to provide something
like that for a child in your own home
and then somebody tries to say no it's
like [ __ ] you
you can't do that go to the store right
yeah yeah it doesn't work the same as
missing [ __ ] this mass-produced it's
like
[Music]
yeah for the prices I don't exactly know
what a gram cost to produce at home I've
done math and it's come out somewhere
between 50 cents and two bucks a gram I
think to produce cannabis at home just
depends what kind of nutrients and what
your electrical happens to be where you
are yeah I've heard as low as 30 cents a
gram what dispensary can you find
anything for 30 cents I'm probably
cheaper and then in my house 10 or 12
dollars a gram at a dispensary minimum
plus taxes plus getting there right plus
we'll look at recreational tax too and
who knows what was sprayed on it who
knows what kind of nutrients it was so
all of the recreational products are
currently tested July 1st was supposed
to be the day I was gonna do another
show about this bull just talk about it
now
July 1st was supposed to be the date
when all of the medical products were
tested but they've pushed it back to
later in the year it's gonna be closer
to September or October before they're
able to test every cuz nobody can test
the products it's like why are we
focusing on that where are we going
after less than 1% and punishing
everybody else we could be going about
the regulation just setting the standard
and making a good presentation for the
rest of the you know if we had eight or
twelve good solid standardized testing
facilities that were bringing in an
excise tax every time that product got
tested do you think they would replace
the revenues that they're making off of
busting petty weed crimes we just need
some sort of operation people will see
it they will start to accept it it just
takes time
you know there's like my wife three and
a half four years ago she was like no no
we hid in my house I think I'm like wow
yeah and now it's she's like well this
you know it works she believes him she
hates the smell she's actually allergic
to it
she tries really hard to like it
does a good job she does she's a good
supporter she says well it's just saved
me yeah probably saved our money go
shopping again and get food on the table
again once I started growing for myself
it was like wow I wasn't spending twenty
seven hundred three thousand dollars a
month dispensary how many prescriptions
were you able to eliminate using
cannabis 24 different prescriptions with
cannabis and if you were gonna if you're
having a shitty week and you're not
feeling your bass you need extra
medicine how much are you gonna smoke in
a whole week now this week maybe an
ounce
okay so somewhere between 150 and 200
bucks worth of quality cannabis but if
you grew it yourself
we're looking at 28 grams maybe 28 bucks
worth maybe $10 $10 okay everything's
pretty much sponsored for me so the
nutrients are paid for and water and
lights okay I mean your effort well yeah
but I don't really know what I include
okay but that's it so I mean growing of
it is therapeutic for you also details
here and there shows you every single
plan that's definitely part of the
healing process and that's another
reason why we want to bring these guys
in cuz it will work for other people I
know I feel calm in my garden me too I
could be happy I have to drive 55 miles
from my house to the office every day
and the last 10 miles of that drive is
like bumper-to-bumper madness probably
park my car run up to the guy in for me
and punch him in the face six times and
get back in my car before traffic
get in the girl is just like I love to
get it done in like 72 in the last two
and a half weeks okay I would do things
a little bit differently but with the
perpetual you have to keep it ideal
across the boards I've got there are
plants three every three weeks or new
plants going in so I've got stuff at
week 1 week 3 and week six week 9 6 &amp; 3
so I have to have 12 12 and 74 degrees
smoke smoke yeah I've been playing with
with light manipulation lately like I
did it 35 days I flipped into 1113 I did
the last one at 15 days and then I did
want to just straight 11 13 and I'm
gonna see how if anything any flavor
changes or anything's enhanced or
anything what I noticed from the 11 13
was when I was doing Fino hunts I would
see much more Fino typical expression
with a dark period I would see much more
variation from different phenotypes so
for a breeder that was really handy what
I did notice was it kind of diminished
on my harvest weight seem to finish a
little quicker to finish quicker
absolutely I've actually gotten a
bumping away from switching over to huge
for me I love that product is it a media
proved can we use it in the meed grows I
don't see why you couldn't okay a lot of
products are banned a lot of [ __ ] is
banned right he's a microbial inoculant
compared to the other things that I use
I can't talk about one of the products
that I use secretary-- thing but we also
use the veg bloom plus life it's all
compared to that and see if it's got the
same stuff you don't pee on your plants
do you know what do you say that
[Music]
refill his water
almost an hour talking to folks you're
already going for a while before to
spend 30 minutes get my sd card fixed
because for some reason it didn't want
to work when I showed up to record which
is almost embarrassing but we pulled it
off electronics man that just happens
all right I feel like since Steve left
we're all stuck at a low because he's
got a notebook over there and he was the
nectar number 8 soil is the one we like
we add a little extra perlite and it's a
cocoa base and their whole line is just
or all the organic things I would use in
my soil but in bottles and pH so that it
doesn't go bad and that stuff works
great half the time me and Steve can't
even tell the difference between our
weed sweet they have like different
overtones and stuff but I'm very
impressed with the nectar further with
God's line and organics guy I don't like
any lines really I understand that I
have a friend named Shawn who's been on
the podcast a lot of times who doesn't
use any bottles nothing he's using comes
from a bottle that's where I am his
product is definitely you can tell that
it's a different product it's cleaner it
burns better though ashes are as white
as this parchment paper fish bone meal
he's got the dog on the podcast oh yeah
it's been trimmed cycle and we just give
the dogs the leaves eat the leaves off
and leave the stem and they'll nibble
around the stem and they're just like
they'll clean our floors afterwards
they're hilarious cool dogs I got the
brother of this dog to pony yeah so the
black one is the mom and then this this
gold one over here came out of her and
Steve got one of the fall black ones and
breeding dogs was an experience I like
breeding plants way more okay well my
mind went somewhere really weird with
that because it's much easier to get rid
of ugly plants
[Music]
[Laughter]
this podcast ironically I did not plan
this is gonna come out on the 4th of
July
[Music]
boat drunk be careful if you're at a
state park celebrating today be careful
with your cannabis and if you're
listening after the holidays off your
head burn a lot of joints yes but be
careful wherever you are you're doing it
burn some joints cannabis may be legal
in Colorado but there's no legal place
to consume it other than your house
that's correct
in the springs we have great open parks
where people love to go and smoke down
but for some reason there's a cop up
there they'll get in trouble and I don't
understand it they're not bothering
anyone give a plan go to jail I I am a
father and I don't want to be walking
through the park with my daughter
enjoying ice cream
and have to explain to her what you guys
are doing when you're else that's not
that's not your guys's conversation to
introduce to my daughter's life their
mind is when the time is right kind of
thanks for being there so now we can
have that talk as my opinion plenty time
past time to have a weed talk we've
talked about weed a lot of times she
doesn't care she was about four it was
like okay look she knows not to touch it
not to get close to it she stays
completely away from it you know she
just know she's been educated she has no
desire for it she knows it's medicine
it's nice oh it's fun it's not like that
but I just I just don't want anybody to
have to have the talk of drugs it's just
gonna go down I just don't want to do
that to our scene we should respect
those parks a little better and I'm the
hypocrites I took a DAB at the park the
other day away from here and my friend
was nice enough to bring me lunch and I
thought she deserves some dabs for
bringing me lunch I was like well let's
go to that Park that's why we need our
dab lounges around in the spring said no
to those two places to ever go in
Springs was to go hang out at the canyon
regulated like alcohol we should be able
to consume in a public place like a bar
that's the most valid argument out of
all of it you try to keep the officials
the legislation is the one that made it
regulated there was their idea regulated
like alcohol there's an alcohol drinking
establishment on every two blocks if
you're a bubble there's one every 30
feet somebody drinking places and
nowhere illegal to consume your house in
your house that's if you have permission
from your landlord if you rent and how
am I supposed to medicate safely on a
lunch break if I don't live here right
[Music]
thing that you want to before we start
wrapping up keep your eyes and ears open
for the car veterans collective will be
starting in about 2-3 months and follow
us go visit our website send us an email
and once that started great work because
you don't have to wait until all the new
all of their new stuff happens if you're
a veteran you need support you need help
in any way cannabis-related or not
reach out to Steve Tofino reach out to
the veteran farmers Alliance on Facebook
you can email me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I will put you in touch with
Steve if you need something and you're a
veteran we will help you out if you need
something and you're not a veteran we
will help you out we're compassionate
smiles on people's faces keep everybody
in a good mood if you need some
immediate help if you need some someone
to talk to whatever you're a veteran
reach out to us we'll take care of you
poor friends if you're listening to this
where your friend already so happy 4th
of July from veteran farmers Alliance
there you go
I think that's a great way to wrap this
up Quintin thanks for joining me was
this your first podcast it was indeed
thanks for joining me you did great
thank you did wonderfully you saved the
[ __ ] show see if we're gonna have you
back lots of times by awesome you've got
something oh let's pitch the event one
more time reminding the people win and
where oh it's November 11th the damn
lounge at 1532 north circle in Colorado
Springs Colorado that's a long ways away
you guys I will have Steve remind us a
couple of times before that comes up
five months away and we all consume a
lot of cannabis we're gathering a lot of
donations even even John here's gonna be
donating a half pound of his own
personal medical girl gonna bring
half-pound roll some joints for these
guys give it away I'm not gonna take any
back up end so I like that yeah we come
home with nothing we give it all the way
for a little while I'm working on it you
guys I'm not too rushed breeder I'm not
gonna hurry up and push it out gonna
breed the way I do it when they're ready
[Music]
we're gonna wrap up the show I will be
back in just a couple of seconds and put
a tail on this thing guys thanks again
for joining me thank you thank you guys
once again for joining me I want to
thank Steve and John and Quentin for
coming out and doing a podcast with me
or for letting me join them for a
podcast make sure you support the
veteran farmers alliance also support
the Colorado veterans collective you
guys I kept messing up that acronym in
the podcast they do apologize for that
thanks for listening you guys if you
have a product you'd like me to review
or if you'd like to sponsor the podcast
send me an email it's grow for me hard
at hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you make sure you follow me on all of
the social media check me out on Twitter
gee fyh podcast on Facebook it's the
girl from your heart podcast and on
Instagram make sure you check out Irie
underscore genetics I think that's all
I've got for you this week you guys make
sure you go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your art
podcast buy in the review section it was
a 5 star rating
type in a little comment let me know you
think about the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode thank
you guys for listening big shout outs
manager spins and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
his cheese cheese cheese cheese it's
raining tacos
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 142 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if your cannabis activists
or even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross the Jeff on
to thank you once again for joining me
as always I need to give a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to catch the entire mystic
[Music]
welcome to the show everybody this
episode is the seventh episode this is
gonna come out on Sunday 7 10 everybody
[Music]
smoking some of those fresh OG Kush
chirps from our friends at Evo labs with
me today celebrating 7 10 is white Mike
how you doing bro I am DTF oh the [ __ ]
[Music]
with tweet me tell me what your dabbing
at GFY H podcast on Twitter let's talk
about some of these fresh herbs we have
stepped up our game here in Colorado our
friends at Evo labs so we they said we
like I'm involved in the [ __ ] I smoke my
role in the consumer
only I do a little product research for
these guys but uh so I'll be your space
monkey I don't care
we take they take some shatter they take
cash I think they're taking co2 oil I'm
90% sure that this is made with co2 oil
a co2 extraction and there's a lot of
people right now in the industry playing
with refining co2 oil in one way or
another and this seems to be my favorite
way this is a fractal distillate home
run I've got all of the clear the
they're calling it distillate all of the
distillate is done with a fractal
distillation process and they're
separating basically everything the
cannabinoids and terpenoids and the
lipids are all pulled apart and this
container right here is a container of
nothing but the THC this is ninety
percent ninety point nine four percent
THC and one point one percent
CBD this is raw distill it from Evo Evo
labs and open the jar here and try to
contain describe what's in this
container the best I can
it looks like really runny honey or
super clear olive oil maybe yeah but
it's got more of the consistency of like
honey or maybe color might be right
though yeah yeah it's like honey almost
in there but this doesn't have much
flavor it's it is just super stupid
potent I put a little bit of this on the
dabber and this is where it gets fun I
take that little bit that's on the
dabber and I dunk that into the ghost
train haze raw turps this is mostly
terpenoids
with a little bit of cannabinoids like
one or two percent amaizing if I call it
the adult version of fun dips this is
definitely well we've oh I'm a Deadhead
and we've got our own little version of
fun dips but this is the weed of a fun
dendrite this is it's a beautiful thing
this is a you take that beautiful ninety
percent THC distillate and then you dunk
it dunk it and the glorious part is in
my other hand
I've got some og cush Turks so I can
either dunk it in my og cush burps or I
can dunk it over here my ghost train
haze turps or i could dunk it in one and
then i could dunk it in the other balls
and we're changing up the flavors it the
OG Kush chirps if you put it on this
distillate and dammit it tastes like you
if apples tasted like OG Kush and you
bit into an OG Kush Apple it was just oh
gee cush all in my mouth and you could
almost chew the flavor that's how much
oh gee cush flavor these Terps put in
your face it's the flavor contents
really really nice this way and then the
high from the distillate comboed with I
really like the high that I get from the
ghost train haze it's uh this is sativa
dominant strain I talk about this every
day the other stuff that's in it that's
the THC is definitely a big part of the
high but everything else that that's in
it really plays with that THC in some
fun ways I almost never go for the most
potent on the shelf and if you think
about the rest of your life you
typically don't do that either you've
got to get that other component to it in
this way you can get both you can get
insanely potent and really really
flavorful I've been kind of being a
snobby [ __ ] I take some of this blue
shirt 120 micron fresh frozen solvent
less hash and I roll out a little patty
and then i dunk some some some durbin
poison shatter onto it then I rub the
little cactus cooler live resin on top
of that then I put a little bit of the
Terps on it and then I put some of that
90% of THC distillate on top of there
and I took a big-ass dab of that
remember in high school when you used to
go park somewhere and see how high you
could get I don't think we got that high
what is when I took that big-ass dab my
arm hair was wiggling around like it was
visibly waving like something similar
which is much much cheaper product with
with just your typical waxes shatter
I'll take a piece of shatter and kind of
pancake it out real far throw a little
wax in the middle row little taquito and
dab that but mine are much smaller and
much less fancy than the ones you've
been throwing down I like to go big or
go home and I take dad's home
go little and go often go big and go
often one of the best parts about taking
dabs is that you can grab the dabber and
Mike can take his dosage Mike's a
cigarette smoker so when you get Mike
worked up a little bit you can hear him
gurgle he doesn't even need dabs to
start making funky like the bong
occasionally so you give them I give
Mike if you handed me the dabs that I
gave Mike I would laugh at you I'd say
can you maybe triple quadruple that up
bread Mike takes just little pin sides
dad's probably the dad's you take Mike
takes that size of the dab us and he
will cough and turn purple and get
sweaty with the email carp cap set up a
beast it's not nearly as bad as cuz I
don't have that curve cap to cut the cap
adds quite a bit people get yourself a
carp cap this is a 710 episode let's
educate folks on the email right quick
the the electronic continuously heated
nail is a beautiful beautiful thing it's
also a little dangerous depending on
where you dab I I had one in the car for
several days well the space I dab often
is also shared by three large dogs that
are really furry and psychotic and so
like if I was gonna add an email to that
makes like something would get set on
fire that I care about yeah dog would
get burned on the bald spot somewhere
there's kind of a reason I don't have
one yet but it's it's on the short list
of things to treat myself to I had to
take mine out of the car I was getting
careless I was getting too high in the
car which I was like I'm pretty pretty
medicated here I gotta chill out on this
and then also I had to set the rig in
the cupholder and I forgot it was there
and I felt warmth a couple times I don't
know that I was gonna burn myself but I
was like whoo that is warm over there
and had to think about it again I'm kind
of close to that so I took the email out
of the car that doesn't happen anymore
be careful you guys I can't tell you
what to do but if there's somebody in
the backseat that needs to have their
medical cannabis available while you're
driving they can consume their medical
cannabis do your thing you're an adult
but so the email there's a box on my
table it's uh six inches long four
inches tall it's smaller than the
original
Nintendo but a little taller yeah okay
yeah yeah and it's got a display on it a
little LED display with the number it's
got a power switch on it one of the
coolest [ __ ] features it's got a USB
port Mike his last six months my phone's
been charging on that USB slot there's a
really beautiful shot it's my friend
Gideon this was actually a gift from
giddy up at emo Tech's a big shout out
and shout out to Margolese for the
replacement coils I appreciate that bro
ah but so there's this box with an LED
screen on the front with numbers
displayed on it then coming out of that
box is another cord it's a silver cord
it's a silver braided cord and it goes
to if you're using any sort of nail
setup instead of the little nail that
sits inside the rig and the dome or a
titanium domeless we've got a much
larger titanium domeless that has this
coil leading to it and then it's tightly
wrapped around the nail so that it can
evenly heat that surface yeah to
whatever temperature we feel like and
that's where I want to jump in and
everybody talks about what temperature
is your email sent to I do not believe
that that number right there where it
says 717 I don't think that's a
temperature I don't think it correlates
to the actual temperature on my nail
surface because I think this box would
cost much more money for it to actually
have a thermostat inside it that's doing
that one of our friends that is a guy
that works on my website actually told
me that's actually a frequency random
frequency that it kicks out plus it
gives you something to work it's like
your speaker's I've posted pictures
before us getting ready to record stuff
somebody always chimed in and there's
like dude your emails like 300 degrees
too hot it's like that's not a
temperature is always like the first
three i'm sure if you bought seven emo
tech units they'd all have seen this
helpful that have the temp
to display and I like that yeah the one
task rock made the original and we're
gonna talk about task rock you guys this
is the [ __ ] 710 episode you best
believe in etosha by deloitte ask rock
the original email that task rock of
highly-educated the innovator the
originator that original email did I
think that temperature did correlate to
the one on the box although I'm not
certain but I'm pretty sure it did shot
it to Big D with the original he's got
the museum version he's got the first
unit task made it's on Daniels shelf
much loved and respected a big deep miss
you bro hope to see you soon
it's get you on the podcast the good old
days I really don't think that that
number correlates I think that's
definitely not a temperature when you
get in your car or whatever where do you
like it where you really like to jam out
when your favorite song comes on was
born to be wild comes on do you want to
drive on the freeway way too fast
whatever
23:39 medium high right before it starts
crackling I think my dad's kind of hot I
like the email a little hotter than most
people when Spence would come over shut
up dispenser from the garden mmediately
tournedos you just you wouldn't even ask
be like yo nail two hot dog and just
read you didn't say dog he would call me
the n-word you're nailed to high and
work and reach over and just turn my
[ __ ] now like it was his and I wouldn't
argue cuz that Spencer and he made the
hatch for about two dad so I'm just
gonna let him do his thing but he'd
always turned it the [ __ ] down he'd be
like my stofflet gift it always says he
turned that [ __ ] down
I take pretty low temps at home every
now and then I understood it or like I
sneeze between heating the nail with the
torch and going to dab and then find
it's a little too cold my puddle I like
a big chunky grateful the remaining
members is grateful that Phil Lesh
doesn't or anymore so they call
themselves dead and Coe I saw dead and
co-ed in Boulder shot it's my friend
that took me to that show but I saw both
the dead in Boulder and [ __ ] there
were some kids taking dad's in the
back of this SUV they had the tailgate
up and they had the daybreak sitting up
on a little thing so that all they had
to do is put it to their face and the
dude heats it with the torch and I'm
just walking toward this car walking
through rows walking through the parking
lot and I see him and I was like it's
hot trying to turn that nail in the
[ __ ] water right now I didn't see any
business I was like oh he's gonna put
the dome on or whatever and let it cool
nah bro I did through the Dolan and
[ __ ] put that dabber to that nail
while it was glowing bright orange and I
just cringed I was like oh my god like
it was not my place to say anything but
my heart just tingled I was like oh god
that for poor [ __ ] damn it not only are
you ruining yourself for no reason
you're also losing so much flavor in the
Terps I the downside is if you
understood it you end up just wasting
your hash on the nail it taught us
instead of vaporize in our world
so that's let me let me talk about that
when I taught when I hid the email when
I'm taking a big fat app a lot of times
you guys I come home from work and I
want a dad like a half gram maybe a gram
of hash in one [ __ ] dab I'm not
kidding there are more people in this
room don't wait raise our hands a
[ __ ] testify Rasta Jeff will pull a
grandma dad Graham dad no problem we got
hands up testify it's a lot like a big
fat dad I will do that on the email a
lot of times I'm smoking these Terps in
the distillate I bust out this one right
here my elevator with a little bang yeah
it's got they say it's quartz I bet you
money that's [ __ ] glass I've got a
little glass of banger on there that's
my flavour saber that I think it tastes
a little bit better I think quartz
versus Thai I think sometimes gotta say
that the quartz tastes a little bit
better in my opinion I I have that on my
short list of things I want to treat
myself with is a nice quartz banger I do
this one here this is a highly-educated
titanium base with the quartz that likes
to travel with a little rig like that
that's the way to go because this banger
the way that I travel with it that would
get destroyed quickly well where were my
Derrick's it
most of the time that would be safe like
I can't risk that you know right now but
I could risk the pup you could take the
bucket but not the email hold it's safer
it's the cord that's the problem on
email like just in practice I know my my
household well enough to me
to know that that rate would get yanked
off that cord is dangerous at this table
right that cord is knocked over and
broken this exact rig once before just
sitting there had just wobbled and spun
itself over cuz the you guys the cord on
this he knows it's was coiled in a box
for a hundred years it looks like and
shipped from [ __ ] China and vacuum
packed and so it's gonna be coy Li
shaped for the rest of his life and
sometimes you try to straighten it out
and it makes you think it went straight
but then it just starts coil and slowly
itself up tip your rig over so turn your
email off when you leave the house
that's a reminder to myself also have no
idea how many times I've come home and
been like oh lo tip is better what I'm
doing a small dab is what I wanted to
kind of take that email versus the
quartz the titanium versus course the
nice thing about the course is you can
bring that temp down even further just
let it cool get it get a glowy ha and
let it go do is don't be that don't do
be that guy that's adjacent margulies I
got so many friends it'll heat the nail
until it's glowing orange and bust on a
[ __ ] timer and they have timed
exactly like from what it glows right
here bro you hit go and wait this many
seconds perfect [ __ ] die bro cuz it's
too cool for me I like a little warm if
I'm trying to dad these Terps all
oftentimes go for the courts and go low
temp low temp we say you gotta taste it
to waste it
hit it low temp carb cap it just get all
that flavor in there take a little tiny
dab and then grab a q-tip and heat the
nail just a little bit and clean it out
with the q-tip and now you got a fresh
banger again they call that the q-tip
tech I don't play that way I heat the
[ __ ] out of it until it's clean and then
I throw another dad in it that's that's
how I roll with the banger I'm not on
the q-tip Tech in the low temp tech all
that I think take a fat dad and get it
on right my buddy at a mill would say
red means go
in there now I can it's it's too much on
my throat yeah low tip is better for you
low tip is better uh fine so guys when
you're trying to set the temperature to
your email everyone's like what
temperature do I said it go ahead Mike
you got something to jump in that's the
right set up is really key to getting
the most out of your hash you can take a
really nice low temp dab on an email and
with the carp cap you don't waste
anything there's even if you go really
low it's still gonna continuously heat
that surface and vaporize everything off
you've got a carb cap even if it takes a
second to get it done you're not gonna
lose anything you can actually enjoy all
of that and it just it's one of those
things where it takes the time and
investing in the right tools to really
get the best bang out of your product
and that's part of the reason I end up
so baked ears because I've only got like
half the pieces at home and so when I
load template I end up losing a good bit
off the top of my nails or making small
dabs anyway and you gotta clean it up I
noticed it the first step every time I
come over here I coughed way harder than
I have in a week or two and then I think
is because I use a smaller rig than most
folks yeah I really like I prefer a
smaller rig and I prefer an email on a
small rig right now I'm hitting the
Hitman sidecar the e-series sidecar
small to the point and it heats to the
point where he's got to keep an eye on
the water level because it will cook
itself Drive yeah yeah that has happened
before
my mad Rob is like [ __ ] 4 inches tall
I love these little rings I like this
myself rod during a podcast taking a dry
dab this elevate Klein it's taller but
it still got very very minimal amount of
air space and that's it I don't want a
lot of space from the time that I put my
dab on the surface of this dad nail for
it to go down here down this tube into
the water and into my face I want as
little resistance as possible I just
want to get that dab into my brain just
give it to me
and
feel like all the percolators and all
the extra bubbles and [ __ ] that's just
stealing your dad's still in your Terps
stealing your flavor I don't want all
that extra bubbling I want enough water
just to cool it down from hitting that
nail and then let me get it actually
took dabs today through this little rig
without enough water in it and I got
ultra high it made my throat tingle a
little bit but holy [ __ ] I was red-eyed
the first time I used a really good
portable hash pen they never last for
very long but the first time I used one
they gave you like that first dozen hits
well circulation tastes like hot plastic
knows the different companies still
tasted like hot plastic because the
mouthpiece was plastic but [ __ ] dude
that burn lasted all week throat burn
for a week remember like when you stay
at a bong and fill it get it full and
you keep sucking and that chamber would
fill and you keep sucking and all your
friends pull it pull it and you look
like nope I'm gonna get high you pull it
and then all that smoke goes in your
head that's the point of a big pipe or a
big bong or a big rig build that [ __ ]
up and then carpet and get smoke if you
notice add a brig there's no carb you
just want that [ __ ] smoke when you
throw the card cap on to trap the heat
and in the nail and put a little vacuum
in there you got a little tiny hole in
the carb cap you get less air flow it
through that heat stays in there every
bit air that comes through moves that
oil around on the top of the nail then
it goes into your brain and then you get
stupid high I don't feel the need to
suck like a liter of oxygen through my
bong before I start getting I'm not a
song and I know a lot of people that are
I sell an amazing nail that is it's a
beautiful six in one that's designed for
rigs or bongs it'll fit anything on the
market it's a copy of the
highly-educated infinity nail I'm sure
it is it's an awful beautiful invention
completely as I'm talking about
and every time I see it and I've got
extra money in my pocket and I'm like
that's [ __ ] so much but then I
remember that I don't like dab bongs
it's just way too much volume and it I
you can see it on the inside of the
glass you like that sash
it's supposed to be my brain yeah it's
you cough and choke anyway you don't
need to spend that extra energy on your
lungs pulling a liter of air up through
your it's funny I love a bond for flower
that's my primary smoking device clean
my bong yesterday loved it
um picked up flower today and yesterday
because that's mainly what I've been
smoking at home um but for a nice nap
you gotta go with a small array yeah I
prefer when you started talking about
flower maybe you want to segue into
something else that I wrote down I
prefer indica flowers if I was gonna go
shopping like right here on the table
I've got some blue shirt that I grew at
the green or healthy wellness garden I
smell so yummy and then here in this
container I got some Jeff Shoji that I
grew these are both heavy indica
dominant strains thank you this so far
is my proudest grow in this garden but
wait until you see the next couple runs
I'm already impressed but I prefer these
indica dominant flowers to sit you down
chill you out cushy piney dank flavored
flowers I'm gonna roll a joint with that
and I'm gonna smoke it and it's just
gonna taste earthy and funky and coffee
like but then when it comes to my dad's
if you notice all my dab selection
everything over here is like candy
flavors and should I like the cactus
cooler and over here this one doesn't
even have a label anymore whatever that
was we got some of the blue shirt of
course the solvent list we got super
lemon haze over here this one is cold
treat cush because obviously like those
cush Terps
I've been going super heavy citrus
lately for a while the only exceptions
the durbin which is all pine I was
building up to the lemon G oh there's
nothing like lemon Jie Terps the flavor
of lemon G live resin in my face like if
I could all if I can only dabble and you
would be my water no lis but if I had to
pick three strains that I had had to dab
for the rest of my life lemon G would be
in that mix it may have to replace it
with lemon Geoffrey though I'm not sure
I'd have to set him side by side diktat
I've been going sweet for a while I've
usually go it's been a few Lee for a
while and I just went all sweet the last
six ones you like the feel yep this that
heavy diesel flavor I've loved since
nearly 2000 sighs dad for my
is that in your dad's or your flowers
both okay
I'm you know me I love the Sour Diesel
yeah
sour decent live residents so taste you
home right now I can treat myself with I
don't enjoy Sour Diesel concentrates at
all remember what time I ended up with
some Sour Diesel concentrates on
accident I'm pretty sure I don't care
for that flavor also good I saved I used
it as treats for like my I did [ __ ]
around the house that I didn't want to
do it all really good strawberry
strawberry banana tangi the SBT brother
everybody seems to be going cuckoo over
the strawberry banana tangi stuff from
Krakow that's at rocket for makin killer
killer seeds
it's funny how being a breeder and
somebody that works in a large scale
cultivation facility seeing the
difference in buds that are grown in
plants that are grown for flower
production and plants that are grown
specifically for oil production we've
got a cut but we gave it to somebody in
another state and they grew it and once
they grew it out and saw it they're like
[ __ ] this plant and they cut down all of
the remaining plants of it and they sent
the flowers to an extraction lab and
that extraction lab was like what the
[ __ ] did you send us I don't like some
cuts that we got from our friends in
Colorado that would be me like what the
[ __ ] is this [ __ ] and the extraction lab
ran it and they called the guy I like
bro you gotta come over here in the dude
went over there he took a DAB that's the
best [ __ ] hash I've ever smoked and
like this is the best hash anyone in
this [ __ ] building has ever smoked do
you have any more all of the [ __ ]
plants that he had luckily I still have
it so it's still around it's still here
we live in the future here forget it so
often here for the rest of the country
and for for sure the rest of the world
oh when it comes to legal cannabis
products with cannabis products period
we have stuff that I mean if you guys
went legal yesterday you wouldn't see
yes right this legend takes that kind of
time this train will not finish for
anything and it's ugly but it makes the
best oil bro so things are gonna change
you're gonna start seeing different
different types of plants growing for
different things we're growing specific
[ __ ] if they grow right now they will
only be made into oil these nuts transit
I will never let anybody see that flower
because they're ugly a [ __ ] but the oil
that comes out of it is tremendous
through a while now the hash has been
stalled out it just wax and shatter and
butter and butters just basically wax
you you're kind of stumbled over if I'm
not mistaken hey maybe I'm wrong for
butter lovers sorry but that was it and
then live resident came along and people
really started thinking about where can
we go max with this yo and I love that
people started playing with co2 oil
because there's a huge demand for that
but then you're left with this goo in a
syringe that's impossible
right so I used to hate co2 oil I was
like dying hate that goopy [ __ ] but it
didn't taste right now it cleaned it up
and it's now that they've cleaned it up
the taste is pretty good yeah um and
when it's further refined like this or
separated completely and then you
reconstitute it back on with your desk
like do-it-yourself style it's a lot of
fun it is a lot of fun tails for
yourself I like I've been just taking
this chatter and dunking it straight
into the Terps all night um it's the
long expensive process you guys don't
even want to know but you could buy a
house yeah yeah just for the equipment
but this isn't the only variety I've
seen there's a local outfit that's been
bringing samples by in their first two
samples were epic fails like
unmarketable unsellable not unsmoked
bull way better than [ __ ] you're gonna
get in Florida the name of the company
have a family member in the name of the
company okay but it was just not at all
good a good concentrate ready to go like
nothing about it was was
but attempts three and four were really
really nice final products that are
probably gonna be really popular nice
but I'm seeing a lot of that there's
products that we get people who ask him
by name this stuff and like I don't have
people asking for the Leafs by Snoop I
do have people asking for new styles a
hash that come out every couple of weeks
nice yeah when we send material out to
Tirpitz does all these extractions for
us from the green excuse me
tur packs does all the extractions from
the green and healthy walnuts garden and
when we send out material we send them a
lot of fresh frozen material we send
them a lot of dry material the fresh
frozen we can request it's obviously
gonna be live resin that's why it's
fresh frozen in dab in your coffee
you just hit material we chopped out a
plant we cut it into small buds we throw
those buds into freezer bags those
freezer bags go directly into the
freezer they get frozen immediately then
we run to the store and get bags of ice
and put those bags of ice into a giant
cooler put that frozen material into
that cooler drive that to a location
where it is then turned into live resin
at that point we can have it turned into
live SAP live sugar we can almost get a
live shatter from some of the strains
the Sour Diesel won't live shatter once
you build a relationship with the
extraction company you're working with
we have two specific extractors that we
talk to a lot they work with chirp X and
we can tell them what we want and they
like that strains not gonna do that or
that straight is gonna do that and so we
know that we can get triangle killer
sugar and rudeboys SAP like on
consistent levels the Rudeboy Live resin
sugar is one of my favorite [ __ ]
things to dab ever it is so turbid ellic
that the high is right where I want it
like some things get you on the top of
the head something used in the back of
the brain some you feel on the shoulders
this rude boy hits me right in the eyes
and in the forehead and it makes me
still it makes math skills go away it
just makes me Goofy's like I like pot
they just [ __ ] I want cookies after I
smoke that [ __ ] yeah
yeah all right so it is the 17 episode
you guys we've been talking about 7/10
for a whole long time we should talk
about the origin of 710 Mike you have
any idea where the number 17 lawless
culture part of this community upside
down that's because a lot of the people
who started this movement were of the
age where they had beepers and that's
about as far as I've bothered to follow
it alright so 710 is the 420 my friend
had a mill coined the phrase 710 is the
new 420 back in the day it was all about
420 let's get together at 420 and smoke
some weed now at 7:10 let's get together
710 take some dabs if you turn 710
upside down it does say oil ah to the
best of my knowledge task rock is the
person that created the phrase 710 I
think task rock and a couple other guys
or either in a chat or on a conference
call and they were talking about stuff
we need they were like we need something
a little more bougie than 420 let's
upgrade it let's do it with the hash
hash kids were separating from flour
kids kids you know I mean right the
hustler kids so that's that's where 7/10
came from 7-10 was coined as far as I
know to the best of my knowledge and
I've done a little bit of research but
task rock and a couple other cats with
the guys that coined the phrase 7/10 so
they created 710 shot it's a task rock
cast rock of course is he's a rapper
TAS Brock has a couple of albums out one
of my favorite songs is probably first
place I like do it again
of course boil that oil he also does
hits from the nail music to listen to
some task and take some dads or get
dabbed out and drive around and listen
to some task we're not like I didn't say
that hypothetically I would like to get
dabbed out driver as a passenger and
listen to tasks like an ass Brock is
also the founder proprietor this the
dude for highly-educated titanium that's
task rock a lot of the times if you go
to a cannabis cup even in California
Colorado those are probably the ones he
goes to if you go to those Cannabis Cup
events and you go to the highly educated
booth to purchase
highly-educated products you were
probably going to pay your money to task
rock directly he will be the dude there
that helps ya the task is integral in
the 7:10 community integral in the 7:10
movement he's been a big part of it
since the beginning he's a huge
supporter a shot at the task has made up
the number 7/10 not the number but the
phrase 7:10 and that mic stands kinda it
might need a little bit I just might get
droopy we have a quick equipment it
might be done I just have to hold it
just give it a minute give it a Gatorade
[Music]
7-2 420 Shantanu Hannah mill and Big D
is the person that gave me my very first
dabs I want to give a shout out to Big D
at the time he was with Broadway
wellness he moved on to be top shelf
extracts Big D moved on to be the
founder of proprietor of the secret cup
not the secret session the secret cup
the one with the dragon in the logo the
first hash competition I think I ever
attended
[Music]
I think task
I think Big D I think Adam Hill the guys
from health stone glass and of course
I'm gonna give a little bit of credit to
hitman glass dougie because he does make
the rigs that a lot of us are purchasing
and smoking hash through so the lot of
those guys are pioneers of the industry
old school folks in Colorado and the
hash movement Spence did a lot I want to
give a huge shout out to Spence in the
Whedon crew kind bill that whole crew
they did a lot in the hash but honestly
we all owe a huge high-five - Derrick
Cummings [ __ ] Derrick that dude did so
much for hash that's what it's an inside
joke but hash tag [ __ ] Derrick joke with
all his friends but Derrick did a lot
for learning about hash Derrick did a
lot of research and learned a whole lot
of [ __ ] then of course there's Tony V
there's a whole bunch of guys doing
stuff for hash in Terps but shadows all
the people that helped get 7-10 popular
originated that [ __ ]
tasks rock we're gonna play task rock at
the end of the shows the the original
people as many people involved in
keeping it as what it is today
um it's been fun to watch it grow
if it goes so rapidly would now that
it's legal that we can do whatever we
want with this the equipment the
products have just every couple months I
gotta go buy all-new [ __ ] just to have
what I need to have to be on top of
things it's like any other tech right
now every six months it evolves two to
three times faster and more effective
than it was before
the Terps will be part of the legal
marijuana industry which is fun to watch
we got a huge variety products about a
year and a half ago they're all getting
really really really good now um it's
just so much fun to see you guys gotta
legalize it where you live
remember when I was like the only one
that had little jars of Terps on the
table there's a lot of people out there
now they're available a lot of shops
eating them up it's really it's a whole
new thing I really love it a lot of
people probably the [ __ ] turps the
compounds that mainly provide the flavor
and aroma to your cannabis and or
cannabis concentrates they are they're
part of the flavor the Paley it's and
the esters have a lot to do with the
flavor the flavonoids have a lot to do
with the flavor obviously but the
terpenoids are mainly what play the part
of the flavor that work on your tongue
that's mostly the part that you get they
also contribute to your high I think
that the OG Kush what makes me a little
more mellow it gives me a body thing it
kind of makes my body go wall and the
ghost train haze makes my head go like I
just dabbed a [ __ ] bottle rocket well
essentially that's what separates indica
from sativa is what you've refined into
that tiny little jar it's everything
around the THC there's there's some
other stuff that goes into that but yeah
it's it if you had to describe somebody
to somebody you had to show them
strongly this is the difference between
indica and sativa that would definitely
be a good way to do it
just take that those two just like the
Friday's a heavy sativa was a V Annika
oh you're way too high watch try this
one just put him to bed with the OG Kush
Oh their problem was I'm Way too I
flavor but all right all this talk about
dads has got me wanna dad so I've got
some of this mob boss shatter and I've
ducked it into some ghost train Hayes
turps you can see the Terps on the tip
of the dab it just looks like a little
wet spot on there I'm gonna take a dad
hey Mike I tell all of our listeners how
they can find you on social media and
make sure you include your facebook
group you can catch me at 12:04 sensible
cannabis laws on facebook or add nema
5-15 on twitter and that dad was massive
he's gonna turn colors right now you can
turn colors without choking I see now
he's pasty white now he's going to read
[Music]
it's amazing it's just like heaven I've
always described Hayes strains and the
ghost train Hayes is really uh it's
definitely stands out for what I'm
talking about there's like a velvet
thing that happens on your tongue just
feels like you know when you smell while
ax or lavender if there's that specific
thing there's it almost has a similar
coating like that that happens but it's
more enjoyable to me because I [ __ ]
hate lilacs I like the smell that should
makes my nose nuts yeah there's probably
worship that hotel rooms and that
lavender bro no I know but it's the
lavender that I've like choked on and
can feel in my mouth for like the next
hour I think it's it definitely has a
coating right I don't know maybe we're
just equally high all right shout out to
710 shot at the task there's something
else I want to talk about on this
episode that is not really dabbe related
not really 710 related but it needs to
be mentioned
amendment 139
man bump bump bomb there was a group I
don't know exactly who put this petition
out there was a group that was
petitioning to limit all cannabis
products to 16 percent THC that's right
the buds that we grow at the agreement
healthy wellness this should test
anywhere from 20 to 30 percent THC
nothing is lower than 22 I wouldn't
guess the average THC content in
Colorado's 18 really know there's
actually a pretty solid demand for stuff
that's between like 12 and 16 percent
people that retired after 35 hours doing
[ __ ] they were drug tested for they
really don't want our our moonshine
potency weed they freak out when they
try to roll it join us and smoke it like
they did back but they like the whole
like passing back and forth with their
wife for a while I have a friend who
rents yes so they like stuff that they
can smoke on it burn and was writing
yeah there is a call for that but the
average is is 18 and so the estimates
are that this should have shut down
eighty percent of the industry as we
know right now I wouldn't want it I
would move to a place where I could grow
high quality cannabis well know
immediately all conscience rates gone
most of the edibles gone most of the
vapor is gone like what's the point of a
vapor cart it's 16 percent that would
feel the black market so well yep and
that's the design is the people that
were behind it wanted it to kill the
industry they know that a public vote to
an amendment 64 statewide would die
laughably and so this was their more
reasonable attempt to give voters to go
along with gutting the industry so there
were three parts to this they were gonna
add childproof packaging which we
already do they wanted us to add a
health warning that said this root
causes like a reparable brain damage or
some [ __ ]
we already do health warnings that are
reasonable we're willing to add more
reasonable health warnings but we're not
really glad some random [ __ ] did you
just thought up um and then it was gonna
limit potency to 16% the group behind
this claims they have 80% of the public
support on this but what public where
that they won't tell you didn't ask any
dad kids
I think it's 80% of the people at the
last anti-pot meeting yeah
but 80% of the people in Parker that's
just from they they really really want
hate marijuana and they wanted to shut
us down this way they claim they have a
huge amount of support which is nonsense
they they withdrew their effort today
they essentially said they could stop
trying and the reason they stopped
trying is kind of funny
um they claimed that the group of
marijuana industry supporters and
businesses that formed to oppose this
effort called up all of the petitions
signature-gathering companies in
Colorado that are good at what they do
and can actually get a statewide ballot
effort on the signatures collective
because it's like a hundred thousand or
98 thousand signatures it's a lot there
are companies in Colorado they can
definitely get that done for you
apparently they all got a phone call
from the marijuana people like we're
gonna hire you for this here's what you
got to do nothing oh go ahead and Bill
us and just hung up the phone and they
raised enough money to apparently make
that offer to the two biggest companies
or three biggest companies in Colorado
and on the off chance the anti-pop
people tried to hire all three they were
prepared to pay all three to do nothing
um and so the anti-pop people were like
well if we have [ __ ] do this
ourselves let's go ahead and not do it
nice which makes me laugh especially
when they're like well we have at 80%
support of the public oh my god then
it's so easy you just they kind of
played old-school drug dealer tactics
though I like that you just
but up on Facebook in you say hey
community that supports this so much we
need all of you to grab a signature and
take it to work the next day and say hey
sign this the 80% of put this is just
such nonsense they didn't have 80% no
and then they claimed that the marijuana
industry raised tens and millions of
millions of dollars to do this and the
digits public all you have to do is know
where to Google and you can check how
much they're raised it's like for us is
that if you hand in a petition to most
people and you're like hey would you
like to limit the THC in cannabis to 16%
I mean sure people are just willing to
sign about by law you have to print the
actual language that you're asking
people to sign for across the top of the
sheet they sign it can't be a separate
page or nothing like it's there's a lot
of rules we've discussed this before on
the show a lot of the people that
Walmart are in their pajamas you're when
you're out really collecting this stuff
and trying to get people to give a [ __ ]
no one reads it you live in the county
18 sign here son here that's pretty much
what you get all right so that dropped
it did not the group behind it is has
pledged to reform as a broader coalition
of people uniting to [ __ ] over the
marijuana industry sounds like a whole
bunch of [ __ ] bunch of bailiffs that
the lawyer type for them the funny part
is is a big part of their press release
today they're like will this former high
school principal who was who was behind
this said this and this this local
parent who's behind the other person
behind this said this and I'm sitting
there reading a press release from a
major anti marijuana personality in
Oregon and the press release talks about
major funding from a national anti
marijuana group
and if you keep reading the article it
talks about the actual people behind the
initiative who are these local lovable
characters like a teacher and a parent
their major politicians from around the
country who make a living doing stuff
like this but they're able to portray it
is like oh there's there's just these
little folks being picked on by baking
industry marijuana so do you threatened
a billion-dollar industry and they
raised 300 grand to knock you out of the
fight like come on now so you just gave
me a perfect segue before we start
wrapping up the show give me an update
on what is going on with the effort to
eliminate and/or eradicate recreational
cannabis from Pueblo County
ok so locally our petition effort has
been significantly more successful than
the one statewide I there have all their
signatures turned in it looks like
they've got more than enough valid
signatures to make the ballot there's
two questions in front of the courts
right now the first question is how many
signatures they should have collected
they collected 5% of the voter
signatures from that last election down
here which was like 5,000 signatures
they collected 9,000 almost and so
they're covered there if it's 5% but
recently a bill was passed at the state
level requiring this specific question
if it's going to be put on a ballot
anywhere to have 15% of passed voter
signatures which we jac that number to
around 14 or 15,000 which means they
don't have near enough signatures
gathered and they need to get back out
there and gather signatures that
decision should come any day now well
it's Friday when we're recording this
it'll be Sunday when it comes out so
it'll probably be within 4 5 days of
this coming out when we get that
decision hopefully maybe as many as 15
but if your roster said this will be
Monday because he's from the future base
um but hopefully within seven or ten
days we get we get that first decision
about how what percentage of the vote
they should have gathered odds are
strong that the judge is gonna rule that
5% is fine
recently we had a local politician make
a primary ballot and the it ended up in
front of the same judge and the judge's
ruling was yes he failed to follow the
law here and here yes he broke that rule
there but elections are about choices
and why not give you guys him as one of
those choices and a lot of people were
like wait what really but kinda I guess
like the judge gets to make the rules
that's why they wear the outfit it's why
they have the job so let him make them
and that was the decision they made so
we're kind of expecting the same thing
here there's another court issue that
involves some serious campaign finance
stuff that could really keep them off
the ballot Colorado and pretty much
every state in the Union has very
serious laws that govern their elections
when you would like to put something on
an official election ballot there are
rules you must follow the anti marijuana
people down here are terrible at
following rules it's a very fun
character trait for them to have if
you're me so as soon as they said they
were running a public ballot I was
hoping for like with complicated there's
a lot of important in ins and outs and
if you can't handle a licensing hearing
at the county level running a countywide
ballot issue is probably gonna trip you
up and it looks like it has one of the
things is you can't raise money in a jar
at a fundraiser that's not a thing in
politics if this donations over $20 I
gotta get your name I got your serial
number um and that's just how elections
go the money is tracked like that unless
you're super rich and by which case you
invite you can donate hundreds of
millions of dollars to a company to run
evil attack ads and [ __ ] that's fine but
if you're a little guy trying to give
twenty four dollars you got to give me
your name as your serial number
you can't just throw a jar up on the
piano and at the end of the night have
three hundred or a thousand bucks in
there and call it good enough so they
did that twice and then there's major
polling that they've bragged about and
most people don't understand what what
kind of money's involved when you're you
when you poll people in a county like
Pueblo we're not a big County there's
only a hundred fifty thousand people
down here a poll like that still costs
ten fifteen twenty twenty-five thousand
dollars the good ones cost twenty five
thirty five forty thousand dollars the
ones that'll really give you the
information you want are expensive they
did one of these they paid for one of
these we know all about it
and for some reason they're lying about
it that's gonna play out really
interesting Liancourt do we have access
to the truth on those surveys we we
don't know what the results they got
back but we know they bragged about them
enough to the local hospitals for the
local hospitals to put literature
together that involved or that
referenced this the polling done we know
who did the poll we know who paid for
the poll we know who probably got handed
the check they paid for the poll we know
who probably cashed it ah it's
disturbing that they're lying about it
all I had to do is put it on the
campaign finance report and nobody gives
you [ __ ] but they didn't and then they
keep claiming to the press that they
didn't and eventually the judges
couldn't want to know why and that's an
issue that could keep him off the ballot
- same thing with the money in the jars
that's a big enough screw-up to keep you
off the ballot um if you want to make
law you gotta follow law it's really
that simple they hire a lawyer they did
it's their main volunteer he's donated
like ten or twelve thousand dollars
worth of lawyer hours to their effort
like six hours I have no idea what he
charges but that's not that campaign
finance reports okay um I've spent it a
disturbing amount of time going through
those reports um it's fun to work on
campaigns
I'm sure the look on your face when you
talk about is great it's it's fun it's I
mean it's very could very well could be
the death of webelo
like yeah yeah really can't handle the
loss this would be to our community we
were on the edge for a while parts of
town are still very very bad crime is a
huge problem infrastructure spending is
a huge problem if we lose 60% of our
construction industry 1300 marijuana
jobs all of the expansion that industry
is supposed to go through over the next
several years all of that real estate
floods back on the market like that's a
death blow all those people that moved
here because somebody like myself had a
job and was like I need a helper and I
got somebody that I know in another
state that I trust brought them out here
those people and myself would be [ __ ]
you'd be [ __ ] well there's a huge note
where people were five people that move
here within the last year yeah how many
people are employed by the spot like
3035 yeah that's one dispensary how many
of them are there in Pueblo West hundred
licenses it's 1,300 people
it's literally if this vote passes 13
other people are out of work it's a full
1% of our population down here you add
that immediately to the unemployment
rolls and then you compound that with
all of it's not like I got fired for
stealing its thirteen hundred people got
put out of a work as an industry closed
we no one gets to apply for the job I
just lost all of us are now applying for
whatever jobs we're currently available
in our industry shut down what
percentage of those people go home and
buy a bunch of [ __ ] lights with their
first unemployment check and build a
black market girl and start flipping a
black market weed well that's I mean I
figure half of what we do about twenty
million in annual sales down here I
figure half of that immediately goes
back into the black market and the other
half goes either up the highway to
Colorado Springs or down the highway to
Trinidad the tourist money goes to
Trinidad and mana to the medical money
goes to Colorado Springs everybody
doesn't feel like that's effort worth
putting in for a bag of weed just goes
back to black market yeah just put some
seeds in the dirt in the basement some
whites on that [ __ ] we lose out on five
million attacks
next year like that's paying for all
kinds of cool [ __ ] that wasn't getting
paid for before because we didn't have
the money the city starting to look
decent it's clean it's getting cleaned
up the potholes are going away
it's nothing little by little just
getting more man I noticed that the last
Street I drive on on my way to your
place is really just got repay ya in
Jackson's I've known about Pueblo yep
that whole Boulevard has been marked pot
for potholes it's working it really does
work it's just little by little it takes
a minute people are like why has it why
are our schools perfect we've had legal
weed for two years why aren't all our
streets perfect to spend two years it
just makes a minute do you have any info
on the scholarship that was awarded to
the child to use the potty doubled it
boom like if I was king of the world the
scholarship would be bigger and
spendable in more places but it's still
really awesome dude we're sending 25
kids to college that probably wouldn't
been able to go without that two grand
explain a little bit how that happened
to people that have up at all these
county commissioners we passed the
voters passed the local excise tax so
all of the production when you grow
marijuana and then sell it to a retail
store it gets taxed at that point and
that money goes into kind of a slush
fund for dream projects we couldn't pay
for it before the flowers a green and
healthy wellness I have to they have to
be packaged and then transferred to the
store yep and that's where the tax
happens yep okay if it was in Pueblo
County that's what the tax would happen
okay Aram when Colorado Springs passes
an excise tax on medical event it'll
happen there okay but we already did
that down here for wreck and so that's
gonna be this is the first year that tax
has been in effect so money's just
starting to trickle in but we expect
three and a half million dollars from
that excise tax this year and that's the
bulk of the marijuana taxes that Pueblo
County is gonna make next year we get
3.5 from the excise tax ish it's an
estimate so far we'll see what how it
actually plans out and then we're
definitely gonna get 1.7 1.8 and
in fees and sales tax yeah if the
industry exists if the we'll know that's
that's through the end of this year so
even if the election goes against this
in November we still get to operate
until next November it was sort of your
licenses can expire as it comes comes up
for expiration until November 2017 so
the shop that gets their license in like
November the first yeah this year is in
is in the best shape to operate as long
as possible regardless of the election
outcome hopefully that made sense yeah
yeah uh it's just a deathblow to us do
this we're doing so much with it's not a
lot compared to our whole county budget
but the problem with our County budget
is that it passed its breaking point a
couple million dollars ago and we just
have to look at middle school kids
walking in the middle of the street with
the buses in the car traffic can go
sorry
no money for sidewalks or crossing
guards or crossing guards yeah like all
kinds of stuff there's we took a
specialist out of a couple of schools
and I read that the newspaper and I was
like asbestos in schools it's [ __ ]
2016 oh it's hurting my face ow
no that was way down in San Juan County
because that's how we're spending that
the state also collects an excise tax in
the first 40 million from that fund goes
to school construction through our
state's best program and the best
program literally when you apply for you
explain how your school districts broke
how they've never had money since the
40s and how you badly need to do stuff
that should have been done thirty years
ago but you've never found a way to pay
for and so they're doing stuff like I'm
taking the lad out of the pipes taking
the asbestos out of the gym pads in the
playground
yeah like or building a playground
period um paving the road to it all
kinds of crazy stuff that we really
should have done decades ago
just never had the money in we were
never gonna have it in the now we can
fund it with weed money because it's
just enough more than what we need to do
everything else that wasn't getting
funded
Lupe's background of the scholarships so
sorry the scholarships they gave each
kid that wanted up to 400 kids a
thousand bucks 400 kids got a thousand
bucks well that was the offer only 25
ended up applying okay part of the
reason for that is you have to be a
Pueblo high school graduate and we had
way more than 25 of those fix and
thinking that but you had to go to
college in Pueblo County so yeah if I
was king the world it'd be at least
anywhere in Colorado right cuz nebraska
need my [ __ ] keep the money in the
cal
yeah they just wanted to keep it in the
county they wanted to promote the local
university and there's a lot of cool
things happening down here at our local
university so when i keep it all the
good music program a good program but i
don't know about governor like the
program so much he he used state
marijuana taxes to double it to 2 grand
and i mean honestly that's books for a
whole year
that's meals for for most of a whole
year for happier as you well know i was
a college student so some of these
numbers not real unrealistic that might
just be a decade old sorry but uh i mean
two thousand dollars down here in pueblo
that's fully the difference between i'm
able to go and i'm not able to go yeah
and honestly if two thousand dollars is
gonna really make or break that
difference like college in New York or
wherever else I'd be happy to send you
with that two grand probably wasn't a
make or break anyway right like it
requires a lot more to live out of state
than it does in your hometown yeah you
stay with the fam oh for sure like that
takes a huge amount of a huge huge
amount yeah but it's a fantastic program
and the anti popular all over it they
like this is just propaganda it's real
sure that more kids get to go to college
it's a propaganda when that kid goes to
college how was that propaganda like
some real [ __ ] one of the things people
want refuse to accept is that marijuana
was always here in a way that's so much
larger than anyone really wants to admit
and it's 60 billion coast-to-coast
6 0 billion I mean that's a huge amount
of money I don't think anybody can
fathom that much cash it's I mean yeah
in 20 hour bills it's a couple of high
schools probably but it's an insane
amount it's all just under the surface
it's your neighbor's house it's the park
your kids play at it's the school your
kids go to it's even the [ __ ] prisons
like prohibition doesn't work at all
it's right under our noses it's always
has been it always will be
it's just mostly invisible the only
people who are able to be visible with
it are the people with nothing to lose
and no one's willing to admit that in
Colorado anymore everything it's new
especially the anti pop people and all
we did was shift where people buy it and
we're able to do so many cool things
with that money we can make Terps
because now we got science be afraid to
go if you get caught buying the
equipment it takes to make these Terps
at the store they turn you in for making
a [ __ ] meth lab back in the day and I
can be like no we're with this
dispensary and we need all this
equipment to make hash and now you can
do that we can more effectively treat
patients everyone forgets about the
patients we're all about the turkey out
now I used to spend the first 20 minutes
with a new big fat bag of weed looking
for mole looking for mildew looking for
washers my rigs all kinds of nasty funks
yeah sit there breaking up bud and half
the bug crawl out of the noggin up your
arm like it was [ __ ] we used to put up
with and the fact that it's all gone now
I'm like there did this the benefit
stream just it's endless it's so far
past the money but for a place like
Pueblo the money's vital does south us
in town even smaller the sheriff was in
the paper like it wasn't sure what to
think at first now I love it
to the downtown area yeah yeah they
built a Riverwalk down there because of
cannabis money yep there Trinidad's not
gonna die now yeah we had steel here and
steel isn't as big as it used to be
people want to go lightweight now so
it's titanium and we don't have a
titanium mill we have a steel mill and
so people were leaving and people don't
want to work at a steel mill forever now
it's kind of the technology era people
are getting the [ __ ] out of here that
was going bad I've lived here for a long
time Mike and I have been here we were
here before all the cannabis [ __ ]
happened and I have seen this town it
was kind of a little little cow town
when I moved here it was flourishing
like it's actually going somewhere now
I'm kind of proud we're finally crawling
out of the funk we were in for like 40
years
oh the flood [ __ ] us up I mean
honestly it was when the steel mill
started to slow down a whole huge
generation of people didn't have an easy
way to feed their families down here it
wasn't easy to find work anymore um you
really had to work at it when I moved
here you had to know somebody that was
hiring yeah period that's how this town
is this is one of those towns where you
could fill out a thousand applications
and unless you know somebody here you're
not gonna get a job most of the job and
housing listings never make it online
here it's you drive up and down the
streets you want to live on and look for
someone putting out a for rent sign and
walk up and talk to that person before
it's it's out there too long
it's the same thing with jobs you heard
a friend of yours got fired wandering
where ever they used to work and talk to
the manager stat um cuz otherwise there
ain't no job for you in the city um and
that's slowly changing now we have
hiring a terse staffing agencies now
that that help people get a foothold in
the marijuana industry we have an
industry down here that's gonna need a
hundred more trimmers next year shadow
to lioness um the real downside is that
we're not publicizing in all 50 states
what it takes to work in this industry
but people think that they can show up
late and take a [ __ ] be twenty minutes
late and hang out I talk to people every
day that are shocked to learn it's like
a real business yeah they think you
could just hang out smoke joints all day
[ __ ] off and they thought their high
school weed dealer had a store now where
he just kind of like hung out and played
Xbox in this totally data stable and
then you gave him money and it was weird
and then they'd leave they walk in and
they see what looks basically like an
Apple Store or a purse or shoe store in
the mall you just gave me a chance to
tease something that we're gonna talk
about on a future episode I want to wait
until you and Lindsay are here we're
gonna talk about the weirdest [ __ ] that
people have ever done in a dispensary I
wasn't asking to do that episode to buy
someone at work who listened to the
dispensary etiquette episode oh we're
gonna talk about that when lens is
available Linds just got back from a
little vacation and she took the night
off she was invited but she needed a
nappy poo
so she's cuddle up with Scooby scoob's
good boy shout to that air conditioner
over there but uh we're gonna get Linds
on we're gonna talk about some weird
[ __ ] that's happened in dispensaries
I've got a pretty good story myself two
dispensaries are awesome this it's a
really magical place where Bananarama
[Music]
we ran the place before you like you
could get really my leg hurts I need
weed card and they'd say how much money
you got and you tell them they'd write
you that many plants like here you go
have a great [ __ ] day they didn't
even care back then like weed card for
sale well that was in the very first
days like even the doctors were at the
fringe of society because the DEA was
still threatening that if a doctor wrote
a recommendation for marijuana in
Colorado that they could lose their DEA
license to write prescriptions for
anything any other drug and so the
doctors that were like the first five
doctors in Colorado to sign paperwork
period were the kind of doctors were
like if you were there because you fell
on some and it went through like your
forearm or your leg you start talking to
him and after 15 or some minutes or so
you'd be like you know what
don't doc I'm just gonna the next doc up
the road sorry
I don't care that I've been tailed for
something that's not gonna kill me
immediately yeah but that changed six
months later when they stopped counting
doctors remember that weird-ass doc that
used to come to holy tail yeah with the
ponytail no that was the husband the
husband had a ponytail in a cane the
doctor was the woman who wouldn't look
you in the eye
oh no I'm talking with the crazy guy in
the crazy wife used to come together
yeah okay yeah well I was working in a
dispensary lady that owned that
dispensary used to bake edibles and she
would show up with trays of edibles and
she liked Mike and Jeff you have to drag
some of those days this carrot cake this
[ __ ] banana bread the nine products I
make here's your nine samples and then
you restock the shelves with the rest at
five minutes later should go which one
did you eat it's 11:00 a.m. on us at
work and she would go which one are you
gonna eat right now in front of me yeah
she didn't give a [ __ ] she'd stare at
you and then look at the pile of options
you had really curious as to what you
might fake totally oblivious that you
took this a little more seriously than
she did or you're not interested in
finding out how strong she made him this
week at 11:00 a.m. and 15 minutes after
you ate the first one she'd ask you what
the next yeah and did there some days
where I don't know how we made it for
clothes there were sometimes the numbers
were a little bit off so I'm pretty sure
there were some eat gram quarters going
out the door sometimes like there was a
window that we had to stay with in
between and we just kind of kept it from
going too far outside of that little box
add it to Karen and her homemade edibles
[Music]
Josh and I fell down the stairs laughing
like ladies
I remember walk three flights of stairs
and ridiculous heat because it got
really hot in that building and I did
get to the third floor knowing that that
was where I needed to go and have no
idea why was I get half way back
downstairs before I remembered whatever
it was I went up for that place was fun
speaking of edibles I'm pretty sure I
mentioned eating a 1000 milligram gosh
excuse me for that a 1000
folks guys I don't recommend it don't
eat a thousand milligram animal unless
you want to be [ __ ] up for a day and a
half if you're not me probably three
days I feel like a civilian if you gave
that novice gobble that sucker up six
eight hours is what people report it's
just you ate the hundred milligram just
talking about a 1000 honest I haven't
been a big gun Scheiber I haven't eaten
inedible since then I've been a little
bit happy I did it to myself the other
day it wasn't even with a really big
dose I just I popped a couple I thought
I'd be comfortable with it we got to the
movie theater I looked up it was just
there were so many food choices and
before I could figure out what I wanted
I heard my wife giggling next to me but
she knows when I look up but I'm just
too big to pick from the menu and I
didn't mean to do it it was an accident
so what happens to the pros to ya on my
system it [ __ ] me up my whole body
felt weird for a day and a half people
assumed that that's like the comfortable
intro to some marijuana consumption and
it's not like smokings the the
time-tested flowers through a pipe so
explorers through a bong or a joint get
used to that take a DAB one day you know
like three dads in one day and then
start taking big dabs and then dab every
day and then eat some edibles
progressive Ricky I like a good rag as
long as you can do you can you can look
people in the eye and say I don't reject
what I'm addicted to I just buy glass
it's not the same different kind of
glass just rig after rig after rig
beautiful my friends at elevate glass
5:17 stay home if you need a break glass
rigs everywhere you just want you might
hear this kind of oil slick
place oil slick it's a shout out hey
it's time to wrap up the show yes the
[Music]
podcast children checking out check out
Mike's Facebook group make sure you
follow Mike as make sure you go to
iTunes itunes the girl from your heart
podcast by the review section review let
me don't you think about the show what
you think about of the show sure do that
let me know what you think about of the
show [ __ ] gone with it don't you
think give me a little star rating I
will read your comment on a future
episode it's always fun to hear what the
people want to think Mike's catchphrase
the program shit's making it hard we get
to sober it could be it could be an I
took a phat nap go to go follow me you
guys go follow me on all the social
media go to tit why do I want to see
tinder follow me on tinder [ __ ] it do
that to totally different app don't do
that I'm not on there you can't find me
podcast on Twitter with the dev you
that's way better
it's our podcast go to Instagram and
check out i reaiiy rie
Irie endure score genetics I read
genetics is my seed company that's where
I post all the pictures of my cannabis
photography the other day I posted
a butterfly had just to get a little bit
of variety on my page but I usually post
a whole bunch of good cannabis
photography ah big butt shots big room
shots trichome shots like to post a
great whole bunch of great [ __ ] so check
that out I think that's all I've got for
if you want to sponsor the show if
you've got a product you'd like us to
review you can send us your product and
we will unbox it live on the show and
Mike and I will check it out we will
talk about what we think of it we will
follow the instructions if it needs to
be charged up fired up primed Lube but
whatever you need it done first before
we can use it we'll do that we'll follow
the instructions we use your product
properly and we'll review that's the
truth I'd love to hear from you love to
check out your products I think that's
all I've got for you this week
shout out to dead in Co that's my friend
it took me to dead in Co shop to the
friend that got us the tickets nice Big
Shot its main engine spent and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 143 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation new grower here a
professional grower through a new smoker
or a dedicated jammer if you're a
cannabis activists even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
jeboa thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout outs
a cat coop and the entire mystic roof
crew I've ever really had a great 710
hope everybody enjoyed the sunday
episode you guys on this episode I am
joined by Jesse grows from the Colorado
podcast that we talked a whole bunch but
outdoor growing we talk of a whole bunch
of random stuff
the episode was an hour and 20 minutes
long so I'm not gonna waste too much
time here at the start of the show I'm
gonna let the music play and in just a
second I'll be right back with Jesse
grows hang out with us
[Music]
what about your social media so they can
Instagram similar things
yeah website yeah we've got I do
Colorado podcast we are now on stitcher
we're also on soundcloud and we're also
on our own website at Colorado podcast
Arco make sure you guys support the
Colorado podcast and my friend Jesse
pickable D and our boy 44 that's all
those guys it's podcast
[Music]
wacky or wild adventures for the most
part yes yes of podcast your podcast had
a haircut your mic may jump out of that
little welcome to the show thanks for
joining us make sure you guys support
his podcast you guys so uh Jesse is kind
of an outdoor grill expert he's been on
the show several times he people listen
she knows a lot about outdoor growing I
know a lot about indoor growing so we
had some outdoor questions Jesse wants
to talk a little bit about the
differences in small like basement
cultivation compared to large commercial
growth so we'll get into that also but
let's talk about an email I got an email
from a listener I don't have the email
on my phone right now I just set the
phone aside today but shout out to the
guy that sent me an email he asked when
he's growing outdoors how big of a hole
does he want to dig to put his plant I
told him through an email I told him to
listen to show and I'd have Jesse on
more info but I told them basically make
the hole as big as you can
what else can you tell us about that yes
I personally over the years I've noticed
offense somewhat limited especially when
it's in the ground by the size of this
container
the grounds each container put your hole
has a treated soil in it the shoulders
of the plants are chemical too far past
to edge it at home I started off with
two by two poles and worked up to three
by three poles and now you for my coils
probably keep going someday five by five
foot when you're doing these four by
four mold is it a four by four square
right won't be wide four feet long just
how deep you go 18 inches I used to go
deeper I've learned a little bit more
about music since - we canvassed am i
right in thinking that cannabis wants to
root outward instead of downward for the
most part okay I mean it does like to go
down especially for go go go go go hard
extraordinary
but for the most part close
[Music]
reach out to the sides and stick a note
on that' free by stream by 18 inch of
both three foot by three foot hole
that's 18 inches deep
that is a lot of fans dirt you know I
mean cubic feet that is well we'd have
to do the math on the size of the whole
dish you just said right
the boy's neck is one of those Fox horn
bags is 1.75 cubic feet company those
bags you think we the take
[Music]
this is how growers think in math you
guys alright that's a lot of root space
yeah how big are these plants that in
your example how big are your plants at
the end of the season four or five foot
around I mean all the way around you
know not just through one spot so you
can't hug your plants around yeah they I
kind of limit my plants they can only
get about six foot tall
if that if I was able to let him get
bigger they'd probably end up eight nine
foot
okay so eliminated by privacy yes that's
a [ __ ] yes you do such a great outdoor
girl let me you as a [ __ ] I used to
fight it real hard to keep them down I
have learned a new trick
lazy tech win what are we are we in the
flowering phase officially yet or do we
still have a few days to go okay so
about a week here in Colorado and we
were doing research before the show from
coast to coast there's only about a half
hour in sunlight photo period in natural
photo period right now we're talking
about it jesse was doing the research in
difference between what I was finding it
was like New York the Sun was coming up
at 5:30 9:00 in the morning and in Los
Angeles it was coming up at like six oh
eight or some [ __ ] so that's odd but
yeah so but of photoperiod you know it's
it's gonna start really shrinking from
here on out and you know the first
you're gonna get your indica varieties
into flower and then you're more sativa
varieties yeah your flow and blueberry
those are really gonna start taking off
right when in Colorado the gross blow
that [ __ ] is gonna go into flower real
hard here in about a week
in days she'll be spitting out calyxes
real soon for you you'll love it you'll
see pistols in like 20 days I bet yeah
all right
plant later is such a ridiculous
solution for you yeah all right that's
been my Michael lately it's just KSS
keep it simple stoner yeah your plant
sorry I keep putting the throat guys
we're taking some dads let's talk about
these dabs for a brief second I was
dunking my dabber into ninety percent
THC this is 91% THC it's distillate from
our friends at Evo lab and then I take
the 90% distillate that's on my dabber
and I duck that into pure terpenoids of
ghost train haze also made by our
friends at Evo labs this is amazing you
guys is one of the best highs you can
get the first couple of times I smoked
this I got stupid high I was just goofy
I tried to go back to work and I pretty
much just ended up doing stuff on there
for the next hour a little bit clogged I
do apologize for being so congested
today yeah yeah that's delicious isn't
it I've got a g-ghost train our ghost
train Hayes Terps and OG Kush chirps and
then a couple nights ago I took some of
this 120 micron blue sure fresh frozen
saw melis hash and I rolled out a little
piece into a taco shell and I put some
what did I have it was cactus cooler
Alive resin on top of that I smeared
that on like taco sauce and then I took
a piece of Durban hoisin put Durban
poison shatter and rolled it into a
little snake and put that in the middle
like some taco meat and then I put I
ducked to the dabber into the ninety
percent THC distillate and had that on
the dabber and then I picked up the taco
with the dabber and dunked that into the
ghost train haze turps
I was blast-off I was rocket yeah my to
put a little making funny faces and
funny noises I was really
for a little while my first turk dab my
arms and legs with very pleasantly numb
almost immediately yeah there's
something about smoking just raw yeah
I immediately I was like damn there's
this is medicine there for someone
someone heated for me it's great
recreation but for someone somewhere
that that's something I like to take
just the normal shatter I've got I've
got this Durbin poison mob-boss shatter
and I just take little chunks of that
and dunk that into the this is gone I
don't know if I'm gonna be able to
properly get high anymore because if
it's smoking distillate and these Terps
leave it my tolerance game is upped
itself when I go smoke with other people
they're just like dude what the [ __ ] is
wrong with you and don't you want more
dabs and they're in the corner one more
quick question that come on pink the
Terps I mean I think I already know the
answer to this but I'll just ask do the
Terps complete if you dip it in just
like a normal shatter do the Terps
complete something there or make it more
powerful meet opinion it pushes it yeah
it pushes the high a little bit higher
it certainly pushes the high up
I think the my theory is probably not
such a theory but terpenoids
work along with the cannabinoids just
like the the entourage effect absolutely
terpenoids that we're using guys that
looks just like it looks like pee it's
just little here drops a gold in a vial
it's got the consistency of like a
really high grade like a machine oil or
something okay really runny olive oil a
little little runny er than olive oil
maybe and you just dunk the dab right
into it is what I've been doing -
putting been putting a dab on the dabber
and just dunk it and I did I don't get
too hard one time I just don't do dinner
and gave it a little swizzle and when it
hit the veil I heard that the Terps
could like sizzle and I had turf face
like my house just tasted like ghost
rain haze forever
it was almost unpleasant it was like IO
deed my face on turps but then I was
rocket high that's something I'll say it
kind of you can almost wash away the
flavor with with to it like it's so
overwhelming you don't even get it you
just burn yeah you maximum overload your
mouth and it's like I can't taste
anything cuz you just ruined my palate
yeah it's like we need something too
spicy for the next hour everything just
tastes spicy
alright so to our friend that send us an
email about digging holes the bigger the
hole the bigger the plant jesse
recommends about a three by three four
by four about eighteen inches deep fill
it with the best soil that you can
afford
put some amendments in there um let's
give them a list of five good amendments
to throw in there worm castings oyster
shell alfalfa count mill kelp meal
name's Sutan neem seed meal raja seed
meal that's six I'm gonna throw in crab
crab shell oysters shrimp shell okay
alright pretty much there we go you guys
I hope you wrote that down if not hit
that little 15-second back button twice
and hit it again
write it down put that stuff in that big
hole with your soil they put some
perlite in there yeah some sort of
drainage want to get some oxygen in
there but you don't want to take up too
much root space with a bunch of rock
perlite so figure out your mix outdoor
soil doesn't need to be as area's indoor
soil especially in the ground so you can
do yourself a great disservice by
putting too much more light in there
it's just it's gonna increase the
frequency of a flute of water okay let's
see that's why you're the outdoor prone
on the indoors all right big shout-out
to my friend that sent me the email keep
the emails coming if you have any more
or follow-up questions let me know we'll
get on the show for you and mulch that
soil up keep it mulched they got makes a
huge huge difference at the end of the
season laughs it's totally totally worth
it we're gonna talk about a bunch of
stuff for outdoor season I've got
questions this year
alright so our friend Fred Fred Garvin
is ready he keeps the messages coming I
listens to the
Colorado podcast both of our shows we're
gonna have to do more of the swap casts
oh yeah yeah those are fun we'll duct
tape at it next time I also love picking
on you look you're doing well so Fred
sent us a message while back he was
making seeded plants he had Paul and he
put pollen on female plants those plants
have now been pollinated they're forming
seeds he put them outdoors
he had many questions about putting
putting them outdoors about acclimating
them to the outdoor area and how to get
this timer right once I message Jessie
about this Jessie had a great idea
Jessie said that once you once those
plants are pollinated if you go put them
outside and the light cycles a little
bit off they're not going to her because
they're already pollinated they've
pretty much passed there I guess if they
were humans now they would be in
menopause if they were females and now
they can't there pass to that cycle
their whole sexual reproductive thing is
done they've already decided they're
making seeds they have a manifest
destiny girls pregnant you can't already
get her pregnant you can't really like
so that that's those plants that we told
Fred to put outside should be a hundred
percent legit he also mentioned in one
of his emails that his outdoor plants
were in full flower so shout out to Fred
for sending me messages dude I
appreciate it I hope you've got at least
an eye region attic sticker or something
send me a message girl from your heart
at hotmail.com
tell me that it's you cuz I know that
that's not your real name bro come on I
know better than that it's an email
we'll get you some more stickers or
something if you want it we love all of
your input to clear that one out clear
out that was ridiculous
I got a friend on Facebook that uh heard
her or his name I'm pretty sure to her
though is the last name the first and
last name is last names of movie stars
and I called her out on it one time in a
private message like I know your names
fake how'd you figure that out and I was
like well doves like so and so so so
I use my real name you think about your
postman you can't spend time trolling
people if you get your name and face up
there alright so Fred put his plants
outdoor outdoors they're knocking a
hermaphrodite on him he's gonna have
viable seeds if he waits long enough yep
yep I think he was he actually pulled
some of those seeds I think I think he's
got some of those a lot of them were
white but plenty of them were viable and
tiger stripes so it's good work bro do
you know what the cross was I can't I
really don't remember I don't remember
honestly I read so many emails and read
so many crosses that a lot of that share
a lot of the crosses in the green and
healthy wellness garden I can't remember
what they are off the top of my head
yeah I learned a few I remember that all
right so he's they've got seeds in him
and since then as [ __ ] got attacked by
spider mites and he asked is I don't
have his email in front of me but
basically he said none of this plant
material is going to be consumed or
smoked by people since it's all just
seeded how nuclear can I go to spray the
[ __ ] out of it for these spider mites my
opinion would be as nuclear is
comfortable that's what I told him I
told him keep in mind his health while
he's applying pesticides and keep in
mind the health of the rest of his
garden because I know he's got other
cannabis plants out there and the
insects in that garden absolutely of
that area yeah be be aware of that bees
don't kill the bees that's super
important if the bees go away everything
goes away we don't have food if we don't
have bees I saw my dad's neighbor spray
and roundup in his yard the other day
how can chase that [ __ ] down I was
like no I was like see those three light
boxes over there
and instantly he was like oh man I'm so
sorry
we got him set up with some Epsom salt
and vinegar there you go go organic yeah
yeah that'll get rid of almost any
insect it's you don't want around yeah
several several tablespoons of Epsom
salt per gallon can I ask you about how
to get rid of [ __ ] grasshoppers right
now in a ganja garden outdoors yeah that
is a very popular question lately yeah
they're super heavy everywhere this year
I my wife Bernadette my life my life my
beautiful life she has a list of
pesticides
I cannot require or recall any of them
and none of them knowing the way they
work and how grasshoppers work I felt
really weren't necessary I didn't I
didn't feel like he may kill one or two
grasshoppers with it or you may
discourage one or two but it's so my big
thing mow the weeds around your area
that's one of the biggest ones that take
away their food supply okay but lastest
traps which is a mason jar that is a
quarter of the way filled with water a
quarter of the way filled with molasses
buried to the rim around the plants I
know it's kind of arcade you know really
simple here it's a built in the moat but
yeah that's they fall in it and they
can't get up alright so that makes total
sense
try to attract Blue Jays and Robin's to
your girl Robins I don't know how to
attract Blue Jays I know really like
peanuts there you go gonna show up if we
throw our peanuts that gonna bring
rabbits I suppose so possibly can see my
first idea I told my friend to put a
chicken in his yard is that gonna bring
me more problems in the beginning stages
chickens love grasshoppers they also
have juvenile marijuana plants okay once
you've got a four or five foot tall Bush
the chick is gonna use it a shade and
really is it gonna notice it too much it
might pick it the understory a little
bit
okay let's yeah for Cox Tree Service
blame it on the Terps hashtag blame it
on the Terps there we go yeah shout out
to the Terps one other comment on
grasshoppers I'm hippie dippie when it
comes to growing outdoors as soon as I
hear about a grasshopper problem I feel
like something's out of balance so
instead of killing the grasshopper you
might want to look at the bigger picture
it's always seeing something's missing
there that's you're doing something
wrong so I'm gonna say that's like 75%
of the time that is a catcher it really
I feel like this applies to smaller
girls like those guys out on Salem Road
where they've got four acres planted in
the ground I mean that's a completely
different scenario they're gonna have
those issues regardless that's a lot of
damn cannabis yeah went out and drove
and looked at it today they did it's
[ __ ] huge Siloam Road I like near
Beulah yeah okay take a drive out there
it's called the Green Mile for reason
yes do huge things everyone talks [ __ ]
about Pueblo Colorado but everywhere
around this is green houses and outdoor
grows and just acres and acres of hemp
and acres and acres of cannabis it's
everywhere it's so rad right now drive
out there 50 we need more more I don't
know that there's a technical term for
these restaurants fast casual I think
more fast casual restaurants because
that's what the grow industry and people
like us that's what we crave we don't
want the Taco Bell the dr. pepper I hate
what you got there's that Sonic yeah
yeah kind of stuff it's it's DS I don't
there's nothing at Sonic for me yeah
honestly there's nothing there
McDonald's offers nothing for probably
don't eat it mini fast food places
sometimes Jimmy John's if that's even
though you know Qdoba and Chipotle
because he can get a veggie burrito
there that's pretty much the options the
beans at both those places taste like
even vegetarians course vegetarians know
what's up with a good batch of beans oh
yeah I made a Facebook post the other
day about sorry that microphone funnier
oh that's cool about if you know the
smell a good if you can tell good Beach
based on smell alone not too salty which
Tokyo Joe's yeah all kinds of free
advertising for a bunch of shitty rescue
tomato juice can I eat there it sounds
like a place I could eat they do have a
veggie I'm sure sandwich for sure it's
just uh your mic is totally getting away
from you Rockstar yeah yeah we don't
limp on you yeah they got a couple of
veggie sandwiches just a little
mom-and-pop hole in the wall it's right
by the library the best alright let's
put this trainwreck back on on a bond
some rails here let's talk about
cannabis growing this is not the
Colorado podcast we did not bring 44
sandwiches Sam who couldn't read 44 he's
not allowed to go anywhere this is that
no poor dude we can't wait to play again
so Jesse wanted to talk about something
that I find to be really important that
people don't realize people want to jump
into the cannabis industry people move
from all over the country to Colorado to
Washington to California to Oregon to
and all these places that were cannabis
growing is legal and they show up here
and they've either grown in their
basement in an illegal state for a
couple of years and had two or three
lights or they set up a small grow here
their garage or their basement they run
four or six lights and then they think
I'm gonna open a big-ass grow and
they're either gonna do it legally or
illegally they're gonna get permits or
not or maybe they're just gonna do this
in an illegal place they've been grown
in their basement for a while they're
out there in the sticks in Nebraska and
I [ __ ] we're gonna buy that old meat
plant we're gonna hang us a mistake that
a lot of these people [ __ ] up is they
don't realize that going from the
basement to a large grow facility it's
not just taking this much air
conditioning and multiplying it times
however more many lights you're gonna
work it doesn't work that way you run
into a whole new [ __ ] Stewart problems
when you start going to big scale
growing a humidity is ridiculously hard
to control in a large room retardedly
yeah you can you can see that it bugs me
a little bit it's hard as [ __ ] to remove
a lot of humidity in a very large room
it's also hard to regulate the
temperature and the airflow and the co2
so there's a lot of tricks to it what's
the biggest mistake you see people make
when they go from what a dude goes and
just builds his first big when new
people get their OPC license and they
can build a grow where do they [ __ ] up
air conditioning always humidity never
even gets considered cuz yeah they think
this is the desert I mean it is the
desert but they think it's not gonna be
an issue because it's so dry you're
right that's a bunch of BS
you're gonna go pumping water into those
plants every single day and they
transpire and there are a thousand watt
lights a bunch of them right above those
plants and the water wants to come out
and go up toward those lights and then
it things out by the ceiling and then it
falls back down and then it hangs out
and it gets between two leaves and it
festers for a couple of days and then
you know what it does it turns into
[ __ ] powdery mildew yep so that's
spores are there yep there's just
waiting for you to give it a pride
tradition yeah that whole grow room is
the perfect condition for
bugs and [ __ ] funguses and problems
so you bear conditioning in the humidity
are always definitely the first thing
that I think of yeah it's a big-girl
room is a it's a living organism that is
full of lots of other smaller like
living organisms
it was explaining it to a buddy this way
earlier today and it itself has special
care that needs done to it not just the
plants inside of it it's there's a lot
to it
we've got 85 lights in the flower room
and green and healthy down and we run if
D it's 50 tons we've got a 30 in the
middle and two tins on opposite sides 50
tons of air conditioning to cool that
yep three years see that's smart three
air conditioners right yeah one goes
down
we're running kavita's with the kavita
master controller see it's above eighty
six in here I want you to dim the lights
until it gets bad a master controller is
awesome we run two of them because we
have so many lights yeah they're so easy
to program it doesn't even matter there
are 50 lights each other I think they'd
only do 40 they have to do 50 because we
run 85 lights yeah so yeah the nanos do
199 each nice that's but see what sucks
about that is you still might have to
buy multiple units if they're in
different rooms break them into zones
right right luckily our room is 185
light big giant open room with like six
rows right now big shot it's my friends
at veg bloom if you are growing on a
small scale a medium scale or a large
scale and you want nutrients to push
your garden you want to see what you can
really do [ __ ] veg bloom is something
I would recommend it's affordable it's
easy to use and so far I'm six seven
weeks in and this is the best girl I've
done at the green and healthy walnuts
garden and there's a run right next to
it there was not veg bloom and I've
already I've already passed the size of
those by
they're being harvested at week 9 and
these other buds are a week seven and
they're already bigger than the week
nine buds so I support vegetable oh that
would be awesome only place you could go
from your last performance right yeah
last time we crushed it we did pretty
damn well
shut up to the boys at Green &amp; Healthy
Wellness and the whole turf jungle for
helping me I appreciate it nobody
considers getting rid of the humidity
there needs to be an exit for all of the
moisture that comes into the room you
might be filling the room with co2 cool
but where is all of that old stagnant
air going that's in there you need to
get rid of that [ __ ] you don't want to
be in there if you walk into the grow
room and it feels funky to you it feels
funky to the plants you should be able
to close your eyes and breathe and not
notice that you've walked into a grow it
should just feel like normal like this
living room knows things I've noticed
humans like we were talking earlier
fullier spraying you know how even just
watering brewing a damn tea you know
brewing 200 gallons of tea can spike the
humidity and oh yeah 200 gallons of -
you too close to the whites and it just
starts evaporating the oats up the t's
little that all that moisture in the
room carries heat heats up the room as
well you go through the hot and cold
cycles naturally through the day at the
building getting heated up and I mean
most of these grows are in fairly thin
shield commercial warehouses that aren't
insulated as well as it could be and you
know so you get the heating and cooling
effect from you know just the natural
outside temperature we had to build a
concrete wall on the outside we defer it
is I think the the construction turn we
had the furrow wall out six inches with
concrete to kind of insulate ourselves a
little bit well I'm glad to hear that
you're not the only heard I'm not the
only person that might have to do this
are the east wall of our facility right
about
the west wall I got the west wall of the
facility did the way it all sits as the
Sun starts going down it just makes it
yeah and the wall goes you know from
being in the 70s all the way up into
it's radiating heat I can feel you can
see those waves coming off and you go
outside yeah ours was the exact opposite
when the winter came it got so cold on
that wall that we could see moisture on
the inside because you're introducing
moisture right temperature fluctuation
near that wall should have seen the guys
that did the concrete over the front of
the building there were three dudes that
didn't speak much English and they
showed up in a truck with a truck a
wheelbarrow a whole bunch of cement and
some janky scaffolding oh yeah two dudes
carry the scaffolding to where they
needed to be and they just pointed and
grunted a couple times they set up the
first level and then one dude climbed
that and they threw parts to him while
he was standing on the scaffolding and
he stuck him in place and then climbed
up that and hung and grabbed other [ __ ]
and built like a for self so they start
the cement from the top and let it run
down kinda and he's up on the top of the
scaffolding and heels oh no and the guy
on the bottoms mixing cement in a
wheelbarrow with those little trowel
things in his hand and he puts a pile on
the thing and he doesn't throw the tool
but he throws the concrete just Chuck's
it up into the air between the
scaffolding and the dude up top puts his
trial down doesn't even look and the guy
throws two of them up he puts both of
his little tools down it catches both of
them and smears it on the wall and he's
running left and right and just yelling
uno dos as he gets to the middle and the
guy throws how many he needs and he just
[ __ ] smooth and as it's coming down
he goes to the top and pushes it down
and then jumps to the next level and
repeats and then they got her all done I
went back and smooth it out it took
these three dudes seriously two hours to
do the entire front
[ __ ] building amazing I would hire
those guys for [ __ ] anything that's
or so [ __ ] you Trump yeah a hard work
and [ __ ] I mean do you know my
background I worked in the construction
industry for over a decade there's a
reason why there's not that many white
guys employed in the construction
industry anymore
yeah so yeah take that Trump yeah [ __ ]
you Trump hire illegals can do some
construction work they do this [ __ ] that
white people think they're too good to
do that's the truth [ __ ] yeah you
couldn't pay me enough to do some of the
[ __ ] that some of those guys would do
just to make enough money to send home
to their family yeah and that's why I
have no problem with that do you that
fault black tar roofing I do draw the
line there without a doubt yeah [ __ ]
white is this paper you don't honestly
any kind of roofing I draw the line
to be honest all right so you gotta get
air conditioning and humidity you gotta
have an exit you gotta have a vent
drying stale air out of the building and
getting it out of the ceiling
that's something super important when
you're going from a basement grow to a
larger commercial grow do you guys have
to run we should be but we're loud were
loud one more complaint before we get in
trouble the fine is cheaper than the
filters that we need we we had to hear
it well oh that was they immediately
there was like one of their big concerns
was carbon filters and we've got six of
those big [ __ ] all of ours we've even
got the inline ones on our air crew
flights
we're disgustingly lucky because across
the street from us is homeward bound dog
crematorium nice and so every day around
noon you smell garlic bread and then you
realize and I smelled it the other day I
was like I can't even let him do that I
walked into the other room where he was
a brace all that garlic bread news yeah
who's cooking I go that's the dog
crematorium next door don't enjoy it
much that's Rover and he just looked at
me like that's that's fluffy because the
first few days I worked there I smelled
something and there were two girls that
used to work there that are no longer
affiliated with us but they used to work
there every day like noon or two o'clock
I smell garlic bread the reason I
brought it up is just carbon filter
systems in a home grow versus a
commercial grower drastically different
hugely different yeah yeah that's why I
said what we need is way expensive like
HEPA filter great [ __ ] UV lighting
possibly we've got a small UV light that
I use on small plantings I run it over I
just walk through the grow room and just
hover that white about four to six
inches over every little plant and it
keeps them nice and bug free is the bugs
want nothing to do with that and the PM
yeah that thing is helpful I was using
that on another guy's garden they had
bad PM and I think it took eight days to
just deteriorate all the PM that has
[ __ ] filtration it refuses to blow
the air out of his house cuz he's afraid
keeps getting PM they keep learning new
tricks on how to get rid of it for him
yeah keeps us on our toes
alright so filtration is something they
choose super definitely need give that
stale funkier out you're gonna need UV
lighting you're gonna need a HIPAA
filtration your air conditioners have
exchanges and they're gonna pull the air
from the grow room and that's gonna blow
back into your grow but also a large
portion of that is going to escape into
the outside atmosphere so you're gonna
be stinking it up that way also you need
carbon scrubbers inside the grow how do
you know it's us there are some
dispensary owners that don't get along
with those people because they're shifty
dicks and they're keeping it real and
we're trying to be on the legit side
we're cool and they come over hey what's
up I'm actually I'm looking forward to
your first visit because the place that
we're at now is completely different
than some of the other places it's nice
when you can look forward to a media
business John I know they'll have some
issues I'm sure they will they're all
they're always going to that's their job
but I'm not scared of anything
you know that's anything that we have
messed up on it's either cuz we didn't
understand it properly or
right invite the Department of
Agriculture in for a walk through like
invite them and then if you invite them
they won't give you any violations for
whatever they find they'll tell you to
correct it since you invited them and
they'll be like you've got 90 days to
get it corrected when we come back
that's when we'll actually be able to
put you on like a warning notice yes
vitam they show up and they're like oh
good job thank you and you can be like I
need help come show me what - correct
[ __ ] cool I can't think of his name
right now I can almost remember his name
in my head he's a cool little dude he's
kind of a short guy but he's cool he's
fun to hang out with he's very
informative very educational he'll talk
to you like you're a human he won't
treat you like a stupid grower like some
of the industry people do like
electricians and HVAC guys franchises
like we're [ __ ] [ __ ] HVAC guys
yeah I was dealing with one yesterday I
was about ready to strangle the guy I
just had to walk out of the office
you're [ __ ] sorry
sometimes some contractors are a pain in
the ass to deal with so that's something
to look forward to you're building your
big grow find some contractors that you
can trust in Pueblo good [ __ ] luck if
you're in Pueblo Colorado
you'd be better off paying crews from
Denver to come down and build your grow
in my opinion is that a good a good
builder he's decent okay and he's very
connected in the city
um he knows he's on personing basis with
everyone
alright so check this out if you're
trying to get a grow bill in Colorado in
the Pueblo Colorado region find a guy
who does construction by the name of
gaglianone AG Liana's construction in
Pueblo Colorado when you contact them be
like hey I was listening to a podcast
Jeff told me about you so anything that
we do business with you owe him two
percent commission yeah just make sure
that he sends me two percent not a lot
to ask
[Music]
coins on the floor that's that's
breaking that's breaking the big one
find yourself a good contractor is the
point of all this yes yeah cuz
contractors can [ __ ] up your whole day I
worked in another facility that the
blueprint was drawn by one guy the HVAC
system was designed by another in the
electrical which we're gonna talk about
in a minute was designed by another guy
and they were all it was like we took a
Ferrari engine maybe a Porsche Turbo kit
and then maybe like a Lamborghini body
and then the suspension system for a
Corvette and they're like you got all
these dope-ass parts make it go fast
Ricky Bobby doesn't work when you turn
on all the lights [ __ ] engineer that's
very key as an engineer that understands
ya cuz you're not always gonna find a
contractor that understands indoor
cultivation actually rarely will find a
contractor that understands it but you
can't find engineers that know what
they're doing and engineers are smart
people you can explain [ __ ] to him so
yeah that was real key in the uncle bun
company development we had a really good
engineer let's talk about that in a
minute also all that you give them a
nice plug I'm gonna write it down so
that I remember I was able to relate
concerns I had to to him and I'm like
you know we got to make sure this
doesn't happen like electricity I was
like great we just have to have plenty
electricity
three-phase power all day long yeah well
how many apps we allowed to pull we're
four hundred on each box yes nowhere
near bridge you get to flip the [ __ ]
on switch we've got to the inside yeah
ridiculous in the contacts touch do like
if you if you're not strong enough to
push it all right through you don't want
to do it like because that's a baller
that's a wad of yeah and some smaller
folks might not be able to push that
thing all the way another thing we kind
of touched on this one get a [ __ ]
certified qualified reliable
professional electrician if your
contractors do [ __ ] up you can fire them
this guy got a [ __ ] dough you're not
dating and I can call them on it and you
can make a comeback and fix it or take
away their junk and you're not gonna pay
for it there you go
let's take weather every contractor has
got a pile of his [ __ ] in your facility
while he's working there bro you doesn't
[ __ ] that my walls are all crooked make
my Wall Street then I'll pay you you
gotta do [ __ ] right the flooring
flooring has always been a [ __ ] in
every facility I've been to the flooring
has been an issue yeah it's just hard to
get floors right in this industry oh
I've got a brand name of specific paint
for you but I don't know it off the top
and I'll let you know
it's been great I've got one little
flake out of two thousand square feet oh
[ __ ] yeah yeah I'm a detective
almost three months of we've got ours on
the floor right now that's cleaning
mopping up after six plants 12 plants is
one thing mopping up after 176 plants is
a completely different story I've got an
assistant grower now and every like few
days he's like what do you want me to do
bro just clean up he's like seriously
like yeah just go [ __ ] every little
random thing that's fallen out of a
plant all the pearlite that's on a table
or any whatever if there's a person's
lying around go clean all that [ __ ]
exactly start from the top in the flour
room go all the way down if there's old
trellis or old pots in there from
harvested that's got to go sweep every
goddamn corner get out the shop vac suck
up underneath all the weird random
little nooks and crannies that we got in
there anything that's not gonna be used
doesn't need to be in the flower room I
don't think like scissors and boxes of
material that [ __ ] should go in the
storage room store that put the broom
and dustpan and trash can outside the
flower room you put that [ __ ] outside
just don't have that in the flower in
room or the bedroom simple little tasks
that you don't even think about doing in
a small girl can literally take days in
a big defoliating oh my god shaving legs
shaving legs defoliant aching I know you
guys are all netting but yeah I'm doing
a big Seeger on so that wasn't really a
right an option likes double and triple
layer trellising I get crazy on it I
can't wait I've got a guy a former
employee that would defoliate the entire
room for an entire shift and he would do
10 five-gallon buckets full of leaves
and he would push him down like you just
chocolate
all day and then go back and scoop up
the leaves out of the trays into
five-gallon buckets and he'd probably
fill ten five gallon buckets he'd fill
one of those big like thirty gallon
trash cans halfway full it just leaves
just from the first run of defoliating
things you don't have to do in the
basement we have to weigh all that and
we have to track it
[Music]
yeah document what all that [ __ ] weighed
yeah off so we've got a you know you're
supposed to like mix it with soil or
vinegar oil or something like that
before you can throw it away okay yeah
let's so let's catch the listeners up
though and a commercial grow when you if
you have see maybe a but isn't desirable
or they're the bottom part of the plan I
throw that [ __ ] away when that's in the
trash can you have to cut it up into
little tiny pieces and then you have to
mix it like Jesse said with soil or a
kitty litter is what they recommend for
gravel or vinegar or like you got a good
idea yeah we've got three worm firms
there you go feed it to the worms yeah
and they're loving it too I'm sure they
love their chamomile and the best we use
a [ __ ] ton of worm castings too so it
helps cut down cost there you go pre
cycling that's a good way to do it yeah
[Music]
that's pretty read we we grind it up
pretty small we chop it chop it up with
uh like Thea the shears
go ham on it with the shears and shake
that soil into the trash we let them dry
they've all sat around it dried for a
couple days
dump all that soil into the trash can
they're all bunch of the waste into
there
dump a couple more pots more soil couple
more far more a waste yeah just keep it
like that so that's a way to get rid of
all of our old soil at the same time and
you have a use for it wasting all that
good dirt
I know it's recyclable I totally know
and we use so much cocoa we buy 14 big
bags of cocoa at a time when we go
because that's what fits in hunts car to
shot it's a way to grow I hope nobody's
heard me burp into that microphone
excuse me it's a good way to grow I was
buying cocoa grow the other day I really
like the botanic air cocoa grow I don't
prefer the aeration bag just get the
cocoa it's just fun you don't need that
aeration in there I don't like that [ __ ]
but way to grow is nice enough to throw
in a bunch of bags of Fox farms ocean
forest soil for free they carried that
[ __ ] to my car like you buy a lot of
shits my friends a way to grow they know
who they are I don't know if they listen
to the podcast if you do listen to the
podcast contact makes I'd love to have
you as a sponsor yeah the Rasta Jeff
[Music]
it's really funny all right so you need
a good [ __ ] electrician you need way
to get rid of humidity you need a way to
get rid of heat plenty of air
conditioning
you're gonna seal up all the cracks all
the nooks and crannies you gotta be able
to clean the [ __ ] out of this place it's
gotta be a semi clean facility you don't
want some old car garage where the floor
is all greasy no you need a floor drain
for drains are crucial absolutely yeah
and water you need access to water a lot
of warehouses out in Pueblo by the
airport they don't have water ran to
them because they didn't need water for
anything if you get one of those
warehouses out there make sure that was
on track here yeah those warehouse is
out there you you might not have water
you're gonna have to be getting trucks
of water you have to pay to get water
out there something people aren't aware
of if you get a large grow on private
land out say in Pueblo County somewhere
you have to get water right
you just because you have land doesn't
mean you're granted water rights even if
there's a well there you have to
purchase water to offset what you're
taking out exactly yep if there are
enough grows around that area that that
jurisdiction deems the water is
compromised by you coming they can
decline your waterways you can't have
any water and this I mean even to the
point that they don't care that you're
going to town to buy it and that you
have a big truck it's sorry
yeah you can't prove that I've got a
side track with the Department of
Natural Resources now if anyone has any
questions or anything Jesse it's fun all
of the great people that we meet these
people would never take you and I
seriously Jesse's got a semi ponytail a
beard [ __ ] tattooed up he's got a
trout on your arm on his arm he's got a
Colorado flag he's got a chili that's
just one arm oh he's got a monarch
butterfly I'm six five with dreadlocks
and red eyes good it's pretty much a
good disband a crooked hat are
indestructible and these contractors and
business folks would never have taken us
seriously before this gas industry and I
find it so funny I've noticed when I go
to restaurants in Denver and I'm wearing
like a does the dad kid sure baby sure
and my hat crooked and a pen D and skate
shoes and my Dickies and I walk in red
eyed before restaurants would kind of be
a dick to me they've kind of like this
guy's here he's [ __ ] up our vibe but
now there's always some young hip
waitress it's like what's up guys at
work in the weed industry you're gonna
tip the [ __ ] outta me you want some
great service honey there were courage I
don't want fancy things I want a nice -
a lot of good shows we go see the dead
whenever they come around I'll go see
fish every time around she took out the
dead company I saw the dead and it was
[ __ ] rad this most recent one yeah
just this recent one when they're in the
folder at Folsom feel
super awesome yeah come with me one time
I used to eat a bunch of psychedelic
drugs when I used to go to those shows
and I've quit doing that I had a head
injury anybody that listens to the
podcast heard about the head injury it's
not been a year and a half and I still
have effects still have like I've got
post concussion syndrome and I've got a
traumatic brain injury still I played
high school football very competitively
I have major concussions in high school
and I know I didn't let them heal up
correctly right and I wonder sometimes
how that affects me givers you for doing
[ __ ] and you go oh that's from that time
I have those moments where I wonder
[Music]
water OH
water tanks water filtration your
average on the shelf go store water
filter can't handle them you need a lot
of water I use a thousand gallons of
water every 48 hours grow and that's 105
lights total I'm doing 155 to 165 right
now oh gosh see we're still not even at
full capacity
yes full flower five feet tall with big
[ __ ] donkey dick buds on them and
either way that's still a lot more than
your oh so much more yeah if you're
using I figure use about indoors you
probably use five gallons of water per
light every 48 to 72 hours yeah so if
you guys are trying to figure out how
much water you should be using in your
indoor every 1000 watt or 600 watt light
600 thousand watt light you should be
running about five gallons every 24 to
48 hours if your temperatures and your
human
and everything are dialed in and your
plants are at their optimum growth your
plants are growing a little slow you're
probably over watering them yeah that's
usually the first sign of over watering
some plants outdoors it's gonna be
average I'd say five gallons plant per
plant per day per day is it okay to just
turn on the hose and just let the hose
just [ __ ] follow those outdoor plants
yes for the most part I try to
concentrate it more just around the
clamp because I feel like it's wasting
okay yeah okay yeah no you could totally
do like a field flood irrigation
actually know of a also a place here in
public County that floods their field
just like they do with cantaloupe or
watermelon or wow yeah yeah just blow
the whole field out let it dry and
reflet it they're just doing a flood and
drain outdoor basically that's okay I
think they do it like two or three times
I need to go explore and visit more of
these outdoor cannabis and I want to see
how you guys are doing a lot of this
[ __ ] I can implement into my indoor tech
stuff the sudden pretty I think is
pretty cool the overwhelming majority of
these places are know to raise bed Oh
neat yeah so no tell you guys the they
make an amended soil with a lot of
special amendments and then very
specific amendments that I make my rent
too honestly I don't know what goes into
that
live worms live worms okay so it's
living soil you guys yeah and the plants
are harvested and do you pull out the
big root ball or you just leave that in
there pull out the stem around it okay
try do you actually want to leave as
much of the root ball in there as you
can cuz the worms are gonna eat it to
add into nutrients for the planting wife
so I'm going in circles
you pull the plan out and you put a new
one in
you send her off again they use a lot of
cover crops stuff like that oh okay so
you stacking stuff into the pot and then
the worms will eat all of that mostly
that stuff will decompose and become
plant and so you're gonna start losing a
little bit of depth every time right
just refill it with your fresh that's
how you got charge no tells you it's
awesome go back in top dress in all your
researched amendments that's pretty
awesome I never saw that of a crow it's
uh babe it's extremely economical that's
why most of these places are running it
hell there's such a large scale that
it's just if the plant stays good
because grower who uses mainly bottled
nutrients for most of my growing always
been taught to flush my plants since
they're not feeding a whole bunch of
bottled nutrients a bunch of she lated
salts their plants aren't backed up with
stuff their plants are probably more
able to I don't even remember the word
right Emily all of the nutrients that
are going through they can use it a
little bit better it comes up and goes
down they get rid of it a little more
okay i debuff a star they get to pick
and choose yeah yeah that's crazy the
plants actually finish themselves off
they start fading just like you they
would if they're flooded I mean flushed
no do you see a difference in specific
strains does strain a versus strain B do
they finish differently in the no-till
outdoor I haven't done enough of it to
say that just curious if that was
nutrients running out or if that was
actually the plant realizing hey done
I'm flushing myself I I know in my
experience the way I grow in the ground
is kind of no-till pretty much yeah I
know Girl Scout cookies and flow will
finish themselves off
what half doubt they'll deform cut girls
cookies flow will finish herself off you
guys
[Music]
we are 13 days in the flower just about
the end of that right now and the lights
just shut off so I'm gonna go get on
with it a few more times and ya know me
where the forehead greenlighter do you
have a room light no I got the forehead
one I don't like the full room once okay
inevitably that light switch always gets
left on right yeah it's actually focused
where I am we've talked a lot about
building getting your large commercial
grow going you have any things that you
want to add before we start wrapping
this up so that I don't cut off any of
your useful data for our listeners find
a person that can be vouched for by many
people throughout the community to work
with your engineer to help design your
building and pay him what his worth like
you know if it'll be a gonna like me or
Jeff and even if he's not gonna grow for
you pay him what it's worth and your end
product will drastically improve and
work better by doing it in my first week
in green and healthy wellness I made
minor improvements it improved the
financial it just made sense fixed their
books a little bit just by [ __ ] doing
a couple of adjustments like making the
garden more more profitable just by
eliminating this and adding this it just
took me a week to make a whole bunch of
small
it's just cuz the person who set it up
and was running it was not an
experienced grower was not I don't want
it I don't want to bash this person but
they weren't a forward thinker they were
it didn't they didn't look far enough
into the future they didn't have
foresight to realize that if I don't put
glue here the shit's gonna come apart
eventually don't you like that yeah so I
fixed a lot of just small details they
didn't have any heaters in the so his
winter when I started there were no
heaters and the reservoirs and they're
feeding the plants 54 degree water and
they couldn't get the pH of the [ __ ]
water to come up it's 30 degrees outside
thermometer was 54 degrees that's why
the pH won't move that's why the plants
have the claw they all had the [ __ ]
downward claw but the plants were purple
[Music]
they have put two in each one sentiments
74 degrees what a run to get the glass
beautifully there for heaters those
would have been more economical but I
didn't think of that because I'm not a
farm boy I just never thought of that
for sure I ordered a couple at the store
last winter nice we've been selling the
glass ones and I found the stainless
steel ones very quickly that glass ones
gonna break in there on accident fifty
gallons of water you know someday it
will but yeah that's a failsafe so
you're not gonna get shot right yeah
they're not in there right now yeah you
guys a lot of the [ __ ] you're gonna go
spend money on it the hydro store go
check out the aquarium store before you
do that because it's cheaper or even
Granger to be totally honest oh yeah to
buy all your big R has a lot of very
useful [ __ ] the normal grossed or not
the Hydra
next door but like the local garden
supply center has a lot of [ __ ] Home
Depot and Lowe's and Target have a lot
of good shoes just do not buy nutrients
soil anything that is going to be
consumed by you or your plant don't
purchase that at Home Depot Lowe's are
targets only accessories made out of
plastic or whatever that kind of [ __ ]
lighting that's cursed or specific still
at this point Hobby Lobby sells Fiskars
scissors for $12.99 as opposed to Home
Depot and everywhere else is 1999 a
little titanium tip Fiskars trim
scissors okay high grow sorry change
names
I can't I'm not as involved with the
store is that the wife now oh yeah it's
always been the wife Shannon to the wife
yeah
that's her baby nice she does a good job
I understand Springs they finally if I
were there I'd shot there but I'm right
up the street from the store in spring
statement as if I needed 14 bags of soil
I don't know that you'd have it that's
something we should mention commercial
orderings yeah good luck the first time
you want to figure out how much [ __ ]
soil you need to fill all those pots cuz
it's that's a math challenge you heard
Jesse and I say you're gonna have to go
back to the store a couple times don't
expect all stores you're gonna be able
to get commercial quantities of things
when you need them you need to think
ahead about stuff yeah you might have to
start letting we let the store near us
know that this is these are products
that we use on the regular if you keep
these stock we'll buy them if we come
here and you don't have it we will drive
directly to another store and get it
history no [ __ ] yeah and so it took
them a couple of rhythms you know it
took them a couple hey you don't have it
like it's coming Wednesday the trucks
come Wednesday I don't care so we kind
of a job we compromise with that we
can't [ __ ] with the day the trucks run
like that's some [ __ ] we can't ask for
it I go get it on your next order it
doesn't fit like you know like bringing
on the previous order you guys ordering
a truckload of [ __ ]
a truck of your stuff it's funny the
there's two main truckers that they
literally move I would say seventy sixty
to seventy percent of the gross stores
or gross the places old and Krause
stores all across Colorado up and down
the Front Range that's awesome it's Gary
and James cuz there's probably great
warehouse think it's [ __ ] everything
there's three main warehouse it just
gets distributed from there out to
Pueblo Springs day they're a company
named Denver air is one of the only
delivery companies that will work from
Denver south on a daily route oh wow
they go - way to go they go to us they
got a girl generation they go to all of
them way to grows my favorite if you're
going big you're going big stuff if
you're going you want to buy stuff for
your small Grove definitely hit one love
life if you're big huge gigantic County
greenhouse grow we already deal with a
handful of half a dozen clients out
there we know what it takes to to
service big grow so if you're blind
you're out there in the county
commercial account going for you like
Jesse said he said to hire somebody that
knows what the [ __ ] they're talking
about when it comes to working with your
engineer to build to grow something
super important that just sounds
egotistical coming from myself and Jesse
but also hire a master grower that is a
master grower interview people look at
pictures of plants they've grown I
brought people to my home grow to show
them that I can grow on a commercial
scale as I here is what I can do if you
put me in a big grow I can do it and
they trusted me and they gave me the
opportunity by seeing the cleanliness
and the organization of my home grow
yeah you can go look at their grow
before you hire a master grower do it
and if you're the business guy and you
think you're gonna grow it yourself and
be professional you're gonna [ __ ] it up
I've got faith in your skills I've got
faith in your mind but cannabis is
something that takes a lot of practice
to learn it's like playing an instrument
you might have natural skill but you're
not gonna be Bon Jovi the first time you
grow
[ __ ] practice you're gonna have to
tour a few times you're gonna have to do
it ten cycles under your belt before you
even think about going big full cycles
from this clone all the way to drying
and curing all the way to move in the
packs there's a lot to figure out my
boss gets my head owner he gets down and
dirty in the Guru it's it's and he is
this like child like excitement about it
so [ __ ] awesome I've never I well I
know hunt he gets down in the room to
max for me all show comes in at 6:00 in
the morning on a certain Don Tuesday's
he'll be there at 6:00 in the morning
and I'll come in a couple few hours
later and he'll have a hundred pots
filled with sweeps I'm not too good to
clean the shooters and take out trash
but you're right I should be hands-on
with a plan
it feels good though to have to work for
people that realize you don't want to do
that stuff that you would do it but you
[Music]
know you don't have to worry about the
giant facility all to myself
[ __ ] some Windex right there's that
Mitch down for people that um don't know
much about the industry or don't live in
Colorado is not common at all to find
owners that are actually involved in the
grill that's I think being Jeff are both
fortunate to work unfortunately it's
equally as common to find rich dudes
that own Porsche dealerships and want to
double their [ __ ] money by opening a
dispensary and being a [ __ ] to
everybody and don't know anything about
cannabis Oh
[Music]
guys they just want to double up because
they have a little bit of money and
that's where might talk about hire a
real master grower loops around a lot of
people want to hire their cousin because
they want to give their cousin a job or
their nephew or their [ __ ]
brother-in-law because he grew weed in
the 70s and he talks a good game this is
your investment it's gonna cost you a
million bucks to get your your grow and
your dispensary going it's six hundred
thousand bird to get started and then
you need like another four hundred for
some payroll and whatever pops up and
you're gonna need a lawyer and an
accountant it's a million bucks just for
a small small facility our little
facility man yes so unless you trust
your [ __ ] cousin a million bucks
worth your future is on the line your
business is on the line your grows on
the line
some of us growers are weird people oh
we've been taught to hide this for so
many years the guys that are good at it
did it like when we were hiding it and
we're kind of sketchy about it so
sometimes some of our background history
on the application is a little vague
sometimes we've got a big furry ass
beard they could have squirrels I
sometimes you got dreadlocks down to
your ass they could have the whole damn
Zoo hidin in it they don't we don't like
sharing secrets we don't like to share
too many secrets owners by street people
by friends by family things have gone
wrong so we're a little we're a little
protective of ourselves of our knowledge
it's one thing I had my phosphate the
other day growers are some of the only
people in the industry that don't
actually need a job right they could go
make their own money didn't there's more
money being a black market grower than I
ever have in the legal industry but I
don't have to look over my shoulder
anymore I don't have to when I hear
rustling outside the front door too
early I don't think the door is about to
get kicked the [ __ ] because I spent
20 years of my life just wondering is
today the day they kicked this [ __ ] in
you can get a loan for card
it's hard work but I've got he can get
done brand-new car in the driveway that
I couldn't have done when I was a street
hustle or because now I've got paychecks
and taxes yeah I pay child support
because I've got a child that lives with
their mom and just because we don't live
in the same place I'm required to
[ __ ] pay child support
it's cool with me just driving it over
there I have to go through a system
which documents have being paid
they were always on my ass about my
income you're paying child support but
we want to know where your money comes
from like why does it matter if the baby
yeah I just kept telling like my mom
pays it or money just [ __ ] told that
kind of [ __ ] thank you so having a job
not looking over my shoulder is well
worth the difference
it's the distress reduction although
there's other stress that comes from it
right the different kind of stress just
but now I can be I I am more proud of my
grow now than I was when I was a black
market for sure like it was kind of cool
having that thing in the basement that
nobody knew about
then I would disappear for [ __ ] 12
hours at a time what have you been doing
trimming weed but I can't tell you guys
we may look like weirdos we might be
tatted up get yourself somebody that's
on [ __ ] time somebody that doesn't
drink and do some drugs but I've had
some problems in the past with employees
that have recently hired that one guy
was I party too hard the night before
and was too drunk to come to work and
then I had another guy that ate too many
mushrooms a night before it ripped way
too hard and had a headache and couldn't
come to work plants don't care about
that yeah [ __ ] you you got a job to do I
rely on I need the plants rely on you if
you don't show up and water those plants
they're dead it's a business yeah if if
you don't show up on time and a pump
died overnight because pumps die you're
fired
the whole gardens dead you're [ __ ]
fired there goes your million-dollar
investment so hire yourself a real
master grower somebody that knows what
they're doing not just your cousin we
might look like weirdos we might be
introverts
but if we're on time we show initiative
or dedicated you got to be a soldier you
got to be dedicated to the grow gotta
respect the plants you got to be able to
build a relationship with the plants you
need something you can communicate with
someone they can multitask someone that
can deal with a contractor someone
to be a dick when the electrician shows
up so well that's not gonna run out the
back door and matches compliance binders
with all your info you tell them to have
a good day and they get to sit there and
figure out what's wrong and they can't
come in and check until they tell you
they need to those compliance binders
and wait for them to find an issue go
back to work and by the way I'm not the
owner so you can't even tell me [ __ ]
I'll call the owner I'm doing my job
just go back to work I feel like we've
gone a long way in this podcast that's
15 minutes in but there's a lot of good
information this cause this podcast was
everything there was news education and
conversation I'm not sure what the news
was Terps Terps officially you guys
Terps are awesome jerks on Terps turps
all day long shout out to the yet the
Terps sweet and all those kids I've got
one more thing written down on my paper
of notes that we need to talk about it
is the Uncle Bud company tell me all
about the Uncle Bud company Uncle Bud
company is the company I'm employed by
as daddy grow and a dispensary yes we've
got an MIP added OPC oh that's a my
piece of license to make cash available
medically infused products yes marijuana
matters Prada yeah yeah we we use a co2
extraction method so that's primarily we
make bait or what we started off it's
the company's still new we're evolving
we started off with co2 oil vape pen
refills in cartridges we're bringing out
a line of edibles we're going through
testing and approval which is a bit of a
process right now but those will be on
store shelves soon and it will also be
bringing you I don't know how I can
state that we're bringing a fractional
distillation similar to a product called
clear okay all right market and I will
be bringing our version of terpenes to
the record market as distillate is the
new stuff let me read the label on the
distillate that I've got this is raw
distillate
is total potential and it's broke and
pull it out the going to be available to
alkyl bud company or are those going to
be available at recreational and/or
medical shops statewide we are
wholesaler yes
our our co2 oil right now I know here in
Pueblo available at the spot it's also
available at the spot in Trinidad your
co2 oil that you guys made yes okay cool
um so it's recreational product yes
edible products were coming up with at
the moment we've got a barbecue sauce
it's going to the proven cross no she
and we lose ass yeah a the people that
owe my company are from George in Texas
[Music]
it's really good how many how many
milligrams of THC per serving um that's
part of the thing we're figuring out
right okay the bottles good it's gotta
be limited at 100 100 a smaller bottle
okay but it's but I think it'll be like
two servings so 50 milligrams so gonna
make some red you could just squirt the
whole bottle across the ribs as the heat
when you're cooking the ribs gonna [ __ ]
up my medicine that's one of the things
we've got to figure out all right
[Music]
hypothetically talking about BBQ ribs
over here I had no idea the proofing
process the state requires for for a new
new style and it's rigorous then we're
doing popcorn balls to oh I had some
popcorn balls that were coated and clear
hi that's a part of the a lot of art
demand we've been getting for clay right
now it's coming from edibles
manufacturers nice they don't want any
smell right it makes it so much easier
and it's more viscous it's easier to
work with it's not chunky like pho it's
a higher percentage so it's easier to
work with my friends at titi extractions
they gave me a 1000 milligram chokolate
bar it was kind of like biting into
taste
they told me if there's a gram and a
half of shatter melted into that
chocolate bar they just took a gram and
a half of shatter into a chocolate bar
and just dropped the shatter directly
into the chocolate because when I bit
into it it was chocolate chocolate
chocolate my teeth when I pulled them
apart they would do that I got so high
then I made a list of things to do to
work to do I would read on the list
water plants and I'd walk to the water
and turn on the hose be like the front
door do an hour and 20 minute podcast
that's awesome of you thanks to burn for
letting me borrow your husband for an
hour and a half and take it some dad's
with me that's super cool shout out to
the uncle bud company you guys I'm gonna
wrap up this podcast thing thank you for
coming Jesse make sure you check out
Jesse grows on Instagram Colorado
podcast come check it out stitcher and
SoundCloud - we're gonna get you on
iTunes yes you know how to do that I
just haven't had the time to sit down
and know how to do it nice need help I
will get you on there bring get this
podcast on iTunes cuz iTunes is a place
most people listen stitcher is number
two I
which is number 12 so I have to go
through over to know I love doing it
[Music]
home we're gonna take a couple dabs and
I will be back to put a bow on this
[ __ ] nice see you guys later
all right podcaster I want to thank you
guys for listening to a long episode I
want to thank Jessie for joining me I
also want to thank Fred for sending me a
whole bunch of useful emails if any of
you have questions that you'd like
answered on the podcast send me an email
let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to answer your
questions on a future episode also I'd
love to read your reviews on iTunes on a
future episode go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store find the review section
find the girl from the heart podcast
type in a little review let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your review on a future episode
give me some stars let me know what you
think of the podcast I would love to
hear from you also I love all this
social media interaction find me on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast find me
on Facebook that grow from your heart
podcast and find me on Instagram it's at
Irie underscore genetics it's all i've
got for you this week you guys be good
to one another take a bunch of fat dabs
shot it's my ninja Spence and until next
time take a fat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
bleaching
I used to get upvotes mama check but no
magetta
check every time we track our boats by
your dead don't forget Oh
[Music]
all right podcast world open to thank
you guys again for listening to a long
block of old episodes I would love it if
you would email me and let me know what
you think about these old episodes the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to stalk me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a fan
dad and give your mom a hug for me
you