[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 264 of the
growth from your horror podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots van flooding use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at the hella dank seed bank if you need
new seats for your lineup visit the
hella dank seed bank at dank seed dot
store I hope everybody's having a great
day I hope everybody had a good holiday
I hope everybody stuff themselves out be
sure to meal with some friends and
family and I hope you were safe yeah I
hope you got to consume some cannabis
with somebody new over the holiday if
you got to smoke cannabis with a new
family member over the holiday I would
love to hear about it send me a tweet
send me an email on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast the email is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com if you smoked or
consumed cannabis in some way with
somebody new over this Thanksgiving
holiday especially a family member I
would like to hear about it share your
story with me all right
speaking of smoking with people what am
i smoking on I just took a gigantic dab
of some berry cooler shatter and it
really hit the spot you guys I've been
I've been talking about different kinds
of concentrates here on the show um I
smoked the hdfs C I smoked the the
batter's the rosin 's I don't smoke a
lot of raisins I smoked a lot of batters
smoked a lot of Ambrosia and live resins
and the the Q RCS and the hdfs C
honestly no don't go Google and qrc you
guys it's not a real thing I just made
that up don't please don't go google
that that's the future that's alien hash
it's coming soon but I was getting at is
I think I like shatter I've got some
batter I've got some live resin I've got
some butters got a lot of great stuff
available but I tend to reach for the
shatter most often something about the
shatter it's affordable it gives me a
giant dab and it just it seems
old-school that's back to when hash
started getting really popular again
shatter is where it all started I really
seem to like the shatter but that being
said I think my next dab is going to be
a dab of this screaming tangerines
batter from apothecary so it's gonna be
a berry cooler and screaming tangerines
type of episode I hope you guys are
smoking on something delicious with me
all right on this podcast I do want to
talk about a little bit of a debate
between organic and synthetic nutrients
and organic and synthetic gardening but
before I get there I would like to read
some iTunes comments let's turn out this
music just a little bit here we will get
into some iTunes comments and reviews
there are actually iTunes customer
reviews ladies and gentleman I would
love it if you would leave me a review
on iTunes if you're listening to the
podcast on iTunes simply go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart podcast scroll down about
halfway there will be a big square with
my face in the middle - red yellow and
green square with my face in the middle
click on that you'll have three options
the one in the middle will be ratings
and reviews when you go there you'll be
able to type in a customer review and
you'll be able to leave a star based
rating so far most people everybody
except for one person has left a
five-star review or a five-star rating
one person has left a four star rating
everybody seems to be leaving positive
reviews I've got two reviews I have not
read so let's get to them here on the
show
this first iTunes customer review was
left by a person who calls himself
Maddie E and the review goes like this
the headline says the best and they gave
me five stars and then they said this is
by far the best fully comprehensive
podcast about cannabis out there what a
great find thanks Ross to Jeff for all
of the knowledge and good vibes hey
Maddie you are very welcome thank you
for the great encouraging review and the
5 star rating I truly appreciate that
I'm glad you find my show to be
comprehensive that means a lot to me
sometimes I feel like I may over talk a
certain subject but I'm really trying to
make sure you guys don't make mistakes
out there I'm trying to give you the
best advice and guidance I can I can't
make eye contact with anybody when I'm
doing this so I don't know if what I'm
saying is sinking in I can't see any
facial expressions so I'm not sure if
people look confused or if they're
catching on so I just over talk my [ __ ]
until I'm sure that everybody gets it so
I'm glad you find it comprehensive I
appreciate that
dude thanks for the great review and
thanks for the 5-star rating I'm gonna
read the next one it comes from a person
who calls themselves Deni D bat and the
headline was great podcast of course
they gave me five stars the review goes
like this great podcast and very
informative
rhasta Jeff gives detailed information
and sound advice in all growing
applications the guests are always good
- and I like it when they ramble thanks
Rasta Jeff once again Thank You Danny
I appreciate the great review I'm glad
you find it informative because like I
said I like to talk my ass off sometimes
I feel like I may be over rambling so
I'm glad you appreciate it and it's good
to hear that people say they like it
when we ramble I'm glad you find my
detailed information useful I'm glad you
don't find it overwhelming like I said I
could get to get to be and all
applications all growing applications
you know I'm not sure that I talked
enough about hydro and stuff like that
because that's not my wheelhouse but I
will try to get people in here to talk
about things are out of my comfort zone
and teach me and you all things I'm glad
you like my guests and I'm glad you like
it when we ramble because sometimes we
do take too many dabs we meaning myself
and we do get quite rambling here so I'm
glad you enjoy it thanks for the great
review and thanks for the 5-star rating
I truly do appreciate that
once again you guys I would appreciate
it if everybody who listens on iTunes
would go to the iTunes Store and just
leave a short sweet review let me know
what you think about the podcast and I
will read your review on a future
episode alright let's get into the main
topic of this podcast now the start of
the show I said that I wanted to talk a
little bit about growing with synthetic
vs. growing with organic nutrients
before I get too far into this I want to
make some disclaimers and say that I am
NOT on either side of this debate I am a
cannabis grower and I support you
growing cannabis the way that you are
passionate about doing so if you want to
grow organically if you want to grow
no-till if you want to grow with salts
in rockwool however you want to grow I
support you and I love you for growing
cannabis as long as you do so safely and
carefully and you don't apply pesticides
that are gonna make people sick as long
as you're not a corrupt piece of [ __ ] I
support you growing cannabis your way
but also being said I grow mostly from
bottled nutrients
I run a large cultivation facility where
we have lots of plants lots of lights
lots of work to be done I am well versed
in working with bottles and synthetic
nutrients on the same hand I've got a
lot of experience using organics and
growing organically but I do not have
nearly the amount of experience and
knowledge as I have with bottled and
synthetic nutrients so I may seem biased
in my debate here but I'm going to
try to play evenly on both sides so I
can keep this argument fair for both
sides but I also feel like this
shouldn't be too much of an argument
because we can all be friends we're all
growing cannabis I know some people are
haters I know some people have put a lot
of time and energy into perfecting their
technique and they feel like they've got
some hot [ __ ] going on and they feel
like they're special I'm not gonna worry
about any of that I'm not gonna play
that game right now I am going to do an
unbiased honest personal debate between
organic versus synthetics when it comes
to growing cannabis so I'm gonna press
pause I'm gonna actually take a quick
dab of this scream and tangerines before
I get into it and when I get back
synthetics versus organics round one all
right podcast world I am back with the
ever so pleasant taste of screaming
tangerines in my mouth it's like I just
bit into a tangerine delicious alright
let's talk about growing with synthetic
or organic nutrients now I said it
earlier a lot of people think that they
have some special technique mastered a
lot of people that grow organically a
lot of the guys to grow no-till a lot of
the guys that grow some fancy Korean
natural farming sort of method they seem
to be kind of sensitive when it comes to
bottled nutrients and they want to talk
trash right away because they say
growing with bottles is too easy now
sometimes a new grower may need
something easy we don't all have all day
to dedicate to growing aa bottled
nutrients are easy so that's good for a
beginner that's good for a hobby grower
it's for good for somebody who is fully
employed and has a full time job it's
good for somebody who has a little bit
of space and can't have that doesn't
have space for making extra things some
people don't have a lot of room so
bottled nutrients are good for these
types of folks bottled nutrients are
good for large facilities the bottled
nutrients can be used on all types of
grows for someone to dismiss the idea of
growing with synthetic bottled nutrients
because it is easy just seems
closed-minded and silly to me don't let
anyone on the internet discourage you
because you're trying to grow with
synthetic bottled nutrients it works
it's the most common practice in a
large-scale facility and you're not
doing anything wrong as long as you're
flushing your product at the end so yes
it may be easy but it's also reliable
bottled nutrients are reliable
and in most cases they are available so
I know that whenever I buy a bottle and
I'm just gonna pick a bottom just gonna
say what's in front of me I've got a
white jar in front of me I'm gonna say
whenever I buy white jar nutrients and
that's not even a real brand so I'm not
advertising for anybody I know that
there's a certain amount of this product
and a certain amount of this product or
a ingredient inside of that product and
every time I buy it it should be within
a certain range so that my nutrient
mixes are consistent so my product white
jar should be reliable and available
when I need it it may not be available
that may be a con to you what the bottle
that you're trying to get may not be
available in your area
jimena you may not have a gross store in
your area you may not be able to go to
the gross store so for guys like that
you may want to lean more toward the
organics if you're in a farming area
people are gonna be buying farming [ __ ]
anyway all the organic stuff is gonna be
available use that that may be the way
to go for you but I feel like the
bottled nutrients are reliable and
available and almost everyone's got
amazon available to them so I feel like
everybody should be able to get just
about any bottled product shipped to
them as long as they can find it on the
internet oh one of the pros of bottled
nutrients is feed charts are easy to
follow no matter what brand of nutrients
you were using out there you can type it
in and there will be a feed chart
available for that brand and then you
can adjust that feed chart for your
particular plant but the feed charts are
easy to follow um if you're making
organics you've got websites like build
a soil and places like that but you're
gonna have to build a soil and you're
gonna have to get all those amendments
and things shipped to you and then
you're gonna have to mix them and
hopefully you get all the mixes right
and hopefully nothing's too hot and then
once you get it mixed you're gonna have
to let it cook and it's gonna have to
sit for a little while so that's one of
the cons of working with organics is
that it's not as consistent and it's not
as reliable in my experience and in my
opinion once you get it dialed in it
will be perfect but I'm sure the getting
it dialed in will take a couple of
trials and errors now if you're brand
new and you're growing with this soil
that you just made and your plants
messing up your soil is mix and you're
gonna have a hard time figuring out
what's wrong because you're a new grower
and now you've got to figure out what's
wrong with the plant and how to fix the
soil now
if you've got a relationship with the
soil that's not as hard to do but when
you're a brand-new grower and you don't
know your plants you don't know your
soil as well this is where bottled
nutrients may be able to help you may
look at the plant and you can say [ __ ]
this is wrong you go to the internet the
internet tells you or you listen to
Rasta Jeff we figure out what's wrong
with your plants then you can get the
correct bottle and you can treat the
plants with that bottle I know that
sounds simple and that's the way some
people need it you guys that are doing
the organics you've already built that
relationship I'm sure most of you that
are doing the organics started with
bottles like a lot of us start on
bottles then we graduate up to the
organics and that's how you learn to
spot the deficiencies so that when you
mix up your soil you can see what was
wrong with the plant you can learn how
to fix it by topdressing or mix it in a
tea I also feel like a lot of you guys
grow in the organics and no tills if you
didn't start with bottled nutrients and
graduate to the organics I feel like you
started with some sort of horticultural
experience in your background and your
family is where a lot of you guys
learned it that's what I've noticed is
from paying attention so what I was
gonna get to what I was talking about is
feed charts are available that's one of
the great pros of growing with bottled
nutrients feed charts are there you can
google it you can print it out you can
post it up on the wall it's always gonna
be there feed charts are reliable ah
Grandma and Grandpa's old organics
recipes crazy old man Steve's organic
recipe Mountain Tom's recipe that shit's
gonna work if you've got that recipe if
somebody gave you that recipe on how to
grow cannabis on how to mix up things
how to prep things how to feed things as
long as somebody passed that down to you
but that's not available to everybody so
that's where bottled nutrients come in
not everybody had somebody in their
family to teach them this kind of stuff
or not everybody had it as a passion so
the bottles are good for those folks
let's see let's talk about the cost of
bottles versus organics the cost one
thing about the cost of bottle is you're
paying for water to be shipped across
the country
so let's just say if you're buying white
jar products and that company is in
California and a lot of their stuff that
they're sourcing comes from California
it's probably gonna come from
hopefully states around there but maybe
they're [ __ ] they can't get in
California maybe they have to have part
of their ingredients shipped from
Massachusetts so now you've got a pallet
of stuff being shipped from
Massachusetts to California to get
distributed
into a bunch of bottles to get mixed
with water to get back on a truck to get
shipped to a gross store in Colorado so
that you can buy it so that you can
drive it to your house so that you can
then add more water to it and then feed
it to your plants so when you buy a
bottle nutrients you're paying for
trucks to drive across the country over
and over again is kind of what I'm
getting at you're paying for people to
ship you water that kind of sucks you're
also paying for plastic bottles a lot of
your organic stuff sure some of the
organic stuff does come in bottles but a
lot of the organic stuff is being
produced by the organic grower they are
making it themselves along with their
kin of their cannabis garden so it's a
symbiotic grow they're growing the cover
crop in the pot that the cannabis is
growing in they're growing so it's all
happening in one container there's less
packaging less shipping and less less
harm to the environment but that's
something we're gonna talk about here in
a little bit
so the the difference in cost with
bottled nutrients you're paying for a
lot of water you're paying for a lot of
labels you're paying for a lot of brand
names when it comes to organic
amendments a lot of that stuff comes in
a cardboard box it doesn't have a brand
name on it a lot of it was possibly
grown by another local farmer a lot of
it was traded from farmer to farmer a
lot of it was grown like I said earlier
by the grower that is going to use it
organics is kind of cheaper because you
don't have to pay for anything to be
processed it is what it is if you're
buying bat [ __ ] you were getting bat
[ __ ] if you're buying liquid bat [ __ ]
from a nutrient company you're probably
getting bat [ __ ] and water and then
something else that they put in there so
that they could write on the label hey
there's this other cool [ __ ] in there so
organics may be a little bit cheaper but
that is probably mostly because you
don't have to pay for that advanced
nutrients or that botanic hair label on
your bottle and you don't have to pay
for as much processing of the materials
so that's a little bit on the cost let's
talk about I said the availability of
bottles and organics earlier I mentioned
that if you lived in some places like if
you live in a farming area you may not
have a hydroponic store store in your
neighborhood you may not have the hydro
warehouse or grow a warehouse for all
long distance around you may have to go
to Amazon but at that farming store at
that garden supply store or the whatever
you've got in your area you may have a
whole bunch of agricultural and
supplies available to you that you can
use to make great organic amendments I'm
sure that you can find everything that
frosty spoke about either at your local
garden supply store or if you're in that
type of area maybe one of your local
farmers has got what you're looking for
and you guys can work out something put
a few bucks in his pocket maybe return a
few buds to his pipe when you're done
you never know what you could work out
and like I said earlier everybody's got
Amazon so you can get your hands on
every nutrient that you can think of you
could probably get your hands on every
amendment you could think of somewhere
but if you're gonna grow organics you
probably want to source everything as
locally as you can but I get it that's
not always possible so let's talk about
one of the downsides to organics is the
extra prep time if you want to make some
soil if you want to make some teas
almost all of that organic stuff
especially the ferments those things all
take time you have to plan ahead so your
first grow you may be out of rhythm it
may take you a couple of grows to get
your rhythm down because your teas need
to cook for 24 or 48 hours they need to
brew your soil needs to cook for like
three to six maybe eight weeks it
depends on what you're putting in there
so all of your organic stuff is going to
take more prep more cook and more
planned time which means it's also going
to take more space so in my opinion
that's some of the cons of growing
organically also one of the things that
you don't get as much with bottled
nutrients that you do really get when
you're growing organically is some stink
a lot of the organic nutrients and a lot
of the organic amendments any of the
fermentations a lot of the compost teas
a lot of the teas you're gonna brew
they're going to smell terrible if
you've got a small house or a small
space it's gonna stink it up so it's
gonna take more time it's gonna take a
little more space and it might stink a
little bit more if you're using organics
if you're a weirdo like me you may enjoy
some of those funky ass smells and it
may be the highlight of your day
sometimes so it may take you a little
more time if you're gonna make teas and
if you're gonna make your own soils and
things like that
but if that's what you want to do that's
another thing to do if you have more
stuff if you want to be more involved in
your garden that is a great way to do it
so you
to pre-plan you organics you have to be
on top of it you have to have your if
you're going to make your own pesticides
if you're gonna make your own sprays you
have to get on top of those way before
its time to need them one of the good
things about bottled pesticides and
bottled nutrients is if you see a
problem you can walk over there and grab
that bottle and shake it up and you can
mix it and you can apply it there's no
waiting but it's also a dangerous
pesticide so it's got its pros and cons
you've got to pre-plan your organics a
little bit more than I feel like you've
got to pre-plan your synthetics also
there's that extra space for the extra
the trash can that you're brewing or the
five gallon buckets you're brewing your
teas in your jars that you're making
ferments and sometimes that makes takes
a little extra space not a whole bunch
because you'd have bottled nutrients
anyway but if you're making things like
we heard frosty say did he'd grind stuff
up real small he put some stuff in a
blender so he's already got a grinder
and a blender I don't have that in my
grow so it would be two more things that
I would have to add so there's a little
bit more extra equipment but it'll be
worth it because you don't have to ship
a bunch of bottles across the country do
you see how it's weighing out you guys
there are pros and cons to both of these
so with organics it's much easier to
reuse and recycle your soil especially
if you're going no-till so that means
less trash you guys the less stuff you
have to throw away for our environment
the better we're gonna get to that part
here pretty soon so it's a lot easier to
recondition and recycle and reuse soil
that was grown in organically especially
the no-till style you just pull a plant
out and go back right back in it but if
you try to recycle and reuse your
synthetic or your soil that was fed with
synthetic nutrients it may be too hot
there may be stuff stuck in there
hopefully yes you did flush but
sometimes that some stuff will stick in
there I wouldn't recommend regrowing
in soil that you used synthetic
nutrients in you can throw that outside
and put that in the veggie garden
outside next summer or do something like
that let it turn outside in the dirt
maybe mix it with some fresh dirt with a
bunch of organics but I wouldn't go
straight back into it it needs some love
they need some reconditioning and it may
be too hot and it may be kind of funky
from having all of those synthetic
nutrients poured through it even if he
did flush it I just don't like reusing
it I don't know I would mix it with some
fresh dirt at least but I would
recommend putting it outdoors
let the
bake all that crap out of it let the
earth do what it does to it and fix it
for you and just get some fresh dirt for
inside well let's see when you're
growing with organics it seems to be
more forgiving in my opinion you are not
pouring concentrated nutrients into your
plant so if you make a little bit of a
mistake if you over a measure or under
measure
I feel like organics gives you a lot
more leeway you're not pouring like I
said concentrated chemicals into the
root zone feeding your plant an overdose
really easily it seems like the plants
kind of know what to take and what to
absorb and what to eat a little more
when you're going organically when
you're going synthetically you're kind
of force feeding them everything is
right there
everything's buffered they suck it all
up and they can over feed themselves
very easily also it's very easy to get a
salt build-up problem with synthetic
nutrients if your pH gets off a little
bit or you start getting a salt build-up
you start getting a lock out your plants
start changing colors [ __ ] starts going
bad really quickly that's much less
likely when you're growing with organics
don't don't try to challenge me and go
crazy and feed your plants a bunch of
ridiculous organic [ __ ] because you can
cause problems with the organics I'm
just saying it's a little bit more
forgiving now since I said that I kind
of triggered myself into a whole another
rant um you guys don't be sold by the
word organic organic has become such a
buzzword lately they can print organic
on a package and put it next to a
package that doesn't say organic on it
they could be the same damn thing and I
guarantee you the one with the word
organic on it is going to sell just
because of the word organic printed on
the package um water is organic but they
don't print it on the bottles I bet if I
printed it on one bottle you would buy
that one instead I bet if I printed
gluten-free organic dairy-free sodium
free I put that [ __ ] on there and didn't
put it on the other one bottle next to
it would sell so be careful being sold
by the word organic cyanide is organic
you guys cyanide can [ __ ] kill you
and it's organic alright keep that in
mind just because people say their
plants are organic doesn't mean they're
perfectly safe it doesn't mean they're
harmless
don't be sold by buzz words and I'm not
just talking about just cannabis I'm
talking about in every product you can
soon every product you rub on your body
any product you put on your face read
organic on the label does not mean it's
all organic organic doesn't mean that a
product excuse me is specifically safer
for you actually read about let's just
pick one on this list read about
nicotine sulfate nicotine sulfate is
organic it's a neurotoxin and when they
tested it on humans it killed them but
it's organic and it's also approved in
organic farming so before you are too
mesmerized by the word organic keep in
mind that things like like cyanide and
nicotine sulfate are organic and they
can kill you all right so let's get back
on track here another thing I want to
talk about is mono ammonium phosphate a
lot of the bloom boosters that you buy
especially powdered bloom boosters
there's one in particular that I'm not
sure I want to say the name of it but it
is mostly mono ammonium phosphate that
is mostly what though the whole product
is now mono ammonium phosphate excuse me
is formed when a solution of phosphoric
acid is added to ammonia until the
solution is distinctly acidic and that
is largely used in agricultural
fertilizers that information actually
came from Wikipedia but I knew that
already is just reading it off there to
keep myself in in line oftentimes
cannabis grown with a lot of mono
ammonium phosphate has been proven to
give people a headache and have adverse
health reactions to people who already
had a compromised immune system or were
already experiencing a medical condition
so if you are growing with synthetic
nutrients check your bloom boosters and
see if you are applying mono ammonium
phosphate or dial ammonium phosphate map
and DAP are commonly used in fertilizers
but I'm starting to think they should
not be used in things we smoke so make
sure your fertilizers don't have mono
ammonium phosphate or diammonium
phosphate sand if they do maybe consider
switching bloom boosters maybe consider
switching to organics if you want to
read more about map and DAP Google Kyle
kushman and map
that fertilizers and a lot of great
articles will pop up Kyle is the one
that brought this to my attention
Kyle kushman actually grows with a
program that he calls vegan matrix and
it is vegan growing so it's organic with
no animal products although the line
that he did put out had some there was
some type of ocean creature in one of
his products but uh veganic growing you
guys no animal products at all so that
means no poop so no bat guano no seabird
guano no chicken [ __ ] no horse manure no
cow manure no poop all veganic no [ __ ]
that's his sales pitch no [ __ ] alright
so we've talked about map and dab we've
talked about veganic growing let's talk
about one thing that you organic non
bottled growers are going to have the
advantage on here's one thing that most
of us don't think about the end of the
[ __ ] world one day shit's gonna go
wrong and there will not be an
electrical grid there will not be a
gross store there will not be Amazon to
deliver your [ __ ] to your front door
if we have one thing we can still grow
if we've got the Sun and maybe just a
nice patch of dirt we can still grow
cannabis you guys so you guys are
growing organically when the end of the
world comes you guys are going to win
because there will be no growth store
there will be no feed chart there will
be no Google all you guys are going to
have the advantage then so that's that's
one of the advantages of growing
organically you guys so more of the
great benefits and advantages of growing
organically are the sustainability um us
guys growing out of bottled nutrients
we're just sucking up resources and
eventually the resources we're sucking
up are going to run out we're not able
to provide ourselves with the amounts of
products that we need because we're not
making it ourselves we're relying on a
manufacturer distributor a vendor
whatever there are several steps in our
chain it's not sustainable you guys I
don't think so in my opinion I don't
think my grow I've got a large
commercial medical growth that I am in
charge of and I do not think that I
could run it organically with my level
of experience and produce the quality
and quantity and consistency that we do
with synthetic nutrients I think on a
large scale like what I'm doing in
doors I think the bottled synthetic
nutrients are the way to go if I were in
a greenhouse or outdoors I may change my
mind on it but so far I think that the
application for indoors is a synthetic
environment I think as soon as I go
outdoors I would switch to the organics
that's my opinion on that one but when
it comes to sustainability I think you
guys doing the organics you're doing the
right thing you can make your own stuff
you can recycle your own dirt you were
using you were recycling your food waste
you were doing positive things for the
environment which is what I want to move
into next the bottled nutrient guys are
ruining the environment slowly we're
shipping bottles of water back and forth
across the country we're wasting a lot
of stuff that's not good so the
reliability for large-scale the ease for
a new grower the ease for a hobby grower
those are the things that make bottled
nutrients worth it but the long-term
environmental costs our carbon footprint
that's what would make switching to
organics worth it for me but since I run
a large scale product production
facility that is based on numbers and if
I don't produce those numbers there are
consequences I cannot take the risks of
switching to a synthetic regimen and
having to relearn everything I've got
our bottled system figured out very well
I've got it dialed in we're pulling
great lab tests we're pulling great
weights our patients are happy the
owners are happy I am happy so I
couldn't make the switch right now if we
started some [ __ ] out door I would hire
a guy like frosty or a guy like Shawn to
come fully educate me or a guy like
Jesse to come fully educate me on the
outdoor setups and then I would be a
black male a black belt outdoor grower
just like those guys so let's wrap it up
here you guys let's talk about in
summation let's talk about the pros and
cons of bottle versus synthetics I think
some of the pros of growing from organic
nutrients is the sustainability the
positive effect on the environment the
recycling that we're doing the long-term
I think that's great
between medicine I think that that is a
great thing the ability to make your own
nutrients I think that's a great thing
some of the cons of growing organically
there's a lot of extra prep work it's
gonna stink you may need more space and
it's definitely gonna take more planning
and more time
now some of the
pros of growing with bottled nutrients
they are available and they are reliable
anybody with enough time to mix up some
nutrients and read a feed chart should
be able to work a garden ran off of
bottled nutrients it is fairly easy it
is easy if you're a new grower if you're
a hobby grower if you're somebody
growing in a closet it's easier if
you're running a large scale facility
it's still fairly easy to mix up a large
amount of nutrients pH it feed it to the
plants it's reliable and it's consistent
and it is a great start it is a good way
to mix up a batch of nutrients and start
learning your plants and then if you
want to sway away from that and go
organic in the future you've got a good
foundation you've wondered about the
plants you've learned about growing and
then you can learn how to make your own
stuff and make the switch so some of the
cons of growing with bottles ah you have
to pay money to ship them you have to
dispose of a bunch of bottles that's one
of the shitty things you have to worry
gonna put them if you don't live in an
illegal state where you can grow you
have to hide those bottles when you
throw them away nobody can see your
advance nutrients Big Bud or you're
gonna get in trouble that's gonna suck
also look out for a map and dap if
you're drawing synthetically things like
that will cause you problems you have to
flush with both people think you don't
have to flush if you're growing
organically unless you're growing
no-till you're going to need some flush
time or it will affect the way your
final product burns clean out that
excess silica clean out that excess
whatever get it out of there all that
excess nitrogen get it out make your
plants burn and taste a little bit
better so let's wrap up the friendly
debate about organics versus synthetics
by saying I feel like bottled nutrients
is a great way to start if you're a new
grower start off with the bottles get a
good relationship with the plants with
the rhythms of the plant learn how to
grow learn how to get a few grows under
your belt learn how to grow learn how to
grow from seed learn how to spot males
learn how to take clones learn how to
Wally pop learned how to defoliate learn
how to crack the stems to make more
productive plants learn how to trellis
things down learn canopy control get
stuff like that dialed in become a good
grower and then once you start
understanding the plants once you start
being able to identify deficiencies and
learning things to do to increase your
yields start finding ways to dial back
the bottom
and replace those bottles with some
organics and make the switch graduate
from bottles into organics and become a
black belt that way and don't forget
when the end of the world comes you guys
you're only gonna have the bottles that
you've got and once you run out those
will be gone you're gonna have to learn
how to do it like all the farmers do
just like the organic guys all right now
let's stop being uh let's stop bickering
with each other over organics over
synthetics they all have their place
they all have their purpose
everybody can grow the way that they
want we are all cannabis soldiers we are
all cannabis growers we are a community
let's quit arguing let's quit bickering
let's raise each other up let's do it
right you guys we're bringing ourselves
out of the dark ages we don't have to
hide anymore
there's no reason to be weird there's no
reason to be sketchy we could talk about
this this is a it's actually an industry
now we don't have to be [ __ ] we
don't have to act like we're artists
doing some secretive [ __ ] you're not
your girl cannabis it's a [ __ ] plant
you guys can all learn as much as I do
about as I know about cannabis just by
reading and studying and doing it that's
all you have to do so let's not be dicks
to each other let's not act like we're
all the Wizard of Oz or something
because we're not we're growing plants
nature was doing it long before you got
involved in nature had it [ __ ]
mastered you're just you're just
facilitating you're just giving it a
little place to do it and you're kind of
getting in the way so stop acting like
you're a Jedi stop acting like you're a
ninja we're all just pot growers playing
with some plants all right so we're all
one now the no-till guys the bottle guys
the commercial guys the closet guys the
seed breeders the pollen chuckers the
guys that kill plants the brown thumbs
the green thumbs the guys that can't
figure out how to water clones to save
their lives the guys that can't cure bud
to save their lives the guys at cure bud
like a Jedi the guys that cut clones
just by looking at them
we're all equal because we're all
cannabis growers and we're all coming
out of the dark ages to the green ages
together so let's be equal all right no
more bitching ladies and gentlemen I
feel like that screamin tangerine dab
put me on our rant thank you for
listening I really enjoyed doing this
episode of this podcast I feel like this
is one of the better episodes I've done
I had a lot of fun I would like to know
what you think about this episode ah you
can find me on Facebook send me a
message there look for the girl from
your heart podcast you can tweet me at G
fyh podcast or you can find me on
Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics I RIE
underscore genetics or if you're not
into the social media stuff you can
always send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and of course
I would love and iTunes rating and
review ladies and gentlemen I've got
almost a hundred and thirty videos
posted up to YouTube so make sure you
check out the YouTube channel go to
youtube and search for the girl from
your heart podcast also I want to remind
everybody about patreon if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
and you'd like to contribute to my
patreon campaign all you have to do is
go to patreon.com/scishow to the podcast
I would greatly appreciate it all the
information that you need is there by
signing up to contribute to the podcast
what you do is help me pay for my
website which is where I host the
podcast you help me buy things like
these little microphone covers you help
me buy bottled water for when Mike comes
over big shout out to bagsied Jessi by
the way I hope back see Jessi a shout
out he contributed some some funds for
some bottled waters and such big thanks
for that but you guys if you do
contribute to patreon that's what I will
use the money for I'll buy a new
microphone covers and another microphone
stand the one for one of our guests is
getting a little limp I'll get a little
viagra for that microphone stand so it
stands up I also pay for the web hosting
I think I already said that but if
anything goes wrong with the technical
gear your patreon contributions are used
to replace the equipment and keep the
equipment updated I pays for my Wi-Fi
stuff like that it just helps me out so
I do appreciate it if you'd like to
contribute patreon.com slash girl from
your heart also big thank you to
everybody who's been contributing to
patreon a lot of people started off
sending me one dollar a lot of those
folks have upgraded their subscription
to a four dollar and 20 cent
contribution every month I want to make
sure you guys know that I noticed that
and i truly appreciate it so thank you
for all of the patreon support also
don't forget to support the hell a dank
seed bank make sure you guys check out
dank seed dot store and send them your
support let them know that you listen to
the girl from your heart podcast I want
to thank everybody for listening to this
episode I look forward to all of the
interaction I'll be back Thursday with
the long throwback thursday episode and
then of course i'll be back Monday with
the fresh new episode I want to give a
huge shout out to my friends in the
Colorado raiga unit for letting me sit
in with them
we can and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]