[Music]
ocean Rasta Jeff in the house
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
joining me as always my friends in the
mystic music podcast the traveling
stoner welcome Lindsay thank you
directly in front of me is the man the
myth the legend mr. Bobo Blaster thanks
for joining us bro thank you for having
me dude how was Portugal it was amazing
Portuguese drugs I did not I did not I
actually finally got a spur turning down
the music I wish you guys could see the
look of disappointment in my face
Portugal everything and I was like
[Music]
didn't try any Portuguese drugs hot in
Florida with you yes yes my for Layla
Layla beautiful dog welcome home thank
thank you taps tabs to my left my 9
o'clock ish position you guys you know
who he is it's the bramble king Mike is
back on the show enough sometimes I've
had too much caffeine I think we're
doing alright so this good [ __ ] show
welcome everybody we're gonna settle in
and do a podcast the main beef of this
podcast the main heart and soul is going
to be somebody sent me an email they
wanted to know since aren't a lot of our
friends who are working dispensaries and
I've been in dispensary environment for
the past several years we got a question
they want to know about what's the
craziest [ __ ] we have ever seen in a
dispensary or to smoke event but before
we get to that I want to do a couple of
emails let's do let's do Kip's first
because his name is Kip and that's cool
as [ __ ] I've never met anybody in person
whose name was Kip I don't think your
name is Kip he's got cool parents Kip
shoutout to Kip ah I found Kip on
Facebook you sent me a message it says I
have some plants that I need that I had
a friend take care of during a trip and
even though an average he's a decent
grower he put my 10 inch plants with his
that were a few feet high and didn't
raise him up and they were severely
stretched almost 8 inches between notes
he said on average I'd waste him and
start a new stock but I'm currently out
of seeds and clones due to the trip and
I don't have any good candidates for
clones other than the tops of the plants
there's your answer right there bro he
goes on to say if it wasn't the last of
the genetics I had I'd waste them or
pull the tops and clone it but I'm
wondering if you had any quick ways to
maybe get a plant to put out some shoots
so I have something to clip by the
corner I'm running 600 watt HBS at the
time age-old newts in dirt I usually use
nectar the gods but I can't see spending
a fortune to raise these plants any help
would be appreciated
uh you can put them into bigger pots and
top them and they'll start shooting out
more shoots give them a high phosphorous
diet with a lot of nitrogen and
phosphorous they'll spit out more shoots
there's a product called Bushmaster
that'll make them shoot out more shoots
put them into bigger pots feed them a
good diet and they'll shoot out more
shoots even plenty of white give them
plenty of space
top them do some topping and pinching
techniques but your main answer to your
question is what's left
the tops of those plants clone those bro
Kono's right away get those healthy tops
cloned in the cloner labeled get them
routed and then take really good care of
those new clothes that's the solution
for that Kip I appreciate the message on
Facebook if you have any more questions
please send them to me on Facebook or
hit me up it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I will read your
messages on the show all right I'm
searching for an email I've got one more
email about these folks have seen some
interesting he says one Rasta Jeff first
off I love the podcast I burned through
all the episodes on stitcher and about a
week and I have to wait painfully from
week to week for each new episode I
think yeah if you go to my website I
read genetics Colorado comm there are
100 episodes available on there for you
the last hundred episodes are up there
if you want more episodes
other than that send me an email and I
will consider sending you files of the
[ __ ] that's not up there I do need to
post some of the older stuff there's
some stuff it was really useful that is
phased out like a couple of episodes
were really so those early episodes had
a lot of heavy girl information I may go
throw some of those out like midweek
episodes just as bonus repeats again
alright but anyway he says I found that
what it lets see being from an illegal
state of Pennsylvania I cannot take your
advice in the literal sense due to
legalities however I have found that
what is good for the cannabis plant is
also good for some vegetable plants
adding organic nutrients such as compost
teas and trimming techniques like wall-e
popping have done wonders for my
tomatoes and hot peppers keep up the
good work I'm glad that's applicable to
your outdoor veggie her that's
he goes on to say I was I also welcome
the great advice from white Mike on the
legal side of things recently in
Pennsylvania the Senate House
unanimously passed a bill allowing for
restricted hemp production for
university research it's currently
awaiting the final signature from
Governor Tom wolf Tom wolf yes I know we
are miles behind Colorado but I guess we
need to start somewhere it continues
with my wife and I will have the
pleasure of visiting your fine state
next week that'll probably be by the
time this podcast airs emailing before
that but he says we are overjoyed if it
counting down for weeks we will of
course be flying into Denver into the
Denver area and beginning our venture
adventure from there my first question
is do you have any recommendations for
recreational dispensaries in the Denver
region we want to make sure we establish
a reputable place with products that are
grown from the heart then a second
question is do you think you could do an
episode on how to troubleshoot and solve
different signs of nutrient burn and/or
nutrient deficiencies if you have a
potassium deficiency you would see these
signs as opposed to nitrogen deficiency
etc I think that would make a great
informative episode bro that episode is
gonna happen watch a screenshot of your
remember it's a really good idea he says
anyway before I keep rambling don't
worry but oh we like it when you ramble
I just want to say you are a you are
very good at your career and give great
advice if you are if you ever have any
photography questions don't hesitate to
hit me up it would be awesome to someday
meet you and do some dabs but until then
give my mom a hug for you best of luck
and then he says you can just call me
fats if you decide to read this on the
air well thanks fats I will edit your
name out the thanks girl we appreciate
that he had two questions for you guys
he asked about a dispensary a
recreational dispensary recommendation
in the Denver area I unfortunately have
no clue where to tell you to go because
I don't buy recreational cannabis I grow
and then I'm a master grower at a shop
or I just go there and pick up flowers
on that employee discount smoke those
does anybody in the room have a
recommendation for a reputable
dispensary in the Denver area
[Music]
my favorite places to send people the
clinic has a rec side the clinic is a
great place in my opinion flowers are
always quality anything in the room
listening they say natty REMS I was just
gonna say that
so did natty rims that's funny I would
say the only thing I can really
recommend is places I've been I've been
into natty rims and it's actually a very
nice bit take green solutions I would
say fly into Denver get to your hotel
get on your phone download the weed Maps
app just look what's near your hotel and
then read reviews for a few of those
places and don't hit just one place go
to a couple places I check them out get
the experience because every place is
going to have a different vibe of some
sort there's gonna be different music
like if the spot the music is loud it's
reggae in-your-face as soon as you get
there it's a party sales the environment
they want you to buy buy buy things are
set up to where it's like impulse buy is
right where you need them and it's got
that kind of flow to it green and
healthy on the other hand I know the
owner he wanted to set up more with the
art gallery sort of a feel and it does
have that sort of a feel it's more
spread out it's more spacious there's
artwork everywhere and so every
dispensary and the quality of product
from the two shops is amazingly [ __ ]
different different to I mean every
shops gonna have its own vibe its own
selection its own way of doing things
and especially if you're from
Pennsylvania it's worth hitting several
just to check out the different ones
you're also gonna want to make time to
hit illusions glass gallery downtown
shout out to white Mike yeah you're
definitely not - yeah it's somewhere
you're gonna want to stop this just
makes make sure it's part of your trip
and be careful smoking in your hotel you
may think that because you're in
Colorado now we can smoke out the hotel
negative make sure that you've got a
marijuana friendly room and
worried about calling and asking the
hotel just call it from your phone and
pretend like you're lost or coming next
week and want to know what their policy
is they'll be happy to explain it to you
in your room or do something like that
I would highly recommend looking into
things like the smoke buddy and the like
scented candles from smoke shops the
ones that are actually yeah off the
smoke alarm they will charge you the 250
or 500 are cleaning for you depending on
how boozy the hotel is charge you for
that [ __ ] kinetic products is what they
are on Instagram their website to order
stuff will be up and running on the 25th
of this month so and I don't actually
have the exact website for that yet but
you can check them out on Instagram at
kinetic products and they have a wax pen
that has a quartz coil in it for a
little kinetic force because I think
when you see kinetic I see with a K but
it's the Colorado right it's see a
[Music]
little bit all right so let's get back
on track Kip your second question first
question was dispensary recommendations
second question yes I'm gonna do that
make an episode on troubleshooting and
solving problems that's a really good
idea I've actually got a written down
it's gonna be a really in-depth one of
those long episodes I've got to write
out and really plan well there's a lot
of stuff to think about I've got to find
a starting point I think the starting
point is printing out that chart that
shows you all the leaves with the
microphone thank you like a bad kid
[ __ ] out of it all right so uh what am I
supposed to call you fats fats dude
thanks for sending us an email when
you're in Denver contact me bro let me
know message me somehow be like I am
about to land in Denver I'm a busy man
honestly and Denver is 125 miles from my
house 60 miles from my work but you
never know
[Music]
either way bro send me a message let me
know that you're coming email me just
like you did and let me know a little
more accurate your details this episode
will probably come out by the time your
trip already happened but I'm gonna
message you talking about you your trip
that already happened to us it's in the
future to you it's in the past all right
so I teased this part of the show we
want to talk about the craziest [ __ ] we
have ever seen in a dispensary or at a
smokey event or any cannabis cup or at
the dab lounge some crazy [ __ ]
taking a drink so no first Mike Mike and
I ran let's give you a little background
story Mike and I ran the first and only
dispensary in city limits in Pueblo
Colorado and this dispensary was located
right in the middle of the city yep the
east side of our town is [ __ ] there's a
lot of face tattoos there's a lot of
pocket knives there's a lot of youse
guyses
it's not it's not the prettiest place to
go so all those people came and then all
parts of Caro this was back in the
purely medical days it was just anybody
who had or wanted I'm medical marijuana
card there would be we had probably ten
seats inside the place and there would
be people in every chair and then
standing outside waiting to come in
still and there was a receptionist and
myself as a budtender and then I hired
Mike as a backup but tender because I
couldn't get through everybody's there
and then my second week we hire
the security guard now if you're
thinking about opening you can just go
to your favorites there wasn't even that
the boss would pay me to drive to Denver
on the if I was going to a concert maybe
like here's some money stop at a couple
dispensaries pick up some advertisements
and some product and see what they got
and he just throw me money to go do
recon work and come back and kind of
adjust our [ __ ] to be a little bit
better every time we went crazy old dude
so Mike and I ran the first place and I
had some [ __ ] crazy experiences in
that place I wrote down just just to
give you a tease of my list
threats plants gun chat trades and gifts
[Music]
gifts older lady kind of looked like
maybe a 55 65 year old it's normal
transaction nothing surprising or
interesting about it and so right at the
edge she's like you two are sweet here
check this out she reaches into her
purse and pulls out this little plastic
bag with this plant it looked like old
bubblegum in Pocket lint like it was
black and in like stringy I guess is how
I would describe it she's like you're
some opening for me I hope you enjoy it
like that folded up in a cellophane
[Music]
that place was bizarre that my favorite
people there were the the kids coming
there to sell so we just wander and Tara
was the terrified look on their face
with a little messenger bag that they
were kind of hugging to their side just
terrified because this was in the
beginning when like you could have as
much marijuana as you had medical cards
for but it was still four hundred and
outs like in the story and so they're
hauling around a lot more money than
they're comfortable with on their hip
and as far as most people are concerned
that's a major crime just wanted into a
store to try and sell it like it's a
weird experience I'm sure well we can
meet a lot of friends from those folks
yeah I would offer those guys eight
hundred quarter pound or thirty two
hundred pound - take it or leave it
you could get nine hundred out of me if
it was really really good but a lot of
those people will just look at me like
they wanted so much more for that back
then now herb is now wholesale
commercial herb is about two thousand
dollars a pound
you can find it if you're looking for
like some house nor commercial like
wreck we'd like some we've gotten way
cheaper what's when your [ __ ]
craziest memories you have from met amar
there's so many bizarre ones YouTube
falling down the stairs
it's the edibles one of the managers
owners would make they were all homemade
they were all delicious and they were
all insanely potent and she was sweet
and she would kind of insist that you
eat like one of everything when she'd
bring in a new batch and so by like
middle midday or lunch you'd be like -
hi - form words sometimes and now
watching a co-worker tumble down a
switchback stare and then land like it's
sprawled out face-first in front of a
lobby full of customers and then they
just pop up they're like who's next down
the stairs hauling all the plants out of
there do you remember that yeah we have
an RV or was it the RV time u-haul truck
when we got shut down
that was just you have to stop and we
were like okay we'll stop then but we've
got the [ __ ] in the store where we do
with it
and basically all of the plants that
were in the grow were just if you want
them hauler and so for like half a day
from like noon to midnight randomly
people would pull up out back walk
around knock on the door come inside
we'd pick out the half dozen or dozen or
whatever plants they had paperwork for
and wanted they had they bail it was one
of the most Ranger experiences of my
life but it was a lot of fun to be like
at one point there was a u-haul and the
dude had was a caregiver for like 11
people and so we sat there and went
through his paperwork for like 20
minutes double-check and everything and
then loaded [ __ ] you don't even know by
the time we got that back of that u-haul
loaded I was sweating so bad a lot of
plants around at that place removed
plants around recently I had a dude show
up he's just in bed maybe 350 pounds
maybe 45 years old the like life's been
rough so this is a new place
um he comes walking up to the door and
our a security guards like uh-huh but
like halfway to that door we noticed
that like there's a good wobble to his
walk too so he gets the front door he's
like does the lead star in the security
guards like no sir you can't come in
it's like why not like well hey you're
barefoot B you're not wearing a shirt
you're topless let's see you're drunk
like sir you have to leave he's like nah
this is the weed store and he like goes
to push past my arm security guard it's
the security guy blacks his way just
like sir you really can't come into
you're barefoot you're not wearing a
shirt just like sure like that doesn't
mean we're gonna let you into our
dispensary
yeah there's that's just random stuff
that's popping in my mind right now I've
taken some dabs I know there's stranger
[ __ ] I just keep seeing you follow in
those stairs what time I sitting at met
amar and the reason I mentioned the
thugs that used to come in there was a
bunch of normal people and then like a
group like four or five youngster
gangster kind of kids and they were all
talking about their gun collections and
I can see the white folk just like just
cringing just like we're all gonna
[ __ ] die in here I can see all their
faces that was one of the funniest
[ __ ] things I remember bro you're not
you don't wear uh Chris you don't work
in a dispensary but I'm sure you've seen
some wack-ass [ __ ] some wire to smoke
club or to spend three yeah people just
see the crazy [ __ ] inside of Spencer
it's like people think just because it's
legal they can just say whatever the
hell they want right like this isn't a
law free zone like it's just we have
legal weed stores yeah like when you go
in with your friends and then your
friend passes you all the money you say
yeah I got you don't worry about it
you can't do that
No you have to leave I had some guy come
in the other day and he was like buying
an ounce of flour and he was he says
something about it was for somebody else
and I was like no this is for you you
know like you you can't say that in here
like this is your one warning you know
and he was like well it's not a big deal
on gifting him this bud so I'm allowed
to do that and I was like no no you're
not allowed to take your medical card
anybody's birthday go and there's
different rules for rec and medical and
when you're in a medical shop you have
to play by the height of the medical
rules is is legally it's essentially
your your to pharmacy and the pharmacist
is like here's your pills you know like
cool I'm gonna give my cousin Billy to
the pharmacist [ __ ] you and your clothes
like you ain't getting these don't call
the cops you actually sign a member a
three minute green and healthy walnuts
that says in bold letters I will not
redistribute this medicine to anybody
else and so that's what our main concern
there is that you're not going nobody
needs to get that medicine from you if
they need that medicine they have the
means to get that product legally
themselves we don't need to be a you
don't need a middleman for them we don't
need to know about that if once you take
that cannabis home and take it out of
the black package that we've sold it to
you in and some time passes we don't
know what happens after that and we
can't care but don't tell us about it
and take it out of our [ __ ] packaging
no matter what you do with it that was
now it's your cannabis all right then
whatever can happen you can you can give
to your cannabis to people all right go
for it
[Music]
well hang around this motion people just
thought it was a dispensary just the
obvious thing - you know what you know
it's actually really odd that really
doesn't have anything to do with weed I
was working in the smoke shop one day it
was a Saturday and me and my manager
were both on the floor and I had some
guy I was showing him some hand pipe and
I was I guess I should explain that I
don't have hair on the sides of my head
like I have besides my head shaved and I
was like I had my head down and I was
like pulling out a pipe to show him and
he reaches across the counter and he
takes his hand and he runs it across the
side of my head please don't touch me
like I didn't think that I had to make
this guy it's similar lines this guy
used to come in and he was kind of a
nightmarish customer like you did not
typically have a pleasant smell to him
he was typically dressed in and like
took too much acid went to good
[Music]
what do you had a car that didn't match
his wardrobe and odor it was like a
better kept up like early 2000s like
Corvette I think and he shop in any and
he buys like six dollars worth of
something or whatever not a lot of the
money worth of flour in his my
co-workers stapling his bag shut he goes
I just got new carpet in my trunk and
the two girls I'm working with it like
what an odd thing to say just kind of
look at him and they're like oh
interesting and he goes you two want to
come outside and smell it and there were
like three heartbeats were all three of
us that worked at night like he just
[ __ ] since he said smell it not look
at night he said smell and wit just so
smooth Jess goes no sir were actually
we're not allowed to leave the store
until after closing
it's rule just smooth as anything I have
believed it when she said it was she
ever a stripper that's like a stripper
line I have no idea would you go out to
someone's car look at someone's new
carpet in their trunk you obviously just
killed somebody and threw them in the
trunk and got your carpet redone back
there and now you want me to go out
there and look you can't even see the
spots anymore
Jesus yeah that one stands way out oh
that's terrible
you remember when people used to bring
plants into met amar that had problems
they breathe yes he brought a big old
plant and a [ __ ] like a Walmart bag
in a pot and a potted plant with leaves
just sticking out he carries it in the
opens up it's all coated in powdery
mildew he's like what is this I was like
get the [ __ ] out here bro we got plants
and told him what it was that's rude
that's only solvable by fire I remember
you like just kind of mumbling under
your breath like [ __ ] dude now I'm gonna
have to shower like three times before I
[Music]
because just one full after another had
brought in a potted plant with like a
paper trash bag like gently set over the
little stand-up support sticks so that
they could kind of hide what they were
what kind of plant they were carrying in
public view as they brought it into the
dispensary to try to get us to diagnose
it [ __ ] people open it up [ __ ] with
spider mites on it with clones and [ __ ]
we sold clones in cups and you could buy
if your plank count was 140 140 pounds
we didn't give a [ __ ] back in the day
and people would leave with just trays
of clones in their hands like 6-inch
tall plants and cups just carrying them
out to the car we didn't care at all I
remember one guy coming back like two or
three days in a row maybe six trips
total and buying like two clones at a
time and when I asked him like what the
hell's going on and he was he goes
I keep setting them out back so they get
used to the light in the birds keep
beating oh and I flicked your clothes
like seven and eight like come up with a
plan bro get a shotgun like get some
chicken wire put them inside speaking of
bringing things into the dispensary I'm
friends with the person so I'm not gonna
say where any of that but somebody came
into a place that I work and brought in
a product that they wanted us to look at
and the entire dome on the pen was just
like this color you know like you know
the like dome open globe could not even
see it and I was just like you can't
have that right vaporizers out of their
pocket left right I've got a weird bag
of returned ones that we've got like
receipts in like as much documentation
as we can because we send them back to
the company for replacement units but
half of them are like burnout and a tiny
bit dirty and so we keep epic records on
all of that [ __ ] so that there's no but
that's a daily occurrence people pulling
[ __ ] like that out of their pocket Mike
at the place you work be careful how I
ask this you get a prize for wearing a
small shirt sometimes that's some of the
random [ __ ] that I've seen happen at
that place crazy
I mean sometimes we'll see today in
weird things happen when it's that crazy
in the summer if you shop at Mike's
dispensary and you're in like a bikini
there's a good chance you'll get some
gifts yeah it's funny when you watch all
the dudes there all right so I'm gonna
tell a ridiculous story that happened to
be one time when I worked at our
dispensary that's probably be the last
one
crazy stories for this episode because
it thank you for listening so one day I
was working at work at the dispensary
selling goodall weed and it was myself
and my receptionist is I guess what she
would officially be her name was tree
she probably weighed 90 pounds and was
afraid of the wind she was and so one
day a normal customer there were regular
customers that would come in there was a
lady she wasn't even a lady I'm not
gonna call her lady because of what she
did she was a female she was large
female and her husband was a dude who
was about equal size with me and they
would come in often and I knew who they
were and one day she came in early in
the morning and said how much is an
ounce and I told her in ounces this much
at the time at that dispensary an ounce
was three hundred and twenty dollars and
she said if I come up with three will
you do it since she was a regular
customer I said don't tell anybody hook
you up for 300 bucks does like you send
your old man in later I'll do it for
three for him also because I got a baby
and they switch shifts and I just know
how that should work so she comes back
later and she's got like 200 I don't
even remember how it goes and she comes
in like way later we're about to close
and she comes back in and she's like hey
sell me an ounce for like 250 or
whatever and I was like I can't do it
I'll do it for three any lesson that'll
get in trouble and she's like begging
and I'm like I can't do it just like let
me go out to the car and see what I can
come up with she goes out to the car and
they're out there for a few minutes and
I asked riyals like what's going on cuz
sure you can see the window and see
their car she's like they're kind of
yelling each other they'll be back in in
a minute and I was like cool give him a
second so he came in and she's like I
need to see your paperwork you have to
check in every time you come in and he's
like nah [ __ ] that I want to talk to
that [ __ ] and I was like oh
something's about to go on and I know
it's me that he wanted to talk to he
pushes past her it comes back to the bud
room where I am because we got the bud
room in the back of the building so we
get privacy and he's like [ __ ]
you told my wife that if she sucks your
dick you'd give her an ounce for 200
bucks and I was like bro I'm not
interested in your wife it's not my weed
I couldn't give her that anyway and I'd
never [ __ ] say that to your wife you
guys are regulars here I know who you
are why the [ __ ] would I do that and
honestly I'm not even trying to be rude
she was not attractive she
was way way not in my weight class I
know thanks
so I was like what why would anybody
want her to suck their dick and so he's
going off on me dude he's like I'm gonna
[ __ ] you up and he's kind of a big dude
he's my size like I'm [ __ ] six five
he had to be at least six three or
something he's straight in my eye he's
on the other side of the counter he kept
hitting the counter and the counters
glass like he's gonna break this counter
I gotta [ __ ] figure this out quick
entry kept asking do you want me to call
the cops do you want me to call the cops
and I'm like no I don't want the cops at
the dispensary you know I mean that's
like the last thing I don't want to
bring back to this business already and
so I've got mace and I've got some
scissors Within Reach like right within
reach I was about to go down and he's
like you [ __ ] you told my wife
they'd if you sold her an ounce were you
torn out if she sucked your dick and and
then tree starts yelling I was right
[ __ ] here all that's between tree and
I and the office in the bud room is a
tapestry honestly that's all it was a
black tapestry and she's like I was
right here he didn't [ __ ] say any of
that she's like I can hear everything
he's like [ __ ] you and finally when he
turned his head I grabbed the mace and
the scissors I got the mace with my
right hand in the scissors with my left
hand and by now his girlfriend came in
too and was backing him up and left they
left the baby in the car and so I told
him bro you're kind of threatening me
and I'm not sure what to do about it so
I'm gonna [ __ ] mace you then I'm
gonna stab you and then I'm gonna mace
your [ __ ] wife and then I'm gonna
call the cops if you guys and tree
looked at me like wow peaceful dude that
grows weed and smoke weed and sees me
about to spray some dude in his face
stab him with [ __ ] trimmed scissors
and then go after his girl with the mace
I think the only thing that saved me
from fighting was when I told him I'm
gonna spray you stab you and then I'm
gonna spray your girlfriend she looked
at him like umm I don't want to get
maced baby there's an ID ain't workin no
mo like that's when it all kind of
started that [ __ ] cool down but he's
like [ __ ] you I know where you work and
I'll find you
I thought dude yeah why I was like bro I
can't be here by myself with [ __ ]
twenty pounds of weed at that point I
mean we were brand-new and we were
getting like two calls a month from
people that would say like random
horrible [ __ ] into the phone because we
were stealing their business yeah and
they didn't like the idea of a
dispensary it sound like we should add a
security good loan for that yeah and
then the security guard we got was
pretty funny yeah one day I was driving
down northern Avenue one of the main
streets here in Puebla and uh I see the
security guard we're both going to my
tomorrow to work I'm the budtender he's
[Music]
and he pulls up next to me he goes damn
ese that smells good I was smoking a big
old fat ass joint on my way to work roll
down your window and he rolled down his
window all the way and I was in the
right lane he was in the left lane
he put his hand out and I threw that
[ __ ] joint from my car into his
passenger window directly into his hand
he caught that [ __ ] and didn't have to
make adjustments I just hit it together
beautiful all right you guys I told my
craziest story that I can think of what
so we didn't cover events really my
friend Katrina took she took a DAB and
she looked at me she was I'm so hung and
just fell the [ __ ] over dude I caught
her but we stayed in a really swanky
hotel the night before and they had free
lotion and she herself up in all the
damn lotion she used it all so I tried
to catch her and it was trying to like
trying to catch like three times and I
finally got her all awkward and then
Toni was with me and I go Toni just pick
her up and put her on my shoulders bro
because I was holding her just like
she's like a wet noodle so he spun her
around and threw up on my shoulders now
I got her and I spun her around I told
him pour this water in her face it just
gave him water and he was like pouring
water into her mouth and she started
drinking it and woke up
that's pretty funny she's all pale and
[ __ ] for the rest of the baby defeat her
twice this dude from Texas one time I
took a fat dab a fat fat dab at the
Cannabis Cup the first one that they did
at the new location what's a new place
Denver mark from Texas so what y'all
doing right there it's like it's dad I
tried to give him a little dab and I've
told this story on the podcast before I
tried to give him a little dab and he's
like nah I saw you do what I want big
one like you did and I was like I don't
think you want to do your first dad like
Rasta Jeff sighs dad he's like give me
demo dab dab and by the time the last of
the smoke hit his lungs I'm pretty sure
part of the dad came out of that came
out of his mouth my friend lovely work
with the cascade shatter should show
since it's also the [ __ ] out oh my god
the Terps for a couple few episodes
they're still around sorry I'm wiggling
my head funny my hat is pulling my dread
I need to fix that it's not a large
container but the last for these Terps
are amazing did you guys get to try the
lemon gene
[Music]
you can have to lick the bottle if you
want to taste ride the ghost with the
lemon gee I've heard about but haven't
tried the ghost was wonderful we're
talking about ways to use it earlier I
really like pouring the OG Kush Terps on
to solvent less hash like the 120 micron
drip cream or blue sure - yeah just
press out this ones press right here
there's like a little patty just just
pour a little drip on there it's pretty
it's pretty thick the Terps are pretty
thick and kind of viscous so you got a
poor quickly or it'll run down the side
of the bottle you don't learn to get the
angle going but I really love parted on
the [ __ ] solvent list I poured some
onto just a little piece of shatter the
other day and so that I had a whole
piece of shatter with some money and of
course I'm dripped onto the oil slick so
I was dipping it up using shatter and
solvent listen whatever I was smoking
just rubbing it in on the oil slick my
favorite way honestly is to get a small
ish dad and then just dunk it right into
the Terps and don't even go too hard
just a little bit of Terps they just
smoke it that way I actually dropped a
little bit of the ghost train haze Terps
directly onto the email head made it
like the next five or six or eight dabs
to steel chirpy he didn't last as long
as I had hoped for lens you work at the
store where we're selling this medically
what are these going for for a quarter
of a gram now do you remember sixty
think you're right I think there's sixty
bucks a quarter gram sixty-five for
non-members just be a member I don't
know what you're thinking you can get
the blue shirt if you get the cream I
know I grew all that [ __ ] amazing you
get the Terps if you're a wreck shopper
you can get the Terps at natty Rams
called before you drive because I don't
know what they've got you guys wouldn't
this episode comes out they can be
cleaned out they could laugh at you that
was a few weeks ago good [ __ ] luck to
the evil lab crew because we've seen a
lot of really cool cannabis products
come out in the past a year past two
years past or whatever and this one
might be my favorite the Terps this
might be the newest greatest thing to
come out in cannabis what do you think
Mike
there's been some stuff recently that's
been impressive but this kind of took it
to another a new place a very fun new
place a very connoisseur level I like
getting I do like playing with the
distillate I like taking the distillate
the just rock dis delicious 91% THC and
eat a little tiny dab of that and I like
to dip it into the OG Kush and then
maybe put it in the lemon G after that
then maybe revel on the coast rain hey
is gonna see what the different mixtures
do but honestly that got old quickly it
was fun a few times like it was like
mixing jelly bellies I I've been having
some fun mixed in random hashes they
plan with the different flavor profiles
for tacos looking down this table folks
and there's like 12 different varieties
of hash the street of Oz delicious
distracting it's a delicious table it is
I've got this beautiful if you smoked
that whole thing you made these 10 mic
dabs on that little pancake which is
funny because that's like a quarter Jeff
dab I put a drop of OG Kush strips on it
that'd be one Phil you started talking
about Dripping this wonderful podcast
furniture table make sure you guys check
furniture
alright so Burnaby cartel custom table
yes he's a bad mofo contacting for
custom are whole bunch of email
furniture definitely go check out the
site how long ago did you hook me up
with that email table it's been a while
now it's
over the year yeah easily and it works
it still works the coils are still good
the workhorse because I've used a couple
of coils on this unit here more like a
microphone you guys for binding email
get the one with the coil that looks
like a microphone cable not the one yeah
right yeah I remember when you were
making that table in Florida like I
remember you and I try to figure out how
you are going to paint it and you doing
the tape on the top yeah and the tape
when you pulled it off or whatever and
that's the reason you painted it because
you originally we're gonna do something
[Music]
that's right and then when you put when
you put the tape down you pull the
[Music]
unboxing video on periscope and we
watched it when I was it I was like well
Jeff just got it
the video may be on YouTube I'm not sure
I can't promise May 23rd I think it was
in May I don't care what day was that
day I ate a whole bunch and then
somebody gave me a thousand milligram
Anibal at that eBay and I ate that the
next day yeah I actually ended up
getting when it does I'm mad because I'm
wanting to like eat a thousand and I
didn't cuz she surprised I finally got
you one that you've we've been like
talking about forever what is this idiot
do he opens it he's like oh sweet grabs
the grabs it from me opens it up breaks
off two of them throws it in his mouth
immediately right now I can't right now
I did I would not have ankle weights on
your brain my teeth were sticking
together really I was eating while I was
driving so I was held in their hands
[Music]
half of shatter in each bar this is not
100 percent THC this is probably in the
high 80s so they threw a gram and a half
in there they couldn't be tested by the
media they could maybe be products these
are just somebody's days when anyone
could have used lab testing we only had
those days for about two and a half
three months chunk of time big shout it
to the end the end there I totally wish
I could remember the chemist named the
scientist that I met when I know his
name it's right on the tip of my tongue
damn it as soon as we recording I'm
gonna yell his name out loud you really
taught me a lot of stuff steep hill was
the first group I mean way back at the
the first kush con they had like the
saddest little booth at the show with
the coolest information pack they were
the first people I really saw breaking
down cannabis testing past THC they were
advertising pesticides heavy metals like
12 different cannabinoids at that point
um and I just it was one of those things
where you saw oh that that's where the
industry's gonna go this is gonna open
up all new avenues in sure [ __ ]
potency jumped 20% quality went up I
mean an incalculable amount right after
the lab showed up shout out to Johnny
trill and trill Gardens they have their
[ __ ] tested zero traces of any
pesticides and all
[Music]
actually I've been highly into edibles
lately ever since I went to Florida I
over roasted myself with them when I
want to see Deadpool and I've been going
real licensed
I probably eat a whole bunch of edibles
again at the next secret session before
then no spot cast will not be out by the
time secret sesh happens to follow the
instructions of check out underscore Co
on Instagram if you ever want to come
join us the instructions will be posted
there follow the instructions if you
[ __ ] it up
you won't get to go it's just a simple
email you gotta follow the instructions
a lot of people do something stupid just
gonna do this properly and you will get
in alright quiet I can tell you've just
obscene things people I've said and done
but you know like when people
ridiculously blatantly just flirt with
you yeah there's there's that there's um
when I was working in the smoke trap I
had someone come come in and be like oh
are you the trap Queen what is my boy
sloppy for making a really great joke of
a dispensary the other day we're not
gonna repeat any of that we all go there
but now that's [ __ ] golden shout out
slap I hope you listen to this podcast I
heard what you said
[Music]
shut up for killing it out there on the
mountain bro you said you were gonna do
something a [ __ ] you were doing
it yeah
proud of you oh he was a youngster when
he moved here and right when he like
first moved here no idea but the font
wins it made me a Chewbacca torch
everybody hears dad the [ __ ] out
somebody dabble I start talking and
rambling so we can hear people cough I
do have some of the lemon G root boy it
is in this pile we just got to dig
through these piles follow all of my
friends on social media Mike is at Nemo
punk 15 on Twitter make sure you follow
Bobo blaster Co on Instagram Instagram
and of course make sure you follow
myself it's at I understand that excite
Instagram you guys if you've got a
product you'd like all of us here at the
table to review send me an email it's
girl from your heart at hotmail.com
if you want to sponsor the podcast we
would love to hear from you also make
sure you follow me on all the social
media you guys Facebook our podcast on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast find me I
think that's all the social media I got
right Facebook Instagram Twitter barely
ever [ __ ] with it I'm on green door I
don't mess with that one very much it's
family hide she's the one that runs that
does a lot of stuff with that she's one
that introduced me to it she gave me a
bunch of tokens to get started it's a
tote
based system if you go for that one
trust me sorry I haven't tried the OG
Kush yet so you would prefer the lemon
juice why there's so much of which one
laughs I got a freshie of the ghost
train haze over here there you go be
quick I'll stick to the jar a blaster Co
on the dunk um what else do we got
social media that's where we were we
were on social media I think that's all
I've got for you guys now this is my
buddy Fred Garvin Fred Garvin you send
me a lot of useful tips and questions
and stuff you keep the show moving
anybody else Gmail's send them to me I
would love to hear a whole bunch in here
we're gonna take somebody else to
everybody they listen to the podcast
shout out to everybody to the podcast
shout out to everybody that supports the
legalization of cannabis nation
[ __ ] wide I love you guys all
like you're my own adopted children
shouting just fancied until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom
[Music]
welcome back Canada's Community sniper
episode number 145 of the girl from a
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversations just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots band to let
him use their music on my podcast big
shout out to Kat and the entire mystic
cruise have a great week you guys this
episode is packed with information I'm
gonna do an episode about an email I got
about making feminized seeds and
selecting phenotypes / seeds and seed
breeding and feminized seed making this
one was right up my alley so I took a
lot of notes this would be a great
episode in my opinion I'm excited to do
it but before we get that far let's talk
about the secret session guys the secret
session was just a few days ago and in
my opinion this was the best secret
session we've done in Colorado
you know the secret session on 421 the
day after 4/20 that was pretty [ __ ]
fantastic but that was the day after
4/20 there were a lot of really cool
people in town that wouldn't normally be
here we had a lotta extra height because
of 4/20 weekend a lot of extra momentum
that really helped us out it was a
little over overhyped and too big for me
I like a smaller more intimate event so
without all the hustle and bustle this
was my favorite secret session I think
there were plenty of people there the
place was packed but it was a little
more intimate there was more room to dab
more room to chill out I was a little
quieter you could go get some quiet
space and talk to some people if you
wanted to I really enjoyed that so huge
shot it to the grimy Gatsby for throwing
a stellar event big shot up two miles
putting it together
big shout out to hunt big shout to
everybody who participated in the secret
sesh here the Terps from Evo labs good
shout outs a big huge shot it's my buddy
Brett Brett Mary's motivation on
Instagram make sure you follow him that
dude showed up with a pocket full of
Terps somebody said something
my buddy Bobo said something too to
Brett and Brett goes so you want some
turps and of course Bobo was like well
of course I want some turps and he threw
him a canister filled with little turf
containers and Bobo's eyes lit up like a
child
and I just happen to have a bunch of
packs of seeds in my pocket that I was
gonna give to some friends to draw out
and since I saw that beautiful gift
given right there I decided to return
some karma and I passed some seeds
Brett's way so Brett's got some I read
genetic seeds in his garden he'll be
grown those out before too long and
we'll talk about those on the podcast so
big huge shout out to the trippy boy
Brett hooks it up with his dad he had
some super good flavors everybody at the
event had fled the event had good flavor
shout out to our friends at the Terp
sweet all those kids always bring the
flame is good to see Diamond Dave at the
event Dave I don't know if you listen to
the podcast a big shot I was good to
shake your hand and see you haven't seen
in a long time
it seemed like we weren't getting along
on Facebook for some reason bow bro and
it's a good to shake your head and
[ __ ] put that behind us so welcome
back to the crew my friend big shot it
to Lindsey and Chris Phil let me kind of
tag along to be their third wheel I had
fun hanging out with you guys about
stickers stickers too we did not forget
Mike and Lindsey and I talked about it
via text message I know we owe you guys
some stickers Fred your stickers are
coming a couple other people you got
stickers coming the people that
participated in the mullet challenge you
do have stickers coming I did not forget
about you the people that hit up hash
tag I like it when you ramble you've got
stickers coming nobody forgot about you
or his dad we're blazed and confused for
doodle he can to keep up so back on
track your shot it's a DeMille a DeMille
comes all the way from California he
flies in from Burbank all the way to
come to Colorado here to host the secret
stash wish with us it's a big shout out
to my boy animal Wow
if you don't know about of a tree fall
it's at Adam blunts I think so he always
has to change his social media always
shut down a social meeting has to
restart new [ __ ] search animal on
Instagram I think it's Adam blunts on
Facebook check him out he's the hostess
with the mostess that's my buddy giddy
up I haven't seen giddy up in a while
and giddy up was at the secret stash
rocking a mohawk building a stage great
dude that giddyup guy makes you guys
support emo tech they do just moved to
Hollywood California he's young and rich
and lives in Cali now good luck with
that one bro things hope things go well
for you Oh big huge shot it's my buddy
Jason Margulis it was good seeing you
there sorry I missed your lovely lady it
would have been good to see her and give
her a high five and a half hug you know
those one-armed pugs
what we do good to see her but it's good
seeing you bro thanks and I bring the
lady with you we'll all hang out take
some chirpy dabs I think that's all the
shoutouts I've got for the secret sex
you guys I turn
down edibles this time I did not eat any
edibles if the secret sesh I shot it to
TNT extracts he gave me some 200
milligram bacon bacon wrapped in
parchment paper okay but of course I
gave that to her buddy buh buh buh buh
buh blaster Co all the edibles I was
given that night I passed it right over
to buh buh people people just walk by
you and hand you edibles they're like
you need some edibles bro and I will
take but then if I'm not an edible zone
that night I just pass them on to
friends Bobo got all of my excess
edibles he was lit up that's pretty fun
I'm afraid you guys ate a bunch of
edibles at the last secret session I I
don't even know a lot of edibles I had a
lot of THC in my body I'm gonna guess
somewhere between 800 and 1500
milligrams of THC in my body I was
challenged I was having a rough time and
then our friends at teensy TNT extracts
gave me a 1000 milligram edible and I
ate it for breakfast the next day on my
way to work by the time I got to work I
it felt like I had wrapped a vise around
my brain and I was trying to function on
half speed all day so I've been afraid
of edibles since then to tell you the
truth and I haven't eaten any it's been
quite a while I don't know if I'll do it
for a little while probably go see fish
and eat a couple hundred milligrams at
the fish that might be what has to
happen all right you guys let's get to
the point let's get to the point the
point of this podcast I received an
email from a friend let me open up this
email I've got a save right here on the
phone this dude signed his name as just
a noob trying to learn and then he
called himself ban so noob trying to
learn this question was great you asked
a lot of great [ __ ] and you really
sparked a great podcast in my opinion so
let me read the email the email goes
like this greetings Jeff first off I
want to say thank you for the kick-ass
podcast and then you have taught me so
much in these weekly sessions they make
my Monday morning commute tolerable
that's why I put them out Monday morning
so your weekend doesn't hire you sue
your week doesn't have to start with a
shitty Monday you start off with some
kick-ass podcast material I'm glad you
noticed thanks for checking it out so he
goes on to say while I have yet to grow
by because of where I live the topic
nonetheless consumes much of my thoughts
and I try to learn everything I can
much of the gain knowledge has led to
practices that have benefitted my
outdoor vegetable garden even still I
have what may seem to be a stupid
question
dude your question is not stupid I was
so excited when I read this I was like
oh I know a lot about this and I'm gonna
get to ramble on for a long time so I'm
gonna continue with email it says it
seems that many screens are named for a
special phenotypically Express trait
that manifests any particular smell
flavor or color now if you're lucky
enough to find one of those desirable
phenotypes the strain is known for when
popping seeds it seems that you can
enjoy that treat continually if you had
the foresight to take clones absolutely
correct that's why I encourage everybody
every time you grow a seed every time it
gets big enough to take a clone you take
a clone off of it before you flower it
because you don't know if that seed is
going to bear the most amazing cannabis
you have ever smoked in your life and if
you don't have a clone of it you might
try to kick yourself in the ass and
you're gonna be kind of mad about it
it's heartbreaking when you don't get a
cut of your of this super amazing herb I
grew some excuse me for the throat
clearing of course that's a bunch of
dabs sorry about that
I grew some Holy Grail cush from DNA
genetics and it was honestly superb
cannabis if you can get your hands on
some Holy Grail Kush seeds I recommend
that from that from another breeder
that's not even my brand get that from
DNA to genetics and maybe a reserve a
privada project by now but a Holy Grail
cush get the real deal the old-school
[ __ ] from DNA genetics it's amazing
cannabis I could not get the phenotype I
selected would not make clones they
would not root for [ __ ] I put them in
rock wool they'd shriveled up I put them
in a corner they got funky and fell
apart I could not get that [ __ ] to clone
I'll never get to taste that flavor
again my friend pops is an old guy he
says that was one of the top-five best
pots he's ever smoked that pops is all
dude hard to impress so the holy bro
cush was some special [ __ ] I could not
get it to root I wish I had a clone of
that it is gone one of my favorite
strains ever was the p90 one and there
were some serious raids of large grow
facilities in the p90 one rumor has it
was lost in that raid somebody claims to
have it but I really don't know if that
is what they got anybody can claim to
have it so let's talk about something
else you said in here it seems that the
screens are named for a special
phenotypically expressed trade yes
that's why the Sour Diesel is called
Sour Diesel because it smells like
diesel feel I think they tried to name
the Girl Scout cookies
because they wanted us to think that it
tastes like Girl Scout cookies it's a
little bit they called The Thin Man cut
if you get the Thin Mint they taste the
Finn mint cookies and the Thin Mint cut
it could be close so that part is
totally accurate now here's where what I
really uh what I really like to get into
in this part of the email it says ah
if the traits are passed from mother to
clone would it be likely that the same
traits would be present in nearly 100%
of the seeds if you were to make
feminized seeds from this plant
you would hope so because of logic but
that is not accurate and I took a bunch
of notes and I'll get into that I'm
gonna have to take a break here in a
second take a drink but let me keep
reading the email and then I'll take a
drink take a quick break just cuz you
guys don't wanna hear me clear my throat
a thousand more times the email goes on
to say my logic may be way off on this
as I am NOT a botanist or geneticist but
if if it does play out like this then
why don't the seed companies grow out
several plants to find that rare
phenotype and then make feminized seeds
from that plant any knowledge you can
drop will be greatly appreciated thanks
bro
from just a noob trying to learn then he
signs it been noob this is a great
question I'm gonna press pause for just
a second here take a drink and then I'll
be right back all right you guys I'm
back took a big fresh drink I feel like
I'm better I'll be better for a minute
I'm gonna take a DAB and [ __ ] it all up
again but I'm better for now alright
let's get back to this email the part
that got my attention here at the end
said if the traits are passed from
mother to clone would it be likely that
the same traits would be present in
nearly 100% of the seeds no a clone
you're taking a cutting from an existing
plant and that plant is making a root of
course right and then you're getting a
clone so all the traits are passed
because there is no opportunity for any
other chromosomes or genetics or traits
to be introduced into that cut there's
nothing you're not gonna pull DNA out of
the air to change the traits oh yes that
one will be exactly like the mother that
it came from now when we're working with
seeds we have the opportunity for
variation because we're using pollen
that has chromosomes from the
grandparents you're not only getting
parents not only getting chromosomes
from that selected phenotype but you're
getting chromosomes from whatever that
plant is a cross up so let me back up a
little bit something that I want to
mention we do search for those selected
phenotypes that you mentioned right now
I'm making a rise f2s which means I made
in a rise plant a rot and a rice grain
which I took Daybreaker as the male and
I put Daybreaker pollen on a golden goat
female and I took those seeds and what
came out of that I named that arise so I
found a beautiful male I've got a studly
male he produces the structure I want
the aroma I want he makes resin this
male plant is a stud so I've got that
and then I've got I think right now I've
got three or four gorgeous arise females
that I need to pull it pick one of those
because I want to take that arise male
and I want to put that pollen on that
arise female and make a rise F twos and
I'm doing that by selecting the perfect
phenotype of the perfect male and the
perfect female to bring out the traits
that I'm looking for now I could screw
that all up I could bring out a bunch of
recessive traits and it could be a total
disaster and I'll have to go back and
find a different male and female and do
it all over again but that's why I grow
out a bunch of them myself before I try
to sell them or give them away to
anybody I make sure to cry probably a
hundred of those by myself before
anybody else will even see them so we do
look for those phenotypes we find those
perfect phenotypes and sometimes a cross
will be made it wasn't intended to smell
like something I don't think the tangi I
don't think that the guy that made tangi
I think that was Crockett
I don't think Crockett was like I want
to make tangi I think tangi should be
Caleo and this whatever the hell used I
forgot but this orange plant uh I don't
think he was like I want to make tangi I
think he crossed some [ __ ] and they came
out and tastes like tangerines and he's
like that's a tan gee I think that's how
that came I don't think Sour Diesel I
don't think anybody was like I want to
make a strain that tastes like diesel
feel I think it was actually named
because of that so they selected that
one now let's talk about something else
you said why don't we use those selected
phenotypes we do and then if I'm gonna
make feminized seeds from that selected
phenotype I'm going to treat so I'm
gonna take two clones of the same plant
the selected phenotype that has the
traits that we like the one that so
we'll say grateful dog I've made
feminized seeds of grateful dog I've
grown a bunch of my own grateful dog
seeds I found the one that is stellar so
I take two clones of that I reverse one
and I put that reversed pollen onto the
female grateful dog and now I make
grateful dog seeds now sometimes those
grateful dog seeds look like chem dog
and sometimes those grateful dog seeds
look a little bit more like San Fernando
Valley OG Kush but a lot of them look
very much like the grateful dog clone
that I reversed and started with and
then we'll get a little a little bit of
variation that's a little closer to the
chem but more OG and then a little more
OG but closer to the cam and then you'll
see blends of the traits it's kind of
like making kids you know like your
sister might look a little
from you but you could definitely tell
you're from the same gene pool it's just
gonna vary a little bit more from so
you're gonna see traits of grandmas what
I'm saying you're gonna see traits of
grandpa's what I'm saying and sometimes
you might see great grandparent traits
so let me refer back to my notes here to
keep myself on topic because I'm getting
way way off of what I'm trying to say so
we do search for those phenotypes and
that's how we make our f 2s and then we
do reverse those to make our feminized
seeds I breed with my second and third
generations from those select I make my
second and third generations from those
selected plants and I was talking about
picking one female and one female
something else or one male and one
female something else I also do I will
take multiple females of the same strain
and one male of that strain and hit
three or four different females with
that male pollen and that way I've got I
can see the variation I can see that
this girl produces more resinous
offspring I can see that this girl
produces tall and lanky offspring so I
don't want to breed to that one again
let's go ahead and get rid of that I can
see that this one over here produces
really lanky plants that stink really
well but don't make a lot of resin so
maybe I don't want to breed to that one
so I'll go and hit multiple females so
that way I can find the best breeding
plant so that I can use so I'll also hit
different females of different strains
in that room with that male so I'll put
four females so when I do this will rise
f2 it's about to happen pretty soon I'll
probably put two maybe three females of
a rise in there to be honest and then
I'm gonna probably put seven or eight
maybe nine or ten females of other
strains in there that'll be a grateful
dog in there I'm gonna put a golden goat
in there to take it backwards a little
bit I've got some other stuff that's
gonna go in there I've got some crosses
I made that'll go in there then I'm
gonna hit all of those with pollen and
then we'll see what comes of all of that
progeny there'll be a whole bunch of
great stuff in it all right let's get
myself back on track he said my logic
may be way off on this but I'm not a
botanist or geneticist which I like they
said but if it does play like this then
why don't the seed companies grow out
several plants to find the rare
phenotypes and then make feminized seeds
from that plant well that's kind of
exactly what they slash we do my friend
I hope I explained that in a way that
makes a lot of sense to you one thing I
want to go back over is the word
phenotype I hear a lot of people say
phenome it's a Fino Phe and
fino phenotype a phenotypic expression
Fino not phenome just just to make you
something cooler in your circle so when
you're making seeds and those seeds do
come out of course variation is natural
that's something that we expect we can't
control it completely if you want to
make something that I did that I didn't
even realize I was kind of I was doing
something out of the norm I made
feminized seeds and then I found my
favorite my favorite phenotype out of
that batch of feminized seeds and then I
hit that feminized plant with the
original pollen that I made feminized
seeds from and the progeny from that was
super stable I did it again and then I
tried to reverse one of those plants and
I could not get it to reverse I could
not make the plant herm
I could not change the sex of that plant
to make more feminized seeds with that
generation of that progeny and I was
super impressed with the stability of
that plan that plan is still around it's
been named Gd 77 a lot of people ask me
about my naming schemes they're very
random grateful dog was Gd
1977 is one of my favorite years of the
Grateful Dead so GD 77 it's the Grateful
Dead 77 female I love it it's in the
mother room right now that's one of my
favorite keepers I've probably had that
one for I don't even know how long I
really can't remember I've had it for a
super long time long time eight years
I'll say eight years I've had that clone
alright let's get back on track here I
like the variation that's what I'm
saying variation is cool when you're
making seeds I like variation I don't
want every seed to grow out just like
the picture on the package because
everyone's got that one I want a little
bit of variation that means that the
grower down the street that bought those
seeds doesn't have the phenotype that
I've got and it means that there might
be something better in there that means
you can always keep growing more seeds
that's why I always that's why I love
see you might find something better than
what you've already got
sometimes if somebody loses a plant or
if something doesn't root when you try
to clone it I always look at the bright
side that means I get to grow more seeds
because see the way to go
seeds have vigor you can find new [ __ ]
in there every every strain that you're
smoking every clone that you've ever
grown that came from a seed
right and had to so uh the variation of
course you could stabilize that just by
by breeding make f2s make f3s by the
time you get to have five those seeds
will be super stable you'll start making
seeds that produce almost clones once
you get to the f6 generation probably
90% of the seeds that you plant are
going to look just like the picture on
the package if the breeder did it
properly alright guys I'm gonna take a
DAB in a drink I'm gonna get another
email to you before I do that I want to
give a big shout out to our buddy the
noob that sent us this email I really
appreciate it I like talking about
feminized seeds I like talking about
making seeds I like talking about
breeding that's my favorite [ __ ] so if
you have more questions about that send
them to me gross my heart at hotmail.com
I will read your emails on a future
episode guys I need a drink and a DAB
bear with me play some reggae music Andy
and hang out for a second
[Music]
all right my back took a drink did not
take some dabs this time I think I have
a voice I think my throat is gonna hold
up for at least a couple more emails
alright let's get to another email
this one says Rasta Jay recently
discovered my latest batch of girls are
not as innocent as I would like yes they
are flat ass full of seeds my question
for you is if there are any dead
giveaways to determine if they were
pollinated or simply harmed I did have a
sneaky male get by me until about week
three I had him labeled wrong and stuck
him in the flower room I'm hoping this
is the case and not a her issue then he
continues to give me reasons why his
plants may have harmed and Duty out of
male he [ __ ] up you got a boy in there
that male at three weeks he Buster did
not be pollinated you girls do you know
what that male was that's my question
now if you know what that male plant was
you may have accidentally just bred some
[ __ ]
keep those seeds grow them out see what
you got yeah I'm pretty sure that that
mail drop Paulette it only takes about
14 days for some of those stud layer
males to just start blowing pollen
everywhere so if you had them in there
until about week three I'm pretty sure
that's who hit those girls with fallen
from the list of things you mentioned
that may be reasons why those plants
earned it does not look like Lee to me
the recent switch of lighting that would
not do it the site Fox healing emission
that's because they got too hot I don't
think that made them firm so you had a
dude in there
[Music]
if you were growing from seed or if you
have a male plant
I have males in my stable I got a couple
of big fat male arise plants in there
got Solomon just chilling he's kicking
it like three feet tall but if you're
going from Seaton you got boy plants
those boy plants will drop pollen I've
actually got a strawberry tangi banana
male plant in a very small pot it's
getting root bound and I can see male
flower clusters forming on the top if I
don't get that out of there in the next
10 days he will drop all that pollen
will come from there so if you're if
you're growing from seed keep an eye on
those pollen sacks and if you don't want
seeded plants if you don't want pollen
don't be lazy
get those males out of there let's do
the perfect example of why you don't
want to have males in your garden he's
got seeds that brings me to something
I've wanted to say for a little while
and haven't had the opportunity to run
in a garden and there's some [ __ ] that
needs to be done do it today
tomorrow wai-wai-wait that's your garden
that's your love that's your medicine
that's your product if you're going for
commercial if you're growing from
medicinal if you're drawn just for love
do that [ __ ] today those plants are
alive you wouldn't if your dog was
hungry and your dog needed water you
wouldn't make the dog wait till tomorrow
why do you make the plants wait one of
those plants they're yours you gotta
care for that bulb is dirty if that bulb
is dead that lens is dirty if that
ducting is funky don't do that [ __ ]
tomorrow do that [ __ ] today don't be a
lazy [ __ ] get in there clean your
gardens take care of that [ __ ] do it
today
love your plants that garden that crop
is only gonna be in flower for 63 days
56 63 maybe 70 days if you're going hard
why not make every day count get in
there do that [ __ ] right do it today put
some love into those plants quit
bitching I'm sorry I feel like I kind of
got on you just love your plants you
guys get in there take care of that [ __ ]
you claim to love your garden another
message I want to read remember a few
episodes ago we had a listener send an
email asking about recommendations for
dispensaries in Denver and I took a
screenshot of his latest message he sent
me this message on Instagram and it says
Rasta Jeff wanted to thank you for
reading my email on your podcast and for
recommending natty REMS my wife and I
loved our trip I wanted to let you know
that stitcher has all of your episodes
starting at episode 40 all the way to
the current episode keep those beautiful
Instagram images coming from our friend
fats that's a great message to read
there's so much good [ __ ] in there ah
man I'm glad you enjoyed natty REMS I'm
glad Colorado was super kind to you I'm
glad that you and your wife had a great
trip I'm also glad to hear that all of
the episodes starting at episode 40 are
on stitcher that's awesome that means
that everybody can listen all the way
back to episode 40 it's probably 44 ish
by now it's 45 by the time this comes
out that means they're gonna keep a
hundred episodes on there that's cool
awesome so there are a hundred episodes
of this podcast available on stitcher
you guys if you want to go listen to 100
episodes of the show I encourage you to
go back and listen to old episodes one
of my favorites I think is the
scheduling your perpetual grow episode
that episode that should have been a
million dollar book idea so make sure
you listen to that one for me if you
haven't heard that one go listen to it
that's that's a great episode I think
it's number 72 I'm gonna be a
responsible podcast host and press pause
and don't make sure what
that is alright I found the information
I wanted to find but I want to let you
guys know something funny that I just
did my buddy John hunt gave me a pencil
dabber it is made out of green Stardust
glass and it's got some coloured tips
and a colored eraser and or a colored
tip where the pencil mint would be the
color tip of the eraser and would be
it's made out of glass it's meant to be
used as a dabber and my high-ass just
picked it up and tried to write a
[ __ ] note on my notepad with the
dabber pencil so shoutout to cannabis
and THC for that [ __ ] you guys the
episode I was actually referring to his
number 73 make sure you check out
episode number 73 it's scheduling a
perpetual grow she liked that episode
should have been a million dollar
episode while we're going through it
check out number 76 about phenol hunting
and then if you want to learn about
outdoor our friend Jesse comes by
episode number 79 definitely go back and
check out 73 and number 55 is one of my
favorite episodes if you're new to the
podcast make sure you check out 55 you
know I've thought about going back in
releasing some of the older episodes on
like a Thursday like a midweek episode
so maybe you want some of those older
episodes fall out of the feed once I put
so many episodes in that there's like 50
more that I can repost I'll go back and
put those up on a Thursday or something
so that they're still in the feed you
guys can listen to him cuz there are
some great episodes that need to stay up
for a little longer
alright let's get the show back on track
you guys big shout out to our friend
fats I do appreciate the interaction
dude next time you're in Colorado give
me a heads up we'll get together we'll
smoke some turps we'll take some selfies
we'll have a good old time you guys if
you want to send me a message or an
email or if you want to hit me up
somehow email me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll read your message on a
future episode I will answer your
questions if you want to follow me on
instagram it's at I understand it
accessor to grow from your heart podcast
I'd appreciate it in an upcoming episode
my buddy Sammy sent me an email asking
about easy cloners I'm gonna talk about
that a little bit and I will also talk
about how to set your email to the
appropriate Tempranillo question about
my dream grow I'm gonna kind of talk
about that on an upcoming episode then I
also have an episode off another a
question from a listener I've got an
episode about identifying issues in your
garden and then in a future episode I
will
about how to treat and prevent most of
those issues and/or problems so if you
guys have some content that you would
like me to talk about I encourage you to
send me an email most of the episodes
lately have come from listener questions
this podcast this comes from my heart
but this podcast is for you this isn't
for me this is for you and I love doing
it
so if you give me some content I would
love to read your stuff on the air could
you guys go and get you grow and help
you guys out
if you got some that you like too saying
you're not in all that social media
stuff all you do is email me grows me a
heart a hotmail.com you can't remain
anonymous and won't see your name on the
air I'll keep you safe I don't know what
state you're in so I don't want to get
you in any trouble you guys make sure
you check out the podcast on iTunes and
stitcher don't forget that most of the
episodes are available on I read
genetics Colorado dot-com I think that
is all I have got for you this week
that's all I got for you guys I wanna
give a big shot it's my ninja Spence
also a big shout out to rust a sub make
sure you check me out in seven days
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
do it for the Terps
yeah welcome back cannabis community is
time for episode number 146 of the
growth mare heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you my
friends call me Ross - Jeff want to
thank you guys once again for joining me
as always I want to say a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
group span for letting me use their
music on my podcast
[Music]
Lindsey sitting across from me and she
just mouthed the entire intro word for
word girl good job make sure you follow
my friend Lindsey on Instagram snapchat
every single social media available she
is traveling stoner the traveling stone
or travel stoner that is her check her
out
are you one of those Boston Asian chicks
[Music]
yeah also you guys to my left here one
of our favorites a crowd favorite mr.
white Mike is back yeah make sure you
guys follow Mike on Twitter an emo Punk
15 yep
also a shout out your Facebook page for
us so people can check that out while
they're stocking you cannabis laws you
guys check that out support it click
like post your positive cannabis
experiences on there share with the
world why you think cannabis should be
legalized why we should have access to
safe medicine why we should not get rid
of recreational or medical cannabis
anywhere do that go there support that
[ __ ] yes hey guys everybody in the room
right now has his dad the [ __ ] out look
on their face folks let's get really
high for this episode and nobody in the
room argued that it was like I like this
roasted track I wanted to cop real hard
it has been confirmed we are going to
have the wonderful the Miss Debbie
granny on the podcast if you know about
the dead granny stay tuned for future
episodes you will be joining us I'm not
sure if I'm going to her if she's coming
to me Lindsay can you tell us a little
bit about your friend the Devin granny
Oh dropping the real name name dropping
like you're the homie now dabbing granny
and I in Colorado Springs
we actually have hung out a can of
Canyon a couple times and gotten to take
some dabs and we got to hang out with
Brett Mary's motivation I actually um
left work for lunch for 30 minutes and
got to go over to candy Canyon hang out
with her Brett THC Sam THC magazine Sam
and a couple other people can learn a
couple of people yeah it was super fun
but yeah she's just because everybody
wants to follow a dabbing granny so yeah
granny also she listens to the podcast
when you told me that she listens to the
podcast who put the biggest smile on my
face
so actually you have Brett to thank for
that and well I mean like I was just
sitting there we were Brett and I were
talking about the podcast at canna
Canyon that day and granny was like what
podcast is this and Brett said give me
your phone subscribe to the podcast he
goes here you go and so and so she turns
to me and she said you're on this and I
said I said I'm very fortunate Jeff has
me on the podcast way more than she
started listening to them and so like I
guess one of the first couple of ones
which I don't know what the first couple
ones she listens to actually work but
she listened to the dispensary talk one
yeah and she was like oh was it me that
you were talking about flirting with you
in the dispensary a lot of people might
know who we're talking about you guys
check out the dab in granny on Instagram
she's on Facebook when I discovered her
she took a giant dab like a big dab you
guys she did like a hundred of my dabs
one of the first time I saw the video I
felt so bad she's a little young to be
my granny but she could be Lindsey's
granny she could definitely be your
granny so she's a granny she's for sure
we're not being derogatory handle is
dabbing underscore granny I don't think
it's the dab off of a rig and then she
jugs a beer like a whole pint glass and
then she takes a shot and then she blows
out her dad and takes another dab from
the nectar collector and smiles into the
camera like that's how you do it [ __ ]
and then ends the video so that's
actually like one of her staple things
she kind of like changes it around a
little bit but like I'm pretty sure she
did that on Facebook live today or some
version of that you know like a dab of
beer and then like a shot and then
something you know didn't mean like a
bong rapers I don't know but yeah so I
think she does some sort of variation
and that's her like I think she calls it
her party trick okay I could be wrong I
really could but yeah that's I think
that's where she really her version of a
sprite
[Music]
they caught my eye because it was
someone who could be my grandmother with
the dab lined up that was like I mean it
was YouTube dab worthy size it was
massive my pink try to take maybe half a
gram three-quarters of a gram and then
she takes this dab like a champ and as
I'm sitting there like wow she like
throws down a pint and then does a bong
rip and then exhales the bong rip and
the dab and I'm looking at this video in
my mind just shocked what I'm so I bet a
lot of people her YouTube her Facebook
or Instagram is just exploding as people
listen to this you guys go support davon
granny we're gonna get you on the
podcast really soon look forward to that
in a future episode you guys she's a
patient
she's cannabis advocates she's a smoker
but she's a savage it's my favorite part
about her she seems to be super-sweet
from everything I've seen all right
granny can't wait to have you on the
show Lindsey thanks for arranging that
that's your fault
you said blame Brett Brett thanks for
rating that that's your fault you guys I
didn't reach out to her you guys did
that that's what I loved about the idea
of places like candy Canyon it's the
community doesn't have any good place to
meet up and as soon as we started
getting them really cool connections
started being made he said that I really
liked Brett right on for his grabbing
someone's phone and subscribing them to
my podcast you're subscribed to rusty
Jeff's podcast now have you seen his
Instagram lives like his snap the new
Instagram snapchat no no I have been in
tears the first one he ever put up was
like by snapchat and it was list like
he's done and then the next one was just
something like oh my god I'm so excited
about this I can answer all your
questions now like yes and he goes like
down and then he comes back up he's like
I am in my underwear right now and like
that was it it just cuts off and I was
just like
yes these are going to be so amazing
that dudes a really cool dude shout at
the breath support thanks for the Terp
love you guys want to talk about that
new stupid Instagram feature I'll just
give it a second there's a new feature
on Instagram I don't know if I care not
I don't know if I like it just feels
like it never ends there's just so many
pictures that scroll by I'm like honey
the Karen I forgot I forgot that I don't
care that's right I think what you have
to remember is that Instagram was
originally just pictures look at how far
Instagram has actually evolved and what
it actually started from can you really
hate them for doing a live feature I
don't know I don't really like I have
pros and cons about it so I just don't
really I just feel like they're trying
to suck up too much of my attention now
I can scroll up and down and left and
right and it just [ __ ] me all up
there's no and there's no end to it now
because there's that's enough I have to
stop alright since we're talking about
social media this is a good segue
Twitter people I've got three names of
folks that I have got envelopes with
your name written on it there's a stamp
on there there's a return address label
on there that someone claimed it was
mediocre but I think it's just fine it's
gonna work just fine there's a return
address label on there that gets lost it
will get back to me I'll get it back to
you those of you the receive these feel
free to comment about the quality of the
labels in Twitter please do we'd love to
hear your comments there will be
stickers in there for you those are to
say thank you for participating in
Twitter challenges or just for being a
friend if you guys want some stickers
contact me hit me up on Facebook hit me
up on Instagram make me up on the
Twitter or you can email me it's grow
often harder hotmail.com the real trick
is to listen to the whole episode when
it's no longer one yes that does help
out that pays off if you follow me on
Twitter or Instagram or something send
me a message Instagram is Irie I RIE
underscore genetics I regen etics
if you used to be following me you might
now because a long time ago they crushed
my account and I've started a new
account
I had like almost 20,000 followers I'm
mulling around six or seven thousand now
so come follow me again please that
would be cool on Twitter it's @g fyh
podcast on facebook it's go from your
heart podcast and of course there's the
email that I like to say that lets go
for mail calm I love you some stickers
so these friends of mine are gonna get
some stickers big shout-out to James
Howlett
you're gonna get some stickers in the
mail Jason Hawkins you got stickers
coming in the mail and Sami Braille you
got some stickers coming in the mail bro
my painted chef friend also that segues
right into the next part how you guys
like that double segue we're doing a
Grateful Dead style one right into the
other we're not gonna stop keep on
jamming Sammy asked about easy cloners
his basic question was do you recommend
an easy clone or do you like an easy
cloner yes I love an easy cloner what I
really like about an easy cloners you
can cut large clones if you take big
clones they'll route quickly and those
big clones I think they take off much
more quickly than clones and rockwool
cubes Mike remembers my old school days
of trying to cut Collins and rock wool
cubes
I took so many clones and put them in a
rock wool cubes I did that for a lot of
years with a lot of different Brewers
Mike used to grow hand for everybody
around here and honestly the easy clone
is a huge step up it's in my mind if
you're growing in cloning regularly it's
worth the investment I just make sure
you get a good would you remember your
first easy cloning bro yeah let's not
talk too much about that no but two
seconds after you would plugged it in
your advice would have been don't buy on
that crap yeah those old ones sucked the
new models are awesome yeah they worked
out all the kinks it doesn't explode and
turn your grow room into a waterpark
anymore that's the best description
there are new models the new ez cloners
the low what are they con the low rise
the low-profile models they're white now
I really dig them they require less
water which is really helpful because
that also means less nutrients I'm only
familiar with the big black beast but it
gets the double thumb it's the same
thing but just a new design they used to
delete remember how the old black ones
used to spray out of the side
they don't leak or drip anymore the new
design is way better they're easier to
clean I really like the new easy cleaner
so Sam uses if you're looking to up your
clone game get yourself an easy cloner
it is super easy to use that thing you
need a healthy mother poke a get your
cloner set up by that I mean get the
cloner [ __ ] bill if the neoprene is
in there get the little manifold and
there get its brand get it run and fill
it up with water just below those red
sprayers remember how much water you put
in it figure that out put nutrients in
there I would use a little bit of bloom
like your base blue nutrient a little
bit of micro and just dip them in some I
like to use the the EZ clone or gel
though with that what's that one called
should I can't think of the name clone
ex it's a purple clone ex gel like to
use that [ __ ] dip it in there put it in
a little neoprene collar cut it to where
there's like two or three nodes
underneath that collar put that [ __ ] in
the cloner put the cloner on for 45
minutes on 15 minutes off because that
water will heat up because of that pump
I put a t5 light about you know foot
above that and just let the t5 light run
24 hours a day and no [ __ ] in like 7 or
8 days you'll start seeing little warts
pop out of the plant that's where the
roots are gonna grow like 10 to 14 days
you'll have savage roots in 17 to 21
days those roots are gonna be so big
you'll have to go to a 3 gallon pot and
skip a cup a huge step up in technology
from the old school clone domes huge
step up so I highly highly recommend we
use those at the grow I run a big
commercial grow and I've got 1 2 3 there
are 6 easy cleaners filled with clones
right now yet to grow that's how we keep
it thank you go on like this about the
cloner for a while it's really an
awesome product so easy cloner if you'd
like to send me some easy cloners hit me
up I could use like 160 side or 190 site
you know just my personal setup I don't
need anything for the for the store just
send me one I'd appreciate that yeah
alright so Sammy I hope I answered your
question but I hope it's not too late I
know that took me a while to get to that
message I apologize I do want up sowed a
week I need to fix that I did too we
could probably get more questions y'all
right over there headphones alright get
headphone ear know it here
[Music]
yes right in the next topic on the last
episode we talked a lot about dabbing
and stuff and I want to talk about email
temperature and getting your email set
to the temperature that is perfect for
you because I like my email a little bit
hot if Spence was here spent some garden
weeding shout out to my brother some is
would reach right over and just turn my
email down like [ __ ] that's too
hot oh that slightly scold you for
having it too hot yeah but you know it's
my email and I like him hot well no it
was just a beautiful thing to watch it
was pretty funny it was pretty funny but
I just let Spence do his thing he's a
hash maker and he would bring over slabs
and dab me out with them and you could
bake it whatever temp you want if you're
gonna drop that much hash on there do
your thing player but uh most people
keep their emails a little lower than I
do I like mine a little hot somebody's
asking me how do I get my email to the
perfect temperature the temperature is
all kind of subjective it's all about do
you want it hot and her tea do you want
it low tip all taste some of the new
trend is to heat a nail and this is not
that you know this is if you're using
like a banger the new trend is to heat
the nail let it get way too hot and then
let it cool way down and then put your
dab on there and waste half the [ __ ]
dab and then act like it tasted real
good and then get a q-tip and clean it
off that's what all the trendy kids are
doing now that's what you see it all the
events that is not my style I like to
heat it and when it's hot enough to cook
the dab I drop a real big dab on it make
sure it all cooks and I get a big thick
fat milky hit that makes my eyes water
and makes my lungs kind of Twitter a
little bit and I put a carb cap on it
make it even fatter and I like to get a
fat dad so sending the email to the
perfect tip is kind of subjective for
you the way I would say to do it use a
carb cap definitely uses carved-out
they're actually went and googled apart
about a carb cap let's talk about a carb
cap for a second here this actually
comes from High Times Magazine and it
was written I wrote it down it's written
by Shawn black
this is like this the carb cap is
exactly what it sounds like a carburetor
for your rig it restricts restricts what
the [ __ ] does that word mean it
restricts the amount of airflow to your
nail allowing you to collect the last
bits of your oil to punctuate the end of
your head by cat and this is the part
that's important by capping the nail you
restrict the air flow into the rig
through the small contact area between
the cap and the edge of the nail while
inhaling strongly the reduced air flow
places the entire rig under low pressure
including the oil that pulled on the
nail without vaporizing under low
pressure every component of the hash oil
suddenly has a lower boiling temperature
what once boiled it should say which
which once boil at high temperatures can
now do so at much lower temperatures
giving you a bloom of thicker better
tasting smoke the carbon cap lets you
actually finish the dab instead of
wasting it in a thick sputtering puddle
the trend now you guys is that thick
sputtering puddle because everyone wants
to taste if the Terps turps is the new
word Terps is the new thing I like that
carb cap description there so you get
your email you guys set it to hot set it
to low just go one direction I recommend
just slowly climb up you're looking for
the sweet spot in between wasting a lot
of your product and burning the living
[ __ ] out of your throat like I did
myself last night how far away right now
is my finger from the top of that nail
inch and a half perfect that's what I
thought so put your fingers and inch to
two inches above the nail and should be
able to sit there comfortably for like
one or two seconds before ooh that's hot
it should feel like your fingers getting
pinched like someone's just pinching
your finger a little bit that's about
the right temperature where I like it
Audrey kind of feels like you getting
pension after a couple seconds see the
toy that I should have now but I don't
is a laser town I've got have left the
house with money in my pocket to go buy
one a couple of times and something
happens and I end up at home without one
it's just not in the cards because it's
not necessary it's it's just depends on
what kind of hash you're smoking also if
you're smoking shatter like this shatter
you can put it on there kind of hot I've
had some
accent probably go hotter if I smoke and
live res I might turn it down just a bit
to get more of that taste so it depends
on the concentrate you've got you guys
get the concentrate that you've got get
the nail sit a little bit low put the
dab on there if it doesn't put the carb
cap on start smoking if that dad doesn't
melt enough obviously turn that [ __ ] up
and just go five or ten degrees higher
every time until you get the dab you
want I can't recommend the carb cap
enough the first time you use one when
you throw it on top of the nail the
first thing that goes through your head
is where'd all that come from as you
watch the vapor going through your rig
quadruple and thicken because that
wasn't on your nail a second ago had you
taken a breath and hit it you wouldn't
have gotten any of that and suddenly
you've got a huge milked out rig going
for you again it's so sweet I love just
when you cap it you just see it you just
start pulling like ah there you go
you know that's part of the reason I've
been so baked the last couple of shows
I've done is because I didn't have one
at home for the last several months and
now was not getting nearly as stoned at
home because I didn't have all the tools
with me so when he dropped the carb cap
on there you guys you're pulling your
head you're taking your hit then you get
enough smoke to fill your lungs you want
to blow out so that you could pull the
rest of that don't take the carb cap off
because at that time you're letting all
that vapor and that pressure and that
vacuum that you've created you've just
ruined that by letting the carb cap off
leave that carb cap on there almost
until you're done dabbing sometimes it's
a good idea to lift it cuz that [ __ ]
gets hot but just put it on there inhale
blow your head out leave the cap on
inhale the rest and then take it off as
soon as you're done don't don't take it
off until you're done Davin cuz a lot of
folks lose part of their dab that I've
seen people feather them and try to get
fancy with it just set it on there and
let her go one thing I do I honestly do
turn it a little bit there's one hole in
there and the top of that carb cap and I
like to turn it just because I think
that I move my or I take a larger dab
the nose with you need to spread it
across the top of the nail just a little
bit more than some and I'm not trying to
be a big [ __ ] dad when we're talking
temperature I can get away with a much
lower temp and now waste anything
because I'm putting a much smaller dab
to the nail each time you can't do
low temp half gram or a gram dab you end
up doing a point to dab in the rest of
the puddles and then you feel like a
dick for wasting watch your ass I wanna
mention one more thing and then you just
kind of said weighed me into another
part I want to talk about you guys when
you're taking a DAB with a carb cap and
you're using an email this happened at
the can of Canyon and it happens here
occasionally I just wanted to bring this
up for the folks that are learning to
dab and even the experienced neighbors
bra take the carb cap off the email
because that email is turned on and it's
hot and you leave that carbon cap on
there and it heats up the carb cap and
then whoever whoever sees it wants to
take a DAB they're not thinking about
that is hot they're thinking I want a
dad and they reach through the carb cap
and they burn the [ __ ] out of themselves
so be careful please take that
yeah please take that carb cap off of
the email just set it on an oil slick
pad I see so many people there's an oil
slick pad on my table this pad is
designed to catch hash oil not stick to
here my table right here this would part
the hash will stick to this all [ __ ]
day just put the two put the carb cap
down on the oil slick pad if you see one
that's what that's for utilize that
would segue me into another part that I
wanted to talk about
when we're giving dabs to somebody is it
up to me
to heat that it I feel like if I give
you a DAB this will be another question
I'm gonna ask one of us pulls a dab off
the parchment paper for you I'll heat
the rig to be nice just because we're
dabbing at my spot or in my car or
wherever we happen to be I'm gonna heat
this I know like I know I'm sorry I'm
gonna heat the nail to the appropriate
temperature and then I'm gonna maybe
we're camping and I'm gonna heal the
appropriate temperature and I'm gonna
hand it to you
do I hang on to that [ __ ] until it's
the right tip or do I give it to you and
let you decide when to dab that's if
it's someone new and new to dabbing I
would just be like okay like I would
just probably hold on to until it was
ready and then give it to him but if
it's somebody you know dabs a lot
[Music]
because do you remember a couple weeks
ago when we were having a conversation
about somebody he came from somebody
tried to be nice and give me a big fat
dab and they heated the nail nice and
hot and when I went to pick up the rig
they put their hand on it and said it's
too hot and I tried polite I'm like cool
you're giving me a DAB I'll let you do
your thing but in my mind I thought it's
gonna cool down way too much and this
big damn is just gonna end up as a
puddle on your nail and these guys were
like proud of how much they clean out of
their rig with the q-tip you know I want
to smoke that bro put that in my lungs
if we paid for it the dispensary wasn't
like oh you're gonna q-tip it here's 30%
off I don't understand how people can
waste that amount of hat it's like when
you're paying 20 30 60 80 100 gram for
hash how do you waste half of it on the
just letting it puddle and then kicking
it into the trash
that's like taking two sips off your
beer and putting the whole bottle the
rest of the bottle of the trash and
ordering another beer and dragging that
way all night dude choose how hot he
wants it if I want to want to burn my
lung as if on a roast my esophagus
let me new people and be gentle a lot of
us have a good story about the
introducing someone the hash where they
were like nah I want to take the hit you
took and we give it one or two no you
don't bro like just a bit of advice go
slow very strong and they resist a
little bit so we say [ __ ] it and let him
jump off the cliff that's not
necessarily I've told the story of the
dude a guy I was at a cannabis cup
mistaking dabs and a guy walked up he
said what are you doing there bro does
like smoking dabs and he's like I never
seen dad's before can I get a dad and I
was like sure and I gave him what I
thought would be a normal first dab for
a guy but I saw what you smoked give me
what you smoked that's gonna [ __ ] you up
I don't care I could smoke and so I did
what he asked for and I gave him a Jeff
sighs dad she dude up hooked him up that
dude took that hit and pulled in the
smoke and blew it out and vanished he
walked into the crowd like bye I gotta
go he was so high he didn't know what to
do with himself he couldn't look me in
the eye anymore he was done I thought
it's kind of funny but good chunk of my
day explaining to people who aren't
familiar with hash and edibles - please
go slow I talk to people all the time
that have I took the way too big a dab
and it was like the longest 12 hours of
my life while I waited to come down and
I feel bad for those people and it's
unnecessary like we used to be a little
gentler with it and there used to be an
initiation process before these products
were available and it negated the
necessity to do to say that a lot of
this stuff there are people out there
whose first experience with cannabis was
a DAB yeah it's unfair that's like the
first time you drank when you were in
middle school or a teenager or whatever
you had moonshine and you guys were
[ __ ] beer funneling it it's it's so
unnecessary there boof and shine why
would you do that it's the same thing my
first my first intro to marijuana with
us
a giant dab a life resin and it's like
in in what happened next you spent seven
hours in your hotel room wondering if
you were dead or not it's just you were
too big to handle it it never should
have happened like you didn't need to be
in that end of the pool go slow I need
to put a disclaimer on my dad videos do
not try this at home so I think with
that going back to your original
question your Jeff I think it's about
knowing your audience and about knowing
like who's in your car like if it's a
you know experienced divers let him do
it but if not because we're setting a
bad example we're talking about dabbing
in the car what shouldn't happen we're
the kids we're you and I each have
slipped about dabbing in the car like
we're outdoorsy it's Colorado I think
it's [ __ ] fun to dab in the car wash
when you get the car wash
[Music]
we can handle that if if I'm wearing my
logo on my shirt and I'm at every
[ __ ] secret sex you seem yeah let me
choose my temp on my dad talk about size
we're we're all friends here so when we
have dads we come to the table we just
there's some of my hash on the table
Lindsay's got some hash on the table
Mike didn't bring any today but I'm not
calling about last time he got some hash
to taste [ __ ] tremendous we all if
somebody wants a DAB this is my what is
this
Tristar shatter and I'm just gonna pass
him the parchment he's gonna pull off a
DAB for himself cuz that's the homie
over there is that how are you supposed
am I supposed to pull him off a DAB or
is that his job or I think Lindsey said
it perfectly a second ago someone
knowing you're on depends on who's who
you always get that one kid hanging out
at the secret stash and we're all a
bunch of friends we're a bunch of heads
were a bunch of family there's always
one guy in every [ __ ] group and you
know who I'm thinking about right now
that guy if you hand him your shatter
he's gonna try to smoke all of this in
one DAP just because he wants to smoke
as much as he can while he's there and
get as high as he can everybody every
group has that one guy that one friend I
think it's funny when people ask me for
a DAB and they try to do that because
then I get to watch them cough and turn
red and turn purple and most not out of
their face
it's worth it to me is watching them
function after that exactly because you
know what Jeff the thing about it is is
they watch people like you take huge
dabs and you know be able to just take
point five you know or bigger dabs and
they say here and go oh I can go on this
level with this guy and they take this
one they die and then they can't
function and you know what you do you
continues to take point five or bigger
DAV's and you keep going through the
night and they're just like been
trainings you're going deep this is your
Olympics you just for comparison there's
more residue on the dabber I just used
then the dab I just took Mike you're the
Segway champion because I want to talk
about ninja dabs right now so a lot of
people we take for granted a lot of
folks listening to this podcast or not
colorado-based people I can tell by
looking at the stats I try to ignore
them because I don't want it to
influence my performance but I could
tell by looking at the stats and a large
portion of our audiences in Colorado but
more than 50% is not Colorado based and
a large portion is not even in America
those people don't get to dab they don't
know what dabs are somebody put me back
on track ninja dabs obviously what the
[ __ ] ninja damn sorry ninja dabs so if
Lindsay was to get herself a DAB and she
was to start dabbing I would sneakily
I've got my MacBook here open I would
well she can't see me by behind the
computer I put another dab on another
dabber and as soon as Lindsay starts
inhaling that dab right before she puts
the carb cap on I would reach over and
put a sizable amount of hash on the nail
for her and ninja dabber I just get that
just add a little to her and make her
coughing get her a little extra [ __ ]
up more than she expected I've also seen
it referred to putting a DAB underneath
the carb cap so you lay the carb cap is
just it's a hunk of metal with a hole in
it did you set on top of the hot nail so
if you take some hash
surreptitiously place it underneath the
car cap of all that car or the wall they
their carb caps on their cap in their
dab it's gonna heat up enough to drop
that on the nail so be a good 3 4 5 10
seconds into their hit their hit
quadruples all of a sudden they don't
even know where it came from
yep that's happened to me more than once
in his led to some less than productive
afternoons I've called those time bombs
or landmines but I've also heard them
called sniper dabs for mother folks I've
got multiple enzymes and ninja dads
Roseau is when I heard those calls
we've got multiple carp caps and I'll
just set them out on the table and
occasionally one will have a little just
keeps going and they turn red they blow
snot out of their face and they choke
for a few minutes and it's really funny
to me I laugh a lot it is it's the blue
one if it ever happened we're talking
about dad stuff I've got notes it's
summertime and it's hot here in Colorado
and your dads are gonna be stuck to the
parchment paper and hard to [ __ ] okay
first of all I saw a dispensary on
Instagram today selling their patch in
little plastic discs [ __ ] that step up
your game use parchment paper it's cheap
get some parchment paper put your dad's
in parchment paper or one of those like
silicone containers let's get away from
the plastic things we're all your dad's
stick to it you gotta scrape it for
[ __ ] days to waste like a quarter
grab no one wants to scrape out of that
little plastic dish yeah that's the
first time you go to scrape out of you
realize that it's plastic and half the
divers out here aren't gentle enough to
I mean it's it quickly becomes a
question of who am I willing to dab
little strips of plastic oh it's great
that off my nail or do I just have to
kiss the rest of this hash go just let
it go
yeah honestly step your packaging up a
little bit I'm be sensitive to this
nevermind well like the packaging
matters and a lot of people don't think
it through to the end stage they come up
with the dough product and it's like
pork
the Lamborghini engine and a [ __ ] pen
so sometimes it's ridiculous and it's
that it's gotta move it doesn't matter
how good your product is if the
packaging is hideous and it's not
displayable it's gonna annoy the people
that sell it just a little even if
they're annoyed just a little they're
gonna reference the product that isn't
annoying more that's gonna move 10 times
faster you're gonna make a lot less
money all because you think you're
packaging through to the end and I mean
we're watching a change in waves in
Colorado right now every hash company
had their cool unique shaped logo
package and all of those are
transitioning to almost identical
envelopes now when you guys are seeing
it just as fast as I am up in the
springs I'm sure the packaging matters
in the original point of this was it's
summer the shatters a little tacky right
now that's a problem when it's a plastic
container yeah use parchment but where I
was headed with that is air conditioner
tech you guys your shadows getting all
funky go just set that shatter put her
in a baggie
well you if you're not gonna be there
for more than four or five minutes you
don't have to put in a baggie just set
that parchment in the freezer close the
door make sure you sit on a dry area
close the door let that [ __ ] get nice
and cold for a few minutes and pull it
out and now you can function with that
shatter it's gonna be a whole lot easier
to deal with it's gonna be real snappy
real crunchy if you maybe you know
there's an air conditioner in places you
can turn on that vent and turn that
[ __ ] up cool down your carb cap cool
down your dab and then you can cool down
your shatter also but make it a whole
lot easier for you guys to function I
don't buy a lot of shatter during the
summer for this exact reason I just
wanna bother like if I go with the
butter or a wax or a live resident it's
already a little tacky or soupy it's not
gonna mess with it much ain't no season
gonna stop me from davin different st.
seasonal this is something I do all day
every day
I'm not a fair-weather fan
money on hash in Hawai Rosano summer
it's not a bad thing have you ever been
in the cold that we're so cold your
torch wouldn't light yeah no just click
click click my smoker I can make fire
anywhere dedication to your cigarettes
fire anyway I could teach you some
things
Lindsay seems to be really good at
forgetting us fire source see that's
what us like tumor written [ __ ] sore for
like we've always got 7 Bicks like we
can find a way to get that now hot give
us a minute so you're on the go and
you're going somewhere to dab somebody
take a can of butane you have no money
no idea how many times everybody's had
everything we've needed to take dad's
and nobody had any butane so I'm the
kind of butane in my backpack so I'm
like I'll trade you guys a phat dab for
this butane and I get the next dad that
comes out of that as soon as that torch
is filled guess who gets a DAB that
would be me because I had the butane to
save the day I don't know if it's the
Boy Scout in here the smoker or the
stoner but I've always got a couple of
lighters like if I'm gonna go dab
somewhere I like a can of butane two
torches two nails two rigs because rigs
get dropped nails get lost they call so
it's a weird [ __ ] happens and it ruins
the session it's oh dude we could all be
high right now but we forgot a part in
our tweets fancies so now we're sober
Lindsey texted me one night she's like
dude I'm somewhere I don't have a rig
wanna smoke some patch did you ever
Reagan no torch yeah I had a Reagan I
had note so we say Reagan it sounds
terrible we mean a small water pipe I
prefer a smaller I went over this on
another episode of small pipe with a dab
nail on it we go domeless nowadays a lot
of us use of what's called a banger it's
a quartz hash nail hash bucket it's
[ __ ] marvelous but Lindsey had the
pipe in the nail part but she didn't
have a way to make the nail part hot to
where she can melt hash on it do you
remember my advice lens the way that I
really thought would work for you uh
what you gave me two that I thought were
actually quite so you gave me the gas
stove
you know how's your stove Oh sir either
way it would work the stove use the damn
stove right and then I just take the
deal on anything on the stove the car
the car cigarette I told her to use the
car a cigarette lighter as a carb cap on
the banger like if you just heat that
[ __ ] up till it glows and then you
drop your dab in the banger and then put
the cigarette lighter over it and draw
the heat would work just like how the
carb cap works yeah she didn't try it
because she didn't have the [ __ ]
cigarette lighter you could probably
take a dab by using that what the nail
and the rig is for is it replaces hot
knife it's exactly what it sounds like
you take two butter knives she's an
electric stove until the tips glow and
then mash a piece of hash in the middle
that's how like everyone in Europe got
stoned for like 71 to 75 to smoke hash
like that my buddy Sam's [ __ ] kitchen
years ago when people my parents age
come into the shop and ask for hash what
they're thinking about is hot knife hits
or the little pin under the beer mug
what is that [ __ ] I literally explain it
as this is the new fancy hash like
that's my it's the easiest way to bring
them up to speed but yeah hot knife it's
work on the fancy hash - it's just a
little closer to crack smoking that most
of us likes to get what time I suck our
buddy Kevin took his car cigarette
lighter and took a DAB just through the
dab on the course easily
we're at a party late one night and
we're smoking a bowl and we had shatter
and this is before like like Kevin and I
were kind of weird were some of the
first dab kids around here Boehner
smoked weed at the time I was Kevin was
me i Kevin was making chatter out of the
material I was growing we're kind of
ahead of the curve so we'd go places
people would have a rig and I didn't I
didn't used to drive around with the rig
on me I wouldn't take glass with me I
wouldn't do any of that stuff I didn't
like taking a rig with me anywhere but
we would get a bowl burning real hot
just get it super ridiculous cherried
and then just drop globs of hash on to
it and then try to smoke as much of that
as we could I would make us choke so
hard but we would get highest in the day
the swingarm skillets where we have them
glowing like the Sun and then throw a
quarter gram dab down because we didn't
know anything about what we were doing
[Music]
one day we're dabbing and he heated the
banger and I don't know what he was
thinking he grabbed a phat dab and like
just hits the banger sets the torch down
and just puts the dab on the nail
usually you got a way to fit at least a
few seconds a lot of these new kids are
setting a [ __ ] timer they got a
little [ __ ] hourglass right in he
just goes in and I was probably 15 feet
away from him sitting in another chair
and I can hear the dab scream the dab
way and we could all hear from across
the room and that dude turned a purple
and red tons of different colors and
coughed forever that poor dude took the
hottest dad ever and I'll never forget
it she was terrible glowy glowy
the first generation of dab kids have
some of the best little burn and brand
marks where's your where's your dab
wound I've got to drip wounds on one of
my legs from the skillet days that you
can't really tell what they're like
their dad related unless you could
explained and then the straight makes
sense but I remember seeing kids like
when domeless nails first started being
notched
little bit sort of like castle towers
yeah I was in like Walmart or some [ __ ]
and a kid reached out with some money
and I saw this forearm that he had that
brand mark on his wrist and I was just
too [ __ ] busted up laughing I saw a
whole bunch of the circular dome with
snail burns yeah um back in the dome
days people had all sorts of crazy drip
burns you guys don't let your friends
try to carb the dab rig just don't pull
that hot nail it's hot you just heated
it with the torch don't carve it just
smoke it's not it's not a bond you're
not smoking pot it's not gonna burn
you're not gonna carve it if you just
smoke it'll quit smoking when it's done
just do it you'll be cool a friend of
mine he was being handed a rig and the
person almost dropped it and he reached
out reflexively and grabbed it in the
heat sinks in the top of the nail wind
up in between his thumb and forefinger
and the brand right there looks like
half space-alien he just because of the
the way the bowl pressed into his hand
and then the heat sinks below it the
little metal stripes sounds terrible no
was hideous but now the brand looks cool
yeah alright let's good to go back to a
positive note guys the new thing is to
take some good chatter or some good hash
of any kind and then dunk it into fresh
terpenes either from blue words are hard
at the end of the show or of course our
friends at Evo labs that is the thing I
think Duncan the dads in Terps kind of
pushes it to a whole new level the ghost
train haze dabs make my eyes vibrate and
lemon g dabs I make my head spin a
little bit and the OG Kush tabs just
make me want to lay down and chill the
[ __ ] out the Terps the chirps so these
new Terps are definitely the next level
you guys if you have the opportunity
come to Colorado find a store that sells
turps recreationally get some shatter
get some turps put a dab of shatter on a
dabber and dunk it into the container of
Terps put that onto a properly
temperature nail carb cap it enjoy the
flavor that shit's amazing that's what I
recommend come to Colorado say what's up
come see us would be awesome to see you
we'll take a hike with you we'll take a
dad with you we're volunteering
I go for 45 minutes a lot of people are
getting a TD the people at the table are
super high and they're getting really
quiet so it feels like it's time to wrap
up this show like you look good in high
what we gonna say it's gonna be Mike
your Twitter handle so the folks can
follow you and also remind them of your
Facebook page it's at Nemo Punk 15 on
Twitter and below for sensible cannabis
laws on Facebook Lindsay that's a killer
stretch that's inspiring you're making
me want to stretch and get an inch
taller all the social media the
traveling stoner on Instagram and
periscope my snapchat is travelin stoner
without the G and my twitter is the
travel stoner oh and uh Facebook is the
traveling sooner - I guess everybody has
to work in the morning so it's all the
people they're out there busting their
ass all the growers all the bud tenders
everybody that's making this new
industry move there's no room for some
lazy [ __ ] in this one all the people
that are on it now are grinding a
hundred percent so it's time to step up
get it going yeah yeah we'll just gave
me that yeah I laugh at the lazy stoner
stereotype like when you see this
industry work
it's such yeah we put it in shut up to
the people that have been trimming all
week at the have to grow much appreciate
it
alright you guys I think that is all
we've got for you this week now the
show's over I would appreciate it if you
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for the girl from your heart
podcast find the review section type in
a comment let me know what you think
about the podcast I will read your
comment on a future episode while you're
there you guys you have the option to
give me stars one through five stars not
gonna beg for five stars give me what
you really feel I deserve I'd appreciate
that I would love it if you follow me on
social media we talked about Instagram
we talked about Twitter we talked about
Facebook I just searched from your heart
also follow me on Instagram its genetics
I'd love it if you email me if you're
not into social media stuff you got
something to say send me an email grow
from your heart at hotmail.com you guys
don't forget to the podcast available
sorry I'm gonna call from a DAB hold it
no cops cops are for the weak I don't
forget the shows available on iTunes
stitcher and every single episode is
archived on I read genetics Colorado
dot-com I think that's all I've got free
this week you guys coming up next time
we'll have the dab in granny next time
in a future episode we'll have the dab
and granny we're gonna talk about pests
and issues and how to solve those and
[ __ ] like that in the future so big shot
that's my ninja Spence I want to thank
my friends for joining me once again
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[ __ ] it went something like this
cruising down the street in my 6-4
jacking the [ __ ] slapping the holes
went to the park to get the scoop
knuckleheads out there
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 147 to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education &amp; Conquer see
grower if you're a professional growers
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross
the Jeff I want to thank you guys again
for joining me as always I want to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots been holding these
their music on my podcast big shot to
cat
you guys I'm starting this podcast off
kind of bummed out I'm disappointed in
myself I'm disappointed in technology
you guys I [ __ ] up you guys I recorded
a marvelous podcast with the davon
granny with Bret from Evo labs and of
course our friend Lindsay the traveling
stoner this evening I pulled out my zoom
h6 I took out my trusty memory Carter
through it my MacBook and the files are
all there I can grab the files and I can
move them to my macbook but for some
reason none of that [ __ ] is playable so
none of the material that I recorded
with Gavin granny will be aired on this
podcast unless one of my tech-savvy
friends is able to get this SD card and
pull this information off of there in a
usable format because so far I'm [ __ ]
I tried for about an hour all I did was
frustrate myself I was not able to get
it going
grannie podcast that I recorded is lost
it's available on her Facebook we did a
Facebook live video of it but I think
that's the only way you're going to hear
or see any of that episode granny I
apologize technology [ __ ] me I don't
know what else to say Brett I apologize
Lindsey I apologize the bad news is the
podcast is lost and gone for [ __ ]
ever technology aided Technology kicked
my ass you can't win every time the good
news however is that Davin granny's got
to come back to the show and Brett's got
to come back and Lindsey has to come
back and we have to do another podcast I
think I want to do a podcast was granny
by herself and with Brett by himself and
then a podcast with the group together I
think granny should be on the podcast
kind of frequently because she has a lot
of great [ __ ] to say so I actually think
Randy needed
oh [ __ ] so much to say I encouraged her
to start her own podcast was something
that actually said when she was here so
I apologize you guys I advertise that
like we're gonna have an amazing episode
for you today it's not going to be the
episode that you expected but I'm going
to do my best to make it amazing so
everybody that was on episode that
[ __ ] up I invite you guys all to come
back it was a great episode we hung out
at the candy cane and we smoked so much
hash that it was ridiculous we had a few
friends stop by pop tea and chosen one
pop deep glass art and chosen one glass
art showed up this took some dabs for a
little while so everybody that tried to
make that podcast happen I'm gonna move
forward and quit talking about that
let's talk about some positive things
more positive stuff you guys the other
night I got to see Joey Coco Diaz it
comedy works in downtown Denver you know
anything about me you know that I love
comedy you also know that I love comedy
works in downtown Denver I think that
Comedy Works downtown is probably the
best comedy club on the planet if it's
the second it's the second best to the
comedy store in Los Angeles California
other than that Comedy Works is the best
comedy club in the world now since I'm
talking about comedy you guys are son
Joey Coco Diez that is one of my that
might be my favorite damn comedian right
now
that dude blew the roof off of Comedy
Works hey guys Joey Diaz walked out on
stage and he grabbed the mic now before
he could get to the mic he got a
standing ovation
Joey walked out to a standing ovation he
grabbed the mic and he said what up you
bad [ __ ] and that's just the
way Joey starts the show and I knew it
was gonna be a party from then he had
this little strut in his stride the
whole time Joey was killing it the show
was hosted by a comedian whose name I
cannot recall he was a new guy he's got
some dreadlocks
he's a very entertaining dude there's a
another comedian whose name I cannot
remember who was the opening act then
there was a feature act whose name was
Rick who I've seen several times he's
pretty good he did see everyone trying
to do a bunch of weed jokes in Colorado
hey guys if you're a comedian and
aspiring comedian a touring comedian if
you're a funny guy and coming to
Colorado chill out on the weed jokes
we've heard it all we've heard every
[ __ ] weed joke you're gonna tell
unless you got some super creative weed
joke we've heard it trust me that's for
the pros that's for the noobs we've
heard all the weed jokes so the opening
actually but both all three did a couple
of weed jokes that hosted a couple we'd
joke to joey barely talked about weed
but joey smokes more wheat than you Joey
eats more edibles than you and Joey
still is able to go onstage and put out
an amazing [ __ ] comedy show Joey had
me laughing Joey Coco Diaz you guys he's
the host of a podcast called the Church
of what's happening now he was in a
movie called The Longest Yard he's an
amazing comedian he's Joe Rogan's
favorite comedian if that tells you
anything
he had me laughing so hard that the
sides of my stomach and ribs were
hurting my back was hurting in a weird
way my cheeks hurt there's a little spot
like right behind where my sun glasses
would rest on my head that [ __ ] hurt it
felt like tumors squeezing my head nose
from laughing so hard and then I told my
buddy I was like I'm laughing so hard I
think I'm gonna cry
and I think Joey might have heard me
because when he heard I was gonna when
he heard that I was gonna cry think he
too started hitting harder he's like oh
you're laughing now [ __ ] watch
this I had tears coming out of my left
eye my right eye was twitching weird I
haven't laughed that hard in a long time
and I probably won't laugh that hard
again cuz Joey was [ __ ] incredible he
blew the roof off of Comedy Works much
left to Joey Coco Diaz much loved to
Comedy Works and also a big special
thank you to my friend Baker Baker I
truly appreciate what you do for me I'm
always treated like a VIP at Comedy
Works I appreciate that
also shout-out to my friend buzzy for
buying the ticket so you guys are got a
sweet deal with my buddy buzzy he buy
his tickets and I Drive and then we go
see comedy shows and it's [ __ ]
amazingly fun so Jonathan everybody
involved that was a great night
shot it's my new friends that I made
that night let's talk about other
positive things that happened in my life
last night you guys I got to see one of
my favorite bands
Joseph Israel and the Jerusalem band
they were in my hometown of Pueblo
Colorado they were ten minutes away from
my house at the Bruges Ale House all I
do is drive over there find parking
March on in and get my reggae on it was
local it was amazing I shot it to the
Bruges Ale House that club is great it's
probably the best venue in Pueblo right
now there are a couple theaters they
compete but I'm gonna give that place
the number one venue for the vibe I
think in a back door that rolls up
you're right on the Riverwalk you can
see the river right behind you the sound
is good in there the vibe is good it was
a great place the band oh my goodness
Joseph Israel and the band tour because
I've been seeing Joseph Israel for
probably I've been watching his band for
probably ten years this was I've seen
several of their shows I've seen this
band progress and come a long long way
and last night's show is the best show
that I've ever seen them do it was the
second to last show on their tour and
you could tell that they just played
until they were done tonight's show
they're not gonna have a lot of energy
cuz they wore themselves out last night
whoever sees him tonight I'm sorry I
drained all their energy my favorite
album from Joseph Israel is an album
called gone are the days I think it was
his original release they played there
probably 15 songs on there I think a
couple of more like dub remixes so
there's like probably 10 songs on there
they must have played seven or eight of
them and they played all my favorites
now I could yell out a song and they
would play it for me they weren't gonna
play a song called
the truth is one of my favorites and
there was a break you know when the
musicians are like tuning their guitars
they're all talk and I've taken a drink
I yelled out truth and I was like right
in the front row so Joseph looked at me
like oh yeah and they talked about it
for a minute and they said we haven't
played this we don't practice this we
haven't played this since we recorded
the gone are the days album and they
started singing the chorus they just
started doing like a really cool
acapella harmony version of the chorus
and then once that chorus ended the
guitar player started playing the guitar
lick and they played the song truth for
me it wasn't tight and it wasn't perfect
but you know what it was beautiful that
my friends tried to play that song for
me so much love - Joseph Israel and the
Jerusalem band and the entire crew at
Bru's Ale House and an amazing time I
get to smoke after the show with a
couple of the guys something I should
mention I have been a huge fan of a bass
player by the name of Chris
Meredith he plays with Joseph Israel in
the Jerusalem band but he's also known
as a recording artist in Jamaica and
he's also well known for playing with
Stephen Marley I walked into the
building and Chris Meredith was just
standing there talking to Joseph Israel
and I realized he was gonna be the blade
bass player for the show that night that
put a huge smile on my face because he
recorded Joseph's album with him he went
on tour for the first tour and then he
had to go back to Jamaica and he took
off for a little while so we didn't see
him on tour with Joseph it was great to
see Chris and the original drummer back
together in the rhythm section I
actually got to meet the original
keyboard player from the gone are the
days album we got to talk about the
recording we got to talk about a few
things got to talk about the tuff Gong
recording studio Jamaica really nice to
hang out some Jamaican rastas some
awesome faithful folks floats with good
vibes folks a positive energy with good
things to say you guys I recommend that
you listen to Joseph Israel New
Jerusalem band I just talked about for
like five minutes we're gonna move on
from that but big shout out much love
much respect bunch of good vibes from
Joseph Israel to Jerusalem band last
night I had a great time shout out to
the friend they went with me I had fun
dancing we get to laugh at some some
crazy drunk people drunk people are
super entertaining I am so glad I do not
consume alcohol anymore I just smoke mad
cannabis there may have been a little
smoke session in the back of the club at
the end of the night that was a good
time
shout out to everybody all right let's
move on to some grow knowledge you guys
been talking about my weekend and my
week long enough
let's talk about Gro knowledge a few
episodes back I was asked how to handle
grasshoppers and what I've noticed is
everybody is getting bombarded with
grasshoppers and their outdoor cannabis
grow this year the number one way that
you can get rid of your grasshoppers is
just to clean up if you can mow all the
grass mow all the weeds get rid of
anywhere for them to live get rid of all
the stuff for them to eat the
grasshoppers won't want to come around I
understand that your neighbors probably
have a big-ass pile of grass and leaves
and [ __ ] in their yard that you cannot
do anything about it's illegal to go
over there with the torch and just burn
that [ __ ] down so if you're having
problems with grasshoppers somebody
recommended to me garlic and fermented
garlic sprays to help keep grasshoppers
and other pests away I assumed that this
would work on most insects and most
living creatures if you ferment some
garlic or mush garlic up into a spray
and spray that around your plants on and
or around your plants and on the
perimeter of your plants most bugs are
going to stay away from that and
definitely you will not have any
vampires so if you're worried about
vampires in the garden you could double
up on the garlic spray you'll be just
fine so shout it to the person that told
me about fermented garlic sprays and
using them in my garden to keep away
grasshoppers
outdoors because I don't grow outdoors
myself very much but a lot of our
friends do and I think you know the next
episode may feature our buddy Jesse and
we're gonna talk about some outdoor
stuff shout out to Jesse if you're
listening to this call me dude let's
plan this episode so we can get it
recorded well record it at my house
we'll use my computer we won't use the
zoom h6 because I'm paranoid too that
thing looks red it's gonna break and not
record the damn show again so probably
won't do that grasshoppers yes emails
I've got some emails here at my phone
people have asked some questions you
guys asked great questions I want to
give a shout out to everybody that sends
me an email I'm gonna try to read all of
the questions over time on the air I'm a
little bit backed up something after
record more episodes anyway
here's an email they came from let's see
how did he sign it he signed it as our
4/20 so shout out to Mazza 4/20 his
email says hoping you can read my
questions on the show been loving the
show helps me get through my day at a
mind-numbing job with robots you work
with robots or just like people who are
unaware at people who are programmed to
act like robots I'm curious no he said
questions for the show when you flip to
twelve twelve or eleven thirteen DJ
short style how long till you want to go
from metal-halide to HPS
I want to talk about this 12 12 or 11 13
DJ short style thing but Mazar 420 is
asking is when I change my light cycle
from my vegetative stage either 24 hours
on or an 18-6 cycle or maybe a 16-8
depends on where you are when I change
my light cycle to my flowering phase
which would normally be 12 12 or he says
the 11 13 DJ short style let me talk
about that for a minute
DJ short is a well-known breeder he's a
great speaker he's an author is well
educated and very passionate about the
cannabis plant
DJ short breeds amazing strains he is
known for the blueberry DJ shortbread
the flow so there's something in DJ
shirts catalog that you have smoke that
you have enjoyed they came from all DJ
now DJ does a trick when he's flowering
his plants he does not run them for 12
on 12 off he does 11 hours on and 13
hours off
his theory on this is that you will see
broader variants in Fino typical
expression from your plants so if you're
a breeder and you're looking for
phenotypes this extra hour really lets
the plants express themselves and show
the variation and show their potential
it also will save you one hour of
electricity over a sixty-five day cycle
which is gonna be 65 hours kilowatt
hours that you're not spending on your
lights it's also gonna be an hour
resting off of your air conditioning
it's also going to some people think it
increases their yield I tried it I
didn't like what it did to some of my
plants I did like what it did this some
of my plants so it's very plant specific
it's Stream specific it may be phenotype
specific I have not experimented enough
to know but a lot of people in the
community are switching to the 1113
method it saves money
it saves time and if you've got the
right varietals it will work for you one
thing I've noticed some of my heavier
sativas didn't like it in the beginning
it took them a while to get used to it I
liked my sativas on twelve twelve and
then toward the end of the phase that's
when I would start dropping down the
timers they didn't seem to really like
it when I went 13 hours of darkness
right away so that catches us up to
speed on the DJ Shore 11:13 method now
he says how long once you do this flip
do you want to go from metal halide to
HPS that's his first part of his
question generally I let it go 10 to 14
days rocking the metal halide when I see
the bud starting to form when I see
those little pre buds and the pre
flowers just starting to pop up they're
getting a little dandelions that's
usually when I switch in that bowl if
you if you really want to go crazy do it
three weeks because I think when you
flip those plants are gonna stretch for
about three weeks and keeping that
halide bulb in there really I think
helps prevent them from stretching so
much so keep that halide in there for 10
to 14 days if you want to go extreme go
21 days but you may slow down bud
development at that point I like to
switch it in there about that 14th day
because that's what my buds are gonna
start happening one thing that you can
utilize that I've done and had great
success with is mix and match spectrums
use a little bit of metal halide and use
a little bit of HBS if you can so I had
a I've got a reflector it's called the
Gro Zilla and I haven't used it in a
long time I should fire it up and do
some
experiments with it just for fun but
this reflector holds two bulbs and they
say not to put more than a thousand watt
total in there it may say 1,200 total so
you could put two 600 bulbs in this one
reflector what I did I put a 600 watt
high pressure sodium and a 400 watt
metal halide in there and hung that bulb
in a 5x5 hydro Hut and I put nine three
gallon pots under there and honestly I
grew some of the most photogenic and
most aromatic most flavorful and most
potent cannabis I have ever grown came
from that 5x5 Hut with that mix spectrum
light there was some very impressive
cannabis the only problem was it didn't
harvest what I wished it would have when
I heart when I use a thousand watt HBS
in one of those huts with proper ducting
and venting and air conditioning I can
pull a pound and a half really close to
two pounds it's hard to hit two pounds
in those huts cuz you're really limited
on height and space so you gotta like
top him out and pull him out real far
and train them you can get a pound and a
half out of one of those huts when I did
the HPS metal halide combo I got right
about a pound in a corner so it didn't
do what I would expect I think that 600
watt light kind of didn't let it push
but the flavor and the aroma and the
potency made up for the lack of weight
because it was for me I was growing it
from my own head stash so I didn't need
a whole bunch alright so that's the
first party question I would do it
somewhere between 14 and 21 days 10 days
if you're trying to go early 14 days is
about ideal 21 days if you're really
trying to keep those plants short
because that's that halide lamp is gonna
keep them from stretching on you as part
of why we do that so he also says also
was wondering how long once under 12 12
do you wait to switch your nutrients
from veg to bloom
he also says hope to hear my questions
get answered on the show sincerely
master 420 so he's wondering how long
from the day we switched to 1212 do we
wait to switch our nutrients from
vegetable I kind of do a slow transition
I believe that your plant is going to
absorb somewhere between 80 and 90% of
its nitrogen that all that all of its
going to observe through its whole life
it's gonna absorb most of that through
the vegetative stage once you hit
flowering once you get to that second or
third week of flowering you're not gonna
use a whole lot of nitrogen just enough
to keep the leaves green and keep the
plant moving so nitrogen is gonna kind
of fizzle out so you can switch the
nutrients right away if you'd like to
or you can keep those nutrients going
slowly and taper so if you're if you've
got grow and you've got bloom maybe go
seven to ten days with that grow before
you pull out the grow nutrient and throw
in the bloom it or you can just switch
right away it's up to you it kind of
depends on the strains also Gorilla Glue
really likes to eat so I kind of stick
with my veg nutrients for an extra week
or two with the Gorilla Glue
things like flow-flow doesn't require a
lot of food flow will just grow like a
son-of-a-bitch so I'll switch flow right
away when I go 12:12 that day they get
fed their bloom nutrients they start
getting but basically your first day of
bloom nutrients aren't very far off from
your last week of veg nutrients so it
shouldn't be too abrupt of a switch
either way but somewhere between that
first day and about seven to ten days in
is when I will totally have switched
from vegetable nutrients it kind of
depends on the plant it kind of depends
on what I'm doing it kind of kind of
depends on the room the stream the brand
of nutrients if I'm using botanic your
bottled newts my switch from my veg
stage to my flower phase like I said is
not very different it's a base nutrient
it's cal-mag liquid karma and maybe a
little bit of what else am I using in
there potassium silicates and there
wouldn't be a whole lot else oh there's
a dog resting on my feet and I just move
my foot kick from right in the head I'm
sorry puppy I didn't mean to do that boy
I'm sorry I apologize big shout out to
make the dog you guys make the dogs been
hanging out with me for a couple days a
cool ass dog you guys would like him
sorry I just kicked your head boy I feel
bad everyone on the show hears me
apologizing I won't do it again buddy
I'll pet you so yeah my veggie newts
there'll be some what did I say base
nutrients which would be the botanic air
pure blend Pro grow and then you've got
some cal-mag in there maybe a little bit
of liquid Carmen that's a potassium
silicates that's basically my veg mix I
would add something in there for roots
some sort of root inoculate use whatever
you would like you can use either the
plus life from veg bloom bigshot at the
veg bloom you could use the rhizome mix
the botanic air makes you could use what
am I think there's there's one product
I'm really thinking I can't say the name
o G bio war use some OG bio war in that
[ __ ] to get your roots going so add
that to it for roots and you got pretty
much everything you need there week one
a flower you basically want to feed the
same thing that you've been feeding for
the last couple weeks of veg
because your plants are just gonna start
transitioning so week one you've got the
option a week one to switch out that
pure blend Pro grow to the bloom formula
or you can do it at the start of week
two or definitely do it by week three
your plants are gonna need that much
nitrogen by week three and if you keep
going with the grow formula you may burn
them so you can go the first week or two
with your grow newts and then by week
three definitely switch all the way into
your flowering newts you don't need to
add everything by week three you really
don't need a lot at week three you can
start introducing things slowly maybe
get some sugars in there at week three
you don't need a lot of week three by
week four or five and six that's where
things really started cracking that's
when you're gonna want to start adding
bud boosters whatever you gonna use to
make the weight a little thicker or
whatever you gonna use to sweeten it up
four or five and six is when all that
[ __ ] comes in so if you're running a
strain that likes a lot of nitrogen keep
those nitrogen nutrients coming keep
that base grow new coming for the first
couple of weeks if you've got a strain
that's got plenty of nutrients if your
leaves are nice and lush green if
they're dark green don't even worry
about that grow new go ahead and switch
it over to the bloom nutrients alright I
hope that answered your question I know
I used a botanic hair as an example
that's the brand that I use in my
small-batch personal growth for myself
if I'm gonna smoke it it's probably
grown with botanic hair I do plan on
doing a side by side between botanic
hair and veg bloom in the near future
and I will be completely honest about
what I see and I will share my
experience and my results here on the
podcast you guys make sure you support
botanic hair and veg bloom I've used
them both in different environments and
different scenarios that are both
wonderful products I can't wait to run a
side-by-side I've got a 5 by 5 Hut and
another 5 by 5 hydro Hut in a row but
very similar light with the same lights
they're on a flip box every 12 hours one
comes on one shuts off so we got a
flowering chamber that's always being
used I'm gonna do veg bloom on one side
I want to do botanic hair on the other
and I will completely post a ton of
pictures to my Instagram and I'll let
you guys know how it goes all right I
want to thank a friend Maz our 424 sent
me a great email that gave me a lot of
information to ramble off at you guys
I'm pulling up the next email here on my
phone the next email comes from he
signed it with his real name I don't
know nice and hi my name is Kelvin
I'll see let's read this we have spoken
before but I have another question so I
live in Oklahoma
city where the heat gets pretty hot it
can get into a hundred or above in my
garden room I was wondering if a bigger
carbon filter what helped me out any
right now I'm running a 400 watt high
pressure sodium and a metal halide Apolo
light with a 4-inch carbon filter and
inline fan I was thinking about getting
an air conditioner but I don't want to
if I can lower temps with the carbon
filters during the day the temps get
from a hundred and ten to a hundred and
fifteen thank you Jeff
growers love dude 110 or 115 in your
grow room that is tremendously warm for
your plants your plants are freaking out
development stops growth and development
stops production stops inside your plant
around 85 90 degrees unless you're
introducing co2 if you're inducing co2
if you've got very high levels of co2
your plants can tolerate in the 90s 110
to 115 you're stressing the [ __ ] out of
those plants the buds are starting to
spread out you're gettin Airy buds
they're gonna be fluffy they're gonna be
small the plants are gonna be stunted
growth the humidity is probably getting
[ __ ] ridiculous in that room with that
type of heat the good thing about this
is you're not gonna have any bugs no
damn bug in the world is gonna want to
hang out 115 degree grow room so your
main question let's get to the point
here your question is well a carbon
filter help cool that room no not at all
a carbon filter does not provide any
cooling you need you you need to
introduce cooler air into that room and
you need to remove the hot air from the
room a fan won't help you because it's
just gonna blow hot air around you need
to exchange the air you got to get that
heat out of there maybe bigger ducting
and a bigger blower to blow the heat out
but a bigger carbon filter won't help
you cool the room you need an air
conditioner ifit's a large room get
yourself a window model like the window
kind if it's a smaller room and you
don't have a window for it get yourself
one of those portable rolling air
conditioners I really like the soleus
14,000 BTU portable air conditioner they
do not pay me they do not sponsor me
it's what I buy if I need an air
conditioner or a rolling air conditioner
for a home grow or a small grow that's
what I go get is one of those soleus
14,000 BTU - heater is an air
conditioner and it's a dehumidifier
all-in-one unit
it's about waist-high it's only about
three
feet tall looks like a little r2d2 you
guys and it's got a duck that runs out
and I think it's got a duck they can
come in also if you choose to ducked in
but I don't ducked in I just let the air
conditioner recycle the air in the room
is where that air comes from so that air
is already cool kind of that's going
into the compressor and then it blows
the heat through a duct a four-inch duct
and you can mount that duct wherever you
want
I usually board up a window cut a four
inch hole through the window put a duct
mount onto that window and run that four
inch air conditioning duct right out of
there that 14,000 BTU unit would be
overkill for your 400 watt HBS and your
metal halide apollo light I'm assuming
that your small grow room is inside of
another room since it's so small and I'm
not I'm not I'm not worried that you
have a small girl band I make it funny
but I'm just wondering is this grow room
inside of another room do you have this
like did you construct a small room
inside of a bedroom or this maybe a
closet also but if it's a small room
maybe you can air-conditioned that room
a little bit better and then duct the
heat out of your grow I just air
conditioned the outside environment so
that you're bringing in cooler air
you just need cooler air in that room
carbon filters not gonna cool off the
air a fan is not gonna cool off the air
you actually need some freon in there
you need an air conditioner bro so hope
that works I hope answered your question
big shout out to our friend Kelvin he
says we've spoken before I remember
seeing your name I remember your reading
your email address bro thank you for the
email I encourage you to send me more
emails I will read your questions and
answer your questions on the podcast all
the time if anybody wants to send me an
email I would love to help you out send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com if you want to follow me
on twitter it's at gfy each podcast
check me out on Instagram you guys I
post a whole bunch of quality cannabis
photography on Instagram it's at IRA
underscore genetics i reaiiy rie
underscore genetics check that out you
guys have to press pause for one quick
second I'm gonna take a DAB and a drink
and I will be right back with you a
pineapple jack shatter from turf backs
and I dunked it in OG ghost rain haze
fresh Terps from our friends at evil
labs then I feel like my brain was put
on a rocket and launched into outer
space
and then it blew up like one of those
beautiful fireworks and then it all just
came back together and floated down into
my head that's what happens when you
dunk your dad's in Terps and you take
big old fat dabs whoo shouts everybody
involved in making these Terps happen I
had the lab manager from Evo labs in the
last podcast and that's the one
the memory card ate and we cannot listen
to so sorry Brett I wish we could have
done that but Brett that means you gotta
come back on the show and smoke some
turps with me I owe a huge thank you to
Davin granny and I owe a huge thank you
to Brett Davin granny showed up with
enough Terps to dab out an army and
Brett will try to compete with that
so big thanks to you guys for showing up
to the podcast too well prepared also
thanks to the candy canyon for letting
me invade the small corner of their
facility I had four couches and a table
occupied and nobody can hang out that
region because we're doing the podcast I
didn't mind if people hung out but when
they saw the microphones come out they
heard me talk and they all just took off
to be polite I don't I think it's cool I
like the ambience and the vibe in the
background I'm rambling like a
[ __ ] hashtag they like it when I
ramble I wanted to share with you guys a
little progress on my most current
breeding project if you follow me you
know that I am a breeder
I am the head breeder for I read
genetics I am currently working with a
male plant that I call a rise the screen
is known as a rise the male plant
himself has been named Solomon that is
King Solomon he is going to father many
children he will be the grandfather to
many children but Solomon is my male
plant is a an arise plant which is a
cross of a golden goat female that was
pollinated by a Daybreaker male
Daybreaker came from gage green genetics
so much love and respect today - gage
green the day breaker is Joseph Oh G and
Kim D so there's gonna be a little bit
of og cush and Kim dog lineage in there
and then I crossed that - I put the
pollen from that male on to the golden
goat the golden goat is Island sweet
skunk and Romulan and a Hawaiian sativa
so you got that tropical tasty flavor I
pollinated it with that cushy skunky
funk flavor a little bit of everything
in my opinion mixed it all together and
it made a strain called a rise
I found three or four really great
phenotypes of the arize there's a very
golden goat reminiscent phenotype of her
eyes I do not keep that one because I've
got a golden goat it's too similar I get
rid of it there's one that's got this
sweet skunky funky you can't keep it in
a baggie without all your friends in
smoke some of that weed with me kind of
smell to it that's my favorite female of
the bunch then there's one that makes
really long skinny buds and I don't know
where it came from but it gives you this
hazy high I don't know where the haze
came from in the genetics but it just
makes your head melt your eyes just get
[ __ ] squinty you go dumb you just
start stuttering it so that phenotype is
great but you know there are three or
four key key phenotypes that I found
I've put all three of those phenotypes
not the golden goat dominant phenotype
but I've put my three favorite
phenotypes in a room with a male of this
same cultivar but the male of the same
strain from the same seed back they're
all F wands so I put the F ones the male
and the female in a room this male I've
posted pictures of into my Instagram he
makes male flower clusters as long as my
arm which is very amazing for a male
plant to make buds like this it's
incredible it's got a little bit of
resin on it it smells very pungent it's
got a hint of vomit to the smell as a
breeder vomit is a good treat if you've
got a male plant that smells like vomit
or feet or a bar trashcan that is a good
breeding plant it's gonna pass on good
good aromatic traits so I've got that
male and then I've got let's see what
else is in there there is a golden goat
female because I'm gonna do a little bit
of a golden goat backcross there's a
lemon skunk female in there because I
want to see what this arised does to the
lemon skunk and there is a grateful dog
female so there are multiple themed
phenotypes of the arise so there would
be a rise f2s coming out very soon it'll
be tested by a bunch of my people before
they're available to you guys but a lot
of people get to test them out then
there will be grateful dog to arise
which doesn't even have a name
there will be golden goat to arise which
would be like a golden goat backcross
kind of and then there'll be lemon skunk
cross to arise which who knows what
that's gonna do that's gonna be amazing
both of those plants make a lot of resin
both of those plants have a really nice
structure I really see a lot of great
things so I'm excited about that they're
currently the date today is I'm pressing
my button on my phone as the 14th they
went into flower on the 3rd so they're
11 days in the male plant is getting big
old balls
his balls are starting you know when the
male plant starts to flower out the
balls point up but now they're starting
to hang his nuts are starting to hang
which means within the next four to six
days I'm gonna have pollen coming out of
there which may be a little earlier than
I wanted so I'm gonna move him over to
another room to keep him away from the
girls because the girls their pistols a
little you guys call them hairs probably
the little white pistols the hairs on
the plant that looks like a dandelion
I want those nice and thick and stout
before I put that pollen on there so I'm
gonna move this boy to another area just
to keep him from dust and his pollen on
these girls too early and then once I
see all the girls have their pistols
nice and hairy nice and furry
almost that tarantula look then I'm
gonna bring the boy over there and I'm
gonna just leave him in the room with
them overnight and then in the morning
as soon as lights come on my give a
little shake and that pollen is gonna
dust all those plants and I'm gonna do
that probably 4 or 5 days again or 5 4
or 5 days later I'm gonna do that again
just let the lights come on and walk in
there and give him a little bit of a
shake and just get that pollen all over
all those plants so when I see a little
bit of a shake guys if you grab a male
cannabis plant that is in full flower
that's got pollen sacs hanging off of it
you could flick it like listen to I'm
gonna flick the microphone stand that's
all you got to do you flick it that hard
pollen goes there everywhere everywhere
so after that I'll have to take a shower
off to change clothes I'll have to go
spray down any female plants that I do
not want receiving pollen it'll be some
work but it'll be definitely definitely
worth it off to change clothes wash my
dreadlocks before I go to anybody else's
garden I wouldn't disrespect anyone
else's garden like that I'll put on
specific clothes they cover me up most
of the ways that I just drop them right
in the washer it's a chore but that's
where my breeding project is you guys
the mail is just getting ready to draw a
polity I'm I just kicked the doggy and
I'm sorry boy sorry dude I didn't mean
to kick you his head's right here on my
foot so every time I get excited it was
my st. no UFC I apologize
so my plants are the Britton project is
11 days the males
just dropping pollen the male is just
rot starting to drop all the females are
almost ready to take it I'm gonna
separate him for a little bit just to
put some tension in the room then
reintroduce them together in few days
and then once they pollinate it's
probably gonna be about six weeks before
those seeds are ready for harvest I'm
gonna let them go about seven I don't
wanna let go too long but I want them
nice and done I want um hard then we'll
cut down the plants we will set them all
in individual areas over individual
containers and just let them dry for a
couple few days once they I will pre
trim them at that point will give them
will just take off all the big leaves
and we cut them down most of the
families will be gone so well dry it
we'll hang them let them dry and then
you just take the plants and you cut
basically cut one stick off and I put on
rubber gloves and hold it over like a
pie plate and just start crushing up the
buds and you can just hear the seeds
fall out it's like you're smoking
old-school Mexican brick weed and all
those seeds respond tink tink tink tink
tink tink tink into the pie plate just
crumble them up with my fingers and then
I push all the wheat up to one side and
I tip the pan and all the seeds roll
down to the other side and I take those
out put them in a jar it gets carefully
labeled of what it is I leave the lid
open for a couple few days just so that
if there's any moisture in there that
those seeds will try out so now I've got
a mason jar full of well labelled seeds
and then once I've got all of them I'll
weigh the seeds get a good estimate of
how many seeds I've got then I'll send a
lot of those seeds out to friends of
mine with a note that says these are
testers please test these take a lot of
pictures make a lot of notes let me know
what you got I will give some to local
people and the requirement is if you
find a champion I get a clone of that
sir you've got something good I get that
I get a clone of the best one please
that's kind of I'll give some texture
packs it'll be probably looking at 12
weeks before anything will even be done
from this point but there will be seeds
in twelve weeks they'll be testers
people check them out I'll post pictures
of what comes of it cuz I'll grow a
bunch of them by myself the dog just got
up in life because I kicked him in the
head I'm sorry boy sorry I didn't mean
to kick
you guys don't ever take your dog in the
head love your dog scratch your dog
and breed good cannabis ladies and
gentleman that is all I've got free this
week I wanted to update you on my
breeding project I hope you enjoy
following along with my breeding project
I'll give you another update in a couple
of weeks and let you know how things are
going you guys I'm gonna wrap up the
show if you've got a product you'd like
me to review or if you'd like to sponsor
the podcast send me an email at school
from your heart at hotmail.com I'd love
to hear from you make sure you follow me
on all of the social media you guys and
also now that the show is over go to
iTunes to go to the iTunes Store search
for the podcast sections there's a
review section no wait I [ __ ] that up
you got to go to podcast then you got to
go to grow from your heart when the
doors my heart a section pops up there's
a little just a little icon of the show
click on that one and then go click on
ratings and reviews and then type in a
review let me know what you think of the
show and I'll read your review on a
future episode
while you're there you've got the option
to give me some stars you know I want
five stars but I'm not gonna beg for
five stars give me the amount of stars
that you feel I deserve and I would
truly appreciate it because I want to
thank everybody for listening to the
show once again big shout out to make
the dog shout out to my Buddy Baker
shout out to Comedy Works Jonathan
Joseph Israel shout out to Joey cocoa
Diaz shout out to each and every one of
you you guys love one another because
I'm gonna sign off for now
shouts my ninja Spence and until next
time take a fat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
tribute
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
we got follow you zombies get that
bounce on your chair
get that blow up your TV
no no man I'm playing it this old town
you see it right you gotta lose the
booze tonight
I got the festival coming around
Papa's
the streets shadows we review
I feel y'all hit with the beat love is
to shuffle sorry
whatever you got
keeping the one we're turning with the
best
[Music]
[Applause]
tips on your bed
[Music]
hanging out over the top
you