yo yo this is coot dog and Catherine
from mystic roots and you're listening
to grow from your heart podcast big up
Rasta man Jeff
[Music]
yeah welcome back Canada's community
it's time for episode number 266 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation a thread if you're a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots man to let him use their
music on my podcast big shout out to Kat
ku and the entire mystic roots crew
welcome to the show everybody I just
took a big fat bag of some super
delicious chocolate live butter it was
extracted by our friends at CRX I picked
this up over at levity wellness in
Colorado Springs
this is Rasta jeff approved this is a
nice sativa got my head doing nice
things it's got a great flavor to it
I like to weight this battered feels in
my lungs I know I talked about love and
Shatter but when you smoke the batter it
kind of expands in your lungs and you
don't have to smoke as much and you get
a big fat dab Rasta Jeff approved I like
it hopefully it makes me real talkative
real clear for the show thanks for
jumping in you guys it's good to see you
here let's see what are we gonna talk
about in this podcast let's talk about
my breeding project to keep telling you
about for the past few weeks I've been
updating you about a breeding project it
is just about completed that's right
maybe when I finished this podcast the
lights will have come on and I'll be
able to go in the room and I'll see how
much longer we've got to go been pulling
a random seed out every couple of days
to look and see some of them were
getting nice and hard a couple of them
weren't where I wanted them yet so maybe
maybe they're ready today there's some
new stuff in there I crossed of course
everything was crossed to arise arise is
a golden goat female that was pollinated
by a Daybreaker male Daybreaker is Kim D
cross to Joseph oh gee so that makes
real OG cushy real Kim funky feet kind
of smell and traits to it then he put
the golden goat in there it made it kind
of sweet made it kind of tropical it
made it grow bigger and faster so I took
the arize I took a male of the arize put
that in the grow room with a whole bunch
of sexy ladies there's a strawberry
fields in there
that's gonna be brand new I don't have
Strawberry Fields cross to arise until
now I just made a small tester badge to
check out for myself we'll grow those
see how they go what else is in there
there is uh there's a grateful dog so we
could make more morning dew seeds there
are a couple of arise females so we can
make more arise f2 seeds there's a
kosher cushion there that I'm really
excited about I'm gonna make some a rise
to kosher cush that'll be my new cross
that I'm gonna test out for myself and
see where that goes but I've been
talking a lot about my breeding project
and I'm excited that it is almost done
all right what else should we talk about
yo
Thursday night I am proud of my city we
finally hosted a very successful
cannabis event we've had a few small
cannabis events here in this town we
used to do a little smoke out sesh at
the cloud9 hookah bar then one night the
cops came and everyone got paranoid and
nobody showed up after that but we had a
large official smoke event it wasn't a
smokey van it was a cannabis event but
there was no consumption we'll get to
that here in just a minute I'm turned
down the music slowly so I can think
better it's hard to think with all that
music in the headphones
Cinci night we had sensi night here in
Pueblo Colorado on Thursday it was it
the Union Depot which is the old train
station is what it used to be I was a
big fancy building it was a great event
everything was done with class there was
not consumption inside the event however
there were three dab buses sponsored by
different companies outside and you were
able to go in one of those buses and
take a DAB if you brought your own you
could smoke your own [ __ ] concentrate in
there excuse me if you did not bring
your own concentrate they had a dab to
offer you in there it was free just hop
on the bus take a little dab the bus was
parked so you weren't going anywhere
the catch is you're not allowed to smoke
in a building like the the Union Depot
that would be illegal to smoke in there
because that's basically a public place
but those dab buses are private property
so all the windows are blocked out you
can't see in there they check your ID
make sure you're old enough you go up in
there you take a DAB then you come out
coughing so that was the catch that was
how people were able to medicate of
course if you're Rasta Jeff you've got
your own ways of medicating you
medicated heavily before you left or
perhaps before you walked in but anyway
sensing I think it was a huge success it
was a very classy event it was set up
for those of you that don't go to any
cannabis events if you do go to cannabis
events it was just like all the other
events except you couldn't smoke there
if you don't go to events
to basically like a trade show everyone
sets up their little booths all around
the walls so you walk you mill around in
circles and they build like a little
island in the middle of other booths
that are back to back so you just walk
around and do the laps and check out all
the vendors and all the booths and trade
business cards and pick up free samples
of things they can't give out product
but they can give you samples of like um
maybe people were giving out a lot of
hats and stickers and [ __ ] like that
some of the nutrient companies had small
nutrient samples to give away so stuff
like that they were giving out it was
like most any other trade show that
you'd go to for any other industry
except this was cannabis based for being
a pluggable event I was actually quite
impressed I wasn't sure if I even wanted
to go the always lovely always beautiful
miss Jenny Beth works for a dispensary
and she was she wasn't required to go
but I mean her dispensary asked that she
go and she went and so of course I met
up with her and a couple of her
co-workers and then I hung out with of
course everybody from Three Rivers you
guys white Mike went to an event why am
i Carly ever makes it to these cannabis
events white Mike was there walking
around being social had a big smile on
his face I think he might have been high
out of his mind for a little bit but
Mike was there having a good time
everybody from Three Rivers was there
all the management big shout out to miss
Kelly for going to an event I think that
was her first uh industry event of
course Christina was there having a good
time and so I was sitting at home
debating if I wanted to go I was making
myself some food and I was like I might
eat food and I might go down to that
event or I might go take a nap and then
uh Mike texted me and he's like you need
to come down here and then Maddy texted
me and she's like you need to come down
here and then miss Jenny was like hey
where are you and I was like you know
what I should put on my shoes and I
should go hang out with all my friends
at the Scentsy party and you know what
I'm really glad I did because I ran into
a lot of friends people that I have
known for a long time people that I
haven't seen for a long time and then I
bumped into a couple of people that I'd
never met before
and that was a lot of the fun I want to
give a shout out to a guy named Warren I
met Warren right when I walked in and
also Steve Young Steve I don't know if
you listen to the podcast but it was an
honor to finally meet you we will hang
out you live very close to me and I will
make some free time and I'll get over to
where you are and we will hang out and
medicate and talk I'm sure you've got a
lot to teach me so I met a lot of new
friends people I'd never met before ran
into all the Pueblo people were there if
you're from Pueblo
and you didn't go you should have gone
because all the local stoners were there
all the people from the dispensaries all
the people from all the head shops they
were all there hanging out everybody got
along there was no beef it was a great
time um it was a lot of fun I ran into
the legendary Matt Foxx Cooper Watts was
there Linus was there would have Linus
the always beautiful maddie was there
Spence from garden of Weeden was there
Mike from garden of Weeden was their
frosty organics was there hanging out
miss Jenny Beth was there it was a huge
party a bunch of great people were there
Vegas from the spot was there getting
goofy from with everybody it's a really
good time so big shot at two cents a
night I think it was a huge success
there was no consumption in the building
however they were serving alcohol and
around mid 10:30 or 11:00 you could tell
that they were serving alcohol at the
vibe kind of changed people started
getting uh they didn't care to represent
their brand as much as they did around
nine o'clock
I may have stuck around the event a
little longer I was getting hungry miss
Jenny Beth was getting hungry it was
time to go but I may have stuck around
the event a little longer to see more
people and be a little bit more social
if there wasn't so much alcohol going on
I could see the vibe changing and I did
not want to stick around to see if
anything was gonna go wrong because
there were a lot of people there and
with that many businesses there could be
rivalries there could be beefs that
nobody even knows about and sometimes
alcohol will light the fire underneath a
beef and some [ __ ] could go wrong so I
left I don't appreciate the alcohol at
the Cannabis events but I get it since
it's an event and it's social I
understand it I just wish that we could
smoke why can we drink alcohol but we
can't smoke in there it's weed in
Colorado we voted to regulate cannabis
like alcohol so they can be in the same
building they get along they're really
good friends I don't understand it
anyway overall since he met was a huge
success I just wish that we could smoke
some dabs in there while the people are
drinking beers seems fair
all right you guys I'm going to press
pause I'm gonna take a quick dab I'm
gonna take a drink you can hear my
throat's getting that thing again so
I'll be back in just a second and we're
going to read a couple of emails
together hang tight
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back and
I'm well medicated I just took a pretty
chunky dab of some lemon party ambrosia
from apothecary farms big thumbs up to
the lemon party there's a lemon Terp in
there that I just love something about
that is delicious
you know I just realized that in the
background you guys may hear some street
racing going on in my neighborhood I
live a few blocks away from a pretty
large street it's a big big open street
and they are street racing like a mofo
out there tonight so if you hear in the
background I do apologize I've got some
software and some equipment that's
trying to cut that out but they're loud
tonight and I can hear it in my
headphones which makes me think you guys
can hear it so I apologize for that I'll
run this show through another program
and I'll try to take all that background
noise out but I don't know how well it
will work let's get back into the
podcast ladies and gentlemen before I
took a quick break I mentioned that we
were going to read some emails on a
previous episode around Thanksgiving
time I asked you guys to tell me if you
consume cannabis if you smoke some weed
if you took a DAB if you ate some
edibles with a family member or somebody
knew or somebody that you haven't smoked
or consumed with in a long time I wanted
to hear about your Thanksgiving family
cannabis experience I got a couple of
responses I printed out one to read on
the show tonight I'm pulling it out of
the pile of papers and it goes like this
this is hi my name and address and I'm
just kidding
I'm not gonna read this person's name it
said I'll remain anonymous right at the
top of the paper and it says you asked
for your listeners to share if they
smoked with the new relative on
Thanksgiving and I absolutely did for
the first time ever I shared a bowl with
my mom
well congratulations man that's super
cool they go on to say we had a blast
and she over shared quite a lot about
her newfound dating experiences I never
thought it would happen but I'm a little
jealous of my mom's sex life so there
you go
peace out and I actually did take a fat
dab and I gave my mom a hug well a quick
awkward hug signed no-name a no-name
thanks for the great response I really
like that you uh you finally smoked a
bowl with your mom and I think it's
funny I kind of apologized but I'm kind
of grinning funny at you that you had to
hear about your mom's newfound dating
experiences I find it super awkward that
you're jealous of your mom's sex life
that means you need to step up your game
but anyway I'm glad that you got to
smoke
down with mom that's always a great
thing I haven't smoked with my mom in
quite a long time she used to go to
concerts and stuff with me we still do
[ __ ] together but now she's uh she's got
a job that does drug testing and so she
just can't smoke and also she's clumsy
as [ __ ] so she's just got that kind of
luck that she would smoke a joint with
me just to celebrate something silly and
just the next day she would pick up a
cotton ball and it would cut the [ __ ]
out of her because my mom is clumsy she
could hurt herself with a bag of cotton
balls I don't know how she could do it
but she can but so I've been smoked with
my mom in ages but we used to get down a
long long time ago my mom's kind of a
lightweight it should take 1 or 2 puffs
she's like the new weed is too strong
she take like one or two hits off with a
good weed and she'd just be [ __ ]
wrecked it'd be so funny but years and
years years like a hundred years ago my
mom and I smoked weed I think the last
time we smoked was at a Tom Petty
it's probably a Tom Petty concert at Red
Rocks so shout out to moms anyway to my
my listener dude I'm glad you got to
smoke with your mom keep that bond
strong all right I'm gonna move into
another email this one's got a different
tone I don't think this one needs much
introduction everything is here and the
message was well done I goes like this
first off love your podcast I found it a
couple of weeks ago and I've just been
devouring episodes whenever I get a
chance I've been learning some great
things and it's been really helpful my
favorite so far was episode 252 on
topping as like most growers do
sometimes I was nervous about topping my
girls too low or too high that same day
well so far thanks for the compliment
dude I'm glad I was able to help you out
with episode 252 I'm glad you find me
helpful then the email goes on like this
it says I think you should consider
revisiting episode 264 with someone who
has more organic based growing
experience and have a serious debate
about the pros and cons of synthetic vs.
organics I was hoping to glean some
useful info for comparisons and ways the
two can work together but I couldn't
even get through the episode because it
was so biased against organics I think I
started out as a bottle grower myself so
I definitely know that they have their
advantages but I've been making the
switch to organics because I was
starting to feel like a mad scientist
with all the bottles charts and mixing
times etc I've been able to simplify a
lot of things saved money and traded
time spent mixing notes for spending
time enjoying my plants and the garden I
worked so hard to put together it was a
little frustrating to hear such a great
resource steer so many growers toward
direction when we need all the honest
unbiased information we can get in a
market where companies are eager to
profit off of people's lack of knowledge
Clackamas coud tad Hussey and tad Hesse
of the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast or Nelson Lindley who grows a
mix of organic and said synthetic are
all great knowledgeable resources that I
think would be happy to discuss with you
if you reached out just a thought
keep up the great work and stay black
eyed pretty sure that's a Joey Diaz
reference so I will stay black
[ __ ] and if that's a Joey Diaz
reference I'm not calling you a
[ __ ] idle line it's a compliment
god damn it ah but anyway I hope you're
a Joey Diaz fan cuz that doesn't make
sense if not anyway let's get back to
email get serious here um I appreciate
this I know you're calling me out and
saying I gave a biased opinion on my on
my podcast when I did what I tried to do
was a fair debate
I appreciate this I'm not taking this
personally I'm taking it personally but
I'm not taking it as an attack
personally I'm taking this as proper
guidance my thing was uh I am a bottled
synthetic grower so I of course I lean
that way I tried to do it unbiased
obviously I failed at that so thank you
for pointing it out um if you're in
Colorado and you'd like to come on the
show let me know I'll get you on the
show if you can put me in touch with the
folks that you listed at the bottom here
or send me a link to get in touch with
them I would love to get in touch with
those folks I'm sure I could find him I
help me out I honestly clack admit makes
me nervous you know so much about
cannabis he's just gonna come blow my
mind but I would love to have him on the
other two folks I'm not sure who they
are but I am aware of Clackamas coot
another thing you said you only listen
to halfway through the episode you
didn't hear the end where I said that
organic growers are gonna win because at
the end of the world
we don't have bottles when the end of
the world scenario comes whatever that
is I always try to think like that I'm
kind of a paranoid hippie shit's gonna
go down dude I don't know what it is but
some shits gonna go down and one day
you're not gonna have a grow light and
you're not gonna have a bottled nutrient
so I think that in that case your
organic farmers are gonna win because
they know how to farm they know how to
grow everything if they know how to grow
cannabis organically indoors they could
do it all natural the under the Sun
they're gonna win so I wish you would
have listened to the whole episode that
may have helped you out but um I do
agree that maybe I was a little bit
biased because that's my experience I
can't I I tried
keep it fair but obviously I missed it a
little bit so I apologize for [ __ ] it
up and not getting a fair episode like I
should have done so if anybody out there
would like to come and do a friendly
debate I want to open this up and keep
it going I want to keep this
conversation happening
I think this email just sparked even
more of a debate if you want to come on
and keep it friendly I don't want you to
if you are on Team organics or on Team
salts or on Team organics plus salts you
can't come on my show and bash the
opposite but you can come and tell me
the pros and cons that you feel are why
you do what you do so if you want to
have a friendly debate if you're in the
southern Colorado area I've got gear
that I can come to you I've got a zoom
h6 that fits in my pocket I can carry
all my [ __ ] my hoodie if I need to drive
up to you I got to get the car fixed
that's another story but once you get
the car fixed I can drive right up to
you we can have this debate wherever you
are if you're in the southern Colorado
maybe Denver area make some time I'd
love to have this conversation maybe one
two maybe three other people we could
talk about organics versus synthetics
all together now we can make it a fair
debate if you guys want to put me in
touch with these folks that I just
mentioned in the email Clackamas coot
tad hussy or Nelson Lindley
I would not be opposed to you guys
putting me in touch with them
I'll keep this email sitting on the top
of the pile here so I can research those
names heed the person that sent me this
did you put a name on here I'm not gonna
call it your name your names on the top
of your email hmm you should correct
that if you don't want people to know
your name because it says your full name
up there ah but I do appreciate the
email and uh thank you for the
constructive criticism and pointing out
that I kind of [ __ ] that up and maybe go
back and listen to the second half just
so that you can hear that I tried my
best man I really did I I'm not on
either team I just I use one so I have
much I have more to say about the other
it's like if I try to tell you about I
don't know ask me about my iPhone and
ask me about your iPhone I don't know I
know the basics of yours but once you
get to the apps and [ __ ] I don't know
what you got I know everything that's in
my phone been doing it I don't know your
phone so I I can only tell you so much
about your phone it's an iPhone it's got
a case on it glass screen you know what
I mean just like mine does but I know so
many more details about my ex I'm doing
that so maybe that's why I seem biased
and I apologize if anybody else out
there has any input or has any
complaints about any other episode I'd
love to hear you guys I think I just
showed that I can take criticism well
and it's gonna make me a better
a podcaster a better teacher a better
grower and I'm trying to move everybody
forward together so you guys are moving
me forward by calling me on the [ __ ]
like this I'm not afraid of it I'm a
grown-ass man I can take constructive
criticism bring it please so thanks
again for the email it doesn't look like
you want me to see your name let's move
forward into the next email this one I'm
looking to see if they've got their name
on here then to done I see their name
right there but no [ __ ] starts the
name like this hello my name is Anthony
I have basically zero experience growing
cannabis but I want to try
I've been reading tons and listening
exclusively to your grow show I have
some seeds from what I assume is Mexican
brick weed a sativa I'm guessing i've
sprouted several seeds i pulled off from
this stuff and it shoots up brother I
have heard that all these problems stem
from poor white I was always saying it's
just shooting straight up I hear all
these problems stem from poor light or
could it be that it's just the strain
the real question I guess I'm asking is
if the light isn't the problem could it
just be tall as plants I'm indoor
growing on a low-budget do-it-yourself
grow box
I've run on a post these stems okay I'm
gonna stop right here yes you need more
light the thing that plants want the
most is light its lights and then maybe
next is either water or air and then
they need some dirt I don't do that mine
that's not science but that's plants
need light light is the number one thing
that plants grow off of and then water
and air those are the three things you
need them without those things you can't
have a plant but light keeps that plant
alive you got to feed that plant as much
light as you can give it or they're just
gonna stretch especially seedlings I
like to get the light really close to
the seedlings keep it right on them keep
I give them some T fives let's set the
row eight T fives right on top of that
seedling tour it's about maybe six or
eight inches above it and it's just
getting illuminated and I do it for 18
hours maybe 24 hours a day and the
seedlings just get them started super
strong so if they're stretching up if
they're shooting up real tall that's
called getting leggy in the weed world
um they're stretching they're trying to
get to the light another thing they need
a fan on them if they're growing that
fast you if you they're growing that
fast and you put some wind on them
you'll at least make them strengthen
themselves up they'll get a little
stronger but you need more light you
need to get more light and the plants
need to be closer to more light that's
you're obviously the problem just from
what you've described it is not the
strain
you put under that condition without
enough light is going to stretch it's
gonna shoot up like that things you've
said indicate that you need more light
so I'm gonna keep going it says where
was I did today I'm in it growing on a
bud I've read that these pas that I've
read on a post that these stems can be
planted deeper and will develop roots
does that make them a longer tap root
does that make the stem a longer tap
root I'm not necessarily making so
you're talking about taking this plant
that's too leggy putting it in a larger
pot digging a deep hole burying it so
let's say your plant has grown 8 inches
you want to bury it down to where you've
only got 3 inches sticking out that is
effective but you can also overwater and
kill the plant doing that but it will
work it will help you out it doesn't
make a longer tap root necessarily it
just makes the stem buried deeper but
it's the same same idea but no because
the tap root developed away at the
bottom there and grew out so you just
make you're just burying it deeper which
works I will do that occasionally
if I start off my plants in a cup or a
small pot and they over grow that and
they get a little too big I'll cut off
some of the bottom branches and bury
them a little deeper in a 3 or 7 gallon
pot before I flip them and that does
help so they're more of the email will
the plant get more oxygen then um no
won't get more oxygen than your barring
it will get less oxygen will it ruin my
plant
if you overwater it if you buried it too
hard if you bury it too tight if you
don't put it in good soil if your rough
about it yes you can ruin your plant the
plants are very delicate when they're
that small you can touch it and break it
in half when it's that little
so you got to be super super careful
then you say this is costing me nothing
out of pocket so I can take the chance a
short segment of leggy seedlings or
whatever you think may help me and
others like me would be super awesome um
so we see he said a short segment on
leggy seedlings or whatever you think
may help some others like me would be
super awesome yeah I'm glad to help you
out man I'm gonna kind of do that right
now so if it's costing you nothing and
your ceilings are that stretchy and
you've got more from that Mexican brick
weed I would recommend starting more and
cuz right now you're already starting
off with a struggle it's if you've got
free seeds out of that brick wheat if
you have more start more of them dude
just start more and then get more light
put more light closer to your seedlings
that's why your seedlings are stretching
put them in under either like a t5 or
underneath like a 250 watt high pressure
sodium or
a 250 watt Hal I don't know if they make
that I've never seen that I've never
tried to buy that or underneath a 400
watt halide lamp and then just put it
kind of close not don't let it burn them
but you want them to get plenty of light
and you want it to be kind of warm and
you want to put a light light fan on
them not hard with the fan you want to
move the air and as they grow and then
start increasing the fan so that's a way
to get them a little stronger
but if you've got plenty more start more
to throw the shitty ones away and start
fresh if you can especially if they're
free especially if it didn't cost you
anything don't be in a hurry start right
you don't want to start with a struggle
that sucks just starting off with
problems you could just go back and fix
it now and have a better start you'll
blow up the old one and build any one
mm-hmm so I guess that is my short
segment on leggy seedlings get the light
closer use the proper soil I hate to
advertise it kind of soil but if you're
new and you need a cheap light fluffy
soil that you can go out and just drop
some seedlings in light warrior from Fox
farms will work just fine they're not
I'm not advertising for them it just
works it's easy you can go buy it it's
available at almost every hydroponic
store just go get yourself some light
warrior if you're an experienced grower
you can figure it out I bet what kind of
soil to use if you don't want to use the
light warrior if you know why you don't
want to use light warrior you know what
to get that's what I think I'm trying to
say there's just it's not there's
nothing wrong with white warrior just
some more experienced growers would
prefer other stuff but it will work
great for you if you're if that's what
you need
it'll do it so go get yourself some
white warrior soil go to the grouse
store and get a t5 light if you're gonna
grow some stuff get the proper stuff put
it under some good lights put it under a
t5 light maybe the short one the little
18-inch long one I don't know how long
they are like 18 24 inches you don't
need the big 3-foot by whatever one get
the one with like the four bulbs in it
put a few a few cups of the light
warrior soil in there and put the plants
into the dirt and then let them pop up
like that and then see how they grow
then you'll see the difference if you
keep that light close they'll start
pushing out and then you'll have to
transplant them pretty soon and they
don't need a bigger light and then
you'll have to flower I mean you'll need
a bigger light so yeah I have not list
all of your podcast yet so I'm not sure
if it's something you have covered yet I
listen to them at work on headphones
while I'm trimming trees in Missouri man
that sounds like it could be so much fun
sometimes
and I'm not even being a smartass
sometimes I just want to go outside
we've got a big roll up garage door at
the grow that we bring pallets in when
we get deliveries and [ __ ] we'd bring
the scissor lift in through there we
bring the forklift in through there and
sometimes when that thing opens up I'm
like lalalalala outside I just want to
go play cement sometimes would be
awesome just to be out there trimming
trees with you in Missouri with the
headphones on not dealing with people
that'd be so rad anyway he says keep up
the awesomeness and I appreciate your
helping the grow community both very big
and very small and going off to hug my
mom signed Anthony P hey man thank you
for the great email thanks for the great
question about seeds I hope I can help
you out basically more light and closer
if you can uh don't if you can put your
hand in the light where the seeds are
put your hand right at the top of the
seedlings and it should feel warm but
not hot you should just be able to leave
your hand there it should be warm but
not hot it should be comfortable ooh
that's nice and you just want to leave
your hand there that that's what the
plant wants to it just wants to get a
nice little suntan just wants to kick it
it does want to get cooked
I just wants to feel warm so they'll
like closer get more light on it
everything will work just fine one thing
I would be concerned about though if you
don't have enough light for seedlings
you're not gonna have enough light to
flower plants so it's gonna be time to
start thinking about bigger better
lights and more space and getting all
that ahead of yourself instead of having
those seedlings stuck under a small
space and not be prepared so start
getting that planned out before we start
those new seeds if you choose to start
new seeds thanks again for the great
email I do appreciate it ladies and
gentlemen if you want to send me an
email if you've got grow questions if
you need advice if you need guidance you
can easily reach me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you I would also appreciate it
if you follow me on the social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the grow from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast and on
Instagram I use my other company name
it's ireon der score genetics I RIE
underscore genetics simply search for
ira genetics I'm sure it will pop up
give me a follow I post a bunch of great
cannabis photography also the YouTube
channel has approximately a hundred and
thirty videos up so far so if you want
to hear old episodes that aren't in the
throwback Thursday feed go check out the
YouTube channel and of course don't
forget about my patreon campaign you can
go to
from your heart and if you'd like to
contribute to the podcast I would
greatly appreciate it all the
information you need is at patreon.com
slash girl from your heart also if you
want to help me out if you're listening
on iTunes I would love it if you go to
the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast scroll down to
where it shows my little logo there it's
a red yellow and green Rasta flag with
my face right in the middle and it says
the girl from your heart podcast click
on there in the middle of the screen
you'll have three options
one says ratings and reviews click on
ratings and reviews type in a little
review let me know what you think about
the show and while you're there you get
to click on a star rating so far
everybody has given me a five star
review actually one person may have
given me a four star review I think
everybody's giving me five stars the
last time I looked so go and click on
the amount of stars you feel I deserve
and I will read your review on a future
episode ladies and gentlemen I will be
back Thursday with the throwback
Thursday episode and of course I'll be
here Monday with the brand-new fresh
episode I'm gonna give you a huge shout
out to my friend Juan Zilla and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
we might be dead
left you know we've got 50 on the with
the project from the with me we go
quickly like the bomb I got stick here
my mom with me on the song Nokia blowing
up because they miss me when I'm gone I
got no time for tripping off them cuz
there's just too I named a project chick
and yes we got plenty $20 Sachs got no
place in my face I like my barman hash
like the dog and a stray legs shake the
food it takes about my momma shot shakes
and Rich's boys I smoke a power Peter
Parker does he know we're still no
joking cuz we stay hot so the freeway
smoke
[Music]
I wake up in blaze up get my purple
hands up blunts and wrong y'all can put
them J's up dodo
throw all I twice up I spoke your broad
out before we leg up stick up in North
cap but it hit big I hope I had a - the
path to your style for most out every
day all day
I'll be off on like trying up in the
century Jean doubt my eyes being down
never without set up the drop back up
I'm in the freezer always pleasure to
mouth please pretty please boy believe
can find the people with the weeds
Walker wouldn't deceive y'all couldn't
conceive dog that herb it will relieve
your stress look at the West got the
best young
[Music]
I'm from be enough respect to Oh Jamaica
scripture says I'm legit legally
California
[Music]