[Music]
oh [ __ ]
Rasta Jeff in the house
[Music]
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 148 all
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're professional grower loose
smoker are a dedicated dabber if your
cannabis activists reason someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends calling Ross -
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I'm gonna send a
huge thank-you shout out to my friends
in the mystic leaps band for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic we're screwed up everybody's
having a great week ladies and gentlemen
this episode features myself and our
buddy white Mike make sure you follow
white Mike's Facebook page level for
sensible cannabis laws make sure you
support all the sensible cannabis laws
you guys I wanna do too long of an intro
I'm just gonna let the music play I'm
gonna get right back I'll be joined by
our good friend white Mike hang out
[Music]
Blue Dream
so you guys we are back we're here it's
gonna save the studio can this
officially be a studio I think when all
the gears that we can call it a studio
that's fair so today we've got the
pocket studio we're recording on the we
are recording my mouth is [ __ ] high
my brains not as high as my mouth I
think we're recording on the zoom h6
handy recorder you guys I'm doing a
little test run I want to make sure that
I've got this figured out because I'm
gonna go record with dad and granny
again so here on the podcast with me in
the the makeshift pocket studio is our
buddy white Mike welcome back bro thanks
man let's do this part that I always
like to do tell everybody that's
listening where they can stock you on
social media so that they can check you
out while they're listening
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook and at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter
but low for sensible cannabis laws what
kind of stuff are we gonna see if we go
to the Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
Facebook page pretty much any marijuana
news related event I can find that's
even remotely relevant to the US gets
linked up there I appreciate what you do
for the cannabis industry and for the
cannabis community Thank You Man
I'm not I'm a working man and I'm always
at aggro anybody that listens to the
podcast regularly knows that I am the
lead cultivator of a hundred light
facility so that keeps me busy I've got
a day job
most of the politics happens during the
day yeah so when there's politicking to
be done when there's uh people have to
go to City Council meetings and speak
and show support when that stuff is to
be done Mike is the guy that goes and
does that in my place because I am stuck
at the gross oh thanks for doing that
kind of stuff thanks for having a
Facebook page to keep our community
together thanks to all the people that
helped with Mike
Mike's organizations and all the people
that join up with Mike to go to all
these rallies to go protest things big
shout out to all those people if there
are a couple of protal what's the word
activist in town I couldn't think of the
word active several now it's kind of
nice then I'm not totally alone anymore
do you want to give two or three of them
some shoutouts anybody that may deserve
a big fat thumbs up um juicy J
been doing a lot of stuff on social
media that I love there's a guy named
Brooks that's been doing a ton of stuff
on social media right now lots of great
infographic memes for our side and our
fight down here he's been doing some
amazing work and I really appreciate it
some of his work shared to my page has
got record views and shares and stuff
like that so nice CJ and Brooks thanks
for supporting the cannabis community
you guys we need people like you on the
team
Mike dude awesome you showed up with
this orange flavor e citrusy grapefruit
hashed lemon time sugar wax from rock
and extracts it's a new Pueblo company I
really like it I took it to uh just as
something fun to take along with me to a
meeting uh several uh
jab kids is the wrong term but it's the
closest one we got I guess but several
folks getting together davon and it
ended up being the talk of the table
which I thought was funny because we
were dab in raw herbs on distillate that
night two fresh frozen product how much
do you know about that I'm actually not
sure on that particular step the big
part of the big pitch of this company is
it's a proprietary mixed gas okay um
extraction that explains a lot to me
somebody that knows a lot not a lot but
that smokes a lot of different types of
concentrates I can tell that this that's
why I asked if it was live resin because
your color and texture color and texture
are not what I'm used to seeing from a
beauty and extraction unless it's live
resin very very close to what I see you
call that color
[Music]
it's a butterscotch color that's a
really good description of it it's not
orange it's not yellow and when it was
fresh it had a little more orange
yellowish pop to it okay but it's a
propane butane mace I can see the
problem
it's this is legitimately the first
propane hat I've ever dabbed I've seen
it made there's a great vice media
documentary where they go and interview
a guy building a propane extraction rig
in the the hash that comes out of that
is like frightening Lee Orange like
she's a tourist okay well what I've
smoked a bunch of propane hash oil from
our friends at altitude organic medicine
I've smoked a bunch of propane hash from
altitude and it's always white like
completely white and it's real lot it's
kind of mushy and it always stays really
good what I don't like about it is it
kind of makes my lungs feel sort of
heavy it gives me a butter long sort of
feeling um I over dab myself with some
of this one night I I way overheated my
banger and took an insanely hot dab just
not paying attention the last one I'd
taken a little cool so I was a little
yeah while I was coughing the cough
scene would go on quite a while and for
a minute I considered is it the mixed
gas but from everything I've seen all
the lab testing it's it's totally clean
okay we talked about lipids and plant
fats and all that kind of stuff on that
episode previous so I wonder if there
are plans and lipids and stuff like that
left behind in there that they're not
taking out either way it's marvelous
hash is what I wanted to get to the
flavors oh my goodness yeah it's like ah
at first it was like orgy and then I
waited a few minutes and as my mouth
dried up it turned to grapefruits just
straight-up grapefruits on my tongue it
was really delicious I didn't want to
take a drink for a while but I had to
grapefruit coating now it's really nice
nice good job on bringing the good hash
big shadow to rocking extracts you said
they're a Pueblo company yeah they're
the right up the street from the shop
that's pretty cool yeah the good guys
they make several different products the
other deliveries better always be on
time yeah they're never let them over
it's cute
but yeah there are what the manifest
can you walk over a product yep um they
uh they make it a couple different
products that I'm enjoying right now
they've also got the first vape pen
cartridge I've actually not felt bad
about spending money on nice does it
come in flavors or is it just one flavor
right now it's just a single extract run
so it's a mixed batch no strain specific
sativa or indica a hybrid blend of
course they just threw a bunch of [ __ ]
together yeah I have a feeling House
Blue Dream I think it is your local weed
store if that's the thing where you are
asking what what new stuff is in and
check out new stuff don't don't get set
in a total routine there's a lot of new
cool stuff coming out you should check
out what's new you know I kind of
stepped out of my little box I was I was
really familiar with chirp X I mean I
grow the product a green and healthy we
take it to turf X they turn it into
concentrates for us why wouldn't I buy
that you know what I mean but lately
I've been buying the craft extracts the
craft makes really good products I've
been getting extracts ink I think that's
what they're called extracts yeah they
make really good products I had some
darkness cookies the other day it was
really tasty stuff like I've been
stepping out of my normal 17 labs a
really good [ __ ] viola you know if you
get the right batch of viola it'll taste
really good yeah don't be don't be
afraid to try new stuff you're gonna get
a quality product I'd been I'd spend a
lot of time going through the edible
section making sure I'd tried kind of
one of everything and I'm doing the same
thing with the hash lately and that's
it's a lot of fun it's fun watching you
step up your hash game it's so expensive
you started off basically I think I gave
you your first dad probably yep the hot
oil days yeah the syringe of black co2
oil on the dabber oh those days when
they were selling us dental pick dabbers
at the events for like the price of dab
tools and they were just old dental
dabbers from Pakistan yep yeah oh man so
but it's good to see you
if you went from taking little tiny dabs
of just booboo to now you take pretty
good sized dabs and some Clementine
sugar wax bro right it's nice I got you
a decent sized dab of some pineapple
jack setup there that's gonna make you
cough pretty good the last pineapple
jack which company made this was it sir
yeah this is from the turf ex the the
shop got in a shipment of that a long
time ago and I ended up with like eight
of them at home by the time we sold out
I had a a back stash I probably grew
that it was delicious
yeah that's a really great strain it
grows very well very very well it's uh
it's actually New York pineapple diesel
is what it would be it's a pineapple
diesel cross on accident I think but
there were a bunch of seeds and that's
what came out is that phenotype and it
grows like a [ __ ] savage super sweet
it's a great it's a great plant so we've
been talking for quite a while here I
don't think we've gotten any any sort of
topic out why this is Deb you let the
listeners yeah yeah well the first stop
I'm gonna read a couple of email maybe
maybe two depends on how long we go I'm
gonna read one email we'll talk about
that I should find my phone because it's
on there I wanted to remind everybody
that I did promise everybody a podcast
about the davon granny featuring the
davon granny I recorded that podcast at
the can of Canyon and unfortunately I
got home and my memory card would not
let me pull the files it would let me
drag the files from the memory card to
my desktop but they will not play they
won't play from the memory card they
won't play from the desktop I even took
the zoom h6 and ran the USB cable to the
computer and tried to open the files
that way and use it as a file reader it
will not do it so far with my tech
skills that that shows lost so what I
have done is I set up another show I'm
not gonna tell you when cuz you might
show up that's creepy but in the future
davin granny myself Brent Lindsay and
maybe a couple of the folks are going to
congregate at the can Acadian Mike is
gonna cough his face off
tomato red turn a purple again but we
recorded a bit grainy podcast so stick
around that will be coming up in the
very near future uh we're gonna read
that email I said that the one thing I
wanted to talk about with Mike the main
thing because Mike is our smart friend
that comes over with smart [ __ ] ladies
and gentlemen the DEA has failed to
reschedule cannabis considered a
Schedule one drug which let me tell you
what that means schedule one drugs are
the most dangerous drugs with the most
potential for abuse and psychological
dependence so now cannabis still is in
the same category as LSD as heroin and
ecstasy there is no medicinal value Mike
how do you feel about that I saw it
coming a mile away but I'm still
disappointed it's 2016 so about 90 days
ago the DEA said that they were
considering rescheduling cannabis they
taunted everybody they teased us they
made us all think that there may be a
change and then in 90 days they just
said oh never mind sorry we're not gonna
do that well there was a change and it
is big it's just not as big as the media
made it sound they didn't reschedule
cannabis but they did open up more
research growths production sites for
cannabis for pretty much everybody
listenings whole lifetime the feds have
been growing marijuana for research
purposes at the University of
Mississippi sorry I'm still dabbed out
but that's the only farm that grew it
and if you've been watching Sanjay
Gupta's weed 1 2 &amp; 3 specials on CNN
they covered the research restriction
topic pretty well basically there's only
one farm growing research marijuana in
the US which means there's almost no
variety of cannabis to research in the
u.s. they've only got four strains or
some really restricted number sorry my
lungs are still doing a little not good
dad good we can hear it but you're good
you're making enough sense to make it
matter yeah I hope you guys are
following along I'm trying
really hard not to watch it right into
the minds do it really well T shouldn't
see the look on his face this makes you
dumb it's nonsense you just stoned guys
I've seen the cannabis that they grow at
that facility there in Mississippi and
it's garbage they don't have a proper
girl facility they don't have proper
technique I don't think they have good
genetics I've seen what they're doing
and it isn't it's an embarrassing growth
my girl looks like that I would put
matches to it there's you can pull up
some footage on YouTube what a lot of it
looks like and when you listen to the
researchers talk they tell you we can
produce anything that's requested we can
mix a batch of 19% THC or 10 percent or
4 percent or 12% whatever you want and
when you look at what he's talking about
he's basically like well we just grind
up enough leaf and stem in there to
bring the 21 down to 12 or the grind
enough but over the 4% until it's a 9%
and it's yeah it's not pretty
I've seen their facility they don't
think they ever passed 15% um the feds
have run a medical marijuana program
since 82
where patients get mailed 11 ounces each
of pre-rolled joints every month and
like a coffee can look a really cool
coffee tin that's actually a bizarre
collectible in the u.s. now because you
can find them on ebay from time to time
in one of the federal patients that does
a lot of public speaking will give them
away for charity events like silent
auctions and stuff but the marijuana
that those patients get is from this
farm and some of the video of it
especially that was taken at conferences
in the late 90s early thousands the
quality's just atrocious if they have to
unroll the pre roll joints rehydrated in
the fridge like old hippie style with a
piece of lettuce or a piece of bread to
bring the moisture content up real quick
and then reroll it like Mexican brick
weed from America yep guys in
Mississippi hire me I know how to grow
cannabis let's do this since a lot of
that footage was shot I hope so
did you see the CNN footage do you know
it well enough to discuss quality from
that I think that's the footage that I
saw they walk into the room with like it
looks like a shitty led and they've got
like a small hydro table and the plants
just looks sad yeah it's definitely not
like Colorado commercial production
quality it's definitely not homegrown
quality yeah super stretchy plants with
the UFO light above them that's what it
made me think of you know the DEA claims
that cannabis does not have a currently
accepted medical use in the US and there
is a lack of accepted safety for its use
under medical supervision and it has a
high potential for abuse all of that is
[ __ ] you guys what why aren't
worried like why is it the DEA smart
enough to see that all of that is
[ __ ] oh they totally do so what's
there is not doesn't have anything to do
with marijuana itself and everything to
do with seceding power in my opinion
marijuana being illegal is an amazingly
powerful tool it does several things
that they want to keep happening if they
lose that stick they lose a lot there
are a lot of things that are built on
that pyramid they crumble after is it
the pharmaceutical industry there are
definitely financial interests the
president is it the prison industry um
there's been some good reporting lately
Washington I don't remember which paper
but looking at major lobbying efforts
recently against marijuana rescheduling
against marijuana legalization in a lot
of that's coming from alcohol and
pharmaceuticals alcohol pharmaceutical
prisons okay well there's a big report
out recently that legal marijuana states
in medical marijuana states huge
reductions in Medicare and Medicaid
prescription billing oh wow
and it was an in enough states and over
the same time lines to draw causation
conclusions
not a one-to-one like mathematical
conclusion but enough to infer that
where people have easy free legal access
to cannabis they can just swing by a
store and get it basically they consume
significantly less prescription drugs
and that's a huge loss to a major
industry same thing with alcohol when
twenty-something males have marijuana
that they can go buy at a store they
consume significantly less alcohol
really hot sorry honestly when I got my
first medical marijuana card I told
myself and my friends and my family I
was like you know what I can smoke all
the cannabis I want I'm gonna quit
drinking and they're like [ __ ] and
here it is probably six seven eight
years maybe later I haven't drank since
I started using medical cannabis since I
was able to go to the dispensary and
point at that jar and say let me get an
ounce of that tastiness right there and
go home and roll up and puff down as
hard as I want without any worries cuz
back in the day I didn't know where I
was gonna buy my next weed you have to
deserve that outs cuz you paid way too
much and you don't know if that dude is
gonna have good weed or not next time
now you can medicate as needed alcohol I
don't like being drunk I'm no good I
don't know if I'm really good at it or
really bad I'm not sure what the case is
but I know that it's not my friend
over and cannabis I've got a very
similar story it's not I quit drinking
before I had a medical marijuana card
but essentially the same thing is I got
really good at drinking I decided that I
didn't like some of those character
traits so I was gonna take a couple days
off couple days became a week and now
it's been like eight years I went to
Mardi Gras two years ago and had three
beers like just like with dinners just
because I was there and I was at sea
level and I wouldn't feel the
repercussions of it the next day like I
would have had I had up three beers here
is that where Davey happened bro no we
found out we found out about Davey the
day after we got to New Orleans how we
found out
the the day we got there she took a sip
her first drink and got queasy it was
like man and then the second day the
same thing and after the second day she
was like go to Walgreens Oh
yep so we were in New Orleans for 10
days and we found out we were we were
pregnant on the second day you get to
celebrate while you're there kind of we
did it was a it was great we celebrated
the whole time way too truckload of good
food newly rose to real heavy drinkers
anyway so it's not like we're missing
out on anything
right yeah but yeah had a great time and
I had a lot to celebrate but yes I don't
really drink and a lot of it has to do
with I can relax and unwind with
cannabis it's a much better unwind
there's no there's no penalty the next
day then that's what I hated about
drinking is the incredibly bad decisions
that would make while drinking how to
get home DRI am I gonna drive I'm gonna
take a taxi
am I gonna jump in one of my drunk
friends cars so many mornings have woken
up saying I am so thankful that I made
it home last night
I talked to someone today who's like I
quit drinking this morning and it's like
[Music]
yeah the point we're at here is people
are consuming less cannabis are
consuming less alcohol they're consuming
less pills because we were able to
access cannabis safely it's it's there's
a lot of people who don't want that to
happen and there's a lot of people who
don't want to lose that lever of control
on people it's an immediate excuse to
get to further a car stop I smell
marijuana there's there's not one video
on YouTube or the cop goes I smell
heroin I want to search your vehicle I
want to smoke cocaine or I smell cocaine
I want to search your vehicle right that
video doesn't exist it never gets said I
I think I smell a gun I want to search
your vehicle I think I smell someone
you're smuggling in your trunk I want to
search your vehicle though that video
doesn't exist every single video is I
think I smell marijuana when that
steps away everything's for long for
someone gets a little bit harder that is
so true because I recently got pulled
over I talked about it on the show
and the first thing that cop said was do
you have any marijuana in the vehicle
and I had to reprogram my brain real
quickly because first doesn't make no
sir there's no weed in here but then I
was like wait a minute
it's 2016 bro you've got your badge on
you've got your purple card in your
pocket and I looked him straight in the
face and I go maybe because I wasn't
certain but there may be there could be
weed here
he's like it smells really strong gonna
grow and just being honest with him
everything he had no problem to mess
with me now see right that does take all
the stress I'm not a criminal anymore
the only thing I used to do wrong was
have a bunch of weed in the car those
first couple of law enforcement
interactions or bizarre it you did it's
almost a genetic response with this
community at this point right because if
we admit to being part of the cannabis
community or having cannabis or
supporting it in any way we subject
ourselves to all sorts of horrible
things in Colorado that's not true
anymore and as those realization sets
and it's awesome have you been to an
event or a place where you have consumed
cannabis near law enforcement and
they've watched you many before it was
legal I I was up in Denver and Boulder
during the heydays of the boulder
Poquette on 4/20 in the Civic Center
gatherings on 4/20 where tens or
hundreds of thousands of people get
together all at once everybody lights up
at the same time sort of as a dare go
ahead there's 10,000 of us arrests 11 of
us see what happens
right like we're gonna peacefully sit
here and smoke pot and play bad music
and then cheer at 4:20 and all smoke pot
together and there'll be a big cloud and
by 5 o'clock we'll all be gone the shops
in the area that sell food will all make
an extra 5 grand 10 grand that day
everybody's happy everybody's people
that have to take public transportation
or commute during those hours
anyway but uber drivers are making math
in downtown Denver a hundred thousand
people just convene at Civic Center the
cops stand by and they always had and
just kind of made sure everything was
calm and collected didn't nobody got out
of control and it was fine but at post
legalization only a few okay it's just
I've been too busy I always end up
working those it's not the guy that goes
to all the events you're not that dude
there I desperately want to go to like
the next secret session I need to get
out and enjoy a few events now August
22nd now that Davey's a little bit older
I can start doing that a little bit yeah
yeah he's gonna be so much fun pretty
soon so I remember the first time we
used to go to smoke nights at the cloud9
hookah bar here in Pueblo I've talked
about him on the podcast way back in the
early episodes cuz that was back in late
in the day here since then they've shut
him down we can't do that here in Pueblo
anymore but we were at the cloud nine
hookah bar and I was sitting I was at
the bar which is it's an old bar but
it's now turned into a hookah bar but
they didn't change much you know still
got the bar seating they just put
hookahs out I was sitting at the bar
there was one person and then me and in
front of me is my little oil slick pad
my rig my torch a little variety of hash
I was hitting the ball or a toe ball I
was in a bowl that night and a bowl some
flowers in it had a bag of weed next to
me I was just chilling just sitting on
the barstool and the cops walked in
three of them together and I heard the
radio you always do that and then they
walk in and I was like what do I do
but I thought [ __ ] sit here dude
you're a 21 year old you're over 21
you've got a red card in your pocket a
purple card now cannabis is legal the
owner of this place is who's gonna have
to [ __ ] deal with anything yep those
cops walked right past me and they went
and talked to the owner the owner nodded
and smiled a couple times they all shook
hands the cops walked past me and they
kind of looked at my what I had sitting
on the table like they looked at it more
curiously they were like huh okay that's
what smoke and hash supplies look like
and they walked past it they nodded I
mean they kind of smiled like hey what's
up stoner like one of them kind of
condescendingly smile like what's up you
weed head you're high as [ __ ] and the
other cheek just kind of nodded politely
they walked out one of the kids that was
there was younger dude just just being a
typical dude I probably would have said
the same thing
[ __ ] 15 years ago but as soon as man
[ __ ] the police and I looked at him I
was like bro unfuck those police they
didn't take my hash and we didn't go to
jail cuz you were the first [ __ ]
they saw when they walked in here they
didn't do anything so yeah it was remind
him like we didn't go to jail for that
dude like two years ago they would have
threw me on the floor like just for
having that [ __ ] there there are a lot
of people who don't want to give that
out yeah that's why you see thing the
DEA make decisions like this it's it's
just silly
it is silly if they if they would have
rescheduled cannabis to a Schedule 2
substance what that would have mean what
that would have meant is it would have
now been allowable for prescriptions by
all medical doctors so they'd be able to
write you a prescription for cannabis
basically well and they'd also it makes
research significantly easier I mean I
hate to keep going back to CNN's
specials because usually obnoxious is
all ho but their marijuana reporting
that they've done has been spectacular
it's easy to research cocaine in the
u.s. because it's a schedule 2 drug it's
easy just it's easy to research schedule
2 drugs because their schedule - if
their schedule one significantly more
red tape right much much harder to
research and it I mean it takes years of
going through approval meeting since
submitting paperwork years to just begin
your study and then in studies take
years to complete they take more years
to write the conclusions examine the
data all of that and then more years to
publish and when you had another decade
of red tape at the beginning of all that
marijuana research is something that's
not gonna happen it's a world mint and
that's because it's a Schedule one drug
and moving it to schedule two changes
all that any competent researcher can
submit the paperwork and and within a
relatively reasonable amount of time
begin researching and none of those
changes were made and so even though
they created more places to grow it in
the selection of research grade cannabis
that's
available to be researched will it be
expanding access to that material won't
be and that's really unfortunate and
this is why I rant and tell people to
vote because none of this [ __ ] changes
until a most of the people involved in
this have gotten old and died like we
just have to wait until the generation
that's so tied to this has seceded power
to our generation and it's just going to
take another couple of decades and in
the meantime we need more people in our
generation politically active so many
members of our community tuned out
because if we spoke up about what we
believed in we went to jail I was scared
dude back in the day you would be like
come to these City Council meetings with
me and I was like no I grow and that
scared well and that's part of the
reason I became the politically active
one down here is because I didn't
physically have the space to grow or the
money for the start-up equipment and so
I like go ahead and show my ass valoran
twelve square feet with the dirty
laundry prick like I didn't care I like
I could have cops show up
I could have cops pull me over and
demand to search my car and I'd be okay
most of the time but I was able to risk
it where a lot of other people in the
community simply weren't in a position
to do that but one of the one of the
really interesting things that I noticed
when I spoke out is that it gives you a
shield when you go to City Council
meeting reporters for the local paper
there if you live in a major city
reporters from major papers are there
when the guy that comes down to City
Council or keep the county commissioner
meetings it makes really coherent
articulate arguments in the appropriate
manner and setting for marijuana gets
his house raided they break a bunch of
furniture rough him up shoot his dog and
don't find anything that [ __ ] makes the
front page of the Washington Post every
day
for a week and they know this and so it
doesn't have it um and that's not
universally true it's not being granted
immunity by a judge but it does provide
you a significant layer of protection
because by becoming mildly public you
you're granted some of that protection
all right so the DEA failed you guys
that was my point in that I want to move
on to another topic here Mike thanks for
having a whole lot of info on that one
for supporting me on that I'll just
learned a lot as we were recording this
it just passed midnight right now it is
August 17th happy birthday Gibbs Gibbs I
don't know if you listen to this podcast
bro I love you it's great being your
friend I miss you we should hang out
more hope everything is going well for
you happy [ __ ] birthday giblet also
today marks the anniversary of the first
time that my friend Amanda and myself
took dabs together Amanda has been in
Colorado for one year now Amanda I don't
know what Colorado would be like without
you I'm so glad you showed up yeah
[ __ ] friends forever there dude not
to get all sappy on everybody but some
some landmarks to to note so shout-out
to Gibbs and Amanda love you guys
I draw my roster um I said I was gonna
bring an email to the table to read I
took a screenshot of it cuz it's much
easier than going and searching through
[ __ ] let me read this message to you
I've got two of them
this one says first of all he said sucks
that uh sucks about the grannie podcast
he said you killed it with the emails
though and we love your updates on your
genetics I should give you guys a quick
update on that cuz I said I would do
that the mail plan we are now the date
is now the 17th so we are now 14 days in
you guys the mail plant just started
sprinkle in a little bit of pollen any
bits of pollen are coming out of them
the girls are just starting to go into
full flower you can see their calyx
pistols are just going nuts right now
the stretch phase is in full fledge
they'll quit stretching in about a week
I'll let them get pollen in about seven
to ten days they'll start getting a lot
of pollen on them
I've got pollen in a jar for backup I've
also got that male throw in pollen
they're gonna get pollinated so they're
looking great everything is going
beautifully on the breeding project
everything is on schedule not a whole
lot to report
than the male his balls are big and he's
just barely started to dump pollen so
this message says I was wondering what
you know about Fox tailing I don't
really understand what is happening and
whether it's a good or bad thing when it
happens maybe a good show topic and I
replied with great topic so that was a
message that actually came from a friend
on Instagram the emails been killer
lately right I get a lot of topics a lot
of content from the people that are
sending me emails I really appreciate
that send me your emails guys send them
to me and grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
that's the easiest way to reach me grow
from your heart at hotmail.com it's
easier if I filter all the questions
through that one channel I'll read your
questions wherever they come from
honestly because I know you're not some
of us are friends on Instagram on
Twitter runs whatever wherever we're
friends I'll read it but it's easier you
got more of a chance if you hit me girl
from your heart this guy wants to know
about foxtail Fox sealing is when you're
growing above some buds and they start
popping off like little fox tails at
little fingers they just get they start
spreading out a little bit I call them
cheeto fingers - yeah but some strains
its genetic
if the bud stays compact if it's tight
and it's doing what looks like a fox
tail more like a crown that's genetic if
it's if the bud is airy and you're
getting fox telly that is most likely
from too much heat
that's usually what that's from your
plants are probably too hot they're
probably a little bit too close to the
light also coming with that Fox tailing
you may see a little bit of taco leaf
your leaf will look healthy it'll look
cool except on the edges it'll be
folding up like a taco shell like you
could just make a little taco out of
your leaf right there both of those are
visual descriptors if you're seeing both
of those it certainly is too hot in
there I've seen it most often when we
call it kissing this guy where the
plants grow up into the light while
they're yeah that's probably what's
happening to this guys poor plants yep
if that's not the case Fox tailing could
be from too much humidity that are
trying to spread out this is the
grossest description I could give you
but it's completely accurate Mike knows
where I'm going with this imagine you're
in Las Vegas in the summer it's like 114
degrees outside
ah you're man junk tries to just move
away from your body these plants are
doing the same thing it's too hot your
balls want to get away these plants are
too hot they want to get away from each
other they're starting to sweat they're
getting funky they're just trying to
peel off of each other so they're not
getting sweaty and funky and compacted
in there the plants just trying to make
some air room for itself so it's trying
to get spongy it's Foxx stealing out a
little bit it's gonna get fluffy it's
gonna it's getting heat stressed it's
probably what's happening or you could
be over feeding it that also could could
make Fox tailing happen one of those
three it's it's nine times out of ten
your plant hit the light yeah some
Jillybean phenotypes like to make a
crown shape foxtail strawberry-banana
tangi likes to make some crown shaped
foxtails tangi I guess it's a lot of
things cross to that Caleo worse with
the Lemon Haze we know that dinner
difficult in eight inches the light it
was a [ __ ] okay but it was the plant
would drip and so the grower wouldn't
get rid of it because it would just
literally when you were harvesting it
would just drip THC it wasn't saying
that's awesome I know that plant the
closer if it go light a wood foxtail
like mad so chances are bro your plant
is getting too close to the light it's a
little bit too hot if that's not the
case
send me a follow a message and we'll
figure out what's going on we'll talk
about it on a future episode I truly do
appreciate the interaction with my
listeners send me more questions more
messages I love it you guys I like it a
lot I don't to read one more email this
one's gonna be quick I'm finding it on
my phone here I did take another
screenshot this one says hey I was
listening to the podcast today and I
heard you answer my questions on the air
this one's from Nazareth 4:20 by the way
he said it was a trip and he said thanks
for that bro what I see I work with
robots I just may act like robots kind
of like office space but different he
said I got another question for the show
I was hoping you could shine some light
it says show questions number one what
are your thoughts on monster cropping
and he said I read that it's great to
use first scrog honestly I don't know a
lot about monster cropping all you gotta
do is send me another message and tell
me what Monster Crossing is and I'll
tell you my opinions on it I'll learn
about it just tell me what's going on
there
I don't know what you mean by monster
cropping there's a couple things that
could mean you could mean a lot by like
snapping the stems and bending them if
that's what you mean that's cool but it
takes too long for my type of growth ah
number two question he said I was
curious to hear your thoughts on LEDs
any experience using one I don't have
any personal experience with LEDs so I
don't have a lot to tell you I tell it I
can tell you that it changes the way
your plants function they use they do
everything they use their nutrients
differently they drink differently I've
seen friends run side by sides with LEDs
and HPS lights and the LED plants and
HBS lights looked completely different
being fed the same thing they
photosynthesize differently they want
different nutrients it's a whole new
thing to learn I don't have any
experience with it personally I can't
guide you on any lights to use I don't
know enough a lot of time researching
light spectrums and their effects on
plants and I've only seen them really
successfully regularly used as an
auxiliary color augmentation right when
they're a primary light source every
harvest I've seen has been miniscule
I'll give a shout-out to my friend Nancy
Bud well she grows with a very specific
brand of LED lights and she kills it her
plants are gorgeous but I've only ever
seen the cheaper ones in action right
never seen like the $1,800 the lights
did the Nancy are using those lights are
quite expensive they're a thousand to
1400 all our lives but LEDs can be
extremely expensive allegedly you pay
for it in the first year in electrical
savings right what you're gonna save
yeah you gotta throw it down on the
table to walk out with that light but
you're not gonna have to pay the
electric bill every month like I do with
my HPS lights
you don't have to run as much
electricity on an air conditioner to
cool it off also there's no saving there
it's just I've never seen them
effectively used alone check out Nancy
bud well on Facebook or Instagram and
she is a representative for a specific
lighting company and she has great
pictures and she will guide you through
your purchase of an LED light if it's
something that you're really interested
in he's got a third part to this
question it says also wondering what are
your thoughts on happy buckets and deep
water culture what are the
and cons and your likes and dislikes I
am not super experienced in deep water
culture do you remember our friend from
Hawaii that dude grew some deep water
culture buckets and did some great work
the problem was if something goes wrong
everything goes wrong if your pump goes
out on that deep water culture pump and
you don't spray for three or four hours
if it quits brand all your plants are
gonna die that's the the major dislike
to it I thought it was awesome our buddy
had 5-gallon deep water culture buckets
and his plants were taller than me and
I'm six foot five and they were putting
on weight they were packing it up the
only problem is he had a lot of fungus
gnats all the damn time he could not get
rid of the fungus gnats I've never done
it myself so I don't have a lot of
experience but that's what our Hawaiian
friend was experiencing from what I saw
I spent a lot of time researching
different growth methods and this one
scares me because of its complexity it's
the same thing with Hydra the more
complicated it gets the more random
things might fail and cause your crop to
suicide when you were only gone for six
hours that's why I'm a soil grower and
honestly soil is insanely forgiving and
part of the reasons for that or what
make me favor it so let's talk about
deep water culture a little bit because
there might be people out there going
what the hell's deep water basically
deep water culture is a five gallon
bucket this is just a one you can do
multiple site deep water culture buckets
and you can have a main bucket that
feeds or a main reservoir that feeds
multiple buckets but for a one plan deep
water culture bucket you've got a five
gallon bucket and then there's a lid
type device that goes on top of the
bucket but it's got a little mesh basket
cut out of the center of it and you fill
that area with rock wool cubes and you
put not rock quilty hydroton clay balls
put your rock your clone that's in a
rock wall you just set it in there and
then it'll root and the roots will hang
down inside of that 5-gallon bucket
inside that 5-gallon bucket you put a
sprayer there are a lot of different
types of sprayers available there are so
many different ways to do it they sell a
circular it's a circle sprayer that's
got spray jets this shoots straight up
and it's kind of a mr. type thing so
you're misting is essentially a long
growth version
yeah it's a real Big Easy cloners those
roots from the bottom real heavily and
you put nutrients in the water and a lot
of oxygen heavily oxygenated and
nutrient and water spraying from the
bottom so that those roots hang down
into that and grow into that spring
water cuz gravity makes the roots want
to go down I think gravity does I don't
know if they just want to go down or if
it's gravity boss they may just want to
do it naturally but so the water
spraying up onto there and it's growing
and then I put it on time on a timer so
that it stops every once in a while so
the roots can kind of dry so that they
don't raw then you just keep it cycling
so every like 15 min every 45 minutes it
shuts off for 15 now let your water cool
down so that the pump doesn't overheat
your water because the oxygen pump and
the [ __ ] moving it pump is gonna make
that water huh a lot of people throw a
chiller in there to keep that water cool
it's a lot of work it's a lot of
technology and if one piece of all that
tech goes wrong your whole thing could
die yep the production is amazing it the
plant seems to really love it what
everything's humming but it's one of
those things where if you're setting it
up the one the one bucket version on the
cheap like that's the quality of the
parts you just require constant
attention
and you have to understand that you like
your plants got a gun to it said the
Hammers [ __ ] one piece fails and that
trigger gets pulled and you start over
period and that's why I read that far in
the book it was like I know enough next
chapter so sorry I know I couldn't
answer a lot of your questions but at
least I kind of gave you the answers
that I had I don't know a lot about
monster cropping tell me what your you
think monster cropping means cuz if you
google it there are several different
takes just cuz it's a that's a very
common word so let me know what you're
thinking I'll talk more about that
LEDs no experience dude I told you what
I saw from my friends deep water culture
we ranted on what I saw from my buddy
called him pineapple Express cuz he's
from Hawaii I used to come all the time
but as our 4/20 thanks for the email
please send me more emails we will talk
more about this stuff on a future
episode
[Music]
just like he was staring into them I
know the rigs looking at me do you need
a DAB
I did already and I think I'm probably
so good I'm gonna dab the rest of what
is on this parchment paper this is some
pineapple Jack from our friends at term
X buy last quarter gram that's probably
quarter gram but I'm gonna take this and
then I think they want to wrap up the
show after that Mike got anything
pointing it to say I'm just we're
gearing up for November make sure you
can do it online most places make sure
you're registered to vote make sure you
know what election issues are coming up
in your area take a minute to actually
research them it's gonna be a hell of
election all the news is focused on the
circus that is the presidential race and
honestly it's the local stuff that
really really really matters that's the
stuff that's really gonna impact your
day to day and that's the day I did and
that's that's the local issue stuff for
the the things that tend to really
matter to most people take a minute to
figure out what those are
the local issues are now set County
voters will be voting on one marijuana
question whether or not they want to ban
the industry city voters will be voting
on three marijuana questions the first
one do you want to ban the REC industry
yes or no the second question do you
want to allow recreational stores yes or
no and the third question do you want to
tax those stores is it like four and a
half percent kind of a confusing set of
questions and there's reasons for that
like a lot of complicated reasons for
all of those three questions and peirong
for publicity motors but you need to
know which questions which you need to
know the wording so that you don't
accidentally vote the wrong way and it's
important that you know that stuff
regardless of whether you live near me
or not because whatever the issues are
in your area they will impact you
personally
make sure you know what's up and make
sure you vote have you gone to your
Facebook page your Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws Facebook page and kind of
typed in guidance on which way to vote
since it is worded awkwardly there's
already a beautiful infographic that
helps with that the pueblos pulp did
they've been doing some amazing cannabis
John Rodriguez Lisa wheeler and I don't
know the other reporters name okay
thanks Lisa wheeler and your colleague
who are helping us out in the cannabis
fight not so much that it's just doing
solid honest reporting and when that's
done it leans far to the pro cannabis
side because that's just the reality you
can't be a good reporter it not end up
reporting that truth but know the issues
in your area it's not that difficult
doesn't take that much time and it's
incredibly important folks get out and
do it Mike always knows what's up he's
always got the right thing to say if
you're listening and you're in the
industry you should think about some
sort of show up with your I've voted
sticker get a dot dot dot you hear that
think about it awesome promotion motors
store managers people that voted get a
something like a percentage off today a
free pre-roll if you spin something go
vote go to the dispensary and celebrate
your freedoms all right Mike thanks for
coming and hanging out it'll be good to
get home but I love the podcast I I'm
happy to get over here and I love doing
it
thanks for coming on but I love having
you on the show you're always a good
material that people love it when you
ramble good content you guys the next
episode I have planned well I don't even
know if I should talk about Jesse coming
Jesse says he's gonna come over tomorrow
Mike might go pick him up and make sure
he shows up so the next podcast will
either be myself and Mike or Jesse and
myself or myself Mike and Jesse you
never know how it's gonna go in these
parks there may may not be a podcast
recorder tomorrow it may or may not be
epic it's outdoor season so you never
know what could go on right now but I
hope to have Jesse know tomorrow Mike
you know you're invited back after that
you guys I will be recording once again
with the Devin granny I can't wait to
have her back on the show this tentative
scheduled that's the intro about the
gear we're test running everything to
make sure that this goes smooth this
time for 48 minutes in of this part of
it before it works things look good yes
it looks good so far so far so good
alright let's quit while we're ahead
thanks for coming I'm gonna wrap up this
part of the show and I'll be back in
just a single and I'll put a bow on this
[ __ ] alright everybody I want to thank
you guys for listening to another
episode I want to thank Mike for coming
to joining me
you guys I owe a huge shout-out to my
friend Chris Baker make sure you listen
to the broadcast geeks podcast and
support my buddy Baker
Baker's a great dude he's got a great
podcast we owe him a high five in a
favor so make sure you support his
podcast you guys I want to thank
everybody for listening I'll be back in
another week with another episode if you
have a product you would like me to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
show all you have to do is send me an
email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to get you all of the
information that you need show's over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your art
podcast find the review section give me
a 5/5 star rating that's hard to say
give me a 5 star ratings I've been a
little comment and let me know what you
think about the show and I will read
your comments on a future episode I
would love it if you follow me on all
the social media sites I am on almost
all of them just search for a grow from
your heart on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast if you've got something to say
and you're not into all the social media
you can simply email me girl from your
heart at hotmail.com
i would love to hear from you don't
forget the shows available on itunes
stitcher and every single episode is
always and forever archived on ira
genetics colorado dot-com the show is
also available on toked radio make sure
you support talk radio and listen to all
the other great podcasts on their big
shot it's my friend Lucy in her podcast
Lucy in the sky also shout as my buddy
citizen Jay you guys that's all I've got
for you this week I'll see in seven more
days the next episode will be Jesse on
an outdoor episode Jesse and Mike join
me and then episode 150 will feature the
dab in granny we're gonna do that one
again so join me for those until next
time take a phat dab and give him a hug
for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 149 of the
girl from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversational smoker or a dedicated
activist or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff want to thank you once again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic root band
letting me use their music on my podcast
big thanks to cat week hope you're
smoking a fat joint I hope you got the
email turned on I hope you're taking a
DAB if you're smoking some good shatter
maybe some good live resin maybe your
smoke to some rosin with me whatever
you're smoking I hope you get them high
as [ __ ] having a good time with us
ladies and gentlemen this episode
features our good friends white Mike and
also Jesse Grose's back we talked about
a little bit outdoor growing we talked
about a whole bunch of randomness this
is a really wonderful episode in my
opinion you guys I did drop a Thursday
episode if you didn't catch the episode
that came out on Thursday make sure you
go back and check that one out number
148 is available it came out Thursday I
usually post every episode on Monday I
have had a bunch of content so I felt
like I could put one out on Thursday for
you I hope you listened I hope you
enjoyed it send me a tweet let me know
what you thought of that episode find me
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast I would
love to hear from you you guys I'm gonna
let the music play and when we get back
Mike and Jesse will be joining us at the
table enjoyed music for a moment
do it Mike you wanna bust a freestyle no
it looks like you're about to let one go
no I want to hear free style rap I want
to hear the white Mike freestyle rap not
a white Mike freestyle
[Music]
guys we're recording at this podcast
ladies and gentlemen welcome back to
episode number 149 as promised sitting
to the left of me is a repeat offender a
returning champion ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the podcast our good buddy
Jesse grows welcome back bro hey with
raw Terps today he's got some distillate
he's got some shatter he's locked and
loaded and ready to go bro thanks for
showing up ready started talking to the
cottonmouth killer yeah serious here
today Jesse before we get too far tell
everybody on social media how they can
stalk you while they listened to your
sexy voice Instagram
Jesse gross and then also you can check
out my podcast we've got a Facebook page
Colorado dope podcast on Facebook the
Colorado podcast make sure you check
that out support that it's a great show
I've been on that show a big shot to
make the dog ladies and gentlemen make
the dog will be joining us also on this
podcast right now he's taking a comfy
seat underneath the table to do that
Jesse thanks for joining us everybody
make sure you follow Jesse grows on
Instagram take a look at his photography
while you're listening to the show check
out I'm out see what he does we're gonna
talk a whole lot about outdoor growing
you guys also across the table from me
another repeat offender a returning
champion the guy that was here just last
night recording a show with me I missed
you bro welcome back Mike Mike is on the
podcast if you're not a regular listener
you can check Mike out he's at an emo
Punk 15 on Twitter and he is also a blow
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
make sure you check out that group page
I get that right perfect I've been
trying to train that in my brain that's
a lot of words for my stoner brain
I told you on the last episode we need
you out there fighting that part of the
fight
I'll do the breeding Jesse I'll do the
growing you get us legal fight for us
welcome back to the show bro I
appreciate having you here taking time
away from the baby the family the dogs
you're a busy dude it's great to have
you here you were supposed to trim all
night so I'm glad that you waved off
yeah
back for the podcast with Jesse finally
this is a first like 50 and I think
you're both here for those yeah I think
we did one before too as I met you at
the stable of doing a podcast completely
it's hard to remember some of those
early earlier right there for him I had
people remind me of things I've said and
done on those episodes the first
meaningful one this is episode 149 you
guys a hundred and forty nine episodes
into this podcast I haven't missed a
week in two and a half years every month
as a podcast to listen to in some
Thursday's it's been incredible episodes
I call it a swap cast I learned the
phrase swap cast from Doug Stanhope but
when two podcasters come together and
record one podcast and then they both
put it up on their feed so that
everybody gets exposed to both shows at
the same time I did one of those with
the Colorado a podcast make sure you
check it out it was good fun it's a
little bit of chaos but it is a great
show listen to it on their feed so that
they get to click so you guys know the
Colorado
podcast page and listen to that episode
on their feed because they can use the
traffic we host em up we've got some
internet problems there's some website
problems at the moment
we'll find them difficulties May 12
episode won't come out for a few days so
hopefully you've got hopefully your tech
guys on it if not I know a guy that'll
work on that before yeah all right I was
gonna say I'm excited because episode
150 it has been confirmed episode 150 is
going to feature the dab and granny once
again I know I recorded the episode
before I'm still heartbroken that it
failed everybody's when everyone has
been real supportive and encouraging
everyone's all about coming back and
re-recording that podcast
davin granny went and bought special
hash to smoke with me to show me that
she doesn't mind doing it again tomorrow
night at a secret location I will be
recording with the dab and granny you
guys it'll be at the can of canyon by
the time this goes out it'll be too late
for us but tomorrow night at the can of
Canyon it'll be myself davon Grammy
Brett from Evo labs and Lindsey the
traveling stoner and probably boba
blaster Co we'll be there hopefully miss
Camille will be there hopefully Erin
will be there hopefully Biddy and Sirius
will be there we'll try to I'm not even
gonna try to mimic the show we did last
time that's [ __ ] to try to do there
would be things that get left behind
we're just gonna have a conversation
like we did some of that is lost it was
a band granny's first podcast and she
wasn't sure how to go about it right
away so now she is completely [ __ ]
comfortable and she knows what to do on
a podcast so it was a practice run you
guys please 150 will be the dab in
granny that's kind of a cool way for a
karma to land on us that's not a bad
deal that's gonna be awesome
yeah all right we're gonna talk about
how you're growing guys I wanna talk
about these dabs it's distillate and
these Terps no bro you showed up with
some delicious [ __ ] Jessie remind me
what's in each of these little vials you
got here critical mass critical mass
Terps
just to the rod distillate this is the
VM to the garden of Weeden for an
amazing breeding project that was his
first run Chuck in pollen and those
[ __ ] that strain came out amazing I
don't know how much he's growing it out
but I could tell him a little about it
[Music]
girl gorilla glue rock terms so you guys
they have figured out how to take a
plant a cannabis plant probably takes
more than one plant to take a large
batch of cannabis and extract of the
terpenoids from that specific batch that
one plant and then you can get the
essence the flavor the aroma the taste
it all in your face and all in your
palate and it's amazing overwhelming
[Music]
okay really overwhelming I really think
the terpenes are really contributing to
my high also it makes me skyrocket to
that next level that became crystal
clear what I started playing with the
distillate in the Terps it's you're
taking the same THC but when you add the
critical mass you go one way hard when
you add it to something like the Durbin
you know the other way we are and you're
not changing the THC content right it's
the other parts of the plant that really
shaped that that entourage effects in
effect what Gupta talked about it's
exactly evident and when we're using the
Terps like this yeah dude good job
you're kind of your company's
experimenting give your company a shout
out so we can hype them up a little bit
the Uncle Bud company the Uncle Bud
company based in Pueblo Colorado you
guys we were pulling raw Terps out here
in Pueblo Colorado can I have no - you
know zero th-these terpenoids zero - lab
proven so these it would not be
hypothetically I'm not gonna do this
don't [ __ ] ask hypothetically we could
make these available nationwide because
there are no cannabinoids in there yes
awesome diverting it out of metric is a
whole nother story
right right making them so it's it's
virtually impossible for that to leave
the Colorado marijuana enforcement
tracking system that is stuck you're not
gonna get it you guys well how does it
concern once you once if you purchase it
in a store
if there's no THC they can't travel yes
I would yes that was also my because
there's nothing that's terpenoids
terpenoids theoretically it's also legal
to ship in the mail I wasn't gonna go
there but yeah theoretically since it's
just trippin toys I mean you can buy
toys folks but if there's really no THC
in it I think there's a loop here to be
played with it's necessary there's
actually might got too hot there's a
website called just chirps calm or
something similar to that where you can
purchase terpenoids you can buy limonene
you can buy all of the terpenoids
separately is that the big pretty wheel
I've seen probably but those turps are
not derived from cannabis those are
pulled from things like bananas and
roses and oranges and other fruits this
is just the terms and you would people
that are not able to smoke this quality
cannabis would be able they'd have to
get some dabs or some distillate or
something to carry it you can probably
put this in it like a vape pen cartridge
you can mix that up with some VG some
vegetable glycol or something yes it's
actually pretty amazing it makes a vapor
and then you can actually taste gorilla
glue you could taste this ovm you could
taste the critical mass you could taste
I've got ghost train haze over here I
had lemon OG or lemon G that lemon GU
guys people do crazy [ __ ] for the lemon
G they'll stare at you like could I get
wondered a lemon g dabs look like they
got them white lips for the Friday and
five o'clock free lemon
I got VCRs and [ __ ] in their hand for it
something about the lemon G Terps are
amazing I had oh gee cush chirps there's
paradism Terps floating around here
somewhere it's so delicious to taste
these cannabis terpenes we're getting
spoiled it's actually it's really not
that hard to extract them either it's
just yeah I was gonna say tell us what
you feel comfortable sharing I don't
want to prior too much information out
of you but if there's something you want
to tell us that some of your process
I'll tell you this if you get with me
and give me 100 bucks we'll walk you
through the entire process 100 bucks I
can even I've already proven I can do it
Rasta SAP how to do our consulting fee
just for showing up from Shirdi bucks it
takes it takes an investment in
equipment the equipment cost for a small
operation so maybe I had five pounds of
plant material to run how much equipment
should I buy what would I be spending
for a five pound run
yeah did equipment you're looking about
600 bucks and you're gonna be doing five
runs instead of one five pounder okay
well so about a pound at a time and it's
600 bucks in I don't care it's a solvent
list process completely and totally
organic it takes a little bit of a
chemistry background or or you just need
to know someone who can walk you through
the process it's a back until it's all
right between you and Bret maverick I
should be able to figure it out oh yeah
yeah I mean I taught em how to do it
okay so that's the Rasta SAP also by the
way yeah
I don't know if I'm ready to answer your
Facebook messages yet robust shout out
on the show I'm just not ready to
interact on the show because jesse is my
outdoor expert it's a lot of pressure on
you bro
my outdoor expert the Pokemon go buddy
it's time to take some notes about the
Gro probably about three weeks in to
flower you should start seeing the
pistols the calyx pistols are starting
to form on your plants those little you
guys call them hares the white hairs
those are popping up on your plants if
you've got girls those are popping up
something super important and
hypercritical your boy plants need to be
[ __ ] pulled by now walk through your
garden look for boys look for
hermaphrodites get rid of that [ __ ]
because how far can paul and travel at
least four miles or so it's very first
yeah I don't I don't want everybody's
crop getting pollinated because your
excuse me I just a full solid burp on
the podcast I was read I don't need
everybody's crop getting pollinated
because you're too lazy to pull a male
plant out of your garden so go outside
hold the male plants if you haven't
already done it you might be [ __ ] up
already I talked about it on another
episode of how quickly male plants drop
pollen I've got a male plant another
room right over there he is like 15 days
in and he has just blast and fallen
right now so it only takes 15 or 16 days
for serious trouble to start happening
yep doesn't take long I've actually I've
known as a mature breeder that
pollinated his neighbor's screw that was
let's save 400 500 feet away oh man
with with trees fences houses all kinds
of pollen it's amazing
yeah that's its whole purpose of life is
to just land on the female plant and
climb up that pistol and get up in there
there's a couple of places that have
passed special rules keeping hemp and
marijuana grows like five or six miles
away just to make sure that there's
never I totally know a solution to that
I would I would grow my sensimilla of
grow right next to em field are you
willing to expose your secret on the
podcast I think I know you told me the
way you told me we tell us on the show
or do you have to keep that a secret
hemp plants only pollinate once a year
or they only release pollen once a year
okay so plan your your your bloom cycles
accordingly if you can yeah but also
most Tim crows like to grow clones
there's significant other ways you can
protect your own grow from the next the
guy next door who doesn't know the
difference between a male and a female
you just gotta it's part of the planning
in the research you should have done by
now or he should have done he should not
have a male out there outside in the
first place I actually know a couple
breeders in California to do everything
outdoors and I just shake my head's at
them getting bugs right about now you'll
start seeing the bud sites it's time to
get in there and kind of take off that
lower [ __ ] yes shave the legs in there
you guys get in there and clean off all
the lower canopy where the air is not
getting in something we're like a little
squirrel could get help climbing up the
little ladder at the bottom take that
off of there all that stuff that's gonna
hang down and touch the dirt get get rid
of that all those little sucker branches
just a little thin pale yellow branches
that are just shooting up take all those
off you don't need those go clean up the
inside a little bit you want to focus on
the tops of the plants that's where all
the magic is gonna happen so clean them
up a little bit follow them out yeah
hollow them out a little bit pull them
apart and spread them if you can if you
need to get a giant stick and stick it
in the dirt and pull one branch this way
in one branch this way so that they're
getting Sun properly
feel free to do it they could take a
beating
out into your grill around noon one
o'clock when the Sun is really high in
the sky and everything that's not
getting direct sunlight right then and
there you know that's that kind of use
that as a guide of what to take off so
it's you know I mean not everything's
gonna be getting full sunlight but you
know things that are just in the dark
you know at the bottom you know you can
take that off things that are you know a
little further down the side or bud
sites that are further down the side
they may not be getting full sunlight
but they're still getting sunlight leave
those there so you know just judge
accordingly but all that all that dark
stuff you definitely take that off
that's gonna be Laura fee yeah yeah you
don't want to turn that and unless
you're making a bunch of hash that I
mean maybe you leave that if you want to
but it's gonna take the energy up top
yeah so stretch phase should be just
about over right we've about the first
three weeks we really start stretching
that should be slowing down now so we
can see kind of how big our plants are
actually gonna be gonna get a judgment
of how tall they're gonna be how much
panicking you need to do on readjusting
yeah well people are growing crazy
outdoor plants here in Pueblo and it's
completely illegal is bad but there are
people that are doing it there's
building a higher fence every week I see
them like giant TV sets you guys there
it's gonna be all over Pueblo you guys
sure drawing outdoors this year and
someone tries to steal your [ __ ] don't
[ __ ] shoot them grow more weed next
year do we have to do this episode every
year but just it's just we just it's
happened here though somebody got shot
trying to steal somebody's cannabis
outdoors and that medicine that was
supposed to be medicine became a target
of theft which became an attempted
homicide which [ __ ] that we don't need
that vibe attached to this plant at all
that's why we tried to make it legal
that's why we wanted safely accessible
so nobody's getting shot over the [ __ ]
we took it away from the cartels but in
the hands of the medical community yes
it is not justifiable it instantly makes
it into criminal you're protecting your
illegal crop anybody please guys if
you're listening to this you're probably
not gonna shoot me you know peaceful
cool ass people is why you're listening
to my show
you're gonna start seeing what size
plants are don't pop don't top anymore
that's one of the next things I had
written down is no more topping the
hormones and the plants have all decided
where the tops of those plants are gonna
be and where they need to bake it's the
most energy where they need to send the
THC where they need to send all the
energy for budding quit topping them no
more topping you can kind of bend them
you can stretch them down but don't cut
any more off the tops of the plant so
you take all that bottom [ __ ] freely but
the tops where the hormones have climbed
up don't take that off of there no more
topping is it time now to adjust the
nutrients that were feeding them
for sure probably you know especially by
the time this comes out but yeah last
week
most definitely now but yeah go for it
we can put this out we can put this out
Monday morning out outdoor plants
they'll use a little more nitrogen then
indoor plants will through the bloom
cycle so keep that in mind you know keep
that bottle of bloom or I mean bottle
grow around the way I do it is I'd
probably just if I felt they needed a
little extra nitrogen shot I just mix up
some some grow and maybe a little cow
milk and feed that in addition to the
normal fee okay so add it on top of
normally feeding you know I saw sub cool
take a bottle of nutrients and pour it
directly onto the soil on his outdoor
grow and then just watered it in like so
cool really did that bro like one of the
most reputable growers you could find on
the Internet and they dude just poured a
bottle of a nutrient I won't even use
straight onto the dirt and then watered
it in just fine
you know sub cools kind of kind of from
south a little bit flavor to him so he
doesn't give to just the feet he might
want to keep Jessie made a really good
point that I didn't think about these
outdoor plants are gonna use a little
more nitrogen than what we're used to so
increase your nitrogen feed if you're
not gonna be a bottle fed nutrient kind
of guy what kind of stuff can we add to
top dress to get a little more nitrogen
yeah now we're talking some neem ill see
bird guano's a great all-purpose guano
if if that's your thing
I've quit using it but I had a [ __ ] ton
of it so it's not going anywhere I gotta
use it up I'm just not gonna buy anymore
but seabird guano gives you PK and
nitrogen so it's a real good one there's
something about whatever they're eating
the the fish and the kelp that's in that
I think that really adds to the flavor
and the funky smell of a good cushy but
I think kelp and seabird guano really
contribute
other ocean products may make the best
tasting blood of my pantry I've done
began acai have done you know the blown
bone mills and blood mills I'm
everything and that's I love my little
my ocean style you know kelp and crab
shell mill seabird guano works good with
it yeah it's I like the product SEAPLEX
from organic hair definitely as it's a
cold-pressed blue algae based product
product and it makes I think it makes
the buds taste better smell better they
get more density and I think there's
something else in there that just makes
them grow better whatever is happening
in that kelp that life that's in that
kill makes my plants happier hey
definitely a little boost helps the
fastest growing plant on the face of the
planet so yeah there's all kinds of
natural PD yards going on there ok it
works
yes auxins and cytokinins yeah stuff is
not for everybody so here's a quick
little kelp kelp is also a great bloom
booster so you can take kelp take put it
in a mason say quart mason jar put a cup
of kelp in there go ahead and top it off
with water let it rehydrate for 24 hours
strain any extra water away if there is
a little bit run that kelp through your
food processor and that'll turn it into
just a mush at that point you can it
dissolves into water and you can follow
your spray it as a bloom booster right
there on your plant and then store it in
your refrigerator in the back keep it as
cold as possible so it'll definitely
make your plants happy would you add any
fulvic acid to that spray
that wouldn't hurt a bit but make it a
little more absorbable that's probably
the recipe to a lot of organic boosters
and them are why they're alive yeah
[Music]
brain has got Kelvin acid naturally and
kelp like that the silic acid comes in
there's a little bit but most of that or
the big source of that is aloe vera
that's really popular right now you
could easily add some aloe vera into
that and that's am I actually going to
do that let's really see back in the day
we were taught not to take too many
notes because if your door got kicked in
and there were notes it said feed on
week six feet on week seven you just
left a paper trail in your handwriting
you had to have those plants in there
with no [ __ ] notes in a good memory
yep yeah it was harder that time at that
time so many things changed in
legalization and that's just one of the
really nice ones that she not everyone
even gets to see [ __ ] I was scared to
look at it on the internet even like
even to Google or back then it was like
Yahoo or American were you part of overt
over drug calm I was way too scared to
ever ask questions or post on it but I
totally read totally told it all right
yeah I used to go look and all that good
stuff I used to make up fake accounts on
other sites and just go look like I was
supposed to be like cannabis culture
magazine had a really good one too after
they shut down over girl a lot of the
people from there went and that's
I got into the forums years later when I
got my med card I was like [ __ ] this but
once I had my med cards game the [ __ ] on
yeah I think and a lot of people may
argue with me I think that the OG Kush
the og and OG Kush could be og from
overgrow calm cuz if you met somebody
from overgrow they'd say are you [ __ ]
Jesse from og and you wouldn't because
you wouldn't want to say overdrove
because if it wasn't you then I mean I
just [ __ ] up like from what I think
that people were shipping seeds around
like one guy had a seed he's some of
them to Jesse and then Jesse grew him
and found the phenotype he liked and
bred to that and then shipped those
seeds to somebody and I think that
somebody ended up with the bag of seeds
and they call it to overgrow cush I mean
that's adapt Jase you know of another
one I've heard okay
that's that one and then the one that
involves the bubba kush guy yeah Matt
from Florida that's kind of the same I
mean it kind of falls in there but
that's the - I tend to believe
personally okay there are plenty of
other stories of how that happened I
don't even bring up the podcast that
I've heard them on the oh geez I have I
yeah I love oh gee I love some good OG
my Jeff's og has got some flavor to it
there would be some Jeff's og available
on the shelf at the store pretty soon
here that John Randall's junior trimmed
up for us it looks delicious
so we're top dressing with nitrogen
heavy products how about some ha I mean
Adam in there yeah alright but don't go
to art yeah you want to hit hard with
your your P's and K's peas and K's now
yeah I remember it takes a week to two
weeks on a typical top dress for it to
break down enough
to be um uptake above like the plant so
Rick plan ahead and you know that's if
you do it right now we're in the morning
whatever it is you know that's not gonna
really take effect for at least a week
so think about that plan is already
yellowing you're chasing it by now yeah
yeah see you sure you should have done
more nitrogen already so next year do
more yeah and I would still add nitrogen
to keep it from getting worse and
that'll help your buds develop it'll
keep everything moving all right other
top dresses though knee mill is a
favorite of mine Crabb mill is good for
blooming and then kelp I mean most
organic bloom boosters are made out of
kelp so that's really where you want to
go do you mess with the Quran Jamil oh
yeah yeah it's the neem a lime mix I use
it's okay great mix that'll keep most
bugs out of the soil those bugs off the
plants and you'll never notice it when
the finished product
alright so let's talk about defoliating
because at this point of the season it's
time to clean up a bunch of the leaves
do you like to heavily defoliate or do
you just kind of clean them up I'll take
off a lot of leaves to where people look
at you like you're crazy but then they
come back a week ten days later and all
the leaves are back and they can't even
tell on this year I've got three of the
same strains planted in a row so the one
in the middle they're all about the same
size the one's gonna get tortured yeah
let's do you have Northern Lights or the
lights number five the cut that goes
around doing four shops quite a bit that
the one that spends bread - yeah nice
it's a good cut I had that for a little
bit that's the code I made uh my grape
og with - oh that's a great guy you make
some donkey dicks for buds for sure
yeah make some huge huge [ __ ] buds
alright so D Foley you guys clean up in
there basically any leaf that looks like
it's gonna be blocking a bud site from
getting sunlight just go ahead and pull
that [ __ ] off and it's gonna grow back
because it's an outdoor plant and you're
gonna be amazed at how quickly
leaves grow back you'll pull off a leaf
the size of your hand and in ten days
you'll have one back bigger than your
head it is grow and grow they love the
outdoors all right so we've talked about
feeding a little bit we talked a little
bit about top dressing we talked about
defoliating you mentioned specifically
that we need to talk about caterpillar
prevention so this is the time it
happens every year you know what do we
do to get rid of caterpillars and
they've already got full-blown or
full-grown caterpillars inside your
fully developed bud your [ __ ] there's
nothing you can do aside from just
manually picking through and pulling
them out yourself that was now yeah it
sucks yeah now is the time to apply
those preventative things that will keep
them away and you're gonna have to spray
your bud sites spraying your sorry
I just heard voices in my head jump
[Music]
trying to fix it but you fixed yourself
you're good you need some buds ight for
that BT to beyond to to ward off the
parent from laying the egg in there in
the first place so BT is what I
recommend us like captain jacks
Monterey Spray okay back back solicitor
Schneider Bacillus thuringiensis I think
Google keep talking on Google that way
that's what I recommend for for getting
rid of any kind of bud warm and now's
the time to apply it so also the garlic
oil ferment that you were talking about
yeah it's very good for that too even
just a sensual garlic oil from the
health food store would probably have
some of the same properties in it right
there yes it's bacillus thuringiensis i
was really close yes that's that's
available from Captain Jack's it's
available in Monterey Spray is a very
very popular product used for keeping
away it's also usable you can use it in
the soil it will not cause any problems
the mosquito dunks that you buy and
whatever Lowe's or Home Depot it's
that's the main ingredient and there you
can crush those up you can put that in
some water you can water that directly
into your soil that will get rid of your
fungus gnats that will get rid of most
soulbound creatures is another brand
name that's a dry powdered product but
it's same active ingredient natural has
the same thing you guys if you're gonna
use any of these powdered products
beyond the dunks the dunks are just fine
probably to use without a mask if you're
gonna use natural or activate please
wear a mask research everything before
use yeah when you get a new pesticide if
you take that little booklet that's on
there I know it's crazy nobody does this
that little booklet if you open it up it
tells you all the safety precautions how
much to apply on certain types of crops
it tells you how long between
applications it tells you what kind of
safety equipment you need to wear
[Music]
because if it's gonna rain and you apply
certain things it's just gonna wash
right off and you just wasted that whole
application time and the expense on the
product also in there it tells you the
re-entry interval how long from spring
this product should you avoid this room
without wearing protective gear because
some of the chemicals and products that
are available to Hydra store much more
toxic and dangerous than you realize
they expect you to be a responsible
adult that can read that label
that bear stuff the bear spray they sell
for your outdoor house it Lowe's that
can kill you that can completely kill a
human if you [ __ ] around and do it wrong
so pay attention to the labels you guys
read that [ __ ] read the safety sheets
and then it's really important I know it
sound like a preaching to you but a lot
of the things that you can get from
these products you won't notice until
ten or twelve years down the line you'll
start getting a facial tic or something
from that time there's a brief Laura
might into the fin and it came back into
your face that's how they affect you to
its most they nervous system and
reproductive system it's the exact same
thing they do to the insects exactly to
kill yeah she's gonna take a little
while longer on you because you're
[ __ ] 160 pounds alright so
caterpillar prevention use that bacillus
thuringiensis spray it's available in
Captain Jack's Monterey insects spray
has it you guys a very good
recommendation for if they do not pay me
they don't sponsor me in any way there's
a company called RB koat.com a RBI
co.com they sell all types of
horticultural supply gardening supply
type stuff you can buy almost any type
of sprays you want you can buy organic
sprays you could buy crazy they sell
anything from styling oil to Flora might
and this one catalog they also
beneficial and they sell beneficial
insects that is something I was gonna
talk about on a future episode with you
but let's jump into it for a minute
beneficial insects is now the time to
release my a whole bunch of beneficial
insects yeah yeah I mean that'd be
totally cool predator mites and ladybugs
for sure lace wigs I'd go for ladybug
larva especially outdoors okay the
larvae are a lot more productive meaning
they eat more [ __ ] okay they're still
growing yeah okay and there's no hanging
around longer - alright ladybugs - stick
around is there a trick to that I've
heard some pretty awful things for me
you know outdoors is where I use the
most and just having a nice welcoming
environment you know it's
there's not normally many pests on the
plants but there can be pests found in
the mulches and the garden beds around
so I think that works to keep them
around stick around there too okay how
do you feel about a praying mantis
they're awesome okay are bucco calm
happens to sell praying mantis larvae
you can order them set the larvae on a
plant they will hatch and come alive in
your garden you can watch it happen it's
kind of cool I haven't seen it happen
but I've seen videos of it because I'm
kind of an internet nerd but yeah I
check about that company does not pay me
anything but I mean they've got all the
products that you need if you want a
preventative to keep the bugs away if
you want something a little stronger to
destroy them or if you want to go full
[ __ ] madness nuclear they've got the
product for you you can order from there
they'll ship it to you quickly check
them out I use that product catalog all
the time just for plenty of research to
compare this versus this which is better
you just hold the page aside and see
what you like better and read them yeah
they've got everything in there but
again if you get some floor might if you
get something crazy
get yourself a Tyvek suit and some
gloves a mask
suit up go all Walter White style and
that [ __ ] do it properly
don't get Sam and I also think you're
bastards for spraying that [ __ ] outside
yeah don't ever spray it outside it
don't kill bees it's just personal
opinion without the food right
everything I eat grows everything I
either grows something that grows your
food eats my food yep it's not fair
it'd be a pretty shitty place without
pollinators yeah absolutely so we want
ladybugs we want beneficial predators
predatory mites is what I'm thinking we
want some of the preying mantises what
other kind of bugs can we put out there
to help us out
worms in your soil okay oh yeah put
worms in the soil is a spider good luck
in your garden is it a good thing to
have one or two spiders oh we've got
those too okay
they're gonna cause any problems are
they no not really I've actually watched
a wasp carry away a full-grown bud warm
before Wow
okay here in Colorado we get something
that I don't know if these happen
anywhere else Michael remember these my
microphone cover is bright orange we get
these orange blood worms I've called
them I've heard them called melon worms
before yeah do you get those in your
buds around here I've never had those
ones I get like they're like a brownish
green color okay but they're all I mean
there are all beetles of some kind I
believe all right I've seen the orange
ones is the Captain Jack's and the
Monterey Spray gonna keep that [ __ ] away
it'll yeah our Aksum all equally I mean
for the most part if you got something
really exotic and crazy you know I don't
know but I know here in some of the
Colorado it takes care of anything so if
somebody is local if they're here in the
Pueblo Colorado area where can they go
pick up some sprays to take care of
their insects one loves its 116 East 4th
Street right 618 618 I had the right
numbers as close as close as dyslexic or
some [ __ ] on there but yeah 618 East 4th
Street go support one love garden supply
for sure burns down there go say hi to
my beautiful wife yeah go support that
place go support local businesses if you
can't guys for you dad awesome all right
we've been gone for like 40 minutes
talking about outdoor growing if you
guys have any outdoor grow questions
that you would like me to ask Jesse send
them to me
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I will compile the questions I'll
take screenshots into my phone I'll put
them all in one little section and then
I'll get Jesse back over here and we
will address your question specifically
so that we can help you out with exactly
what you need
kind of dial it in and aim it a little
more at you specifically get what you
need one other quick thing plants are
gonna start using more water so don't
just give them what they'll take and
what they need to stay perked up if you
want big fat bugs you gotta get them
lots of water lots of water I guess that
that mainly applies to inground plants
but same same you know same for potted
container it I mean it'll take so much
water but right but as soon as it dries
give it some more oh yeah don't be shy
don't sleep in and think you can water
those plants later no you can't you
gotta get out there and water right now
if you're not want to stay on it don't
start it that's the truth
if you let them dry out it's a
noticeable chunk out of your harvest
yeah it's I'm sure it's like that an
indoor or outdoor yeah how do you feel
about using a drip system in an outdoor
girl awesome awesome
okay it's I've promised the listeners
that I would talk about building a drip
system but it's not a lot of plant
involvement and I don't want to spend
too much of an episode talking about
building PVC pipes that actually kind of
be a hard episode cause it's not really
hard but some that just go do it just
get your hands dirty yeah I'll just
there you go that's perfect I'll give
them like a 5 or 10-minute primer like
here's what you need a pump and some
tubes and a [ __ ] octopus head and
some tubing and some sprinklers and you
build that it seems really tutorial yeah
just like Jesse said just doing it
because you got to get out there and
measure you need a tape measure and a
PVC pipe cutter and just got to go to
town to learn how to build it's like
Legos basically I bought these two $30
kits from Lowe's and like I'd never this
was last year never really done a drip
system before I was a little nervous and
by the afternoon I'm like I'm a [ __ ]
expert what it is they have all the
parts over there at Lowe's if you go to
that little section and look around your
head will just start spinning and you'll
know what to do I'll do a quick lesson
on it in the future here I might let you
come hang out with me and also it'll be
fun alright guys we've gone 40 minutes
is there anything fun you want to ramble
and talk about chaotically randomly that
you want to make sure that people hear
on a podcast anything you got coming up
that you want to share with people
I just put you guys on the spot you both
looking me blankly secret sessions
coming up you guys August 27th I cannot
reveal the location but it is coming up
I should be there the same days reggae
on the rocks so I've got to go to
regular the rocks I wish I could tag you
in for the headlining band bro they're
playing with I raishin it's 311 and I
raishin doing a set together
oh man at Red Rocks yes like the first
time the plebeians snuck into the roman
council rocks has been not as reggae
every year my favorite reggae bands ever
are opening the show Steel Pulse of
course if you're a reggae fan you know
good old Steel Pulse if you've ever hung
out with me you know I love Steel Pulse
and Morgan heritage is also theirs and
those are my two favorites like if I had
to just pick two reggae bands it like
defined what I like about reggae those
would be the band's so that's that's a
great show for me it'll be the afternoon
I'll get all sunburned I'll have a good
time nice and when it starts getting all
311 e gonna come on I met 311 backstage
at work tour one time I went tickets and
a meet-and-greet from kilo yeah that's
cool the dopest thing was this dope ass
JanSport backpack I got in the cave of
18 actually there's a 311 you used to
actually get in fistfights with sublime
which is my favorite band and
a lot of people they sound like the
exact same band but so I don't like 311
and the whole time I was bringing up all
these fights and these guys are like man
these guys are lame and just kind of
wandered off I was like 19 years old
nice you weren't as polite as you are
now either no no I'm sure you were
you're having a little more fun with
them you're letting on them a little bit
before trolling people was a thing out
of the social media of course if you
want to follow me on Instagram I am at
ireon discord genetics most other things
just search grow from your heart you'll
find me if you want to send me me send
me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com Jesse tell us about your
podcast one more time and how everyone
can find you on the social media check
me out on social media
Jesse grows on Instagram and then you
can check out the podcast on soundcloud
that's Colorado podcast and we've got
some of the episodes up there and then
you can also check us out on Facebook
just Colorado podcast make sure you
support him guys check him out we'll
have a website back up soon which is
Colorado podcast calm so do you guys get
hacked oh that's easy to fix
yeah that's easy enough dude thanks for
coming taking some time away from the
garden taking some time from the Uncle
Bud Co thanks for bringing Terps yeah
thanks for also Mike let's remind people
about your your Facebook page and how to
stalk you on a social media ah you guys
can find me at Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook and at Neil
funk 15 on Twitter thanks thanks for
coming thanks for taking time away from
the wife and the kid the dog this is a
great show thank you a lot of fun I love
these episodes I've got no books full of
notes from other shows from these hope
you guys got some useful information and
hope you took a bunch of good notes I
hope you had a great time I'm gonna wrap
up this part of the show if if you're
listening this would be a good time for
emails about tips and tricks for harvest
oh there you go if you got any harvest
questions we have time to answer for you
to prep for that outdoor harvest matter
overwhelming yep yep somebody that from
their Facebook posts looks like
overwhelmed oh I know two people that
still haven't trimmed all their [ __ ]
from last year and I'm not even kidding
and they put themself in an even worse
predicament this year Oh sounds like you
know them very well all right don't be
shy you guys I would love to answer your
questions on the show Jessie would love
to come back and have questions
specifically laid out for him to answer
Mike would love to just come be on the
podcast and take some dads and hang out
I love bringing material so bring it I
would love to have it send me your info
send me your questions grow from your
heart at hotmail.com because I'm gonna
wrap up this portion of the show where
I've got friends with me you know I'm
gonna play some reggae music for a
couple minutes and I'll be right back
and I'll do the end of the show thanks
for hanging out you guys
[Music]
yeah I want to thank you guys again for
listening I want to thank Jesse and Mike
for joining me make sure you follow my
friends on social media I also a huge
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band thanks for letting me play
all your music on my podcast I truly
appreciate that make sure you support
the mystic roots band ladies and
gentlemen I will be back Monday with
episode number 150 podcast number 150
will feature there's a dabbing granny
the podcast also features Sam from THC
magazine Brett from Evo labs Lindsey the
travelling stoner and boba blaster Co
the podcasters recorded at the candy
candy make sure you check that one out
it will be available on Monday August
29th um if you guys would like to
sponsor the podcast or if you've got a
product you would like me to review send
me an email it's a grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I will get you all of the
information that you need now the show
is over you guys please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for the
girlfriend heart podcast find the review
section type in a little comment let me
know what you think about the show and
give me a star rating that you feel I
deserve I'm not gonna beg for five
starters give me however many stars you
feel the show deserves everybody else
has left five stars so far I'm confident
I'll get five without begging of course
I would appreciate it if you follow me
on all the social media outlets I'm
available on Facebook it's the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast on Instagram I use my other
company name it's Irie underscore
genetics I RIE
underscore GE and ET ICS I read genetics
that is my seed company make sure you
support that on Instagram I post a lot
of great cannabis photography if you've
got something you're not into the social
media of course you can email me it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and almost every
episode is archived on ira genetics
colorado dot-com ladies and gentlemen I
appreciate you for listening to the
podcast I'll be back in seven days with
another episode big shout outs made in
just Spence and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
it's a podcast world that your boy Rasta
Jeff before I start episode 150 I wanted
to drop in and say thank you to everyone
that listens to the podcast and everyone
who has ever been on the podcast 150
episodes means a lot to me and I
appreciate all of the support also this
podcast was recorded live at the canna
Canyon from about six minutes till ten
minutes it gets a little noisy I tried
to fix it the best I could but it sounds
a little crappy and I do apologize after
ten minutes it'll be crystal clear and
you'll enjoy the show once again thanks
for the support
and now here's episode 150 of the girl
from your heart podcast
[Music]
it's your source for cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you for
joining me my friends in the podcast at
the canyon labs and everything you need
[Music]
welcome to here's a he was given to me I
did not
[Music]
beautiful all donations to dab and
Granny on that corner flows Nevada
[Music]
you might get to me the dog this is my
favorite a balls
like mine sitting down
[Music]
giggles about your book have you on the
show it's great in Barnes &amp; Nobles
across the country
[Music]
we're trying to get everybody
more than 50% of my listeners are from a
place where cannabis is illegal so they
know very basic knowledge about cannabis
[Music]
well terpenes are in basically every
type of well there's two different types
of things that could be in fruits or
vegetables and stuff like that beans or
esters but a lot of stuff that you get
either smell from or taste from comes
from some type of terpene combination
and apples oranges bananas everything
they also are in cannabis now from my
understanding as of right now there
hasn't been any esters found in cannabis
but there are tons of terpenes and there
are over a hundred and fifteen terpenes
150 terpenes that make up kind of a
plant profile yeah right now the best
labs can maybe test for thirty of them
maybe 34 um maybe the best labs honest
you don't even know ha anchor those 30
tests those 30 terpenes two testings
actually how accurate they are but after
that there's some companies that can go
for 15 or even 10 so I mean it's it's
that's basically there's a whole bunch
of different terpenes that make up a
plant profile so the Turks are basically
it's smell it's taste but also there's a
lot more than just smelling taste to it
and this guy sat next to knows a lot
about the health benefits and actually
knows a lot about terpenes and that's
why actually the big article in the
magazine is about and he knows a lot
about the health benefits there is a lot
of stuff to do with the taste of it
most people that buy it only understand
[Music]
so basically as popular as terpenes are
for flavor they do a lot more medically
I actually had a chance to talk with max
Montrose he's the head of the trichome
Institute and he is you know he is
probably the beats her peen head beats
her peen expert so he gave me you know
really nice little education and you
know terpenes are basically the way he
described it in the way that I kind of
explained it in the article is basically
like a glass of beer so when you have a
fresh cannabis plant that's a fresh
glass of beer with all of those bubbles
floating off all that carbonation
floating up to the top over time that
disappears over time with a fresh
cannabis plant those fresh oils those
fresh terpenes on the end of the plan
are going to disappear over time okay
and those not only add flavor but they
also add depending on what time of
harvest you do with the plant you can
also pull different terpenes they do
earlier you can get a higher CBG or cbn
rate usually
[Music]
definitely would be affected to
increase/decrease and really what
fascinated me most I think about my
conversation with Max Montrose's really
that what people think is the medical
benefit coming from cannabinoids might
really be coming from terpenes so it's
really kind of you have to really
combine the two to really get a full
picture of really what's happening cuz
every strain has CBD CBN CPG depending
on the distrain to some ratio but what
really differs of what really
differentiates excuse me a lot of
strains is that terpene profile because
not every strain is gonna have that
certain combination of the combination
of talking about I have talked to max
and I do know that there are still more
studies hopefully that there's gonna be
even bigger studies going on obviously
with the advancement of cannabis in this
community hopefully more studies but
what Stan was saying with is really true
without terpenes might not transfer in
your brain or transfer in your body the
same way so that's what kind of might
there's still studies I'm not don't
quote me obviously but I know that
there's people talking about
without the terpenes and it's kind of
true because I felt it I mean when you
[Music]
say
there's another one I was like oh man I
should cuz it matches his rig and I was
like you know he's not gonna want that
he's like why'd you buy me an iron now
you love and I'm like crap that one's
gone
[Music]
all right we're talking about Terps do
believe you get a better medicated
feeling once you add any of the Terps
like I like in the morning I like that
lemon gee oh god you know that goes
train Hayes that's wonderful sir in the
mornings are my two favorites granny Zen
berry or that Blackberry crush
definitely I mean that's what I was
saying
I know I personally feel that without
surfing's cannabinoids wouldn't transfer
in your your body the right way the same
way as I don't see the right way the
same way as they do right now when with
terpenes I know one thing is I love
Terps like what specific terpenoids work
for specific conditions what they may
help with because we already know
strains will work well for seizures high
CBD works good for like epilepsy oh he's
got an article in his hand to refer to I
love it when people come with research
this is gonna be awesome we're gonna
learn what annoyed will help with
specific ailments he's pulling out a
chart helping them find the right page
to do his page-turner Brett over there
[Music]
all of this in
if you've got a strain that has flavors
and characteristics the D limonene
terpenoids let it get a little bit too
close to the light and it will panic
will start treating as a panic response
my plants too close to the white too
many times my experience podcast you
know it was what you just did is the
reason I started listening to you it was
you're in
[Music]
and it was like wow this one today this
is 150 so obviously got one of the can
ready to go
[Music]
are incredible because really can you
see your mother or your grandma doing
and smiling and then most people think
oh she's laid out
I'll come back for you
[Music]
I'm a free agent
so everybody what we're talking about in
Colorado if you're a medical marijuana
patient you were allowed to grow a
specific amount of plants plants based
on what your doctor feels is appropriate
based on your medical condition or
honestly based on how much money's in
your pocket it just costs more honestly
so you pay for an elevated plaque on is
what we call it that allows you to grow
more plants and also to possess more
cannabis when you go to a dispensary in
Colorado Springs we are able to grow
those patients have the dispensary to
grow those plants for them we call it
signing over your plants you become a
member
anybody have her business unless she
wants to tell us I don't know the first
thing about growing well I've always
I've always smoked I've smoked long
before it was illegal and this dabin
thing was pretty new um about what maybe
two years ago and at the dispensary I
was going to they kept saying you need
to try this you need to try this I know
y'all are young boys with slapback hats
I'm not gonna try this
this is not for me I'm an old lady well
then actually it was the owner of the
canna Canyon Aaron Ana Pete they were
like come on try it you have a high
tolerance try it when I tried it but I
wasn't too big on it cuz I didn't know
what I was doing then in November I got
a portable email de barro up and in
Denver because they're the ones that
encouraged me to go in front of a camera
when I didn't know what the hell I was
doing
and doodads and smile and talk and when
I was like but why should I do it now
everybody wants to dab quiet that you
just talked about kind of how she's
changing what it looks like to take a
big changes what people's opinions look
like you know what a high tolerance
looks like what actually functioning on
that high tolerance looks like
I woke up this morning - but you know
the best thing about being young yes I
needed butane my torches and I see Rasta
colors and it said
Pop's crops gift shop no red card needed
okay that's a butane right I walk in the
door and there's somebody on a couch and
it's not the can of Canyon vibe it's
more like dad lounge family joint kind
of vibe yeah
barroom kind of vibe and a person on the
couch goes you looked familiar
I'm the davon granny and I wasn't
Tooting my horn or anything so I said
yep butane and the girl goes yeah she
was kind of attitude with me Anna
she said if I turn you on to a DAB can I
record it and I said sure I don't care
so she's recording and she goes she says
she's famous I hope it was worth the
wait
she doesn't carbon and lifts off the
pipe it was very weird they didn't like
me there granny don't go there somebody
was just killed in the parking lot there
last week
[Music]
awesome
so inside Joe it's about the car to make
you blush back we did experience one
thing in the car though I don't like it
when the person dreadlocks and that
freaks me the [ __ ] out completely last
podcast when someone was sitting behind
me on the couch and they were using a
torch and I look to you and I was like
okay you're right that's weird I don't
like that or my dreads down how is there
one of them loose
[Music]
right now we have anyway I got to know
because of the parchment paper anyway so
some Biola which needs to be kicked up a
notch it's not real flavorful so our
good friend the Turk has some Durbin
poison I'm distinguishable it's one of
my favorite flowers to smoke honestly
and I don't enjoy the what was the
combination you had last week thank you
it was the Durbin poison on some shatter
I remember what the shatter was it's
within the Terps the flowers are amazing
I love the lemon tea the ghost train
haze the OG Kush the parentage
[Music]
No
she's like bread up for being such a
kind loving person in the cannabis
community when I jumped on the scene
back
member I didn't know what the hell I was
doing in none of you in fact most people
were like where the hell did this woman
come from note that Brett wrote me with
one of his first slaps as people call
them to just slap them up on everything
is lightbulb Mary's motivation that just
encouraged me to keep being positive and
Cillian because I don't think he
believed that I really kept that letter
for that long you always are and like
every time I see you you're never upset
you just alright let's do this here's
Terps let's do this I'm you know like so
positive all the time is Instagram
it displays exactly that guys follow
Mary's underscore motivation or
motivation yours right to your mouth
what the hell is that that was so
perfect I was like dude I'm never gonna
do that I don't have a rig that's it was
just perfect hi I was just looking at a
stone looking at the rig and I was like
okay take a funny day and I looked at my
Bob Marley poster on the wall or
tapestry in the wall and I'm like well I
read kind of curse maybe I could do a
headstand it'll reach right my mouth and
honestly a first trial
to try my first trying to work the box
[Music]
will not hop over my head so I ask
grumpy grandpa will you give me a lift
and he said you are not one of those 25
year old kids no I will not help you do
a handstand granny to blow my nose
that's the best he was like but I don't
want to be on the camera and I respected
that and I was like well what do you
want no you ass and he is like well just
just call me grumpy grandpa and I was
like okay
grandpa actually because he has such
chronic pain and chronic illness some
days he's pretty grumpy but considering
I've been with him since every day he's
[Music]
right
how hard was it for you to get some
cannabis when you lived in the corn I
started meeting guys coming back from
the Vietnam War you know I was exposed
to first cannabis and then many other
things in my life I can truly say what
life experience don't mess with that
other [ __ ] I can agree with that I mean
okay you all you young folks say you
need your spiritual experiences with
psychedelics I respect that I'm not
gonna do it and as far as like oh man
that's poison stay away from that crap
anything that anybody has to make sounds
contradictory because we smoked herbs
but we're extracting something from
groan all right coming back from Vietnam
and start smoking cannabis in Iowa the
corn raisin he'll be a youngster when
did you move to Colorado
[Music]
yes okay but yes before the Revolution
I'm telling things I'm telling secrets
but I would every now and again get my
hands on cannabis oh boy did the
Europeans love American cannabis oh I
bet and I always I just have always
found people that consume or like-minded
folks which we like to you can always
find it's like we if you get a new job
if you go to a new school if you move to
a new town if you go to a new whatever
if you join if you're an arch in the
archery when you go to that new archery
class whatever it is if you're a
glassblower you walk in your class for
everyone smokes bad example but if you
walk into most places that dude over
there he's a Terp or just like me feel
the waters out when it's break time you
want to go [ __ ] get some 4/20 on you
can always just find the like-minded pot
heads in the group it's it's just
because we put a vibe outward
where's a few haters in the community
but you know that's like every every
sect of life you're gonna have a few bad
people of course but for the most part
the people in the cannabis community are
happy people were loving people we wanna
help each other we wanna help other
human beings and we love the earth we
want to respect it I mean we're all
pretty like-minded we're all connected
in that one way we if we don't love if
we don't take care of the earth easier
to love each other I'm never angry think
about it
you can be angry at somebody and know
it's ugly
[Music]
you know you're so angry at your
neighbour whatever it's an anger is a
pretty ugly emotion does your neighbour
know that it's eating you up probably
not yeah he's renting space in your head
[Music]
yeah all right grantie you're awesome to
have on the podcast I like some of the
stuff you say you said a second ago
you're telling your dark secrets
okay in my life and I have no criminal
record I'm destined to be here right now
right here at this oceans and I think
everybody can find you on all the social
media YouTube Facebook and I'm Facebook
because I am the dab and granny I
consume a large amount of Medicine I
know there's many of those out there
many names any one of those companies
could have come and said hey we like you
we're gonna help you they didn't divide
Oded
I like tomato whose 420 they had pens
they have silicone things that make exit
bags which you have to have at every
dispensary here in Colorado
and then I'm gonna be reppin mega Tok
which is smoking cannabis so this is
gonna be smoking flower which is kinda
different for me so be watching for me
to be doing some more mega toh mega
chokes - do you smoke in one day on
average about 4 to 5 grams good quality
shatter or life resin every day you guys
yes amazing
that's impressive she keeps up with me
if she doesn't do me the sponsors I love
that this community is willing to
sponsor each other and help each other
out
it makes the wheels go round that's
right thanks for coming on the podcast I
look forward to having you on future
episodes because I love your vibe you
need to have your own show that may be a
possibility in the future I'm going to
encourage that I'm being told not to
talk too much about it but you need your
own damn show that's what I think I've
said that before you need a show
together Sam first podcast - kind of
supposed to practice run remind
everybody where they can find you on
social media and then tell us about the
magazine
[Music]
guys make sure you follow the hep
connoisseur it's a great magazine
well printed Brits time grab the mic
buddy
[Music]
never seen you before this is my go way
back like this before we even met
so he's intimidating he's like a six six
six to know what he does and who he is
actually saw Matt it was some cannabis
event it was ahead of II think champs
possible here in Denver I couldn't even
say what's up because I don't even know
what to talk about but now look at me
I'm just like I'm so didn't this teach
you that every one of us were all alike
I completely appreciate that and it's
returned bro you are a lab manager for a
well-known lab that makes one of my
favorite products
[Music]
those are some people's favorite
episodes thanks for coming dude I look
forward to doing more podcast with you
and you both yes I can speak for
everybody at this table we're just
people we we get thirsty when we wake up
we gotta pee in the morning we like to
take dad's you know who I am I will be
very upset because I know eventually I
will say what's up to you and if you say
the same thing I've said and you've
heard this I've got dreadlocks down to
my almost what is behind that voice
hello and I'll be your friend we can
hang out we can take some selfies now
what
[Music]
so tell us a whole bunch about furniture
I was excited sweet little furniture
ideas ideas I have a whole bunch of
products that are available on Big
Cartel dot-com
and basically I make coffee tables and
tables
I have shelves that with basically
emails built into it so you don't have
to have a clumsy little that's why he is
not all over social media he's too busy
building my table decoration was to
really get that working
[Music]
thank you I appreciate it's a great
product I fully endorse furniture tables
we get you locally for in Pueblo we get
you if not I do like custom stuff if you
have stuff in like ideas you want to
come to me yeah you want le cases
[Music]
sometimes the traffic is illegal for
medical
[Music]
remember you need places to gather and
consume you have people that have leases
that they can't medicate in their own
apartment where they're gonna go
you need places like this we have
learned here in Colorado so listen to us
we're trying to help you
we're not being arrogant he's completely
right and Colorado
the bills here we did not include
consumption areas so there's a gray area
these places could be shut down at any
time this candy cane in where we sit
here at this table and gathered
peacefully and take some dabs and have a
podcast together no more and it could be
over so when you do get around to
writing the legalization bills in your
state make sure you include these types
of places make sure you put so many of
these places available in so much
locality and rules for them because if
you don't rules rules will be written
for you you get really [ __ ] okay
nothing rules if you make the rules
yourself you'll be a part of that make
sure you get the social clubs in the
legislation get your [ __ ] together
remember people knowledge is power thank
you the beautiful most of our listeners
know how to find you by now everybody
connections without G my Twitter is the
travel stoner and my periscope is the
travelling stoner you are one travelling
stoner that's me I like sponsoring you
that you need to support while your
honor
[Music]
I can't speak highly enough of her as
well because they are high school now I
[Music]
pick up the leaves there's no need for
you to be out there
[Music]
you're and always try and do it for
somebody in this I always talk about I
see his Instagram pictures about you
already grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
you've got a product anything from you
content is amazing I want to hear your
opinion I want to know what you got
going on in the cannabis industry to the
candy Canyon we're on Avenue
[Music]
to apologize
I hope you were able to get through it
thanks for joining me also big shot at
the TV Sam also shout out to Brent
Lindsay and Bobo blaster Co Canyon and
elevate glass everybody listens to this
podcast and also to everybody who has
been a guest on this show I completely
appreciate each and every one of you
guys show's over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for the door
from your heart podcast find the review
section type in a little comment let me
know what you think of the show and give
me some stars and give me one through
five stars give me as many stars as you
feel like I deserve I would appreciate
your rating so far everybody has given
me a 5 star rating and I appreciate that
if you leave a comment I will read your
comment on a future episode I would
appreciate it if you stalked me on the
Internet
follow me on Facebook at growth my heart
podcast find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast and check me out on Instagram I
use my seed company name it's Irene or
genetics please check us out I post a
whole bunch of great cannabis
photography I think you would enjoy it
if you've got something to say you're
not into the social media thing you can
send me an email it's girl from your
heart at hotmail.com if you'd like to
sponsor the podcaster if you've got a
product you'd like me to review once
again send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I'll get you all
the information that you need
don't forget the shows available on
iTunes stitcher and most of the episodes
are archived on I read genetics Colorado
comm you can catch the show on Tok radio
every Tuesday that's right check us out
on Tok radio.com
they play the show Tuesday at 1:00 p.m.
big shout out to citizen Jay and
everyone on Tok radio.com it's all I've
got free this week ladies and gentlemen
thanks again for listening I want to
give a huge shout out to my ninja Spence
it's all next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast then you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the drove from your heart podcast I
hope everybody out there has a great
weekend I'll be back Monday with the
fresh new episode and until next time
take a fan dad and give your mom a hug
for me
you