[Music]
yeah welcome back campus community it's
time for episode number 268 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write a fear a new
grower if you're a professional grower
who's here at new smoker or a dedicated
davor if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic route been flooding use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to cat to the entire mystic Brewis crude
once again welcome to the show everybody
I am dabbing on some Tahoe og batter
from apothecary and it made me totally
numb for a couple of seconds that's
something I haven't experienced in quite
a while
took a big old fat my whole body went
numb I felt like that dude in that movie
I can't feel my legs and then I was like
wait I can't feel my legs it's kind of a
cool thing I was like I'm [ __ ] numb
feel all rubbery and Gumby like that was
kind of nice shout out to our friends at
apothecary for great work with the Tahoe
batter I don't know who grew the
material but the hash did a hell of a
great job alright I'm gonna get my Gumby
ass together here and we're gonna talk
about some podcast stuff because I had a
great week I hate to come on the podcast
and brag but holy crap a big shout-out
to white Mike and also the white Mike's
wife white Mike invited me to go see
Kevin Smith and Jason Mewes Jay and
Silent Bob get old a recording of a live
podcast here in Pueblo that's right
Kevin Smith and Jason Mewes came to
Pueblo Colorado they did a live
recording of their podcast at a place
called Memorial Hall which is right
downtown in Pueblo first of all I'm
[ __ ] surprised I've never been to a
show at Memorial Hall because the place
is super cool it's real tiny it's uh
there we are right up front so it seemed
real tiny to me it's kind of it it's a
smaller sized venue one thing I did
notice that tickets for every show are
quite overpriced you can see the same
show for cheaper somewhere else but it's
a really tiny place it's kind of a cool
place I'm amazed I've never been their
first show but Kevin Smith and Jason
Mewes of course Jay and Silent Bob from
all the Jay and Silent Bob movies Kevin
Smith is director of quite a few movies
he directed Mallrats clerks chasing amy
what's the other one tusks they make fun
of him a lot for tusks Jay and Silent
Bob strike back anyway we got to go
check that out Mike got front-row
tickets for that Mike went his wife
joined and our buddy Brian from work
tagged along with the the other ticket
that we had so that was a good time
hey Mike thanks for taking me bro I
laughed my ass off I ate a lot of
edibles before I went and I took a
gigantic dab right before the show
turned like a couple of my friends like
you okay bro I'm just high as [ __ ] I
don't have anything to [ __ ] say
people were trying to talk to me and I
just couldn't think it and there were no
words there were not words for my head
at the time he just wasn't [ __ ] for me
to say
I just stayed silent most of the time so
that was my Friday night Friday night a
zipped home from work kind of cleaned up
a little bit man windsock Kevin Smith
and then Saturday what did I do Saturday
hung out a little bit I bet some
gardening did some stuff like that and
then went up to Colorado Springs and saw
Harry mow and the Colorado reggae unit
featuring miss Jenny Beth on vocals and
quite a few other amazing reggae artists
I watch them play one set danced around
there weren't many people dancing and so
I thought watch this I let my dreadlocks
down and I went standing in the middle
of the dance the wind stood in the
middle what did I just say wouldn't
stood it I think I said I went standed
god damn I'm high I went stood in the
middle of the dance floor I don't know
how to dance you guys I'm six foot five
and I'm lanky and I'm goofy but I just
left my dreadlocks down and just wiggle
around like a [ __ ] white hippy and
just shake my dreadlocks around to the
reggae music and the reggae band was
smiling at me like I know what you're
doing and then suddenly all the people
were dancing it was a good ass time you
just got to break the ice he just got to
dance but then for the second set we ate
some food during the set break there's a
little break there for the musicians to
take a rest played for about an hour and
then they took a break and then I was
eating some food finishing up some of
JB's free meal she gets from being in
the band and uh they yelled Rasta Jeff
we need you to come up here and play
djembe so they invited me up on stage
again to go play djembe with them it's
always fun to join the reggae band bunch
of really good reggae musicians they're
all I think all of them are probably
older than myself and I really like
playing with older musicians there's
less ego there's a better tempo it's
more musical nothing to get stealing
musicians but the older cats have
something especially in reggae music you
just need a rhythm section
they just lays back and plays rhythm you
don't need a whole bunch of fancy [ __ ]
and these guys are older cats and they
nail it so shot a two Jenny Beth
Harry Moe and the entire Colorado reggae
unit alright let's turn down this music
because I'm still dad the [ __ ] out from
I took two dads at that Tahoe the first
one I was like that wasn't enough so I
went in a little harder on the second
one and my whole body went numb I got
goose bumps and my arm hair moved around
it was [ __ ] awesome I could feel my
eyes all droopy
I hope I'm not doing a terrible podcast
all right guys let's talk about my most
uh my newest breeding project my newest
and most recent breeding project I'm
always talking about breeding stuff
right so my current breeding project I
have got a
course it's a king Soloman male King
Solomon is golden go across to the day
breaker I am using King Solomon I found
an amazing male I've talked about it a
lot I probably went through somewhere
between 250 and 500 seeds of the arise
cross to find the male that I wanted
I've got the stud that I want I named
him King Solomon he's in a room right
now he is getting ready to pollinate
amongst many other several other sexy
ladies he is going to pollinate for the
first time cactus cooler for the first
time he will pollinate durbin poison and
he will also pollinate a star dog female
so there will be cactus cooler durbin
poison and star dog all crossed to the
arise in the near future that's
something I am really excited about I'm
super excited about the star dog because
I start out to arise that's gonna start
hogs already a great producer it's
already resinous I think it's gonna put
more of a funk to the flavor and it
should increase trichomes and it should
increase production the Durbin poison
cross I'm hoping that that brings out
some of that anise and licorice and that
funky flavor from the Durbin poison into
the sweetness and the funkiness of the
arize I think that'll be a very great
cross now that I'm thinking about it
it's gonna be I have an idea of what its
gonna be similar to I don't know if I
want to say it out loud I want to let
other people smoke it and see if they
see it also when it's done cactus school
or to arise cactus cooler tastes like
pineapples and oranges and sweetness and
I'm hoping to bring that out in the
arize cactus cooler is already a huge
growing plant so this should be a very
interesting cross this might be
something that may be a hit for the
outdoor grow season I'm sure that I'll
get several phenotypes that at least
have that orange e citrusy pineapple e
kind of taste to it and that's what I'm
looking for I want to breed with that a
little bit so those are some of the
things that are coming up in my newest
breeding project I like to keep you guys
updated there are of course some of the
classics the classic females are in
there the Grateful dog is in there to
make morning dew white widow is in there
to make storm shadow
cookies and cream is in there to make
the cream there are a couple others in
there also so we're gonna restock some
of the old stuff and create some new
stuff at the same time of course there's
a couple of a rises in there so we can
make some more rise but everything in
that room there's a purpose for that's
kind of what I was getting at by talking
about my breeding project everything in
there I've got a goal and a
and why I'm making it and I'm also going
to start using a new male in the future
so I'm crossing a bunch of the older
stuff to have a nice stockpile of some
of that and making some new stuff at the
same time some of the stuff will be made
in 2f twos the arise that are being made
in this room right now will be F twos
there's some new ideas in there also
when January comes they're changing the
limits in Colorado so my rules will be
different to the amounts of plants that
I can have will be different so my idea
for breeding instead of having a large
amount of females and one male I will be
using probably two males and a smaller
amount of females that way I can keep my
plant counts legal and be safe and keep
myself protected under all the Colorado
laws that's what I need to do that's one
of the most important things that I have
to do is make sure I'm legal and
protected and safe so now that they're
tightening all the numbers here in
Colorado my breeding will become much
more focused I'll have to think it
through a little bit more I have to use
less space less plants but it challenges
me a little more but you know what we
used to grow when it was completely
illegal so giving me rules and making me
work with rules and dance around those
rules I will follow them I'll stay
completely legal and I'll still do well
because I love a good challenge it's
kind of cheating now because you know
like we can have all you could buy all
the gear you could do it legally back in
the day you couldn't even have the gear
you'd get in trouble for having a grow
light now you can have the [ __ ] and grow
as long as you're not growing too much
so as long as they're gonna let me grow
a certain amount I'll do it I like the
challenge I like they're making me think
a little more it sounds fun I'm ready
let's do it but anyway my breeding
projects are gonna tighten up a little
bit you're gonna see a little bit of
different stuff coming from me pretty
soon you're gonna see a different male
enter the scene pretty soon there's
actually a feminized project coming up I
haven't done much feminized stuff no it
will not be the grateful dog it will be
something brand new but we'll talk about
that when that time comes anyway I feel
like the main topic of this show may
take a little bit of time so we should
work our way into it did I cover all the
opening stuff I think we did if not
we'll talk about it next time let's talk
about the main topic of the show I was
on Instagram life if you don't follow me
on Instagram you should follow me on
Instagram it's I read genetics Irie
underscore genetics IR ie
underscore GE and et ICS follow me on
Instagram you can check out my Instagram
live videos in my Instagram live videos
I let people ask random questions and
then I try to answer them to the best of
my ability with no preparation with no
notes just off the top of my head I try
to give them the best advice and
guidance I can and we have a lot of fun
times talking sometimes we take a bunch
of dabs or I take a bunch of dabs I
don't know what everybody else does but
I take tabs I eat edibles and hang out
but somebody on one of my Instagram live
videos asked me to talk about what f1
means and what IBL means and all that
type of stuff so I did give a brief
explanation there on Instagram live but
I feel like it would be a great podcast
episode so I took a few notes I did
write some of this stuff down so that I
actually sound like I know what I'm
talking about
and they told me that I got it all right
on the Instagram live video and I just
pulled it pulled it out of my ass and
shot it out off the top of my head and I
hope I got it right they all said I did
so I was proud of myself there so I made
notes this time so that we can talk
about what land races are what an IBL
what an f1 through f5 and so forth and
we'll talk about a few other things but
if you don't know what I'm talking about
here's where I'm headed with this if you
go to shop for seeds if you're looking
to buy a new package of seeds and you
want to grow something new there's a
whole bunch of letters and numbers on
the package that may not make sense
you'll see let me just pick a cross that
I want to go random but I'm gonna pick
something of mine of course let's say a
storm shadow storm shadow is White Widow
cross to theorize that's kind of an f1
it's also kind of a poly hybrid so I
would just write storm shadow X arise
that would show you storm shadow to
arise it should always be listed with
ladies first whichever female plant was
used since the storm shadow was the girl
plant ladies first storms or white widow
I'm sorry the white widow was the female
plant white widow X arise now it's a
white widow girl that's obvious because
the girls ladies first is how it goes
when you're listing genetics white widow
X arise now a lot of breeders will put
either an f1 or an f2 after that now if
you're gonna put an f1 or an f2 you have
to put the white widow to arise white
widow X arise in parentheses and then
put f1 or f2 next to that because that
will indicate that that whole cross it's
the f2 of that cross so now let me talk
about what I know that may sound
confusing but it'll make more sense one
nice
talking about what an f1 is what an f1
f1 F stands for filial the filial
generation number one if I take you
create an f1 by crossing two different
parents and when you indicate parents
when you're listening genetics it is a P
the letter P represents parent excuse
the throat clearing you guys that big
dab is still getting me so crossing to
different parents will result in an f1
and those parents should be either
inbred lines or land races and those
will make F once a lot of what you're
buying now our poly hybrids and we're
gonna talk about that a little bit later
in the episode ah but to F will are
crossing two different strains that are
either stabilized IB LS or stabilized
landraces
will make your f1 F ones the first cross
if you take two different things a boy
and a girl and cross some filial
generation one brand new [ __ ] that nunu
is f1 all right
so F ones are cool because they have
hybrid hybrid vigor which means they're
it's two new things that have finally
hit and there's so much new energy in
there those plants are gonna grow huge
they're gonna grow better than the other
parents then your parents so hybrid
vigor is gonna come out of there
Oh F 1 is semis stable and phenotypes
you're gonna see phenotypes that look
like mommy you're gonna see phenotypes
it look like Daddy you're gonna see some
that mix and then you're gonna see some
that are widely different okay way off
there but you're gonna get pretty close
to mommy and daddy and then the crosses
your prep probably 25% mommy 25% daddy
25% a perfect cross and then 25% of them
are just gonna be [ __ ] whatever like
whatever genetics are in there you'll
see crosses of all kinds of weird [ __ ]
in 25% of them and that's a guess you
guys I can only estimate on genetics on
what you're gonna see but on average
that's kind of what you can expect
so F ones are cool because they've got
that hybrid vigor you're gonna see a lot
of cool phenotypes from an f1 hybrid and
now you've got some brand-new [ __ ]
that's why F ones are cool so now if you
grow if you take a male and a female of
two different strains and you pollinate
the female and seeds come out you have
now made f1 you take those seeds and you
grow them
and you can either just leave him open
and you can have all the males and all
the girls together or you can take a
select male and a select girl or you can
take a select male in several select
girls and you can pollinate that way so
it's either open pollination of a whole
bunch of F wands or select selective
breeding of F ones if you pollinate that
together the seeds that come out of the
F ones if you take a seed from f1 and a
seed from f1 and once a boy wants a girl
or there's a cluster of boys and girls
the seeds that come from that are f2
filial generation f2 now those you're
gonna have a little more stabilization
than the F ones are gonna get a little
bit closer but you're gonna see some
random [ __ ] and then you're gonna have
50% mom 50% dad and then some generate
some some variation in their f2 s are
always it depends on how the selective
breeding process went if you do an open
pollination you're gonna get a whole
bunch of different phenotypes some
people like that if you did a selective
breeding you're gonna see less different
variation in the phenotypes so now if I
take my favorite male and my favorite
female from that f2 and I breed them now
I've just made an f3 and you continue
doing that you can continue doing that
until you reach whatever number you'd
like but by the time you get to the f4
they have 5 generation if you've done
your breeding correctly things will
start coming out like clones if you
plant 50 seeds and 25 were male because
these are regular regular these are not
feminized if you plant 50 25 of them
about 25 we're gonna be at 50%
25 will be males and then 25 of them are
gonna look almost like clones are gonna
be very identical if you've done your
breeding properly now if you keep
breeding you work on what is known as an
inbred line because you are just
inbreeding which means you are actually
eliminating traits because you are
breeding for selective traits and you're
narrowing it down true you're just
inbreeding and inbreeding to get the
perfect plant now that's when you have
created an inbred line an inbred line
also known as an IBL you guys in it
brenton inbred Lahaina or hybrids or
crosses that have been stabilized to
show very little variation like I was
talking about they almost look like
you're making clones you in breed by
just selecting the plant that looks just
like you want and then breed that one
and then pull the seeds out
and growin and find one that looks just
like what you want and then make f4 of
that and then find ones that look just
like what you want make the f5 of that
by the time you get to f5 they're all
gonna start looking like how you want
them to so that's your inbreeding it to
get exactly where you want it you may
need to go further you may need to go F
six you may need to go F seven I
personally have never seen anybody go
past and f5 that I know of but I would
be interesting to see what happens f5
seems to be far enough to get these
seeds completely stabilized to make them
how we want him DJ short said if he goes
past f5 when he sells them it doesn't
leave any work for the public to breed
with them so there's nothing left they
all come out looking just like what he
did if he goes to the f6 so I guess uh
DJ short has gone f6 and he just goes
back to the f5 and releases those he's
probably he's been breeding for longer
than I've been alive I think so he's
probably got some half sevens f 9s or
some [ __ ] in his arsenal he just doesn't
release him or talk about him too much
anyway that's when you get yourself to
an IPL an inbred line is when you inbred
it so much that it's super stabilized to
where almost every seed you plant comes
out looking like a clone of the last
seed you planted or the next seed you're
gonna plant from that same filial
generation so a very common way to find
an inbred plant aren't I BL line an
inbred line is a land race land braces
are purebred lines from specific areas a
lot of people know about like durbin
poison the legendary Durban poison is a
land race from the Durban area of Africa
it's very stabilized it probably came
and I don't know how accurate this is
you guys this is what my kind of if I
had to make up a story of a land race
plant this is what it would be somewhere
somebody traveled to a place and they
gave somebody some weed and that person
smoke that weed and they're like holy
[ __ ] and this is like thousands of years
ago in my mind I don't know how long
honestly I don't know I'm making up this
vision in my head right now ah some two
people that spoke different languages
from different villages were traveling
somewhere and one guy brought a bunch of
weed I'd not have not even a bunch just
some and he shared some weed with this
guy in this other village and he got
five seeds out of it and that guy smoke
that weed and he's like holy [ __ ] that
[ __ ] was good I have to grow those
[ __ ] seeds and he grew the seeds and
he didn't know anything about pulling
males because
this was way back in the day they didn't
worry about that they didn't know they
wanted since Amelia buds so he grew all
five seeds and they got crossed the
males and the females all bred with each
other and the seeds fell into the ground
just like it's supposed to and now he
had like a thousand seeds just plant out
next to sprout up next year and he's
like oh [ __ ] that's a lot so he cut down
some but the males and females that
survived they bred again and it happened
year after year after year so this guy
only had one strain of herb on his
property for however many years he grew
weed and then his son took over and his
son grew that same strain on that
property or maybe nature did it maybe
the people that grew it a hundred
thousand years ago died and nature took
over and it's been F nature f27 to this
[ __ ] plant out there without anybody
intervening because that's what cannabis
would do if nobody got in the way it
would just keep going your after year
after year so maybe this plants on like
f 200 you know and so that's a land race
that's an inbred land race it's inbred
itself so far and now it's just every
seed that you plant is gonna look and
smell just like that that's what I think
a land race is I think an inbred line
and a land race are very similar but I
think n breads are kind of done human
and a land race was done by Nature over
a course of time before humans
intervened so imagine traveling back way
back in the day whatever you believe the
earth was like it's round whatever the
[ __ ] you believe right now it was still
round two then it's still round now but
people are traveling around it then and
it could be one piece of continent it
could be a broken up bunch of cotton
it's it could be a whatever you'd be
alive that way as long as you agree that
it's [ __ ] round come on but somebody
got some herbs somewhere they traveled
around and they dropped obviously they
dropped some off in Thailand cuz there's
Thailand races they drop some off in
Brazil because there's Brazilian land
races and they just dropped off a few
seeds and at F 37 itself and I'm just
being hypothetical with AF 37 s and
whatever but that's kind of what
happened somebody traveled around with a
little bit of weed and it got dropped in
off off in all these places Vietnam so
there's Vietnamese land races of course
there's Afghan land races their land
races everywhere there are Mexican land
races Mexican sativa LAN races are
[ __ ] amazing it's funny because
people are afraid of Mexican land races
because they think it's gonna be schwag
weed just because most of the weed they
bought from Mexico was compressed
that doesn't make any [ __ ] sense I
just think it's hilarious but so that's
what I that's my take on a land race
seeds got traveled around way back
before it was common for people to get
around a whole bunch they were
unadulterated and they just bred
themselves either with the help of a
local farmer or by nature but there were
no more seeds introduced there were no
more variations or no more varietals
introduced to that to breed to out breed
that to out cross it so that's a land
race it just stayed the same and kept
stabilizing itself and getting better
and better over time and that's what it
is those genetics are those genetics
they never got adulterated
so that's landraces inbred lines and
filial generations one through five now
let's talk about something else you
might see on a seed pack is BX BX stands
for bat crossing now bat crossing would
be if I took an f1 so if I cross some
stuff let's say we'll just go with the
the golden go to the Daybreaker cross
those you may can arise f1 now if I took
and arise f1 seed and pollinated it with
the original Daybreaker male that would
be a bat cross and I was really
confusing for me to do because I was
trying to make all the different names
of the strains as I did it so and I'm
gonna say it again just to make sure I
get it right I'm gonna read my notes
without using strain names back crossing
is crossing an f1 back to an original
parent you guys so you make an f1 with a
boy and a girl the baby comes out and
then you either can cross it back to the
boy or back to the dad or back to the
mom that's a back cross and now people
might say why would you want to do that
I've got a good explanation of why and
this will lead me into B x2 which is a
back cross number two so let's say you
want to make seeds that are not
feminized because if you want them to be
feminized it's a different process if
you want regular seeds of a strain that
is clone only and you do not have you
have a female of it but you don't have a
male of it what you can do is create a
back cross so perhaps I want to make
grateful dog there is not a male of
grateful dog I've only got a female of
grateful dog maybe I want to make
grateful dog seeds that are not
feminized because I made feminized seeds
that's the only way it's a
feminize grateful dog let's say I want
to make my favorite grateful dog female
that I've got I want to make it
available in regular seeds I would find
something that is similar to it kind of
kind of similar to it or maybe I'd fun I
don't know there's two different routes
to go there I would cross it with a male
okay I would find a male if you cross it
with a male that's very similar to it
it's gonna be harder to find the male
that looks like the grateful dog to
reuse for the BX but if you cross it to
a male that's very different the one
that's closer to the grateful dog will
stand out and it will be easier to
determine which one to bat cross with
that that's a whole lot of different
talking but for this example we're going
to take the Grateful dog female and
since I've got the arize male on my mind
we're going to use the arize male we're
gonna pollinate that grateful dog with
the arize now we have just made aa
that's actually morning dew so now let's
take morning dew and find a morning dew
male I want to find a male out of this
morning dew that looks just like the
grateful dog so now I've got a male
grateful dog kind of looking plant and I
want to pollinate that female grateful
dog now I have just made a BX I have
made a bat cross now there's another way
you could do that I could take one of
those morning dew seeds and I could find
a female that looks just like the
grateful dog and then I can take that
original rise pollen and throw that on
there again and then that's gonna make
more seeds that would actually be a bat
cross again but it's not the way I was
trying to go I was trying to make the
grateful dog and I think by finding the
male that looks like the grateful dog
and putting it back on the grateful dog
female I'm gonna be putting so many
grateful dog dominant genetics into
there I think it's gonna be very
grateful dog dominant then I will take
seeds that come from that so now I have
taken the morning dew the morning dew
male it looks like grateful dog and I
put it back on to the grateful dog
female right now I've made grateful dog
bx1 because I have gone backwards and
used the grateful dog female that was in
there I'm back crossing you can do it
with the male you can do it with the
female either way it works but my goal
right now is to try to make that
grateful dog in regular seed so now I've
made the morning dew to the Grateful dog
back cross now I would take seeds that
come from
I would grow those BX ones and find one
that looks just like a grateful dog and
once again I would back cross and I'm
gonna find a male and I'm gonna take
that male that looks like the grateful
dog and I'm gonna put that pollen on my
female grateful dog and now I have made
grateful dog BX to regular seed that's
what that would be you guys I'm gonna
press pause I'm gonna take a drink in a
DAB and I'm actually gonna listen back
to this and make sure I feel like I got
this right if you've got any comments or
concerns on what I've just said I would
love all of your input you can send me
an email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail calm or of course you can send
me a tweet at GF wih podcast on Twitter
or you can find me on Facebook look for
the girl from your heart podcast on
Facebook I love the interaction you guys
I'm gonna press pause gonna take a drink
gonna dab some of this Tahoe batter and
then I'll be right back all right
podcast rolled I am back i listened to
back to everything i said and i feel
like i was accurate and what i spoke so
I'm gonna continue another thing we need
to talk about our um feminized seeds now
feminized seeds are labeled differently
or at least they should be
they aren't oftentimes labeled correctly
is what I've noticed but that's uh
that's up to individual breeders I feel
like they should be labeled um as
feminized at least and then the correct
if you're labeling them genetics wise to
list what they are like on a website if
you're gonna say hey this crosses this
to this um it would be an S one if you
took a and we're just gonna pick a
random strain that we keep playing with
the Grateful dog if I took the Grateful
dog and I reversed it which would mean I
treated it with silver thiosulfate or
gibberellic acid or maybe the other type
of silver colonial silver which I don't
feel works well enough I do the silver
thiosulfate myself but if you treated
the Grateful dog plant and pollinated
another clone of the Grateful dog the
same plant it's got to be the same
cultivar you have to reverse one and
pollinate one that is the same cultivar
that is reversing the same cut and
pollinating the same cut you are now
making S ones that is a self
that is an s-1 is what that is so if you
reverse a strain and make seeds of
itself
you are making s ones now if I were to
reverse that grateful dog and take that
grateful dog pollen that is now
feminized pollen and I put that pollen
on any plant other than the grateful dog
I am making what is known as an r1 a
reversal one so I'm using feminized
pollen on a different cut to create new
feminized poly hybrid is basically what
I'm doing so those are two that you need
to know about s1 and r1 now earlier I
said something about breeding with
landraces and breeding with inbred wines
a lot of what you see available in the
seed catalogs and I read genetics
included I'm not calling anybody out I
am part of this group a lot of what we
are breeding is actually poly hybrids
we're taking F ones and f2s
possibly F threes and breeding them to
other F ones or f2 s and they are not
completely stabilized plants that are
being used for breeding although through
experimentation and testing those plants
have been tested well enough for my
approval to be used in breeding I know
they're not gonna hermaphrodite on me I
know that the progeny they create is not
problematic so they are yes they are
poly hybrids but they are stable enough
most of us breeders are aware enough and
educated enough and experienced enough
to know if that strain is worth crossing
or not it would be a good idea for us to
breed something to the f5 before we
crossed it to something else that would
make a true f1 but the poly hybrids is
kind of where the market has gone to now
it's kind of where cannabis breeding has
gone to now it's got its pros and it's
cons so now that you know all of the
glossary words we have got landrace
we've got an IB L which means an inbred
line we've got f1 f2 s all the way up to
f5 s when you start becoming an IB L
basically you can go F six or seven I
talked about nature probably doing F 50
you never know honestly I really don't
know there's probably somewhere in some
jungle or on some island that those
plants have just been making their
finial generations without interruption
that we don't even know about yet
so you can you've got the F Jenner
relations then we've got back crosses
which is when you take an f1 back to the
parent and then you've got a back cross
to is when you take a BX one back to the
parent then we have got the self which
is when we start playing with feminised
seeds then you've got the r1 then we've
got poly hybrids which is mostly what
we're seeing on the market now that
we've got all these glossary terms let's
talk a little bit about the labeling on
seed packages a lot of the companies do
it differently I myself will list golden
goat x day breaker and then it will say
arise because that's golden go across
the day breaker that makes a rise that's
what you're gonna get there are other
breeders who will list that would list
the genetics of the golden goat in a
parentheses which would be ah in one
bracket you'd have a parentheses and
then it would say island sweet skunk X
Romulan then in other parentheses then
it would say Hawaiian sativa then
another parenthesis closing that so that
shows you that it's an island sweet
skunk to Romulan female cross to a
Hawaiian sativa male in one set of
parentheses like a math problem so you
got parentheses starting it and then
another one closing it and then another
one even closing it I don't know what
direction you call those parentheses but
one part sinter parentheses and then
there's another one on the end of that
to make that all one equation x the day
breaker which is joseph OG x chem d that
those two would be in parentheses
together so it showed the male the
breakdown of the male all in parentheses
x the breakdown of the are the female x
the male all broken down into genetics
that's how some folks do it now
sometimes you might see I'm gonna get
hypothetical right now you may see just
a pack labeled arise BX 2 now that means
the arize was back crossed but they
don't that does not indicate what male
was used or what female was used in the
back cross that may be listed in the
parentheses underneath it just depends
on how they do it now that means that
that is the progeny of the back cross it
doesn't say now they may say arise BX 2
in parentheses or arise BX 2 x
Daybreaker in parentheses and that means
that the arise BX 2 was used so where
those parentheses fall kind of indicate
which group the plants were in so
everything in the brackets is that plant
and then if it stays inside of another
set of brackets it's still that plant
but it's the male or the female so I
think what I said makes sense because if
you're listening the grandparents if
you're going that far to list your stuff
it's going to be female X male in
parentheses X female X male in
parentheses and the first set of
parentheses will be the female the
second set will be the male now
sometimes you're gonna see maybe a
breeder used something that's got three
things in it because maybe he took a boy
and a girl and crossed those and then
crossed those to another boy and use the
offspring of that as a female in the
project so that would have female X male
and parentheses X male and then you just
put another parentheses to close that
and that would show you that that's your
female and then X and then whatever your
male is on there
I hope I'm explaining that properly
without writing it down on a dry erase
board and showing you what I'm doing and
feel like I might just be confusing you
but keep this in mind ladies first and
if it gets too confusing when you're
trying to write something down just make
it simpler instead of writing all this
Exodus Exodus parentheses just write
golden goat times Daybreaker arise you
get right to the point it's easier but I
want you to be able to understand it if
you do see all these weird labels
because some people try to just make it
look fancy some folks out there I'll
give a lot of respect and a lot of
acknowledgement to Collin Gordon and the
ethos collective those guys label their
[ __ ] correctly it's a little confusing
but if you're an experienced grower and
you know what you're looking at it makes
a lot of sense and it is very helpful
because they offer different versions of
the same line which can be confusing if
you don't know what you're looking at so
I hope you guys learned a whole bunch I
may have just confused you guys a whole
bunch more talking to you about how to
label things and how to read a seed
package I would honestly love your
feedback about this episode send me an
email I already told you it's grow from
your heart at hotmail com send me a
tweet at G fyh podcast on the tweeter
you can always Instagram me it's IRA
underscore genetics on Instagram what am
I missing
Oh Facebook you can message me on
Facebook alright now since I've talked
about land races and inbred lines
and all this breeding stuff I want to
talk about something that I've seen in a
couple of videos now there's a breeder a
group of readers that travel around the
world and they like to go to places and
I'm not hating on them I'm just bringing
this up to spark conversation I actually
respect these folks they do great work
they've done a lot of work for the
cannabis community and the industry let
me say that before I kind of say what
I'm gonna say and then we'll talk about
I want to make a conversation out of
this um so these breeders they travel
around the world and they go to places
like Africa like Jamaica like they've
gone all over the [ __ ] world to tell
you the truth they go everywhere they've
got a lot of money and they've got
private jets and they know a lot of
people they get all over the [ __ ]
world so these guys get access to go
visit very large outdoor ganja farms all
over the planet now a lot of these
outdoor ganja farms are older than me
they are older than these guys that are
going to visit these are the places
where the land race strains are being
grown just organically these guys didn't
have access to any other seeds nobody
goes there nobody that goes there is
bringing cannabis seeds it wasn't like
hey I should go to Jamaica and take
cannabis seeds nobody ever said that
everybody thinks I should go to Jamaica
and get cannabis seeds nobody nobody
takes sand to the beach so the land race
strains I'm just gonna guess Jamaica now
because I've said that that's gonna be
what we stick with the land race that is
growing in Jamaica that these folks who
went down there and found they went
through it they were like this one this
one's [ __ ] awesome and they broke
open a couple of buds and they told the
guy that owned the farm they're like can
I take these seeds and the guy was like
oh yeah you could take plenty of seeds
so now this breeder brought home a big
old jar of Jamaican landrace seeds
[ __ ] awesome cool now he's got them
they're preserved he's gonna breed with
them he bred them to the next filial
generation he actually sold them through
his website and through his breeding
company through his seed company and in
his coffee shops in Amsterdam
now here's what he did in return he
reached into his pocket and he offered
this farmer handfuls of his own seed
that he is bred now this company color
coats all of their seeds they've got a
product that so they make a prod a
strain called and you're gonna figure
out who I'm talking about if you know
what I'm talking about what I'm just not
gonna say their name they make super
Lemon Haze they coat all of their super
Lemon Haze see
it's in a yellow coating so that you can
just put them in a baggie and carry them
and they don't have to be labeled and
you know those yellow seeds are super
Lemon Haze and then they coat all of
them each screens got its own color and
I don't know what the colors for all of
them are just obvious that super Lemon
Haze was the yellow one that's what I
remember so he reaches into his pocket
and pulls out well it looks like a bag
of M&amp;Ms and it's just colored feminized
and regular seeds and he puts them in
the farmers hand and says thank you for
the trade grow these next year now great
trade right really cool our friend with
the seed company has now got some great
new Jamaican land race genetics the
Jamaican guy has now got some new [ __ ]
to grow the problem is and I don't know
if it's a problem I'm just curious about
this and I want to know how you guys
feel that land race in Jamaica it's been
growing there forever on that island
without human adulteration has been
inbreeding itself in making itself
perfect for that climate and it produces
the product that they're familiar with
every year and it drops seeds and it
grows and it does it again no has this
breeding company has this seed sharer
adulterated that land race by dropping
off these other seeds on this island
because the pollens gonna travel is
everything gonna get pollinated by these
other seeds that he left because there
were feminized and non feminized there
were regular seeds in there so there
will be males to pull and these guys do
not pull males they they throw out so
many seeds and they just let it grow
naturally they don't call any seeds
because they want
ah they want the seeds for next year
they want them to fall and they want the
seeds of thing grow dope mixture because
they don't go get seeds from anybody
that's not what they do they've just
been using this inbred land race so I
kind of want your interaction on this
how do you guys feel about this are they
traveling around the world adulterating
land races while at the same time
collecting land race seeds so that they
can breed them for their own use are
they kind of does that seem like sort of
a a ploy maybe eventually there won't be
any land races and until you have to go
shop with them to get them because
they've traveled all over the world and
picked up some of the land race from
everywhere and labelled it very well
they've got land races from different
regions of different countries they've
got northern Jamaica southern Jamaica
land races and they've got them laid
they know exactly what they are but they
also dropped off their own seeds there
and I'm sure that those farmers planted
it because those farmers probably
weren't thinking the way that I think
they weren't like you came to disrupt my
my land race and he's gonna do something
to the future of cannabis I don't know
is it disrupting their crop is it
improving their crop do you think it's
detrimental to their crop I kind of want
your opinion because it just sparked a
lot of thoughts in my mind so I want to
know what you think interact with me
let's have a conversation about it you
guys email me tweet me social media with
me about it and go watch the videos if
you know what I'm talking about go watch
the videos again and see what you think
I'm just curious on your opinion there's
one thing I should say to that and I was
only just using Jamaica as an example
there are great growers in Jamaica
especially now but there have always
been great growers in Jamaica some folks
were calling the mails they were able to
get other good seeds in Jamaica but just
a lot of the places that I'm talking
about are like mountainside rural places
and if you've seen the videos these guys
have gone to dozens of different
countries and gathered cannabis seeds so
also what can we do about it
I guess if I'm gonna start a
conversation and bring up a problem I
should have a solution right I guess if
you are a seed collector if you are a
conservationist or a preserver of
cannabis seeds maybe you should find a
good vendor that's got reliable landrace
seeds and get your hands on all the land
races that you think you may be
interested in before they get all
adulterated and messed up with the new
cannabis revolution because money is
getting involved so everything worldwide
is going to change with cannabis
all right podcast world that was a fun
episode thanks for joining me for that I
really did have a good time I feel like
I got to teach you guys a whole bunch I
feel like I got to learn a bunch myself
just doing some research I feel like
also I got to go on the rant about that
seed company that I've always wanted to
say publicly I want your opinions I want
your input on that let's see what else
do I have you know what I've got for you
patreon I would appreciation
appreciation [ __ ] I was so smooth until
then I would appreciate it if you guys
went to patreon.com slash grow from your
heart and check it out if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
of your time I'm not begging for money
there are a few people out there that
have said hey I would love to contribute
to the podcast how can I do so patreon
is the way you can do it go to patreon
REO n.com / grow from your heart all the
information you need is right there you
can sign up you can contribute to the
podcast you can help me cover the cost
of hosting the show the podcast is free
it will always be free for everybody but
some folks would like to help out with
the cost of the website some people
would like to buy me the little fuzzy
covers for the microphone so I don't
have to keep spitting into the same one
I can always use a little help with the
new equipment and things like that that
I have to upgrade I buy bottled water
for everybody that comes on the show
stuff like that always helps out so I
would appreciate your help at
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
if you can't contribute to patreon
that's okay I still love you I still
want you to listen to the show keep
hanging out keep learning how to grow
cannabis do your best to improve your
garden with the lessons I give you
that's all I really ask for that's all I
want back is that you love cannabis that
you respect cannabis that you treat
cannabis in a good way
and that you only share positive stuff
with cannabis to the public don't make
cannabis look bad ever don't be too high
and do some dumb [ __ ]
don't ever do some some some dumb [ __ ]
and blame it on being high just always
support cannabis in a positive light
that's all I ask for in return for this
podcast there are a few people that can
help out with patreon thank you I
appreciate it if you can't keep
listening dude join me it's free to
party everybody's invited also what you
can do for free is you can find me on
Facebook search for the girl from your
art podcast you can find me on twitter
at g f YH podcast and of course follow
me on instagram so you can be a part of
those Instagram live videos it's Irie
underscore genetics
don't forget about YouTube there's a
youtube channel to grow from your heart
podcast YouTube channel there are
approximately 130 issue videos up right
now I'm making more it takes a long time
to get them up there alright I want to
thank everybody once again for listening
to a long rambling podcast I will be
back Thursday with the throwback
Thursday episode thanks again for
listening to those long episodes let me
know what you think about those also
please then of course I will be back
Monday with a brand new episode I wanna
give you a huge shout outs my friend J
Dennis and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
just
so me
[Music]
yes
you