[Music]
ocean Rasta Jeff in the house yeah
what's up podcast world it's Thursday
and that means it's time for another
throwback Thursday episode of The Grove
from your heart podcast before we get to
the old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any giveaways any promotions or any
contests all of that stuff has expired
there are no advertisements promotions
giveaways or contests that are valid in
these old episodes I want to thank you
guys for listening and with no further
ado here's a block of old episodes of
the girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 151 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation someone who's just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you I'm
your host my friends call me Rasta Jeff
on to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku and the entire
mystic episode 151 this episode features
a new guy we brought Juicy J to the
table he comes and hangs out with us
also white Mike and Lindsay are back I
hope you enjoy this episode this episode
is brought to you by our friends at
elevate glass that's right elevate glass
517 South Tejon in beautiful Colorado
Springs Colorado if you're in need of a
new smoking device if you need a new
smoking accessory if you need a case if
you need a nail elevate 5:17 South Day
home they've got everything you need to
get nicely medicated before we get too
far you guys only give a huge shout out
to my friend at Stone trikes make sure
you follow at Stone trikes on Instagram
shout out to my brother Stone trikes the
music played for a couple of seconds and
when we get back we'll be at the table
we'll be joined by Lindsay the traveling
stoner we'll have Mike Nemo Punk 15 and
Juicy J from North Carolina we'll be at
the table hang on listen to some music
welcome back to the podcast my left is a
returning guest a repeat offender my
buddy Mike welcome to the show buddy
thanks man
Mike tell everybody I'm sure most of the
folks know but remind everybody that's
new how they can stock you on these
social media you can find me at pablo
for sensible cannabis laws on facebook
or at nemo funk 15 on twitter you guys
also uh make sure you support his pablo
for sensible cannabis speech because
there's a lot going on and level right
now once you listen to this you're gonna
want to go there you're gonna want to
read all the stuff he's gonna post
you're gonna want to know it's gonna be
a huge marijuana election folks stay
tuned
yes huge huge and the new voice that you
guys are hearing kind of in front of me
to my left just a little bit over there
on microphone number three is my new
friend Juicy J blaze we're gonna call
him J today welcome to the podcast my
friend thank you and thanks for reaching
out you reached out to me on facebook
and asked to come on the show I love it
when people do that I
appreciate it welcome to the show
sitting to my number right number four
microphone before I don't know what
where that is over there it's kind of my
in front right ish this joy is running
like Usain Bolt if you want to fix that
when I pass it to you all right so what
cast everybody everybody listening thank
you for joining us there's a lot going
on before I get to that I want to talk a
little bit about my weekend ladies and
gentlemen I had a good friend blessed me
with a front row ticket to reggae on the
rocks if you've never been front row
right down the rocks that's a damn
experience go check that out it's
different it's way different well you
got to see let's go for it I just bought
my first concert tickets to Red Rocks
today actually are we gonna see I'm
gonna see gez on the 22nd Mike and I
were discussing earlier that how we're
in the way different music than a lot of
people Mike's like 10 years older than
everybody he works with I probably I'm
the same age as Mike ten years well
that's funny because I had a front row
ticket and the headlining band was
Mike's favorite band which is 311 love
it I guess I went to 311 I stuck around
for one of the best venues in the
country I am the spoiled brat I've
probably seen 30 bread rocks concerts
and that's no joke probably 15 of them
were widespread panic
I was working that night and I caught a
couple I remember that you would
probably had just left a lot those
videos were being
yes so I get to see I get to see Morgan
heritage that's most the people that
listen to the podcast frequently know
that my favorite reggae band currently
it will change it does just my taste
change over here some that'll catch my
attention but Morgan heritage has been
my favorite reggae band for a couple a
few months here
probably the past year or so they were
awesome they played at 4:45 I got to
catch most of their set they sounded
fantastic they played a bunch of new
[ __ ] that I didn't know which was kind
of cool
I kind of wanted to hear some familiar
[ __ ] like you know you want to hear your
favorites but I also like seeing them
they do kind of a jam band thing they
start off with one song they don't stop
till about halfway through their said
they just segue song to song to song so
I was kind of neat to kind of did a
medley what's your favorite song by them
Joe it really depends on the mood that's
a good question right now like not like
this moment I'd probably throw on like
Jah seed is one of my favorite songs by
them but then strictly roots is also a
good one and then there's a bunch of
like remixes that they do put out a
single all the time but strictly roots
is a great one
so I got to see them they ended then I
was in the front row and I looked back
toward the sound booth just looking into
the crowd and I see one of the band
members hanging out I was like ah he's
over there I was like I'm not gonna go
bug him but he's right there and I
turned around and his brother Peter
Morgan was walking right past me and
Peter Morgan is probably my favorite
reggae singer if I could sound like
anybody if I could sing like a reggae
artist and probably be a Peter Morgan
you know that sounds really weird cuz
he's got a high-pitched kind of voice
he's kind of squeaky but then you could
[ __ ] sing and if I want if I could
sound like anybody probably beat him him
a Richie Spice but uh this is the kind
of reggae voice I wish I had I know I
don't but it's cool but that dude walked
right past me so I just put my hand on
his shoulder and that dude is beefy bro
like you know he touched some people
they kind of move that do did not move
he's one step [ __ ] Jamaican I put my
hand on his shoulder and I was like bro
thank you and he just turned around
looked me straight in my eyes and he
stood out his right hand he shoots my
hand and he said respect and then he
kept on walking cuz he didn't want to
get mobbed you know if I would have
stood there for three seconds he would
have got crowded so he just kept not
moving so that was cool I got to meet
pretty much my favorite reggae singer at
reggae on the rocks that was awesome so
he walked by time went on and then Steel
Pulse came on
Steel Pulse might be my number two
favorite reggae artist so it was great
seeing them I'm hit you guys was great
but they were a little slow everything
just seemed a touch slow they're getting
[ __ ] old like all the dreadlocks are
super gray in steel but they're getting
gray so shut it's my anonymous friend
who got me up front row they're a reggae
on the rock so truly do appreciate that
that was a good [ __ ] time I'll never
forget it
thank you so bring in the rocks oh I
keep going the band after that was I
raishin if you like I apologize
I like roots reggae that I raishin was
not doing it for me that night so I left
and I drove to the secret stash it was
in a really good mood there's a really
great time I got to meet Adams wife for
the first time I see her she follows me
on Facebook we follow each other on all
the social media so it's cool to finally
shake her hand and give her a hug shot a
- Adams wife I bumped into Lindsay there
I ran into the dam in granny
I saw Bobo blaster Co there saw Brett
for a brief moment I saw the grimy
Gatsby the great event you guys if
you're ever able to go to a secret
session didn't recall rod Oh make sure
you get on the list make sure you go do
it come take some dad's with Lindsay
myself the Devon granny it's a good ass
time shout out to max for that big ass
daddy gave me those delicious expert
every time that we see him every time I
see him is so take this dad here's some
bacon here's something he makes
medicated bacon
you see people grubbing it and they look
satisfied bro I mean I can't speak I
think his is in the crust it's like a
cinnamon
I mean I could be wrong on that really
so don't call me I've never eaten it
because I'm a vegetarian I would assume
you have to like cuz I mean cooking it
in the oil wouldn't do enough because
you were ready to tell the dosage it's
real crispy and it's coated in something
because I he handed me someone gave it
to me but I just gave it to Bobo blaster
Co because I don't need bacon when I
told him that I'm a vegetarian
he kind of looked at me and he felt bad
that he had been offering me bacon he
felt like legitimately guilty like [ __ ]
I'm sorry man I got this no and he gave
me a big-ass dad like a really like a
manly sized dad when I told him I took
it all in one chunk I'm good on that
little one but thank you thank you what
did we just smoke that was Space cream
okay that I had a good flavor a good
smooth burn nice white ashes I like that
packaging can you tell me about that
company in that packaging to our friends
at altitude showed up with two packages
of pre-rolled joints the weed was good
[Music]
one of their managers is a very good
friend of mine and I trust that place
because of her so cuz I know she
wouldn't represent a place that wasn't
uh wasn't worth representing she's got
too big of a heart so shout it's
altitude that's really cool it's great
packaging this new packages of
pre-rolled joints of quality joints oh
yeah Teva Indic on the top that's rad
cool great packaging good ID you guys
over at altitude I like that the first
place I saw that was a place called
pride in medicine in Denver but they
fell off on all the new rules came
different places doing something similar
and
I like the way that this project turned
out those are sleep I get a chance to
try just about every I'm a sucker for
name-brand and marijuana you know I've
tried to dog
but Willie forgot to give a shout out
the hammies the his model he actually
grows his weed in house you know this
[ __ ] likes Willie actually this is his
company grew it and I went to a blue sea
sky in Denver and they had a full room
set up at guitars albums were Eastside
all kinds of merch and then is that a
recreational or a medical place okay so
anybody that's coming from out of state
make sure you check out what's it called
again
Willie's reserved Lucy sky and you can
check out Willie's reserve there and
there's a dispensary where they got some
Willie Nelson memorabilia and
merchandise that's kind of cool okay
[Music]
concentrates and edibles - I haven't
tried those I just tried a couple of
pre-rolled joints I've just seen the
packaging the Patchen packaging looked
intense packaging is intense pull it out
and there's another pre-roll tube in
there
it's like a Russian doll trying to buy
cannabis now exactly that's all right
Lindsay what did you just bust out they
just threw some snacks here on the table
what do you got for us 20 milligrams I'm
gonna move these right out of my reach
I appreciate you I love you more than
turps but I have any medals since my
experience at the CP I know I'm it's
it's once I get on a streak I'm really
weirdin I like to stay on a streak I
don't I'm and I'm on a streak I got five
milligrams in the car yeah whenever I
pick a streak whatever I'm doing I'm
really stubborn so if I commit to
something then I just like to once I
made it like a week or two and I've
broken the desire or whatever then I'm
like it's easy let's just see how long I
can go on whatever I'm doing here
whether it's not eating meat which has
been 20-something years now or not
brushing my hair which has been almost
12 years or nice and close you got
almost you almost brush your beard I
just felt like trying so they come to
sample pack so I had the person that got
me those regular on the rocks tickets
that might be her favorite edible that
you brought there the tiramisu one there
I had a bunch of people asked before and
that's the one I plan on trying but you
know how I act for lemon G dad's she
gets for those terrorists they're
animals the packaging is impressive as
[ __ ] they're totally compliant with the
new rules - which I like is a lot of
stuff but I'm even that I'm getting
samples of right now is a packaging yeah
I think they knew that that was coming
just they just planned really get yeah
and I I mean I haven't tried one yet but
so far packaging and presentations at
home run remember back in the day when
we had a dispensary and the packaging
was basically one of these Ziploc bags
with the product we would get the
owner's owner one of the owners were
walking in with a laundry or not you
know like the sweater storage bin the
big plastic bin for like under the bed
was one of those Tupperware things he
made a lot of people make an easy cloner
out of it would be full of like slices
of banana bread individually wrapped in
ziplock bags with just a piece of scotch
tape taping the flap down so it fit Todd
and that was what went onto our shelves
like yeah it was exactly that and you
know they stayed when we closed at the
end of the night advanced where we are
now because it's a good thing that the
health department is overseeing edible
production but I do I never pictured
something like the product I'm holding
in my hand I mean even three years ago
let alone five or seven that's like
something that you would get from a
really fine hot chocolate company
through the mail or something like
[Music]
that's probably just somebody making it
up but I've paid a lot of money to give
these two girlfriends throughout my life
just not medicated I've paid the same
amount for these that I paid for
unmedicated chocolates more than one
holiday let's go let's give a quick
shout out they didn't pay for any
advertising but they seem to be the talk
of the show for a couple of seconds here
Kota signature truffles the signature
truffles they're packaged very nicely
they come in a black box it looks like a
[Music]
it makes a circle I had heard about
these long before I actually got any
milligrams is each piece use it with
some acid some THC how much does that
package cost if you're not an employee
at the dispensary
[Music]
it's about 23 okay if you're a dude you
were in trouble and your girlfriend's a
pie and you brought those home to your
girlfriend okay thank you
[Music]
delicious dudu that they call their
significant others mother I mean like in
30s and 40s to tattle and like get them
in trouble just say yeah my mama just
laugh and hang up bunny see you guys we
did come together for an actual podcast
we're not gonna talk about dads and
chocolates and all that pretty much Mike
called me similarly today for Mike and I
it might have been early for most do you
folks is probably well into your day to
myself I bet this conversation happened
at one still had an am attached to it
[Music]
and he's like hey ah this is what's up
this reporter is looking for somebody to
talk to because there's this news story
going on and he's like would you like to
speak and I was like new and about two
seconds later my phone blew up with a
whole bunch of other people asking me
would you like to speak for us would you
like to speak for us cuz I'm well-spoken
I guess I'm well-known amongst the
cannabis community and they felt that
I'd be a good representative so Sean
it's all the people that message me and
wanted me to contact this reporter for
you that's cool
I passed the baton over to our buddy
Mike because I don't want to be on the
news talking about that I grow cannabis
I just don't want to do that so I let
Mike do it and Mike's well-spoken and
eloquent and well there's a reason
caregivers don't do interviews yeah it's
really good Markowitz effect
I just want to name it on the show the
Berkowitz effect the one and only
caregiver in Colorado to really do an
interview
paid for it severely yeah is still
paying for didn't in many very real ways
and it's been a lot of years in in
pueblos that means that we had no
caregiver advocates down here as sort of
for lack of a better candidate that
became me a long time ago thank you
you're welcome it's a fight that I care
about caregivers have been part of
Colorado for more than a decade we've
never been part of the problem and I say
we in a very general term because I am
NOT a caregiver but right now in
Colorado from a number of different
angles people they're going after the
doctors right now and looking at plant
counts there every County is restricting
the number of plants you can grow in a
home garden for directly
it's a rough time I predicted a couple
of years back that caregiving wouldn't
be a thing by 2020 we saw this happen in
Springs less than a year ago and now
that's basically the same rules are
trying to implement Springs are trying
to be here it's it's even more than that
they've already done it here and what
their what the what's going on right now
is our Board of County Commissioners is
talking about putting a question on the
vote this November on the ballot that
says should we go to the state and
continue to lobby for a statewide cap of
18 plants per house even even if you
have a medical recommendation from your
doctor to grow an increased plant count
of say sixty plants the didn't [ __ ] your
medical card [ __ ] your needs [ __ ] your
condition the new rules that they're
talking about wouldn't affect the card
that you get written it would just
affect your ability to grow on that card
okay you'd be limited to that number of
plants unless you had a specific type of
property which I haven't just seem to
find anywhere it's just not in a house
or
residents and because of what caregivers
are and what the other rules around
caregiving are in Colorado that means
you can't be a caregiver and have more
than 18 planets period because of your
caregiver you can't have a storefront or
a building or anything like that you
have to do that Bureau so essentially
these new rules statewide means no more
caregivers and your extended plant count
card could still exist and you just be
excited assigning that extended plant
count to your dispensary which feels
like is what they're trying to do with
most of the patients are trying to take
away the caregiver and send it all to a
dispensary so they can make some tax
money off of it and not worry about
what's actually needing to be taken care
of that's been the goal statewide for a
long time
caregivers have been the scapegoat for
all continued black market activity in
Colorado for the last eight years
anytime a home girl gets busted they're
like oh my god these medical rules are
so confusing and I go back and reread
the article in the paper and it's there
was no paperwork it wasn't a caregiver
that was breaking the rules or
manipulating the rules or hiding under
the rules it was just a black market
grower that's been here for forever
doing what they've always done the only
thing that's different is that
caregivers also exist in the same state
but caregivers are the public face of
home growing and so they take all that
heat at the same time the state has got
the taste of recreational taxes and
they've gotten a real look at the sales
totals by volume in the Med markets
still eating up half of what Colorado
period is selling and they would love to
tax that at the higher rate so medicals
kinda under attack under all fronts
right now which is why telling people to
register to vote for eight months
something then you can clear up for a
lot of Colorado folks people in Colorado
have this thing that they think this
since as an adult they're allowed to
grow six plants if they get their basic
six plow plant medical marijuana card
are you allowed to grow your 6 + or 6 or
are you just limited at the original six
it depends on where you're living that
is confusing a [ __ ] it really really
really really ok so here in Pueblo it
matters city to County the city doesn't
care what your plant count is I work
incredibly hard for a very long time to
make sure that the city of Pueblo did
not implement a plant count limit just
we found sympathetic ears inside city
government and myself and a caregiver
here in town who isn't willing to go on
the news but is willing to work with
city government people managed to get
them to hear reason and not do a plant
can't live it so they just where footage
limit and require air filtration we
couldn't get them to hear reason on a
number of other rules implemented that I
don't support nearly as much but in the
county they've already passed an 18
plant count limit which means if you
live in Pueblo County versus City you're
limited 18 plants period if you live in
a residential area there are some
exceptions to that and you'll have to
look up your specific zoning your
residence and then what the specific
rules are for that zoning designation
but before I could give you a hard
answer on that me that Pablo was an 18
count
County and I was like what are you
talking about I was like no it's not
Lina's like yeah it is
I I remember that fight and there was
not much public support against it
carriers for really busy people the
state put the squeeze on them several
years ago with a couple of statewide
limitations that mean in practice
caregivers don't have a lot of free time
to lobby City Council's and when they do
they tend to get treated pretty badly
because they're there for one specific
issue they don't have six months to
learn how to play the insane game you're
required to play to do things like that
it's often unfortunate that the system
works that way but that's how it works
and so caregivers have had a rough go of
it in Colorado and it looks like one
maybe two more elections and they're
gonna be something that's in our history
books
we need caregivers so if you can really
do if you're a part of the vote make
sure that you wait for this to come up
on the ballot and you do not allow them
to limit our plank count to 18 plants
just as an example if you've got a four
by four train you've got one light it is
very feasible it makes a lot of sense to
run 64 plants in that 4x4 train that
sounds like a lot of plants right but
here's how you do it
you cut 64 clones as soon as they start
popping fat roots you put them in the
4x4 tray you put a little capillary mat
down for those roots to grow into you do
it's like a an ebb and flow system you
fill that tray then you drain that tray
every hour fill it drain it fill it
drain it
you got 64 little plants and there you
flower them they're about six inches
tall they finish off about twelve inches
tall and you pull about six or seven
grams for a plant that's a pound of weed
but you got sixty-four plants you do the
same thing with one plant or four plants
under seven gallon pot just depending on
how long you want to veg it it takes a
lot longer it's way easier to pull that
pound of cannabis for Mike's medicine
with 64 tiny tiny plants than it is with
a whole bunch of big pots and bigger
plants that you have to veg for a longer
time so it makes a lot of sense it's not
like sixty-four plants is not like
cartel numbers kicking out although
that's way that's one pound just one
example
I mean people when they see something
like ninety nine plants is the state
limit they picture
plants they've seen in the newspaper
that are the size of a Volkswagen bus
[Music]
the end they just don't realize that
immediately the numbers cut in half
because only half of those planets can
be flowering right when you're talking
about a caregiver with that's growing
ninety nine plants it's often because
their caregivers four or five patients
often five patients and then themselves
and each patient requires two or three
strands each strain requires one or two
moms when you start dividing out over
life cycles in two different rooms all
of a sudden you're you're just
struggling to stay under 99 and you're
barely producing enough marijuana for
just your patients and if you want to
run a seed pack to find something new
then you're really already over numbers
so you can pop those ten and get them
planned it gets very complicated and
when you're number six it's it's almost
impossible you you're basically left
with plant a seed pray it's female maybe
keep one and rotate five I mean it gets
very complicated quickly and it's not
productive and it doesn't do anything to
combat the things that people that are
writing these rules are hoping it will
it's not gonna do anything to the
illegal growers it's not gonna do
anything to the smell of marijuana in
neighborhoods bullshitty gross with no
carbon filters it's just gonna make life
a lot harder for patients who rely on
caregivers for medicine at a price they
can afford
it's gonna force them to go to a
dispensary it's gonna force them to
maybe find a ride they don't have a ride
maybe they don't have time maybe they
don't have money because I know that
what if you've got a caregiver what you
are reimbursing your caregiver compared
to what you are paying at the dispensary
is a huge huge drastic difference the
difference is massive almost 50% yeah
the I mean just the cost to the the
patient is 50% at least so here's
something that we should think about
Mike I've been your caregiver for how
long now since probably 2010
give or take so six or seven years I
know your cannabis needs very well I
like to think I've watched you evolve
into a little dabber lately I need to
see it I can name straight I know which
strains you like I know if I walked into
my garden I'd be like I gotta throw a
couple of these into the room for Mike
because he's gonna need this in about 60
days I gotta get this ready for him
Lindsay's a budtender she's a very good
she knows you but how much do you know
about Mike's but that's exactly what I
needed to do for me in the evenings but
we're wandering caregivers are important
my point is that I know what Mike needs
I've got flowers pretty much prepared
when Mike needs them I know like Oh
should I better put that into flour soon
cuz my got this from me a little bit ago
you got this that means pretty soon as
jars gonna be empty is gonna be like
where's my grateful dog bro and I'm
gonna need to have something that ready
for him and no offense to you you're not
supposed to know that but you don't know
that [ __ ] you're the you're gonna be the
one providing his cannabis if they
eliminate me from the chain and you're
gonna have to learn all of these people
that do not have a caregiver anymore
you're gonna have to try to learn their
medicine you have to try to have that
product on the shelf can they grow it
green and healthy wellness supply those
flowers that Mike needs the juicy needs
that I need that you need if people in
that room need people in that house over
there need can we [ __ ] supply those
specific flowers like a caregiver can
know is they don't have that many mother
plants and they don't have the time the
part of the equation that really worries
me isn't really the part that affects me
directly um a lot of the people that use
the caregiver system in Colorado are
consuming
if amounts of THC concentrated oil and
CBD concentrated oil and in the medical
or the rec market this is gonna cost
them hundreds of dollars a day per dose
when you price it out recreational
several hundred dollars a day per dose
two doses a day so you're looking at
twelve thirteen hundred per day in
medication and in the caregiver market
with the plant counts that are under
attack right now they're getting that
same dose at the same quality if not
better depending on the production and
it a far cheaper price pennies on the
dollar because of how its produced and
where it's produced they didn't need the
million dollar machine the two million
dollar building the hundred thousand
dollars in permits and so they don't
have to pass that on to the epilepsy
patients into the cancer patients that
are taking a thousand milligrams of CBD
twice a day or a thousand milligrams of
THC twice a day
I had a caregiver give me a bottle that
was I think six hundred and forty eight
milligrams of pure THC what would that
cost me at a recreational 648 rec you're
looking at around sixty to ninety eight
gram for good for good like co2 oil if
it was pure CBD teacher oil and THC I
mean you're still looking at maybe 300
bucks okay I exchanged a ten pack of
seeds for that teacher because it was a
caregiver to caregiver transaction for a
child
I mean recreationally that would have
cost a fortune
yeah you prefer 160 milligrams you
in it I mean like 60 would have given it
to me if I didn't even offer him the
seed pack in exchange right I was like
you get something you know like there
was stuff here so you get stuff for my
stuff it's how it works I mean the
caregiver system is where the people
that really really need the in high
quality high dose medicines that's where
they get their their product if I have
to I can deal with the recreational
market I've got a job I've got access to
enough cannabis product selection to
keep myself on my feet and healthy
enough to work but there are a lot of
people who can't say that in Colorado
that rely on caregivers and that's why I
don't mind standing up and doing even
though I'm not I definitely appreciate
[Music]
the porn shop for some people they just
can't be seen doing that the porn shop
or the dispensary there's definitely a
stigma attached for a lot of people I
still run into irregularly I run into
customers who are from other states who
are like I can't use the ATM in this
building yeah because my bank might know
that this address is where a pot store
also is
or that paranoia yeah I mean like a
handful a day I'm it's not rare because
large parts of the rest of the country
doing what we're doing while we're
talking about it this table will late
your ass in jail for an incredibly long
period of time
um these delicious chocolates we were
just eating are like a serious felony in
some parts of the US because a little
more okay I told the cop so I'll use
those for [ __ ] stains I'm on work I said
in court too by the way
it's really embarrassing forty forty
five days of my life was taken away
rolling rolling papers man I remember
those days though when when I was in
band in like seventh grade they told us
to buy rolling papers for something I
don't even remember what about the
instruments but the paper specifically
was good for something with the rack you
read it yeah but I remember the speech
in class they're like alright what
you're buying now is currently
contraband if law enforcement contacts
you about these you can explain that
it's for your instrument and hopefully
you don't get a ticket for having what
we're telling you to have and that was
like 20 years ago and there's still
places in the country that I like that
[Music]
too years ago I was in that hail man I
mean
and I went back about a year ago I don't
have a paranoid feeling a little bit in
the corner you like [ __ ] I'm going to
jail don't jam going to jail
so what brought you to Colorado from
North Carolina I'm glad you came on the
podcast
I'm glad you reached out to me you said
you work as a courier for a company okay
[Music]
the ones so you just drop these straight
into your drink and it dissolves and
then you drink it that's the brand new
price we don't have the the brand newest
scent on our shelves yeah just the
strattice pills ah I was pretty damn
cool they're uh brand new product on the
market last what six months everywhere
across the six months ago
I really liked them personally they're
they're a great low-dose medication
option their their CBD products are
really convenient and they're available
recreationally milligrams and three
different kinds the relax is like a it's
a hybrid the energies the sativa and
then we have also one asleep the sleep I
get more feedback is it just had a real
heavily activated THC a yeah okay that
makes sense that makes no sense and
[Music]
we decided that was not safe around
[Applause]
[Music]
there's not mild flavor yes nice a lot
of drinks have a heavy flavor so an
option that I can a medicate whatever
beverage I want without adding tincture
which is always a little weird I do like
this sodas but you can taste that
medicine you know the flowers just need
THC in there I was like damn Jeff's
gonna call me out on this but like man
Brett really had it right in the last
one when he did like the stretches in
the middle he kills it on Facebook
Brennan or on Instagram post the
greatest [ __ ] on Instagram Sheva Seva
labs at Mary's you know he has a fake so
make sure you follow the right one
Mary's motivation yeah show to the
correct Mary's motivation he's only got
two post-its the fake one don't follow
him so you're a courier and you get to
go to probably almost half of the
dispensaries in the state what's that
like we had an episode variety medical
and recreation
part of that makes me real jealous it's
a gorgeous state and I would love to
spend part of my day everyday driving
around it but after a while keep in mind
it's September now social media feeds
the photos are amazing you're a podcast
listener so you probably listen to we
talked about the craziest [ __ ] that
people have seen in a dispensary going
to all these dispensaries I'm sure
you've seen something crazy something
that stands out something that you'd
want to share with a bunch of people
that listen on a podcast anything you've
seen either at a dispensary or at like a
smoke lounge or a smoke event but for
craziness you've seen at an industry
event or facility he's he's got these
sativas from altitude organic medicine
premium Kanak owns five high-grade cons
may be health risks associated with this
product [ __ ] you'll feel really good
it'll kill your cancer and you'll have a
smile on your face super bud nice that's
a great stream I know a dude that drew
that for several years
yeah I'm looking at looking I'm at the
end of the table guys and I'm looking
down the table and I see at least eight
mainstream cannabis companies I mean
different companies products vastly
different types of products yeah and
just this afternoon I was reading an
article that was saying Colorado doesn't
have real legalization it hurts there
there are people that are gonna vote
against legalization this November
because they're worried they won't make
enough money when their state ends up
exactly like Colorado isn't
it's insane I can't believe you to vote
to risk going to jail and keeping it the
way it is because of something silly
like that I was a black market grower
for far too long and it's much more
comfortable having shifted to having
this badge around my neck all the time
and knowing that what I'm doing is not
something I'm on a camera you could
watch me all day this is what I'm doing
I was so much easier that way but the
Olympics is running so fast
so you know sorry altitude we didn't
mean to just completely bash your
pre-roll at a concert you're like I'm
gonna fire up this joint
I gotta light the other side and then
that part falls apart like this one just
[Music]
actually couldn't smoked any weed the
front row on the rocks breaking on the
rocks I asked a couple of people I was
like how's the check and like oh they
just gonna patch it and they let you
through [ __ ] they almost got the
gloves out everybody at reggae on the
rocks but they were cool about it
because they pull your pipe out or pull
whatever you whatever they found they
didn't find my [ __ ] and they be like
alright check it out I'll give you the
option to take this to your car you're
not bringing this in but when you come
back if I find this on you again we have
to call the cops like we're turning you
in to the police and like in the camera
right there and the camera right there
just saw you can do it again that's cool
you get the past at least as long as
your show the one little choose like the
pass it's just for the record one
security guard lady was a prison guard
by day or a prison guard by night and
[ __ ] around a concert yeah she's like
arms up take your sweater off your ways
to put you take your hat off first I'm
gonna touch you here then I'm gonna
touch you here then I'm gonna touch you
here now I want to check by your dick is
that okay right before that they'd
really started looking at security and
making some improvements inside it's a
completely my first Red Rock show I
think was fish in ninety five six nine
ninety five saw fish there and it was
basically a hard to judge of any of
security from the night fish play my
client
it was it was a giant dirt field it was
a giant dirt and cactus and [ __ ]
brush fire waiting to happen type of
field and if we're a hippie wearing
sandals
it was just I remember it wasn't just a
concert it was an adventure up hill I
[Music]
kind of challenged myself a little bit I
was like I'm gonna do this [ __ ] let's go
and I did well I I can control my
breathing quite well and I've got
[ __ ] these climber legs because I'm
so tall I got a lot of leverage so I
just go up that hill all day [ __ ]
long a little bit before I get to my
seat a lot shorts a t-shirt a
long-sleeve shirt a rain poncho a bottle
of water for fish I 95 but I ate so much
acid that I didn't know where I was
anymore so it didn't matter Red Rocks
looks like it looks like a state park it
looks it's really cleaned it's cement
it's all cemented everywhere a lot of
the parking is now submit it's not used
to be a 95 it's completely different in
96 I snuck over the back of the stage
and watch the Allman Brothers Band from
the rocks behind the stage for free this
year I saw somebody up there and I'm 99%
sure security [ __ ] climbed up there
and arrested those [ __ ] and
they got like if $10,000 ticket so you
can't do that [ __ ] anymore Red Rocks has
changed they almost got the glove and I
was waiting oh yeah Red Rocks how do we
get there that's crazy
it's been a long stretch I like it when
you ramble
[Music]
the concerts there but I've been to
plenty of the boys I'm actually got
tickets to see Jeff Tate and Emma Arnold
at the dab lounge this Thursday so by
the time this podcast airs I think I
will have seen that show it was [ __ ]
great you guys you should have been
there it was awesome [ __ ] that's
tomorrow that's why we're recording
tonight it's tomorrow night I think the
shows at 7:10 you can get your tickets
on a friend of Mines Facebook page I'll
link you up with the merchants go to the
dabble on just Facebook page and there's
a link I think it's in like five bucks
dude yeah I think it's like seven bucks
at the door so you're not gonna spend
too much money Jeff and his friend Emma
Arnold and they are doing a show called
good cop bad cop I didn't mean to do
that it's never done that before
[Music]
this actually okay so okay this is gonna
it has a well I'll probably give it away
right here but there's a laundromat
two weeks ago she was you know happy
birthday was her birthday and we went to
this place and this guy comes out of
there I don't know and just blew my mind
there was nobody in the product I've met
people do that before that either just
not directly on a backward or are used
as chewing tobacco people that I grew up
in tobacco farm land that's where I'm
from Pretoria so you know that was kind
of normal
you know I mean he I'm sure he grew he
raised to back my mama sit there tell me
how she used to pick it was just five
years old that's so bad yeah I'm sure
he's probably just through a whole bleep
in his mouth yeah it's pretty rugged I
get really lit up when I smoke blunts
something about that tobacco leaf just
really makes me spin around and get sore
yeah
I barely been smoking joints I mostly
just abs is my world lately there's
people in the house that are not on the
podcast and when they were offered some
of the shadows they just took off if you
want that it's over you can reach it all
your pressure these one the Cannabis Cup
this year if you guys want any of these
I've got all the flavors dive in stop it
work for something and I've had people
ask me for or asked me if we carry them
and so I just grabbed both both kinds
that we carried and brought them for fun
dive in did you try that monkey right uh
not yet but it's not the do list they
don't pay me to say this at all but that
monkey bar from Incredibles is one of my
very favorite edibles that's ever been
made how much did you eat so yeah this
is this is this is why I hit this twice
within a 12 hour period I consumed over
2,500 milligrams of edibles
[Music]
that was when I was going in but any
more than that and I'm like because I
can sit there and pop six of them and
have that is like I'm really toasted
dose and I actually - like - and enjoy
the edible most of my graph of edibles
is they're delicious but now they're the
size like some joint and you take one
tiny little brownie bite in like I'm a
big guy when I take a tiny bite of a
brownie most of the rest of my
body that's not chewing in that moment
starts looking for more that [ __ ]
browning and when all of the brownie has
weeded it back in get dangerous fast but
yeah that's why I like this is the lower
dose stuff because I can have a couple
pieces and enjoy because most of them
are insanely good now I've got a new
idea for an edible company what's sell
let's just copy our favorite edibles and
we'll sell those and then right
alongside those will sell the same thing
without any THC in it it's people have
been joking about it there's more than
one company that does a larger piece
they just don't do it in a multi pack
successfully they need to make like a
dozen of cookies right and they need to
have one packaged in the front of it and
that one is edible and I passed it on
and they looked completely offended I
was like sorry I'm on a thing and they
just that's cool but I mean what the
[ __ ] why'd you give it away and so they
giving it back oh I forgot sorry I'm not
doing those strokes anymore
I'll do it again
it's just I'm I'm just stubborn it's
funny it's more of a joke to me now that
I haven't done eating any edible since
that time it's secret Szechuan I ate
like 2,500 milligrams and then I tried
to go to work
always and I swear to God every time we
have the conversation like we're not
gonna eat edibles like the last two
times you followed through on that
obviously the last two times I have not
it was 9:30 at secret stash and Chris
bought me a cookie I was gonna bring
this out I'm like eating the cookies
open shop the next day and the guy was
like I'm eating it and he's like yeah
these cookies were like 300 milligrams
that's what I've been telling everybody
he's like but realistically they might
be like I was like I'm 3/4 is cooking
I'm like but like man I wish I would
have known that before I started eating
it I would have only eaten a quarter or
one of the things I like about the rec
market over the Med and there's not a
lot on that list but the dosing in the
lab testing them to perfection it's
coming to the medical scene variance
it'll be there
less than a year probably but I heard
November I was supposed to be July and
then they said November so we have to
built the labs yeah bring creating this
from the ground up which is like why
we're joking about like different models
for edible companies if we're really
watching it's fun I had the honor of
giving Lindsey and her better half mr.
Bobo Blaster Co a ride home from the
secret sesh
[Music]
that cookie killed me second of all all
right Jeff wanted to do a podcast on the
way home and I was totally down to do a
podcast and then we were all smoking and
I guess I had said I was gonna wait to
do a damn and I've said no I don't want
to Chris thought I said that I was gonna
wait so apparently we're all waiting for
me to take it down I fell asleep in the
back of the car and then I woke up and I
was like all right I'm gonna keep eating
so that I will stay awake and then Chris
started troll you both started trolling
me about how much I was eating in the
back of the cars like [ __ ] this I'm
going to sleep you just blank then
where's the torch and she's like it's on
the floor some people could just sleep
in the car I'm not that person that's
why I Drive everywhere shut up to dad
and granny for coming to the secret
session that was so fun damning with
dead she's got so much enthusiasm she's
you know I mean she's already there
she's got more Instagram followers than
all of us combined
[Music]
it's funny because I was listening to
the last podcast and she was like gets
it going alright just a little over an
hour you guys Jay just said something
that made me think about something do
you want more people to follow you on
Instagram you can tell everybody
listening right now how they can stock
you see it right in the top of the mic
[Music]
where can anybody stalk you if they want
to if they want to check you out while
they listen into your sexy voice yes use
the hashtag tweet that Adam guys chicken
fish I like it I like it
check your fish follow them on Twitter
you guys sit have some good stuff
hashtag it like it when he rambled this
is a fish with the band fish or just
happened to have a pH yeah oh you're a
fish fan oh why didn't we just start the
podcast like that was your favorite show
what year what era
I just stopped 99 ok that's a good
that's a good run yeah it's not a bunch
of 99 shows I mean that really and I
knew that but you know back in cleaner
back in the 90s I couldn't just go to a
Turin Sutton
grab the whole catalog or some band that
I've heard of you know yeah yeah busy
get some spoiled nowadays my friend won
tickets
my friend won tickets there's a fish
though the next day on the radio and I
heard it I actually heard it on the
radio so I went over
we still have pay phones back then so
they didn't play it by the way if you go
to see fish do not expect to hear your
favorite song again in Charleston
Virginia drove all the way up there not
Charleston Charlottesville where the
University of Virginia's okay so I'm in
there this is ten years later this time
shout out to you baby Santana oh but uh
bring her next time I will I will she
wanted to come this time but she had
something she had to do that's life
and that's way it is but anyway I told
her about you know soon as I went to the
one Edie winston-salem North Carolina
the first one soon as the lights went
out joint I was like [ __ ] cheap and I
said yeah give me the whole joint fire
up another nice you know I was I was 21
I was 19 something like that
[Music]
Susi's lines go out you've got to see
something she's like oh yeah I can dig
this and you know seeing all the people
dancing around I told her all about that
she tripped out I'd love to go see them
against they'll be here this weekend I'm
doing my best do my best people say yes
you're sold out yeah it's old the
[ __ ] deal if you got a lot of money
you're gonna have too much damn money
how much close to 200 bucks one night
per person and they're doing three
nights he just put his head down yeah
that's where the soccer field bro they
sell out that giant soccer field three
nights in a row that's my advice this
podcast to come out the Monday after so
listening this I'm probably hanging out
with Doug Benson I'm gonna see Doug
Benson Thursday I got the Jeff Tate
thing Friday Saturday Sunday as fish at
Dick's and then Monday Doug Benson at
Comedy Works for you yeah one time he
called me out on stage he looked at me
he's like you got me - hi raasta Jeff
[Music]
excuse my coughs also sizzla Kalonji
at servantes September 19th that's gonna
be a fun one if you're a Rasta if you're
into that Reagan rattles getting awesome
it's just continuous now I've never seen
sizzle I'm pretty excited I remember a
time here when you had a few good
concerts at the beginning of the summer
and a few good concerts at the end that
was it
there was no it wasn't the concerts were
yeah you know I've been to almost an
extra house in Telluride and your
coolest [ __ ] and you're tired of it my
buddy Juicy J will trade you he's got
two packs of pre-rolls girl from your
heart we'd love to take your offers they
used to be very much seasonal it's a
good thing people just give you a house
[Music]
there you go all right Lindsay it's time
for you to do your plugs tell all the
people that are still listening how they
can find
um so my Instagram and my periscope or
the traveling stoner
I almost so my Instagram my periscope
are the traveling stoner
my twitter is the travel stoner my
snapchat is traveling stoner without the
G well I actually started out in Jersey
and moved down to Florida I kind of just
like came out on the other hand I really
want to that it's we can handle this
it's a whole show okay it's just got
jotted down so it's gonna be a future
episode
sorry I was loving your 65 um I do want
to give a big shout-out though to like
in the past couple of weeks I've been on
the podcast a lot these past couple
months actually um thank you for that
and I have had a lot of people message
me about the podcast and say you know
great podcast you know listen to it this
morning loved it like the day it drops
like by 7:00 a.m. there's usually one
person that has messaged me and said
already listen to it it sounds great
so I just want to give a big shout out
to everybody that has been listening and
messaging me to say that the podcast has
been great
that's awesome Thank You Lin's for
supporting the show since you and Granny
and Brett have been on the show
frequently the lessons have gone up my
Instagram and Twitter followers have
gone up on all of the accounts the Rasta
Jeff thyri genetics and the G fyh
account so thanks for participating your
social media skills are [ __ ] awesome
so yeah you're killing it there thanks
to all those people that message Lindsey
and don't message me for some reason
participating with lens that's really
cool I get so many messages just keep
messaging her that's cool dude that one
mountain girl I
she's messages me and tells me how great
the episode is before I wake up every
morning it's like getting ready and it's
like the girl from the heart you can
hear in the bathroom in the bathtub or
she'll be taking a morning dabs or on a
morning hike or whatever it's on
snapchat
her name's that one mountain girl her
and smokes that's why I couldn't find
her today but shout out to you girl I
hope you're doing good in Washington yes
I love it
shout out thanks for supporting the show
yeah everybody if you're listening to
the show we've been going for an hour
and 18 minutes that means with the intro
I put on this we're probably about an
hour and 20 minutes ish I love all the
people that listen this place it's
amazing yeah listen I wanna thank Mike
for coming taking time away from his
dinner his wife and his baby thanks for
coming out thanks for joining us on the
podcast position for a spot cast ever
regular you got good stories you got a
good vibe you're gonna be here
[Music]
appreciate the last to go for all the
time huge shout out to Jo buzzy I don't
know if you listen to the podcast on a
regular basis but you've taken off
you've taken new ventures in life and I
wish you nothing but the best on your
new endeavors but I hope that works for
you you guys we're gonna wrap up this
portion of the show shot I think people
that are in the room that don't have
microphones I've just been hanging out
smoking blunts with us and taking dad's
I'm gonna wrap up this portion of the
show and of course I'll be right back to
put a tail on this fishy did I really
just say put a tail on this fish that
was [ __ ] weird you guys thanks for
listening to the podcast I truly
appreciate all of the support you guys
if you have a product you'd like to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast send me an email to grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
to hear from you want to thank everybody
for joining me big shout out to Mike big
shot up to Juicy J big shout out to
Lindsey thanks everybody that was in the
room smoking blunts and having a good
time with those people are taking beds
and smoking blunts off mic it's kind of
fun having extra people in the room kept
it a little chaotic kept things moving
I'm gonna quit it's been like an hour 20
minute podcast so catch me in about
seven days
is until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community is time
for episode number 152 of the girl from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank-you shoutout to my friends in
the mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat we're gonna talk a little bit
about reef edgy and reverting your
plants some people like to take their
plants all the way through the flowering
phase and then return them back to veg
and reuse those we saw Emma Arnold and
some other opening comedians my friend
Ben Verbeck was an opening comedian up
at the dab lounge they did their
good-cop bad-cop comedy show it was a
great time I got to hang out with Jeff
Tate and Emma Arnold and they treated me
like a rock star I've seen Jeff Tate
several times that was my first time
meeting em Arnold I've seen Jeff Tate
several times with Doug Benson so him
and I have become comfortable with each
other he has recently become a a pot
smoker he has made the switch from
alcohol to cannabis so excited about
that
I got to see Jeff Tate mrl do some
comedy ah Ben Verbeck open the show
another guy whose name has left my head
I knew his name until right now
that guy went on second and then an
Arnold went on and her set was great
then Jeff Tate went on he did a comedy
set and then toward the end of his
stand-up routine he said I'm going to
light this joint and start smoking and
at some point in this comedy show I'm
going to become too high just continue
doing stand-up and so he lit his joint
he kept doing his bit and then at some
point he obviously got too high
and he said thanks and walked off the
stage that was pretty cool to see it was
fun to watch that was a good experience
Friday I took the night off got some
rest hung out a little bit
Saturday and Sunday we went to Denver
and I saw my favorite band my favorite
band is fish I saw fish at the Dick's
Sporting Goods arena Stadium whatever it
is a gigantic big ass soccer field saw
fish there I was sold out all three
nights were sold out if he did not have
tickets it was a challenge giving
tickets I'm lucky I got into that one ah
man fish was awesome played some of my
favorite songs they played a really
amazing version of a song called maze
they played tube played some great great
music we had a great time really good
show a good time amazing evening safe
drive which was great because it was a
busy holiday weekend Monday morning we
head back up to Denver we get some food
up in Denver and then we got to see Doug
Benson at the comedy works one of my
favorite podcasts is the Doug loves
movies podcast and I got to see Doug
Benson joined once again by his friends
Jeff Tate and Emma Arnold and also a guy
named Trey Gallion join them for the
Doug loves movies taping and comedy
works and of course I got to hang out
for that one I was front-row ah big shot
it's my Buddy Baker forgetting me front
row all the time at comedy works I
appreciate that
it was a great taping you guys I suggest
that you listen to the Denver a show of
Doug loves movies it is out now by the
time this podcast comes out that will be
out make sure you check it out it's a
great podcast Doug loves movies if
you're listening to this podcast you
have access to Doug loves movies check
it out it's one of my favorite shows I
could see live taping
great time at the end of podcast taping
we're all hanging outside in the alley
smoking because Doug and his friends
long to come and just smoke out with
everybody I made friends with Trey galya
on almost instantly like instantly that
guy and I are homies now we'll be
friends for life I before I left all
four of the comedians were standing
there and I said hey you guys it means a
lot to me that you come and do comedy
because comedy is super important to me
so like thank you guys and they all like
sincerely felt my thing so that was kind
of cool to see all four of their faces
like holy [ __ ] we made this dudes day
that was pretty cool so that was my
weekend you guys I got a bunch of good
comedy a whole bunch of good music once
again shot it's my buddy Baker
shoutout to Ben Verbeck from the dab
loud shutters to the dab lounge in
Colorado Springs big huge shoutouts to
Emma Arnold Jeff Tate Trey Gallion Doug
Benson and everyone at Comedy Works also
shout out to fish and my fishing buddies
that was appreciate that so where are we
gonna go from here let's not a girl
update I've got to grow update everybody
on this been listening to the show knows
that I've been working on a breeding
project I've got one light with a very
small breeding project happening in
there the other day I went in there and
pulled out the male plant I collected a
little bit of pollen from him then I cut
the plant down and of course I hosed
myself down with a good shower because I
don't want to get that pollen everywhere
so now the male plant is out of the room
I had one arise male that plant has
dropped his pollen and he is now gone
there are five arise female types there
are number two number four nuts number
four number five number seven number
eight and then one that was labeled E he
was the remaining phenotype from another
Fino hunt that I liked a lot he has been
around for a minute he is the arise that
you see a lot of pictures of the other
ones are really good competitors that
have great traits so I've got those five
female phenotypes in there I have one
golden goat one grateful dog one lemon
skunk all of those are females in there
so there are eight females that have all
been pollinated by this one male
there are currently 40 days into flower
it's been about 25 days since
pollination I've still got probably 20
to 30 days before I can harvest these
plants and the seeds will be ready
currently the seeds are visible
you can see that the pollen worked these
plants took this took the pollen they're
seated now they're developing nicely um
I kind of like to see what's going on so
the other day I grabbed a bottom bud and
just pinched one of the seeds out of it
they're white still but they are
starting to develop an embryo inside the
shells are getting a little bit hard but
they are still white they taste weird
also if you're curious but they're not
quite ready yet so we got a little ways
to go so when they're ready my plan is
to let them go until those seeds are
really well done and then I'm going to
cut down each plant and label each plant
very carefully as to what it is and I
will hang each plant in its own area
with the bowl underneath it so but if a
seed does fall out I'll catch it
actually you guys I'm a drummer I'm
gonna use a drum head hope the drum head
upside down put it underneath each plant
so they differ seed falls out it lands
in the drum head it doesn't go anywhere
then once they dry I will take each
plant individually and crush it up into
probably a Tupperware dish I just like
I'll take off the fan leaves and I'll
crunch it up all the buds yeah just like
hand-ground like I'm gonna roll joints
then I'll just all the seeds will fall
out at that point I'll pull out all the
seeds I'll separate them I'll jar them
up I'll label them as to which phenotype
that is like a rise f2 like it'll be a
rise 5f to arise 7 F to whatever planet
comes from moisture it's labeled and
then I'm gonna grow a bunch of those and
some of my friends are gonna grow a
bunch of those and I'm gonna see which a
rise phenotypes I want to continue
breeding with and then we'll see if this
golden goat The Grateful dog and lemon
skunk will see if they do anything so
that's my goal I want to make some new
stuff I want to stabilize this and rise
a little bit my goal is actually in the
long run to take this a rise all the way
to f5 that's what I would like to do
that will take me a couple of years
probably two more years maybe three more
years to get there depending on how
selection goes depending on how stubborn
I am depending on what the f2 s and F
threes show me all right so that's my
breeding update you guys I appreciate
you guys sticking around for the
breeding updates with me if you have any
questions on my breeding project please
send me an email it's girl from me hard
at hotmail.com I would love to answer
your questions about my breeding project
alright so let's get into some listener
emails and this will segue me into the
reverting and revé edging topic that I
teased about at the top of the show
we've got a bunch of great messages this
one came on Instagram and this was
actually this guy had no idea that I was
gonna use this as podcast content this
was a personal convert a conversation
between him and I I don't know if he
wants me to say his name on the show so
we're just gonna call this the seeded
Erb question and email number one ah
this guy says quick question I pulled
off almost all the fan leaves on an
early flowering Strawberry Cough plant
from Sag 'martha seeds this was at five
to six weeks ago I guess the Strawberry
Cough plant threw bananas before I saw
that because I have seeds in all the
plants fully mature now and the only
plant that had bananas was the
Strawberry Cough so when he says he saw
bananas he means that he saw male
flowers developing on his female plants
which means that this female was
actually a hermaphrodite or or it was
stressed and it caused it to panic and
cause male flowers so that it could try
to keep itself alive by making more
seeds and then continuing its
generations so he continues with another
message he says will these banana pollen
seeds make mostly plants that have a
tendency to toss bananas easily or at
the end that's a really good question
see the thing is the main thing here we
don't know why that Strawberry Cough
plant threw those drop us through those
bananas we don't know why hermaphrodite
it out on you we don't know if it's a
herm we don't know if it's got herm
traits in it we don't know if it's one
of its parents was a herm we don't know
if that specific phenotype is a herm we
don't know why that plant threw bananas
it could have been stressed things that
would have caused it to throw bananas
would have been a light leak if that
plant some things I've seen white comes
in through your ducting you guys are
ducting those hooded lights
you've got ducting running you're
running it out the window or wherever
light comes reflecting into that and the
plant that is right underneath that
reflector
I've seen those hermaphrodite because
they are getting hit with light leaks
another thing that could cause that
plant - hermaphrodite could be heat
stress another thing could be over new
training it too much nitrogen toward the
end of flower could absolutely cause a
plan to become a hermaphrodite too dry
too moist any kind of weird interruption
on some strains can cause them to herm
so now the main question is did that
plant herm because it's a hermaphrodite
itself or was it an environmental factor
either way it's harming that's not
something's gonna hermaphrodite honey
that's not something I would keep in my
garden I would go ahead and get rid of
that one let's talk about the seeds that
come out of there and I also have
something else to mention you said that
every plant that is now mature has seeds
in it that makes me think that you could
have a white leek in there in all of
those plants all produce seeds because
of light stress and only that Strawberry
Cough showed the hermaphrodite flowers
just because that's a few no typical
thing the other ones may not have shown
either hermaphrodite flowers but they
could have seated on their own just from
being stressed even if you didn't see
flowers in there and maybe that
Strawberry Cough is the only ones you
actually noticed the flowers may be
produced in where you could see him
that's just a possibility also you're
right that all could have been seeded by
that rogue hermaphrodite Strawberry
Cough if that Strawberry Cough is are
hermaphrodite you may have created some
seeds that may grow some great
phenotypes but you may also run into a
bunch of hermaphrodites the same thing
could be true if you got your seeds from
stressing those plants from white stress
or from overfeeding or from under
feeding or for over watering whatever
caused that you may have produced some
amazing progeny you also may have
produced a bunch of hermaphrodites my
main piece of advice is don't share
those seeds with anybody until you've
ran a bunch of them yourself and when
you do give them out make sure people
know that they do have a tendency or at
least a likelihood to have some
hermaphrodite traits in there because we
don't want people wasting their time
growing hers when they can be growing
quality stuff and the guy that sent me
this message you have produced some
quality stuff so let's just stick to
that because my throat's burning out for
a second I obviously need a quick drink
I'll be right back
all right you guys I am back while I was
taking a drink and a couple of dabs
something dawned on me our listener and
his message said that his plant was an
early flowering Strawberry Cough plant
now that phrase early flowering
indicates a couple of things to me I
wonder if that plant flowered more
quickly than the other plants like did
it show flowers and like day 10 when the
other plants waited till day 14 or 15 or
did it flower on its own while it was in
under vege lights under 18 or 24 hours
of light I'm not sure what you mean by
early flowering but
says something to me a plant that wants
to OTO flower like that is probably a
hermaphrodite
the reason it's trying to flower early
is because a male plant wants to get up
above the female plants it grows a
little taller it wants to get up above
the female plants and it wants to start
dropping pollen so that it's already
speeding out pollen by the time those
females are ready the cannabis plants
whole goal in life is to reproduce so
that plant is probably her man a
hermaphrodite it wants to get taller
than everybody wants to flower first it
wants to have pollen falling before all
of those females are ready so that it's
ready for the party it's over there at
the party setup it's already got a beer
in hand it's just waiting for the chicks
to show up so I would not use that plant
for growing or breeding anymore the
seeds that you made are probably
produced from a hermaphrodite plant
you're going to see some hermaphroditic
tendencies in that progeny I wouldn't
give those out to anybody I would grow
those myself and pay very close
attention to what happens to those
plants all right dude thanks for the
message if you ever have any more
questions send them to me I will use
more of your stuff on the podcast
because you have some great questions
because you're in advanced grower and I
like where you're going keep up the good
work
shout out you're doing a good job I
won't see your name on the show you know
I'm talking to alright that brings us to
our next email this is a little bit of
an update a few episodes ago I was sent
an email about monster cropping and I
told the dude that I wasn't sure what he
meant about monster cropping because
when I googled it there were a ton of
different options so I asked him for
more information
his replied this is what he said he said
hey bro when I was asking about monster
cropping I was meaning when you take a
cut off a female plant that's about
three weeks in bloom and revenge her I
had a buddy telling me about this last
week he says that the clone goes crazy
making shoots and there's no need to top
her so I'm assuming you were rivetting
the clone that you're taking and you
were letting that plant flower and
finish out that sounds like a decent
idea if you're taking that clone from
near the bottom of the plant if you're
not taking it off of the top because you
don't want to disrupt the flowering tops
it kind of seems like it it's a good
idea it kind of also seems like it could
be a waste of time in the amount of time
you've got a plant that's three weeks in
the flower it's already starting to show
little buds it's already in flower the
hormones have converted it wants to make
buds now you need to take that
clone and get it in the cloner or how in
the dome however you do it it needs to
be under 24 hours of light and you have
to revert that plant all the way back to
a vegetative state then you have to veg
it to the size that you need it and then
you can flower it but it seems like it
takes a long time and honestly I
wouldn't even flower out that plant I
would take clones once it started
getting healthy and revé edging and
spitting out proper shoots I would take
clones of that and turn those clones
into a mother plant and then start over
so it kind of seems like a lot of work
for just a plant with some extra shoots
to tell you the truth you can pry in the
amount of time that your avenging to
develop those shoots to revenge it to
get it healthy I could probably just cut
another clone and make a happy plant by
topping and shaping and pruning and
making the plant the size and shape I
wanted it to be it seems like kind of a
waste of time in my opinion I'm not
gonna knock anybody's method because
they may have a purpose for this it may
be working for them that's great but I
bet you in the amount of time you're
spending reeve edging I could probably
just cut clones and do things the simple
way top it train it get it going so it's
a great message I'm glad you told me
what monster cropping is I've never
tried that if anybody else out there
tried monster cropping send me a message
send me some pictures let me know more
info about it let me know how it goes
for you it's easy girl friendly hard at
hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you so we've
been talking about revenge and I did
kind of bash it and say that it's sort
of a waste of time but there are times
when reeve edging is a very useful
application there are reasons to do it
maybe you forgot to take a clone I
always talk about when you grow from
seed make sure you take clones cuz you
may grow the best [ __ ] you've ever grown
and if you don't have a clone you're
gonna be angry so if you didn't take a
clone of that plant reeve edging is
always an option or maybe you're like me
maybe you did take a shits on a clones
and maybe you [ __ ] up and maybe all
your clones died so now you don't have
any clones of that strain that has
happened to me before and [ __ ] does
happen or maybe you're even more like me
and my friend Colin maybe you grow too
many seeds and you don't even have any
room left to take more clones so your
only option is to revert those plants so
there are reasons why so let's talk a
little bit about Reve edging Reve edging
is actually when you have flowered out a
cannabis plant and you want to return it
back to its vegetative state so you can
start fresh now like I said before
I would return that plant back to a veg
state and I would take clones from it
and then use those clones as my new
mother plants I wouldn't try to flower
that one back out it feels to me like
you would just kind of where that plant
out you can do it but it's gonna stress
that plant out it's probably going to
get weaker as it goes I can't guarantee
that but I wouldn't do it I would take I
would revenge it and then try to take a
clone this is like your second chance so
hopefully your clones live this time
hopefully you don't kill them all
hopefully you remember to take them so
you're gonna revenge your plant
something really helpful that will
really speed up your rivetting process
and this sounds crazy but this will work
when you begin to flush approximately
ten to fourteen days before harvest time
I fully recommend that you turn your
lights back on to eighteen six that's
right no more twelve twelve we went then
we want them on for 18 hours and off for
six hours a day for the last ten to
fourteen days of your flowering cycle so
while you're flushing change the timer
back to 18 6 isn't enough that two-week
period isn't enough time to revert those
plants back to veg since they're so far
along and flower and you may see some of
the buds start to try to revert just
harvest you're cool it's time just do
that it's harvest time anyway you're
cutting those plants down it's cool so
about 10 to 14 days before harvest time
put your timer back on to 18 6 that is
your veg schedule put it back on there
that'll get the plants sped up back into
the revenge phase let them finish cut
your plants down when you're harvesting
leave the bottom three buds on the
bottom branches of your plant so if
you've got a single stock plant if you
did not top if you've got a plant with
one stock coming up there's a little
intersection where it makes a peace sign
right you got the main stock going up
you got a branch coming off the left you
got a branch coming off the right up the
left branch and up the right branch
there will be little buds leave those
buds you want to leave the bottom three
buds on those bottom branches so from
the bottom of the plant up find the
bottom ones and then go one two three
leave those three buds and harvest
everything else on the bottom two
branches if you topped it you've got
four branches on those bottom four leave
the bottom three buds that's what you're
going to revert into a vegetative plant
and start
so once you've harvested the plant move
it to a room with 24 hours of light you
can either use a t5 you can use a metal
halide or you can use an LED the more
light you use the more quickly your
plant will return back to a vegetative
stage and you can start taking clones
from it and then use one of those clones
as a new mother plant veg that one out
and then take clones from that and those
clones can be your next crop I feel like
you've now solved the problem of a
flowering plant you fix the hormones
you've gotten it back to the way it
should be as a vegetative plant and you
were right back where you began one
thing I should mention is while you're
waiting for your plant to revert you
should feed it with kelp and vegetative
nutrients just use your basic veg newts
more nitrogen will help speed up the
process but don't overdo it now if you
want to speed up this process there is
one thing that you can do you can add
two hundred particles per million of ga3
that's gibberellic acid to your feed and
it will really speed up the reverting
process what this will do now earlier I
talked about taking that flowering plant
and reverting it back to veg and then
taking a clone from that and using that
clone as your new mother and then
cutting clones from that one if you use
the gibberellic acid I feel like you can
take that plant that was flowering and
you can revert it and then take clones
from it and those clones will be
completely fine to work with keep one of
those is your mother plant flower out
the rest of them and you were back on
track with vegetative plants and a
mother you did not lose your strain now
you can grow that strain forever and
keep it around make sure you take clones
from here on out
that's how you do revision guys I hope
you learned a lot from that I want to
give you a huge shot it's my friend
Colin from the ethos collective make
sure you support the ethos collective
they're a seed company in Colorado I
strongly endorsed that brand Colin knows
what he's talking about he knows what
he's doing big shout out much respect
because I wanna thank you for the emails
all of the listener content definitely
makes a better show I like aiming the
show at you it's easier when you send me
emails and let me know what you want me
to talk about so keep it coming you can
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I would also like it if you follow
me on social media follow me on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast find the show on
Facebook it's the girl from your heart
podcast and also if you're on Instagram
make sure you find my Instagram page
it's at IRA andersz core genetics
I run a seed company we make feminized a
regular ganja seeds I post all my
pictures under the seed company name
post a lot of great cannabis photography
make sure you check that out I would
love it if you would follow me I might
even follow you back alright guys now
that show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast find the review
section type in a comment let me know
what you think of the show and I will
read your comment on a future episode I
would love to hear what you think of the
podcast big shout out to everybody who
has left comments and given us readings
in the past I look forward to your
rating ladies and gentleman I think
that's all I have got for you for this
week I will see you in seven days the
next episode will feature Mike and we're
going to talk about CBD I hope you'll
join us for that conversation that's all
I've got for you so a big shout out to
my ninja spins thanks again for
listening and until next time take a
phat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 153 of the
growth from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation
new grower you're a professional grower
through a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff Mona thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band let me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Cash to the entire mystic
roots crew ladies and gentlemen this
episode i'm joined by white mike and we
talked a lot about CBD the episode was
kinda long so I'm not gonna waste a lot
of time I'm done with the music play and
when we get back Mike and I will be at
the dab table hang out with us
[Music]
I just now did so you seriously aren't
gonna cough that was all I just got a
pretty funny text message mayor the air
conditioner in the back just cause of
what I got I think we got there me too
I'm try not to call from the microphone
get everything set up here I think we're
ready to talk about this claiming that
this dude in France is has trained his
honey bees to make th laden honey by
collecting THC from cannabis plants now
I'm not a bee expert but I don't think
that's how this works
I I'm here to say that I don't think
that this is real I think it's [ __ ]
to tell you the truth I when I first
thought online I was like oh that's
really cool I want to wait bees collect
pollen yes trichomes collect pollen yeah
they are not themselves the pistils
collect the pollen to be more to be more
accurate but the pollen is actually used
as a defense against insects and they do
show pictures of bees on the canopy on
the female cannabis plants and what
somebody says in one of these debunking
websites cuz I did do research before I
came on long time
it out on a podcast and said that it was
[ __ ] I did do some research to back
myself up they claimed that they just
simply sprayed sugar water on the
budding female plants to encourage those
bees to land their yes maybe a little
bit of THC as a marketing ploy for
homies honey I think so yeah so in his
video they do show male plants yeah so
what I think may be happening little bit
this guy says he's getting THC honey
from cannabis plant he can be doing that
he maybe that's totally a thing it's
just not gonna be psychoactive right he
may be getting pollen from male cannabis
plants those bees are gathering that
pollen they're flying back to their hive
they're putting that pollen in little
thing that they put it in a little
honeycomb and then they actually bees
actually chew up the pollen in their
mouths and they regurgitate it and
something in their regurgitation creates
the the nectar to turn into honey see
this is why I don't like knowing how
everything's made yes nature's [ __ ]
gross yeah it's straight up bee puke
you're pretty tasty Jelly Belly has
created some new flavors and one of
their new flavors is vomit vomit
flavored jelly bellys that's not funny
so these these flies these bees are good
and they're collecting they could be
collecting the male pollen from these
male plants and flying back and creating
honey out of that that is very feasible
I do not see how they could land on a
female cannabis plant with trichomes on
it gather trichomes and fly enough
trichomes back to the hive to make
cannabis honey that doesn't seem
feasible to me well I don't see them
purposefully gathering the tribes are
there so any sort of tri-coat gatherings
gonna be incidental or accidental yeah
completely and I think that it's
probably ever been trimming and rub your
eye yeah don't do that it burns
we've spent like the first half hour at
any new trim gig warning the dude the
new people not to do that right and
somebody will do it it happens it's the
plant gives off pheromones sometimes
people have allergy
reactions to it and sometimes your face
gets itchy when you're tripping that's
just a thing and so you rub your eye and
it burns getting maced and it sucks you
can't make it quick because your fingers
are sticky cuz you're trimming so you
got to deal with it I think that the pH
was far too hot for these bees to be
able to handle it I think it would burn
the bees I think they would just be like
nah [ __ ] this I don't want anything to
do with it see I don't know if it would
be too acidic or to like burn them but I
think that that's definitely part of
what the trichome is designed to do it's
partially to keep those bugs away from
there so you can see this totally be
like this there may be serious benefits
to bees collecting male cannabis pollen
and turning that into honey but it's
definitely not like weed honey is as
advertised right it's a very cool
marketing ploy it is a very cool video
but I think it is inaccurate I think
it's misleading and I don't think you're
getting THC honey I want to see this
happen you know what I mean I want it to
be somebody said earlier they ain't
gonna do it on the honor system I want
to watch this honey and I want to watch
the bees honey to a lab and let's deep
hill test that honey for me and see what
type of cannabinoids are in there before
the show is for that to happen we would
have to bring this me to Colorado with
his bees and his cannabis plants because
that's the only place on the planet
where we could really collect and lab
test that in a controlled way without
him going to jail immediately after I
think you can do it in Spain man he's in
France so he's just a border jump boy I
think spins spannabis and there's a
hillside in Spain I forget the name of
the place I feel bad that I can't
remember the name of the region but
there's a small region in Spain where
they do not care about cannabis growing
there a lot of people go there yeah they
might have the ability to grow but do
they have the access to the same test
and kind of Slavs that we do that's a
very good question
because both in the same area are one of
the things that make Colorado's cannabis
market so awesome dude come to Colorado
bring your bees bring your bring your
gear will do we got a do we want to see
this happen we
test your biryani dude in a mildly
related note the dude in Oregon that's
doing the Hogs no yeah you know how here
the waste from the cannabis grow you
have to do specific stuff with it so it
doesn't end up right whatever ground up
into little tiny pieces run through a
wood chipper and then mixed with other
product right a shop up in Oregon found
a hog farmer to take care of a farm
perfect and so they take all that plant
material and I I'm not exactly sure what
he what the farmer does to it between
picking it up from the shop and dropping
it off with the pigs but I'm assuming
it's not much and they chow down on that
as a primary food source for most of
their lives
that's the Rocky Mountain worm company
in Colorado Springs has a deal worked
out with the very well-known vape pen
company open they grow their products in
their warehouse they chopped down their
plants and the waste from their plants
is then it's mixed properly so that it's
meb compliant and the media's approve
this transaction they send all of the
waste to the rocky mountain worm company
and the rocky mountain worm companies
feeding that back to their worms and the
worms compost that and then the rocky
mountain worm company in turn sells
their worm castings at a discount back
to open vapes gross it's brilliant it
goes full circle yeah so it's getting
reused and reef add back to the worms
it's kind of keeping it a little more
eco-friendly we need to learn as growers
as professional responsible growers it
is time to figure out how to reduce our
carbon footprint I don't know how to do
that very well well a lot of the places
the the laws around cannabis make that
specific topic incredibly brutal right
and Boulder I think they have to run
solar to offset all of their electricity
or something has to law in Boulder say a
hundred marijuana businesses had to be a
hundred percent energy neutral which
means they can't consume any power they
don't generate and immediately after
passing that law they realized how
unenforceable and I are not
unenforceable but unfeasible it was to
require that immediately and so they've
been given some time to upgrade but this
is one of the things that made pueblo so
popular is that we allow greenhouse
Denver is now a greenhouse Boulder just
not
greenhouse and we have the prime
greenhouse area here is perfect
greenhouse country beautiful country
here to grow cannabis or him yep we
designated a whole bunch of water just
kind of set it aside for you no that's
all well least marijuana grows at the
beginning of this we've barely touched
that number cool so there's a ton of
that still in reserve industry as it is
down here that's one of the hardest
things to do is to get the water rights
once you get something set up you can
get a water a lawyer there was something
nobody thought of until about a year and
a half two years ago when we finally
finished the rules and regs process
you can't just hammer out a well and go
to town down here in Southern Colorado
we've got a lot of rules when it comes
to water here yeah well they know they
know that big commercial growers are
coming and trying to use up the water
and they want to keep it for you and I
had a drink which was a good water plan
down here so all that's taken care of
the it's one of the more recent anti pod
talking points is how much water the
plant drinks or how much energy growing
it endure cost it's like well you know
if you didn't prohibit it in 46 of the
50 states more of it would be grown
under the Sun will be using
significantly less power to produce all
this if we could just grow it outdoors
like a normal crop but oh no when do we
vote on the city elections for 200 and
300 in the presidential November
November November 8 we will put out a
podcast I'm making a note yeah we'll do
an election podcast at some point people
this is not that episode we need to
guide people on what to vote on locally
specifically do a little segment on it
just for them what's the date today is
today the 9th today maybe the ninth okay
so yesterday was the last day for people
to submit ballot issue paperwork so the
final election ballots they're all
hammering out that paperwork now so
we'll have all the final information for
November here no we could do so it's
perfect perfect we'll do an episode to
teach you guys locally what to vote for
because the wording is confusing I do
agree with that there's gonna be it's
more way more than one question it's not
just via yes or no vote yes for we vote
no against weed it's gonna be much more
complicated than that yeah all right so
this episode I want to put this back on
some some educational topics some rails
Mike's not a headache he's really his
color came back he's more relaxed I can
see that the headache has kind of gone
away a little bit you feeling better bro
I'm feeling a lot better where's the
profit container because I got three of
them they look alike the product I'm
consuming right now is three percent THC
1.3 percent CBD thirty eight point nine
nine percent CBD a and six there thirty
six point three two percent THC a and an
additional six percent CPG so this has
got a a bizarrely wide range of
cannabinoids in it and what kind of hash
would you call that what kind of at
about sixty five degrees
it's a pretty nice shatter it shatters
real nice it's seventy it's really
sticky taffy okay you take two pieces
you pull it apart it just kind of
stretches I want you to get out of there
it can be a little tricky to get a DAB
out of there it it above like 65 so what
he's talking about is a smokeable
concentrate it's some hash some chatter
with a pretty good CBD to THC ratio it's
about 50/50
you could tell Mike was hurting about 20
minutes ago he had a pretty good
headache and heat all right let's record
a podcast so the CBD definitely reduced
of the pain in your headache and it
improved your attitude because of that
oh yeah I feel a hundred percent better
now that I've put something that's half
and half THC CBD into my system for the
day my knees feel better my neck the
tension in my neck feels better
I had a wicked headache when I got here
folks that was uh we're sitting at the
table kind of catching up and dabbing
and I'm basically just staring at the
table rubbing my eyes and my temples cuz
it hurts so bad I'm thinking I might not
podcast and I might just have to bail
after a day or two and go home some hurt
and the addition of some CBD into my
world has reset that completely I've
been a big fantasy me
for a long time it's good for tells you
I'll put it that way that's the truth
one thing that I and I've said on the
show I'm not a huge smoker of CBD I
don't use a lot of CBD product when I
smoke I prefer a nice THC head buzz I
want to get high I want to make my head
spin I want to get confused I want to
get goofy only a talkative that's what a
good sativa does to me when I smoke too
much CBD I honestly just get lazy and it
kind of ruins my hi-yah I'm not stoned
right now and that's I took four knobs
all THC dabs here a minute ago and I had
a nice little buzz going on but right
before the show I don't want my headache
to come back so I took two more half and
half THC CBD dabs and it it brought me
my high back down I liked it too if you
want to feel free to reach in I'm gonna
pull this piece off right here for
myself but here's some piece it's like
six of my dabs it looks like a flag that
Dad would be American flag probably
about 0.3 ish I I don't use a lot of CBD
products but one time listeners of this
podcast don't know over a year ago in
April of 2015 and I was having issues my
head hurt for three weeks
like honestly my head was throbbing I
was [ __ ] up I had a traumatic but I
have a traumatic brain injury I still
have post concussion syndrome I have a
lot of it's been over 18 months and I
still have effects from that concussion
I knocked myself clean the [ __ ] out I
was out for a good 30 to 45 seconds like
unconscious on the ground people had to
pick me up get me going again it [ __ ]
me up my head hurt for several days I
could not get right when I took a DAB oh
you were yourself for six weeks after
yeah no I was myself for six months
after it felt like
there was a substantial improvement
after about six weeks but I mean it took
half a year before you were feeling like
yourself all the way in so Spencer would
invite me over just to check on me come
hang out you've been like you could tell
I was getting depressed cuz when you get
your head and have a traumatic brain
injury you get depressed and chickies
you're not the same that you used to be
my skills weren't where they were and I
was bummed out so my friends really
hanging out trying to help me out at all
my friends it helped me through that
head injury but Spence would invite me
over and one night he's like bro I made
some CBD hash oil for the cannabis cup
and this should actually won the best
CBD concentrate at the High Times
Cannabis but he gave me a big smoke
normal shatter like THC or sativas my
head would throb even more it would just
feel like I can feel it and I felt like
I had I felt like I had a belt around my
head or like my hat was way too tight is
what it felt like all day every day for
a couple for like weeks and Spence gives
me these CBD dabs
and I breathed in with the dab and I
blew out that dab and it felt like you
just undid that belt about one notch you
didn't like fix it but it totally undid
that belt a notch and Maddy and Spence
looked at me and they go wow did that
help and I was like yeah how could you
tell I like you sat up your neck went
straight again and I was like what do
you mean like even like slouched and
weird and you've been like crooked let
me get another dad like that
and after like three or four of those
CBD dad's I was like I haven't felt this
good since before I hit my head like it
really did something to me it fixed and
so they gave me some of that stuff and
like dad this like damn it every day and
it's got me it really did help I found a
good half THC half CBD mix about oh
maybe two years ago and it was really
hard to come by back then um but I've
got a lot of inflammation in like my
knees and my neck where it's just for
one stupid medical reason or another the
bones grinding on each other and the
tissue gets we're both overs you're like
6 4 right you know I'm six five you
probably weigh good 230 I'm guessing I'm
not good at that
right about 200 pounds most of the time
these knees bro
God our knees get there's so much Lee oh
yeah and just cramped your neck I've
been in car accidents I grew up in
Colorado there's a lot of fun stuff here
that you can tumble down unreleased on
my feet was one of the really fun
[Music]
California but the results all this
trauma over the years of having fun in
Colorado is that there's a lot of
inflammation and a lot of swelling in
places the press-on nerves and then that
causes phantom nerve pain are basically
the same stuff amputees get with like
they lose a finger and then a finger
tingles or hurts those nerves create or
or make up or feel that they're getting
signals they're not really getting and
it can feel like it's tingling or
tickling or it can feel like it's on
fire or stuck in a car door or it'll go
numb and when I first stumbled on
medical marijuana that was one of the
things I like to do it helped me ignore
that sensation but it wasn't until I
found something that was a good ratio
with THC CBD that I really started to
attack that inflammation and bring it
down to a point where it doesn't hurt
anymore like it's hard to explain to
somebody when you're at work and they're
like why are you rubbing your hand and
it's like well because the the three
small fingers are numb and my thumb and
my index finger feel like they're stuck
in a car door and it was like that when
I woke up and I can't make it go away
but like which Jackie did you want to
try on it's just one of those things
that sucks that you just have to deal
with and so I found something with there
really helped that inflammation I was
just taking random pills that the doctor
gave me and going to the chiropractor
and the pills didn't do a [ __ ] thing
other than mess with my stomach in my
life
but the chiropractor was helping some
but when I found something that's have
to have CBD that inflammation really
started to come down and I started
having lower pain days I'm lower crazy
sensation days and then slowly but
surely I started getting pain free days
do those first couple pain-free days
were the do office look it was a
teenager
yeah like never happened guess your
endocannabinoid system back in line and
now that the rec industry has progressed
where it is there are several places in
town where I can go in and pick up half
THC F CBD concentrates in like when I
get home from one end of a long day my
knees are swollen a little bit my feet
hurt my back hurts I've eaten enough
[ __ ] for the day and I'm in kind of
a foul mood 2 or 3 D for the win yes
medical marijuana has saved for sure I
don't know if I honestly I it's hard to
think stuff like this right now because
we've lost a lot of people this year but
I don't know if Doug could still be here
without medical marijuana you know
mentally spiritually and physically Doug
would not be the same person without
medical marijuana I mean III saw some of
the same stuff I was going through in
his world like I mean listeners if you
don't have a lot of pet like physical
pain in your life or if you've never
really been injured for a while it's
kind of hard to understand what people
who do have nerve damage and pain like
that go through and it's the best way I
can describe it is it's like a sound and
it gets louder and louder and louder and
it gets louder the world around you gets
smaller and that sound presses in on the
world and there are some days where
there's nothing but
sound like it's just pain it doesn't
matter that if you don't pick up the
phone you're not gonna have a job later
it doesn't matter that you've got to go
to the bathroom it doesn't matter that
you had something really important to do
that day that you have to get up and go
do now for or it's you know you're gonna
lose it forever it doesn't matter all
there is is the pain and you'll do
anything to get away from it or make it
stop for a while you'll give people
ridiculous homes of money because they
claim to have a treatment that works and
for the most part nothing helps like I
was wearing a thing that electrocuted me
slowly like a tens unit and it works
okay for some issues but for mine it was
literally just an electrical shock that
scrambled the pain and pulse on the way
to my brain damn like that was the best
that Western science had for me and then
one day I hit some high CBD hash and
about half an hour later I was like wait
a second nothing hurts and I kind of
drum my both my hands on the table when
I was like and I could feel all my
fingers and none of them hurt like what
is that where did that come from where'd
that guy with that vial of station yeah
it is absolutely wonderful and a lot of
people are starting to figure it out so
much so that there's a lot of scam and
fake [ __ ] around yeah unfortunately that
Chinese imported CBD [ __ ] it's not
you're not buying stuff with the lab
tests on it from a very accredited
retailer you don't know what you're
getting I'm sorry to inform you oh yeah
unfortunately it's there's a lot of
research going on in to CBD right now
hopefully in the next ten years we know
a lot more about its medical
applications but I can vouch for its
ability to calm a headache and lower
inflammation and swelling in your nerves
or around your nerves in your joints so
that those pain signals aren't just
ability produces vomiting and nausea
smoke some CBD it'll take that away it
suppresses seizures that's something
we've talked about on the podcast before
it'll make you not have convulsions and
seizures hopefully
that's like the most Potter's everyone
but it's there's several different forms
of epileps
that THC work on and that CBD work on
and then that the two together work on
stop doesn't stop it will slow down your
PTSD and your nightmares and your
thoughts if you have PTSD amazing hopes
with anxiety that's an anti-inflammatory
we talked about that it's an anti an
antioxidant it helps with degenerative
disorders which is pretty cool it's act
as a protective enhancing tumor it'll
it'll it will not destroy your tumors I
think you need THC to destroy the two
layers slow a tumor for sure there's a
lot of very very very recent cancer
research on THC and CBD and CBD slows
tumor growth majorly is what they're
seeing in mice trials which is huge if
if we can slow tumor growth that gives
us a better chance to fight it yes the
good news to that court or that equation
is that THC has been shown to kill it
which is kinda the you know the the
first real medical research into Rick
Simpson oil style products that would be
it concentrates of both that's why those
are so effective I'm a little bit baked
from that last 90 dab I'm gonna take it
down here and below that as the medical
research that we're starting to get I
mean it really isn't it Symphony is
bitsy folks I'm not saying that if you
have cancer and you find some of this
you can't cure yourself real easy that's
not what what I'm saying here but um the
research is promising and honestly in
our lifetimes we might see legitimate
packaged perfectly dosed you've got this
kind of cancer we're gonna start you on
this much THC this much CBD style
Trion's
exactly in our lifetime which would be
oh that would make me so happy
did you smell that dad that I just took
a little bit oh that smells it tastes so
good I tasted a minute ago that's the
turf ex pineapple Jack yeah
chatter that was delicious yeah man
another thing I wanted to mention that
CBD does it's an antidepressant which
you know I think it it's got its own
antidepressant properties but also if a
dude's not hurting every day that's
gonna work as an antidepressant if
you're not having PTSD symptoms and
panic attacks you're gonna be less
depressed
I mean honestly most days when I wake up
and I'm not hurt and it feels like my
birthday
still cuz they're pretty rare most days
I wake up at least a little stiff a
little sore something somewhere I was a
teenage more than one doctor go if you
don't knock this [ __ ] off it's gonna
hurt yeah we were still free to like
before everything was nerfed
in the future it was the last generation
the relief got that but I remember more
than one doctor know it's gonna hurt
when you're thirty they were all right
it does but the days that are pain free
most of those I can accredit to last
night I was I was I knew whole lot of
THC concentrate instead of my normal mix
of predominately THC flour and shatter
and I wake up feeling a lot better
really restful sleep and really really
nice work on the inflammation while I
sleep one thing we should totally
mention to CBD buyers by itself will not
get you high no you can consume a lot of
CBD and you may get a little grin but I
don't think you're gonna get like any
psychedelic psychoactive effect it's not
a high the mood improvement is like you
were saying when the pain goes away your
mood goes up a thousand times like it I
mean if you don't know what I'm talking
about room think about getting a bee
sting when you get that dude stinger
pulled out or a splinter pulled out
or you've got a big painful zit finally
pops like in that relief of pressure
imagine that like through your whole arm
like if your whole arm felt like it was
on fire and then one moment it stops
like that just felt like your arm again
the sensation is incredible when we
finally get there you know how well it's
working another thing that we can talk
about is CBD will reduce the effects of
THC so if you're a little too high if
you've had too many dads if you're new
and you take a big giant dab of THC and
you're just spinning you're [ __ ] up
you take a little dab of CBD and it will
calm you down a little bit it'll balance
out your high there's some company that
made a product they work on earth rescue
pills CBD filled joke app that's pretty
cool yeah if your buddy took some
Doritos and he'd be just fine
a friend of mine makes for a relative
before he makes CBD capsules and I was
taking those I had a few and oh good
Lord that I feel wonderful
I'm just pain free and just in a really
really nice mood it was really nice
there are a couple of companies that are
making CBD dog treats which i think is
really cool because a lot of the
Shepherd breeds are known for their
dysplasia and hip problems there's a
shepherd dog that stayed at my house for
a little while now and he gets some CBD
treats occasionally and he seems to be a
happy little dog doesn't seem to cause
him any problems and it's gonna keep him
pain-free keep his little hips happy
I've got a Malamute that's pushing for
13 and a half now she's almost 14 breed
expected life expectancy is 8 and so her
knees hurt her ankles are basically
every joint is shot and you can see when
she doesn't want to go up and down the
stairs I've been adding a little THC CBD
teen true to her food and the days that
I added she
nice you can see it helping with the
pain and inflammation ah it takes about
20 minutes half an hour to kick in for
her and you can see the change overnight
I had five or six customers come in
looking for something for their dogs
before I thought to try it and yeah I'm
glad I did there are companies that are
making specific edibles for dogs now if
there are things available at hem stores
that have CBD for your dogs that are
made in America with actual hemp
products there I can't say there's
anything wrong with that as long as it's
made with real real hemp or real
cannabis you're basically in a brick and
mortar retailer in the United States it
has to at least contain what the label
says recently the the DEA just scented a
thing to a bunch of the CBD only
companies in the internet kind of
freaked out was like oh they're just
attacking weed like they always do it
was they were targeting the people that
are selling like cod fish oil and
calling a CBD oil because people don't
know any better and you can't take this
stuff to a lab and get it tested as a
civilian yeah you're just getting
scammed out of money on the internet so
be careful if you're ordering online
folks with this the if you've got a
number of different ailments
you should get online and check out to
see if there's any research on what THC
and CBD can do for those for your
specific ailment yeah and then check out
the laws in your state and see if and
where you can get this stuff if you have
to come take a vacation in Colorado I
see a lot of the people doing exactly
that they come they visit at one of our
rec stores and a good rec store will
have a decent selection of CBD products
at this point they might not have a huge
selection or a wide selection but they
should have some you can go to more than
one store water here so you'll check out
weed maps you can check out Leafly there
are menus available to see what you want
unfortunately on the mobile apps they
cannot show you pricing anymore all the
pricing has gone on all the mobile apps
but you can still find them on the web
if you use your computer it's weed maps
calm and Leafly le AF ly if you're
coming to Colorado I think those are
effective in all the marijuana States
yeah pretty much nationwide now yes if
you want to search for locations of your
favorite favorite
strains or products or topicals or
whatever you're looking for it go to
those websites and you can find
information on the products you're
looking for and you can find specific
locations that have them don't get mad
at me if a dispensary does not update
their weed maps menu sometimes they like
weed maps and Leafly are great places to
start your search but if you're looking
for a very specific product or even kind
of a general product you're looking for
something with a certain ratio of
cannabinoid some THC some CBD something
like that
check out weed Maps release we make a
list of possible shops and then go ahead
and give them a call
and just real quick ask oh hey what's
your your selection of blah yeah what do
you have in for CBD options right now do
ya black-dick pens yeah but like be
specific in what you're looking for as
much as you can and then narrow your
list that way because I mean the
industry is weird right now and you
never know when somebody's gonna walk in
and so it gives me all of that so what's
on their menu might not have anything to
do with what's on their store shelf and
right this moment it might just be stuff
that's been on the store shelf in the
last 30 days I was shopping at Green and
healthy the other day and I was
frustrated because I wanted I bought
something and the guy behind me was
frustrated because I had purchased all
of it and he said I want that and she
had to say it's gone and he said why is
it on the list and she's like he just
bought all of it sorry so that's how
quickly she can sell out I bought her
notes and I cleaned him out I took the
bottom of that I watched a dude by 160
things are hard candies once I'm Jesus
it was just like okay let me get you a
box and sweep all of these into the box
and like for the people sorry we're out
of that particular product line and
there were likes there's something wrong
with it something amazing with it
currently honestly every every month
I've worked in a dispensary that's
happened with at least one product line
once I mean sometimes it's only the last
eight or ten or twenty units or whatever
but it happens well I used to go to you
went with me we went to the clinic in
Denver and they had Durbin poison wax if
and they had vortex wax I loved from the
clinic
on Mexico in Denver it's still open they
don't have these products anymore
they've changed their game but they used
to have the vortex tasted like
cranberries and dirty feet and rotten
fruit I don't know why you liked that
feet smell oh man I just loved that in
my weed but the high that he gave me I
couldn't focus on anything it made my
eyes jump around like I was on a bumpy
road it was really crazy that durbin
poison just I love the flavor a good
urban poison wax and that head-high is
just so amazing so back in the day we'd
go to the clinic and I would save up as
much money as I can afford to save up
and I'd walk in there and I'd say how
much did that Durbin poison do you have
and they'd say there's about 14 grams
and I'd say I'll take it and then I'd
say how much did that vortex do you have
and they usually have somewhere between
14 and 28 grams I would buy it I would
clean it out the guy behind me would be
like oh yeah he bought a lot of that I
want something they'd be like sorry he
bought all of it
yeah I did it the other day with those
delicious truffles I uh they cut me off
eventually hours away from my house at
the time I had to go stock up I got the
last four boxes of code and I watched
the lady behind they don't have a pro
tip ever but if you want to sound like
you know what you're talking about
don't say CBDs say CBD yeah it's cat boy
dog are the initials there's not an
apostrophe s th seize this train has a
lot of th C's in it you say this train
has a lot of THC [ __ ] that up on this
weed special started but like it's a
common mispronunciation or yeah just CBD
you guys there you wouldn't say I want a
glass of water you just say I want a
glass of water and you know that there's
a lot of water in there there's a
measurement with that contains a
specific amount of water and you're
looking for see me Dean CB
Deas because it's not a group of things
it is it's it's CBD and you don't see CH
C's no you don't see corns I want some
corns we're gonna do an episode in the
future about sativa and indica and the
differences and the benefits and
balances and the growing styles and
everything of each so we'll talk about
set of sattva and Indigo's phenotype phe
note2 type while we're on it strain oh
my gosh that's my boy Cooper Watts he
made a short educational video on the
difference between strain and strand
strands are ropes or fibers strains are
different varieties of cannabis if you
want to be technical you can call it a
varietal or a cultivar but let's let's
go with strain instead of strand as a
start you guys it's trichome and not
trichrome I wanted to talk about Nate
Diaz from the UFC the fight that doesn't
matter but those dudes through the [ __ ]
down ended with them both standing beat
the [ __ ] out of each other from I didn't
see the fight but I did see the
press-conference we're about to talk
about it holy [ __ ] he got punched in the
face a lot of times
directors got some punches so one thing
I want to talk about when they're
interviewing him do just Street pulls
out a vape pen and starts taking vape
pen rips and one of the report the video
here let's just play this video it's
only a couple of seconds long here to
play this video and then we'll talk for
a couple of seconds and we'll wrap up
this podcast but if you haven't seen the
video it's your standard concentrate
vape pet I've got a million different
versions of this on a store shelf I work
at I'm gonna bring the volume up slowly
[Music]
are you just for the record smoking the
true company it's a CBD it helps with
inflammation stuff like that so you
wanted to get these for a big part of
this story to hear that the key right
there make your life a better place
that's what he do several times he
[ __ ] up where he said it's good to use
before and after the fight he shouldn't
I said before the fight [ __ ] up right
there buddy but still well there there's
he might be in a trouble for doing that
yeah that's that's what I wanted to talk
about I'm glad you said that it's the
specific rules bar cannabis consumption
period until six hours after the fight
is what I was reading in random press
coverage of this I like I don't follow
the sports make sense in all their rules
catch that from my intro to this story
is that you sorrow rules or is that
rules from the local governing sporting
agency lose rules with an S
a fighter's can't use any sort of
cannabis product until or any sort of
banned substance which marijuana or
cannabis products would be on the list
until six hours after the fight I'm
pretty sure I already know your answer
here but do you think a dude that just
spent twenty five minutes of his night
getting kicked in the dick and punched
in the face should be allowed to take a
couple of rips off a CBD vape pen at the
end of the night almost the most surely
[Music]
anything that's gonna help you recover
faster and deal with that level of
trauma is encouraged by me
reduces inflammation and swelling and
that dude the his face looked like a
jack-o'-lantern it did and honestly I
incur a plot his use of anything other
than heavy narcotics is usually you know
I don't know what they do to deal with
the pain at the end of that but I need
Diaz did make a joke he said I'm going
to a party and Conor McGregor is going
to the hospital I don't know how
accurate that was because his face
punched in I can't even talk about who I
feel like won that fight that doesn't
matter at all in this podcast that's not
what we're here for all I know is that
Nate Diaz took a hell of a beating and
that during the press conference he was
ripping a Seabee dgn blatantly ripping
it - he looked took like two or three
big fat rips off of it so he didn't
cough like I do yeah yeah they call him
young wheezy so I feel like this dude
should I think I feel like every athlete
feel like almost everybody should be
allowed to consume everybody why not
let's see dick it was about last night
the new episode that aired was
medical marijuana use in the NFL to deal
with the chronic concussion syndrome or
whatever it's called no one helps I'm a
victim of a head injury and I know we
talked about that 42 minutes ago
yep that definitely that CBD changed my
life and it helped me get out of my funk
that I had focused on CBD but that's
sort of what they were interesting that
is a part of the story that were telling
was
THC CBD oil protects my next question
was gonna be do you think that cannabis
use is a performance-enhancing drugs
performance by people fighting UFC
fighting how about football
no not performance-enhancing at all how
about recovery enhancing how about
basketball no I'm trying to play devil's
advocate here how about video games yeah
yeah I feel like when I smoke in my mind
since I am so comfortable I've got a TD
my mind wanders you can tell by
listening to the podcast my mind is
[ __ ] starts around all over the place
when I smoke some hash it does help me
focus a little bit there's a moment
there for the first 5-10 minutes where
my brain just spins but once it lands
back in its place I'm pretty well
focused and so I mean I've got mild ATD
as well and that's one of the things
I've always enjoyed about cannabis is it
helps slow down the pool better I could
shoot basketball better I can probably I
don't play football I could probably
throw my football with more accuracy
after I took a couple of dabs ah I'm a
musician I've played drums for 20 years
I've had drum lessons I've been on tour
I've played in big bands I played in
small bands sometimes smoking a little
weed makes me play a little better
sometimes smoke a little weed [ __ ] me
up to tell you the truth so I don't know
how alters unless you're talking about
like just helping the D athlete of the
performer - now other distractions and
focus on the competition in the moment I
don't see it you know making you run
faster jump higher and that's what I
think of when I write performance and
answer yourself full of blood so that
your heart can move more oxygen more
testosterone so I'm faster meaner leaner
quicker right yes steroids so that you
have more physical muscle mass but like
able to kick you in the face any harder
it doesn't make me give you more damn it
helps me recover from that face kick
faster but like that's not a performance
enhancer that's the recovery enhancer
that's very different for the music
they're got these long chicken legs and
they come out and I cross them Jeff you
got to fight in 30 seconds you ready for
your pre-show dab let's get it and they
drop me like a half a gram of some
pineapple jack nut run shatter on there
and I blow it out you know what I want
to do after that not fight how do you
want to fight at all no I'm just watch
you couldn't manipulate no you can
manipulate the rake huh because if they
need their fingers to grapple I was
thinking boxing style you've got one
manager holding up the smoke buddy one
manager holding up the rig another
manager working the nail on the car cap
yeah this seems complicated for a free
flight that I would use one of those the
hinge nails
so you do one hand I can do with my
glove on I figure this out the
announcers microphone comes down Geoff's
rig comes down I am one of these guys if
there's a dab to be taken I will make
sure that's awesome I'm glad we got to
work the Nate Diaz clip into this
episode that was photoshopped I click to
follow him on it and they start talking
about it away proud to lead the way
about politically correct or gentle the
[ __ ] head I'm gonna smoke some CBD to
help it out it's gonna help don't be mad
at me that's cool I like that but both
of those brothers are gonna end up
banned from the UFC and banned from
fighting for life if they keep playing
the way that they do and that's gonna be
terrible because I like to see their
performances large hippie Rastafari and
dude but I love to watch some UFC I
think about it this way those dudes
weigh 200 pounds they're [ __ ] jack
they've got more testosterone and then
their body but most people should have
and they want a break [ __ ] I'm glad that
they're in that cage breaking each other
then out at the bar or at the dad lounge
trying to break me if I condone that go
to battle in that cage let's see it
that's cool that's skill jujitsu we've
both known people who were just built to
brawl yeah that's just yes some people
are here to drum some people are here to
high-five some people are here to brawl
we've all got our skill and it's good
that they have an outlet and I'm a fan I
think I am accidentally an MMA fan
because of Joe Rogan and because of Joey
Diaz and it's out the fight companion
tour him and a bunch of his friends and
I also listen to find her in the kids so
that's more MMA that gets pumped into my
head but they put out a fight companion
where two guys from Fighter and the kid
and Eddie Bravo and Joe Rogan sit around
and they watch the UFC and they talk
about what's going on they drink beer
and smoke weed and get [ __ ] up and
talk [ __ ] to each other but they're
watching the UFC and they tell you like
in the
like all right round three of this match
we're at 29 28 27 seconds and you can
sync up your computer and watch that
video and so it's almost weirdly like
you're hanging out with Rogan and the
crew watching the fight i watch it if
it's on somewhere I'm at but I don't
like actively pay attention yeah I pay
more like if I'm over at your house and
it's on it'll get more attention out of
me than like football or basketball and
I took a little karate when I was a
youngster so I've always been fascinated
with that type of skills to conclude
Santu for several years and then go
karate for even longer
I was just rip it on some CBD oil took
like two or three good maybe three or
four good rips all right like we've been
rambling for almost an hour I think it's
time to wrap up this show what do you
think I crossed out all the stuff on my
list except popular CBD strains so that
if people wanted to grow cannabis that
was high in CBD just a few strains I
would recommend anything Harlequin canna
tonic Taurus ooh Tora Bora ac/dc the
Tora Bora is really wonderful folks that
I've had a lot of personally and I know
I went over that list really quickly
those were just off the top of my house
the other thing I'd like to touch and I
think before we wrap this one up is for
at least for the pain and inflammation
that I'm dealing with THC and CBD
together in roughly 50/50 mix work two
or three hundred times better then CBD
alone or THC alone the two of them
together works it's not one plus one
equals two it's one plus one equals
seven as far as I'm concerned the effect
is amplified greatly cool last man no
it's wonderful when you when you mix THC
and CBD the medical applications are
wonderful I'm sorry if I sound a little
stone and I am pretty tired but I feel
clear-headed I feel like alert and
president we're gonna wasn't true when I
got here I was hurting so
I I seriously almost didn't come folks
and I really like it and I didn't almost
didn't come because my head was down
then I'm glad you made it glad you
pulled through I'm glad those CBD tabs
fixed yup yeah I should've just started
a video earlier in the day I just I was
that's how life goes sometimes you got
to get home and get the dad bread going
bro remind everybody how they can follow
you on social media and absolutely
remind us about your Facebook page you
can catch me on pleb low for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook give us a like
comment share we really appreciate that
we're reaching more and more people
every week on that it's I mean the
viewers that I get per week spike and
change topic the topic but this we've
been getting closer to the election the
view counts been going up steady that's
been nice and I like to think this show
us something to do with it
so if you're checking us out from the
show go ahead and send me a message say
hi or if you just want to hit me on
Twitter it's at an emo Punk 15 on
Twitter and e mo PU and k15 just like it
sounds and yeah look forward to hear
from you yeah make sure you follow him
let him know that you found him on the
podcast buddy thanks for listening bro
you've been listening to the podcast
since the beginning I appreciate that
and we see those messages merrily
appreciate yes we do we see all of those
messages because if you send me a
message and I have not responded to your
message yet I'm getting to it trust me
we do one Episode a week I get 20 up
messages a week I have turn to filter
out my favorite or the most relevant for
what's going on in our lives right now
that's how I handle the emails so I'll
be back with more episodes with more
email content I love the listenor
generated content that lets me know that
I'm getting the information to the
people that need the information I'm
giving them exactly what they want makes
me feel great
we know way too much about cannabis
folks a little nugget of our vast
cannabis intellect to share with the
listeners this night and it's when we
have an email that's like hey I was
wondering how to block it it sparks some
awesome conversations you say well my
favorite episodes man our listeners with
specific grow questions absolutely I'll
be going through the phone and I'll get
an email and I'll say a show question
and I'll read it you can see me light up
like
yeah cuz now I get to ramble for 45
minutes about one of my favorite things
and it a whole bunch about so it always
makes me good to get those messages and
honestly from where we are in Colorado
especially if you're in Pueblo it's hard
to understand what you need to know now
in Florida or or wherever you have to
Australia we have listeners all over the
place and so you sending in a question
that lets us know where you're at and
how we can help you helps us clue in on
the information to give you and there's
so much fun to do the last two episodes
were fantastic I've got plenty more
coming guys don't be afraid to send me
some emails don't be discouraged if I
haven't replied to you I get so many
messages that it's honestly overwhelming
somebody told me to hire an intern
because it's all about talking to me
they don't want to talk to my intern
they don't want to pre type dancer they
want to actually communicate with me I
do my best to do that I try to keep up
with it because if you don't know how to
get in touch with me this is how you do
it if you have a question for the
podcast the easiest way to get your
question acknowledged is to send it to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com you
can follow the sweets the sweet spot
it's the easiest you can follow me on
twitter it's at g f YH podcast you can
follow the podcast on Facebook search
for grow from your heart a podcast it's
on Facebook I would love to hear from
you on any of those platforms but like I
said my favorite is the girl from your
heart at hotmail.com email I'll answer
all your stuff if you want to sponsor
the podcast if you've got a product you
want me to review anything like that
reach out to me there also you guys I am
on instagram my instagram page is Irie
underscore genetics I own a seed company
we breed feminized and regular cannabis
seeds you can see a lot of my girl
progress right there on Irene or
genetics on instagram check that out
I've been posting some cool pictures of
a breeding project yeah thank you I
appreciate that that picture I posted
with the female grateful dog plant with
the male arise flowers and pollen on top
of it it drops little flowers and the
pollen dumped on there and it's already
showing seeds that picture got 400 and
something 50 something likes that the
last time I looked it's probably close
to five or six hundred by now
we're really getting some notice on the
Instagram please follow me there you
guys I think we're gonna wrap up the
show Mike thank you for coming dude you
down man I had to for the CBD episode
that's honestly what with the final
decision-maker for leaving the house and
coming over and doing the show was was I
wanted to do another good episode we
need you myself and Doug did one a while
back yes and I've had Fox on a couple
times also we've done yeah you've done
two with Fox
that was my who I was hitting now when
you said let's do a CBD episode we want
a third you were like now it's just you
and me she lives in Denver now so it's
harder yeah
but he's sort of the CBD go to that I
know of down here what I have a CBD
question that's who I send a message all
right you guys yeah if you guys have CBD
questions or any other questions please
hit us up any questions at all you guys
we're gonna get out of here it's time
for us to take some fat dad's dispense
and until next time take a fat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]