yo it's Bobby hustle representing for
the real big bite sound Joseph star the
boy can't play we letting a broken
guitar hey yo nicotine you know we're
smoking hard hold on so we'll set
something up my money yeah what's up
ladies and gentlemen welcome to absolute
number 27 of the I agriculture podcast
they call me Rasta Jeff I'm your host
thanks for joining me we got a very news
filled episode for you guys this week
joining me across the table is my buddy
Adam how you doing buddy what's up man
i'm high on seemingly not low thanks for
joining me tonight for another episode
bro absolutely man is 420 and we are
doing a right we are doing for 20 right
wait a little 710 with our 420 smoking a
big old fat joint of some heart of gold
loving this afternoon anyway this
episode will be filled with a bunch of
news and some chatting because this
weekend the weekend that just passed by
the time this comes out this will be out
on a Monday that means that the weekend
I got to see fish at dicks in Denver and
they played all of my favorite songs and
we had a wonderful time so that's my
prediction hopefully that comes true so
let's uh get to some ads real quick here
and then we'll get into some news this
podcast is brought to you by nature's
green remedies calm visit nature's green
remedies calm for gage green genetics
laplata labs Sin City rare dankness mile
high can adventure IRA genetics and many
more trusted brands nature's green
remedies is running a special for our
loyal podcast listeners use coupon code
September 14 that's the word September
and the number 14 all one word for
fifteen percent off any order and free
priority shipping this coupon code is
good through the month of sep tember and
is valid on any brand on the website big
thanks MA chérie much respects to
nature's green remedies for the
promotion and the continued support
spot cast is also brought to you by hi
grill indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at sixty to seventy one
beach street unit f or stop by the new
pueblo location on 618 east fourth
Street in Pueblo Colorado check out
hydros for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
don't forget to visit w WR 0 denver com
for current store hours and special
sales you know hydro is a little tiny
shop they don't have everything in there
but they will order whatever you need
and they have very competitive prices
also they are doing a special you can
get a deal on a tote of soil how much is
a tonne of soil that's about forty eight
seven gallon pots as what we did the
math on so a tote of soil how much does
that cost five hundred and fifty dollars
or six hundred dollars delivered
anywhere in the state of Colorado big
shout out to high grow up web low I grow
Denver also Porsche parts of this
podcast are brought to you by our
friends at treehugger.com sepsis brought
to you in part by treehugger.com live
music lifestyle magazine check out
treehugger calm for concert and festival
news and reviews look out at the cookout
with treehugger.com let's respect to
Ryan a tree hugger thanks for helping us
out bro alright we're going to take a
couple of dads and then we add them and
I are going to come back and review a
little bit of news we haven't done the
news in a while so we're gonna get you
nice and caught up I'm going to turn up
nikka t4 a couple of seconds while I
take a DAB Adam if you want to say
anything now is your chance buddy no I'm
pretty good right now you know and the
way you look it may be best if you just
keep your head down right now bro here
people something there he's not not even
sure he's there you go hang on I need a
dad
[Music]
all right i want to give a huge shout
out to spin and the entire garden of
weeden crew I'm dabbing some some live
resin what strain is that I'm so high to
stick a dad I can't even remember what
it's called yet EOG the Yeti oh gee
thanks bro it's written on there but
it's upside down over I can't see it yet
EOG live resin it's dank it's so high I
couldn't remember the name or it's still
Bank I couldn't remember the name of it
I'm all dad doubt right now and
everything something like I'm in a
tunnel it's epic I just said the word
epic who are I guess i am going to cough
my brains out and then we're gonna
scroll to some news alright check this
out this news i found entertaining this
is coming from the cannabis and it is by
ricardo baca from the cannabis staff the
topic says pot shop owner eighty percent
of our customers come from out of state
adams over there shaking his head you're
an out-of-stater bro i am an out of
state route as I denied you all if I
choose out-of-stater but I'm no longer a
now stator you know I'm gonna rested it
up in here longer in six months yeah
they don't realize that when they check
your know if totally not yeah yeah I
just I feel that because I'm a red card
patient and the place that has my my
card or the place that I like to go to
anyways my preferred place is now
recreational and it's a it's a line
there's a line to get in to get your mad
it's the same place you know they can
only make the st. 12 people back at one
time and it's the same building same how
long does that line take you now I
haven't been out there since they've
really done in the sides one or two
times and one time I've walked right in
there because there was nobody in there
but the other times it's been five or
six people ahead of me and pee
walk in behind me and they're like oh no
and they just turn around and walk out
yeah that's a long time the way we just
had a shop downtown they're not heard
Android the business people would wait
in line for an hour because the whole
front of the place would be full all
right I'm gonna get in this article a
little bit right it says Ryan REE Ryan
Griego on the recreational pot shop and
cover southern Colorado and he's putting
out a bold and formed estimate saying
that decidedly decidedly clear majority
of his customers are from outside of
Colorado I'm gonna take a big breath
here because I can't even read after
that dab I think the dispensary this guy
is from is actually they posted a really
cool shot of the canna sewer and this
article online here a really cool angle
of the sign and the building style shook
in place with a great Colorado
background is that a dope shot a dope
shot right haha I didn't even mean that
fun alright I'm back in my game let's go
eighty percent of my customers are
coming from other states predominantly
Texas New Mexico Kansas and arrogant
Arizona said Griego owner of Kanna sewer
and pueblo west which opened its doors
in may for recreational marijuana sales
I knew there would be out of state
customers coming in but I thought would
thought it would be more of a 30 70
split with thirty percent of my
customers from out of state but it's
more severe than that on the flip-flop I
don't think severe was the right word
out of state tourists account for forty
four percent of all retail sales and
then in the Denver area at about ninety
percent in Mountain Resort such as Aspen
or Telluride according to a recent study
produced by the Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division as we've talked
about the marijuana Enforcement Division
or the Med they're the guys the division
in charge of regulating the dispensaries
and the grows and all of that stuff they
are in charge of the marijuana and they
regulate all of that stuff they make the
rules and they are also are also a
branch of the IRS so that's pretty legit
they're a huge place they'd make a lot
of rules they [ __ ] and put their foot
down and it matters tweet me every time
I say the f-word every time I say [ __ ]
just tweet me and tell me to stop doing
it please but I'm trying to stop doing
that on the show trying to cut that word
out of my vocabulary it's not even a
cool word to use for anything but anyway
but for a shop in Pueblo hardly
considered in the same tourism league as
Aspen or tell
right to make eighty percent of its
sales to out-of-state visitors is
something an oven anomaly even given
plug Louis proximity less than 100 miles
to the new mexico state line they're not
joking at all about the differences
between aspen telluride compared to
Pueblo Pueblo is it's a cool place if
you live here and you know where you're
going but is a steel town it's a steel
mill town it's a blue-collar working
man's town and Aspen until your rider
places where you go to spend some time
we don't have we have a reservoir here
we've got a river walk here we've got
some really cool trails and things
there's a castle about the rent it out
here I mean Pablo is definitely nice to
come and see but there's nothing here to
like oh he also has yeah this it has
everything that a normal town has and
it's pretty yeah so to say that eighty
percent of our sales are going to
out-of-state visitors is kind of
shocking well we have a lot of
recreational weed shops here in the shop
that you're talking about is one hundred
percent recreational so do you think
that the numbers are the same across the
board at the shops at the rec shops that
it's 70 30 I think it depends on your
product that's true and that's something
I was going to get at because the reason
that the Colorado market is not shopping
at a recreational shop when you're
either and I haven't read this article
in advance very well I skimmed it
because if I found it interesting for
the show I think that a Colorado
resident like you did you became a
resident you got your medical marijuana
recommendation for the doctor you've got
your red card now you can shop at a
medical shop and not pay the 25 percent
tax that's added on to the rec weed and
probably you get better herb there I
think it's a med shop but also I most of
the Colorado residents have been here
and we have a guy or a caregiver or just
you've got the photo you're growing your
own or you're growing your own I used I
literally use the rec shops and until I
got my red card and then once I got my
red card then I I used it all the time
you don't say that I don't I went into
the wreck shop with somebody who just
came here recently and I was looking for
a certain product and that's I went in
there because for one she had never done
it before and it's an experience you
know everybody should go yep there you
go
is amazing I've got a bottle of applause
i canna extra strength pain cream arnica
peppermint juniper cannabis ah this
stuff I have said on this show that I'm
skeptical of topicals and lotions and
such 24 bucks ah this was actually
kicked down by the grimy Gatsby to me
because I mentioned some shoulder pain
uh I had a guest over the other night
who looks like Helena we were when they
were saying its tail didn't look like
they felt good I was like what's up and
they said neck hurts and put some of
this on my hands and rub their neck for
about 10 minutes and my hands were high
my hands fell balloony yeah i hate the
cool pink floyd but my hands felt just
like two balloons after exercise and
wrangle no extra strength yeah I can
only imagine what that goes next I'll
like after I rub that I bet she's or
she'll just slathered it all over our
legs and then like you know if she's
talking about it just won that one hit
no one that one is the new shared it was
yeah yeah Adam shirts Colorado cannabis
that I grew with a lightweight yeah and
uh it kind of wrecked their world yeah
that's funny all right I'm gonna get a
little back in this article we got high
and got distracted shout out to the
person that got a massage with the
freakin cannabis arnica peppermint
juniper cannabis lotion from apothic
Canada China huge shout-out to grimy
Gatsby for sure you guys don't even know
he's behind the scenes working [ __ ] and
you don't even know it this article
continues to say so how did Griego land
at these figures especially given the
state of Colorado's restrictions on
tracking recreational customers
information Oh won't we keep seeing
these statistics and that's a question
I've raised twice now all right once and
this is the second time somebody's
raised it for me go for it but you're
you've already explained it where
they're not tracking your name so much
as they're just checking your purchase
you know he comments on it so he says we
have a media group that we hired on and
they monitor all of our social media and
Google Analytics and we've paid close
attention to the progression of people
searching on pcs and mobile devices
Griego said a lot of these numbers come
from inside the store everyone has to
show ID and we check IDs twice one
in reception and again in the dispensing
area plus our blood tenders are always
making friendly conversation asking
people where they're from sure eighty
percent is griegos educated guess but
while he knows he sees traffic locally
as well as from nearby wheel is Colorado
towns Colorado Springs walsenburg
Trinidad and mahanta he said he says
definitively that he sees more Texans
than anybody else uh that's a big state
our bro Kevin works at a shop he's not
here tonight but he works at a
dispensary said the same and he says
it's a lot of Texans yeah not
surprisingly the out-of-state customers
are also spending more than the Colorado
NZ said ah I want to know what you guys
are paying for herb you might have we
did this on my Facebook page on the
Huayra genetics I want to know what you
guys are paying herb in your location
tweet me at agriculture let me know give
me a good don't tell me exactly where
you are but you only know what state
you're in maybe what part of that state
and let me know what good high grade
herb or whatever herb is available let
me know what it costs uh I'll tell you
in Colorado uh I don't go to the shops
dude do you know what a now it's Kevin
those were that's I just really had a
friend I think she said it was 460 that
yeah referee animals that that's right
about the high end of prize a caregiver
my patient you can find them for 350 if
you shopped around and wasn't really
like I want this quality and this you
know you can still find it cheaper
depending on where you want to go
recreational that is alright so I want
to know if you guys are paying ah on the
street right now in Colorado ounces
depending on what you want you can find
an ounce for one hundred and fifty
dollars it's not the dank it's not the
chronic mazing buy it for medical or 50
but for the fire it's about 200 bucks
225 for a good dank outs right now in
Colorado I was in some you know if you
just random dude if you got the hook up
to you I would rather go 50 bucks
believe me you saw that excellent if you
have to let dank that top shelf cush
yeah yeah if you got to go to the
dispensaries and get it it's going to
run you cold air five dollars an ounce
for that same 225 200 all the routes Wow
all right it makes sense but am I guess
it's the Colorado people are getting
that stuff that the caregivers are
growing or their buddies with the
caregiver grow or haven't
extra on or something all that private
cushions a little bit better than the
shop we'd I think it's harder for
someone to get on with the caregiver you
know especially if you don't have a
medical debilitating condition where you
know um I'm not I'm not medical because
I'm in a wheelchair that's for sure you
know or I have cancer it's just knowing
somebody that you trust and want to
assign as your caregiver so here's
something we kind of skipped over guys
we were talking about caregiver and
stuff when you get a and now actually
word is now provider and Colorado
correct when you're back in the day it
was caregiver but that was sounds
confusing when you get your medical
marijuana recommendation from a doctor
there is no license it's a
recommendation it's not a prescription
they recommend that you use medical
cannabis and they sign papers and you
send that paper into the colorado state
registry and they send you back a card
that is a registry card that says you
are registered with state of colorado to
use medical marijuana when you fill out
your paperwork you were allowed to sign
designate a person that is called your
provider which used to be your caregiver
this person the paperwork says they have
to be responsible for something other
than just procuring your cannabis so you
should drive them to their medical
marijuana doctor's appointment you
should probably make them a kale
smoothie and work on their [ __ ]
person I said [ __ ] against somebody
tweet me and tell me to stop doing that
I'm trying I got a note in front of you
still watch your mouth so you make them
a you go to you spend time with me make
them a shake you try to do what their
overall well-being and if your caregiver
I think sitting like you and I do we
hang out I'm not your caregiver but when
you're having a bad day when something's
driving you nuts I got my red card the
same day you renewed you right there
with was a couple of my patients yeah
absolutely and I hang out you can tells
it one of the guys is an older cat his
16 year old guy in him and I he's my bro
because like you come and sit on the
table to sit at the table and they're
having a bad day and we talked and you
feel better about that some people that
have aids cancer major [ __ ] they don't
have those people they just need someone
to talk to it because a lot of people
are afraid of them once you're sick
people abandon you or you just need any
kind of distance from do we hate I
haven't hurt or you need extra support
even if those people are there you can
always use I'm a young energetic
youthful dude with a good attitude I
just spit right across the table at you
my bad so I apologize for that one but I
didn't say [ __ ] about it
hello waita so I think being a caregiver
that's part of it going and I write down
spiritual counseling on my when they say
what else do you provide as I make
smoothies and shakes for these guys that
drive to their appointments and I
provide spiritual counseling just being
your friend but so the caregiver is a
person that is responsible for providing
your medicine the actual Colorado law
does say that they are allowed to charge
you money to cover the cost of your
labor and your lights and your expenses
so you're not supposed to profit off of
caregiver care get your caregiver ship
all right if your provider ship so uh
yeah you can so you can be a caregiver
in the state of Colorado all you have to
do is decide that you want to be a
caregiver and learn how to grow and then
find somebody that trusts you enough and
then work out something with them the
dispensaries I don't think or the
sinners don't give you a good deal they
just give you a little bit of a discount
nah my guys the third people that I'm
responsible for right now there are four
people and I know pretty much exactly
how much I can predict when they need
medicine I'll be sitting around one
night and go out about time for a
patient a to give me a call tomorrow and
i'll put them a little package together
because i know what he needs and we not
only that but that way they kind of have
more of a specific and exactly what they
need you know yea high CBD hi TAS
exactly i grow that tora bora cut
exactly the night nurse was bred for a
specific person his two favorite strains
are grateful dog and tora bora and i
bred them together basically to make the
perfect medicine for one of my patients
absolutely i went that far for this guy
plus i know it's gonna be a killer
string but I mean that was fired that
strain its if you're not probably not
gonna go wrong with it and even if you
do you know it's a test it's it's dull
an experiment sitting there on the table
if you want to give that thing a little
smell yeah I've smelled it it's
fantastic well thank you that's the
night nurse yeah it's definitely frosty
but DNA genetics lets me use their Tora
Bora they gave me permission to breed
with it I've got their award-winning cut
they let me use that to breed to the
Grateful dog and it came out pretty
stinky smells well I'm going to run a
bunch of testers and maybe one day we'll
back to market I def I like the leaders
3 and remedies calm because I move the
indica smoker whereas you're more of the
sativa guy what's weird about me I like
indica flowers if I'm going to smoke a
joint I wanted to make me sit down and
we're out and like why just one joint
seems more like sitting in a hammock
with my feet up with the little
dreadlock girl cuddled up next to me and
some Grateful Dead on the radio and a
nice breeze that's smoking a joint dads
are like taking shots I don't drink
alcohol but it reminds me of when I used
to drink Jagermeister or tequila it's
the it's more energetic it makes my head
spin a little bit more I don't relax
well after dad's it makes me want to do
[ __ ] unless I take a half gram dab and
want to sit down oh my goodness yeah
yeah we won't do that tonight on the
show we will do a large domina it's
almost time the large dad thing is
almost coming to an end I don't feel
good about it as I used to I'm getting
older I guess your lungs have so many
inhales and exhales and I'm assuming by
doing a half gram dab I'm probably using
a multiple inhaling exhales for each dab
and I'd like to live a little bit longer
than I wanted to when I was a kid I
didn't realize one day I was gonna fall
over and die so uh we may do a grand
finale we may be like a gram dab or a to
Graham dab or something episode 100
episodes a long time hey 50 or something
we'll gosh brother so this I just want
to do it so that that way we can retire
the super large dad thing we can put the
dad challenges to arrest and say hey
we're all alive and we could do the life
challenge after that so we're way off
topic on this news thing we've expensive
it could be 200 150 announce but these
shots are selling it for 500 now it's
close enough so do you think we do too
expensive where you live even though
it's legal here it's not the cheapest
for recreational use yeah but it's
available yeah it was an athlete
vailable between the hours of eight and
eight here's a random question you're
from a state where cannabis was hard to
get you've told me stories about waiting
on your deed for hours and hours and I
shot it was hard to get it sista
everybody is too busy there's other
drugs that are more important than your
tent all the time back okay yeah it's
Florida so you guys can imagine what
wasn't that hard I grew up there so it
was a but when I moved back to would you
rather have whoa the internet it's
refreshing multiple times and freaking
me out but it went right back to where
it was ah but music didn't cut out so
that's cool would you rather have ah so
street we'd is cheaper a little bit
cheaper I'm gonna say 30 bucks and aids
on the street how much is an eighth of
weed at the dispensary where you would
shop for recreational but you can go get
your med weed Oh 30 at mine okay would
you have the rules every fourth of the
20th and how much is it wreck
recreational sorry sixty bucks in a holy
crap so 55 to 60 just a bit around which
store would you rather have the
convenience of going to the store and
just paying the extra money or would you
rather sit there and wait for some high
ass dude to show up with the sack that's
probably so high a gram or a just a
joint you know from the pre-roll or
something like that we're gonna get high
and it was eight bucks or ten bucks you
know saying and I could go out there it
cost you a little bit of gas because
it's here at the outside of town but
some places have it you know closer
closer yeah yeah you know if I lived out
there would be a different story but you
could go buy a joint you know I mean
it's as simple as that and that to me
I'm not going to go out there and do it
just because I you move here you get
kind of picky yeah yeah there everybody
in Colorados a damn weed snob now or all
connoisseurs I love is our duty could I
was already a weed stop for a move I
only smoke girl scout cookies people
would give me weed and I'd be like did
you flush this demon hashtag to even
flush bro yeah the flusher we'd we'll
talk about that in the future slushy
early dude it's easy is one of the
easiest it's almost free and it's one of
the easiest things you can do just flush
your lead it'll help out so much and
cure and cure well that's a whole that's
I can talk for hours about cheering lead
maybe I will one day but those are the
two things back east that people are
like what so what a lot of people are
failing on I see a lot of facebook post
about does anybody in Colorado know how
to cure weed yes I do and I'll share
well it's different here what's dry here
so you need to build a humid room and
control your community all right i'm
just ranting yeah let me get back to the
article because i said add a lot of news
and if this rate we're not going to get
a lot of new van new story a little odd
cast magnets it's going the way it
should these out-of-state consumers
because remember we're talking about
people from out of state that's how far
it's been these out-of-state consumers
are spending much more than locals Grego
said they're spending about twice as
much as locals about 120 to 140 dollars
edibles are the most popular with these
people out of state consumers can buy up
to 7 grams of cannabis total so you see
them by one to two grams of bud and the
rest of their allotment made up of
edible products I'm not sure I am not up
to date with that rule we're gonna have
to look that up in the future here and
talk about that what is your edible what
helmet medical they don't really
distinguish between the two you know
I've seen your edibles for this is for
recreational purposes out-of-staters how
much does my edible count as I thought
you and Kevin already went over this
where it was going to be weighed by the
metric gram or whatever you know I mean
gonna remember that we're gonna have to
google i will find that out for you guys
remind me to check that out and we'll
put that on a future episode of course I
just saw fish this weekend after your
while you're listening to this song
forgetful I'm gonna need some some pep
talks for my meal in the future remind
me all right yeah we're going to get
back to the future since it's illegal to
cross state boundaries will legally
purchased Colorado marijuana does
graeagle and his staff inform these
consumers says customer sorry about that
very serious state law and here's where
I have the problem this person that I
got to try that cream was very vocal
inside the store and asking where she
could take here said product since it
was high in CBD just product interior
all and he after informing him after
informing her three times he kind of got
like hey can we stop saying anything
about taking it where you're not
supposed to anything I've already said
it because when you come to golf
Colorado what Adam just kind of alluding
to is have some class
s be careful what you say in the
dispensaries know the answer is no wood
no he can can I put this in my car and
go back to Texas no can I put this in my
suitcase and fly back to California but
what will maybe maybe you're not allowed
to take it there's a mom boxes in the
airport even there is ways to pack it
and if your medical marijuana patient in
California to fly and figure that one
out for yourself i'm not going to
encourage that but you're not supposed
to i'm going to leave all the medical
states out of that but the know you're
not supposed to leave Colorado with
Colorado marijuana products you're
really not supposed to do that I
shouldn't encourage you in any way even
if you're going to California if you're
going to [ __ ] Washington we fall into
it and laws and procedures because I've
seen people you know four cups bring
right abstention amounts just in their
in their backpacks you know so there is
forms and procedures go to that if you
really want to do it but you're not
going to be like can I bring my quarter
home to Kentucky no you shop at
dispensaries this guy says when people
come in we're all about safety and state
compliance and we make sure that the
out-of-state consumers are aware that
there he says then are aware that
they're purchasing their okay I this is
written weird but it says there is for
in-state consumption only we also remind
them that they can't do it in public is
that true to the shops remind you that
stuff when you're there because you have
an out of state ID um a few of them have
not all of them um it just really
depends on how busy you know if they're
having a slow day they'll chatty chat
you up a little bit but if there's 10
people in the waiting room they're not
there they're not informing you of
nothing there what you what you want
okay how much okay you can buy this much
and most you want to bind as much that's
what it really is most of the
recreational shops the pre-rolls are
actually just shake and [ __ ] and you
don't want it so I don't know just
lecture that once on the class you are I
just said [ __ ] does that count the
cust Arnel is that fair i F word and
check out the can of sewer in this
picture they have um I'm not I don't
endorse any dispensary honestly I'm not
paid I'm not sponsored by any dispensary
I don't shop it most dispensary in and I
hate let's see picture is the picture of
the can of sewer here has a picture
there
got a window cut out and you can see
into their grow room so if you are from
another state and you want to see a
pretty stylish looking grow room check
that out I don't I have or anything
about their bra tiny people it was cool
in this picture that very stylish and I
don't like I said I don't know what
their product is like if you go in there
and they tell you hey I apologize so I
somebody looks like i may be right about
that you can say that on my show you're
allowed to have an opinion bro no no no
I just out of 5 stars how many I've
never been there okay so I don't want to
give any rating all right I've just
heard stories all right yeah I've heard
a lot of stories as well that a lot of
the shops here I'm a meditation eighty
percent of our customers are coming from
out of state so that's a good article
there I thought you guys would be
interested let's click over back to the
recording and see how many hours we've
done weren't 30 minutes here we're going
to squeeze into more stuff you guys ah i
sent an email to jodie emery asking if
I'm allowed to play parts of a marc
emery video on a podcast and if I am I
plan to play a little bit of Mark speech
that he gave recently after he was
released from federal prison so I look
forward to doing that and he's a drink
excuse me one second Adam yeah I watched
this and actually linked it to him it
was it a powerful motivating speech he
is on the ball and if he does get you
know the permission to do it I won't
ruin it for me but it is everybody
should watch it you know and if it if it
doesn't inspire you to get over take a
risk and just play some of it I'm we can
or we can just talk kind of what it's
about you know I like I don't really
want to talk with life and innovative
let's uh you know the audio I don't
think we'll be in trouble for I really
don't wanna play video on YouTube you
don't and I mean let's click over here
and pause the music and then I think I'm
going to play a little bit of this video
I wasn't prepared to do it but we're
talking about it and it's like the thing
to do if you kind of play towards the
end of it it would kind of relay the
message more of it unless you want to
play the whole video later on how about
I'll play a couple of intro seconds when
he takes the mic he was introduced at
one point and he brought his friend back
on stage too that's good part ah he gets
introduced marc emery is introduced by
somebody else marc emery comes on stage
and gives thanks to another friend and
Mike to him that guy talks for about
eight minutes and then Marc Emery comes
back on stage and starts his little not
little his big speech we'll start with
two about 10 minutes and 25 seconds into
the video we'll start there I'm going to
give a shout-out to the YouTube page
that I'm playing it from I'm trying to
be polite or do you guys are asking
permission I haven't gotten an email
back saying yes or no yet but uh I'd
they're busy I feel like they let me do
it and it's jodie emery she's cool why
wouldn't she want marks preach the word
yeah and it's coming from pot TV on
YouTube it's on accountable cannabis
cultures website big shout out to all
those guys so please uh I subscribe to
you so I beg for your forgiveness if I
wasn't supposed to do this but I'm sure
you'd want this message out and then
we'll play a few seconds of it and then
we'll find out if we can play a lot of
it and if we can play a bunch will go
ahead and play but I would be a couple
of minutes of it for everyone yeah guys
I'm gonna take a drink will take some
dads i'll start off this marc emery
video this was kind of a weird
transition here that randomly happened
this is marc emery right after he I
think he's like 48 hours out of prison
when he did that absolutely 48 something
like that he said yeah here it goes i'm
gonna click playing i will have to
adjust the sound wall that goes on i
apologize we'll figure out on the toilet
fun to be me by and i even said that
while I was in prison because you know
doing something let's almost use the
word no both doing something on
principle late you know giving a good
chunk of your life in sacrifice i guess
for principle even in prison was highly
regarded you know in the four and a half
years I was in prison I really never
heard an unkind word spoken to me by any
inmate and I was in a medium-security
prison for almost all that and a lot of
these people are serving life
imprisonment without parole they've come
down from the penitentiary they're
covered in tattoos they're badass dudes
a lot of the Marlies they think they are
and and they're serving horribly long
sentences by and large for drugs mostly
methamphetamine crack cocaine but
certainly there were many many people
there for marijuana serving 10 15 and
even in one case 25 years for marijuana
distribution so I was able to be very
productive in jail I wrote a lot i
blogged I
read a book every week I had 25 magazine
subscriptions I got the new york times
every day I learned how to play the bass
guitar was in an outstanding rock and
roll band of incredibly talented
musicians and and all of them are very
patient in teaching me at no charge for
anything music and music principles and
how to be a bass guitarist and I must
tell you that it was a very redemptive
and meaningful experience being in
prison and i hope i always carry the
message forward that i saw there that
you know it is a very wrong society that
punishes people for drugs and put some
in jail for decades it takes them away
from their family and their children and
essentially ruins their life because of
a lifestyle choice they made and we
manufacture crime with the drug laws we
actually by kaz marc emery can talk
quite a while and i kind of fade out
Adams telling me that I should play the
stuff at the end of the video because
it's a lot more moving and compelling
I'm gonna save that I'm going to talk a
little bit i'm gonna make sure that i
can get permission that was about a
minute and a half there i hope i don't
get in any kind of trouble if they take
down this episode i apologize all it was
was some news in a marc emery rant
anyone you would echo way we cut that
out we'll fix it that's right good idea
to go watch the video the message the
message after he gets through this what
i did in jail stuff you know and I mean
that's moving trust me but his message
towards the end is definitely what you
need to hear and it's what we need to do
so take them take the video take 30
minutes and watch it ya feelin me up
well I was lying i apologize if they let
me play that all plays at last few
minutes at the end of this show here i'm
gonna wait for the email try to be
respectful and if i don't get the email
by the time I post the episode that's
then I won't do it I sorry so uh in
Denver ah part of this article I'm going
to kind of paraphrase it because it's a
lot of stuff enough so it's getting long
already I got a couple more things I
want to read about this is from the
cannabis tall so this was actually
published August twelfth that's by Aleta
lebec from the cannabis staff I didn't
say that right I'm sure but I'm sorry
this one is so governor Hickenlooper
John Hickenlooper
for placed these giant cages around
places in Denver he put one in front of
a skate park you put one in front of a
library in Denver the Denver Public
Library and their big cages that look
like your hamster cage and they call it
a lab rat cage it's a lab rat cage that
says don't be a lab rat and it's on the
inside it's got a little thing that
tells you about cannabis and the
problems that cannabis can cause you and
it's saying don't be a lab rat to
cannabis to encourage kids to not smoke
weed well if you put a big 12 foot tall
lab rat looking cage with the giant
looks like those water bottles that hang
upside down that your hamster licks to
get water and then it's got a little
green thing on the outside that talks
about cannabis on it a little note if
you want to come around on the side of
computer Brown take a look it's
definitely worth looking at it's funny
you am i right it looks just like a
people cage for hamsters or a hamster
cage for people's it is a people cage it
is a people cage and so the article says
well that didn't take long the state of
Colorado debuted don't be a lab rat
youth campaign on Monday August eleventh
by dropping human-sized laboratory cages
around the Denver area including outside
the Denver Public Library and the
downtown skatepark vandalize vandalized
signs at the skate park installation
reported Monday evening by CBS for the
cages featured posters it's like
controversial marijuana research studies
and ask open-ended questions about about
pot use about youth pot use sorry those
the heart sentence some cleverly crossed
out a reference to negative effects of
marijuana and changed it to positive
although another message left on the
poster says critically smoking weed
saved my life the campaign which targets
teens with messages that marijuana
research is ongoing particularly in
studies of studies of the developed
developing brain is trying a different
tact from the just say no anti-drug
campaigns of your there are a few
variations of the posters that adorn the
giant cages so a new message is sure to
replace the vandalized signs the
vandalism was taken in stride by dr.
Luri walk who leads the State Health
Department
if they are defacing it or they're doing
something with regard to graffiti or
gathering in the cages at least they're
taking notice and let the debate occur
but probably just breaking that [ __ ]
while they're smoking a joint to be
perfectly honest um there was also the
man who coked up inside the cage at the
skate park according to the TV station
report so somebody was but that's what I
think it is it's marijuana activist I
mean is Denver you know it's not like
there's not enough of you know obviously
people got off their ass and find you
know enough papers that it's legal here
you know the two million dollar project
which includes eight well I stylized
website is funded by a grand by a grant
paid by illegal sediments with
settlements with various pharmaceutical
companies according to the governor's
office another component of the don't be
a lab rat lab rat campaign are the TV
ads as seen below we're not going to
watch these stupid weird it shakes
pharma get off by telling you not to be
a lab rat what they meet they need your
money did I get they want you on zoloft
instead a weed but dude yep well ah
these most of our listeners probably
haven't seen these gigantic lab rat
cages it's quite entertaining they've
posted some three or four stories on the
cannabis about it we down there the
other day I would have liked you know
that a good idea we should have gone and
checked it out if you want to jump
around on this night again and take a
look there's actually people inside of
this one as they were building it
they're almost the email out of the way
that's that's the people cage they're
working with right there it's
essentially a lion cage from the zoo
yeah it's a lion it looks like a lion
cage it looks like a large cat small
enclosure there's that 10 x 10 x 10 x 10
x 10 yeah but then I don't even think
that it's probably 12 x 10 okay you know
saying it's probably longer than it is
wider but yeah and there's a lot of
scrutiny about how kind of ridiculous it
is to from a lot of people by the looks
of these websites so let me click and
see how long we're going on here in a
jail fill
I'm of them and just gonna keep moving
on with that one we are about 40 minutes
in so we can keep going I got a couple
we can make this a perfect our I bet if
we do this right all right all right
I'll try to save a couple of minutes for
the Marc Emery part if we get a chance
to do that so this is something random
and this only support i'm reading this
because this supports the legalization
the nationwide legalization and
decriminalization of cannabis the
headline will say it all for you new
hampshire declares state of emergency
over spice no [ __ ] right you know how to
cure that let us just smoke the weed we
want to smoke and put out of the most
fake spice a lot of that is probation
and and probation and prohibition and
job testing yep i mean i had personal
experience with this where people were
like oh no it's better than sex man you
gotta I've never and I was like all
right whatever and do that will never
again I was in the toilet for six hours
like hack and my lungs up felt like a
piece of [ __ ] young and don't an old
spice yeah guys didn't listen to my show
warp smokes yeah I know and hadn't
animal try anything twice yeah only did
spice once yep all right so I'm gonna
read some of it doesn't even seem like
we need this gets the point across right
yeah don't look and legalize I suggest
said [ __ ] somebody tweet me and tell me
to quit doing it I'm sorry guys I know
it's a senseless and the terrible words
we gotta quit doing there so it's kind
of obvious legalize cannabis and we
won't have to smoke they won't have to
smoke spice employers and probation some
probation you can't drink alcohol but
the employers don't care if you go out
at five o'clock or six o'clock or if you
go down to panic hour at six fifteen and
drink 22 beers your employer doesn't
care but if you smoke a fat joint man
you might get fired from your job which
is terrible I'll read part of this
governor Maggie Hassan has declared a
state of emergency to allow public
health officials to investigate and
quarantine synthetic drugs linked to
recent overdoses in Manchester and
Concord this is New Hampshire by the way
authorities say at least 41 people in
the Manchester area have experienced
serious medical reactions to synthetic
cannabinoid
known as spice that are chemically
engineered substances similar to the
active ingredient in marijuana let's
scrutinize this sentence just for fun ah
cannabinoid synthetic cannabinoids I
don't think that that's what that is it
is ah it's poser pot known as spice that
are chemically engineered that might
subcu mclean engineered substances
that's close i think active ingredient
in marijuana marijuana doesn't have
ingredients it's a compound I think is
what you want to call it there so come
on guys you're the cannabis brah
cannabis properly do you even cannabis
bro concord police have reported at
least three cases since Wednesday
Hassan's declaration gives the State
Department of Health and Human Services
the power to investigate quarantine and
require the destruction of the products
she says the department will work with
the police to quarantine the bubble gum
flavor of a product name smacked such
products are labeled as herbal incense
but are known to be smoked or brewed who
wants to take a product called smacked I
don't know I might take a dab of a
strain called smacked yeah but not a
spice I mean people have been doing this
for years but they put them in boilers
and and use them in rooms you know like
large rooms to give everybody that kind
of oh my gosh the frankincense myrrh has
been used under that an engine and what
if just for years everybody got grabbed
it by jabong and like yeah let's get
baked no they had herb for that because
it wasn't against the lawn then you know
it wasn't all around the world it still
looked at is something crazy and they
people aren't gonna try to get it one
way or the other well here's awesome
decently uplifting news Utah Medical
Marijuana Program 11 cards issued
several for child patients this is i'm
michelle l price of the associated press
in salt lake city utah issued nearly a
dozen registration cards in the first
month of its limited medical marijuana
program that allows those with severe
epilepsy to possess
cannabis extract oil this was August
ninth so this is kind of old news but i
just wanted to put out some news and
catch up as a friday evening the state
has issued 11 card since the program
started july eight said janice houston
the state registrar and director of the
Utah Department of Health's records
office about half of those 11 cars were
issued for child patients Houston said
an application for another card is
pending Health Department officials on
Friday also announced the four hundred
dollar annual annual fee for the cards
had been cut in half the program started
up fee were less than expected and the
registration cards will now cost two
hundred dollars Houston said ah there
there are 11 cards and one more being
applied for this new here hey I was at a
party the other night and there were
probably 11 medical marijuana cards in
the room yeah it's a huge relief that
Jennifer may with hope for children with
epilepsy we've been trying to find ways
to help the families come up with that
money along with the money for the oil
itself those who already paid the higher
fee will be refunded health officials
said Utah's law doesn't allow the
district distribution of medical
marijuana but it permits those meeting
certain requirements to possess the
extract after getting it from other
states so they can at least get what
they need to from Colorado wow man hey
yeah that's a step in the right
direction honestly you know the extract
this is goodbye yes frustrated they [ __ ]
up right here the extract called
cannabidiol okay maybe that's cuz there
look at that CBD but that's not the
extract the come on cannabis to please
the extract called cannabidiol is
believed to help with severe seizures
particularly those experienced by
children with severe with a severe form
of epilepsy um georgia is also looking
at that too close guys nice try the it's
not an extract called cannabidiol canna
vidiyal is a cannabinoid but one of the
cannabinoids in the extract but I see
what you're doing nice try guys you got
it that was that you've [ __ ] me up a
couple times on this article so the oil
doesn't have the psychoactive properties
they get users high and can be mixed
with foods such as applesauce
um I wonder if they'd be able to bring
back the og caps because those og calves
from essential extracts available at
natural mystic cannabis caregivers which
is a medical shop man so they're gonna
have to get a Colorado residency and get
a medical marijuana card in Colorado to
even acquire this type of medicine Utah
maybe not indifferent you know maybe
there's something a little more yeah
hopefully nowadays all right we'll keep
going the cost of cannon bitty all
varies depending on the size of the
patient and the level of the dose the
patient is receiving for
one-hundred-pound person a month supply
of the beginning dose is about 40 bucks
a maximum dose for the same patient
could cost up to nine hundred dollars a
month what they are talking about seems
to be Phoenix tears Rick Simpson oil
full plant cannabis extract full extract
cannabis oil it's only eaten it's black
usually or greenish colored they're not
talking about dads or anything so it's
basically Rick Simpson oil if you guys
are familiar with that there's a movie
called run from the Cure I believe is
what it's called race for the cure run
its run from the Cure of the Rick sent
to the store researchers from the name
Rick Simpson and then put cannabis oil
and you'll find the movie I'm talked
about learning about Rick Simpson oil a
lot of people say Rick Simpson may have
stolen that recipe and gotten famous off
of it I don't care yourself in a lot of
people do your thing shout out Rick
Simpson give thanks there we go into the
gift thanks section on accident the main
producer of the extract in Colorado has
a waiting list with thousands of names
and doesn't expect to have or supply
until fall and other producers of the
product have also also have a waiting
list may said because Utah's
registration cards expire year after
year many families are expected to apply
later this year that a hundred families
are expected to take advantage of Utah's
program Health Department officials said
may who's 12 year old son can suffer
hundreds of seizures a day that she and
many other families are also waiting to
see if they can secure a spot in a
pending drug trial by a neurologist at
Primary Children's Hospital in Salt Lake
City one families receive a registration
card it could face additional herders to
hurdles to actually get the extract from
other states including enrolling in that
state's medical marijuana program all
state marijuana programs medical or
otherwise are still illegal under
federal law
and some doctors and advocacy groups
have warned there's no proof the extract
is effective at treating epilepsy but
family say it's worth the time and cost
if it brings relief to those suffering
from seizures all right do you think
these people are gonna pay four hundred
dollars or now two hundred dollars to
get the medical marijuana card that they
require and then go spend money in
another state they're going to travel to
Colorado to get this oil that costs up
to nine hundred dollars for a freakin
dose of month does they're going to
drive from Colorado to Utah they're
going to spend a couple of hundred bucks
in gas they're going to spend a day away
they're probably traveling with a child
with seizures are they going to waste
and excuse this one are they going to
waste that [ __ ] time if this medicine
doesn't work if there's no no no there
must be something working right there's
a there's that documentary that link do
not that long ago that literally you
watch these people up route their life
they come out here and they try it I'm
pretty sure I've seen that one yet then
they go back to their home state in
their home states giving them a point
zero or zero point something CBD value
and they had to uproot their lives and
move to Colorado I mean there's a
million stories like it all over you
know if you don't stone here and you can
pretty much find what they're calling
the marijuana refugees yeah so it's hard
man and it absolutely okay this dude's
the story you just read said half the
people we get are coming from out of
state yeah like a haven eleventy why
would why would people not come here to
help their children that is yeah in
desperate need or and working though
people are packing up their entire lives
and moving to another state because we
can offer them a medicine that is
obviously when there's flooding and I'm
not going to do don't work for everybody
yeah the union was the first time I ever
saw that brings the guys that have who
he's all shaky and I don't mean to be
rude about he's really shaky and they
smoke and it was gone yep he goes right
back to not shaky so well we got time
for one more quick news article Seattle
pot tickets one cop wrote eighty percent
of citations what were they calling that
one guy out there in California when it
really boomed there was it was hot out
there you know who I'm talking
that was just standing outside of pot
shops like right and people citation
yeah and remember his name but yeah so
this is from seattle a seattle police
officer has been reassigned after review
after a review found he wrote about
eighty percent of marijuana tickets
issue in the city during the first half
of 2014 Seattle Police Chief Kathleen
O'Toole said 30 or said July 30 on the
department website that the unidentified
officer issued 66 of the 83 citations
for public pot use in Seattle she says
that in some cases he added notes to the
tickets or addressed them to seattle
City Attorney Pete Holmes another case
the officer reportedly said he flipped a
coin when deciding which person to cite
O'Toole says the officer also wrote on
the voter-approved state initiative
legalizing recreational marijuana was
silly the police chief said that the
case has been referred to the
department's official of professional
accountability she says the officer
won't be on patrol duties during the
investigation um big middle finger to
that cop so I gotta say about that one
just hatin yeah let some people you know
if you don't eat man another story maybe
they had something crazy may be right
maybe we'd killed their dad or something
I get too bad that have ever happened
you know I don't know I'm just saying
we'd never killed anybody to hire that
and that but I'm the only way that you
can be killed by day marijuana the only
man be killed by cannabis as there's a
bunch of it falls on top of you or if a
cop beats you up for having it at I'm
sayin maybe her death they're crushed
five thousand by crushed by tons of weed
yeah imagine that Spanky death who's got
a lighter would all be you're thinking
about just burn this on top of me
nothing nothing horrible i'm not saying
like he smoke to join you guys you know
i'm saying this i'm just gonna wrap that
part of the start alright guys we have
gone we're pretty close to an hour now
so i'm not sure if they are going to let
me play more of that marc emery video if
they do it'll happen here
I mean that's that's if you told me mark
you're going to spend the next 25 years
you know smoking joints and bongs and
selling seeds and you're going to go to
jail for many many years of your life
but one day after 25 years have you been
arrested if you go to jail if you've
been taken away of you losing all your
assets of you being separated from your
family and your wife after all that
you're going to have one day one day in
2015 and if you can get your people
together it all ends on that day on that
day the next day after that day the
stores will start selling marijuana
people will walk the streets confident
about the marijuana in their pocket they
are not going to get arrested there will
be medical marijuana science experiments
and advancements every day after that
because it'll be legal to study
marijuana in universities it'll be legal
for doctors to recommend it it'll be
legal for doctors judges cops
politicians to smoke it and share it and
understand it it'll be legal to go and
buy it it'll be legal for ordinary
people to grow it it'll be legal for
people to have a business that grows
marijuana it'll be legal for everybody
to make vaporizes and bongs all the
books and magazines about marijuana will
all be legal no one will ever try and
ban them ever again no one will ever say
a bad thing about pot smokers as a
culture as a way of demonizing them and
sending them to jail because mark in 25
years that one day everybody showed up
and it was a happy wonderful world ever
since because everybody showed up so
that's my message we've got a big
opportunity coming at 14 months I'm
going to be touring the country will
endlessly telling everybody even in
other countries you just need one day
where everybody we know who smoked pot
shows up that'll be my message in
Ireland it'll be my message in Spain it
will be my message in Vienna it can be
managed all across Canada and it's
certainly my message to all Americans
who go to vote in Oregon and I
ask in Florida and Washington District
of Columbia on the first tuesday in
november if you show up you'll never
need to think about this ever again
you'll just be allowed to enjoy you'll
be allowed to be part of a culture that
ought to be the one of the most
respected cultures in the history of
mankind because i'll tell you this the
cannabis culture is given more to
humanity and mankind humankind in
science and entertainment and theater
and arts books and culture and
especially in music than any other
culture of the last hundred years the
cannabis culture is one of the greatest
cultures in the history of mankind
strong with William Shakespeare who
smoked marijuana cannabis actually you
know so many great poets and writers and
musicians and scientists and doctors and
explorers and to this day our movers and
shakers spill jobs there sorry bill
gates even jobs pot smokers you know
Carl Sagan pot smoker every musician
you've ever cared to really enjoy a pot
smoker most of the people right today's
great bestsellers and make today's great
movies or pot smokers including actors
and we are a great culture but we have
been denied our official right to be
regarded as first-class citizens like
everybody else who makes contributions
and who ought to be acknowledged as as a
culture that's so if they told me 25
years ago mark it's going to be a long
road with a lot of difficulties but one
day in 2015 one day it all becomes real
if you can get your people to show up so
that's my message thanks very much i
look forward to parting with you tonight
[Music]
[Applause]
alright guys that was Marc Emery that
video came from the pot tv youtube
channel i need to give a big shout-out
to jodie emery she emailed jody and she
gave me permission to use these videos
so we got to give them a big thanks i
also need to give a big shout-out to
cannabis culture calm if you want some
great cannabis news if you're online and
not able to listen to a podcast to make
sure you check out cannabis culture calm
there's a lot of videos and updates from
mark also go to youtube and check out
the pot TV channel there are a lot of
great marc emery videos i will start
i'll try to play some more emery videos
at the end of the episodes that are
short that way we can fill in a little
time if the episodes are long I won't
put that in there we'll just try to get
them closer to an hour alright guys I'm
high and rambling so let's get back to
the regular part of the show thanks for
listening to Marc Emery support those
guys so uh hey on a boobie made it
through a whole nother episodes thanks
for hanging out with me Thank You makeup
you think it's a little bit smoother as
better than we sit here talk to myself
and looking at the wall like I'm left
with the senex I appreciate it and yeah
like always anytime you need working
these guys find you on the Twitter
overthrow to go on Twitter and then I to
website for 20 s com I've never checked
out that website guys so games and fun
no it's nothing it's nothing bad highly
defensive i apologize you can find all
of our Twitter's and all that big shout
out to my homie bender you can work as
hard on the server successful on being
square of yourself we want to come play
some video games with donors come on
there you go who doesn't want to play
video games with stoners guys you can
find me at I read genetics on instagram
at I grow culture on instagram at
agriculture on Twitter agriculture has a
facebook you can email us this I grow
culture at hotmail com I got to give a
huge shout out to DJ make a tea that was
playing in the background big shout out
then she let me play the summit turn up
the electronic dance hall music vol 1
it's not even on the screen anymore and
I remembered it so much respect the DJ
making tea follow him on soundcloud and
now that the show is over
so should i do this watch just in case
all right guys and that was a little
speech for Marc Emery thanks for
listening to that ahead if not now that
the show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search try to a
culture by the review section it was a
five star rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I'll leave your comments on
the show and I'm really seriously got
back I've you're listening to us on
stitcher to leave a comment there and
give us a good review all of those
reviews help is a show move up in the
rankings which in turn to get us more
listeners and I want to spread my
message to everyone who wants to grow
and wants to learn more about cannabis
this is an important message to spread
don't forget that the show is available
on itunes stitcher and every single
episode is on I read genetics Colorado
calm the huge shout-outs my ninja spin
thanks again for listening you guys take
a fat dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]