[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 278 the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated batter if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross - Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band Coletti means their
music on my podcast
big thanks to cat coop and the entire
mystic roots crew
thanks again for joining everybody I
hope you're having a great evening
daytime night times whatever time it is
wherever you are hope you're having a
great one I hope you're smoking on
something delicious then you got a fat
joint rolled up maybe you're taking a
fat dab I just took a giant dab of some
Tahoe og batter mixed with pura vida' oh
gee batter the Tahoe og tastes amazing
hey guys but it just doesn't give me the
high that I want it's kind of mellow it
kind of chills me out which is cool but
I want a little more from it but the
taste is amazing so I've been mixing the
Tahoe og with the pura vida'
and taking good-size dabs of that the
pura vida' makes me forget where I am I
makes me forget what I'm doing so mixing
the pura vida' and the Tahoe it's a
super turkey combo super great head high
super nice body high nice and chilled
out murder you do a great podcast anyway
I hope you're smoking on something
delicious all right let's start off this
podcast by jumping right into it you
guys I've got a brand new itunes comment
um it's a rating and a review as what it
is they're on iTunes I would love it if
you guys would leave me some ratings and
reviews the way you can do so is go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the girl from your heart podcast scroll
down about halfway you'll see a picture
it's a red yellow and green flag with my
face on it it's the girl from your heart
podcast logo click right on there then
we'll take you to the podcast page in
the middle of that page is a spot where
it says ratings and reviews that is
where you are able to leave me a rating
and a review so far everybody has left
at five star review and also let me
screw up to the top and make sure I'm
not lying to you because there was one
you know what they took down no there's
one four star review I have got 77
ratings 76 of them are five stars one is
a four star rating anyway leave me the
amount of stars that you feel I deserve
and type in a little customer review and
I will read your customer review on a
future episode let's get into reading
the most recent this one came in on
November 29th it's from a person who
calls themselves farmer Dan 831 the
headline of the customer review goes
like this best info you can find and
then this is what farmer Dan 831 had to
say I love your show Rasta Jeff got the
whole crew hooked on your show we're
listening to you as we harvest one of
our rooms for live resin keep it real
man good vibes your way hey farmer Dan
thanks for listening thanks for getting
the whole crew addicted to the podcast
and also and thanks for putting some
live resin out there I kind of want to
know where you work who do you work for
what company are you making live resin
for and can I try it I'd like to go pick
up a gram somewhere and see what you are
making all right that's the only iTunes
comment I have got for now feel free to
leave me more iTunes ratings and reviews
I would truly appreciate that and also I
want to give a huge thanks to all of the
people who have left iTunes ratings and
customer reviews in the past thanks
everybody
I appreciate that all right let's work
our way into another topic you guys this
is a little bit not cannabis related but
it is internet related and since my
podcast is an internet-based show I feel
that this topic may or may not affect
you Endor I in the future and I kind of
wanted to bring it up on the podcast so
today the FCC officially they repealed
net true net neutrality rules now let me
explain a little bit about what net
neutrality is and I'm just gonna read
basically from Wikipedia and tell you
what wikipedia says about net neutrality
and then we'll talk a little bit about
it it says net neutrality is the
principle that Internet service
providers must treat all data on the
internet the same and not discriminate
or charge differently by user content
website platform application type of
attached equipment or method of
communication for instant instance under
these principles internet service
providers are unable to intentionally
block slowdown or charge money for
specific websites and online content
gonna skip a little bit and then here's
another part that's important for us it
says a widely cited example of a
violation of net neutrality principles
was the internet service provider
Comcast secrets slowing of uploads from
peer-to-peer file sharing applications
by using forged packets Comcast did not
stop blocking these protocols like
BitTorrent until the Federal
Communications Commission ordered them
to stop in another minor example the
Madison River communications company was
fined $15,000 by the FCC in 2004 for
restricting their customers access to
Vonage which was rivaling their own
services so basically you guys what net
neutrality did yeah what net neutrality
did was made it illegal for folks like
Comcast AT&amp;T Verizon or whoever else you
can think of to alter their internet
service based on your usage or their
preferences right now if you live in the
United States of America and you are not
in an institution and you have public
Internet your internet is wide open you
were able to look at whatever you would
like you can look at AOL you can look at
Disney you can look at Animal Planet but
also you can go to High Times comm and
look at cannabis you can go to your
favorite adult website and look at
whatever you're into there you can do
whatever you want on the internet right
now when net neutrality becomes a thing
your internet service provider will get
to decide what you may or may not look
at they may decide that if you want the
adult package if you if your content is
considered adult if you're looking at
cannabis if you're looking at adult
themed things if you're looking at
anything they feel may be adult they can
put a surcharge on that for you and
charge you money right now it's
currently illegal but now that the
restrictions have been lifted they are
going to be allowed to do this once all
of these rules and laws are worked out
now what concerns me is I like giving
you guys a free podcast I like getting
my show out is it going to cost me more
money to upload my show because they
have mentioned people that use large
uploads are going to possibly have to
pay for more more for their internet
they say that people that download large
files may have to pay more for their
internet as your internet service
provider going to give you podcasts for
free is my internet service provider
going to allow me to upload these
podcasts with no extra charge those are
all things we're going to have to face
here in the future and figure out with
the changing of net neutrality now I'm
sure a lot of companies will rally and
try to sue and hopefully somebody has a
really good lawyer and they can cert a
lawsuit to stop net neutrality from
being lifted but in other countries like
Canada and Chile and Brazil it's a thing
and we all know that North Korea and
China are already limiting their
internet you can only see a few websites
there you can't access all the popular
stuff there and if you're caught
accessing it you are committing a crime
and you will be punished so
learn what you can from the internet
right now you guys get what you can
because things are changing I don't know
what's coming people can't predict
what's coming because this is a brand
new thing but things are going to change
you know most of the articles I read
said that it was going to be a couple of
weeks before the changes roll out so I
hope we don't see too drastic of a
change I hope we don't end up paying for
simple internet paying more for basic
internet we're already paying for
Internet service I don't want to have to
pay imagine if they made it like a cable
package okay you can get basic internet
you can check out Facebook you can check
out Animal Planet you can check out all
that but if you want to go on the
Premium Package it's gonna be an extra
nine ninety-five a month imagine if they
start doing that [ __ ] to you and then
you're not gonna know what you're not
getting until you're not able to get it
and then you're gonna have to add that
to your package how weird would it beats
and not have access to the whole
internet and not even know it because
you don't know that that's there because
you can't even go to it now imagine if
you had Comcast is it okay let's even go
better imagine if you had AT&amp;T as a
service provider so AT&amp;T is who you pay
your bill to AT&amp;T is who your service is
through they are the ones that get to
decide what you get to see now perhaps
there's something really cool going on
that is sponsored by Verizon your
favorite band is doing a cool-ass show
they're doing it live feed but it's
sponsored by Verizon guess what [ __ ] you
AT&amp;T listeners you don't get to watch it
because you're on a different Internet
and we're not even going to allow you to
see the Verizon [ __ ] so [ __ ] you that's
how it's gonna be people are gonna be
left out of stuff you're not gonna be
able to get to see things your friend
with them with an iPhone and your other
friend with an Android you're going to
have different Internet's so you're not
going to be able to see the same stuff
imagine this and this is just my small
mind thinking this I'm not a capitalist
business person but imagine when you go
to a concert if you go to the Verizon
Wireless Center the only internet that's
going to work there will be Verizon
Internet all the ads anything from AT&amp;T
Comcast cricket whatever else phone
companies are I don't even know all
those other ads will be blocked
everything will just be Verizon Wireless
approved content so even and then if you
go to the AT&amp;T or the Qualcomm Center
everything's gonna be filtered by them
the internet you're allowed to use on
your phone while you were in the Verizon
Wireless Sentra will be filtered even
though you are an adult I'm sure they
will filter it that way nobody can be
looking at any adult [ __ ] or any band
[ __ ] or something from a rivaling entity
while you're in their facility that's
what this is gonna do this is just the
start I've got a very narrow mind when
it comes to capitalizing on stuff like
this I can only imagine what some folks
in some suits and some ivory towers with
a bunch of money are trying to do to
[ __ ] us over a little bit more right now
so the internet may change you guys I
didn't grow up with the Internet so to
see the internet happen when you first
heard about it you're like wait you
could put your computer you plug a phone
line in your computer and talk to other
people on other computers sounds kind of
weird but it sounds kind of fun also but
also at the same time I was like I've
got a phone why do I want to type out a
bunch of [ __ ] they're like because you
can go in a chatroom and talk to like 15
different people at once and learn a
bunch of cool [ __ ] whoa I was like oh no
the Internet and then the internet went
from just like simple chat rooms to like
everybody had a website and then it got
interactive and then social media
happened
social media wasn't a thing when I was a
kid you guys all you youngsters that
wasn't a real thing I feel like grandpa
telling stories right now but social
media wasn't a thing when I was young if
he wanted to find friends you need to
[ __ ] go somewhere if you wanted to
know what your neighbor was doing he had
to go there knock on the [ __ ] door
and find out what he was doing if you
wanted to know what your best friend was
doing you had to call him go he Chris
what are you doing bro like you didn't
just jump on Facebook and see what
everybody was [ __ ] bitching about all
at once it was way different so I saw no
internet
I saw chat rooms I saw all of the
companies get a website I saw
everybody's website suck and then I saw
everybody not
a compatible website and then I saw
websites get good and then I saw
everybody start openly talking about
internet porn it just became a thing and
then internet porn lost it's funny and
it's stigma now everybody just talked
about internet porn like it's just
common now it went from like internet
porn to now it's just internet porn
then it went to all the social media got
crazy then everybody had a YouTube
channel and then the internet became
what it is today
if you want to know something if you
have an idea it's on the internet if you
want to watch a video about something if
you want to see somebody do something if
you want to learn about something it's
on the Internet all of it and one of the
best parts about it was there was no
limit because there was no rules so you
could learn about things that you should
probably not be learning about but
you're gonna do it anyway so it's best
to learn it the best you can so you
don't [ __ ] up but now you won't be able
to find all those cool things you won't
be able to watch all that creepy [ __ ]
you may have to pay for a different
package but I saw it I saw it when it
was some creepy dark thing that had no
rules
I remember overgrow the Gov and a whole
bunch of other cannabis related websites
where we used to all go tell secrets and
trade seeds and try to impress each
other with our bud shots before it was
safe to just go post your entire grow
room up on Facebook and Instagram I
remember it ladies and gentlemen the
Internet will forever be different that
was a podcaster it's my duty to do my
best to make sure that my podcast is
available in as many ways as possible as
many places as possible as many formats
as possible in case something does
happen to where people are forced to pay
for it I want you to be able to access
my podcast for free so I'm gonna try to
stay on top of that I don't know what's
going on with net neutrality more than
what I've told you it's a lot of stuff
to take in if something does happen
where you are not able to listen to my
podcast for free send me a message and
we will figure something out if I've got
to send you the file we'll do that I
want everyone to be able to listen to
this podcast for free I will figure out
a way to get this show out to everybody
that's my commitment to you guys I love
podcasting I love cannabis I love my
friends I love helping my friends grow
better cannabis through podcasting so
I'm gonna keep at it I'm gonna make sure
you guys are able to listen there's
always a way around some babble on
[ __ ] rules and I'll make sure my
friends could hear the podcast all right
I feel like I've been talking about net
neutrality for a long time I'd like to
hear your comments
I'd like your input send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
or send me a tweet at GF wih podcast on
the tweeters alright let's move forward
a little bit ladies and gentlemen we are
in the era of cannabis legalization and
medical marijuana and recreational
marijuana but just because we have rules
that allow us to dispense consume and
medicate and recreation all of the above
with cannabis does not mean that we can
ignore the rules the rules were made the
rules are in place and we have to follow
the rules I want to read an article that
I found on the cannabis this has been
the talk of Colorado today one of the
most popular Kent's a most popular a
very well-known a chain of dispensaries
was raided this morning and eight
locations were raided and eleven Denver
area sweet leaf stores were closed and
26 of their licenses have been suspended
I wanted to tell you guys about it I
found the article well written on the
cannabis it is written by AH
Alicia Wallace from the cannabis to
staff I'm gonna read the whole article
that goes like this police raid ate
sweet leaf marijuana center locations in
Denver and Aurora all eleven Denver area
sweet leaf stores are closed and it's 26
licenses have been suspended Denver
police on Thursday rated eight sweet
leaf marijuana center locations in
Denver and Aurora and arrested twelve
people as part of a year-long
investigation into illegal marijuana
sales yes this dispensary was
participating in allegedly I have to say
allegedly I'm not a lawyer I wasn't
there I'm not part of the investigation
I can't prove [ __ ] allegedly this
dispensary was illegally selling
cannabis which could include a lot of
things the article doesn't tell us what
they may have been doing I will let you
guys know what I feel like may have been
happening it goes like this the criminal
activities alleged include sale of
cannabis and violation of the one ounce
per person per day limits established
under Colorado marijuana law Denver
police officials said in a statement
all right so in Colorado a recreational
cannabis shopper is allowed to buy one
ounce per person per day now I did not
know that it said per day because there
are some dispensaries that will let you
come back later
obviously sweetleaf was letting too many
people do that and they've gotten
themselves in trouble so I'm gonna say
it right here if you work for a
dispensary it says clearly right here
one ounce per person per day
I don't know that Ricardo are let's see
who wrote this article again I don't
know that Alicia Wallace knows all of
the laws and rules on cannabis but it
looks like that's what got this place in
trouble so if your dispensary is selling
is letting a customer shop drive to
another dispensary and then come back to
your store or visit within the same day
you were breaking the rules you're going
to get in trouble
check with your compliance officer to
check with your management and see if
this is a practice that should not be
happening in your store and if it is you
may want to consider cutting that off
I've seen it done I'm not gonna call out
any dispensaries that have done it but
there are several recreational
dispensaries that will allow you to come
back multiple times in the day and we're
not gonna do that anymore you guys stop
that one visit per day otherwise it
looks sketchy there are rules in place
these people are getting trouble for
breaking them so you're allowed to buy
one ounce per person per day and now the
criminal activities allege that these
folks were violating that rule the
Denver Police Department of X Ison
license in concert with the police
action suspended 26 licenses for medical
retail cultivation and extraction
operations that conduct business as
sweetleaf said Dan Rowland's spokesman
for the X ice and license department the
suspension order stated reasonable
grounds and probable cause exists to
believe that respondents have engaged in
deliberate and willful violations of
state and local laws or regulations and
and/or that the public health safety and
welfare requires emergency action at
this point in the articles I'm scrolling
through there's a picture of the door at
sweetleaf with a nice little handwritten
note that says sorry we are closed and
then a very well printed letter from
it's hard to read because it's kind of
small it says City and County of Denver
Department of X ice and taxes with the
big Denver official logo
notice of suspension and bright red then
the following text is in black it says
medical and/or retail marijuana licenses
for these premises have been suspended
by order of the Denver department of
excise and licenses for alleged Colorado
or for alleged violations of Colorado
law and that is prominently displayed on
the front door it sweet leaf dispensary
and it is the location at 20
6:09 Walnut Street is where this photo
came from
shout out to Alex who took the photo
sorry I cannot pronounce your last name
but I'll give you some credit cool photo
that's gonna be legendary good shot Alex
so the article goes on to say like this
all sweetleaf stores in Colorado ten in
denver and one in aurora were closed
thursday names of the 12 people arrested
were not immediately released they were
being booked into the downtown detention
center police said the operation was
conducted after a criminal investigation
into the illegal distribution of
marijuana at eight locations the alleged
criminal violations were related to the
sale of marijuana in excess of allowable
amounts established by amendment 64
which allows for the personal use of
marijuana
according to police department news
release no other marijuana businesses
were included in the rates the police
said sweetleaf representatives said in
an e-mailed statement that they were
surprised by police raids it is unclear
at this point exactly what actions if
any sweetleaf took to cause the city to
issue this order the statement said
sweetleaf is cooperating with the
authorities to resolve this issue and
hopes to have all of their stores back
in operation
as soon as possible it was not
immediately clear to what extent sweet
leaves facilities were affected beyond
Denver and Aurora
although the Aurora store was a raided
was raided and no one answered the
locations phone on Thursday the city has
not suspended sweet Leafs business
license for its East sixth Avenue store
said Julie Patterson and Aurora sport
spokeswoman we are waiting to receive
more information from police
investigators to determine whether we
need to take any action oh man imagine
being an employee at that store you're
just a sitting duck shaking all day like
[ __ ] are they coming are they coming are
they coming I bet some people are not
going to work tomorrow like yeah we
might be open but I'm not showing the
[ __ ] up for my shift
I wouldn't go to work tomorrow and [ __ ]
that no I'm done with like worrying
about police raids and [ __ ] and worrying
about cops and someone kicking in the
door going to jail doing [ __ ] legit I
work for a legitimate company that
doesn't do stuff like this I would not
[ __ ] show up for work tomorrow if I
worked at the East 6th Avenue location
[ __ ] that I would be taking a sick day
like a [ __ ] you can already tell
my throat sounds like [ __ ] I would not
be at work tomorrow if this
alright now let's continue at the
article it says sweet leaves dispensary
in Portland Oregon remained open a
person who answered the store's phone
said the employee said snore officials
declined to comment the coordinating
coordinated enforcement action was
solely a Colorado agency effort headed
by Denver police which partnered with
the Aurora Police Department Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division Denver
District Attorney's Office Denver City
Attorney's Office in Denver department
of excise and licenses and Denver
Department of Public Health that's a lot
of people to have come in knocking on
your door the US Drug Enforcement
Administration was not involved in the
operation spokesman Randy Ladd said and
then they list all the sweetleaf
locations that were raided just in case
you're interested 1474 south Acoma
2647 West 38th 5,100 West 38th 4400 East
Evans 2609 Walnut Street 41 25 North
alladhi I don't know if I said that
right ela TI street and 7200 East Smith
Road so I was right right in my
assumption they were selling more
cannabis than they should have been
selling to each customer so you guys
check this out if you are not from
Colorado or even if you are from
Colorado and you go to a dispensary and
you're that guy that's like and you're
shopping recreationally or even
medically and you're asking somebody to
bend or break a rule and you are a dick
because they won't break the rules
because they are a well-trained
trustworthy employee this is why they
are not breaking the rules these guys
lost eight dispensaries let's see I want
to scroll up and read how many licenses
they lost cuz it was crazy eight places
got raided eleven stores were closed and
26 licenses have been suspended because
somebody in this company said that it
was okay to break rules and create major
violations now the whole company is
being shut down everybody from the
growers to the trimmers to the bud
tenders to the managers to the CEOs
they're all on hold right now there
might not be a business nobody knows
what's going on with these licenses
until they have their hearings usually
these hearings happen within I think
it's about 30 days they have to be heard
and everybody goes to court and talks
about this but until this happens the
growers don't know where their paycheck
comes from the trimmers don't know where
their paycheck comes from
everyone's in the in a scramble so they
got greedy they tried to make extra
money they tried to break some rules and
all they did was totally [ __ ] themselves
26 licenses you guys licenses are not
cheap if you [ __ ] up with the license
and they find out they find that you
were incapable of properly handling a
license and conducting business like an
adult they will take your [ __ ]
license from you and I don't know what
happens to it they sell it or you have
to sell it to somebody else or something
but you're not allowed to hold a
marijuana license a business license for
any type of cannabis related business
anymore they can do that who knows
what's gonna happen with these
businesses who knows there are bud
tenders that are not at work there's a
one location open tomorrow and I don't
know that those employees are gonna want
to go to work they're probably paranoid
and worried they know there's a whole
company shutdown millions of dollars you
guys millions of dollars millions I
don't I couldn't even fathom how many
millions of dollars come with 26
licenses so they say eight sweetleaf
marijuana Center locations there's 8
locations shut down but there are 26
licenses which means there are eight
dispensaries there probably 10 grows
that puts it 18 and then like maybe 8
MIPS which would be where they make
edibles or where they make concentrates
mips is medically infused products is
what that license is MIP and that's
where you can do extractions it they're
all specialized it's either a kitchen or
a lab or whatever but so yeah they
probably had eight dispensaries 10 grows
it puts you at 18 and then however
whatever else I said eight more would be
MIPS or whatever I'm just guessing I
don't know what they really are but 26
licenses have been taken away so many
people are gonna be [ __ ] you guys so
when you go to the dispensary and the
budtender won't break the rules or won't
bend the rules or won't sell you extra
or won't hook you up or you don't have
the proper ID and they tell you no this
is why you guys we would like to keep
our businesses we would like to be
employed it is the middle of December
and now there are a bunch of people that
we're probably counting on that next
paycheck that they're gonna make over
the next week
to cover some Christmas gifts to cover
something people already spent money I'm
sure because it's Christmas time and
we're [ __ ] humans we don't plan ahead
we just spend money that we don't have
because the TV tells us that it's okay
because just spend that money and so
they did I bet you they did now these
people are gonna be [ __ ] because they
don't have a job
so stop breaking the rules stop asking
people to break rules and look here is
an example there are rules in Colorado
we're not just it's not the Wild West
anymore for you people that may think
we're just out here slinging dope and
nobody cares
there are rules doors got kicked in
licenses were taken away people are in
jail alright I've got one more little
piece I want to add to this before I
wrap up this segment of the show this
was from the westward which is uh if
you're not from Colorado the westward is
like a little local paper it's the hip
cool color paper with all the ads in it
and all the local stuff it tells you
about all the cool shows coming up it
tells you about all the art that's
happening and then the back three pages
are all ads and coupons for dispensaries
in Denver but they put out a great
magazine I think monthly and they also
have a website and sweetleaf sent them a
message and it's an official assert a
ssin from corporate and westward posted
it and it says this morning sweet leaf
was surprised to receive notification
from the from the department of excise
and license suspending all of our city
licenses in the City and County of
Denver it is unclear at this point
exactly what actions if any sweet leaf
took to cause the city to issue this
order sweet leaf is cooperating with the
authorities to resolve this issue and
hopes to have all of their stores back
in operation as soon as possible yeah it
said that they were cooperating of
course they're cooperating twelve people
are in jail now I'm curious are those
people
owners are they corporate it doesn't say
I've been researching everything I can
find so far at the time of this
recording the people arrested have not
been processed they are still in booking
in the Denver jail the Denver I don't
know the Denver City Denver County Jail
they're still being processed so I can't
find any information on who it was what
I'm curious about is where they bud
tenders where they manage me where they
owners were they where were they in the
food chain of the company because
honestly I don't know I know there is a
rule in place and I have to ask we got
to get white Mike in on this one there's
a rule that says if somebody commits a
crime in the dispensary that it's either
the management's responsibility or the
actual like if a budtender sells
somebody illegally
I think the budtender can actually
legally be held responsible but I'm not
certain so I think the bud tenders made
the ones detained I'm not sure when I
find out I will let you guys know on a
future episode all right so I took a
second and contacted a compliance
officer who knows a lot about the
marijuana Enforcement Division rules and
regulations and they told me yes if a
budtender is caught violating a rule
they will be arrested and charged but
they also stated they doubt that's what
happened in this case they said there's
more to this case that they can't talk
about right now and they will talk to me
in person because we were just texting
so they're an insider they're in the
industry they know a lot of people I'll
find out some stuff and then I'll see
what I can share with you but it is not
what it looks like is what I can say
after reading that whole article and
then talking with my friend it doesn't
appear to be what it looks like this is
a different thing than what I thought
and what the reporters have all said so
far so I'll find out if there's anything
else I can share with you guys and then
I will let you know as soon as I've got
some more information all right I'm
running out of time and my throat is
starting to get a little bit funky but I
want to read one email and then we're
going to wrap up this podcast I know
there wasn't a whole lot of very
specific cannabis education this time
but the theme of the show is cannabis
news education and conversation you've
got some news and conversation for sure
I think the last episode was very uh
education based so we're evening [ __ ]
out I hope you like it
alright so this email goes like this it
says hey Jeff been a longtime listener
of the podcast so much good information
to learn from and I appreciate you
putting it out there well you're very
welcome thanks for the email it goes on
to say the reason I'm writing is I would
like to possibly get a hold of some of
your seeds and was wondering if you
could shoot me in the direction as to
where to find some yes Google the hell a
dank seed company or go to dank seed dot
store and you will be able to find seeds
if you type in hell a dank seed bank IRA
genetics you will be golden hella dank
seed bank is the place I recommend today
or you can always check my friends out
at the dank team.com the dank da NK
team.com the dank team comm check
hella dank seed bank or the dank team
comm or two great places to get IRA
genetics seeds let's see the email goes
on to say I will be road trippin around
Colorado in a couple of weeks so
destination is not much
a concern when did you write this this
was a while ago that trip party happened
there hope you had a good time I
apologize for missing you I'm just going
through e old emails and catching up he
says specifically I would like to find
some lemon Geoffrey golden goat or a
rise the arises available the golden
goat won't be available for a long time
the lemon Geoffrey is not available by
itself but it is available in the form
of lemon sunrise which is lemon Jeffrey
crossed to the arrives so that's
available at the dank team and the hell
a dank seed bank the email goes on to
say I know you recently mentioned that
you don't care the massive feminized
seeds but if there are any feminized
seeds of these strains floating around I
would like to get my hands on them ah
there are no more golden goat or lemon
Jeffrey feminized seeds available right
now that may change in the future but
currently that's not a thing a rise is
currently not available in a feminized
seed form so no feminized seeds right
now from me although I will be making a
new line of feminized seeds very soon
I'm going to reverse a male a female
plant and turn it into a male I'm gonna
pollinate a few things I will test run
those if I like what comes out of those
I will do it again and put it into
production I was asked to do a favor for
somebody because they really liked a
strain and they wanted to play with
seeds of it so I am going to make s ones
of a strain I'll talk about it a little
more in the future but that's that's
what I'm doing with feminized seeds I've
got a whole new plant that I'm going to
be reversing I'm going to make a whole
new line of FEM stuff there will only be
about four or five crosses in the whole
line but those will be coming in a
little bit here I'm gonna get back to
this email and get my brain back focused
he says I hope to hear back from you and
keep up the good work on the podcast
hey thanks I'll keep up the good work I
apologize for taking forever
to get back to you with the emails I've
got a lot of emails obviously the email
goes on to say I lost my space here we
go it is by far one of my top three
right alongside Joe Rogan experience Wow
I'm in the top three right alongside Joe
Rogan so who else is up there I wonder
who number three is it's Joe Rogan
myself and who else do you have up there
I'm very curious and on it honestly it's
an honor every time somebody compares me
to Joe Rogan in podcasting or in any way
shape or form it's a [ __ ] honor
because Joe Rogan is an amazing
individual that man's a sad
there's never an insult to be compared
to Joe Rogan so thank you for that huge
compliment I'm glad that my podcast is
one of your favorites right alongside
Joe Rogan I listen to Joe Rogan kind of
religiously Rogan puts out three
sometimes four or five shows every week
and I listen to almost every second of
every show that that guy puts out that's
one of my favorite podcast so I'm glad
you dig it with me I'm glad we're
probably listening to the Joe Rogan
experience together sometimes during
long days at work man thanks for the
huge compliment
he also says PS you should do more
organic episodes on organic growing I
know it's not your thing but I'm sure
many listeners would enjoy hearing them
yes I would love to get more organic
episodes going I need to schedule some
more organic based growers to come and
be on the show with me I've just been
chaotic lately my schedule is hard to
nail down other people are hard to nail
down I need to reach out to some folks
and have them come be on the podcast and
talk about organics you were right the
email finishes up like this he says
thanks and if this makes it on your show
please don't mention my name all right
dude I won't mention your name but I do
want to give you a huge thanks for
sending me a great email for letting me
ramble on about getting some seeds I
hope your trip to Colorado was fun I
apologize for not linking up with you
and dude huge thanks for the compliment
I love hearing that I'm somebody's
favorite podcast but saying that I'm
right alongside the Joe Rogan experience
never gets old
alright you guys if you want to send me
an email I would love to hear from you
it's a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com
you never know I may read your email on
a future episode ladies and gentlemen
it's time for me to start wrapping up
this podcast I feel like I've been
talking superfast I've been rambling my
ass off I hope you enjoyed this episode
if you're listening on iTunes I hope you
go to iTunes and leave me a rating in a
review also I would love it if you find
me on all the social media interact with
me on Facebook find me at the girl from
your heart podcast you can find me on
Twitter at gfy each podcast also I would
love it if you follow me on Instagram I
use my other company name it's Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore GE
and ET ICS I read genetics on Instagram
please check me out there check out my
cannabis photography sometimes I do
Instagram live videos and I go on and
just talk about cannabis growing I let
the people and the live feed ask me
questions and then I just answered off
the top of my
had the best I can so if you want to
join me for that check me out on
Instagram its Irie underscore genetics
turn on your notifications when I go
live it'll tell you I'm there you can
hang out take some dad's with me if
you're not into this social media and
you've still got something to say of
course you can email me let's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com also there are
about a hundred and thirty videos on the
girl from your heart YouTube channel so
if you want to see old episodes numbers
1 through 130 are available on the girl
from your heart YouTube channel please
subscribe to that also I would
appreciate it if you check out patreon
patreon comm slash grow from your heart
if you feel like this podcast was worth
a couple of bucks please head over to
patreon comm and read all the
information you need to figure out how
to contribute to the podcast I'm not
trying to charge anybody for this
podcast this podcast will always be free
I do this out of out of my heart out of
my love for cannabis out of my love for
helping people out of wanting to make
cannabis legal worldwide out of being
able to help people grow smoke consume
enjoy be more educated everything
positive about cannabis that's why I do
this I love it I want people to grow a
better herb I want people to smoke
better herb I want people to feel better
because they're able to medicate and
read create with the best herb possible
I want to shine light on urban I'm gonna
do it free for you guys but my website
cost money my website is where I host my
podcast my microphone covers cost money
my water bottles cost money sometimes my
equipment [ __ ] up and it costs money
I'm not begging but if you'd like to
help me offset those costs if you're
able to do so patreon.com slash grow
from your heart is the way you can do it
so go there
check it out I'm not begging if you're
not able to contribute please keep
listening to the show I love you just
the same there are a few people that
want to help thank you if you can't help
thank you thank you for listening thank
you for being a part of the girl from
your heart podcast family I appreciate
every single one of my listeners even if
you're not able to contribute being a
listener as your contribution all you
have to do is grow cannabis the best you
can share cannabis in a positive light
never talk negatively
never be embarrassing about cannabis
just be positive about cannabis that's
what you can do to support my show for
free you'll never have to reach into
your pocket ever for my podcast just be
a good dude or a good dudette and be a
positive cannabis advocate that's all I
ask for it's free
all right podcast world I will be back
Thursday with a throwback Thursday up
then of course I'll be back Monday with
fresh content I want to thank everybody
for listening to a long podcast I want
to give a huge shout out to my friend
bagsied Jesse and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]