oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house yeah
what's up podcast world it's Thursday
and that means it's time for another
throwback Thursday episode to grow from
your heart podcast before we get to the
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any giveaways any promotions or any
contests all of that stuff has expired
there are no advertisements promotions
giveaways or contests that are valid in
these old episodes I want to thank you
guys for listening and with no further
ado here's a block of old episodes of
the girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 154 of the
growth for our podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
it's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band to let me use
their music on my podcast
big thanks to Kat ku an entire mystic
groups crew
ladies and gentlemen this podcast was
recorded live at elevate glass gallery
at 517 South Tejon and Colorado Springs
this episode features the dad and granny
it also features the owner and
proprietor of elevate glass miss Rebecca
and we also have two of the elevate
dolls with us we've got Abbey and Lydia
joining us on mic you guys I've got a
wicked head cold so I'm not gonna talk
too much at the start of the show I hope
you don't notice my head called too much
in the episode I'm gonna let the music
play for a couple of seconds and when we
get back we will be alright I hit record
so everybody behave yourselves don't see
anything that you wouldn't want your
your mom and your friends to hear it out
my mom's really a mom really rad she's
super super super is your mama cannabis
consumer yeah does she know what you
were doing here in Colorado yes she does
she actually loves it she came to the
shop not too long ago when she was here
visiting oh very cool very cool shout
out to Lydia's mom
Lydia we'll get back to you just a
second I'm gonna introduce everybody
left to right ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to the podcast we are here
live at the beautiful elevate Glass in
downtown Colorado Springs we're at 5:17
South Tejon this place looks great the
shelves are stocked with I'm looking at
Silver Surfer Silver Surfer vaporizers
that's hard to say when you're this
tabbed out they are custom painted
they're colorful as [ __ ] there are some
really cool dab straws up there
there are hammer pipes behind me we've
got a bunch of a whole bunch of super
colorful hand pipes on the shelf in
front of me we got a bunch of custom
recyclers who made that Zimmerman
awesome that's a great piece I love it
great selection or you guys come to
elevate glass 5:17 south stay home and
check out all of the lovely glass and
also check out the elevate dolls there
will be some lovely ladies here to help
you out I'm gonna introduce all the
lovely ladies that are on the podcast to
my last a repeat offender a returning
champion ladies and gentlemen welcome
back to the podcast might my great new
friend the dad and Granny thank you so
much
meet Jeff thanks for putting this
together Gail this is your idea and I
appreciate it it's a good time isn't it
it is a great time granny just in case
people don't know remind everybody out
there how they can follow you on social
media so that they could check you out
while they're listening to your sexy
voice i'm on instagram underscore granny
i'm on facebook
dabbing granny I'm on YouTube dabbing
granny I'm on periscope dabbing granny
you guys if you search for Devin granny
this lady will pop up she is amazing she
takes giant dabs she will take a DAB she
will chug a beer she'll chug a shot then
she'll do a bong rip and then she'll
blow out her smoke she is a savage she
was also a huge member of this community
she does a lot of events and supports
this community she's got an event coming
up that we will talk about here in a few
minutes and sitting to the left of the
beautiful dab and granny is the also a
beautiful VRE the owner and proprietor
of this fine establishment yes yes
awesome this is a great place thanks for
letting me come to a podcast here thanks
for inviting me thanks for being on the
show with us ladies and gentleman
welcome to the podcast
Rebecca from elevate glass huge applause
it'll sound like a stadium on social
media tell them how they can find you on
Instagram and wherever else they might
want to stalk you I am clean we spelled
Rebecca re b c UL a nice queen Rebecca
lizard underscore anything in there no
it's all one word all right you guys
follow her check her out give her a
follow let her know that you found her
on the girl from your heart podcast the
roeckl girl from a horror hashtag on one
of her pictures or something let her
know that's how you're stalking her
she's doing a little hashtag hand signal
I didn't know there was a gang sign for
[Music]
elevate maybe the hashtag for this
pre-show conversation there I thank you
for joining me Rebecca thank you let us
record here thanks for having directly
in front of me staring at me we're
taking my cables and everything I was
doing sitting directly in front of me
yes you do a lot of snapchatting do you
want people to follow your snapchat they
can't follow me on snapchat I think I'm
on snapchat is Newman six that sounds
right I think so
Newman six follow her on snapchat you
guys I like it you were the first person
that I met the first time I ever came
into elevate yeah I specifically
remember I actually met you like two or
three times before anybody else had the
pleasure of really like knowing and then
I finally came in and a whole bunch of
girls came from the back and gave me a
giant hug and like we've heard about you
I do remember so ladies and gentlemen
who we were talking to is Miss Lydia
from elevate glass do you have an
Instagram page I do yeah but it's just
my name it's really boring I feel like I
need to change that you're folding a
full name so they can stop come on it's
I'm like super dreaming it's okay Lydia
running her so it's ly DUI a ger that's
not all would work I know it's really
hard come up Yeah right cuz nobody ever
skinned nobody ever supposed to ly dya
okay come up with a good name for me all
day long I was posting about this
podcast and I knew Lydia was going to be
here
I didn't know what to tag her so I just
didn't put her in I know what's easier
than just her name also that's the most
simple tag you can find great it's
because I kept coming back to this place
because there are shops thanks guys and
of course dude I got a love you Russ to
death always have from like the moment
your immense height to the building and
I realized have really small I was I
liked it I think your average I think
I'm just above average in height I mean
I thought I thought I was like teeny we
prided myself on our customer service so
that makes me really happy
do you guys do a great job you ladies do
a great job are there any men that work
here at the elevate stores one currently
one oh you're gonna change things I've
only seen one male ever that has worked
here ever before oh yeah yes you know we
were all it was the day that I came and
it was super busy and we just hung out
so he had nothing he was a great guy he
gave me a high five and we talked about
Instagram ladies that usually work here
that we should give a shout-out to the
dark and the tattoos beautifully like
ornate I've laid I've only had the
pleasure of working with her once and
she's kind of quiet but she is super
great she is yeah yeah yeah she's really
unique until you get her out of her
shell then she's she's not so quiet
okay she's super smart like she teaches
me [ __ ] that I never ever would have any
idea what did she teach you um that my
Sicilian is actually the real word for
mushrooms and that they're growing under
like these giant interwebs under the
ground and that they feel everything and
like mushrooms are the birth of
everything and really 50%
away from being having the same DNA did
you know she's all about [ __ ] I didn't
know that it's like legit cuz I called
BS gonna put the mics down I got my
computer right behind me we're gonna go
Google some mushroom stuff we'll catch
up with you guys and she has all of the
writers because we may have taken a
bunch of dads and Rebecca doesn't dab
but I think a couple of us blew them
some rub you can rub on your arms again
and get psychedelic she's magical at
that creepy adult arcade yeah it's like
a warm story and an arcade we call that
a shooting gallery
that's gross shoulda said that now this
got weird really quickly who here is not
from Colorado Rebecca's the only one
that's a Colorado native I think Oh
granny you're from the corn right she's
an Iowa corn [ __ ] you guys she said
corn [ __ ] I just repeated it shouldn't
have a microphone these ladies are the
best
miss Abigail where are you from honey
Chicago what brought you to Colorado my
sisters out here okay did she come out
for cannabis no we actually never been
here and she loved to hear okay and then
she left me here so she left you here
your family yeah elevate elevate take
and the whole campus community is your
friend now you've got so many followers
on Instagram and snapchat you got
friends when I threw up that picture of
you and I the other day there was like
Oh granny I'm jealous yeah there was a
lot of comments about you miss Abby you
made her blush granny she's got a lot of
followers she's very beautiful young
lady and she's as beautiful inside as
she is out oh we just had a moment here
in elevates that's awesome you know I
gotta mention this since you're talking
about the hell of a logo these ladies
were kind enough to gift me a dope new
recycler a new dab rig the base has the
Rasta color to elevate logo around it a
few times it's got the red golden green
elevate logo down the book what's this
called you guys rock the recycler part
right okay just as technical as I was
gonna be the mouthpiece has the elevat--
logo with the Colorado C with the seed
coming out of it and then over here on
the back kind of left side is a
sprouting ganja see guys they kind of oh
I forgot the coolest part of [ __ ] I
gotta keep spinning directly in front of
me now I'm looking at a lion of judah a
red yellow and green lion with some
stars on it it doesn't get any better
than this they made me a custom rig you
guys so huge thanks to the people at
elevate thank you ladies you realize
Beca did that did you have simple this
last also no ok thank you that's perfect
Silver Surfer Steve that blue the pipe
cracked
well shout out to Silver Surfer Steve
why do I have such a hard time a Silver
Surfer is too
Silver Surfer Steve thank you for the
glass it's super perfect perfect I love
it it's great I'll post pictures of you
guys check it out on the I read genetics
Instagram Irie underscore genetics to
fight it is quite Rasta fight it is very
growing from your heart and i truly
appreciate it taking dad's off of it
that's why I'm having a hard time
speaking English let's get back to we're
talking about look I found where we were
what brought you to Colorado sweetheart
um well my now fiancé at the time he was
just my boyfriend but he moved here and
yeah yeah yeah we got engaged in
December so it friends thing was that
gonna happen
we don't really know we're not really in
it for like the big to do and all that
kind of stuff we just want to we I don't
know we might just do it one day
randomly and then feel like hey by the
way this happened let's hang out and
take like dads about it I do
high five were married it's perfect it's
a great union no honestly he's a really
great guy
Becca's kicking off her shoes we're
getting cozy here in elevate tonight
this is also the only one with shoes on
I'm just gonna fall what no that's
really great getting them off right on
for the encouragement
yeah it's elevate company slumber party
now we're just chillin chillin we have a
Hot Tub Time Machine on one of the TV's
back here hon you got a glassblowing
video on the TV over here I just know
how did I not notice that before
that's the making of my piece basically
right there that is pretty red I have to
look away because I could just stare in
then just keep watching and there won't
be a podcast just being narrative of me
watching this guy blow glass
granny vat dab of the orange stuff thank
you I think incredible extra incredible
extracts I met Derek the extract artist
[Music]
difference between you two I mean you're
both pretty tall I am six five I like to
say five foot 17 to confuse people so
he's about wow you would be that kind of
person seventeen
granny how tall are you five - over
there we the five - game I'm gonna go
five seven haha she wins that's why she
is Queen BEC EULA man I thought it was
gonna say something about her great
breasts I'm still I'm avoiding her great
I can't say anything about if I said
it's creepy if you say it it's cute
about your great breasts I'll just make
eye contact and behave myself this is
funny it's my turn oh so tell us you
came here with your fiance oh yeah yeah
you have a purpose when you headed out
here just new life well actually I got
my degree in business management in
Pennsylvania
I had my cosmetology license so I could
move out here and do that if I wanted to
but low-key I worked in a head shop in
the town that I lived in and it wasn't
super progressive at all like the dude
didn't want to carry like whack stuff
but he was a hippie he was like a
legitimate like from the beginning my
old boss and say not Adam no yeah
anyways it was a it's what I really I
loved
that's what I was always a part of so
yeah when I came out here I met Queen
Rebecca and my life has been this ever
since you guys make a great team this is
perfect I like the way that you set up
the store and then the dolls and the way
that the dolls rep the store perfectly
the way you guys do all the social media
stuff you're perfect but you know we
gotta mention that there's also higher
elevations that's part of this fan yes
you know before I came here before I met
Lydia I did get a rig repaired at higher
elevation masterpiece productions
I googled who can fix my glass on the
Internet and that's the first place that
came up and I drove there and they told
me I needed to make a deposit and drop
off the rig and if they fix my rig they
would charge me the other half of my
payment and if they didn't they would
give me a nice deal on a new purchase
from the store and I thought that that
was super fair and they called me in
about ten days and they said hey bro
come get your rig and the rig is
straighter now than it was when I got it
from the original artist I don't like it
when my dad nail points up at an angle
because you're putting hash on there it
needs to stay straight cuz I put a lot
of oil on a nail and the amount of oil I
put on there if it's tilted at all it
will run off so I need it straight up
and down and that rig was a little
crooked before I broke it and now it's
perfectly straight up and out my oil
stays on there perfectly I did it
changed my life so it was perfect we
wouldn't be sitting here right now if
that didn't happen so I guess that was a
good thing
yes all right let's segue over to the
event that granny wanted to talk about
that'll be a perfect time since Lydia's
over here taking a dab
October 1st that that's a Saturday
coming up October 1st this is really a
great event I'm really actually
elevators gonna be part of this as well
but there's gonna be I'm gonna kind of
read off the flyer because I'm pretty
impressed with this event it's with DBK
glass and right now they have 32
Colorado blowers that are gonna be
blowing glass that day then they're
going to auction off those pipes and all
that money all the proceeds are gonna go
to the Institute for Research on
cannabinoids did I get the accent on
perfectly okay and there's going to be a
chili cook-off as well so there's gonna
be people making chili some of its gonna
be medicated some of its going to be
just regular chili it's gonna be from
9:30 to without a saw time 7:00 p.m. is
when they're gonna start judging the
glassblowers so each glassblower is
going to be given an allotted amount of
time to to make a piece and I'm telling
you there's like 32 glass blowers to
make a piece and then at the end they're
gonna raffle that and give that money to
cannabinoid research there is going to
be I'm telling you the glassblowers it's
amazing it's dr. dabs zombie glass wazoo
glass higher elevated borough mojo
rebels glass low glass the glass parrot
our very own silver surfers Steve is
gonna be there Dave the slave I think
Matt's blowing I can pop the blaze and
trees there's a current chosen one gonna
be in there yes he's gonna be there
shadow chosen one pop Dee's gonna be
there josh Josh cobbler Brown I think
Brent Thackery is gonna be there there's
gonna be so many local glass blowers and
that's October 1st yep
Silver Surfer Steve's birthday party
also it's invaded making his birthday
party guys party up bring them a dad
they don't know yet well they're gonna
know Monday you know so hey where is the
location Democratic the location is down
yep 28:33 North El Paso chef's brother
luck is gonna be there that's in
Colorado Springs right yep okay where's
that can you give them kind of
directions yeah so like if you go Nevada
to Fillmore you're going to go right on
Fillmore and then now Paso is gonna be
on your left-hand side yes yep yeah
kinda by the Jimmy John's DB King you
will find it if you drive to the right
direction you will find it food truck is
gonna be there so there's gonna be food
as well I think it's just gonna be a
great event there you know I would say
it's kind of like a cannabis family
event because yeah glassblowing is
always fun to watch glassblowing is
amazing it's an amazing thing to see
they take a rod of solid glass and they
turn it into something you can smoke
through in this room I'm sitting in I
can't even describe this properly
there are probably a hundred different
styles of glass just within my view that
I can tell a hundred different artists
just twisted these up their way
everybody's gonna do it in their way
it's amazing that everything in front of
me started off as just a rod of clear
glass then we have another event we want
to talk about I think October 22nd
there's something going on here
something I heard about something it's
probably gonna be the bee's knees the
bee's knees they still say we're gonna
party till the cows come
she is a corn lady all right October
22nd yes October 22nd at the black sheep
we're going to be caught I'm having a
petty Halloween party so we're gonna
have a costume contest we're gonna have
pumpkin carving contest we're gonna have
a dab buzz we're gonna have dabbing
[ __ ] granny we're gonna have a
photobooth live music from SNOLAB groove
on the ETS about 8 or 9 locals are gonna
play we're gonna have a photo booth with
props we're gonna be pulling scary
movies tickets are only $10
now Becca where they get those tickets
they can get the tickets elevate glass
gallery which is downtown on Tejon and
simmer on higher elevations which is
powers in Omaha or at the black shape
itself nothing online no you can get it
off the black sheeps website I do
believe I bet you can so guys I will
most likely be at the event October 22nd
was likely well they they gave me a
ticket and they're staring at me like
you better be there or I'm gonna burn
you with the dab torch so guess what
rasca Jeff will be there dad's I can't
tell you what my costume will be except
maybe in a costume it'll be a good ass
over $2,000 worth stuff for these prizes
guys so is glass yes come dressed to
impress a new dad band that's the name
of our band dad dad October 22nd guys at
the black sheep come check it out take
dad's with us
lots of glass prizes so bring bring an
extra backpack or something because
you're gonna win some glass you're gonna
need to take home a piece is going to
make a halloween-themed piece for the
grand prize I'm trying to talk him into
making like a pumpkin perk yes yeah and
he's good at UV so yeah lots and lots of
prizes a lot of our listeners aren't in
the dab scene they're not from Colorado
they may be from Oklahoma or Australia
or wherever I wanted to teach them about
UV glass really quickly because UV is
kind of the new [ __ ] it's one of the
newest things that's popping up on the
glass scene right now they're passing
the Grammys passing the mic over to to
Lydia because I think Lydia maybe our UV
[Music]
UV they put I don't know what they put
in the glass they put radioactive salt
in the guys and they make a glass pipe
with it and then you turn on your
blacklight and your glass gloves and it
is crazy looking it looks radioactive
you guys in the dark UV okay that makes
enough sense to me I do have something
to add let's hear it okay so my no okay
no that's not what I'm adding my true
obsession is because I grew up in the
90s and I did those damn fuzzy posters
that whoa under black light and I had
several backlight accessories in my
[ __ ] awesome bedroom when I grew up
what a cul-de-sac did it look like
Spencer's threw up in your bedroom no I
wasn't that like kind of douchey like I
did I had like four lava lamps and I'm
really would like to start acquiring
them that's really awesome you do have a
daddy
Lance oh you've got the did your dad
lava lamp granny yes I have that it's
cute yeah so um that's why I like the UV
glass because it's like an ode
to the 90s like time that I grew up in
because it's just like backlight and
it's dope and I'm smoking from it it's
getting me really stoned so it's like
putting together a bunch of parts of you
know the good stuff it's awesome it's a
nostalgia yeah right I know I'm still
like a child I was just about to say
[Music]
there's somebody from just about every
generation in this room right now
because of cannabis on the right track
these young people just amaze me don't
they you Jeff
I mean you're not as old as me but shout
out to Roscoe King Cola shout out to
barefoot grower look at their stuff I'm
like holy [ __ ] those guys are killing it
and then they work with these young
extraction artists up in the canyon up
there and the medicine they make yeah
you know I like I say this Incredibles
is good stuff you buy that medicine from
the homies that is really good medicine
The Incredibles is made by somebody
younger than me really yeah that guy's
younger than me Diaz yo prod certain
that Diaz a few years younger than me
well they're very proud of their girl
because any product you and I both know
comes from the grow and they have a good
product the frozen monkey any of the
Raza frozen monkey I think it's funky
monkey no it's fresh frozen okay that
that makes more sense to me than do you
want to talk a little bit about fresh
frozen and the difference between the
frozen and the not frozen since Becca
had a couple of questions about it and
these ladies questions well you be in
the big expert
I love today but I'm getting to know the
difference in the products I like and it
really seems like this fresh frozen
keeps the Terps in as we've talked about
before we don't have any of our Turkmen
here tonight the main difference is
we're cutting down the plants while
they're while they're still alive we cut
them down
trim them up just a little bit take off
the big leaves throw those in a freezer
and freeze them up completely I'm gonna
tell the whole world what you just did
so we freeze the plants completely and
then we put the frozen material into the
extraction tubes and extract it with the
butane then it goes into the back of and
then it's properly purged that's the
main difference is that before we're
letting the herb dry yep hanging the
plants to dry and I think that the
frozen we are certainly getting we're
getting way more flavor definitely it's
right now you are looking for but yeah
the myself because I like to that's the
sea makes it really good yes granny
one of my parties that was your only dad
ever know that that was her first dad
ever I did not and because Becca is my
friend I thought I should turn her on to
some good medicine like the orange soda
Oh probably about a third of a gram oh
that's like a by size dad yeah I was
pretty [ __ ] up did you take a nap I
and hid for like two hours incognito and
then I came back out and I was super
[ __ ] high for the next 48 hours
Wow and we did like three shots patron
and we drank some beer yeah it's good to
be the boss right yes great he's always
a good time I've never had a bad time
with grass that didn't work was a good
time yes miss daddy Gil over there yes
what's your favorite stuff to dab sugar
some sugar yes so we gotta explain that
now some live resin will sugar up
sometimes it'll get it looks grainy it
looks real like sugar granules like
golden honey sugar granules
I find that to have a lot of flavor most
of the time yeah I'm not really sure
exactly but I do appreciate a lot do you
like big dabs of little dabs like Big
Daddy how big like pointy 3.20 on Friday
oh we're gonna have to come to lots of
dabs Ford Abigail's birth everybody wish
her happy birthday on Twitter and
Instagram she already shattered out her
stuff earlier at the start of the show
so make sure you tell the same lady
happy birthday its podcast won't come
out till Monday but you can write your
retro actively wish her a late birthday
thanks all right let's get some ABS
going you wanna do a graph grab dad I
got my hands full but I'm gonna make it
happen
[Music]
guys that all came through the
microphones I was just at what I did I
had the privilege of hanging out with
our mutual friend Rasta Jeff THD Sam and
we went up to Denver's it was a great
dude he has a great dude and his friend
Josh
they went to college together he came
with respect we went to Denver and I
went to a few new dispensaries up there
that I'd never been to before and that
that was fun and then I went to THC
magazine the office I really feel like I
need an air is going to be wrecked so
Sam and I are gonna start something up
there we're gonna be doing either a
podcast or a broadcast
she said she's excited well she really
doesn't know how she's doing
this young lady is about to take a point
three maybe a point four of Lydia I will
let you narrate you're good at this
well just because I know this is the
themed elevate recycler she's because
yeah she's a pro without it out of a ten
I give you an eleven yes she didn't
change any colors that cause that amount
of coffee comfortable yeah we totally
for sure I would be dying
like I'm not a way back and I do not
have a contact I just melt that dab all
the way over here Jack Doug run shatter
from Terp X shout out to Turk bass pick
that up over a green and healthy
wellness shot that's my friends at Green
and healthy
what's up Linds I hope you're having a
great shift if you're listening to this
at worked hi Lindsey shout out to
Lindsey the traveling stoner always a
shout out to Lindsey the podcast is not
the same without her oh my gosh she came
in here and got rollers and she was one
of the most delightful people and we
talked about how she hung out with you
at the secret
Shh anyways um she is really really
delightful so um it was actually a
really funny story I couldn't find the
roller that was literally right in front
of my face and I wasn't stoned or
anything what's your style
I don't really ask for forgiveness for
it but yeah I would put the thing is I
wasn't even really stoned like my the
max capacity of stoned and I was not at
it and yeah if she was really really
delightful really delightful Lindsey's
one of my best friends yeah yeah it's
one of my favorite people on the planet
shout out to Lindsey shut up turbo
blasters so I want to get back to the
sea ice cream incident that I saw happen
over here what do you guys doing my
microphone microphone like that label
they increase its christened yeah our
present our close proximity you heard I
was so lucky you didn't go to high
school together sometimes I tend to have
to explain things to her like [ __ ] you
Trap House and what was the other one
lean okay yeah and we started talking
about house parties she was like house
party well okay because somebody used it
as a form of measurement like I was like
oh how many people were there and she's
like oh well it was like a house party
and I was like I don't know what that
means still Dabba gay I was like oh yeah
okay and I'm like wait boy like how does
that make sense to you it's one the size
of group smaller than the black sheep a
small house what if you live in one them
damn tiny houses
[Music]
that's where it came because my brother
had fit 74 people into like a bottom
section of a house and my mom didn't
wake up the holes are and there were 74
people in the basement when did they
give your mother she had just gotten her
top teeth taken out and got there you go
she was done for days she was done Wow
yeah I'll take two so house parties
speaking of being out for four days
let's just shout out to max at TNT
instruction did he get you Grammy um
yeah his bacon I'm sorry Jeff I know
you're vegetarian so you wouldn't know
but his bacon is the [ __ ] you know he
gives me bacon every time I see him and
I remind him you know Terry yeah now he
gives me dabs he's like here bro sorry
sorry about all the bacon I've given you
he's a nice guy
I just met him a few you know a few
weeks ago was the first time I met him
he gave me two separate 1000 milligram
edibles and I'm not sure if I wanted to
be his friend after I ate the first one
that made my life difficult a thousand
milligrams is like I described it as
putting ankle weights on your brain it
was a challenge all day long and the
next day as well it took me three days I
can't because I ate six pieces of that
bacon and then two of those cookies from
that guy that was standing there 450
milligrams cookies each each oh you were
flying granny yes you're sedated
I took my husband to the military doctor
he is like what's wrong with you Gail
why are you so sluggish I know I'm so
tired and I really didn't know and then
by the end of the week I was like I know
what was wrong with me hey wait a minute
to tell you a funny story about the
military hospital we were there Monday
and we were walking to the elevator and
a little soldier in uniform he must have
been about 25 came running up to me and
said
I know you and I said oh you do and he
said yeah let's get in the elevator
though so as soon as we got in the
elevator he said can I have my picture
with you now so we've hung out like
three or four times no there's no selfie
oh well that's because we always enjoy
each other's company and have a good
time if you take a selfie with Rasta
Jeff is that called it Jeffy that's what
I've always wondered I think yes if you
take a selfie on a rooftop is that
called a roofie yes that's not my joke
it's funny either way what happened to
Lydia where does she go to the bathroom
come on Lydia you couldn't wait you
don't have podcast or bladder podcaster
bladder that's a special thing she don't
that's a spot it's like truck driver
bladder this is her first podcast well
you guys are wonderful on about you Yesi
fun isn't it well I hope you guys are
back on another podcast we hope to be
young another podcast if I if my
equivalent learns to behave itself maybe
I can record a little bit from the event
on October 22nd at the black sheep yes
that'd be awesome
all right I'll try to bring this little
recorder I'll get it fixed because
everybody that listens to the show knows
that this thing gave us some issues and
I don't trust it I'll get it fixed
bring it to the one on the 22nd I'll
bring one or two microphones we'll talk
about the event live from the place
while we're there are you cold
you're freezing I had to turn the air on
to get the cloud of dad's moving I was
trying to think of a sackful way to say
that without busting you out on having
the front of the store nice and cloudy I
think it is you and me shuttle to the
pizza guy the last time we hung out
together they had to open the back door
you know something happens when we get
together Grammy we seem to the back door
so the smoke alarms and the place didn't
get shot down Shh let's uh let's talk
about the recent change in the rules at
the cannabis clubs here in Colorado
Springs how do you feel about that
granny um you know what this podcast is
going to air before September 21st
September 21st I want a show of force at
the courthouse here in Colorado Springs
they're shutting down our cannabis clubs
again now I want you to come out we're
not gonna speak we're just going to show
that we support them and I want you to
come acting like adults I don't want no
silliness so if you can't come like
professional people in the cannabis
community please stay home but let's
show these clubs that no we support you
and we're not gonna let the city shut
you down I'm upset it's frustrating
because you know the next step they're
gonna shut them down there and then
they're gonna come after our grows us
our caregiver girls already doing that
here at Springs they've limited how many
plants you can have and they've shut it
down to a number of plants where several
of my friends who are veterans and
patients are unable to grow the medicine
that they need for themselves so their
option was to go possibly to these clubs
and now they can't even go to these
clubs the clubs are know so you guys
what we're talking about is the clubs
you are no longer allowed to consume
cannabis in these cannabis social clubs
you are no longer allowed to reimburse
them for product that they may provide
for you they're trying to do away with
all of the social consumption clubs and
I don't think it's right I think that we
need these places I think that without
these places we have to go smoke in our
cars we have to go smoke in the park we
have to go smoke in the Holly we have to
go park in front of somebody weirds
house they take a couple of dabs in our
car drive on to another weird house bark
in front of there take a couple of dabs
because it's hard as [ __ ] to drive and
dab in the city when you're on a lunch
break or do you think some of these guys
are gonna go back hanging out in the
bars
well yeah that that's what a lot of
people do unfortunately and I myself if
I didn't have cannabis I would probably
drink alcohol and I am no good at
alcohol I don't know if I'm no good at
it or if I'm really really good at it
I don't think anybody is good at it and
when we were leaving that event in
Denver a few weeks ago when we drove
through the bar by the bars in downtown
Denver oh yeah
first thing we saw was a drunken female
her boyfriend pushed her she was so
drunk she fell into the intersection
there was four or five other drunks
shouting obscenities and I just thought
I hate alcohol yeah I was at an event
with people with cannabis that left
their left smiling and hugging and
everybody was happy
high-fiving each other yeah good not
gonna be hungover tomorrow I'm not gonna
drive into stuff so why can't we have
ivorie why can't we have our places to
congregate I agree and the other thing
we need to push for Jeff as you know
they're coming after our medical yeah
why are they trying to get rid of
medical that's not fair that's what
started the whole thing we need medical
marijuana for the patients yes we do
because let's think about it we all want
legalized cannabis all of us do but
we're kind of being fooled watch the
right hand don't pay attention to the
left hand we're gonna give you legalize
but we're and make it rec okay so what
if you're truly a patient that truly
truly needs medical more than likely you
are on a fixed income you have a hard
time affording your medicine to begin
with and so now we're gonna add a 47%
tax or more is that right no it's not
right at all and that's not what our
system here in Colorado was designed for
at all and it's not just Colorado I see
it happening first it happened in
Washington State now it's moving next
door to Oregon it's gonna happen here in
Colorado do you think eventually we will
have a nationwide cannabis program that
is run by one governing organization
that takes care of all the marijuana I
think that's what I think that's what
governs I think that's what our
governing bodies want look how much
money can be made tons of
but that doesn't mean it's right I don't
you know what I see the cannabis
community going the way of the family
farm it's gonna go away and no one are
you gonna have to choose from look here
Jeff we sit here we have all this great
medicine if it becomes what the
government is leading us to you'll have
a strain of indica maybe and a strain of
sativa Monsanto ran product and it will
be a key Walmart package very well be
your genetics
oh no no it'll be some GMO stuff you
will continue growing but then we're
back to breaking the law right so all I
can say is we keep pushing for what
we've been pushing for keep the medical
in your if you have medical where you
are don't get rid of it
keep it medicals where it all started
and like I always say in almost every
episode when we talk about social clubs
if you are writing legislation in your
area for cannabis use make sure you
include some water to consume that
cannabis make sure you include social
lounges or social clubs somewhere that
you can purchase and consume cannabis
with your friends like responsible
adults because that's very much needed
when you do legalize cannabis in a new
area learn from us here in Colorado we
are you know we've always been
everybody's had eyes on Colorado as far
as the cannabis goes we are learning
this was something they slept through
and we just didn't pay it any attention
so we thought you know okay we've got
our clubs while we were walking kind of
in a gray area and now the city is not
liking us any longer for lack of a
better word I guess they want tax money
yes it's all about tax money all right
we've been gone for 49 minutes and most
people usually give up about one hour
into a podcast so we should start saying
goodbye to all of the lovely people that
have listened to the show I'm gonna ask
one more question as we go around the
circle
granny you'll be first to hang on to
your microphone here one simple question
indica or sativa indica all right nice
and easy Becca do you even care
sativa sativa okay did you just pick one
randomly or just no when I smoked I
she smokes flowers too okay think of
flowers I forgot shame on me miss Debbie
Gail it occurs the Diwali I like both
but I prefer sativa okay that's fair
enough
you like choosing sides or anything
we're not gonna go to war sorry into
[Music]
kesariya indica or sativa indica for
sure indica for sure
alright alright I want to thank all of
you guys for coming on the podcast I
don't thank you for let me come and hang
out in the front of your store and take
dabs and eat pizza shout out to the
pizza guy once again that was super cool
customer service ladies thank you for
joining me
granny thanks for putting this together
this was all your idea Thank You granny
messaged me and she said hey I'm gonna
bring Rebecca and we're gonna go to your
house and do a podcast at your studio
and I was like that sounds like a good
idea I was like let me know how it goes
and she said well she closes a store at
8:00 and then she's free and I thought
wait she closes the store at 8:00 and
all the buttons and my head started
pushing and I said why don't I go to
elevate where the dabin or the elevate
dolls are this worked out very well I
was given a sweet gift I was fed pizza
and elevate is spelled ele v8 yes check
it out you guys it's 5:17 South State on
and Colorado Springs I'm sure there's an
Instagram page which one he runs that
yeah and you have a website as well
don't yeah elevate glass gallery dot-com
it also make sure you check out higher
elevations masterpiece productions their
sister store there's a lot of stuff in
there there's so much glass in that
store nine years over there also yeah
you guys make sure you come to the event
granny remind us the date of your event
that you're talking October 1st down on
El Paso DBK glass there's gonna be like
30 plus local glass blowers and
don't forget scary we're gonna we're
gonna surprise them but it is SSB
Steve's birthday Steve he's a good guy
he's behind the scenes a lot but he's a
good guy in the cannabis community and
then October 22nd at the Black Sheep
Halloween heady Halloween come in
costume dress the best hours and be so
much fun my recording deer with me part
of the time I hear there will be a dab
bus that's the word what is that and
hula hoop so it's gonna be cold and the
black sheep won't allow us to consume
inside so we're gonna have a bus parked
in the front so that we can dab safely
and be warm and cozy because the bus is
private property and is not involved
with the black sheep or their liquor
license so the separation and the unity
worked perfect I like that happy
Colorado yay
yep I hope to see all of you there
listening to the show at the black sheep
at the birthday party on October 22nd
I'll be in costume I think it'll be
really hot in there I'll take off my
mask and you'll go there he is
it'll be really fun I look forward to
taking a dab with you on the dab bus
maybe we can put somebody on the podcast
you tell us what you think look forward
to seeing you ladies thanks again for
joining me yes need to start like a
vocal group that's wrap up this portion
of the podcast I'll be back and we will
put the tail on this thank you all right
podcast rolling I want to thank you guys
again for listening to another episode
if you need glass if you need a smoking
accessory of any type if you need a new
nail a new bang or a new case for your
rig whatever you're looking for make
sure you check out elevate glass and
Colorado Springs they're at 517 South
Bay hone they would love to take care of
you big shout out to all the ladies at
elevate for being on the podcast big
shout out to granny truly appreciate all
of you ladies and gentlemen if you have
any questions or if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast
email let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I would also love it if you followed
me on all the social media I am on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast I'm also
on Facebook just search for the grow
from your heart podcast I would love the
interaction
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back in a
few days with another episode big shout
out by a ninja Smiths and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 155 to grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always my friends in the
music healthy Wellness I'm going to
address some emails that have been sent
to me and some questions that I received
on social media I've got a really good
question that I have titled the Terp
sizzle so we're gonna talk about why
somebody's got some sizzle and turps
before we get that far I do need to make
a very special announcement I was
talking about getting my hash at Green
and healthy wellness ladies and
gentlemen I was known as the master
grower or the lead cultivator or
whatever you want to call it at Green
and healthy wellness I am no longer
involved with green and healthy wellness
we're still friends I'm friends with
everybody over there I'm still hanging
out hunt and I are still Bros Amy and I
are still Bros she's a she's a chick but
we're still bros Lyndsey and I are
definitely still Bros forever
breezy and I were never real close bros
but I mean breezy and I are still bro so
I've got no problem with the green and
healthy crew I'm just no longer a part
of that I am moving on to do different
things I want to focus more on breeding
I want to focus more on my stuff instead
of working for another company I had a
great time there I have no problem with
those folks I completely appreciate the
opportunity they gave me we have a
different vision and I want to do my own
thing to tell you the answer it so
no longer part of that much love did
that whole crew shout out to hunt shout
out to the entire green and healthy
walnuts crew I just wanted to make sure
that everybody knows I am no longer a
part of that company I get a lot of
emails and questions if people ask me a
lot of things about the commercial grow
from there just wanted to be straight up
I am no longer a part of that alright
moving forward what the hell am i doing
since I'm no longer there I'm working on
my breeding projects you guys I have got
some I've been talking about the show
the breeding project here on the show
recently I've got a breeding project it
is about 50 days into flour at this
point which means it's probably close to
35 ish days since it has been pollinated
which means in about seven to ten maybe
fourteen days I'm keeping a real close
eye on it I will be able to chop these
plants down and I will be able to
harvest the seeds as soon as the plants
dry up I'll pull the seeds out and then
I'll be able to let them dry a little
bit and then I'll package them up and
I'll get them in a few of my friends
hands and we will see what our rise f2
has done we'll see what comes from that
I've also got a grateful dog female
pollinated by the arize male I'm really
excited to see what that's gonna do
there's a lemon skunk pollinated by the
arize and of course I did the golden
goat pollinated by the arise in there
those seeds will be done in like 15 days
you guys I'm really excited about it the
seeds are getting chunky I've been
pulling it pulled three seeds out total
so far just to do investigation I have
to see what's going on and then I just
get a seed at a normal spot of the plant
pull one seed out clean it up take a
look at it I actually tried to germinate
one it did not germ I was just really
curious that's where we are with the
breeding project I have a lot more
breeding projects planned and lined up
and charted and in my head I know what
the females are gonna be I know what
male I'm gonna use and there's going to
be some eat coming up from the eye
region attics Gardens very soon all
right so that's what's going on with the
breeding project what's going on with me
gosh I'm gonna coffee guys I apologize
oh there we go shout it to the dads
shout it to elevate and the new daybreak
they gave me I'm sure I mentioned it on
the last episode but they gave me a
sweet dad rig with the Lion of Judah on
it I just took a fat dab kind of coffin
a little bit but it's a good thing what
have I been doing on Monday night I got
the honor to go see one of my favorite
reggae artists the master sizzla Kalonji
was at servantes masterpiece Ballroom in
den
that was a great show you know there was
an opening act by the name of dub skin I
have never I thought I had seen dub skin
before and didn't like them but I was
completely wrong you guys the band that
played that night that was called dub
skin was [ __ ] great their drummer was
very charismatic and played very
creative reggae beats in my opinion a
reggae drummer is either boring or
really good either
lock-in and he played reggae beats or
you kind of fill in and you do a lot of
cool [ __ ] and he's one of those guys
that gets on top of it plays a lot of
cool [ __ ] I really liked his sound I
liked the way he played I shot at the
dub skip they did a great set very uh
very Colorado esque reggae is my best
way to describe that and of course is
Luke Kalonji came on stage something
happened when the band switched when dub
skinned left and sizzla came on
something in the sound board happened
and the drums sounded like [ __ ] when
Sizzla came on and I don't know I'm not
a sound guy but I I obviously run a
podcast I've got a soundboard
I'm a drummer I was really bummed out
when the drums sounded like [ __ ] but I
tried to get past it you guys tried to
look for the good I was seeing one of my
favorite reggae artists he came from
Jamaica I had to show appreciation I had
to get down Sizzla puts on an amazing
show you guys that dude put on he used
more energy in an hour and 30 minutes
set than most of us use it in our in our
entire day he came out on stage and a
long-sleeve button-up shirt I don't know
how long his dreadlocks are but I assume
they are quite long but he always keeps
him tied up this dudes always got his
dreads and a turban on his head so he's
got a turban filled with dreadlocks on
his head and he's under the lights at
the concert and he's running in place
basically for an hour and a half and
singing and not missing a beat while
singing and this dude was covered in
sweat it looks like he ran through the
sprinklers he was so sweaty
so that dude put out huge energy even
though he was kind of frustrated with
the sound I could tell I'm a musician
I've watched enough stage shows I've
been involved I could tell that the
drummer couldn't hear the monitor mix so
he was falling off the beat a little bit
trying to listen to everything that was
[ __ ] up the singer and the singer was
getting mad and was kind of showing it a
little bit but it was a great show you
guys if you ever get the chance to see
Sizzla Kalonji go do it also if you get
a chance to
see a show at servantes masterpiece
Ballroom in Denver do it leave all your
fancy shoot at home you don't want to
park right there with a bunch of fancy
[ __ ] in your car though that's kind of a
sketchy area shout out to Denver alright
guys let's talk about cannabis let's get
to some of the emails that I have
received because I've been talking about
my stuff for too long let's get to it
I'm opening up an email right now I'm
unlocking the phone I've got a
screenshot of a message I received I'll
click clear my throat this message came
from a friend on Instagram he calls
himself Terps only 710 and they said hey
Ross - Jeff just recently I was gifted
some pure Terps the first time I've
encountered these before so I don't know
too much besides they taste great sorry
guys I'm trying so hard not to cough mic
off here we go I get a small dab of some
other concentrate and then drop a drip
of Terps on it and it comes out great
great and tastes amazing the thing is
the Terps make the DAB sizzle a tiny bit
not like the fourth of July tan brain
status but definitely a small sizzle
that wouldn't happen to the concentrate
with the addict without the added Terps
is this normal they ask and then they
also said any info any info would be
great thank you
longtime podcast listener hey thanks for
listening and then they say can honestly
say I've listened to all episodes since
episode one and I feel like we're best
friends while we are if you've been
listening for that long
we're friends I've been listening to
Chris Hardwick The Nerdist I didn't fall
on Chris Hardwick basically since he was
on singled out in the early 90s and I've
seen Chris Hardwick spiral out of
control and ruin his career and then get
his [ __ ] back together and now Chris
Hardwick is on top of his game and I
heard Chris Hardwick say several years
ago that all he ever wanted to do was
play Red Rocks and I got to see Chris
Hardwick at the oddball Comedy Tour a
couple of years ago play Red Rocks and
it felt like I was watching one of my
friends reach his goals because I've
been following him for so long and I
listened to his podcast so I completely
know what you mean about us being
friends and I agree if we ever meet if I
walk past you in an event if we're in
the same area you better come see what's
up and introduce yourself because we
were friends now
all right let's get to the point uh you
said you've listened since episode
number one Wow
I'm embarrassed when I think about
episode 1 but thank you I appreciate it
thanks for sticking along so you asked
about dab sizzle
yeah that's understandable and that's
acceptable I think as long as it's not
going too crazy
the first thing I'm gonna say is you
might have your nail just a little bit
too hot when you're dabbing you might
want to let the nail cool if you're
using the email turn it down just a
little bit if you're getting too much
sizzle but what's happening is I'm gonna
pick up my little jar turps here what
these Terps talk me through this the
Turks are liquid at least my Terps are
completely liquid I'm holding them in a
jar I can pour them out of this little
vial if I wanted to they are completely
liquid so you're putting that liquid
onto your dab and also you might be
using a little bit more than necessary
if you're pouring it onto there and it's
sizzling when you dab it you might be
able to put about half of that and
conserve your dad's a little bit make it
last twice as long and you're still
gonna get the flavor you're still gonna
get everything I know how it is I'm
excessive too I like to do big fat dads
with way too much Terps but if it's
sizzling that might be part of the thing
but what's happening
what's happening is you're just putting
moisture on a hot nail and if you would
put water on a hot nail it would sizzle
sometimes in the summer when you get
sweaty and you have to manhandle your
shatter with your fingers because
there's no other way to pick it up or
whatever sometimes a DAB will sizzle
from that too because it's got moisture
from your fingers so all that's
happening is basically you're boiling
the turps on the hot nail so when they
hit the nail it's just like you're
throwing some water in a skillet that's
going and you're just getting that
sizzle it's not a problem it's not a bad
thing I you might be too hot he might be
using too much turps so just check those
two things out or [ __ ] honestly if you
like the way it works do it that way
if that's what you're into do it that
way take too big of a dab with way too
many trips on it smoke it up but it's
not a problem there's nothing wrong with
your chirps that I know of from that
description it sounds like just science
happening because I'm gonna take a drink
and another dab and hopefully get rid of
this thing in my throat
all right podcast world I should be cool
for a couple of minutes thanks for
dealing with bye coughs clerk I
apologize for that all right so I was
talking about turf sizzle you should be
cool I don't think you have too much of
a problem there thank you for the
message if you have any more questions
about your Terps please send
message to me I would love to hear more
about your Terps what kind of Terps are
you davon where'd you get them and are
you sure those are cannabis derived
terpenes that's what I want to know all
right our next email came from Mazhar
421 and he says greetings Rasta I have a
couple of questions for you I was hoping
to hear your thoughts on question number
one I'm always reading and researching
on cannabis cultivation for endless
hours I was hoping you could list your
top three books that you have found a
lot of good information from or have
heard good things about I really love
this question I love going to the
internet for answers but the problem
with the Internet is that anybody can
post anything and I find a lot of
[ __ ] posted on the internet and I
see people giving people advice that is
just going to lead to more problems and
they're not getting to the root of the
evil they're like hey I've got this
problem and they're like well then do
this and I'm like oh [ __ ] that's just
gonna make the problem you've got even
worse and cause three more problems down
the line that you're not aware of so I
try to teach new growers to avoid the
internet a little bit because the
Internet can be really full of [ __ ] so
the way to go is trusted books from
trusted authors if you want to know
three books I would highly recommend the
first one I would recommend for
everybody is called marijuana botany an
advanced study the propagation and
breeding of distinctive cannabis I know
that's a really long title but if you go
to amazon.com and you search for
marijuana botany by Robert Connell Clark
you will find that book it's less than
$20 with free shipping so that's the
book I would start with marijuana botany
by Robert Connell Clark then I would go
with another trusted classic I would go
with the marijuana horticulture
indoor/outdoor medical growers Bible
from Jorge Cervantes Jorge is kind of
old-school actually both of the author's
I've told you about her kind of old
school all three of the authors I'm
gonna tell you about are kind of old
school they've started they started
growing cannabis and breeding cannabis
probably before I was born
so these guys have been doing it for a
long time a lot of their techniques are
very old and they seem a little outdated
but this plant has been around forever
and these guys were doing it right back
then and this [ __ ] still works and it's
like karate
you gotta learn the basics
I started off as a white belt your goal
is to get that that crystally green belt
so you guys started off as a white belt
get these books get a good foundation
and then build on that from there so the
first book again was marijuana botany by
Robert Connell Clark the second book is
the marijuana horticultural
indoor/outdoor medical growers Bible
from or Hazzard vantes they keep
updating that book I'm sure you can find
it on Amazon for like 20 bucks the third
book I would recommend is Edie
Rosenthal's marijuana growers handbook
which is actually the Oaksterdam course
guide it is the book that they use at
Oaksterdam in California to teach people
how to grow cannabis professionally this
book is very in-depth and I really like
the way it's laid out it teaches you the
basics of how to set up a grow excuse me
how to set up a grow how to maintain
your setup what size of a grow to set up
I teaches you about how to find males
and females it teaches you about cloning
vegging flowering teaches you how to
look for bugs how to identify bugs this
is a great book it's an Rosenthal's
marijuana growers handbook and then it's
also known as your complete guide for
medical marijuana that one I'm looking
at it right now on Amazon for $23.99
with four dollars $8.99 said shipping
I'm sure if I shopped around a little
bit we could find it for cheaper those
are the first three books I would start
with then there's a book by soma that I
really like I do not have the book
sitting next to me right now but it's a
small thin paperback cannabis book from
soma then DJ sure also wrote a book by
the same publisher that sohmas book is
out from then there's also a book called
let's grow a pound which is a very
useful book at my opinion it's called
let's grow pound from Seymour buds I
think that book would do every grower
some justice it goes from day one of the
grow all the way up to harvest is a very
helpful guide and while I'm thinking
about it let's throw in a book called
secrets of the west coast masters by a
dude named drew West that should be
plenty of books to get you started you
can find a lot of those books on PDF
form for free on the internet somewhere
just a quick search and you should be
able to find them all of those books
will be available on Amazon and if you
have any questions that you need
answered with more depth or if you need
more interaction feel free to send me
more questions I will answer them you
know my email address it's grow from
your heart at hotmail
those are my favorite books let's get to
part 2 of your question part 2 of your
question goes like this I have read the
digital ballast can mess with and
disrupt radio signals like ham radio and
Wi-Fi cable reception do you know this
to be true
have you heard you were alright as long
as they have something called an RF
shield and then he says thanks again for
the love on the show and keep dabbing
and sipping on that drink
that's funny cuz I said I need a little
sip one time I knew somebody who's gonna
give me [ __ ] about that thanks for
paying attention so let's talk about
digital ballasts that mess with and
disrupt radio signals that is possible
they do put off a frequency and if that
frequency matches your TV or your radio
it could definitely cause interference
or be picked up by something the thing
is most digit most of the digital
ballasts available work any much higher
frequency than what most personal
electronics would work at so most of
them are in the 200 range and most of
your personal appliances are in the 60
range so you should not have any problem
when it does happen you are usually
using a lot of ballasts like more than
15 or 20 that would take enough that
would be enough ballasts to disrupt some
signal or when you're getting imported
Chinese ballots that are poorly made
from other countries and they have a
lower frequency vibration and those will
be more likely to cause a problem the
thing that people are worried about is
that they're putting off an RF frequency
and that frequency is able to be picked
up by law enforcement so that makes a
lot of people paranoid most of the new
ballasts are made with an RF shield
inside of them and they're at such a
high frequency that it will not disrupt
your household appliances it will not
disrupt your Wi-Fi back in the day that
was a thing but they've kind of solved
that problem now so you should be cool
an alternative to the the new digital
ballasts you can go with your old
magnetic ballasts the problem with those
is it's hard to take good photography
they make your pictures look like [ __ ]
so that's your option you can either
have the digital's and you can be
paranoid about the RF frequency or you
can have those old magnetics and you can
take shitty pictures but I really don't
think you have anything to worry about
most of the new ballasts you should be
just fine in my opinion there's a huge
article on THC farmer about this if you
want to read a better
THC farmer that's where I did my
research a lot of those guys bicker
about it but from what I read I think
we'll all be ok with our digital
ballasts all right did I truly
appreciate your interaction and your
emails
I'll keep dabbing and sipping on that
drink if you keep sending me good emails
like this
I appreciate your message Mazhar 421 all
right I've got another email this one
comes from our friend Artie and he says
hey Rasta Jeff don't remember the
episode but you mentioned a female plant
dying as soon as you put it in the room
with the girls well I had the same exact
thing happen except my damn killer male
plant shriveled up and died within 48
hours of entering the room any idea on
either situation
thanks for the show again hope to see
that black cherry chem soon Artie ah so
a long time ago I did a breeding project
where I had a reversed was I putting be
okay I had a reversed golden goat in the
room so I had a golden go that was a
female
I applied silver thiosulfate to it for
about 14 days before I put it in the
flower I put it in the flower
I continued applying silver Scio sulfate
to this plant this golden goat plant
became a male that produced male pollen
this is how I make feminized seeds so I
put female plants in that room so that
they can receive that pollen and so that
everybody so I put I time the plants
differently some plants go in early some
plants go in later for breeding so I put
the plants in most of the girls looked
great I put a clone of headband in that
room to flower it was a female and it
looked okay as soon as the pollen from
that reversed golden goat plant hit that
female headband planet that plant
shriveled up and died overnight and I do
not know what causative because all of
the plants in that room got treated the
same everything was the same the feed
was the same the amount of water they
got was basically the same nobody was
overfed nobody was under fed nobody was
over or under watered everything seemed
legit in there the temperature was cool
there weren't bugs in there everything
was cooled but for some reason when the
pollen hit that plant the whole plant
[ __ ] died and I have no idea what
caused it I've talked to other breeders
about it and they all scratched their
heads and look at me like I'm crazy and
they're like I don't know something else
was wrong
and I something I don't know what
happened honestly so this guy said he
had something similar happened he said
his killer mail plant shriveled up and
died within 48 hours of entering the
room any idea on that um that's really
weird so you took a male plant from a
veg room and then you put it into the
flowering room to initiate flower and
within 48 hours it straight-up croaked
and died I do not know offhand what
would cause that I've got a few guesses
first I would like to know was that
plant is this a soil or a hydro grow
that's something that I really am
curious about because soil is much more
forgiving and hydro you have more option
to damage the roots and everything
happens much more quickly in hydro so
that would explain a little bit more if
it were hydro but my main questions did
it go from like a t5 light to right
underneath a thousand watt light cuz
that may have been a little bit much you
may have just [ __ ] microwaved at our
barbeque - door broiled it however you
want to put it you may have just put
that little tiny plant that came from a
t5 or a little fluorescent if you moved
it to a thousand and put a thousand too
close you might have roasted it you
might uh he might have just overpowered
it wasn't ready for all that you gave it
too much energy and it died it may have
gotten too high may have had too little
light also you may have gone from your
thousand watt in your bedroom where
there was only that one plant you had
all the space and then you put it near
the room and it was not getting enough
light maybe that killed it maybe it was
overcrowded maybe you hit it between a
bunch of girls and it didn't get enough
air that's possible but maybe it got too
hot maybe it got too cold maybe it got
too wet before you carried it into the
flower room or when you put it in the
flower room did you get excited and
overwater it you're like this suckers
gonna be a beast and the over-watering
or did you overfeed it or did it need
nutrients I don't know your room if I
had if I could walk into your grow room
and look at the room and the other
plants that's another question I need to
ask myself how did the other plants look
do you have other plants in that room do
you have females in there that look
happy because if the females in the room
look happy then it's just this one plant
we got to figure out but if all the
plants are should be then it's the room
we have to figure out so there are a lot
of questions I wish I could walk into
the room with
glance and see what's going on in there
I wish I could just walk in take a quick
look around the entire room look at your
ducting look at your lighting look at
your source of fresh air look at how
you're getting rid of the old air look
at how you're handling humidity there
are a lot of things I would like to see
in there that would help me answer this
unfortunately I'm not able to view your
room through my brain yet in the [ __ ]
future that'll be so happy we can do
that I'll just teleport to your room
I'll check it out right quick tell you
what's going on but I can't do that so
if you want to send me some pictures or
send me some follow-ups to all of the
stuff that I just said I will talk about
it further on the show let me know
what's going on because it is really
strange that you put a plan into a room
and it died within 48 hours check out
all the things that I asked you probably
check all that there's sound like an
experienced grower that was probably all
the stuff he went to right away but
check that out if it was hydro and you
moved it from another room to another
room I'm assuming there was some root
damage is what caused that plant to die
because last night I transplanted a
medium amount of clones from an EZ
cloner into Solo cups with soil and I
got kind of hasty and I was in a hurry
and I felt myself kind of [ __ ] up
when I pushed the soil down I felt it
press too hard and I've kind of felt the
roots crush today that plants all
drooped over it looks really pissed off
it may pull through it may die I can
spare that clone it's not a big deal I
like having a hundred percent success
because that [ __ ] but just a little
bit of root damage on a hydro plant is a
huge difference in happiness compared to
just a soil plant you can't mess up the
roots as much on a soil plant is what
I'm getting at I guess the bottom line
is I really don't know what caused your
plant to die I wish I had a better
answer for you I really hope you had a
clone of that male plant if not you just
got to get some seeds and do some more
Fino hunting when you email me back let
me know what strain you were working
with and how many seeds you went through
to find that bail I've got questions for
you all so it will talk about this more
on a future episode all right Ari I want
to thank you once again for that email I
hope to hear back from you you guys I
received two emails one was about LEC
that's light-emitting a ceramic lighting
of the new 315 seem to be really popular
the company that makes it 315 s just put
out a smaller version
lower wattage light I haven't paid too
much attention to that I need to do some
research on it also I got an email about
LED light emitting diode lighting
honestly you guys I've never grown with
an LED
I have never drawn with an LEC I've used
some t fives it's thousand watt HBS's
and some thousand watt metal halides
that's how I've grown I've done some
fours and sixes but I mean I've never
done anything other than I intensity
discharge lighting so I'm going to find
the people that make the 315 you guys if
you can put me in touch with the guy
that makes of 315 I'd love to get him on
the podcast let him know have him email
me grow from your heart at hotmail.com
he's here in Colorado I know I can find
him I'll get him on the podcast also I
would like to have somebody that
represents manufacturers or works with
an LED company or somebody that has
grown with LEDs a lot I'd like you to
come on the show and teach us about LEDs
and maybe run us through the differences
of LED lighting and HID lighting because
I honestly don't have experience in that
department
if you're a pro with that and you're
able to articulate ly tell our listeners
about that stuff I'd love to get you on
the podcast so that's what I've got for
you about le CS and LEDs ladies and
gentlemen if you've got a question you'd
like me to talk about on the show send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you
in the next episode we're going to talk
about a recent cease and desist letter
that was sent to the cannabis lounges in
Colorado Springs and I will also answer
a few more emails once again I want to
thank everybody that sent me messages I
would prefer it if you sent me the
messages it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com that's the best way to get
in touch with me if we're already
corresponding on Instagram or wherever
it is keep doing it there that's cool
but new messages I would love to get
those they grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
again that is the best way please send
me more questions I love building
content based on your questions that
lets me know I'm hitting my audience it
lets me know I'm helping people out with
information they actually need instead
of just talking about random things that
are helping anybody so I appreciate it
keep it coming I want to give a huge
shout out to my buddy John Randall's jr.
john-boy I haven't seen you in quite a
while
know if you're doing well buddy alright
ladies and gentlemen if you would like
to sponsor the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review see me
email I say one more time girl from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
check out your product ladies and
gentlemen now that the show is over I
would love it if you go to iTunes go to
the iTunes Store search for the girl
from your heart podcast find the review
section type in a comment let me know
what you think about the show and I will
read your comment on a future episode
also when you're there you have the
option to give me some stars of course
I'd ask for a five star rating honestly
give me what you feel I deserve click on
some stars type in a comment let me know
what you think I would love to hear from
you also I'd love it if you guys follow
me on Twitter
it's @gf wih podcast also find me on
Facebook it's simply the girl from your
heart podcast ladies and gentlemen
that's all I've got for you this week
I'll be back in a few days
big shout out to my ninja Spence and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
sorry man marijuana
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 156 with a girl
from Earhart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
let's write a fruit grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to say the
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my show
big thanks to cat pull myself away from
narcos season 2 to come record a podcast
shout out to my friend they threw down
the Netflix password for me now I got me
a fresh account there narcos I'm going
to talk about a recent a cease and
desist letter that was sent to all of
the cannabis social lounges in Colorado
Springs before we get to that I want to
answer some emails that were sent to us
by some friends let's just get right to
that part this one came to the Grove
from your heart Facebook page this one I
don't know if she wants me to see her
name on the air but I am going to read
her message it goes like this do you
have any opinion on trimming of machines
we are home growers so we are looking
for something small like the trim inator
mini dry trimmer or the smaller trim pal
but lots of folks are against trimming
machines so I just thought I would ask
your expert opinion thanks for all the
info you share I love your show hey
thanks for listening to the podcast I
appreciate when people send me messages
and I love it when people tell me that
they love the show it makes it all worth
it big shout out I appreciate that so
let's talk about trim machines I there
you're not gonna like my answer but
there is not a trim machine that I like
I really I'm a fan of hand trimmed
cannabis I think connoisseur grade
cannabis should be trimmed by hand if
you're growing a whole bunch if you've
got a large outdoor I might see you
using a trim machine but honestly I can
tell the difference between hand trimmed
and machine trimmed cannabis
and there's nothing like hand trim
cannabis why why this is my opinion why
grow your plants you're gonna have them
for what nine weeks in flower and then
probably four to six weeks maybe eight
weeks and veg maybe longer depending on
how you do things so that's a lot of
weeks that's 13 weeks 14 15 16 weeks
you've got these plants right then
you're gonna cut them down why not take
the time to trim them by hand and love
them and I know it's tedious and it kind
of sucks sometimes but it's so worth it
in my opinion
and then my big thing is when you use a
machine to trim your cannabis it turns
that trim into like a mulch and it just
makes it it cuts it at too many
different angles too many different
times and it makes it it's basically a
mulch like when you mow the lawn and
you've got that bag of clippings and it
stinks real funky you've kind of mulched
up all of your cannabis leaves and
they're releasing too much moisture and
it's starting to there's a there's a
reaction that's happening in there
because it's cut so many times and it's
stacked inside of there and you know how
the grass stinks real bad well your trim
will start to do that also a lot of
times when you're getting shitty hash
from the dispensary it was possibly made
I can't guarantee it but it was possibly
made by material that came from the trim
machine when I helped my buddy Kevin get
started making his little hash company I
was a grower he was an extract guy I was
giving him material I used a trim
machine I used the kind that looks like
a giant salad bowl and it's got the
grill in the middle of it you put the
top on it you spin it that worked it
trimmed the [ __ ] out of some of my but
some of my buds are just mangled I grew
some cushion it was like rocks it
trimmed that okay I had some lemon skunk
that had some fingery buds it just cut
the [ __ ] out of those they didn't like
that at all so one where I'm getting is
I gave the trim from that to my buddy
kevro and he ran and made hash out of it
and the hash was terrible and we
couldn't figure out why and we took it
to Denver with us one time on a trip and
we showed a friend my buddy's like dude
did use a trim machine to make this hash
he called us out right away he knew and
so it made green shitty hash so that's
one major reason why I don't like a trim
machine I think it should be trimmed by
hand you can trim it by hand and then
you can use all of your fine trim to
actually make some product out of you
can make concentrates you can make
edibles you can do it
we want with it but if you use a machine
it's pretty much wasted and like I said
before if you're gonna put that much
time into growing it into drying and
curing it why not sit around the table
with whoever's gonna smoke it with you
you said we're growers I'm assuming
there's you and probably a spouse or a
partner or whatever you call it these
days and maybe a couple of friends maybe
a roommate or something you guys should
all sit around the table and trim it up
talk have a good time experience that
[ __ ] you probably have I'm sayin that's
what should happen in my opinion I
understand it gets overwhelming there
are a lot of great trim machines but
there's not one that I can recommend
because I stay away from them and I hire
humans to trim so honestly that's my a
hundred percent honest guidance on trim
machines if anybody out there has a trim
machine that they think trims to the
quality of a hand trimmer of a person
send me a message send me a video I am
very open I want to know about these
things they're [ __ ] that I don't know
enlighten me
I'd like to be on the knowledge team so
let me know and then I can share that
information with the listeners let me
know what you think about trim machines
if you've got one they can compete with
my quality trim grow for me heart of
hotmail.com all right that's the first
email let's get to another email this
guy sent me like a multiple multi choice
email and it won't open but I'll make it
open but it won't do it hello email it's
broken this one just says podcast topic
the freedom of strains how do you feel
about training is it legal to ship
cuttings to legal states due to low THC
content so how do I feel about trading
strains it's like if you've got a clone
and I've got a clone and I want what
you've gotten vice versa like baseball
cards yes I love trading strains I've
I've gotten some of my best strains by
trading stuff before it's like having a
good baseball card you know what I mean
that right that specific could be like
that I'm not a baseball guy but I
listened enough Greg Proops to know that
like a Mickey Mantle card would be worth
some [ __ ] you know if I had a sexual
paid baseball card I could probably
trade that for a bunch of other cards so
if I've got that one good cut like back
in the day if you had Girl Scout cookies
around here I could trade my girl scout
cookies forum cut for almost any cut
that anybody had the gorilla glue is
very similar
my grateful dog I will not let that out
to people people have offered me
ridiculous trades for my mother plant of
my grateful dog I won't let it go
however so yeah I totally love the
freedom of trading strains you should
give strains away also there's nothing
wrong with that I give people clones I
had a friend started growing recently I
gave them [ __ ] tons of clones just to
get them started bits you should give
away and trade clones and seeds that
should happen if you've got a pack of
seeds if you've got twenty seeds and you
only want to run ten and your buddies
got ten seeds of something else
trade do it get it on I think that's
awesome so then he also said is it legal
to ship cuttings to legal states due to
low THC content you know what I cannot
speak on shipping I do not know anything
about shipping I don't know the
legalities of that I honestly avoid
shipping I don't like to put anything in
the mail
kind of a paranoid old hippie on that
part so I don't really put anything in
the mail unless it's absolutely
necessary
so I can't speak too much on that I low
THC content I guess if you're shipping
hemp plants from one legal state to
another that's probably okay but isn't
the shipping system isn't that owned by
the government isn't that federal so
you're probably [ __ ] up somehow I
would avoid that then your question
continues with people slash clubs buying
and renaming genetics selling breeding
rights etc so let me touch on that one
people and clubs buying and renaming
genetics that sucks I really hate it
when I give somebody a clone and they
grow that clone and then I know that
they harvested and then like a little
while later they've got a bag of
something that smells exactly like the
clone that I gave them tastes just like
it looks just like it they're calling it
some different [ __ ] because they want to
take some credit for it or they want to
make some extra money off of it by
calling it something different that is
frustrating [ __ ] right there
call it what it is or the clubs will do
it also the clubs the somebody else will
name something and then we have medical
marijuana here in Colorado and some
people really like specific strains some
people really dislike other strains and
if you know that I'm gonna say Sour
Diesel Sour Diesel works well for you
medicinally you want to go get Sour
Diesel and if somebody just named some
[ __ ] on the Shelf Sour Diesel and you go
spend your money on it and you get home
and you smoke in say you've got
Parkinson's and maybe sad this is just
hypothetical you've got Parkinson's
disease and Sour Diesel makes you quit
trembling so you just spent your
hard-earned money on this eighth or this
quarter of medicine and you went home
and you probably took all day to get
that bowl packs and you finally smoked
that [ __ ] and you thought you were
gonna quit shaking but guess what some
ass will just mislabeled some weed
because it would sell if we're called
Sour Diesel and it's not gonna do what
you need properly for your medicinal
effect and you just kind of wasted your
money now you're disappointed you
probably wasted an uber ride or it Drive
over to the dispensary that [ __ ] sucks
when people and clubs buy and rename
genetics that's not really cool I think
that everything needs to be left into
proper name I've seen it done I try to
speak out against it I really dislike
when extract companies
take two different strains like right
now I'm not gonna call out the brand but
I'm gonna talk about what I've got I've
got some Curious George live resin in my
hand there's I don't know of a stream
called Curious George but there's some
bananas and probably some gorilla glue
or something you know what I mean so
they just blended those two strains
together and called it Curious George
which I mean that's creative but they
didn't breed that they they don't get to
name I guess they get to name that hash
blend but I think it would be better if
they put like what Terp X did on this
container Terp X printed taffy + Cascade
nug run shatter they didn't put an X to
make you think it's crossed because if
you put taffy x cascade it makes it look
like it's a hybrid of that because
that's how a breeder would do it
so Terp X does it taffy + cascade so I
know straight up what two screens are in
this hash blend so maybe I've got a
friend who if she smokes too heavy of a
sativa she will have a panic attack
right in front of you she might piss her
pants she'll cry she'll have to leave it
gets ridiculous if she smokes too much
the Teva that cascade in there that
would be too much for her head so she
knows straight up not to buy that this
other one it doesn't say what's in there
so she doesn't know if she can even
smoke that so she probably wouldn't even
waste her time buying it to tell you the
truth so yeah it's nice when people
rename stuff I think that we need to
keep the names true I think that bud
tenders or somebody in the dispensary I
think that the jars should say and let's
say maybe maybe maybe they have lemon
Jeffrey on the shelf I think it should
save lemon Jeffrey and then it should
have a lab test of THC CBD maybe CBN CBG
and THC a those need to be listed on
there and then underneath lemon Jeffrey
it needs to tell you the genetics lemon
skunk and golden goat it needs to let
you know that that's the parents I think
that would be really helpful and then it
also should have the sativa or indica or
hybrid marker which is a whole other
conversation
because everything's pretty much a
hybrid these days in my opinion but you
can have things that lean toward the
indica in the city so that's what I
think about people renaming strains I
think it sucks I think if I give you
seeds or clones you better call it that
[ __ ] when you grow it just to keep it
true because what if somebody breeds
with it then you're really [ __ ]
things up you're really throwing off the
family tree we got to keep the cannabis
family tree in line that's part of our
job myself as a breeder that's really
part of my job is to keep it true to
where there's a history and a family
tree so we can look back when things get
different I don't know I just think
that's important I like to be kind of a
preservationist I guess so your email
goes on to say more casts on genetics
and origins please I would like to talk
a lot more about genetics and origins
but the only things I would really feel
fully comfortable talking about would
probably be strains that I bred because
they're the only ones that I would know
the true origin of because unfortunately
a lot of the popular cuts there's a lot
of lies and misinformation and [ __ ]
based around the origins of those cuts
like we know where Gorilla Glue came
from because Josie Wales bred that and
told us about it we know where golden
goat came from because mr. tank bred
that and told us about it but there are
a lot of lies and rumors and untrue
stories about things like Girl Scout
cookies and of course the OG Kush I mean
there are probably 20 different stories
about og cush that I've heard and I
don't want to talk about where I think
it came from too much because I feel
like I'm just diluting the true story
since I really wasn't there and I don't
know so I'd love to talk more about
origins maybe one day I'll talk about
some of the strains that I created since
I can tell you where they came from and
I'm certain of those and I won't treat
any [ __ ] stories about it so I made
a note of that I will talk about that in
the future
you guys want to thank you once again
for sending me those messages that
message came from a dude called that
heavy slim guy on Instagram big
shout-out to that heavy slim guy I
appreciate the message I love getting
messages from everybody if you're going
to send me a message I would prefer you
shoot it to me at grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
I think the email address is the easiest
way to keep it organized it's the most
reliable and I will find your message
there if we're already corresponding on
Facebook or Instagram or wherever we
might be talking this keeps in to me
your messages there we'll continue the
conversation there but if you want to
start a new conversation please hit me
up at grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I really do like making
content from all the messages I received
from the listeners it lets me know that
I'm hitting my target audience it lets
me know I'm talking about something you
guys want to hear about and it always
gives me good content so I appreciate
that thank you guys now the start of the
show I did say I was going to talk about
the cannabis clubs in Colorado Springs
receiving a cease and desist letter I'm
pulling up a website now I'm pulling up
the Denver Post website I and this
article comes from the Colorado Springs
Gazette
they do not give an author name so we
will get into the article I like to give
credit but there's no one to give credit
here besides the Denver Post and the
Springs Gazette so the article goes like
this nine Colorado Springs cannabis
consumption clubs received cease and
desist letters from the City Clerk's
office last week in the first crack down
under a ban on the clubs enacted by the
City Council on March 22nd
the club spring up after amendment 64
was passed in 2012 legalizing adult
sales and use of recreational marijuana
but banning public consumption the clubs
gave people a place to use cannabis and
socialize in private Colorado Springs
outlawed sales of recreational marijuana
in the city but the clubs got around the
ban by providing pot to their patrons
for a reimbursement model they could
either trade cannabis for membership or
sign affidavits saying the club was
growing the customers legally allowed 6
marijuana plants for them alright now
let me back up and talk about a couple
of things on here Colorado Springs
outlawed sales of recreational marijuana
in the city of Colorado Springs when we
did pass recreational marijuana counties
were allowed counties and cities were
allowed to decide if they wanted
recreational marijuana dispensaries in
their County or not and a lot of places
said no Denver has a lot of recreational
marijuana available Pueblo has
recreational cannabis available Colorado
Springs is right in the middle and they
banned it so the way that the city got
around it or the way that people got
around it was by opening up these
cannabis clubs and working on what they
called here the reimbursement model
which means you can sign a paper that
says you remember you probably pay a
cover charge then you can walk into that
club and if they've got some cannabis
and you want to smoke it they won't sell
it to you they'll give it to you but
you've got to reimburse them for the
electricity that they spent and the time
that somebody spent trimming it and
whatever they feel the product is worth
you've got to reimburse them the way
that they made that legal was these
people would sign over their legal plant
count so in Colorado when you get a
medical marijuana card you were allowed
six plants you can pay a larger fee or
you can talk to your doctor and he may
give you what's called an elevated plant
count where you can grow more plants
they will offer up to 99 plants in some
cases but you'll take your medical
marijuana paperwork and there's a spot
where you sign your provider and you
will make whoever runs this a cannabis
club would now become your provider and
now that place is legally pseudo kind of
allowed to grow your six plants for you
and when you go there you walk in and
you're already a member there they're
growing your plants so you're able to
consume products that are there
site this is how it was it's no longer
like this since they came and made these
new rules and sent this cease and desist
letter but this is how it used to work
so I'm gonna continue with the article
it says although the city officials view
such actions as de facto sails the
practice has continued the ban passed in
March however says this clubs cannot
sell trade give distribute or allow the
transfer of marijuana so they're
technically not allowed to be reimbursed
or sell or trade cannabis in there they
cannot give cannabis away which is kind
of weird because what's a cannabis
social club without cannabis it doesn't
say that we can't consume it in there
right now but that was part of what they
part of the new rules was we couldn't
consume in there so I'll continue the
article says the band gave clubs that
existed before September 23rd 2015 8
years to phase out their businesses an
effort to help the owners protect their
investment but under the law every owner
had to submit a consumption club
application and a $200 fee by April 29th
to get a one year renewable license for
$90 plus registration fees only five
clubs applied by the deadline one was
approved to or under consideration and
two were denied the denied clubs along
with seven other identified clubs that
did not apply for licensing have been
ordered to closed because they are not
licensed as required hey guys I talked
about this a lot every time I talk about
cannabis consumption clubs we talk about
the canna Canyon or the dab lounge I
talk about this all the time when you
were writing legislation for your area
if your state or your locality is
inventing and writing and creating the
laws for medical or recreational
cannabis in your area or any type of
cannabis use in your area please include
some type of safe smoking area you need
a consumption Club you need a place
where adults can go and congregate and
consume cannabis safely like adults
there are people that come from all over
the world to Colorado
anybody 21 and over can drive to Denver
or Pueblo and they can show an ID and if
they've got some money they can buy some
cannabis now once they leave that
dispensary there's nowhere safe for them
to consume that you can't smoke in your
car because you'll get a DUI
excuse me I'm coughing you can't smoke
it at the park because that is illegal
you can't roll up a joint and walk down
the street and safely smoke in Colorado
that is frowned upon that's not what we
did here so there's no we're practically
or practical or safe to smoke the
cannabis you just bought at the
dispensary you can go to your hotel and
a lot of hotels make you sign a paper
when you check in and it says that they
will charge you 250 to $500 for cleaning
your room if you smoke cannabis in there
because they think you're gonna [ __ ]
that room up 250 to 500 dollars worth of
stank you better have some good weed if
it cost $500 to get the smell out of
that hotel room so there's no more
practical to smoke
we need these consumption places you
guys so when you're writing this
legislation and writing the rules please
be sure to include that because that's
where we screwed up here in Colorado we
would have it pretty well pretty good if
we didn't know if we didn't skip that
part and what really sucks you guys is
I'm passionate about this because a
couple of my friends own these
businesses but I feel for every owner
how are my friends that were promised
eight years to continue doing business
to recoup their assets or recoup their
investments how how are they expected to
pay their bills now that they're not
allowed to work on the business model
that they have designed and been
operating on they're not allowed to
reimburse for cannabis they're not
allowed to give it away they're not
allowed to trade it there is no
transaction involved for cannabis which
honestly was a large portion of these
people's revenue now how are they gonna
pay the rent as I'm recording the first
is creeping up on us and I know
hopefully these businesses have more
than one month of finances put aside but
you never know this is the cannabis
industry they have to buy products they
have to pay vendors they have to keep
the lights on apparently some of them
are growing products and more which cost
money you have to pay to grow you have
to pay trimmers you have to pay
electricity soil costs money everything
cost money when you're doing business
making money costs a [ __ ] ton of money
money is expensive how are these folks
how are my friends
how is our community gonna pay their
rent now that they are not allowed to
function under their business plan I do
not find it fair I hope that we can do
something about this there wasn't I
would rally you guys for a City Council
meeting but it's already happened if you
were in Colorado Springs please go to
the city council meetings and show
support for the cannabis clubs are
something that we really need we're
allowed to have bars on
the other corner where people can go and
drink whiskey and beer all day and get
[ __ ] and cause problems but we're not
allowed to have a place where people can
go consume some cannabis peacefully I
don't find it to be fair the Colorado
model says let's regulate cannabis like
alcohol so let's do that
[ __ ] if we're gonna do that how about
when we're at a baseball game or a
football game or a basketball game why
don't we have a medical marijuana
smoking section or a recreational
marijuana smoking section right next to
the smoking section if we're gonna
regulate like alcohol let's step up and
do it correctly all right guys I've been
renting for a long time
I really hope that you show some support
for these cannabis clubs I want to give
a huge shout out to all of the cannabis
club owners and proprietors and
everybody who works with the clubs to
make them happen I appreciate you and I
respect you and shout out I hope that
you are able to continue doing business
and I hope you guys all survive I know
most of you are probably yeah families
you got these got a damn dog in a house
to take care of that shit's expensive
I hope you find it means to do it I hope
it all works out for you okay I want to
wrap up the podcast with another message
this one comes from year of the gorilla
on Instagram year of the gorilla was the
winner of the hashtag mullet challenge I
don't know if anybody listen to that
episode but I did the mullet challenge
you had to find somebody in their
pajamas and a Walmart with a mullet snap
a picture send it to me this dude
followed all the instructions he meets
the criteria shoutouts here of the
gorilla you've got some stickers coming
your way by the time this episode comes
out the stickers will be in the mail the
checks in the mail buddy so he also sent
me a message it says hey Rasta Jeff I
was wondering if you have any favorite
pest management routines like products
you use in applications and how often I
know having a clean grow and proper
environmental control play a key role in
keeping things healthy and happy also
maybe what would you do if an outbreak
occurs and how to stay positive and
overcome challenges in the CRO the first
part of that talking about pest
management routines and the products
that I use that'll be another episode I
am writing an episode I've got notes for
it I've got a notebook filled with notes
you guys a lot of people probably
wouldn't believe how many notes I've got
how many half shows I've got I've got a
lot of stuff prepared but I'm doing an
episode on how to identify problems and
how to treat for problems and how to
prevent problems on the list of things
that we're gonna talk about I've got
spider mites white flies fungus gnats
thrips so that's just the top of the
list we're gonna talk about how to
identify those on your plants well we'll
talk about all the pest management stuff
but what I want to get to this part of
this message is how do you also maybe
what to do if an outbreak occurs and how
to stay positive and overcome challenges
in your girl because that is super
important I see a lot of people have a
problem at the beginning of the grow
just not too far in and they get
completely frustrated and they feel
defeated
the very beginning and it feels like
they're fighting an uphill battle
cannabis is a plant that wants to
survive cannabis is hard to kill you
have to almost try to kill cannabis so
if you get a problem you have to first
identify the problem right that's what
you have to do then you have to figure
out how to solve that problem then you
have to put that plan into action and
solve your problem and then your problem
will be solved and then if you do it
right you have a stronger sense of pride
because you overcame something anybody
can put some plants and some soil pour
some nutrients and some water on them
put it on it put them under some lights
and let them grow for nine or twelve
weeks and produce some cannabis it's
when you have a problem that you had to
overcome is when it's really it makes it
more fun for a guy like myself I guess
maybe that's how I stay positive I enjoy
a challenge I don't like the mundane
boring life at all that's why I do what
I do that's why I live the way that I
live I honestly think that causing some
problems and screwing up makes you a
better grower you have to I mean you
didn't learn how to walk until you fell
down a few times and then you didn't
learn how to run until you were good at
walking and then you [ __ ] up running a
few times and scraped up your knees like
so you gotta you have to kind of make
some mistakes and overcome them that's
how I stay positive I know that I'm
learning something I know that there's
something gonna come out of that mistake
that I made so that's how I stay
positive and and also then you're
growing cannabis you can't get too upset
about what you did because you're
growing cannabis if you've got a problem
maybe you got spider mites that happens
you first you have to accept it because
[ __ ] happens and you made a mistake
somewhere maybe there's a crack in the
wall that spider mites climb through it
might not even really be something you
could have thought about or could have
done anything about you got mites okay
accept it
get on the internet Tex Rasta Jeff do so
do whatever you gotta do listen to a
podcast to figure out how to get rid of
those spider mites if you're in whatever
week don't panic whatever week you're in
don't panic there's a solution at
worst-case-scenario harvest flush your
plants and harvest them just flush them
out more quickly than those bugs can eat
them harvest it and get what you can out
of the crop you're gonna get something
even if it's not even if it's just
experience you're gonna get something so
find what you've got identify it then
take the steps to get rid of it and then
clean up the grow room and go back at it
harder than ever before and next time
when you see the very warning of spider
mites in that room you're gonna know
exactly what to do
you're gonna identify it more quickly
you're just gonna be better at it I know
that part of me will always know that
I'm bigger than every bug and I can find
some sort of thing to destroy any insect
that gets into my room and I've got
books that can show me how to get rid of
any sort of mold or anything so I'm just
confident that I can take down any
problem that I'm given in a grow room
I've had some crazy [ __ ] happen in grow
rooms before I've had fans fall and
chopped up plants and lights have come
undone and I've ran commercial grow so
there's a lot of stuff that can go wrong
I've had PVC pipes with oh I forgot how
many gallons per minute this pump used
to push but way too many gallons water
this PVC pipe exploded water one
everywhere you just got a smile
you gotta put some reggae music on got
to turn up the headphones you got to
laugh maybe go take a couple dabs just
get in there and solve the problems just
like anything else in life anything else
in life shit's gonna happen all the time
everyday life would be way too easy if
[ __ ] went right all the time so I expect
problems in a grow room actually when I
ran the big grow and I was training new
people they would always say so what's
the first thing you got to do when you
get here and I would always say find the
surprise they'd be like what do you mean
that's a big ass girl we've got a
hundred and something lights they got
like 50 fans there's a bunch of pumps
there's a bunch of PVC so we get to find
what [ __ ] up overnight while we were
gone cuz it's been like 12 hours since
we've been here and so everybody just
laughed at first and they'd really
realize like oh yeah every day when we
get in here there's some weird [ __ ] that
we have to find we have to repair our
handle before we can even go about
normal business
so it's up to you you can either uh you
can either to laugh it off and just have
a good time and clean it up move on do
whatever you got to do or you can have a
stroke about it and be pissed off all
that that's up to you but I choose to
just have a good time remember that girl
cannabis there's no need to really get
too mad about too much alright so thanks
for that message I appreciate that that
really I hope I was a little bit
inspiring and I hope I answered at least
half of your questions so I shot it's my
boy year of the gorilla
I appreciate the interaction check your
mailbox probably have some stickers
waiting for you if you can hear that
noise in the background that's my boy
make the dog he's chewing on a deer
antler and yeah it's a boy alright make
the dogs gonna find a camping spot right
here by my feet I'm gonna scratch on him
for a little bit ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you for listening to
another episode of the girl from your
heart podcast I would love it if you'd
go to iTunes go to the iTunes Store
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast find the review section
give me a five star rating type in a
little comment let me know what you
think about the show and I will read
your comment on a future episode ladies
and gentlemen I want to thank you again
for listening
give you huge shot it's my buddy Sammy
chanclas hey doesn't that just mean
shoes bro also big shout outs my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
we got to stay positive every time
positive
[Music]
no matter what the crisis is stay
positive stay positive
[Music]
well every time I take a leak oh look up
on the TV seem like the whole world gone
crazy war famine and poverty
people are dying continually so many
people like getting confused so many
reasons to donated applause ho italico
Filton Adam on site plan get my friends
to sing this song stay positive stay
positive
stay positive stay positive stay
no matter what the crisis
[Music]
shine
positive oh yes we up Tuesday positive
positive no matter when a crisis is
positive or yes we have today positive
positive he oh no no no never say never
no never say die and if at first you
don't succeed and try and try and try
again
weird as I will yes there must be a way
tomorrow is another day so you're one
step forward Bundy right truck you
Stalin funny Allah bones right back
you get sidetracked carry on don't stop
but if you gonna straight and pray and
knock the door shall be opened me me
seek you shall find us and shall be
given to you my friend knocking knocking
at the appointed time little a keel of a
mission of the life you live no matter
with the crisis stay positive remember
the words of your DJ King life is a
struggle
[Music]
no matter what the crisis
no matter what the crisis you got
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community is
time for episode number 157 a big roll
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're a new grower at your
professional growers appear a new smoker
or a dedicated a bur if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always you need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
at the mystic huge band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shots
a cat coot and the entire mystic
ladies and gentlemen welcome back to the
show the secret invaded some space
[Music]
people brought super fancy glass the
Dino was the Dino Joe pica lab elbow Joe
Peters
yeah and there's no table there's no we
had Instagram and some stickers so big
shout out I got those stickers they're
gonna go on something cool probably a
case of some sort
[Music]
our good friend max sat down next to us
I've been trying not to say good friend
remember a long time ago says gonna put
our friend max from TNT extraction sat
down next to me at the secret session he
knows I don't need makin and he's felt
bad for offering me medicated bacon at
all the past sessions so he pulls out a
banana pudding to me he's like yo you
want this it's been four or five months
since I eat metal balls yeah and I broke
that banana pudding bar in half and I
ate half of it did a little selfie video
with Miss Lindsay here I passed the
other half of it to Lindsay I think she
split it with Bobo I did so I am back on
the edibles wagon I eat edibles again at
the secret
Friday I the banana pudding bar ate a
couple little smaller edibles that
people gave me like candies and such
like a caramel or something oh and then
I eat something else we're gonna talk
about later on on the show and then
Saturday
I ate a 100 milligram Claudia cherry are
absolutely not my favorite flavor I
didn't like the cherry is [ __ ]
delicious they've got an that's really
good chocolate those are [ __ ]
delicious baby I did not like that one
again I was becoming way over medicated
on I can't do that to myself again
[ __ ] he's a really cool host he's the
kind of hospital there's a band playing
and as the band played you just came in
kick it with us roll the back would
those took some dads with the crew
flirted with a couple of chicks and
[Music]
throws a hell of a party yes this time
in secret session I did something that I
don't usually do i was given the VIP
gift bag
yes forgiving us both one of those yeah
let's just real quickly go through the
gift bag and talk about what's in here
there's a bunch of really cool stuff a
couple things I'll do it like Christmas
I'm gonna start with the things that are
least impressive to the most impressive
to me a company called healing nations
LLC cultivation consulting cultivation
systems and nutrients through in a small
baggie of cannabis it's a little bit of
buds
it's it's okay weed it's not impressive
weed but it was a gift so I appreciate
it we're gonna smoke this year later on
they threw in some weed also next up the
lazy lion threw in a real big flier and
a small baggie so if you guys want to
smoke a preval joint that's probably a
gram and a half two grams of weed that
smoke that Oh somebody shout out totally
random off the cuff here but somebody
gave me an 18 gram joint
I was given an 18 with me shout out to
our friends in New Mexico shots it's
Charlie Torres and his son and also Big
Shot it to Tim and everybody involved in
organic uh down in New Mexico I love you
guys
those guys grew some arise and it tested
@ 30.8 that's Golden Cross to the day
breaker I gave them some seeds two
strains that have been lab tested by
steep hill they've tested over thirty
percent THC in Colorado one in New
Mexico same company the link to that is
both strains or golden goat crosses
lemon Jeffrey is the lemon skunk cross
to a golden goat reversed mail so it's a
feminized seed that one hit 31 percent
then the the theorize is the [ __ ]
golden goat sorry golden [ __ ] full of
[ __ ] right I'm gonna have to add in part
of this because I'm saying this all
wrong ah lemons going cuz lemons yeah
the lemon Jeffrey is a woman's going to
the goal to go and the arize is golden
goat to Daybreaker so it's basically
then non femme
version of the lemon Jeffrey and those
of they've got the golden go parent in
there and those are both tested over 30%
now so shad it's my friends down there
New Mexico shouting - Charlie Torres and
organically grown and trimmed perfectly
cured perfectly rolled 18 gram joint
it's gonna get everybody wherever we go
they said they smoked one the other
night at another event and it went
around for over an hour
so it smells delicious it smells amazing
I haven't smoked it yet but friends in
New Mexico they passed through here the
other day gave me some dads with some
rosin eyeshadow - woody - the whole
truth I appreciate all you guys I'm
gonna continue on with this gift there's
a coupon in here for 15% off any
purchase at a specific dispensary that
didn't pay me for an ad there's from
guys garden probably a good gram of weed
from mile high dispensary this is some
New York City diesel it looks it looks
like I approved so far it's in like a
vacuum sealed bag so I can't smell it
[Music]
New York City Diesel is one of Mike's
favorite or at least the Sour Diesel
smoke or the pre-roll whichever you feel
there might be a pipe here somewhere
that might be cleaning a little like
Christmas the gifts just keep getting
better our friends at Incredibles
extracts threw down a half a gram of
sour banned 0-9 fresh frozen so it's
wive resin concentrate it was kind of
like a sappy shatter sorry you guys I'm
burping excuse me so clear so gorgeous
it tasted
delicious I took half a gram so I do
basically did it all in one dad cuz
that's how I am but I inhaled and I
started to blow it out and I was like aw
it taste so good and I tried to like
catch my exhale so that I could exhale
real slowly and just savor all of that
dab flavor because it was so tasty shoe
so Shantanu Incredibles extracts
shout-out to Derek that shoot was
delicious I approve that's a great thing
to throw on a gift bag for a VIP I
really like yes thank you
my next favorite in here was from guys
garden cannabis creations this was a
caramel apple double karma edible this
had 200 milligrams of THC and 20
milligrams of CBD and in this little
package it's one of these uh like the
pop top pop it there you go on these pop
top containers there were two Tootsie
Roll size and shape products in there
wrapped in cellophane one of them was
Green it was the Apple the other one was
caramel colored and it was obviously the
caramel I took a little nibble off the
Apple it was [ __ ] delicious it's like
sour apple Jolly Ranchers
it tastes really good and then I nibble
off the caramel and it was good but not
my favorite kind of caramel ever it was
a little bit milky maybe might be the
description but then I pinched a little
of both off and threw them both in my
mouth though when you mix that Apple and
that caramel together I was [ __ ]
delicious so this edible is really good
200 milligrams of THC 20 milligrams of
CBD in a shop this probably would have
been a twenty dollar eighteen twenty
dollar edible it was delicious and I
approve so show it's a guy his garden I
really liked that then my favorite thing
in the bag this is last thing in the bag
and then we'll move on cuz I've been
going for way longer than I wanted to on
this I was surprised to see this Dutch
girl cannabis seeds there is a six pack
this is all packaged up properly for
Colorado retail this could be on the
shelf I heard that this was available
this actual product was available at a
local dispensary this is a stream called
the animal it's a hundred-percent sativa
enters a cross of Jabberwocky and ghost
train haze so I got a six pack of seeds
we may have to grow those in the future
here and see what comes
this so shout out to hunt shout it to
everybody from the secrets a shout out
to miles just to Adam he'll shout out to
DJ juggy yes everybody treats me like
like a VIP like we've done to so many
sessions that everybody knows us now
they see us they high-five us when they
walk in they know who we are I know who
they are it's really fun so shadows in
the secret sense we should move on from
that because we've been going for two
[ __ ] Lindsay and Bobo and Brett and
all the people that just let me come
kick it with them when I got there the
party was already started when I walked
in every was like scoot over make room
for Rasta Jeff like Bobo had a gift for
me Brett had part two of the gift for me
so they like come here try the gift and
then there was a podcast listener
sitting there who I only know you by
your Instagram name I cannot think your
real name right now but he wanted to
shake my hand right away Johnny be from
no goo wanted to run over shake my hand
right away
the funniest thing he was telling me how
much he loves oh geez so I brought him
this huge dab of some og 18 that I had
and I forgot a carb cap I had I had heat
of the nail and everything for him and I
forgot a carb cap so as he's taken the
dab I'm like Jason I'm horrid I forgot a
I forgot a carb cap there was the
countertop that was like granite
and he goes underneath it up and down
[Music]
it's awesome walking into an event and
being treated like a [ __ ] rocks yeah I
wish somebody would have told the people
at the door who I was uh-huh told me you
just come through I got you so when I
got there like I know go go I know hunt
though like we don't care it was a noble
for ro you you if I tell huh
you turned me away he's gonna be [ __ ]
pissed you better go let him know I'm
here and the guy came back as well
you're all square to go bro I'm sorry
I'm not trying to be a dick like hunt
told me personally his number and you
can compare it to yours pretty close to
be like you just gonna read my message
one seat other than to take a piss once
or twice shut up for the nachos thank
you I needed that the gift that Bobo
made for me there's a new thing let's
talk about this new thing and then we'll
actually get to the main topic of this
podcast the new trend so I've been
talking about Turks here in Colorado a
whole bunch in my head I've got a half
DRAM vial that's a small vial those
small vials with the screw on lid I've
got the shortie one ah it's some ghost
train Hays liquid turps my friend Tim
from New Mexico my friends Tim and
Charlie showed up from New Mexico with
this device that looked like a large
pipette it's real skinny on one end and
it tapers and gets thicker at the other
end and it's got like a mouthpiece made
onto it and they were dunking it into
the Terps and then letting the excess
drip off back into the container and
then without any fire you keep it tipped
down like you would have straw and you
just draw through they call it a Terp
straw just draw right through it with no
heat while it's cool you pull air
through it and you can taste the turps
incredibly strong and we were able to
put what I would normally dunk onto a
dab four people took two good draws off
of it before the flavor went away and I
don't know that I got any head change
cuz I was already high and we're smokin
rosin and stuff but it's an incredible
way to experience the flavor and the
essence of the terms without any fire or
without any waste I really thought it
was cool so I was talking about this to
bobo who is now learning how to blow
glass who's coming along super [ __ ]
quickly you guys if you could see what
he's doing I don't want to talk about
Elmo spill as beans he's got an idea
he's got a project that I think is
really it's the new [ __ ]
is the new thing I think this guy's
gonna kill but he made me a Terp straw
so shoutout to Bobo for the new sippin
turf straw it's got some red gold and
green line work it's got a little
Colorado mili is that a million's that
what that is inclusion it's a million
[Music]
he's making a modification to it because
it's a new product he's gonna modify it
perfected for me but he's making a
little modification that I requested but
shout out for that I totally appreciate
that but you're gonna see more people
taking cold sipped herbs at events and
things in the future here I think it's
gonna be something that will catch on
also I owe a shout-out to a glass artist
who's Cameron Reid it's hard to remember
I just had to say it slowly which is
funny because we'll talk about this but
shout it to cameron Reed glass well I'll
save that for another episode because
that's let's work on some of the main
topics of this podcast so let's quickly
go through the band names in Oregon they
have medical marijuana available and
they have recently banned some of the
names I've got a they legalized
marijuana for all adults
what a year to half ago and they're just
now getting through to implementing
regulations yeah they've had stores and
like zoning for a minute
and one of the new regulations is some
common strain names are going away in
the state of Oregon because the second
half the article is not even related to
anything involved in what this is they
just ramble on about some stuff this
comes from The Oregonian and the
headline says no more Girl Scout cookies
and other popular names on pot packaging
state says and this is by Noel Crombie
and the article goes like this popular
names such as Girl Scout cookies in
Charlotte's Web won't be allowed on the
labeling and packaging of medical and
recreational marijuana in Oregon under
rules approved by the state Friday the
Oregon liquor Liquor Control Commission
said it had reviewed about 500 marijuana
strain names and identified about 20
that may appeal to children
commissioners saw the rule change after
hearing from members of the public who
objected to the
my old friendly names I'm gonna
interject here um [ __ ] is a kid doing in
the dispensary anyway how's a kid gonna
see that on there Lindsay is the voice
of reason today people have really been
able to get legislators around the
country to listen to and so when we get
to the Colorado rules in a minute the
reasons they were implemented are
essentially identical and I I agree we
need to keep cannabis products out of
the hands of children a medical
condition that they need it I just don't
want my kid taking my cannabis to my
shoe making this to school your kid and
your kid [ __ ] freaking out at school
[Music]
don't worry the strains themselves
haven't been right yeah yeah completely
there been some breather breeders have
been talking on Facebook forums and such
about this the article goes the rule
improved one day before the state
licenses recreational marijuana
retailers prohibits words that refer to
products that are commonly associated
with minors or marketed by minors a
chairman of the Commission called the
new requirement a common-sense approach
if you walk through a toy store and you
can identify things that are straight
names those are probably inappropriate
he said it's also as simple as that
agency also won't allow streams that
refer to illicit drugs such as LSD and
blow LSD is just lemon Sour Diesel it's
just way easier to [ __ ] write and
blow is a stupid [ __ ] name for a
straight name so cool I'm gonna watering
track yeah we'll get to that list a list
of outlawed proper names Girl Scout
cookies Grape Ape Candy Land Charlotte's
Web Cinderella
doctor who bubblicious Smurf Bruce
Banner Death Star's Skywalker and Jedi
Kush those strains will still be allowed
in organs recreational shops retailers
and marijuana producers and processors
can use initials or some others
shorthand reference instead of the full
strain name okay doesn't have to get
renamed or anything yeah but it's pretty
gentle but it's also pretty silly it is
kind of silly you can have Skywalker or
Jedi kook okay I don't know how they're
doing in Oregon but in Colorado it's
blocked printed in black lettering
that's how the screen name gets printed
on pretty much every product it leaves a
legal dispensary I mean it's never down
the front like the toys-r-us logos
different colors what's this you fought
for kids eyes
it's just computer printed on a
packaging label with a shitload other
information on it okay let me be the
voice of reason again
we are still able to legally buy weed in
the shop so is it that they in the
marijuana industry and community we have
such bigger battles to be fighting than
the fact that we can't use the name Girl
Scout cookies I'm not being mean I'm
just saying like to me it just feels
like we can all buy illegal weed like I
get it it's a bummer and it's a big deal
but at the end of the day it's not like
you have to rename the strain to be you
know something completely ridiculous
that that's nothing to do with cookies
you know what I'm saying like they're
not saying you can't use any cookie name
or any they took like 20 names out of
500 which in the grand scheme of things
is do you think Bounty Killer would make
this list the different ones we've care
I've had a shelf in front of me I've
been working the legal industry and I
think about this list when I read the
list I was like well there's a bunch
missing like if this is the criteria
[Music]
Candyland Charlotte's Web
that's all children's dog shows a kids
book character there's a company that's
spent on us a fortune and like half a
decade marketing Charlotte's Web around
the country right yeah [ __ ]
Cinderella I mean girl scout cookies
we're just gonna call that GSC and it
also says derivative strains you can't
use Platinum Girl Scouts or Thin Mints
either so listen you probably can't use
dos Eidos
see those are banned well yeah every the
fruit names I mean how many different
ones vaguely meet like an item a kid
might have for dessert also right sour
lemon sherbert
doctor who was taken because it's a
fictional character currently marketed
to children basically any fictional
character like I was when I first read
this I was like well some jackass made
an Obama crush like is that gone too
because kids know the president I mean
how far they go on with this particular
and that's why I have an issue with it
because as a regulation it's a little
bizarre right like you can ban cartoons
from the name or from the logo you can
do a lot of other things to make sure
that the products don't target children
but banning stuff that's gonna be like
just words in black print like some of
them makes a little bit of sense but
some of its it's just gonna be a
regulatory pain in the ass down the road
for sure just more hoops to jump through
just just more bitching and complaining
for them to do about kids a lot of it's
subjective
yeah and that's what makes it a
regulatory issue in my mind any we'll
get to some Colorado rules here in just
a second it's not subjective let's jump
right to that then that's a good segue
Mike since we're like 27 minutes in
let's get to this about halfway through
the show it's a perfect time to move on
to my my favorite topic of the show
Colorado recently until the first I was
allowed to walk into a dispensary a
medical dispensary or recreational
dispensary and I was able to buy without
any special paperwork I think to the
best of my knowledge I was allowed to
buy two ounces of concentrates I mean I
could buy two ounces of shatters that
correct Lindsey says yes Mike yes in a
wreck shop just the one okay so in a
medical shop I could get my two ounces
I'm a medical patient and a recreational
shop I was allowed to buy one ounce
concentrate which is is it enough
concentrate that's that's not a lot of
concentrate I mean if you're me I mean
that there was [ __ ] two pounds of
[ __ ] rosin on this tables two couple
of days ago play announcer to is
substantial amount now the new rule is
no matter who you are no matter where
you're shopping 8 gram limit the
original I'm pretty sure that's on the
medical side too I'm pretty sure the
article that I read has misled me and
I'm glad you guys have corrected me um
recreational for a hundred percent sure
you can only buy 8 grams of concentrate
now and there are other rules for
edibles and think other items that are
sold by the milligram like edibles and
vape pen cartridges so if I'm not
mistaken I'm doing this from memory
everybody else is a fun out cheater
fact-checking like wow right now you
keep talking go slow uh edible and vape
pen limit is now 800 milligrams it used
to be 2800 and concentrate limits are
now what seven or eight eight eight
grams a concentrate I don't know these
are just recreational rules I think the
only thing that changed on the medical
side was compliance some edible
compliance labeling imprinting on bars
so there are two different rule changes
in cholera are three different rule
changes in Colorado one limits what
people can buy one limits the shape of
certain gummies animals period and but
mostly affecting gummies right now
market wide and then the last rule is
edibles in Colorado now the actual item
has to carry a stamp and I actually took
notes today post an interview with Larry
woke the head of the Department of
Colorado Health and Environment the CDP
AG and somebody from the top of the meed
the marijuana Enforcement Division
the edible symbols there's two
exceptions so like every piece of
chocolate has to carry a little if it's
recreational a yellow diamond with the
letters THC exclamation point in it in
the medical just as the M right for
medical oh they might have dropped the
color that was one of the original
things and people were like well how do
we make it yellow on a brownie without
frosting or somesuch
it took a while for some companies to
get this implemented I've seen one
company that they just made a disk out
of sugar so it's a hundred percent
edible but it has the logo on it and
then they've fixed it to the top of
their product with like melted
marshmallow it is weird in practice but
it's pretty tasty but the only
exceptions to carrying that symbol are
liquids the liquids manufacturers
managed to get the legislature to see
reason and make a specific exception for
liquids so that you know you you can't
stamp a liquid and they were literally
tough for a while talking about making
it having gold style show longer
floaties this or somesuch
or only doing single serving packages of
liquids so it could only come in a 10
milligram serving recreationally which
would pretty much kill recreational
liquids but they carved out an exception
it can still be a hundred milligram
liquid container as long as the
measuring device is part of that
container um and stuff like granola now
has to come in single serving packages
anything like any edible that can't
carry the snap has to come in
individually individual serving size
packages with the label affixed to that
packaging so that you can't leave it on
a table and somebody come along and pick
it up which is a felony in its own right
before we came up with the label it's
still a felony with the label it's like
leaving a loaded gun on the table like
it's it's wildly inappropriate adult
behavior
Wow yeah that's the basic edible rundown
did you find yes the article I had to go
through three articles actually find the
truth medical marijuana will remain
unchanged only one article said that the
first article that I was reading was
actually sponsored by a dispensaries so
they were trying to leave medical
marijuana out on purpose I think because
of the way that it was worded it totally
made it look like it was all over the
board so I'm glad a lot of people are
sweating this because so far in Colorado
not a single licensed dispensary has
screwed up the purchase limit rule
no one's been cited or fined for selling
over the limit yet yeah I was only been
a couple days well no in Colorado no
shop has been cited for that and that's
sort of it's one of those little random
points of pride for a while our team our
teen ID checks things we were in ninety
nine percent which is unheard of in
liquor tobacco yeah and we were real
proud of that and then we had one bad
round and got knocked down to ninety two
just like alcohol and tobacco and that
hurt but they don't even check alcohol
tobacco um they do but it's not nearly
what they do with with marijuana they
were doing numb it was a real ID in the
person and the ID was wearing a hat and
the person checking the ID was supposed
to catch that that was the last ID sting
that I heard about performed on a
marijuana store that's sketchy trying to
[ __ ] with us I know that's checking
compliance to the nth degree
marijuana shops also face ten times the
fine that a tobacco or alcohol retailer
would of course um it's ten grand if you
ask so cigarettes or alcohol to somebody
underage is the possible fine let's
marijuana it's a hundred that could ruin
a business yeah I could just close you
down no matter how big your dispensary
is a hundred thousand dollar fine cuz I
guess we could be careful
that's why one of the reasons that never
happen recreational shoppers can now
only buy eight grams yep
does that mean that people that come to
do that means the ounce Till's are gonna
go away at the REC shops no more cheap
ounce deals because you can't buy an
ounce because you'd see concentrate
deals like for twenty five hundred forty
pounds well and there's no end either
and so you can't get your your limit in
flour and your limit in hash it's been
going around this shows how the
breakdown is how many grams of hash
equals how many grams of flour how many
grams of milligrams of edibles equal how
many grams of flour I don't pay
attention to charters I'm not working in
a budtender station there was this great
like three month period where bud
tenders didn't have to do pointless math
in their head all day long like counting
to seven over and over in different
fractions depending on what the order
was or whatever we was just twenty eight
was the limit and it was real simple and
now there's this that they are we all
have to keep our heads it sucks just
more regulation to follow do you think
is just gonna make people go to more
stores people that are smurfing yeah but
this rule really isn't for them there
hasn't been a lot of that that's why
they just recently upped the
out-of-state purchase limit to announce
okay when this rule was originally
passed they were talking about out of
Staters can only buy one and a half
grams of hash I laughed the first time I
read it because I looked down at my case
and I was like everything comes in one
gram containers yeah you can buy one
gram or well we've got to talk to all
our distributors and see if they can do
I have video but they hammered it out
and then just recently a couple months
ago they up that limit someone I don't
think they're worried about smurfin
there's just so many in the legislature
was like wait we let people buy 28 grams
a hash or 208 was it 2,800 grams of
edibles it's 28 of the 280 of the most
potent edibles souls in a wreck shop
well has to shit-ton edibles yeah I've
seen people leave the spot with [ __ ]
bags but it happens from time to time
it's just one of those things and now
with these new limits it's just anybody
that's looking to do that's just gonna
make more stops but it's a weird set of
rules like you can tell it's not the
same group of people writing all of
these can I ask you a completely random
question that's off topic sure you guys
have both been bud tenders you have
plenty of experience behind the bud
counter and ringing people up what is
the largest ticket you have ever rung up
a single person for my largest person
yeah a wreck shop okay lenz do you
remember do you want to say it is it
beat Mike 1,700 and I'm pretty sure it's
a medical shop you can buy so much more
do I know the purchaser that's true I
just work it basically am all of the
rules I follow other than the ID checks
she works in a medical shop she's gonna
write down a number she's gonna write it
down and we're gonna guess
she just kept typing zeros what the [ __ ]
okay it's five digits anybody tipped you
or to carry you for that peoples how
they have all that extra money exhale
[ __ ] tip that's weird
we didn't see Molly and just realize
that great time Mike did you get to
cover all of your edible stuff that you
wanted to talk about oh I think I hid
all the new rule changes we covered the
the purchase limit we covered that
[Music]
changing you can no longer do human
shapes animal shapes fruit shapes
anything that resembles a candy that's
on the show yeah or anything that's
identical to its non-medicated market
counterpart so all of your gummies are
now squares Oh which works out well cuz
it's really easy to imprint the new
symbol into a ruler you know what else
how are they handling the sodas you can
still do hundred milligram beverages in
the rec market the container has to
carry the new label and the dosing
instruments so it has to come with like
an equal medicine top okay so that you
can dose out your ten milligram dose
that's how they do weed shots with
friends
that's pretty little tagline when I was
selling those all day have you ever
drank like the can upon for the Keef
Cola oh yeah
do you feel like you get high more
quickly the liquids definitely
and your stomach doesn't have to break
down the brownie yeah right it's just
absorbable quicker it's like you drink
it and then you go to do whatever you're
doing and then you turn your head to one
way to look at something you go oh hi
with can a punch check the label there's
a range of THC in the can of punches I
do 200 the back of the label it might be
like to 30 in the rack market there's
like it's a 10 15 20 milligrams swing
that you can see on the back I was
really pumped to see that and I love to
see totally random everything will be
lab tested go ahead we had a customer
appreciation day at the shop and I -
Keith Cole a hundred milligram orange
soda before it not thinking like
anything of it a couple days before that
about how like drinks are sublingually
and they like hit you harder and I was
like wow you're an idiot Lindsey you
just chug that thing right before you
came in not even like didn't taste that
we got a bunch of 10 milligram samples
at one point and I took the four flavour
samples we got home and without thinking
about it drank all four of them and
liked it jot it down a little flavor
review about each one and edible ruin to
an extent I think about 250 milligrams
right now is just about perfect for me I
don't want to go too much farm pass
there because that's when I started
getting a little goofy story getting a
little hazy but I'm back on the edible
horse so when I see you I will not it
probably not you
[Music]
get a feed if you say more than six or
seven or twelve times and it's got to be
a word gonna leave the kids alone they
have enough trouble Lindsay my friend
how can people find you on social media
let's hear about all 37 of your accounts
um I have the travelling stoner
Instagram and I would love to troll your
website share with everybody yes thank
you both for coming on the show Mike I
hope to get you on the next episode
Lindsay we may have you here too
somebody asked me a question and it
directly says I hope you and Mike can
answer this so Nora feedback the better
we know what we know what to dig up and
what's part of our ridiculous amount of
cannabis knowledge to throw at you
that's the truth if you've got questions
that you would like me to answer or Mike
or even Lindsay you can send me
questions for me hard at hotmail.com let
me know what you'd like to know we will
talk about it here on the podcast we'll
give you a shout out if we don't happen
to know a good answer to your question
will find the person in the community
who does and drag them on a podcast Mike
you were like my volleyball partner you
set him up and I will spike him bro
speaking of not knowing the answers to
some things people have asked me to do
an episode about LED lighting I
personally have never drawn with LEDs I
don't know [ __ ] about LEDs I've got two
friends they claim they're gonna drive
from Denver and do an LED episode with
me got a boy I know one of them will
show up I know him personally the other
guy I don't know so I don't know if I
can get him to drive he lives about 130
miles from here if he's willing to drive
to the podcast I'd love to get him on so
maybe I'll get both those cats on we'll
do a quick episode about LED lighting
also I'm trying to get in touch with the
guy that makes the 315 s I think I
commented on one of his Facebook post he
did not reply I'm not even sure it's the
right dude so I'm gonna get in touch
with the dude that makes in 315 the Le
sees the white emitting ceramics we'll
get that guy on the podcast we'll talk
about those in the
also check this out you guys have asked
for an episode about cannabis and
pregnancy
I have done a lot of research there is
so much stuff out there I honestly am
not qualified to do an episode about
cannabis and pregnancy I'm not a doctor
I I'm not a woman and those are two
things that I feel like I should be at
least one of to do an episode about
pregnancy if you are either a doctor or
a woman or a woman doctor or if you've
got experience with cannabis and
pregnancy and you know more than I do
and you're more comfortable with the
subject I'd love to get you on we could
talk all about it I do only thing I
could throw it on that topic is the
relevant laws you might be breaking and
look repercussions you might face
legally and how that system works in
places like Colorado because I will know
I used to read this all the time and in
patients charts when I work with locked
up teens um so it's something that's
gonna follow your kid around for that
life oh man so um if the hospital
chooses to drug test you or your baby
during the delivery and if you've got
dreadlocks or if you look like me as
soon as it comes out for the most part
the system works it's just if anybody
involved in the birthing process like
that whole hospital stay decide so yeah
let's drug test that mom and that baby
then it happens and it's just if anybody
happens to make that decision the local
anti pop group down here they're working
with one of the hospitals and one
they've got one month worth of data and
they're like half the babies we tested
came back positive for THC and that's
the end of their statement if you dig a
little deeper ten babies were tested
during that period five of them came
back positive for THC doesn't tell you
what was up with the other five but it's
part of the National legalization
conversation like it could be a cool
episode we find the right people yeah
I don't have it's not my wheelhouse I
guess you know I literally just had to
look up all of these laws because like I
worked in the league or work in the
legal industry and had a kid while I did
that right what do you do both of you
have been boat owners Mike I don't know
if we should or no longer a budtender
you worry but tender Lindsay is about
tender what do you do if a pregnant
customer comes in and tries to buy
cannabis um it's perfectly legal to
purchase it because you it was like what
happened with us is the I don't are we
gonna do this for this show
there's just something you brought up
random way and all of a sudden this is
like a two-hour show now they serve turn
no issues when my wife was pregnant she
stopped at the gas station a couple of
times and bought me cigarettes like the
second time she's like if I could do
that again like I wasn't paying
attention it's just something she's done
for forever
I was like there's a whole bunch of
stuff the doctor tells you you shouldn't
consumer do while you're pregnant in
it's all legal
well not all is like heroin and coke and
sugar on that one but like 99 percent of
its legal and it's just not advice so
please you know or even have more
education on it than I do and you're
more comfortable talking about it than I
am
I feel like that's more of a woman's
topic and I should have a woman involved
in this to help me through this so that
I don't sound like a sexist dude that's
uneducated so let's get a doctor or or a
lady to come help me out this one I
would love to do this episode I'd love
to do it a lot of people have questions
I've gotten probably more than three
emails on this probably three to five
emails or questions about cannabis and
pregnancy so I'd love to get some help
on that one because I think that's all
that we have got for you in this episode
I want to thank my friends again for
coming and hanging out with me any time
I wanna give a huge shout out to max for
getting me back on the Edible bandwagon
shots of Shuman bars
banana pudding hundred milligram THC bar
set me straight also shot it's my
friends at Gaia's garden shout out to
make the dog
some kind of alarm going off it's like
shut up and see the show you guys
alright it's all I got for you ladies
and gentlemen I'd love it if you'd send
me some questions girl from heart at
hotmail.com she's got a product you'd
like me to review or if you want to
sponsor the show I'd love to hear from
you make sure you check out the show on
talk radio the shows now available on
talk radio Wednesdays at 1:00 p.m. big
shout out to my buddy citizen J also the
show's available on iTunes and stitcher
and you can catch the most 100 recent
episodes on I read genetics Colorado
dot-com ladies gentlemen that's all I've
got free this week big shout out to boba
blaster cub a shadow plant in just
benson until next time take the fat dad
and get your money
[Music]
[Applause]
you