[Music]
now welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 272 of The Grove
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
let's write a pure new grower if you're
a professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who
is just curious about the current state
of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band to let him use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
crew
ladies and gentlemen excuse the coffee
crunchy shitty sound and voice I've had
a little bit of a cold for the past week
and I apologize it's coming through on
the microphone a couple people mentioned
they could hear it in last week's
episode
I apologize for sounding like [ __ ] you
guys but the show must go on as a
professional podcaster I will put out a
show joining me this evening to make
sure the show doesn't sound completely
terrible is white Mike welcome back to
the show brother thanks man thanks for
covering for me dude why like off a
little bit over yeah man so wow you guys
this episode is coming out on Christmas
so if you're doing Christmas Merry
Christmas if you listening Christmas
there's miss Opie had a good Christmas
this isn't going to be a super intensive
episode you probably won't need a
notebook you're not gonna want to take a
whole lot of notes on this episode it's
Christmas I don't know how many people
are going to listen to a Christmas
episode this one may just get lost in
the mix like you know you're gonna hang
out take some dabs and talk about if you
lose one or two yes yes we're gonna
we're gonna take a little Christmas
vacation also while we're on the
podcaster and hanging out take some dabs
yeah I like to start off the show most
of the time by sharing what we've been
dabbing on I started dabbing this
episode on pura-vida high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract with a little bit
of Clementine batter I couldn't get the
pura-vida to stick to the dabber so I
just put it enough of a Clementine
batter a good base a nice mortar yeah
it's stuck in there real well and I just
stick those little crystals into there
and then it gives me a nice little dab
of course I had some of the Clementine
leftover because it was miss JB's
birthday happy late birthday miss JB if
you listen to this I shed a little
birthday party at the studio 64 and I
got her some Clementine to smoke she
took the big old fat dab of that she
took a giant dab of some I don't
remember the stream but she had a giant
crystal a giant hdfs e crystal mess had
to be at least half a gram and she took
the whole dab she didn't choke very much
she got high as [ __ ] she melted into the
couch she had a great birthday so that
is it I'm talking about Jamie's birthday
happy birthday and also big shout out to
all the bearded men and their wives that
joined us for the birthday party I
looked around at the party and every
dude there
killer beard shadow gentlemen thanks for
joining us everybody the kid the party
that was a good time I'm gonna turn down
that music it's making my brain go too
fast um yes it's been a long week holy
crap yeah it's been a long couple of
weeks buddy it has been a long year
we're wrapping up the year there's only
gonna be the last is this the last
podcast of the year that the people will
hear this is it probably next one will
be in 2018 all the future the future so
yeah long weekend Monday I didn't even
go to work I felt so shitty Monday
everybody was sick it was the skeleton
crew for the first half of the week yeah
take your vitamins you guys a skeleton
crew if you're working with a big group
of people take your vitamins because
it's wintertime it ones getting sick
there's like three different nasty colds
going around our area and it's not fun
to be alive right now
yeah way you know you've got to just
dodge a lot of Germans in Pueblo right
you got to wash your hands you got to
drink a lot of water you got to take
some vitamins you got to take the
emergency or whatever might be the other
night I straight looked like Skeletor
all my skin was all dry and wrinkly and
craggy from the freaking weather and
your nose as well
yep yeah everybody's got a runny nose
around here take care of yourselves you
guys that's what I'm saying if you're in
a cold place take care of your vitamins
people yeah Tuesday I went to work but
then all the work crew was like you look
like a Fogle Tommy go home so I came and
slept all the Tuesday and then Wednesday
I went to work and was half-assed
Thursday I was mostly there and today
today was management day where all the
management comes and you do that [ __ ] so
it was eating's like yeah there wasn't
much physical [ __ ] so it was kind of
chilled out so I just got to walk around
and talk and [ __ ] do all that
management [ __ ] today's ready jazz so a
lot of strategic I did happen live [ __ ]
got managed today a lot of things did
get managed shot at or our buddy he
doesn't want to be named I'm pretty sure
but the guys shot it too that dude for
coming and helping us out today
um what else do we want to talk about we
covered JB's birthday happy birthday
again miss JB big shout outs all the
people to join me for the birthday party
ah shout at our friend bacon that drove
down from Denver Denver doesn't consume
our bacon does not consume cannabis and
he came to a cannabis social club to
hang out with a bunch of potheads on
miss JB's birthday so that was cool
shout out to bacon I am excited I talked
about
I talked about it on Instagram live this
week perhaps later this evening is
pollen time they're ready I'm pretty
sure they're ready I was looking at them
last night three days ago you were like
they're probably ready I should weigh
today yeah
and I'm Way impressed you've made it to
Friday yeah well it's Friday it's so
much easier for me to clean up on a
Friday I don't have as much a time
constraint before I go to another garden
that I could destroy someone who works
in the same commercial facility as you
do I appreciate you waiting yes tonight
may be the night that the pollen gets
chucked I've got two clothes of the same
male they're dropping pollen really
heavily and there's uh I'm excited about
the Durbin poison and star dog to tell
you the truth they're gonna come for tea
Durbin Kraus that's gonna be really neat
I don't have any idea of what its gonna
be called I have ideas of what I think
it's gonna smell like I know what some
of the phenotypes I'm hoping for gonna
smell like I'm hoping to bring back some
of that old landrace Durbin with some of
those giant colas but I don't want [ __ ]
that takes like 14 weeks to finish so
I'm hoping I've got some like ten week
donkey dick and it's licorice scented
trichome laden funk going on out of that
crosses my goal with any look it'll
happen it will happen there's a couple
of things I already know I'm really
looking forward to about next year and
that's on the list
ah there's star dog in there and start
August a great commercial grower she
grows big fat dense colas she smells
really well but there's something
missing from the high and I think
putting that a rise resin on it will fix
that I'm looking forward to trying it
it's gonna be a fun next year and then
something that smells really amazing in
that room the smell is overwhelming the
room right now is a platinum tangi she's
got a phone that'll fill up the whole
building smells so good in that room
just because of the platinum tangi
there's a cactus cooler and they're also
which usually stinks up the room but
right now it's the Platinum tangi doing
it yep Tim G's just I mean just that
citrus kind of it's almost like a citrus
and a body order functions for days
I'm thinking about that is why I paused
I was a citrus and body odor that's it's
uh I've called it when the extract when
you smoke
tangey dabs or even Clementine dabs too
hot I think it tastes like orange
chicken or garlic chicken
it smells like to me like garlic like
tofu garlic orange tofu but it would be
orange chicken from back in the dam and
had chicken and [ __ ] years but it
smells like orange chicken or garlic you
remember orange chicken from 1997 yes
circa circa 97 yes but yeah so pollen
this week which means in the future
there will be new crosses for people to
try and then there will be replenishing
of things that are unavailable currently
at the hell a dank seed bank so yeah
also a big shot it's my friends at the
hella dank seed make I should have
mentioned them at the top of the show
there they're just friends of mine and
you know since we're talking about seeds
will talk about the hella dank seed me
if you're looking to add something new
to your garden I would recommend
visiting you know the traditional New
Year's gift is seeds if I'm not mistaken
that might be it I'm pretty sure that's
the new thing dank seed dot store for
all your IRA genetics needs they're also
uh do it they carry other other brands
there as well but check that out um what
else should we hit on before before we
start a ramble fest here oh pretty sure
ramble Fest is already at least third
gear but I'm just getting started
would you Oh hashtag they like it when
we ramble something we did not mention
yet um
Iowa shout out to some friends of ours
what's up friends there's everybody shot
it to all of our friends if you've ever
met seen heard of read about I'm gonna
shout not the people that have gotten a
high-five or better hmm I'm just gonna
extend it
I'm gonna go if a butterfly landed on me
and then landed on you if you read rode
on the same subway car as me if you've
been in the same taxi as me whatever
what's up shout out shout out this got
weird quickly know what I was gonna say
though there is another podcast all
about cannabis a lot of people say Rasta
Jeff you've got the best cannabis show I
appreciate that you can tell me that
that's [ __ ] awesome I love it that
it's your favorite I feel like there's
no cop
tition when it comes to cannabis podcast
because we are all as long as we're not
coming on and being like I shot up 17
marijuana's and I'm seeing the devil I'm
gonna rape white [ __ ] as long as you
come on and you talk about cannabis in a
positive way we're all friends I want to
support all the cannabis podcast there's
a reason the word favorite exists yeah
yeah there are a couple cannabis
podcasts and honestly for the living
[ __ ] out of me I can't listen to him
they just just and kanae in cannabis and
I'm like a [ __ ] shut up alright but
I'm still friends with those guys you
know what I mean if they're like hey
we're we're gonna get shut down if you
don't give me two dollars but fun Kim
two dollars like right yeah as I support
all the cannabis podcasts there's no
competition I love that some people feel
I am the best that I am their favorite
that's [ __ ] awesome but the the
podcast if I were to listen to another
podcast frequently and the reason that I
don't is because I don't want to
contaminate my myself I don't want to
recite somebody else's podcast voice or
style or whatever I don't want to do it
on accident I catch myself turning into
Joe Rogan occasionally when I go on a
rant
I'm Dennis Miller and Joe Rogan Dennis
Miller from the early 90s you can get
some a lot of people our age rant like
Dennis Miller's no cure for cancer of
them yeah yeah I used to watch deal with
the show that he learned why I can't
even remember the show here on HBO show
it was [ __ ] hilarious
that was when I was kind of new at
smoking pot at home like I still lived
with my mom at the time and my parents
and [ __ ] I was young but I would smoke
pot at home and she knew but she
wouldn't say [ __ ] so when Dennis
Miller's comedy show I still I wish I
could think of the name of it
when Dennis Miller's comedy show came on
on HBO it was like 99% sure it was no
cure for cancer yeah it was like a
sketch show weekly but every time that
would come on I remember I would pack up
the bomb [ __ ] edge of the bed and hit
the bong and get all stone and laugh my
ass off to that Dennis Miller [ __ ]
show it was hilarious
but so and then I also I catch myself
doing Rogan and Dennis Miller and a lot
of times Joey I catch myself doing Joey
Diaz sometimes when when you're going on
a write specially on a good solo show
and you're fairly baked yeah Joey pop
out occasionally yeah but sometimes less
than intentionally I've heard so much
Joe Rogan and Joey Diaz
said I don't want to do that I don't
want to turn into Danny Danko or Adam
Dunn or even more specifically Scottie
real and the dude right ah because
that's who I'm talking about Scottie
ruined the dude hosts a show called the
dude gross show and they gave us a
shout-out they gave me a shout-out
technically but they kind of shared it
with white Mike every episode the dude
gross show does a segment called the
executive producer and they pick
somebody who has inspired them or done
something that they feel it's basically
how I give everyone a shout-out at the
end of the show they do it at the start
of the show they say executive producer
this episode and a few days ago they
said Rasta Jeff and they gave me a nice
shadows and then they mentioned that I
do the show by myself
and a lot of that a lot of the times I
do probably 70% of these podcasts by
myself but then they mentioned white
Mike comes and joins him and he has a
lot of cool people on there with him
also so they specifically said white
Mike I might I'm I'm you how do I even
say this I'm my least favorite guest
that you have on I think I like the
shows where everybody else is on way
better yeah you you already know what
you're gonna say in you don't find you
interesting sometimes I find me
interesting I feel the same about you
Mike it's about 35-40 I look forward to
win certain guests I know we're gonna be
on and like I know when they're coming
over a record and then when I know
they've recorded I'm like what the [ __ ]
isn't or no yet right my friends that
have been on my show I want you back I
just feel it feels awkward asking my
friends do you have time to come be on
my show because everyone's [ __ ] busy
especially with the holidays especially
since most of you are growers and this
last year's been insane for every
everybody a lot of us like myself run a
commercial grow and then do consulting
for somebody else's grow and then try to
have our own small private grow and then
we also have lives you know what I mean
I teach from Les and Dragons lives other
gigs we could have done this tomorrow
because I'm gonna be Christmas show
sorry about a giant cough did not mean
to throw out a giant cough yeah it's
then there's a cold going around sorry
folks
yeah we're trying I'm smelling a little
bit too
I'm just we're super busy getting over
here even for me like to do a 45-minute
show like we work together we just slip
over here after work and yeah I looked
at my headings like podcasts go drive
right to my house so that we can record
a podcast right now let's go Friday
shows it's dumb luck my wife is out with
the niece and the kids so I had 45
minutes where I could squeeze away free
otherwise I'd be cooking right now nice
like I feel a little bit anxious because
normally I have responsibilities for
this segment of time during the day
they're like who's got this going on who
took care of this yep but anyway ah I
won't want to get more of my friends on
here it's just weird asking people hey
come be on the podcast all you guys have
good stuff to contribute but all means
and send him a text and say you want to
get on the show yeah do it let's get
together Facebook me message me somehow
you guys are all invited back come be on
the show please what I see did you don't
worry don't worry I'll ask you but
anyway the dude gross gave us a huge
huge shout out ah dude the dude gross
say if I were listening to a cannabis
podcast that's the one I would hit play
if you look at my playlist it's the
spliff podcast with buh who's taking a
little break she's on a hiatus shout-out
to Bo and then the next podcast in line
is our friends at the dude gross both of
those are my favorites list the dude
grows cup is coming up in April I know
the date of ready but I don't remember
off the top of my head I've got it in a
message so the dude grows Cup is coming
if things line up for me I will go to
that event I have to make sure there's
nothing else more pressing at the time I
have to figure out priorities and work
and all that [ __ ] but I should be able
to make that so right stone April tends
to be a pretty busy month for us yeah
yeah in this industry and yeah it's huge
there's a bunch of celebrating that the
community does during then but when you
work in the industry that's that's your
Christmas it's yes the dude or Scotty
what do you guys message me let me know
about the dude gross cup let me know
about boots let me know about vending
can I bend the seeds at the dude gross
cup how can I set up a booth and Bend
the seeds that would have a lot to do
with my attendance best to be there so
let's see yeah I'm gonna press pause and
I'm gonna pull up a message for Mike why
don't you just talk for a second you're
here for a reason
talk for a couple seconds about some
[ __ ] while I find a screenshot of a
message that I
oh you put me on the spot well I hope
you all had a good Christmas everybody
that cool cousin go for a good walk
before dinner introduce them to the
podcast yeah but if you do smoke with
somebody that's new go gentle don't
don't see her them away from cannabis
yep go easy give them the spiel about
how you eat one out of one way two hours
don't eat all the candy bar give them
give them a nice gentle intro or maybe
if it's like you know your cousin who
thinks he's cool and thinks he's hard no
that's like Darrin a teenager to drink
all the 151 like they're gonna try and
then you're gonna feel like an [ __ ]
for doing it or always go easy or are
you know you probably will really all
depends whose car they throw up and
right just gave me a shitty flashback I
think I just gave everyone that's why
it's not cool to do that I heard this
gurgling noise then I looked in my
rearview mirror and I wish I hadn't
looked in the mirror because I just
watched vomit flat of both nose holes
and the mouth all into the backseat of
my car and I was like oh that's why you
don't give a drunk people a ride home
yep yep oops all right so I did find the
message here ah no that's not the
correct message I lied I gotta keep
going there's a screenshot and it's just
not a screenshot of the correct message
here I think this is it alright this was
so it says question for the community
and then I'm gonna kind of a detects I
don't know where the original message
came from somebody took a screenshot of
this and then sent this to me and said
what's your opinion so it says question
for the community first I like to say I
already know what I'm going to do in
regards to this however I'm curious to
see if there is one sentiment over the
other then it says scenario grower gets
seeds from a breeder and/or a seed bank
finds a rare cut or a select fee know
what getting a cut back to the breeder
be the right thing to do
to be clear nobody has asked for it or
has suggested doing so the cut isn't
necessarily for breeding but more as a
gesture or would you just keep it and
sit on it for your own enjoyment and
then this guy also kind of asked me how
do you feel about people breeding with
your seeds once you sell them seeds so
the first part is to be more clear about
the question if somebody were to go
obtain I region that exceeds however you
get them if you get them from me if you
get them from the hella dank seed bank
if they fell out of the sky however you
ended up with them if you were to grow
them and you were to find something
stellar are you supposed to get me a
clone of that I don't expect [ __ ] but it
would be cool if you live near me I
think if you expect it you're a
douchebag but if you offer it like it's
definitely not expected but it's it's
cool and sometimes it's probably not
wanted like if you got one like our
friends at organic I haven't arised the
tested at 35 percent cool I'd love a
clone of that but if I don't get one
that's fine with me because there's the
same level if I told you I had a fire
arise you know and did you want to cut
you probably say no come over and check
it out before yeah yeah I'd go look at
yours like I'd go take pictures of it
I'm thinking of all the people used to
bring those half-dead clones in to -
madam are back in the day that's wrong
with my plants yo and I look at it and
be like yo that's cotton balls
oh no that's spider mite webbing yeah
yeah well mites my take on it is I sold
that seed like that seed went like if it
went to a distributor he paid me for it
and then you paid him for it now
passed its left me twice it's yours
right I don't expect anything in return
when you go to only very recently was
this even possible right when you go to
the grocery store wherever your local
store is and you buy all your
ingredients to make [ __ ] what are you
gonna make tonight for dinners and
pizzas or whatever and then you go home
and you make your pizza and you bake it
you don't drive back to the store and
offer everyone at the store hey I got
this [ __ ] here here's a slice of the
pizza I made yeah but if I give you some
like chickens and then you raise them up
like you might bring me some chicken
yeah might bring it depends on the water
though yeah well I don't expect anything
in return
I know another part of this is a breeder
has probably grown that strain enough to
have found that phenotype that you've
got it's gonna be very unlikely but you
find something if you've got it odds are
they've seen it yeah yeah and we've
probably got a we've got the fire
phenotype it is a really cool gesture if
you live near the breeder like our
friends and organic ax are in
Albuquerque maybe if they are coming
this way and there's they have to have a
medical marijuana patient oh no because
we're legit here so they'd have to have
a caller New Mexico medical marijuana
patient in the car and then the commit
is different federal crime lab your
dress yeah but there's no feds sitting
on the line between New Mexico and
Colorado
what if there's that line what if the
wine is as thick of it as the tip of
this pin and they set the seeds right on
the tip of this pin to where it's half
on Colorado half on New Mexico and Rob's
it but when guy picks it up cops aren't
meant to debate technicalities with you
they're meant to hit you with the
nightstick until you strap resist and
ruin your life however if you wanted to
bring me the con wherever you could do
it you could I be I'd be happy with that
but it's not required once I have once
that seed has been given out that is
your seed unless the offers yes it was a
tester and there was an agreement if
it's a purchased seed from a vendor that
makes it seem like it's not though like
that specifically no I'm pretty sure
that this message says purchased yep so
that that's my take on like yeah do
whatever you want with that clone like
you've got seeds and seeds are going
everywhere and then clones are gonna be
made of clones and whatever you if
you've got a cool phenotype do it every
wall with it it'd be cool if you got it
back on
if maybe if you're in my area and you've
got the one that won the Cup or
something maybe hooked me up so that I
could read back to it or something you
know but I'm probably thinking this way
because I was listening to the dude
gross show earlier in the dude gross
show and this came up specifically with
a different they were talking about
hydro stores in the mid 90s and early
thousands but I feel like so I'm
somebody like some cool and some random
person hits me up on Instagram there's
like hey I bought a pack of your seeds
on wwe.com and I was wondering if you
would like me to mail you a clone I'd be
like nope it's not entrapment right that
would be my first response but now we're
in Colorado and if someone you knew
chatot or Michigan definitely all seven
of them but the further you're separated
I feel like the creepier that offer gets
yeah they're scarier maybe the better
right but I put myself out there so if
somebody's like Rasta Jeff I've got your
clone like it seems it's just I'm
putting myself out there so much for
people to interact with me that it
doesn't feel creepy but yeah and still
if you're not in Colorado I'm yeah
that's why I changed that's why I
changed it to scary immediately because
creepy is definitely not the right word
but yeah the Capleton clone that I run I
did not Fino hunt that that came from a
pack of seeds that I sold to somebody so
I can't leave this has happened to
somebody brought me Ralph's roster ruff
brought me back a clone of blue heeler
so it does happen because he felt like
he's like this is a good one you want
this and he brought me a clone of it and
you know what happened when he did I
gave him seeds and returned for that
clone again right so he got more seeds
well I know people that have suffered
some sort of tragedy in their garden or
accidentally lost a whole Fino due to
one thing or another cats seem to be
particularly destructive why are you why
are your cats near your [ __ ] grow
room what the [ __ ] people doing sorry
[ __ ] up and don't take your dog to
your commercial grow either you're
working on an IPM program in there your
sprint shooting though you're releasing
bugs in and then you bring your dog in
there stop it
viola thank you through yeah
it's via the side beat of this question
was how I feel about people breeding
with my seeds yeah go for it knew that
would the only thing I all the same
reasons we just listed for the first
half of the question yeah but the only
thing I want though is credit when you
if you release that when you post a
picture of it put the name of the parent
strain on their doing yeah be honest
about it don't lie just put that it was
a rise or Capleton or whatever you used
put that on their list it yep that's all
I ask
and honestly I got seeds from somebody
to breed with you don't know me at night
that's how I started my didn't just
invent plants
I got seeds and clones and use other
people's seeds and clones for breeding
that's how it starts you have to do
something it would be cool if you're
going to make seeds commercially make
your own parents like don't just go take
and just buy an established five pack in
column yeah yeah I know I've done it of
course I did it with Daybreaker I got a
[ __ ] pack of Daybreaker from gage
green and there was a mail and there I
was like god damn he's got to be used
for breeding
so I dusted a bunch of [ __ ] with him and
made a bunch of stuff but then I used my
favorite mail out of that breeding
project from the golden goat to
Daybreaker which became a rise and
that's my new mail so I've done some
work with the mail I'm using as my main
stud for my breeding now I didn't just
go pull one from somebody else's but
I've used four or five different mails
throughout different breeding projects
lately so I am using other people [ __ ]
like you have to use other people and if
you don't use this breeding forever like
at this point there's no reason to
reinvent the wheel like use what's
available to you and that's what's on
the market there's yeah there's a lot of
stuff you can do with it and as long as
you're not being super shady with it
like I'm all for it I met DNA genetics
in a cannabis cup years ago I know it's
pretty cool because little Kevin was
wearing an IRA genetics t-shirt and he
was walking ahead of me and I was
walking with just a few other people in
the group being on the group staggers
but Kevin was up front and the DNA
genetics boys came around the corner
they go hey man we've seen your logo
around nice work and Kevin psych is
actually that guy and they came and
talked to me and I asked him straight up
I was like hey do I have permission to
breed and like commercially breed with
your stuff they're like
yeah just give us credit bro for
anything you use just give us credit
that's exactly how I feel like if you
make a package and you print something
on it it should say the true parents on
there I don't even have to put whatever
I rise from IRA genetics just put a rise
to my new thing then we're all happy
yeah you can't use my stuff for breeding
I used I've used some cool stuff for
I've used everybody's stuff for breeding
[ __ ] I've bred with everybody's projects
there's some DNA genetics in there
there's some ethos collective in my
breeding there's some cool stuff in my
brief I see Holly connection in there
there's a little bit everything in there
reserve a privada I hope that answers
the question we got a little rambling oh
I totally picture them known to happen
yeah it'd be cool if I got a clone not
required you're not a dick if you don't
like some people can't share they gotta
grow quietly just added sharing yeah
theirs they can't because they're in
Odessa Texas and they can't [ __ ]
right now they're on the far end from
those reasons there's different people
that are looking to patent cannabis
genetics you know in other breeding
other plants that's a thing yep like I
couldn't cross two different breeders
tomatoes together and then try to
commercially sell them they would say
[ __ ] no there's a couple of outfits that
are just waiting for federal
legalization where they can pounce on it
they're gonna have all their paperwork
ready to just mass submit yeah
unfortunately I don't have the funding
for that type of stuff
not yet not yet Mike was in on a talk
today
next year's gonna be fun people yes no
matter what happens even if what we
talked about today didn't pan out
i'ma have to switch from Mountain Dew to
energy drinks or something next year I
think that's what I'm thinking just
straight coffee and Red Bull
yeah cut the coffee with Red Bull just
just swish two straight pots of espresso
whoo it's gonna be a fun year next year
we're gonna go super fast oh man I can't
wait
hell yeah what what else we got on the
punch seat buddy you know we've done
almost 30 minutes so do you have
anything that you want to ramble about
because I don't want to go I feel like
ice you guys are listening Christmas
showed you I've got a big angry ray in
me that's been cooking for a couple of
weeks but now I just it's Christmas
let's not burn them down with a Mike
Rann you guys are listening on a
Christmas - a Christmas episode thank
you I appreciate you guys real listen to
it like just a 30-minute just Mike and
Jeff hanging out kicking our thanks
Christmas party or holiday but this is
not the end of the episode but they're
what you don't need to pick up a pen or
a notebook for sure from here out I
guaranteed the learning is done you guys
yeah I'm gonna save that rat for another
show but Merry Christmas everybody I
hope you have some good people to spend
it with some good food to eat some
wonderful cannabis to consume if you're
into that maybe a nice wine if you're
into that just hopefully you got
somebody to love on this holiday season
and if you don't tweet me I'll tweet
back at you yes that sounds [ __ ]
gross yeah I got someone to love on
tweet me yep I'm not gonna love on you
but like I'll say hi on Twitter I'll let
you pet my dog maybe I'll send you a DM
of a picture of whatever whatever I'm
about to dam just making it more and
more depressing I've got someone to love
on well I'm sorry go [ __ ] yourself
whoa this show is taking a weird turn
okay remember those times and I was like
Mike ramble a little bit I am starting
to regret it right now see the hash is
coming out the torch is coming out yeah
we're gonna fix you I this a DAB is for
me I kind of wish I had gotten it for
you because your head needs a man
fiction's now they're just thanks for
including us in your holiday cheer
guests we appreciate it
look for a mic rant sometime in January
I'm gonna set this one aside cuz I gotta
save some of that one for uh oh and
there were a bunch of people on
Instagram live one night trying to get
me to join Russ this video that might
happen in 2018 Mike's kind of camera shy
he's not a video friendly dude yeah
I've probably I've got a voice for radio
I'm not sure about the face totally got
a face on nobody that's cold
but yeah one day I'll get cleaned up a
little bit and I'll uh I'll join the
Instagram live world just not today
you guys this episode is coming out at
the end of the year you got like a week
left in this year so if you didn't do
what you wanted to do this year you got
some time to set some goals for next
year goals are [ __ ] awesome write
something down something you want to
accomplish no matter how big nor small
it is write it down and say I'm gonna
[ __ ] do this this year and make it
happen and if it's just a little tiny
thing knock it out and then write down a
bigger thing and then when you knock out
all those little things you're gonna say
man I wrote down some [ __ ] and I got it
done I'm gonna write down some harder
[ __ ] I may get some harder [ __ ] done and
they don't start getting [ __ ] done it'll
just start flowing you like yeah I'm
gonna make more goals and I'm gonna do
more [ __ ] and this year is gonna get
better and better and I'm gonna start
just making more money and stacking more
[ __ ] up and growing better and yeah
anyway it just starts [ __ ] I mean I
started doing [ __ ] and then I get off on
a rant
nail it's not as hot as it should be
we're reheat here yeah can I get a
reheat set some goals that's how does my
goddamn point set some goals absolutely
push some goals
I don't know anybody that's content I
strive for better people you can do it
read a book
strive for a new job learn a new skill
drill better listen to more shows do you
do the New Year's resolution thing I
don't you gave up giving up [ __ ] for
Lent one year yep
that's legitimate ly true one year and I
I had a bunch of friends in college one
year for Lent that we're like we know
you're not religious but everybody's
giving up for something for land you
should give something up and so I gave
up my Mountain Dews for Lent
and the next day they were like now you
can't just [ __ ] switch to dr. pepper
[ __ ] so that I actually gave up
caffeine for Lent and I even went an
extra day cuz they were pretty adamant
that the dr. pepper I had the mornings
of the first day of that was cheating in
the next year I was like no [ __ ] all
y'all I'm giving up giving up stuff for
Lent and I'm just gonna keep that going
forever it's been like 15 years now but
setting goals kind of at the beginning
of the year where would I like to be at
the end of the next year you you know
little stuff like I want to get this
room cleaned out or big stuff like I
want to start a different career path or
buy a new car buy a new house I mean it
can be anything in that range folks just
take a few minutes over the holiday
season you know if you're me you're
probably gonna packable sit back put
your feet up think about it for a few
where do you want to beat this time next
year do you want to be in the same spot
you're in now do you want to be wearing
the same jeans do you want a totally
different life do you want to be in a
different room do you want to be with
different people do you want to be
employed in a different industry and
make that change for yourself man change
is a constant in life and if you don't
embrace it it's gonna destroy you like
I'm watching people trying to hold on to
the past all day watching
prohibitionists online and like it kills
them little by little day by day just
trying to hold on to the past ruins
their lives don't do it set some goals
make some change there's a dad for you
sir yeah but look I don't even believe
in like I think scales are unhealthy
that there's a lot of people who try to
lose weight after the holidays
take that [ __ ] scale throw in the
trash yeah like this is bad for your
mental health yeah it's a number who
cares like your hotness is not
determined by a random number
I've said that same sentence to somebody
I think no I it's where I spend a lot of
time online following prohibitionists
and you end up seeing their thoughts and
opinions on all sorts of [ __ ] I see a
lot of people that are like man I'm 134
but if I could be a hundred and
twenty-eight I'd be happy it's not if
you didn't know those numbers you'd be
happier at least I don't even know how
much I weigh I know a range when they
asked me when I met the doctor will you
a shrug and like I have to get on the
scale and every time I'm kind of
surprised yeah well now when you go to
like the meed to get your paperwork
filled out like how tall are you 6 5 how
much do you weigh
I don't know somewhere between 185 and
205 ish I don't know depends on didn't
eat or did not poo I don't know how many
times was Leslie yeah exactly I don't
pay too much attention to it cuz you
write and you take care of something the
number on the scale doesn't matter all
right Mike you were off on a ramp there
for a minute something's had you fired
up for the past few days shows of all
the cap go with that mic down since it
is Christmas turn Mike's mic down just a
little bit dude he is bred as a candy
cane right now he looks like a candy
cane face is red arms are as white as
white people can [ __ ] get looking
like a striped candy cane over there Sam
I see you trying to get words out make
words happen Mike we're gonna teach my
okay Mike looks like the 40 year old
virgin just took a damn that's what Mike
looks like right now yeah you're pale
and read at the same time I don't know
how you're two different colors but you
totally are sweaty and dry at the same
time I can see it you guys
Mike encourages me to remind you to
drink water hydrate yourselves
I always try to get Mike to drink water
Mike is like on a water strike or
something no not a strike he's got more
to say you just can't make him come out
of his face you guys I really appreciate
hanging out with you guys it's been I
think I've been doing this podcast like
three years now or something I've got
272 episodes I know I'm cheating by
counting the throwback Thursday episodes
but I just keeps it easier to keep it in
line with numbers but that means I've
done at least 170 episodes or so
thanks for hanging out so much you guys
been hanging out for a couple of years I
appreciate it I appreciate all the
support I appreciate all the interaction
I appreciate all the guests that have
come and hung out I like all the
questions the patreon support is truly
appreciated you guys covered my website
this year patreon paid for my website
you guys contributed enough to patreon
to cover the cost of hosting this
podcast this podcast did not come out of
my pocket for the first time this year
that's yeah it wasn't awesome going on
but was not profitable but that's not
the goal the goal of this podcast was
never to be profitable the goal of this
podcast was to teach people how to grow
better cannabis and so we're reaching
our goal come on for sure yeah but we
have covered through patreon donations
and contributions we paid for the cost
to my website which that was pretty cool
I didn't know that that was even
possible I didn't know that it would get
there I thought it would be 10 or 12
bucks a month I never thought it would
cover the whole website yeah it totally
covered a year of web hosting and the
domain name so that's pretty cool with
the SSL certificate so that's pretty
cool I appreciate that thank you guys
Merry Christmas happy whatever holiday I
know everybody celebrates Christmas I'm
not gonna be exclusive or denominational
happy holiday happy wintertime happy
[ __ ] get with your family time and
have some good food season stay warm man
if you're in California where the fires
are be careful be safe yeah remember
that things aren't as important as lives
so if you got to go if you got to get
out of there get what you can and get
out of there ah you can get more [ __ ]
but you can't get more use your people
get your pets and go yeah yeah um yeah I
appreciate all the interaction I was
gonna lead into uh still begging for
more interaction like more Facebook
stuff or Instagram or Twitter and of
course more emails I love the emails I
get a lot of inspiration for the podcast
from the emails knowing that when
somebody asks a question they say one
thing and I can answer that one person I
bet you I'm answering a bunch of
people's questions and if you haven't
had the problem that that person's
asking about yet in your garden you may
in the future and you'll go ah [ __ ] I
heard Rasta Jeff talk about how to get
rid of fungus gnats
just because somebody else sent me the
email about it so I really like those it
lets me know that I'm
just rambling I'm not just talking at
the wall somebody's getting some help
from it I like that a lot so you guys
keep the interactions coming please I
truly do appreciate that on Facebook
just search for the girl from a heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
on Instagram that's where I switch it up
I use my other company it's Irie I RIE
underscore genetics g en ET ICS I re
underscore genetics on Instagram I
posted a bunch of great cannabis
photography I actually have been doing
Instagram live videos where I go on
Instagram live and do live Q&amp;A s I'll do
the live Q&amp;A ZAR awesome if people just
ask me random questions and I do my best
to answer and the chat just scrolls by
the chat just scrolls and I do my best
to answer those questions as quickly and
efficiently as I can and sometimes I get
off on a rant there and I wish I was
recording but I'm usually not recording
with my audio gear so and I don't leave
the videos up I like to delete them for
some reason I don't catch yeah yeah I've
got the option to leave them up or I
could just take them down and for some
reason I just hit the don't share button
and delete them and keep on movin and
one of these times its I'm gonna be in
that video too yeah we'll get white mic
on there he's a little shy he's got a
face for podcasting Wow also there's a
YouTube channel or we still don't show
white Mike's face so far I think I've
got about a hundred and thirty ish
videos I don't want to lie to you and
tell you too many I know there's a
hundred and thirty one hundred and
thirty posted up there it's the girl
from your heart channel on YouTube I'm
making more videos they'll go up slowly
it's old material but it's still there
so if you want to go check it out I
would appreciate that and I mentioned
patreon earlier it's Christmas time uh
I'm not trying to take money away from
your family it's your family some gifts
have a good New Year's take your family
out to dinner but if you'd still like to
contribute to the podcast after that you
can go to patreon.com/scishow from your
heart
check out all the signup information
everything you want to know is right
there if you do choose to help me on
patreon what you will be doing is paying
for my website for next year which is
where I host the podcast which is what
allows me to give the podcast to
everybody else for free until net
neutrality kicks in I'm gonna keep this
podcast free it will be free from me
forever that's what I want to add take
five seconds and write down like you
know the little note
and everybody's phone write down what
you're paying for internet right now
just save that file save it for a year
yep yep right back in somewhere yep
what's your pain write down what you're
paying for everything this here yep yeah
write down what weed costs just write
down a bunch of random prices and then
tuck it away for a year and then open it
up next year and see what the prices
have changed but I'm gonna keep the show
free that's my point and net neutrality
may change that for you but it's not my
fault I'm not gonna make any money off
of that it's some guys your ISP yeah
someone else is gonna suck that [ __ ] up
but if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast and uh some people can I'm not
begging from for everybody but some
people can I maybe compare for the
website again next year it's that sort
of stuff that's what it'll go for to go
for paying for the website or go for
these little fuzzy microphone covers
I've had a lot of this equipment for a
long time some of it will take a [ __ ]
one of these days I'm sure I'll have to
replace that that's the sort of stuff
that the patreon covers so
patreon.com/scishow or from your heart
I'd appreciate it if you check that out
I feel like I've been talking about
patreon for far too long starting to
feel like NPR and with your support we
can continue to bring you free
broadcasting about cannabis and the
future of cannabis a real stony telethon
just consider take dabs til we hit that
goal people all right this is a day
you're dabbing at the red golden green
level and we're trying to get ourselves
yeah no we can't do that in PR please
NPR show beak oh yeah that's the Twitter
question for Twitterverse
all right Twitter verse if we were on if
we had an NPR show what would we call it
wouldn't be called the Griffin Heart
podcast because NPR just wouldn't go for
that it would be something that didn't
sound anything like it was about weed he
wouldn't know what the [ __ ] the show was
about until you listen to it by the
title
all right they like it when we ramble
happy nondenominational holiday do you
know what I miss life when we hadn't
jinda anxiety around holiday greetings
yeah it's because until a bunch of
retards started pretending it's a [ __ ]
[ __ ] cannon did started pretending
that the phrase Merry Christmas was
under a deck like there wasn't a thing
you could say Merry Christmas or happy
holidays and as long as you didn't say
hey [ __ ] you pal
like you were fine and now everyone is
like a little anxious when they go to
say happy holidays or Merry Christmas
it's Stamp you can't assume my gender or
my holiday and you know just let it go
yep yep hat Mary thank you for your
holiday greeting I appreciate it we're
friends too
yeah feel free to send the hate tweets
to new mobile phone 15 on Twitter yep
that's a way to wrap up a patreon
campaign send money send me a hateful
tweets no no that's what we're saying
buy your family gifts hope everybody has
a good safe New Year
mic remind everybody how they can hate
you on social media you can find me on
Twitter at at Nemo Punk 15 or on
Facebook at Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws yeah that's about the easiest ways
to find me yeah harass Mike let him know
you're out there listening let him know
you support him because he's podcast
listeners love to find me on Instagram
which I don't really use but you could
find me there as well yeah he's there he
just doesn't check it I tagged him and
some stuff so it'll make it easier for
you oh do we have anything else for the
end of this show Merry Christmas
everybody yes happy holidays Merry
Christmas
we will I will be putting out a
throwback Thursday episode I'll put that
together here at the start of the week
we'll put that out for Thursday I'll be
back Monday I think Monday is the first
of the year so I'll be back Monday with
some fresh content I'm not sure what I'm
going to do for the New Year's episode
but it will happen just in case you were
curious battery sufficiently charged my
phone just decided to let me know that
low power mode has been turned off nice
it vibrated and flashed really abruptly
so the phone is cool and it's look at
that it's 709 and it's time to wrap up
the podcast
usually I do a shout out to a specific
person but this time we're gonna do a
large group I want to give a shout out
to everybody working on Christmas all
you folks working in aggro that are
keeping the plants alive that are
showing up and if even if even God I
can't talk now [ __ ] even if you're not
working in aggro if you're working
wherever you're working keeping that
business going if you're working in your
own private garden if you are taking
care of a sick person and doing your job
taking care of a sick relative or family
member or even more a [ __ ] stranger
because you're a compassionate person if
you're working if you're putting in
hours on a holiday we're giving you a
big ol shout out so shout outs all you
working keep runnin on a holiday that's
right that is right all you working
people working on the holidays thank you
big shout out until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
right side
he got told you
[Music]
Oh
[Applause]
[Music]
to face
so far
[Music]
[Applause]
whoa
[Music]
I just saw
you