yeah Happy New Year canvas community
it's time for episode number 274 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to Kat
ku and the entire Mystic Krewe crew
once again Happy New Year everybody
thanks again for joining me this will be
the first episode I put out in 2018 I
hope everybody had a great 2017 I hope
your holiday season was perfect and I
hope you had a safe Happy New Year
also I hope 2018 brings you everything
you were hoping for all right you guys I
usually like to start off the podcast by
talking about what I've been smoking on
and today I've got some [ __ ] worth
talking about I have been dabbing on
some lemon Jeffrey's sauce and it is
tremendous let's talk a little bit about
this I'm grabbing the package to tell
you about it I have got some lemon
Jeffrey's sauce grown by our friends at
elevations in Colorado Springs extracted
by her friends at manna extracts a
friend of mine on Instagram actually
contacted me and said hey dude you need
to have some of this so he made sure
that he got a few grams in my hands I
don't know if he wants to be mentioned
on the show or not he knows who he is
super huge shout out bro I appreciate it
also huge shout out to elevations and
manna extracts they did a hell of a good
job with this lemon Jeffrey sauce let's
open up the jar and look at it for a
second here the only problem is these
jars kind of suck these charters get
stuck these childproof lids these suck
it's the only thing I would complain
about upgrade these [ __ ] jar lids but
I've got it open let's look at it the
consistency is kind of like a moist cake
batter or maybe a moist cheesecake
batter the color is beautiful it is
beautifully golden yellow it is perfect
it's what you would think lemon candy
would be the color of and this jar is
eight to ten inches away from my face
you guys and all I can smell is lemon
candy it just smells like lemon heads or
lemon meringue or some sort of really
soft lemon scented candy and I really
enjoy it and I said softy I know that's
weird I think some things have like
lemon pledge has a hard lemon smell a
lemon pledge that smell punches you in
the face and is pungent
I think lemon Geoffrey has a soft lemon
smell it's got like a uh I don't know
it's not real abrasive it coats your
tongue and it's pleasing it makes you go
ooh that's soft and yummy maybe I'm
crazy
but I think it's a soft lemon scent and
I really enjoy it so shows everybody
involved in there this hash is amazing
I've talked about the consistency I
talked about the color I talked about
the smell
the taste is amazing I taste like you
just put ah not the not the lemon head
candy itself because those are a little
strong
what this tastes like but the smell of
the lemon candy it's like you took a
bite out of that like how the lemon head
box smells when you smell it it smells
like you dabbed that flavor and it is
delicious the hi obviously is tremendous
it's very sativa dominant and I think
it's got me rambling a little bit so
this should be a fun podcast once again
shout out to everybody involved in this
delicious lemon Jeffrey sauce of course
the lemon Jeffrey is the lemon skunk
pollinated by a reversed golden go of
course I made that strain several years
ago it's making its way through Colorado
again and getting very popular a lot of
people have been asking for more seeds
of the lemon Jeffrey and I think that in
2018 that will be one of my goals I
think I'm going to make no not I think I
am I am going to make more lemon Jeffery
seeds in 2018 so everybody that's been
asking there's the official announcement
I talked about it on an Instagram live
video the other day but this is the
official announcement I will be making
more lemon Jeffrey feminized seeds in
2018 it may not be till the summer
because I've got other things lined up
and I've got schedules and [ __ ] like
that to go with but there will be more
lemon Jeffery seeds in the future
and speaking of seeds in the future
let's talk about my breeding project I
like to keep you guys updated on a
breeding project I'm working on I keep
telling you guys that I've got a star
dog and a Durbin poison in the breeding
room that will get pollinated by a rise
there's also a platinum tangi in there
there's ecto cooler in there there are
several great females in there that are
gonna get pollinated or actually at this
point in time have been pollinated by
King Solomon they look great the pistols
have curled up I can see the seeds
developing they're starting to get thick
already there's about 30 days to go in
that grow before those seeds will be
ready but I can see that the pollination
went well I can see that the seeds are
developing I can see that the plants are
healthy and I can see that this is going
to be a successful pollen chucking run
so here in about 30 days from now I will
have new stuff that needs to be tested I
will have replenishing --zz of old stuff
so that the hella dank seed bank can get
some restocks they'll also get some of
the new stuff so stay tuned new stuff is
coming you guys I am really excited
about this star dog cross to arise and
I'm really excited about Durbin poison
cross to arise I think that those are
gonna have great potential those are two
of my favorite strains so
them to the arize has me really excited
and I kind of can't wait so I'll keep
you guys updated I'll probably talk
about it on every episode from now until
the time they come down and then I'll
start talking about them again when I
grow them cuz I really can't wait so get
used to hearing about those two crosses
cuz I'll talk about them a lot I'm also
super excited about the Platinum tangi
cross to arise just something about that
that orange smell when I walk in the
garden I can smell that platinum tangi
uh over everything else it's the
platinum tangi and the cactus cooler the
aromas of those things just overpower
everything
also there's a leroy in there that's
gonna get pollinated and I'm making a
strain for a friend and the leroy to
arise will be called the Cletus and
that's being made for a friend so I
don't have any plans to release the
seeds of the Cletus it's not gonna go
anywhere it'll be in my garden it'll be
in my friend cletus's garden it may be
in a couple other small gardens but I'm
really I'm not gonna make a lot of seeds
I expect maybe 20 to 50 seeds out of the
small plant that I made but the Cletus
will be coming and it's something I'm
excited about because it's a breeding
project for a friend who moved away he's
not around here anymore we don't get to
hang out but we still talk I think it'll
be fun to grow the Cletus for my friend
Cletus shoutout Cletus I hope you hear
this brother oh and since we're talking
about naming strains and new cannabis
strains the Zack Hayes cross to arise
has an official name it is now
officially called pure love the reason
it's called pure love is because I was
trying to come up with the name of it I
was sitting there thinking about my
buddy Zach but if you don't know Zack
Hayes is a cross that was made for my
friend Zach from New Mexico who passed
away from cystic fibrosis his real name
was Zack Hayes some friends of ours made
a strain for him called Zack Hayes I was
gifted a Zack Hayes clone I did what I'm
supposed to do and I pollinated that
Zack Hayes clone with the arise and then
took those seeds and I gave them back to
our friends of our cantika
they got almost half of all the seeds of
his a Ches to arise I produced I was
sitting there thinking of a name for it
I was looking at Zacks Facebook page
because it's still up I was looking at
Zacks Instagram I was trying to find a
way to name this strain and honor Zack
and I was like when I'm trying to name a
strain I think why did you do this and
in my head I said I did it out of pure
love and I said well [ __ ] that's the
name of the strain pure love Zack Hayes
2a
is called pure love I do not know if I
will release the pure love strain in
seed form to the public because it has
not been tested yet org antica has got
the first batch of seeds they get to
grow it first they're gonna test it for
me if they like it if it shows that
there are no herbes that there are no
problems that it's a quality strain that
it puts out good THC that it's worth
growing and it's worth sharing with
people I will consider putting it out as
a public release for other people to
grow but until org antica finds their
clone until organic against done with it
it's not going anywhere
myself and organic are you gonna keep it
private because that was something made
for a friend and then it was made even
further for a friend it's kind of a
personal project we're gonna keep it
closed until it's until we've had our
run with it but pure love Zack Hayes to
a rise big shout out to my buddy Zack
miss you and I love you every day bro
also big shout to all of our friends and
organic a' you guys are doing a great
job down there if you guys keep killing
it and crushing it like you are I'm
gonna have to come down there and pay
you a visit and come check out the
garden and come high-five everybody and
shake your hands bring you some more
seeds alright big shout outs everybody
down at organic ax big shot at the Tim
huge shout out to Zack and I even want
to send a shout-out to DS Romero even
though you were too high to get out of
the car and had to take a nap the last
time you guys drove to my house big
shout out but I look forward to seeing
you next time I look forward to taking
some big old globs with you can't wait
alright let's move forward with the
podcast a little bit it is the first of
the year so I thought it would be a good
idea to talk about some attainable
garden goals and ways that you can
improve your garden in 2018 if you're
not thinking of ways to improve your
standing still and moving backwards so
let's talk about ways that we can
improve our garden in 2018 and realistic
goals that you can set for yourself that
you would actually be able to reach for
your garden in 2018 a lot of people may
say hey I want to grow better I want to
do something better next year with my
garden with my life with myself but they
don't know what they want to do so I've
thought of some goals that you can
actually reach some goals that are
attainable these are goals that any
grower can reach for because if you're
an excellent grower if you're a mediocre
grower if you're a shitty grower if
you're an old-school grower if you're a
pro grower there's always room for
improvement and the things I'm gonna
mention everybody can improve on a
little bit so let's talk about goals you
can reach to
prove your garden in 2018 the first
thing you can do and it kind of sounds
redundant cuz I've already said this the
first thing you can do is set some goals
get out some paper get out of dry erase
board get out your phone open up a
notepad and actually write something
down it will actually be a goal for 2018
if you don't write it down if you just
say in 2018 I want to do this sure you
said it it's out there there were no
witnesses there's nothing holding you to
it there's nothing to remind you that
every day if you've got a piece of paper
sitting on your desk if you've got a
note on the refrigerator if you've got a
note in your phone and you see it
occasionally and it says in 2018 I'm
going to improve this it's a reminder
there's some accountability there you
see it and if you stop doing it you kind
of feel shitty for yourself and bad
about yourself because you have failed
yourself
so write it down put it on paper just
say hey I'm going to do this even if
it's just a little thing and a small
improvement a small goal write it down
and accomplish it we talked I think I
talked about this on the last episode if
you write down a goal you'll accomplish
it and then when you accomplish that
goal you'll say oh [ __ ] I got to write
down another goal and then you'll write
down two goals and then you'll
accomplish both of those and you'll go
should I can do a lot of things and your
goals will get bigger your life will get
better and you'll start improving in so
many different ways you'll gain more
confidence you'll get a better
personality you'll get a better life
things will just start coming together
so write down a goal that's all you have
to do one goal accomplished that one
goal that'll turn into two goals that'll
turn into you just crush and [ __ ]
life so write down a goal this podcast
is about cannabis so we're gonna write
down a cannabis related goal here's
something I think we should all be
striving for we all want better yield
right you want to pull more weight you
want more grams per watt whatever grow
room you've been growing in however much
you've been pulling consistently let's
strive for a little bit more let's
strive for a better yield in 2018 that's
an attainable goal the only way to reach
that goal is to find ways to improve
your garden now what are a few ways that
you can improve your garden to reach
your better yield goal things like scrog
doing any scrog Anor any canopy control
you need to get some canopy control
going on in the garden a scrog is real
easy I've done a full Episode on
Draghi Scroggins when he put a net up
above the canopy and you bend all the
plants down into that net so they can't
grow too high but they're growing out
now now you were filling your horizontal
space instead of the vertical space
you're not growing up into the lights
but you're spreading the plant and
you're using up all the space so scrog
will be a great way to increase your
yield popping and twisting and super
cropping the plants would be a wonderful
way to help you increase your yields
when the plants are in veg and they're
getting big walk over and pop the stems
let me kind of explain this a little bit
different I start about two inches above
where the pot cut or the stem comes out
of the dirt so you got some dirt with a
little stick sticking out I just put my
finger there and grab the base of that
stock then I reach up about an inch
above that and I just twist my fingers
opposite directions and it sounds like
this it sounds just like you popped your
knuckle that's what I just did and the
plant goes pop and you're just breaking
the cellulose right there on the plant
can I move up about four inches and do
it again and move up four inches and do
it again and then I repeat this on all
of the larger branches of the plant
you'll start to see knuckles form on all
the spots where you've done this you are
now allowing more nutrient to pass
through the plant you are now making
that stalk thicker and stronger you're
making bigger more robust more active
more productive plants so get in there
and pop them just pop them just give
them up a little just a little pop just
twist it try it on a couple branches
maybe if it's your first try don't do it
at the base maybe you go to the top of
the plant and give it a twist and see
what happens when you give it just a
little turn it'll go pop you're gonna
hear a crunch perfect don't bend it over
don't break it just a little popping a
little bit of a twist right there that's
gonna help that plant become stronger
healthier it's gonna be more active it's
gonna work out a little stronger so that
will help you also defoliation oh and
also the popping and twisting I do that
I start when the plants get kind of big
and veg and I will do that all the way
up to like week three for maybe week
five of some plants it depends on the
strain and depends on how robust they
aren't how they're growing but week four
into flower is not odd to see me walk up
and just pop a branch pop and you'll
watch it recover within a day and start
growing even faster so you can scrub you
can pop and twist and then you can de
foliate get in there and remove leaves
that are not necessary
that are in the way of light getting
into your canopy take those leaves out
of there you're not trying to grow
leaves you're trying to grow buds so
leaves that are too big
go ahead and take them off if you're not
sure how much defoliating you want to do
and you're kind of new at it and you're
a little bit afraid that first day of
flowering go in there and take off any
leaf that's got a purple stem if you got
a big leaf with the purple stem just
take it off if the plants are healthy
that purple stem will probably just snap
right off you don't need scissors or
anything just grab it and pop it right
off in there if you feel like you're
afraid to take too much off just go
lightly you can always go harder so on
week one I like to strip the plants on
week two I like to go in and kind of
bottom them take out that [ __ ] on the
bottom lollipop a little bit that's
another way to improve your yield
lollipop take off all the [ __ ] on the
bottom so you'll have big branches that
come up if they don't come up high
enough to where you think they're gonna
make bud and reach the light get rid of
up rid of them if you've got branches
that do come up to the light but there's
a bunch of [ __ ] on the bottom like
little tiny sucker branches coming off
you can clean those all the way off it's
not rare for me to have if I've got a
four foot tall plant I'll clean up the
whole foot off the bottom there will be
just a stalk for the whole 12 inches at
the bottom no branches coming off then
those first branches that come off it
would not be rare for them to have two
feet of nothing and nothing a nobody for
the last lake foot to ten inches maybe
eight inches there's no bud there I just
cleaned it all off because all that
bottom shit's not gonna grow it's not
getting light it's not getting any
energy it's just gonna be crappy stuff
that you don't want to trim and if you
clean it off the bottom you can move
that energy up to the top buds and get
the energy up to the top or the shits
easier to trim and you get more
production so week one do some stripping
week to get in there in lollipop week
three do more stripping take more leaves
out clean it up make more space spread
them out a little bit so the light can
get in there and then on week four do
your final bottoming get in there and
clean out the bottoms take off all those
little sucker branches all those little
shitty popcorn buds get those out of
there so it's leaf bottom leaf final
bottom and then you can keep me foliated
the flower cycle if you wish to that's
up to you if you go too hard on
defoliation you can kind of slow down
the growth you'll slow down bud
production if you go too hard so you'll
have to find a happy medium it's very
strange specific but if you week one
strip week two lollipop
week three strip a little bit more than
week four ago cleanup the final at the
bottoms for the final part that will
really help you increase your yields all
right so everybody wants bigger yields
the next thing everybody wants to do and
a goal that you can set you for yourself
and a goal that would definitely be
attainable if you work at it is
increasing the potency of your finished
product now how can we do that
potency is kind of limited by genetics
if you've got genetics that do not put
out high THC then you may not be able to
increase that THC much more than what it
already is you may be reaching its
potential but if you've got some plants
that you know can get better if one of
your friends has the same clone or if
you've grown it better before there are
a few things that you can do to dial
that in consistency is the key if that
plant has the potential of getting 32
percent THC and you're only getting 28 a
few things you can do are dial in the
temperature and humidity plants like
consistency plants like reliability
maybe your plant likes it a little
hotter maybe your plant likes it a
little cooler you're gonna have to dial
in the temps and the humidity and it's
going to be plant specific growing
cannabis is like having a girlfriend you
need to figure out how to cater to that
plant to keep it happy you can't have
three girlfriends because you can't keep
all three of them happy one's gonna want
to eat at the Spaghetti Factory one's
gonna want to eat at the Cheesecake
Factory and one's not gonna [ __ ] have
any idea what she wants and she's gonna
leave it up to you
cannabis plants are the same [ __ ] way
it's hard to have multiple cannabis
plants in the same room and dial them
all in perfectly so if you want to
improve your potency select a strain and
work with it and figure out what
temperature it likes figure out what
humidity it likes you'll be able to tell
by looking most of the time you're gonna
have to run a strain several times to
dial it in perfectly
so get your temps dialed in get your
humidity dial then get your feed dialed
in for that specific plant as that plant
want more nutrients does that plant want
less nutrients a lot of people forget
that some of the cushions and og plants
they want a little more cal-mag people
forget that some of the plants may want
a little more amino acids they don't pay
attention to stuff like that so for
better potency dial in your crop start
paying attention to timpz and
be more consistent get your ph on point
it's your feeds on point I wish I could
tell you that the planet wants this
temperature and this humidity and this
much feed but when you're trying to
improve that this level it's going to be
plant specific yes ideally somewhere
between like 75 and 78 degrees would be
really nice but maybe your plant is from
another region maybe your plant is a
specific phenotype that wants it really
hot and likes it or maybe it likes it
really cold you're gonna have to dial in
your plant which is going to take
attention and a relationship you're
gonna have to build a relationship with
this plant so that you know what it
likes you have to be in there every day
looking at it take notes write [ __ ] down
you're trying to get this plant perfect
I run a very large commercial grow we
have got approximately 40 different
strains in there I have got notes on a
board for all the growth staff just to
remind them hey the blueberry cookies
does not like being over watered do not
over water blueberry cookies there's
another one that gets really pissed off
if you do foliate it too hard there's
another one that we have to not pack
them too close together because they
don't do [ __ ] together when you press
them too close together it's learning
each plant it's learning your plant and
dialing it in so if you want to increase
your potency you're gonna have to learn
that plant you're gonna have to get your
room perfect you're gonna have to get
everything dialed in you're gonna have
to grow that plant a couple of cycles
and figure out what it doesn't does not
like so that's a reachable goal better
potency is an attainable goal for 2018
now a lot of you don't live in legal
states a lot of you that are growing may
live somewhere you don't have access to
testing so this may not be a goal that
you can verify but you'll be able to
tell you will be able to see the extra
work you put in you'll be able to tell
the extra details that you worked on
you'll be able to see it in the finished
product and I bet you won't even need a
lab to show that you are getting better
potency
all right we covered the two obvious
things that people want to improve and
goals that people can set which are
better yields and better potency now
something people don't think about is
better scheduling and planning let's
work on scheduling our gardens and
harvests a little bit better
how many harvests do you want to pool in
can you pull six harvests in 2018 out of
your grow room
can you pull five harvests out of your
grow room in 2018 maybe you've got
multiple lights and you're running a
perpetual grow in there are you gonna
try and pull 52 harvests out of a grow
room this year have a goal have some
schedules going you should know how long
it takes for your plants to flower most
of us are running nine week plants if
you've got nine week plants you need to
have veg plants ready to replace them
when they harvest at the end of week
nine so you need to decide how long
you're going to veg you need to decide
how long it takes you to clone most of
us can get clones rooted in about two
weeks so if you've got a nine week cycle
you need to allow yourself two weeks to
cut clones then however many weeks of
veg you want probably about four weeks
of veg for most of us so that's six
weeks that means if you're running a
nine week flower cycle at week three of
flower you need to cut new clones so
that they can ruin 14 days and they can
veg for four weeks and then as soon as
you cut down that flower room you can
move those veg plants in there and not
have any downtime I'm not sure of your
schedule but that's a good example of
what you need to start doing if you want
to make the best of your grow room a
very easy and attainable goal is to set
more scheduling for your grow the
hardest part about that is staying on
top of the schedule once you set it like
I talked about at the start of the show
I want to make more lemon Jeffery seeds
I can't do it until the summer because I
have scheduled my rooms out for at least
the next six months and I know that
sounds like a long time but if you think
about it that's only three crops in a
certain in one room if you're flowering
in one room six months three crops
that's actually 2.75 crops because
there's a few extra days there at the
end because we do the nine week cycles
and not four so that's gonna be like
2.75 crops but my point is that I've got
it scheduled I've got a plan I know what
I'm gonna do and I'm
going to do my best to stay on that
schedule and not mess myself up if I do
it right I know how many cycles I'll be
able to get this year out of that room I
have a good estimation of how many seeds
I'll be able to produce out of that room
this year it just helps you plan it
helps you stay on top of things and it
helps you set goals so set some goals
you guys so far we've set goals to get
better yields better potency and better
scheduling now let's talk about random
things that you guys may be able to set
a goal to get better at and your grow
something a lot of us could get better
at in our grow is cloning how is your
clone tech are 70% of your clones living
are 80% of your clones living how many
of your clones live now if you were to
cut a hundred clones how many do you
think would be surviving and usable in
about 15 days if I said hey dude let's
cut a hundred clones together right now
you and me and I'll be back in 14 days
how many of them would you be proud to
show me and how many of them would you
be embarrassed to show me so if you said
50 of them would have died let's
increase your clone success rate to 70
percent this year
if you said 70 percent let's get you up
to 90 if you're in the 80 or 90 percent
let's get you a hundred percent success
in your clones I'd like to see everybody
have a hundred percent success with
their clones but I understand there's
some learning to be done we're not all
spending all day in a garden we're not
all spending all of our time learning
about cannabis but a goal that is
attainable is improvement so if you're
at fifty percent let's get you to 70 if
you're at 70 let's get you to 85 or 90
let's just improve your clone technique
everybody can get better at cloning all
you have to do is pay more attention
maybe leave the clones alone I see a lot
of people [ __ ] with clones too much and
that's where they ruin them so let's get
you better at your clone technique and
then another thing that people can
definitely improve on at the totally
opposite end of the girl from cloning is
the drying and curing process I see a
lot of people grow amazing cannabis they
grow it they take great pictures they
cut it down they trim it like a [ __ ]
champ they take more pictures and then
they ruin it by not drying and curing it
properly I have put out a couple of
episodes about drying and curing I will
answer your questions about drying and
curing if you email me I will help you
out so all of the crops that you're
going to produce this year in 2018 that
you have got
and planned for your goals you're going
to have to learn to dry and cure them
better let's make that one of your goals
for 2018 even if you're already an
amazing grower if you're a pro grower if
you know how to cure weed you can do it
better especially if you're in Colorado
so let's work on learning to dry and
cure a little better that is a goal that
you can achieve and if we say just a
little better you just have to do better
than last year and if you grow five or
six crops you're gonna get five or six
good chances at getting better this year
so drying and curing is something we can
all work on and if you need more
guidance on that email me to grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I will talk
you through drying and curing I will
write out an SOP and we will get your
cannabis dried properly all right and
one more thing that you can work on in
2018 that you can improve on a goal that
you can set would be to become more cost
efficient if you are a new grower if
you're a pro grower if you're an expert
if you're growing in a closet if you're
running a large commercial facility
there are ways that you can become more
cost effective are you wasting
electricity somewhere are you wasting
nutrients somewhere are you wasting
product somewhere are you wasting time
somewhere let's look at our process in
the garden and streamline the time that
we spend in there and streamline the
money that we spend in there maybe we're
wasting water somewhere let's figure
that out maybe we're wasting electricity
somewhere let's figure that out do you
have a fan and air conditioner and a
blower on at the same time that maybe
you only need two of those if you're
growing for profit if you're drawing for
medicine every penny counts either way
because somebody's got to pay for it and
if you're drawing electricity if you're
wasting water it's just going down the
drain basically and who can afford to
put anything down the drain these days
and also think about the environmental
factors if you're wasting electricity
and wasting water you were destroying
the environment for no reason we're
running out of resources and wasting
money so try to become more cost
effective and at the same time try to
become more environmentally conscious
that's something that all of us can do
we're all buying bottled nutrients that
have to be shipped across the country we
use the nutrients we throw the plastic
bottles away let's try to be more
environmentally conscious let's be more
sustainable let's be more responsible
that's an easy goal then
we can all set and try to reach in 2018
all right I hope I have inspired you
guys to set some goals I hope I've
inspired you guys to improve your garden
I hope you've got a notebook and a pen
or maybe something in your phone and
took a note and actually wrote some
goals maybe take a minute and think
about some goals for your garden also
think about some goals for your life in
2018 your garden shouldn't be the only
thing you're worried about challenge
yourself set some goals for yourself
write it down set some expectations
reach those goals move your life forward
get yourself out of the hole you're
stuck in make your own life better
alright I want to thank everybody for
listening to me ramble on for about 30
minutes
ladies and gentleman I would appreciate
it if you find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast find me on twitter at g f YH
podcast of course there are a hundred
and thirtysomething youtube videos now
if you go to youtube and search for the
girl from your heart podcast you can
watch about a hundred and thirty five of
the old videos I would appreciate it if
you subscribe to me on youtube also
check me out on instagram i am just
about at sixteen thousand followers on
instagram i use my other company name
it's I read genetics i RIE underscore GE
and ET ICS on Instagram I post a bunch
of great cannabis photography there I
think you would enjoy it if you want to
interact with me and you're not into all
the social media stuff you can simply
send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I love answering
listener questions so send me an email I
would love to hear from you you guys
this is the part of the podcast where I
remind you about patreon this podcast
will always be free but if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
I would appreciate it if you go to
patreon.com
and sign up to contribute to the podcast
what I will do with your contributions
is I will pay for my website
I read genetics Colorado comm is where I
host the podcast the podcast is free for
you but it does cost me a few bucks to
host that website so when you contribute
to patreon I will use those funds to
cover the cost of my website to keep
this podcast coming to you guys for free
I also use those funds to buy microphone
covers and water bottles and if any of
my equipment happens to break I will use
the patreon funding to cover that sort
of stuff but that's what patreon is for
I'm not trying to beg I just know that
there are a few people out there who
have offered to make contributions to
the show and so I made sure that there
an option and Big Shot to everybody who
has contributed to the patreon campaign
I was actually able to cover the cost of
the website this year without reaching
into my pocket patreon covered that all
for me this year so huge shout out to
everybody that contributed to patreon
I truly appreciate it thank you all
right podcast rolled I'm gonna wrap up
this episode I want to wish everybody a
Happy New Year
I hope 2018 brings you everything you
deserve I will be back Thursday with the
throwback Thursday episode of course
I'll be back Monday with a brand new
grow episode I want to give you a huge
shout out to my friend Hot Sauce Herman
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
people of some hypocrisy call laws you
can drink John tell you John consistence
and it is legal just because of the
bones and depends on you
[Music]
the word equalizer have you heard the
word legalize er have you heard the word
legalize er a few word the word realized
equipment in life beyond metropolitan
peace I rest in peace we ascend the time
of all the bodies too much time before
time to leave look round the world Oh
primer increase one wattage murder upon
wicked Steve Wang Bacchus the robber
them under six piece under people in
apiece
[Music]