[Music]
oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode of to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 161 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host my friends
call me Ross - Jeff Lana thank you guys
again for joining me as always I want to
send a huge thank you to my friends in
the music on my podcast evening why is
it so warm the barefoot grower is back
on the podcast welcome to show bro
thanks for coming my lips are all sticky
cuz we just took some super delicious
dabs in the dab rig that I've got from
elevate as that mouthpiece that makes
your mouth kind of do the kissy face and
it made my lips all sticky so my words
are going stinky dad waxing my mustache
I used to go to the clinic in Denver and
they sold this Durbin poison wax and it
had the best I loved it but after you
would smoke if you put your teeth
together they would stick together a
little bit stick my teeth together and
pull apart it was almost like you took a
bite of a crown but for some reason I
loved the texture quitting let's see
shadow to our friends at elevate glass
because I've been hitting this purple or
this orange pumpkin rig like a boss that
banger is filthy the rig needs a bath
thanks again you guys for the dope rig
so we've got a bunch of notes are you
still blowing glass dude or is that kind
of endo
just kind of put on I'm hoping to maybe
one day get back into the do miss it I
do miss huge smile when we started
talking about it yeah whenever I go
because I have some friends that still
do it and if I go to their house or
whatever you think you still got the
spin technique mastered like to think I
do but you know I don't know if it's
like riding a bike or not I mean I would
take like a couple days off I've got
these big humbly rookie hands and I
can't so when you're blowing glass you
guys and I do not know very very little
about making glass but when you're
blowing glass you got to turn it you
have to turn your right hand in your
left hand at the same time and you got
to have the torch in the middle ish or
whatever section you're heating
and if one hand spins faster than the
other here [ __ ] starts twisting you and
if you one hand goes higher than the
other your piece starts bending and
there's a flame in front of you and it's
hot and your muscles start twitching
because you're doing the same thing so
it's kind of a pain in the ass but so
shout out to the people who who do yeah
I mean your your work was great so I
hope you get back into I'm sure you will
let's uh let's talk about your new
venture now one of the things that I
wrote down that I wanted to make sure we
cover is that you went from a basement
grow to a large facility in a very short
time so how long you're from North
Carolina right yes did you grow ganja in
North Carolina I did I kind of like I
did it for a few years there not
successfully for the first year dried in
Asheville and just failed miserably
gotten into flour and then like sprayed
cal-mag on the plants as a foliar one
day and like totally like just I don't
really don't know what I was thinking it
was one of those just had no nobody to
ask no nothing to do and thought that
was hell I don't know
so healed those plans you learned yeah
exactly and then when I lived in
Charlotte I had an apartment and I got a
tend to start growing on my claws I've
actually got some genetics so some some
I read genetics
long ago it was about in the future for
you pull off a couple of harvest they're
growing in North Carolina I was doing I
mean I didn't but if I was doing like
North Carolina like
North Carolina all right so you've been
here for about a year and a half yeah
since May how long did it take you to
get a grouse when you got here like not
even kidding I got here all the shit's
still in the u-haul truck I'm glad it
worked out for you a lot of people came
out weren't able to put it together so
glad you're motivated motivated potheads
all right so how long did it take so you
blueglass were like about six or eight
months it seemed like about six seven
months okay
pay attention and then you got into how
did tell us where you're working now
with the large facility I am now at
ascend cannabis company it's a cool name
I was gonna use that first screen name
but yeah it's a sin cannabis company we
have our dispensary up in Lakewood our
grow we're how our growth greenhouse is
here in Pueblo it's really big huge
facilities pretty sweet definitely a big
step up from the basement how many
plants are you in charge of I have 320
plants and flower at all times that I'm
in charge of in flight what size pots 20
gallons forty gallon so those are huge
plants how often in the summer at peak
harvest are at peak flowering how often
do those plants need to be watered we
water every other day sometimes the
plants like in the center of the
greenhouse where they get more Sun and
more light every single day Wow yeah we
had a lot of we had a couple beds that
we were hitting every single day this do
you know how many gallons of water
you're throwing in a 20 gallon pot it's
around two and a half gallons per I've
expected more we have 300 gallons for
120 plants to in a fraction like a good
solid eight to ten hours of work seven
o'clock
until on a good day we got at 4:00 4:30
a little bit of a drive because it's not
right in town I went for a drive I took
a friend of mine to go see the leaves
change shine at the JB I took go see the
leaves change colors out by toward the
castle and we went to the castle luckily
we went before the fires oh my god it's
still raging yeah yeah a big big show
that's all the people that have to deal
with those fires I feel so bad for you
my whole vibe does change but I thought
about it but we went out there and there
are so if you're paying attention there
are so many grows out
there there's a grow every five miles
off to the left to the right side of the
interstate some of them are super
high-tech and fancy some were a little
jank
but there are so many grows out there
from from Pueblo to all the way into
almost to the castle there's a grow on
highway 96 to the left or the right all
the time so you guys have you got to
take your girlfriend's out there or your
significant other your side chick or
your boo you got to take them out on a
road trip you look at the leaves in
Colorado go drive up highway 96 between
pueblos and like Wetmore and then keep
going even further up into West Cliff
and look at all of the grows on the left
and right side of the highway
it's amazing you'll enjoy all right so
one thing I want to talk about you
started off in a basement like a lot of
things do graduated do a basement I've
seen your pictures you crush it you grew
some Kalonji cush that was gorgeous
love that
- my favorite strains put together let's
talk about some of the stuff that you
learned that is different that you had
adjust major differences you've noticed
and learned going from like a small grow
in your basement to this big gigantic
you said you had a greenhouse do you
know how many square feet not ask couple
people no one seems to know for sure
what it is but we have we have two
flower rooms and in each flower room
there is 640 plants and 20 gallons and
or raised bed we got raised beds and a
couple raised beds if you prefer the
raised beds seems to be okay what's
better about them it's just with the way
we do them our raised beds are fed
differently than we do our 20s our 20s
they get we actually get the invest
compost teas okay we use those and we
brew those but for the raised bed it's
been no-till and it's been going no-till
we haven't added any soil to it other
than what goes in with the transplants
it's been like that since the opening of
the greenhouse I think two years ago Wow
and it's full of life because we're all
organic it's full of life full of
microbes and it's just it's just really
cool the plants seem they get they look
bigger in the raised bed - they've got
more
space for the roots to get out and the
flowers just always seem to be a little
bit better out of the race bed Wow
that's what we're trying to transition
into complete all raised beds okay
keeping that life going and then we'll
talk more about that when we get to the
next part here so let's talk more about
some of the stuff that you had to change
and that you've noticed going to the big
grow yeah it's pretty crazy like you
know I the biggest I've ever had at my
house was a 4k in the basement and now
we've got we have 112 kavita's in each
room so we've got 224 lights so I'm
going from four lights to 220 for now
and just getting used to the size of the
plans and how often I got a water room
and how much I got a water I'm really
changed it's just it was just basically
it put into perspective how how little I
actually was doing at my house right but
it made my growing at home a lot easier
to be honest oh yeah I feel the same
exactly it's like wow I used to think
that watering these twenty plants was
hard but now I'm wondering every day
checking for bugs making sure there's no
problems but in supporting sticks
everywhere you need a city it's an M IDI
grow so you gotta make sure that
everything is tagged properly yeah that
was one thing that was really crazy was
going and getting because I had never
done anything other than a basement grow
until I got here like I never worked in
any dispensary I've never been in the
industry ever I got my badge and started
working there and so that was one thing
that was crazy was seeing like how
heavily like it's like everything has to
be tagged react you get rid of it you
have to make sure that you like get rid
of it in the computer and throw it in
the right basket and incinerate the
basket and like it that thing that was
really that was crazy to be yeah it's
still crazy it's overkill but I like I
like the overkill kind of music to it
keeps the I feel like it keeps everybody
in check and it keeps the people that
shouldn't be shouldn't be doing it it
keeps them kind of at bay it creates a
standard exactly and if you can live up
to that standard then you shouldn't be
growing this product this is a medical
product it is it's also a recreational
product for a lot of people but I think
that recreational use is also medical
for sure that makes sense
it's my recreational yeah it's six of us
manage that and so you know we have our
spray days on Wednesday and Saturday and
we've got I think I sent you that
sprayer we had that one time you saw
that yeah huge and so we just have
everybody kind of rotates how we we
spray but we spray every week two days a
week all the way through up until like
the last week but we are like I said all
organic we're spraying 100% organic neem
oil and 100 organic essentials no no
chemicals or nothing all right well it's
a kind of transition to that part
because that's something that I've
definitely noticed since you started
working at this place your home grow has
completely switched to fully organic now
right was that inspired by this place it
was inspired by a few different things
to be honest I started working there
when I got the grow you know I was
watering my plants and so I needed
something to listen to and I started
listening to you old podcast episodes of
yours that I haven't listened to since I
lived in North Carolina so I figured you
know I've learned a couple new things
let me see if I can take anything new
from these and I was listening to the
episodes with Sean Sean Sean at the King
:
and yeah he really he was so passionate
[Music]
rösti and he's super he was he was
throwing dropping knowledge on me every
day and going dad just like you know I
like I was gonna do I had my outdoor
going I was like I'm gonna do a raised
bed no-till organic outdoor for the
summer and see how much I like organic
and I might switch to it then I was like
you know why don't I just completely go
organic it's so much I feel like it's so
much I know it's better like I just you
know I know like it's it's just
I don't know so I made the switch
completely and now that I've been doing
it I've had one fool complete like from
because I switch kind of halfway through
a cycle you know what I'm not gonna use
these bottles anymore I'm organic now
nice and so I had plants and veg and
then plants halfway through flower went
through that cycle of plants and becha
came through when I went through but I
just now just like last week to go down
my first from seed to harvest like 100
fully organic sweet and it's by far the
best Congrats thank you are you going to
eventually turn your home grow into
no-till that's what I want to do do you
want to teach my listeners just briefly
a quick lesson on no tilt because I
don't think we've covered too much
no-till on the but it's basically
no-till soil is when you have a soil
that you've amended yourself and you've
planted the plant in it and you just
defeated top dressings and whatever to
use you want to do whatever you got to
do you've got worms in there you get a
lot of microbe life going in there and
it's after three years I believe that
you've been running this way you never
you never actually like take the soil up
or put new soil you reuse the soil every
time just taking the root ball out and
putting a new plan in we're using the
old dirt trying to just in no-till you
want to irritate the land as little as
possible okay and after three years it's
basically self-sustaining all you need
to need to do is that water Wow yeah but
with the no diligence you've got a lot
of microbe life living in there you've
got a lot of microorganisms breaking
everything down your plants are really
really really gonna thrive in a well
maintained no-till environment because
um you know you're not really feeding
your plants at that point you're feeding
these microorganisms that live in your
soil and then they're gonna absorb all
these things that you're feeding them
release them back into the soil and
that's what your plans are gonna uptake
and it's you know it's a cycle of life
it's how things are meant to be and
you're just carefully maintaining it
there and it allows the plant to eat
what it wants is exactly the ratios
you're not forced feeding it some bottle
you're not holding it down putting a
nipple on a bottle
and formula in its mouth beautiful yeah
okay and so how long does it take to can
I almost take if I grow a crop now
that's not know till they'll cause it's
not amended so I can't do it never mind
I think I know the answer I was gonna
ask if I could take a plant that I'm
gonna harvest tomorrow chop the plant
pull the root ball out can I now start
my no-till process with that soil or do
I need to pre prep my pot beginning you
probably could you know I'm saying but
it would probably be best to start it in
an amended soil okay because you so that
way you know you've already got your
soil is already inoculated you've got
life all the way from the top to the
bottom because if you're just throwing a
new plan in there at that point you're
kind of just it's gonna be it's gonna
take a couple weeks for it to take off
really because it's not gonna have any
the there's no there's no life in there
to give it right food's gonna fire
exacts gotta get going okay sounds like
a great method to Lindsay the traveling
stoner she just called while returning
to a podcast Lindsay I hope you're
listening I'll call you back after we
get done recording I'm excited about
it's called all right so where are we
all my notes we got distracted here then
no till that sounds great I kind of want
to get into that school you learn it's
fun I don't know it's really hard to
explain you just get a better feel more
like it sounds cheesy but you feel more
in sync with your plans when you're like
right when you're controlling their
environment that's sort of uh when Sean
was here often and we all got it when I
was being sponsored by the rocky
mountain worm company big shout out to
Jay from the rocky mountain worm company
they were sponsoring me and they were
actually giving me all of the amendments
that I needed to do everything
organically I really loved my product
and I loved if I felt like a farmer you
know it again exactly had warm [ __ ]
underneath my fingernails and I've
smelled like fish fish emulsion and I
was just funky you know what I mean
Realty brewing in my house right now I'm
gonna walk in the door
just smelling in and you've got the five
gallon bucket of tea brewing and there's
foam three but I also I ran a drain and
healthy we did nutrients that came out
of big five gallon jugs into I put them
into basically a beaker and then put
those into a reservoir and mixed it
adjust in the pH and I did it with like
goggles on and gloves and it felt very
scientifically like that is welcome at
home I'm running I like botanic air
bottles it's simple for what I do I
breed and so I don't need to do a lot of
crazy [ __ ] for what I'm breeding with
and the botanic air is perfect it's I
like mixing the bottles a little bit I
put some worm castings in there there's
a little bottles to be the easiest way
for me I did a bunch of veg bloom I've
got vegetable it'll probably go in the
next cycle I've actually noticed I
wanted to save this for a whole episode
I've noticed it will do an episode about
this certain strains actually prefer
certain nutrients I've noticed that if I
cuz I've ran I've been doing this for a
long time I've ran so many nutrient
lines and I've had flow for ten years
and I've noticed that if I run flow with
this brand it backs this way if I run
flow with this branded acts this way
different brands they've had the same
grow rooms set up for so long and yeah
change from different nutrients psycho
made everything real colorful and fluffy
but I hated the flavor advanced
nutrients made everything taste exactly
the same but I got huge buds but
everything tasted exactly that was I
think the advanced might have been one
of the first brands I tried to use nice
yeah started with Mills it was I mean it
was cool you know I liked the results
that I was getting but the organic is
just it's like there's more fun to me
just I feel like I'm doing more I'm
gonna write no-till look I've grabbed
this
ever this is actually it looks like a
green colored pencil and it's actually a
glass I just grabbed this way frosty if
you listen to this just text me or
message me on Instagram or Facebook
right now I'd be like how do I get on
your podcast and if not I'll get will to
put me in touch with you or I'll hit you
up on Instagram and we'll get you on the
podcast talk about no-till because I'm
sure a lot of our listeners are like I
want to know the recipe for the soil
just got teased on too cool episode
gonna be coming up so there are worms in
there how large is your raised bed I'm
guessing three by three or four by four
we have 40 plants okay there's a really
really really really I'm just gonna ask
how many worms are in there like how
many did you put in there that's I want
to see that gone - enough big outdoor
grows this you gotta label everything
everything's gonna be tagged by the meb
so I can't just grab a clone and drive
over there and be like here's a clone
you guys now you have Capleton
good luck yeah bring you some over there
all right so what's next what's the next
evolution if you go all full no-till
then what's the next the next way to
improve your garden after that I mean
100 you know you do your thing you
figure out some good top dressed recipes
really just you cuz I mean by that point
you got a full-on no to like I mean
Mountain organics everybody on Instagram
really wants to see like some really I
mean this guy's where I
discovered no-till from a couple years
back before I even knew what no-till was
I was following this guy mountain
organics he's he's got the tech down
with the no-till
but um yeah once you've got it going for
like that many cycles you know you you
know what it you know what you need and
I really don't think there's much more
you can do other than just kind of like
seeing if anything new comes out you
know if I do a new style of you know
hunting
you said that you use easy cloners at
the big Grove and we were talking before
the show how do you do those organically
just curious its om our eyes or max okay
[Music]
we just started using this uh inoculum
from mountain organics actually that is
supposed to be the truth so we'll see we
actually just sorted using that last
week so uh yeah
I was told that inside of the claw Dex
dipping gel that I use for Mike Lohner
that there is a clearing that there is a
chemical called purple lavender dye I
think is what it is lavender
I think it's purple lavender dye and a
friend mine was like oh dude don't use
that chicks he saw it on my shelf and
he's actually I don't know his degree
but he's got college degrees and when he
saw he's like no freaked out on me he
told me to get rid of that [ __ ] so you
guys do some research that purple velvet
die or purple crystalline velvet die or
something like that I don't recall
exactly but if you google clone x find
the ingredients that purple dye and
they're supposed to be really bad for
you also there's something in there that
it's really not good for you if you get
it on your hands and stuff it could
definitely cause you some problems so go
do some research on clone X that's why I
was asking well how they do it
organically yeah we do most of our
wheelies the clone boxes those are like
we're trying to phase out of those so we
just have two of those right now
most of our clones go into little root
rights that we have packed into little
like one-by-one cubes with some pro mix
and then just a little like a solution
of ro aloe and then some some humic
acids okay from bio AG and then we dip
those in the aloe and just let those
the domes for two weeks they seem to
love hallo everybody's on the hello
liquid aloe or power we get just
straight raw cold-pressed aloe okay
cutting in that put it right into the
root riot and with if you're putting it
in your water I mean you need this just
a small finite amount of aloe goes a
long long way okay like for a whole 300
gallons when we're watering our plants
we use one ounce oh [ __ ] okay so just
one ounce that's like a coffee cup
basically okay nice a lot of people are
gonna be thinking where can I get some
powder - hallo that's not something if
you've got a recommendation go for it
calm I recommend that everything you
like don't know anything about organics
and like don't know where to go and need
its but he's got everything you need on
there to start doing organically from
like buying the supplies and then he
also has like directions on how to clone
veg flour different top dress regimens
he's got everything you need to know on
there he's a real real those guys are
great I haven't checked out their
website in a little while but yeah I
need to go check that sounds like
they've updated a whole bunch but you've
got all your powder dry organic
amendments and they'll ship them to you
everywhere the great price is very
affordable they're reasonable the more
you buy the cheaper it gets because
they're powdered in their bulk they
don't waste a lot of money on a lot of
packaging so they're actually gonna make
a little package up for you they're
gonna weigh it they're in their
warehouse they're gonna ship out exactly
what you order great customer service
one time there was a weird something
weird with my order
I wondered like two things on the same
day and wanted to be in the same order
and I emailed him and like he personally
called me from like his cell phone and
got it worked out with me and got it all
shipped out no after charge nothing
that's really cool yeah I love companies
to do that kind of stuff in the grow
industry there are a lot of companies
that if they make a mistake they go home
we've got your money have a nice day
he'll either see you again or we won't
[Music]
yeah Bry wrote down a whole bunch of
notes but you wrote down a bunch of
notes do I want to make sure that we
cover anything that you wanted to talk
about shattered out frosty yeah frosty
is a good dude I don't see that dude
often enough we have to make sure to
give that dude a huge shoutout we're
gonna get him on the show for a no till
frosty don't be nervous just come on the
show bro here is the vortex Brewers and
irrigation systems that I learned at
work that sounds pretty cool if you're
into brewing teas compost seeds and
everything you know the more agitation
they get the better it sounds like they
brew faster and a little it's gonna be a
little stronger the microbes are gonna
be a little more active and that they
grew more irrigated I'm just using air
stones works but the vortex is Brewer
it's kind of self-explanatory there's
like you know it's a vortex that spins
inside there's three tubes and it spins
the water really felt like a vortex
super fast super fast yeah and it'll get
I mean you'll get a tube ruin where
you'll have bubbles popping up within
minutes and it's not like there's no
extra yuca in there anything like that
it's just wow it's just it gets so
quickly I've actually seen guys clean
out their vortex Brewer and put bubble
bags in there and make hash in it that's
because it's been in the irrigation
system what else we gonna talk about
there I could never be on a run one in
my house because I mean I'm okay I have
like at most 40 plants inside but uh
it's really cool it's you know I I'm
sure most people know about with their
growers but for those of you that don't
it's a irrigation system is basically a
self watering system that you put put a
little emitter in each pot or down the
line of the raised bed and you turn on a
motor and it just sucks all the water on
the tank and gives each plant the exact
same amount of water it cuts the
watering time from like an hour and a
half to about 20 minutes right the time
it takes you to build that system saves
you so my gosh I've been telling all of
the listeners that we're gonna talk
about building a watering system so you
just teased it again half way written
like a forget about half way written
it's kind of very specific it's for your
knee
it's guyline written so we'll put that
out pretty soon here I can record that
one like it'll take me less than an hour
so just sit down and do that one night
so guys that one's coming how to build
your own irrigation system or their
suite I think that if you've got eight
plants or a hundred and eight plants or
800 plants I think an irrigation system
could be very useful for you it
sometimes when I'm away see if they're
dry or when I had the larger grow I just
wanted I would go to Denver for shows
and on the way back I would stop and
grow and check on the plan she can't go
wrong sometimes it will clog eventually
your your watering system is going to
clog but we'll talk about building one
of those it's very useful matter how
many plants you're running five be as
big as me come on and then I put my
dreads in a giant bun and now I'm like
seven feet tall at that point it's fun
to grow room can't we're too baggy of
clothes because I get hung up on
everything a little bit sometimes
gigantic walk like yeah all right you
shut it up frosty we want to get you on
the show dude let's do some no-till
stuff let's do some stuff we've talked
about your work we talked about you
moving dude I'm glad you came out here
because we made good friends we both got
the kind of blondish all mostly ginger
big freaking Viking beers we both showed
up barefoot friends great friends since
you're on a microphone dude and you got
free rein of the world let's talk about
what you're gonna do next row you got
any huge plans for the world I did mine
just bought some property about five
acres land and Costilla County feeling
super missing stuff right now we'll see
we'll see where it takes us we're just
getting some stuff done out there and
barefoot farms yeah we're hoping to get
a little barefoot
there's something going on out there
[Music]
because the word like 30 minutes most of
my listeners kind of dip out around 36
minutes so man thanks for joining us on
the podcast I've got some gonna laugh at
me I've got some blue dream shatter that
is pretty damn good I think the blue
dream shattered he made us chatty just
have a great podcast - the blue dream
shatter that's really funny because if
you know me you know I got some blue
dream shatter for you that's funny
alright bro thanks for coming to you
anything else you want to share with the
world before we turn off the microphones
Instagram cannabis Co ASCE indeed rising
to the top
we're formally healing house for those
of you who are familiar with the healing
house it was the healing house and then
there was a split and now it's ascend
and the healing house is a separate
company Jess in cannabis Co on Instagram
and then we are also a large hold we do
wholesale for a lot of places all over
Colorado so if you are in Pueblo you can
find some of us at leaf in the Mesa you
can find our flower at live well in
Trinidad we're at Highland Health and
kanuk Oh up in Denver we're at life
flower in Fort Collins check us out at
solace and then if you're ever in the
Lakewood area come to our dispensary
it's a sin yeah awesome yeah how can
people follow you on Instagram you can
check me out on the at the barefoot
grower it's the underscore
barefoot underscore grower I'll probably
follow you back if I think you're paid
school yeah we follow each other yeah
great [ __ ] make sure you guys follow me
also on instagram please I'm almost to
nine thousand followers I think it's at
Irie underscore genetics of course I'm
Harry genetics the seed company sure
most you guys know that by now so you
can hire you genetics the seed company
I'm gonna do another shameless plug make
sure you guys check out the dank team
calm the dank team has got some eye
region that exceeds available a lot of
people been asking how do I get your
seeds you guys you go to the dank team
calm let me click on the IRA genetics
flag it's real easy to find it's red
gold and green it's got a big C in the
middle click on there see what's
available order them up order them up
get them while you can
there is a discount coupon code that I'm
trying to think of it's dank cannabis
discount coupon code is dank cannabis
it'll get you ten maybe twelve percent
off check that out is if you've got a
product you want me to review or if you
want to sponsor the podcast that's what
I'm trying to say send me an email screw
for me heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you bro thanks
again for joining me turn off the mics
and take some Babs and chill out for a
few it's warm in here open the front
door get some air going about the winter
we are rambling again ladies and
gentlemen big shout out to Maddy and
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
music
you
[Music]
well community let me clear my throat
for episode number 163 of the graphic
art podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation if
you're professional growers if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Ross the Jeff
onna thank you guys again for joining me
as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to my friends in the
mystic roots band for letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat to an entire Mystic Krewe ladies
and gentlemen thanks for uh dealing with
the clogged up throat Jessie's fault I
blame it on Jessie Jessie showed up with
good hash and liquid Terps welcome the
show Jessie Thank You Jenna Jessie grows
is back if you're not following Jessie
on Instagram I'm pretty sure he's on
there he's got 44 on there together you
guys I know I know I'm gonna get a whole
bunch of [ __ ] messages I said the
wrong episode number at the start of the
last episode I did not have any notes in
front of me with episode number written
on it like I normally do I wrote it down
this time I think I got it right
although I did have to clear my throat
we did the best we could
thanks for trying to keep me on the
right path
so before we hit record here Jessie we
like to hang out before the podcast we
get nice and medicated we get into a
talking little zone here on a cleanse
hasn't been taken a lot of dad's hasn't
been consuming a lot of cannabis so when
he took the first dam I watched him
see he's a big dude and I just watched
him kind of melt a little bit after the
first dab he brought over some liquid
sfv some San Fernando Valley OG Kush
Turks and some Durbin poison wax I
dunked a dab of what am i smoking some
Jack flash yeah I dunked a dab of Jack
flash into the Terps I was trippin Delic
it was amazing Thank You turbid oh I
think that might be my word Webster's
swag very so we were talking before the
show as I was mentioning we're getting
nice and roasted and medicated taking
dad's off the email and Jesse was
telling me that he went to Oregon and he
was actually ballsy enough to take his
medicine on the plane with him a whole
bunch of it will tell everybody what you
traveled on a plane with I took
ridiculous I took the library as water
hash frozen
some flour a little bit of clear some
turps and a couple of the doctor's
orders vaping cartridges did you ever
read within two rigs pretty much
everything but a torch yeah I knew not
to that is very similar to a bomb it's
already a bomb essentially yes so they
don't they don't want that on the plane
so I took all that well the rigs were in
a locked case so and I put the rigs in
my check-in baggage okay all the product
that I kept it on my purse or in my
carry-on it was back sealed and then in
a ziplock baggie and I took my med card
and a copy of my driver's license and
put it in there so it was the first
thing they would see they totally went
through my bag and it went through the
x-ray scanner and everything and I flew
there and back with with it all okay and
nobody gave you any harassment at all
never so you get to enjoy your medical
marijuana while you were in the great
state of Oregon and Washington I flew
out of a different Airport Oh a great
vacation yeah awesome
very much needed what was your favorite
part um getting to see my best friend
from high school and lifelong buddy
get married to a woman he's absolutely
crazy about was very cool but the Oregon
coast is just absolutely unbelievable
it's so stunning nice yeah I highly
recommend checking shout out to the new
to the new married couple I don't know
if they listen to a podcast but trying
to get you on for a little while you've
been a busy dude you've got a new job
we're talking how many plants you run
well was on yesterday will was running I
think he said 640 plants is what I think
he said on his own it's a lot of work
this is uh basically I've had I've ran
little med shop gross and now I'm in a
big yeah you were saying earlier that it
took you all day to cut three to four
hundred clones yeah yeah people there
were people that would probably they
probably heard that that went [ __ ] man I
could probably cut a thousand calls
today oh great a you know perfectly
chosen right perfectly chosen and you
said that you don't keep mother plants
that you take the clones off the veg
plants you've got to run through the veg
area with a cop or a container of water
and get cuts gather them up and then go
back to the cloning area out of consult
back with with the schedule I've got to
look at the schedule of stuff that's
already been harvested and I got to look
at the stuff that is gonna be before it
so that we have we have a specific
program to harvest four strains a week
out of our 16 strains so that we always
have extra on hand and to keep in track
with all of that also is a lot of work
then it's things that people don't think
about is trying to keep the variety
coming consistently because in a grow
you're gonna want to put let's do this
whole row of Sour Diesel per se just
because you want that whole row but then
when it comes time to put it on
shelf now you've got a whole bunch of
Sour Diesel so if somebody comes to the
dispensary to buy product I should turn
a Sour Diesel if that's all you're
interested in and then see where a
wholesaler so that makes it even worse
so the dispensary buyer comes to us and
you know we got a whole bunch of Sour
Diesel even if it's Bom you know they're
probably just gonna go on
so that's rain big reasons we have to
have 31 flavors yeah that's what keeps
them coming back if you could probably
if you could probably sell 10 pounds of
that saundra diesel but if you had five
other strains you could probably salt
seven pounds of each one of them just
because of the variety yes a variety of
this kink that's gonna people don't
think about what it takes I've been
talking a little bit about it on the
show about commercial growing people
don't think about what it takes it's
good to hear you come in and talk about
just scheduling the Clones cuz it starts
at the Clones you got a schedule two
clones to know what your variety is
going to be in about 120 days it's more
like 94 for my situation but you know
planning preparation and then everything
you do this is something that I got
sidetracked on when I was talking with
will everything you do has to be
documented in metric pretty much of your
scissors you have to open up a computer
and make a note somewhere in the wheels
and I pushed around to one of the
smaller areas if you cut off so there
are varying different different
compliance officers will tell you
different rules on this if you cut off
something on a plant it needs to be
weighed and documented in metric you
have to go to that plant tag number you
have to say I manicured
point four grams off of plant number
nine zero five five five and then you
have to show on camera that you destroy
the part that was manicured off the
plant it's but it's very tedious and
metric very tedious alright so we talked
about dabs on a plane Jessie I was
taking shooter on a plane and he looks
like an ogre - and then we talk about
gross space let's talk about what we
brought you here for the main topic the
G whoa when we talked on Facebook you're
like I want to talk about reminding
people to clean up their gross space
after the outdoor season for sure yeah
so what do you want to tell us about
that that is a super good topic I mean
it depends on how you grow I guess but
you know I'm an organic grower kind of
homestead style as a term a real farmer
yeah yes a term I've been using lately I
picked it up from a person in Oregon so
give that person a shout-out did you
mention the podcast I'm not surprised
hippie Mary she lived on the coast down
the road from the place I was staying
and it's normally not like me just go
out and just randomly start talking to
strangers but for some reason I there
were some huge tomato plants every yard
that kind of attracted me to her so
ended up making a friend out there but
that's the true farmer in you yeah the
tomato plants are done in Colorado
they've been harvested and eaten by now
and she had Tomatoes up there and Jesse
was like oh no I told her how she grows
how I grew is she actually had a couple
times out back too but uh I told her how
I grew and she called me a homestead
farmer so a homestead grower so it feels
good but my situation I've got living
soil I've got a whole bunch of plant
waste the leaves the stalks all that so
I've taken all of that and ran it
through a chipper into the compost pile
ok so by next you know summer that will
be nice black compost and it'll have you
know all the nutrients that were still
in it and this is the this will be the
third year we've done this
but it just all goes right back into the
system again that's awesome um so I I'm
old up my soil real good i watered it
down real good and I've got it covered
with plastic to store it over the winter
gonna make a nice mycelium layer happen
okay that's a good thing guys when you
see a lot of people see that white fuzz
they'll make recent bristle or there or
they'll make some compost yeah and they
see that white fuzz and they freak out
that's what you're working for that's
the goal that white fuzz is magic yes
sir that's what's gonna make all the
[ __ ] happen yeah we got all that handled
the plastic is good for several things
it helps insulate the soil on really
cold days I mean on really cold days
it's it's gonna get cold
there's nothing you can do about that
but on days when it warms up and then it
cools off again it can the the warmer
the soil stays the more breakdown
happens the more healthy 90 days alive
yeah so it protects it from that it
protects it from getting blown away
drying out and blowing you know all the
precious topsoil off and then also
something I've noticed last year is it
keeps the damn neighborhood cats from
yeah neighborhood cats love to piss and
do their thing in your in your nice
fresh garden soil so it keeps them away
too
perfect yes cats probably helps keeps
birds out it's possibly Oh birds
wouldn't be so bad but yeah yeah so you
can shoot in there oh yeah well that
goes into the compost pile so it just
all returns
back to the do you use a bow coffee
bucket at home yes
before that Bokashi bucket right into
there if you have another use for it um
normally I put it in the compost pile
or I'll just bury it directly in one of
the beds okay oh nice but here lately
I'm gonna go ahead and compost it inside
after it's done in the bucket well put
it in a little miniature tumbler I made
and
that'll be to redo earth make it less
acidic and then I'm gonna feed it to my
new warm inside warm bins so awesome
yeah you and Spence are both doing worms
Barefoot's doing worms everyone's going
worm life it's awesome I love it have
you tried to use the stuff from your
Bokashi bucket it's a drainage that they
call it the leachate that's stinky foot
smell and juice that comes out of there
if you have a clogged drain or that [ __ ]
right down the drain like probably two
ounces down a clogged drain it'll
dissolve if you got like a hair clog or
whatever is in there it'll I've got
these dreadlocks down to my [ __ ]
knees the drain the shower just pour
that in there it'll clean it right up
it'll stink you gotta pour it in there
let it soak all through it give it like
an hour and then just go run the hot
water kind of push it down and get rid
of the smell yeah remember you told me
[Music]
you're cloners I had a cloner itself
totally scented
another thing on that's on the bowl
Kashi liquid that is basically I've been
told this from two people but really
know their stuff that is basically em1
yes so it's like great white shark just
actually yeah I've been using em1
all summer and I I've been getting it
from a friend I've been making it myself
and I'm out so for the last couple weeks
I've just been using tokachi bucket
juice when I normally would use the em1
and I see no noticeable changes other
than the the rotting trash can be king
foot smell there's such great stuff
smells like a bar dumpster yeah it's a
bit that has food yeah so you're
composting all of your stocks all of
your big leaves aren't usable for any
product it's all going into the compost
pile the chicken shits in there
ah hydrogen all your foodways that
you've been eating all the time goes
into your Bo Kashi bucket so you're
making fertilizer out of that that gets
buried we've got our soil covered up
look at the soil covered up you can
actually breathe if you're you know I'm
not necessarily no-till wearing that so
you can go ahead and actually Rieman now
and put all your amendments you would
put it in the spring and it just makes
everything better how much of that old
root ball do I need to get out of there
before I do that I leave all over them
you just chop the stick and then kind of
dig another hole later yeah and yeah if
you keep the soil wet and active
throughout the winter in the span the
early spring there will be no root ball
when you come back to it there's if you
let it dry out and you don't cover it
the root ball will still very much okay
okay all right so you can read now in
the winter and that stuff will hopefully
rebuttal colonize and keep producing
itself right then you'll have even more
potent soil by the time okay so and then
at that point the only things that would
add in would just be like kelp and
alfalfa things that are they're gonna
break down all the way through to where
you know there's basically none left for
it so you know go ahead and really
stumbled all over that's early go ahead
when you plant go ahead and do like a
micro eyes that inoculant and then add a
little kelp and this is when you're
landing yeah I'll kind of little alfalfa
to the soil I'm getting ready to roll so
we can talk more about that later shoes
you know we're definitely gonna record a
whole bunch of outdoor episodes for next
year so that we've got them prepared
yeah we were both so busy this year
these big commercial girls keep us on
our feet my summer next year is looking
to be even busier how do you already
know that
well because it's only a few months away
that is true so yeah that's after
November well we'll know if it's got to
happen or not so we're just waitin till
then but we have an app and this is a
whole nother outfit
we we have an outline we have property
that have licensing everything like that
so excellently waiting to pull the
trigger
everything you seem to get involved in
seems to take off and go to get a good
watch so yeah I'm sure it's gonna work
for you I've been off yeah if I stumble
into all these startups I know how to
grow and I know how I know how to do
things but I don't know as much on how
to get [ __ ] done as you do so I need a
guy like you to [ __ ] build the walls
and build the tables and then once you
get the tables built then I can come in
and build the watering system and run
the plants we run it a few times they
decided we need to remodel and rebuild
and so call Jesse back I'll take a few
months off and go somewhere else and
Jesse couldn't rebuild then I'll come
back and regrow it we'll just keep
playing dance around places maybe we'll
get you girl an outdoors this summer
that sounds awesome we can't do it here
I mean I'm talking like 3,500 last let's
do it for long work in the shade of the
plants there we go yeah grown tall
enough so I could be shaded under so you
guys Jesse mentioned he said we will
wait till this November to decide if
that's gonna happen there's an election
coming up we may get a president that
doesn't want medical cannabis or
recreational cannabis at all that may
might put a kibosh on some of our plans
but more locally what jesse is talking
about we have amendment 200 and
amendment 300 here in Pueblo Colorado
if those pass the marijuana industry in
Pueblo Colorado will be forced to shut
down in 17 they get a full year D to
keep going but after that it's over so
no new licenses he's gonna like these
people even though they have a license
they've never gone before so
and and it's kind of a change of
location form too so they went under the
new proposal they wouldn't be able to
let it happen yeah good luck yes it's
probably gonna be too late by the time
this episode comes out I hope you voted
please don't shout out to Mike to white
Mike [ __ ] you Nemo punk everything he's
done yeah he's been putting huge efforts
in for the no on fifty no on 200
campaign the no on 300 campaign he did
more groundwork than anybody else I saw
shout it to everybody else that
participated I know I'm giving Mike all
the credit I know there's a bunch of you
but Mike is a person that let it in my
eye I know there are more of you but
Mike is one of my best friends I saw him
doing it he's a huge shout out I can
name a few more names but I can't name
them all so yeah yeah there's a couple
people I know that deserve a shout out
but I don't exactly know their names but
I know they're all Mike's team so Mike
spread the love let them know they're
getting shoutouts from the podcast
thanks for what you do bro we're gonna
get you on a podcast here in a couple
days it's like 80 degrees in my house
because we expected winter to come I
covered up my swamp coolers so that it
would because it was cold during the
night there was coming in there and
freezing me when I was trying to watch
narcos know be more do a Cali cartel
which isn't nearly as exciting right I
love anything drug smuggling culture I
just eat it up I've read a few books
I've watched every documentary I mean
yeah the dude The Big Lebowski will be
that a chronic take your picture with
them
yeah yeah all right so let's get a
little bit back I don't think we
finished up talking about cleaning the
garden so we've got a top tray or kind
of remanded for next year we filled it
with some kelp and some alfalfa meal and
then when it comes time for season we're
gonna dig a little hole and we're gonna
put some michael rises in there some
more kelp some more alfalfa maybe some
crab meal yeah maybe some castings okay
or just worms themselves if you've got
the compost pile you know by all means
use it up you're planning your plants
submit all that compost that rich
compost can feed those plants even if
you're sorry to cut you know don't fart
even if you're grown in pots you can
still utilize that that compost even if
you're using salt based chemical
nutrients you can still utilize on
Instagram and social media and even the
forums of people they're recycling soil
and running no-till and you're seeing
them top dress and decorate their plants
to keep like layer in their tour they
can keep the moisture in putting stuff
like alfalfa sprouts and other sprouts
on top of there and I'm loving the way
that it looks in a nice indoor garden
with these there's other growth on top
of your play a little on top of your
plant is dying and actually feeding your
plant to learn and see happen it's like
a miniature environment no there'd be no
tool which is a permaculture value but
permaculture is hard to wrangle into one
set you know one definition okay it's
just a way of looking at things
so today so now we're still at the end
of the season let's keep ourselves kind
of on track we're at the end of the
season we've cleaned up we've got our
compost pile everything's chipped up
everything's covered we put some stuff
where the old plants were now what
should we focus on other than that
cleaning up your trash
you know inevitable every grows got a
little bit you know whether it's beer
bottles or you know old netting dr.
pepper bottles yeah you know it's exact
wrapper yeah get get all that [ __ ]
cleaned up it looks bad
get your cages put away if you use those
if you're netting or whatever get that
I'll put up any kind of shade cloth if
you want to reuse it next year you need
to store it away and get it out of the
weather same with like your water
barrels your air pumps any kind of
liquid nutrients you had outside you
need to get all that inside and in a
warm place you know and don't bring it
inside to your grow area outside clean
it if you can take some time and clean
it just polish it up if you had a fan or
something outside take it apart clean it
please clean it with some h2o too
or some of that I think it's the same
thing but the thirty percent hydrogen
peroxide clean it with some of that
gloves you guys
or even like enzymes complete or higher
or some of the cleaner stuff up be
creative you know use what's at your
disposal dr. Bonner soap I mean so that
was like it's like some pine oil and
stuff or something like that in it would
that's gonna kill anything so yeah I
like the dr. Bronner's yeah wash my
dreads with it you can wash everything
with it yeah it's perfect
alright so clean up get out there and
clean everything up take all the
equipment out of there make it look like
there was never a grow there yeah okay
if you're if you grow in pots and you
want to reuse all your soil even if
you're not if you're growing pots and
you're not reusing your soil throw it
away like you know it's just if you had
any issues they're still lingering there
you know if you are going to reuse it
get it all in a pile get it wet cover it
with plastic it's the same principle we
were talking about with covering the
with the raised beds and everything so
you know if we had some fungus gnats or
powdery mildew is that going to be kind
of destroyed in the composting process
or is that gonna compound fungus gnats
if you get it heated if you get the pile
heated up enough which means you've got
to add a considerable amount of raw
green material and just organic matter
to it for it to heat back up it will
most definitely kill the fungus okay
powdery mildew I have no idea okay so we
might we might be killing ourselves
trying to do both because I think if you
put the green in there PMO girl in the
green but I don't think the PM can grow
on well I mean greener could even be
like green manure it could be anything I
mean anything from the way I like to
grow no because there may be some you're
probably gonna get 12 you collect it I
don't it stinks okay put in some bottles
and ship the first tester batches to
Jesse love to try it rinse all the salt
off first place
please just see the plants just rinse
the kelp we are way off topic but we are
still on topic it's amazing how we do it
clean this is something I deal with
every year and I [ __ ] did it this
year
clean out your your outdoor spray
bottles because like mine have teas go
through it which has a lot of molasses
and they always clog up oh yeah and then
in the spring I'm just like [ __ ] and
end up throwing it away and go and get
in the new one you guys know I cleaned
them all out with super hot water this
year I'm good to go for next year you
guys by the pump sprayers that have the
nozzle on it where you can release the
pressure you want to be able to release
that pressure because otherwise you'll
pump it up real hard and the [ __ ]
nozzle get stuck you'll never get it off
of there now you can't refill it and pop
it open with something you're gonna
break it some of the plastic somewhere
will spin or trust me get there with the
kind the type that happens that pressure
release valve so you can well once it's
pumped up and pressurized you can take
that pressure off it's really scary
trying to undo it spray up in your face
[Music]
tank that was back before anyone well
lots of people knew better but we didn't
before we knew something if you get a
brand new Cologne and it came from
somebody and you really really want it
but it might have something to take
clothes from that smoke in the floor I
might add one at least try to get a
generation from there all right so we've
cleaned up everything we've got we want
to cover up the holes for the area for
next year do you just want to leave it
exposed so that all the stuff can
process in there get some heat in there
you got your compost pile going
I got everything cleaned up it doesn't
even look like a girl happened in that
yard or that field anymore right yeah
just make it look nice and good yeah and
it's all it's a clean slate for you to
go back next year and then as soon as
the snow melts and you're thinking about
growing the next thing to do is
there and fix all of the holes in your
fences and go check that make sure that
that thing is super secure go pick up
all of the [ __ ] I'm sure your dog or
one of your buddies dogs been out there
drop in deuces as soon as it gets warm
that's the stuff you got to do then uh I
mean to pick depending on how serious
you get I actually I know of a couple
people that are already growing their
plants for next season but you know if
you're a small you know twenty-five
thirty-five plant or less outdoor grow
you can get away with you know you can
start your plants in February probably
if you're growing from seed and you want
to do a female selection I suggest
starting now but if you're grown from
clones you know that'd be where you can
start you know start them up if you're
going for trees so start about get huge
you don't have inside don't let them get
root bound and I ever yeah
cuz they will start to flower on you
they will start flowering so bedroom
inside get them big top them get them
loved don't let them get root bound to
the pest free don't run yeah keep them
pest free do not run them on a 24 hour
light unless you plan on putting them
outside underneath the 24 hour like see
I would have never thought of that
yeah yeah I mean if you got a hoop house
and you can run a little all it takes is
like just a little fluorescent right if
you can do that sure
go for 24 but in my experience running
them 24 and then putting them outside
under not 24 is it just it either stunts
them out sativas it'll throw them into
bloom I mean in because it'll throw them
into bloom you know so just and then
then you get two weeks of going into
bloom and then going back into veg and
then edging and then going back into
flower and then you got plans to just
look like hell and they're mad very
funky looking yeah and your trimmers
hate you maybe some seeds man is there
anything else that we should mention
when it comes to cleaning up your garden
at the end of the season to prepare for
the winter and the next year nothing
major if you have locks on gates or
something like that
put them inside unless they need to be
out there but it just keeps them from at
least around here keeps them from
getting arrested up and crap like that
so just a lot of the things I do is so
that I don't have to spend money on it
the next year and so that my tools last
awesome or you know first several years
not just one season at a time so I think
a lot of that comes with age or getting
older for sure we're getting tired of
buying the same damn hammer this town
but the town north of us has the other
drug we got the drug that makes you go
real slow and sleepy and then up north
they got the ones that are making a good
idea he's taking a big fat dab of some
Durbin poison my turn to take a dab
oh I'm Jesse do you have any final words
to the podcast you want to put out to
the listeners before we wrap it up shout
out to one loved garden supply come
check us out Denver or boulders my fault
my fault shout out to the awesome people
in Oregon oh that's um I meant to tell
you customer service out there is
ridiculous they are so nice really it's
yes they don't seem like they're mad at
you for wanting a sandwich at the
sandwich place no not at all they're
actually glad to see you that's pretty
rad even in super small little podunk
towns like is the every time we had a
great customer service experience out
there I would think of your rants on
Facebook about how horrible they don't
like you right welcome to our
establishment where you're going to pay
our wages can we help you properly yeah
awesome I'm glad you got taking care of
shoutouts all the nice people on the
coast for sure
awesome awesome experience that's read
shuck shuck your wife for letting you go
on that adventure and waiting for me to
burn I appreciate that
customer service check out my podcast
Colorado podcast at Facebook or on
Facebook as Colorado podcast and then we
have a Instagram too and you can
actually find the show on soundcloud
soundcloud check him out the colorado
podcast on soundcloud i endorsed the
show i listen we've actually done a
crossover episode where the colorado
boys came here and invaded my studio and
acted a fool for an hour and a half yeah
more comedy yeah yeah if you ever need
an outlet for your cannabis talk I've
got a microphone that you're always
invited to come ramble in all right you
guys make sure you follow my buddy Jesse
check out his podcast big shout out to
the boys on the Colorado a podcast big
shot at citator despicable D big shout
out to 44 big shot it's a fetus big shot
it's everybody that's been listening to
their podcast and my podcast I
appreciate you guys ladies and gentlemen
if you would like to sponsor the podcast
or if you've got a product you'd like me
to review or if you've got questions
I've got answers get all the info for
you send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you I'd appreciate it if you
follow me on social media find me on
Facebook it's just under now search for
drove my heart podcast follow me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and on
instagram i am at about eight thousand
seven hundred and fifty followers right
now so give me a follow on instagram
it's ireon der score genetics that's the
seed company check out all the cannabis
photography i've been posting been
posting a bunch of great stuff in my
opinion oh just follow me there I think
I ran out of breath trying to do all the
plugs at the end make sure you go give
garden of Weeden 2.0 a follow - oh yeah
the Instagram police have been shutting
people down so go follow garden of
Weeden 2.0 that's Spence and Maddy
that's a perfect way to end the podcast
let me give you huge shout out to Maddie
and spins until next time take a fat dad
and give for me
[Music]
you
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 164 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversations it's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic boots ban flutter use
their music on my podcast big shout to
cat
[Music]
I'm doing a solo episode today you guys
we're gonna go over some emails we're
gonna go over some iTunes comments and
then if we have some time at the end of
the show I will give a few grow tips
tricks thank you every email I also want
to thank everybody that went to iTunes
and left iTunes comment let's just get
right to it
Oh can't do it before we get that far I
got to do this ladies and gentleman this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends at the dank team that's right
the dank team calm if you need some new
genetics in your garden that's right if
you need regular or feminized cannabis
seeds check out my friends at dank team
comm they've got Mile High they've got
Ken Adventure they've got gage green
genetics they've got Sin City and of
course they have that I read genetics
available right now so check out the
dank team com if you use coupon code
dank cannabis you will get 12 percent
off your entire order and you should get
free shipping at the dank team.com
support them now let's get to this part
later
I appreciate it when people leave me
ratings and reviews on iTunes if you'd
like to leave a rating and a review on
iTunes all you have to do is open up
iTunes go to the iTunes Store type in
the growth from your heart podcast in
the search bar search for the girl free
heart a podcast find the podcast click
on the little logo it's my face and it
says girl from your heart click on that
then you'll go to the ratings and
reviews section there is an area where
you can give me an amount of stars
everybody so far has given me a five
star review I've got 36 5 star reviews
you guys nothing but 5 stars so far and
then 31 people have typed in a written
review I'm pulling up the most recent
reviews right now but we'll read them we
will start with this one from Alaskan
pure organic some use just a little bit
here this iTunes review comes from our
friend Alaskan pure organics and it says
it was left on September 15 says I
listened to every show informative and
great guests it's become my favorite
show about cannabis that's an honor
there are some other great podcasts out
there about cannabis so I appreciate
hearing that I'm your favorite big
thanks for the email and huge thanks for
the 5-star rating I appreciate it
alright our next review comes from a
listener who calls themselves
ikazuchi leader and they left the review
on october 1st they gave me of course a
five-star review and it goes like
rhasta Jeff keep up the fantastic work I
just listened to your podcast oh I
started listen to your podcast sometime
about four to five months ago and the
information humor and love that you put
into this podcast is unparalleled I look
forward to many more episodes brother
well I'm gonna put out a whole bunch
more episodes so stick around I'm glad
you appreciate it man thanks for
listening you've been around for four or
five months probably close to six months
now right it's been a month since you
left this review thanks for hanging out
thanks for listening
anybody else that would like to leave a
review please do so like I said just go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the podcast
find the review section type in a little
comment and let me know what you think
about the show and I will read your
review on a future episode once again
big shout out to active Sookie leader
and Alaskan pure organics I do
appreciate the reviews alright so the
next thing on my agenda ladies and
gentlemen I want to read some emails
from a few listeners and I'm searching
for that email now there we go alright
this listener I don't know if this
person wants me to say their name so I'm
going to skip that but it says Rasta
Jeff your podcast is so much fun you
were really entertaining truly so much
fun to listen to truly so much fun to
listen to you host your growing lessons
are on point
hearing you listen to hearing you listen
to JRE I knew right away this podcast
was gonna be awesome
I'm gonna [ __ ] with I read genetics
forever I'm growing legal cannabis for
myself in SoCal I want to know how I can
listen to your first 50 episodes other
than that I really wanted to give thanks
for what you're doing and then they
signed their name I appreciate you for
the email I appreciate you for listening
yes I am a huge they said JRE that's Joe
Rogan experience I'm a huge doggin
experienced fan I'd never skip an
episode I listened to almost every
episode as soon as it comes out that's
probably my favorite podcast followed by
the Church of what's happening now with
uncle Joey to be honest with you Doug
loves movies with Doug Benson is
probably my favorite podcast it was my
top three well let's see you also say
micro lessons are OnPoint thank you I
spend a lot of time trying to treat grow
lessons that are useful for you guys
that's why I like it when the listeners
send me emails I like treating content
that is generated from questions from
listeners so I'm glad you appreciate the
grow lessons I'm glad you find them to
be on point you're gonna [ __ ] with I
read genetics forever that is awesome I
hope you've got some
genetics in your garden if not we need
to figure out how to make that happen
for you you're drawing legally in SoCal
so that's rad
we definitely need to get some I read
genetics in your hands I want to know
what you're growing out there I also
want to know what part of SoCal you're
in because that's where I'm from I
actually grew up in Bellflower
California I went to Bellflower high
school for middle school and then I
moved to Colorado in the middle of ninth
grade so from SoCal also a lot of people
call me out like what part of California
you from only what are you even talking
about they say that the clothes I wear
and the way that I am they can tell I'm
from California and call that a few
times so then you also say you want to
listen to the first 50 episodes most of
the feeds apparently don't have the
first 50 episodes cuz I'm all the way up
to 160 this is gonna be 164 so it looks
like the last 64 episodes are getting
bumped out of the feed what I've been
talking about doing is going and finding
those old episodes they're in my
computer they're on my my drive over
there I just need to plug that in and
find the old episodes they're probably
on my web server still I just repost
them and then I don't know if I want to
like go back and edit them at all and be
like hey what's up this is a repost or
if I just want to repost it and put it
in the feed as a bonus episode but
that's probably the best way to do it if
you really want them super bad send me
an email if you guys are like dying to
hear the first 264 episodes or something
send me an email maybe we can work out a
way where I can send you the files
through we transfer Dropbox or something
we'll get it going but I may just throw
in the first episode the first 50
episodes back in the feed like every 5
or 6 episodes or something just put
another one in there so that you guys
can go listen to the old stuff and
that'll also be a fun exercise and
seeing how much we've progressed cuz
you'll be able to spot the old episodes
right away so I may have to put the old
episodes back in the feed and maybe if
you send me an email and you ask really
nicely for a few episodes they can't
send you all 50 at once that's gonna
blow up my computer but if you ask me
for a few episodes at a time maybe I can
send you it a few at a time maybe maybe
we can make a list or something to
people and then I could just dump all
the episodes to a few people like five
at a time or something five a week
something like that I'd love to help you
out though we'll get it going for you
email me back if you want them as a file
anybody's listening if you want the
first 50 we can figure something out
send me an email let me see how many
people are interested we'll figure
something out alright thanks for the
email I appreciate it let's get on to
the next email this one is from a very
frequent listener somebody that I
interact
what's on Twitter somebody that's been a
longtime listener I truly appreciate you
for hanging out so long with us
this one I could probably say your name
because you use your Instagram and
Twitter handle this is our friend fast
very fast very says hello Jeff thanks
for the podcast I enjoy hearing you're
curing episodes you're drying and curing
method is almost exactly the way I do it
so word nice it's good to know that
people out there are doing the things
that I'm doing it's good to know that
other people have the same ideas that I
do working with the same methods little
affirmations always a good good thing
you also say I would add that I trim dry
my plants on a piece of parchment paper
so I can collect the resin resin heads
off that fall later when I clean up
that's a really good good idea you guys
when you're about to trim your buds put
down what did he say that he added some
parchment paper put down a sheet of
parchment paper over the table and then
trim onto the parchment paper and then
when you're done you can clean up all
the kief that came off of there you have
a bunch of resin heads on there and then
you can either put those in a bowl and
smoke them or if you're really into it
you can press them if you know how to
make rosin so that's something that's
useful that's a good idea thanks for the
heads up on that one fast Barry he also
continues he says I have a full-time job
so no time for excessive burping of jars
but I do put the lids on upside-down
metal to glass and loosely screw on the
cap so you guys instead of sealing the
cap the normal way where it's got the
waxy seal against the glass and then you
put the lid on real tight he flips it
upside down and puts the metal to glass
on there so it's not making a super
tight seal and then he only screws it on
medium tight apparently loosely screws
on the cap he says it allows some air
exchange but it prevents buds from
drying out I do that for 48 hours then I
start the 12-hour check burp and will
repeat as needed then daily then weekly
blah blah blah and he said you know you
just did the episode thanks fast Barry
on Instagram and Twitter you guys if you
go follow my friend fast Barry on
Instagram and or Twitter make sure you
let him know that you heard his email on
the girl from your heart podcast shout
out fast Barry it's good to know that
other people are doing that and you guys
that's a great update and a great
addition to what I said if you have a
full-time job if you are if you can't
dedicate 24 hours a day to your grow
which is
understandable I'm not calling you out
most people have a normal job and they
grow in their spare time if this is you
and you can't check those jars if you've
got to go to work I for a long time for
like a year
I lived 55 miles away from where I work
so take me one hour to get to work then
I would be at work for eight to twelve
hours maybe 14 hours on some days then
there's another drive home and then you
got to do whatever you do when you get
home you got to eat you got a poopy on a
shower you got to put on clothes for the
next day you got to get all that [ __ ]
going so of course it limited me to
maybe four or five hours of time that I
was able to work on my garden at home so
I totally understand that a lot of
people are in that situation you guys
can put your buds in these jars and you
can leave the lids on upside down and
loose and you'll get some airflow in
there and you'll still slowly dry the
buds because that's your main objective
is to slowly and evenly dry these buds
all right fast berry I appreciate the
email you guys keep the emails coming
that is super helpful I've got one more
email that is actually a correction I
said something in an episode about THCA
converting to THC but guess what I was
wrong I said that [ __ ] backwards so let
me read an email he says his name in the
email I'm gonna skip it he says hey
brother my name is beep and I've been
listening to your podcast since I heard
an episode on talk radio early on
earlier on in the year big shout out to
our friends that took radio big shot at
the Citizen Jay of course you can listen
to our podcast Wednesday's should I
don't know the trek day Wednesdays at
noon
I think it's Wednesday at noon on Tok
radio.com I will correct that by the end
of this episode I will I will make sure
I've got the right time and date it's a
lot of [ __ ] in my head right now
anyway he listened to me I took radio I
appreciate that he said I'm a huge fan
of the podcast your Dro techniques your
advice and your Irie Rasta way of life
I'm an aspiring cannabis enthusiast
myself and I'm working on getting my
foot in the door of the cannabis
industry here in Connecticut for the fat
past few years I've been learning as
much about cannabis as I can before I
enter either the medical or recreational
side of the industry when we establish a
rec side that is and I have to thank you
your friends and your podcast for
supplying me with a massive amount of
cannabis information and grow tips dude
that's a huge compliment I hope that our
podcast has put you on the right path
tour when you're able to get into a
facility you could be a leader
maybe you could be one of the bosses the
cultivation directors maybe since that's
new maybe you can just invent the phrase
you're like I'm cultivation director
tell them so and do that so I hope we
can get you your foot in the door when
the time comes
Connecticut huh I don't think I've ever
been to Connecticut I've been to a lot
of places and I cannot remember ever
going to Connecticut for any reason I
don't think no fish would be the only
thing that would take me that direction
I've never seen fish and Connecticut so
I remember that let's see I'm gonna
continue with the email he says on a
separate note and the episode you put
out this morning you asked to correct
you if you got the THC THC a conversion
raw from what I remember the THC is what
the trichomes start off as and they
transform into THC when heating through
decarboxylation through curing most
likely increases the psychoactive
potency of the trichomes since THC D
carboxylates sorry I gotta spin the page
since TTT carboxylates where lie now in
the form of water vapor let me know if
that was the solid knowledge man I'm not
a scientist I hope the rest of your day
is Irie brother take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me dude you are
totally correct what you said is
completely correct so thanks for the
correction yes don't be afraid to
correct me if I say something stupid on
the podcast if I say something wrong
please send me an email and let me know
that I don't [ __ ] up because it's the
only way that I can correct it and I
don't want to teach people the wrong way
that's a big part of why I started this
podcast you guys I would be on the
forums I'd be on the internet I'd be in
facebook groups and then I would see
people give the shittiest
advice people would be like I'm in Week
five in Flour and I've got spider mites
what do I do and somebody to be like
going there and spray floral might just
cringe like I just now slapped myself in
the face when I read that I was like oh
yeah I just did the Macaulay Culkin like
no so that's part of what inspired me to
do this podcast was not trying not to
pass along fake information and try to
give useful information from experience
because I'm kind of uh I'm kind of a
crazy grower if I have an idea and I
think that something might improve my
crop the only way to find out if it's
gonna improve it is to do it and I
figure I've been growing long enough to
where I've got a good foundation you
know I'm saying I can skateboard I
cannot skateboard this is an analogy I
can skateboard real well
time to hit the halfpipe so sometimes
I'll go in the grow room and do halfpipe
tricks I'll be like what if I just
totally do this and occasionally I [ __ ]
up and kill plants you guys but that's
all part of learning and experimenting
I'm way sidetracked I'm Way off my topic
but if I do something wrong if I say
something wrong please do correct me
jesse corrected me a couple of times
actually Jesse's dad told Jesse to come
and correct me so shout out to CJ and
Jesse Chad so anybody else has ever sent
me a correction I don't be afraid
I like being corrected it makes me a
better podcaster makes me a better
grower and it makes me a better teacher
so appreciate I want to appreciate I
already do appreciate you I want to
thank everybody who sent me an email I
want to thank everybody who sent me an
iTunes comment I do have a [ __ ] ton more
emails you guys I'm not ignoring the
emails the Facebook messages the
Instagram messages that I've got there
are so many of them but I picked a few
for this episode I'll do a few more in
the next couple of episodes alright I
feel like I'm talking really fast you
guys I could probably use a drink of
water and of course I need a big fat dab
so I'm just gonna press pause I'm gonna
medicate myself I'm gonna hydrate myself
I'll be back in just a couple of seconds
cats world I am back I just took a
couple of fat dabs of some Jack flash
shatter from our friends at TR
concentrates super shatter II it's kind
of like the I said this before on a
previous episode it's kind of like the
consistency of a Jolly Rancher if you
tried to break Jolly Ranchers with your
fingers it would just go popping and
fly-in everywhere
it's kind of that hard consistency that
hard texture but it tastes really good
and obviously it gets me really rambley
high because I've been freaking talking
a million miles an hour in this episode
I want to thank you guys for listening
to my rambles so I promised you guys
some crow tips and grow tricks but
before I get that far I want to talk
about my most recent breeding project of
course if you listen to the podcast you
know I made some arise f2s I also
crossed a rise f12 Lemon skunk all of
those seeds have been harvested they've
all been dried out properly they're all
in jars our friend Jessie was given a
few of those last time he was here
barefoot grower was given a few of those
when he was here for the podcast so some
of those have gone out I'm working some
of the new seeds into my growth schedule
so that I can grow some of those really
really want to know what the arize f2
does but I really want to know what that
arise - lemon skunk is gonna do for me
because everything I've crossed my lemon
skunk female everything has been amazing
I also did arise to grateful dog I'm
super curious about that that one will
probably not be released for a while I
wonder why I want to play with that one
for a little bit by myself and then I'll
put it out in seed form I have to make
more of it I only have a small handful
of seed that that one others I have a
lot of seeds so they'll go out so my new
breeding project ladies and gentlemen
let me talk more about that I am using
the same arise male I've gotten a rise
male he is a stud if you follow me on
instagram you've seen this dude on
instagram he grows for a male plant he
grows some of the biggest colas the
biggest male flowers I've ever seen
he puts resin out he smells terrible
he's got this really funky stank to him
which is a good thing for a male a rise
is golden coat was the female and
Daybreaker from gage green genetics was
the male
Daybreaker is Kim D and Joseph og so
those are the ones that the Joseph o G
chem D cross - golden goat which is
Island sweet skunk Hawaiian sativa and
Romulan so it's such a good combo
but Rises a great strain I made I took
the mail and now the Mail's are in
flower this podcast will come out for
quite some time but the Mail's are now
in flower they went into flower
yesterday and I've got two huts with
other plants in them two five by five
huts with two gallon pots the huts are
crammed pretty tight there's two gallon
pot stuff in those huts and there are
cookies and cream
females cookies and cream females white
widow females there's lemon skunk
females there's a lemon Jeffrey in there
there is there are a couple others in
there that I don't even need to mention
yet but we'll talk about those later in
the future those are probably going to
go into flour
maybe Monday but anyway pretty soon
those are gonna go into flour here I'm
letting I need the male to get ahead
just a little tiny bit but I don't want
my girls to get too big and they're
starting to kind of get tall so just
right but I'm gonna keep the male
separate I'm gonna let em flour out
other two male plants it's the same
stream but I just need enough pollen to
do two huts so I've got two male plants
in there they're flowering but I keep
them separate to keep that pollen in
there and then around day twenty five
ish depending on how the plants look I'm
gonna go and pollinate twenty-five of a
flower for the girls I'm gonna go in and
pollinate both of the 5x5 Hut's worth of
plants and then we'll make a bunch of
new crosses so that's what's going on my
breeding projects some you guys really
care some of you guys probably don't
care at all so let's move on to some
grow tips like I talked about you guys
I've been talking about growing in coco
coir a whole bunch several brands of
coco with different nutrient feeds in
Coco
I do love Coco I love the Coco but one
thing that sucks is if you don't make
something in with it it kind of
compresses a little bit it kind of gets
to be too much around your roots and I
feel like the plants that I did in all
Coco could have harvested better had I
mixed something into that soil I don't
like the Coco that I used I think the
plants probably could have been a little
bit better so if you're gonna grow in
cocoa mix in maybe 50% soil or maybe mix
in a whole bunch of perlite because I've
used a couple brands of cocoa and some
of them compress a whole bunch some of
them don't
it's hard to tell when they're in the
bag and I'm not gonna call out brands
I've just learned that I want to mix my
cocoa with some soil and/or some perlite
so that's something I would recommend my
babies my clones hated going into cocoa
they just died they were like no [ __ ]
you that's too much pressure on the
roots there's no air in here I'm going
to die so I make some 5050 with soil and
threw it in there and they grew but they
weren't happy and then I put some just
into street soil soilless mix that I
make for babies and those plants took
off so start your babies in some soil
maybe unless you get them really going
unless you're coming from rock wool then
it might work I'm coming out of an easy
corner of course this is what happened
from the easy cloner so I think soil or
a 50/50 mix is better than just
straight-up cocoa so that's something I
wanted to mention to you guys through
experience let's see one of our friends
that listens to the podcast was posting
on Facebook that he's got a stream that
takes a really long time to flower and
it's way laid into flour already and it
does not show any signs of slowing down
and being done and he was just asking
questions you want to know WTF said what
the [ __ ] is going on with this plant
dude and so my guidance my advice was to
reduce the lights on that plant to speed
up the flowering cycle that plant is
waiting for a signal to say hey are you
done yet just waiting for something to
hint at it that the season is over
wherever that plant it's hard to even
guess where that plant came from I don't
know what strain you're working with but
that plant comes from an area or the day
and night cycle between the winter and
summer seasons does not vary very much
so the what it takes to make those
plants flower they're very sensitive
they'll flower very easily sometimes
those plants those type of plants if
they get root bound they'll flower if
they get crowded they're not getting
enough light gentle flower so those
they're cool because they'll start
flowering very easily when you're ready
if you put them in the flower room
you'll notice sometimes those will show
flower earliest but also they don't want
to finish so since the season doesn't
change let me get back on track here my
mind is racing today since the season
doesn't change very much those plants
can pretty much just go on until they
wither up and die is what would happen
in nature and that's what they want to
do they're gonna keep going until they
receive pollen there's like hey
pollinate me pollinate
please please please and there's gonna
grow until they fry themselves out so
you've got to reduce the whites it give
them a hint that oh [ __ ] grow season's
over I better finish up and that's what
you got to do turn the life you're on
1212 turn the lights down to maybe just
give them ten hours of light a day
instead of twelve oh 1014 aye and just
do that for two weeks and I'm sure
they'll start finishing up they may be
finished up in two weeks from doing that
so maybe start flushing reduce the
lights that's something that will
certainly help you with a strain that is
taking way too long
I had a Durbin poison strain that took
like 16 weeks to flower properly when I
started chopping down the lights a
little bit
it certainly sped up the time I cut off
two full weeks if I did it two weeks if
I timed it properly leg rope is a long
time ago I don't even [ __ ] with that
nervin poison anymore was kind of a mess
no need for that share my garden you may
have a good urban poison cut no no
offense to yours but the one I had
alright so another thing everybody got
not everybody a lot of people got
powdery mildew last winter and the
winter is coming
and I don't want you to get powdery
mildew again so let's talk about some
ways that you can prevent powdery mildew
that's going to it possibly happens
because it's winter time you guys when
it gets cold outside and it stays warm
inside so you're growing grown cannabis
indoors right a lot of you are in a
basement a lot of you are in a warehouse
you've probably got one concrete wall
somewhere that your plants are really
close to the outside of that wall is
going to get temperatures that are
really ridiculously low the opposite
side of that wall you got a beautiful
grow environment so when that moisture
builds up on the outside makes that
weird cold wall and then the heat hits
it a lot of a lot of grow rooms I see it
happen it's happened to me the first
time I moved into this one house that
I'm like drew in this one basement they
had a concrete wall the plant we've
talked about it before that plant in
that corner where the concrete corner
was it got completely powdery mildew all
up that one side I was at another
facility that had a garage door type of
thing and right there in that area those
plants started getting powdery mildew on
the first snowfall so something you can
do something you're gonna need to think
about is how to heat those areas
properly maybe build a separate wall I
know this sounds extreme but if you've
got a wall if your grow facility has a
wall that is on the edge
tear of the building and it is concrete
or it is not well insulated you may want
to build a six-inch gap in there and put
some insulation in there so that when it
snows you've got a buffer zone so that
you're not freezing your plants
something else you can do to help
prevent powdery mildew and this is just
for all seasons when the plants start
going into flower and getting a little
bit of chunky buds I like to go in and
take off most of the big fan leaves most
of those water leaves the Sun leaves
whatever you want to call them I like to
pull the majority of those off some
people think that I'm crazy some people
think I'm nuts for doing it but go in
there about week three a flower and take
off all those pea deals and watch them
grow back you'll freak out because they
come back your plants will be way more
productive you'll see production and
what you're doing is you're letting the
light penetrate a little bit more you
can get light down to the bottom buds
that's where you don't have to lollipop
is high and you're also creating more
air space and at the same time you're
removing places for powdery mildew to
land and build up and a lot of times
what happens you guys in a warm humid
grow room you've got one leaf and
another leaf resting right on top of
each other now imagine if you imagine
you're on the bus and the dude next to
you just rests his [ __ ] hand right on
yours on the bus in the middle of the
summer and his sweat and sweat and you
got a ride all day twelve hours
sometimes the fans don't hit every
single leaf so you got to write in there
for 12 hours with the lights on you
imagine how sticky and funky your hand
is gonna be after 12 hours of that [ __ ]
the top leaf is sweating from on the
bottom because all that leaf pressed
against it the bottom leaf is sweating
from the top is all that leaf against it
and you're just creating funk inside of
there powdery mildew will pop up from
that so if you pull off all these extra
leaves you eliminate the opportunity for
that powdery mildew to develop under
your leaves so that's something that's
really helpful I think also there's less
places for bugs if you go in there and
you pull off all the leaves it's way
less opportunity for bugs to hide the
bugs prefer those leaves with longer pee
deals that stick out a little bit
further they like to go right underneath
those real big-ass leaves and hang out
it's the first place you're gonna see
bug damages on the low larger leaves I
think most of the time
eliminate that [ __ ] get rid of it don't
even give the bugs an opportunity to get
their also clean up the bottoms of your
plants you guys nothing should touch the
pot or the floor or the dirt like it's
hanging off the bottom your plant should
really touch that clean that up if you
can get in there with some scissors
early start a flower just clean it up
you want depending on the size of pot
and size apply you're using I usually
have at least six to eight inches
between the pot and the first two stalks
that come off my branch I will clean
that up sometimes if I'm going a larger
pot girl larger plants I'll clean a foot
sometimes a green and healthy when I had
the large warehouse we would over veg
for too long and then we would just
trellis everything out didn't reach I
would just chop off all the branches
that didn't reach to the trellis and
we'd have a foot and a half or just
naked shave leg sometimes two feet but
just naked bear shave legs but that
promotes better air flow and again it
gives you less opportunity for bugs to
get in there less places for powdery
mildew and we're not trying to grow
leaves we're trying to go grow buds so
get in there about week three excuse me
about week three take off most of your
families if not all of them I like to
leave the two on the top of the but you
know you got that top cola I like to
leave two or four leaves up there so you
can grab some white treat some energy
but that lower stuff just go mad I take
most of that lower [ __ ] right off I
don't even think about it then I get in
there about week five and do it again
I'll feed it a bloom booster I will feed
it a root pack and a foliar pack to make
it explode guys shout out the tiara
concentrates with their Chad flash maybe
a little choked up but I like to take
off the leaves feed it a root pack
feeder to follow your pack feed it a
strong bloom booster about week five
week six and then go there and pull off
the leaves you'll really notice it bulk
up that's my opinion indica strains
really like it flow blueberry that type
of stuff really appreciates it some of
the sativa dominant strains don't go
super heavy but good still get in there
and take off some leaves alright that's
what I think about defoliation also
Jessie and I did an episode we talked
about cleaning up your outdoor garden
clean up your indoor garden you guys get
a broom and sweep up just why not sweep
up at the end of the day you've got to
be there
spend an extra five or ten minutes and
sweep up that place pick up all the
little litter
in the grow room maybe there's a zip tie
that you used for something that you cut
down clean that [ __ ] up there's no need
to leave extra stuff sitting around put
all your tools away put all your
equipment away clean out your sprayers
clean out your pumps clean out anything
maybe clay can be clean so that it's
ready for you the next time you need to
use it just take a couple minutes at the
end of the day and clean [ __ ] up if your
drone at home you guys have dedicated
stuff have a dedicated broom have a
dedicated dustpan for your grow rooms
try to have a dedicated trash can when
you clean up when you sweep up if you've
got dead leaves on the floor if you find
that you've got some dead bugs on the
floor sometimes you'll find randomly
just to be a little pilot dead like
white flies or fungus gnats or some
maybe you sprayed and then few days
later all these bugs that they stole
landed over there by that fan when you
clean that stuff up sweep it all up into
a trash can and take that trash can out
of the grow room don't leave it in the
grow if you got dead leaves in there
don't leave those in the grow either you
don't want that stuff in there every
dead leave and piece of stuff on the
floor is another place for a bug to hide
and I said this to somebody the other
day I said if you got five spider mites
hiding underneath one leaf two of them
are gonna hook up - we're gonna [ __ ] and
they're gonna make a million spider my
babies and if you do the math on that
cuz it's just gonna keep going so I mean
I'm right right if you got five people
at a party by the end of the night two
people are hooking up that's how these
spider mites are gonna be and if you
leave one leaf and you got five spider
mites under there and five days you're
gonna have that multiply it by whatever
spider mites breed out which is a
ridiculous rate so clean up that one
leaf just pick it up there's no need for
all that [ __ ] around there get out the
shopvac and clean up the corners dust
the tops of the lights go in you will be
amazed at how many bugs are in the
crevices in your Gavita lights if you've
got a large commercial facility and you
get up top and you clean out your lights
there's a bunch of bugs up there clean
all that [ __ ] out it's nasty you don't
want to have that in there also clean
your fans while you're at it all right
isn't rambling on for a long time I feel
like that's enough info enough tips and
a bunch of email talking for one episode
I want to thank everybody for listening
to an episode of just me rambling by
myself
I'm still working on the episode I
promised you about pest prevention
management identification and
eradication I'm writing how to take care
of a whole bunch of bugs a whole bunch
of different situations it's gonna be a
multi showpiece trying to write out at
least two full episodes before I get it
started I like to get ahead of myself
speaking up so that I've got written out
and I'm
myself with I've got a debate about
organics versus I don't know if it's a
debate but whatever the pros and cons of
organics versus synthetics and I've got
a lot of other great stuff coming up for
you I hope you guys stay tuned to future
episodes once again thank you guys for
listening I want to give a huge shout
out to my friends at handmade apparel
that's right much love much respect the
community working for the community like
the other FUBU of the ganja community
yeah I said that all right ladies and
gentlemen thank you guys for listening
to another episode of the girlfriend
heart podcast I wanna give a huge shout
out to Maddie and Spence and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 165 of the
girl from Earhart podcast you're a
source for cannabis news education and
democracy new growers your professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff wanna thank you guys again
for joining me as always I want to send
a huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roof spin to let them use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat to the entire mystic brews crew
and the music was loud Wow sorry about
that Mike I didn't need apply Cheers
oh nice nice welcome to the show again
bro Thanks ladies and gentlemen once
again joining us on the show is there
good buddy white Mike I said good buddy
again so cheesy saying good buddy's my
good buddy one of those rhythms I catch
myself doing while we're doing the intro
I remind everybody how they can follow
you on social media and also tell them
about your useful and successful
cannabis Facebook page you can catch me
at at Nemo punk 15 on twitter or pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
stalk him you guys support him check him
out check it out yes see what he's doing
online he sends me a lot of cool
articles that you'll be able to see if
you check out his Twitter on the show we
are going to do a this is the
post-election recap we're going to talk
about what won and what did not win and
what went our favor and what may and may
not change and how things went but
before we get that far we've got a few
things we want to chatter about let's
see where should I start people like to
hear about my breeding updates you guys
remember I was talking about
I had a arise f1 male and I had
pollinated a bunch of stuff and they had
gone for a long time those have since
been harvested those are all harvested
all the seeds are taken out the bud
material is in a container getting ready
to be turned into hash and the seeds are
all in separate containers they're being
distributed to friends of mine for test
growth I am growing a large number of
them myself I'm pretty excited about
that I see some sprouts gone and it
makes me smile to see some stuff sprout
again yeah so those are being tested but
since those are done I cleaned up
everything I sprayed everything down
with hot water and a little bit of
bleach and I cleaned up real well and I
got all the pollen out of the room and
I'm at it again I have got some stuff in
flower it is about I'd say it's by the
time this comes out it'll be three weeks
into flower nice there I am putting the
arize male 2 girls cookies-and-cream
female and that cookies-and-cream i was
one of the most resinous plants I've
ever grown it produced more remember
they'll give us some frosty [ __ ] but it
just made little pinky sized buds all
the way up to stick yep and I could not
figure out how to make it produce better
so I'm thinking if I hit it with pollen
from the arize maybe that big ass of
rice Cola is gonna fix my problem with
the cookies and cream we can hope and
it's gonna improve that yeah so that's
what I'm hoping for I also put a white
wit a bunch of white widow in the room
to get bread - there's a grateful dog to
get pollinated there's a lemon Geoffrey
to get pollinated so here they won't get
pollinated for I'm trying to predict the
future right now at this time they're
about ten days into flour hopefully then
I'll get pollinated for another 16 days
ish and then about 50 days from there
the seeds should be ready so then I have
to harvest dry and remove the seeds and
then I'll have more stuff to give out to
my friends to be tested and keeps on
going and then we find out what's the
best what's worth making a whole bunch
more of and I'll continue those lines
and things that aren't super impressive
since space is limited time is limited
resources are limited I just try to make
the best of the best yeah so we don't
have to go calling things in the future
so that's where I am with breeding I'll
keep you guys updated as it gets further
along we're only a few days in so
there's not a lot of stuff to talk about
the male plants are a little bit ahead
because I like their like their male
flowers to develop a little bit further
so they can start dropping a lot of
pollens and then when the girls are
ready I got plenty of pollen for all
those plants that's pretty much where we
are welcome you guys updated speaking of
a breeding program the dank team comm if
you guys want to know where to get these
seeds that have been tested that are
viable that are that are reliable
they're ready to go their Rasta Jeff
approved a team calm they have got
archived seeds there I'm pretty sure
they've got rules they have they've got
cage beam genetics mile high they have
got Sin City seeds they've got I read
genetics seeds they're a whole bunch of
great brands err I can't think of them
at the top of my head cuz Mike and I
took a massive list and we took an
impressive list of tabs as well yes nice
variety of dad section
yeah yeah yeah good where is let's see
where was I team had you guys I've been
putting out episodes on Thursdays I've
had a little more time I've had a little
more content available I've had more
friends and I've noticed that sometimes
episodes are kind of time-sensitive like
this one we want to get out probably the
Monday after the election not the
Thursday because I want everyone to
catch this Monday episode I think it's
gonna happen it's gonna be the Monday
episode there's there's no reason to put
this one out in three weeks yeah exactly
so you guys that I have ever religiously
or regularly listened to the Monday
episodes don't forget that I've been
putting stuff out on Thursdays
occasionally so go back and check your
feet you might have missed something if
you're not paying attention and also
thank you for everybody that listens to
just the monday episodes or just the
thursday or everybody it's fun watching
my stats move and all of my statistics
on my website on stitcher itunes doesn't
show you a damn thing but the other ones
it's fun watching the stats move I
really enjoy that so thanks for
listening everybody I wrote down narcos
was great great show I'm looking forward
to 3 yeah yeah well spoiler alert but I
don't want to talk about how it ends but
okay no spoiler alert I guess he you
can't have work we're safe that's been a
couple of months but yes spoiler alert
if you haven't watched narcos do hit
pause and go watch two seasons and
narcos yeah I think that's enough for
people to prepare for the spoiler be
good go for it well I was familiar with
the this story before narcos yeah it's
gonna go so every time they hit a major
plot point or a major event and I was
like okay I know where that falls in the
time line how are they gonna get more
than two seasons out of this and I like
where they're headed for season 3 I
think it's a good transition they're
gonna do like arts a Cali cartel is
gonna be the focus yeah that's that's a
great spot to go from there it's uh it's
a really interesting part of history
that you don't often see portrayed
anywhere
other than I mean even a little bit in
class if you take like a really good
history class in college maybe other
than that you've gotta learn this [ __ ]
on your own
narcos actually did a nice job
presenting in a fun entertaining way
okay I know the story and I've read very
little but it sounds like they did a
good job that's right I didn't know that
yeah no they did a really nice ooh I
don't know about all the little stuff
but this story line of they follow is
accurate nice so I know that Murphy is
gonna be in the car Cali cartel show are
they gonna bring Pina back I hope me too
because those two together it's like the
beavis and butt-head it's a perfect duo
you need both of them because that show
balanced I think yeah I like both of
them together and I was glad that that
was one of the things they did in the
season finale was tease that there bring
a pen you back I'm pulling up an article
that I've got on my phone here something
we wanted to talk about to keep the show
moving here um just really random fun
story injection for the marijuana
community I saw this headline this week
there's a band somewhere attempting to
write a song in 420 time and when I saw
that I thought of you specifically
because you you're one of the people in
my world that knows what that means I
can already see he's got the expression
like he wants to laugh but he can't
quite figure out that how funny this is
or how insane this is you know something
about me I did there's a reason I didn't
click play and like you're there attempt
so far because I know just enough to
about music to know what a nightmare
that might be yeah how long does it have
to be to count as a song I have no idea
because that's what I like I can
probably play you six Matt four measures
for four or five measures that's not a
problem but after that you're almost
thinking three versus two choruses Oh
God at least the bridge in there yeah
man in 420 times it four beats per
measure you got to do the whole bit
right when he counts per
[Music]
yeah I saw that I was likewise for
measuring each beat gets 20 counts that
was one of those stories that came
through right before the election that I
was like thank God there's some some
people out there that are willing to do
[ __ ] insane enough to make the press to
just change the top of your conversation
even for a minute
yeah I could still see you trying to
wrap your head around it I remembered
the stories he said a couple cool ways
are they just gonna count 20 beats on
the bottom are they gonna break it down
to like a basic like a like a five or
four or five or something yeah okay my
head I just went one two three four five
six
this went way too far all right so a
while back this has been a continuing
story ongoing story ongoing story a long
time ago it feels like this feels like
it happened damned forever
it happened in May of 2015 to be more
precise which in a pothead mind like
mine that was damned forever back when
we learned not to watch movies on the
podcast there was a raid in the city of
Santa Ana yes the the police department
came in and destroyed the dispensary
they illegally raided the dispensary
they came in they destroyed the
dispensary they needlessly destroyed a
bunch of TVs they destroyed the cash
register they destroyed the display
counters they basically vandalized the
[ __ ] out of this place imagine if a
bunch of teenagers broke into somewhere
and were pissed off and just wanted to
[ __ ] [ __ ] up that's what they did in
there yep and in the process they also
stole and consumed cannabis infused
edibles while on the clock while
conducting a raid slash investigation
while in possession of a firearm while
taxpayer money was paying their salary
while illegally conducting a raid of a
legally functioning operating facility
as far as I'm concerned that's exactly
what the security video shows
unfortunately most of that wasn't
eventually proved in a court of law the
fallout from this has been a year or
more in the making
it looks like they're finally done with
this I think all of the officers that
are portrayed in the video
his main characters let's say that the
nasty female cop who says she was gonna
kick the one-legged old woman who was
volunteering at the dispensary quote in
her [ __ ] nub your mom and then the
cop that was handing out snack foods and
the other cop that was eating snack
foods all of resigned and the city's now
paying out what's the total okay
city of Santa Ana will pay $100,000 to
settle losses over infamous dispensary
raid yes of taxpayer money and if I
remember the article right that money's
getting split up three ways between two
of the main volunteers in the dispensary
and then legal counsel basically that's
a good business plan it's not a bad way
to disperse the settlement as far as I
can tell it's uh I'm glad that the city
got hit with this though there's
dispensary raids all over the place this
raid was clearly out of line from
beginning to end and it should have cost
the police some money it should it
should sting totally unacceptable from
start to finish you know how I found out
about that news article me and Twitter
Mike said it's me on Twitter you guys
article that you'd like me to read that
you think I should be aware of link it
to me in Twitter just grab it send to me
send it to me on twitter at g f YH
podcast I would appreciate it gives us
more material for the show also if
you've got a grow question if you've got
a cannabis related question a cannabis
industry a cannabis politics a cannabis
etiquette a cannabis culture whatever
you want to talk about if it's weed
related [ __ ] if you want to talk about
music and drums you could send me a
message I may reply about that as well
I'll grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I'd love to hear from you I love
interaction from the people that are
listening to the podcast we're all
friends now you're hanging out in your
car you're in your cubicle you're doing
whatever you're doing you're working in
the warehouse carrying boxes you got
your headphones in roster Jeff is keep
you entertained for a little while
we're bros now we're
even if you're at a female we're bros I
will still be bros don't worry I don't
know I don't know what else to cry we're
bros trust me fist bump we're bros so
yeah
Lyndsey just laughed at me I know I know
Lyndsey put her fist up and laughter
she's listening to this podcast shout
out to Lindsay she's in Florida right
now senator listener questions and
comments generate some of my favorite
episodes me - honestly the content seems
fresher and when we have when we're sure
that people want to know what about to
do an episode on it brings the energy
level up it's like watching people enjoy
the food you cook but I did it in
advance because I already know you're
gonna be happy because I did an episode
that you asked for yep I got to serve up
what you wanted for dinner alright and
we know you guys have questions so by
all means let them fly we're 15 minutes
into this podcast and we have not made
any useful we've got we've got a big
main topic tonight it was a stressful
couple of days it's been a stressful oh
man it's been a stressful six eight
months yeah yeah Facebook can we all
just shut the [ __ ] up and be friends
again well we're all in this together if
you agree or disagree or whatever
whatever happens is gonna happen can we
quit bickering and fighting and having a
mudslinging dick [ __ ] weapon contests
and grabbing each other by the [ __ ] and
just be friends again on Facebook
let's go posting pictures again please
it's been highly contentious for man
I've been actively working this election
since April yeah just just wrapping my
own head around that hurts mic episode I
don't know if it is aired yet and
appreciate the face man thank you
because you came on here I all the
listeners owe you a shout-out you came
on here and kind of reminded us several
times go [ __ ] vote so they did sinks
dude that's the first takeaway from last
night's election it's kind of a weird
way to jump into to the main topic
tonight but really you you you have to
vote that's I mean it's the one thing
that we all do as Americans other than
pay taxes and die that really unites all
of us under the same thing we got right
here one of my notes it's the one on the
bottom but I'm gonna ask
at first since you're here do you feel
like your vote made an actual difference
Oh big time okay look at the numbers I
mean there's there's a million different
ways to rationalize I didn't vote
because my vote didn't matter but if you
actually pull up the numbers look at
your area look at the different races
thousands and thousands and thousands of
people voted and a lot of these races I
mean even here in Pueblo races around
the country come down to thirty votes a
hundred votes Pueblo Colorado has been a
strong Democratic they call it a
democratic stronghold back when Colorado
was a hard Republican state Denver and
Pueblo were democratic in at this thick
Republican state and I mean for 40 years
Pablo's been a democratic stronghold and
in this election
Trump won by like 240 votes and
literally the our vote for president
down here was decided by 240 votes a
couple of that County Commissioners
seats which would directly impact both
of our lives and any number of things
locally were decided by a few hundred
votes a few thousand votes and this is
nationally when you look at the stuff if
you look at the polling data from this
election if Gary Johnson wasn't a thing
the conversation we're about to have
tonight would be very different
Gary Johnson running and the little tiny
percent of the vote he got changed vote
results all across the country and that
changed the outcome of the election in
major major ways right there it's not
just President it's so easy to I don't
like the two candidates that the main
parties before for president I'm not
voting just because you don't like the
president you just gave up all of your
decisions on your Senate Senators your
House of Representatives members your
local election
politicians your local election issues
your local ballot issue and a lot of
those are really important some of those
I didn't know how important they were to
me until I got my
and discovered that it was like oh [ __ ]
this needs to be voted on yeah when I
first started going through what was
finally gonna be on this elections
ballot here in Colorado I was like what
the [ __ ] the microphone we literally
voted on abolishing essentially
indentured servitude or slavery in
Colorado's penal system last night if I
if I caught that vote right we voted to
end being able to force prisoners to
work while they're in jail it's an
option not not something you have to do
for or we throw you in isolation or beat
you or don't feed you or whatever which
is kind of nuts that that's what we were
doing beforehand but when you see that
on the ballot you're like wow I've heard
so much about Hillary and I've heard so
much about Donald and I've heard so much
about Gary but I've heard nothing about
Weesa slavery here marijuana was on the
vote in nine states yesterday that's
another subject I wanted to hit I was
gonna say wait two days well that's our
main our main focus of tonight's
election is is tonight's podcast is the
election basically and how it relates to
marijuana I've been on here I can't even
tell you how many times talking about
different marijuana votes this election
locally and nationally I mean so this is
the wrap-up episode for everybody
welcome locally we can just brush this
out of the way for those of you who've
been waiting on pins and needles to
figure out if I still have a job
I do 200 and 300 failed here in Pueblo
so under on the ballot war initiatives
to pretty much dismantle and shut down
the recreational and medical cannabis
industries in the City and County of
Pablo Colorado if this initiative were
to have passed there would be no more
growing man you're processing which is
hash making and edible making there
would have gotten rid of all of the
regulated and licensed business all the
retail stores would have been gone how
many people were employed by that
industry's thirteen hundred is the low
ballpark number okay thirteen hundred
people would not have had jobs fortune
enough people did go out and vote that's
part of what gives me faith that my vote
counted because I voted one of them was
like 5,000 and changed the only 7,000 it
changed both yes and no on these
questions got over 20,000 votes okay
so literally every vote counted this
election every door that got knocked
mattered had we not done the work that
we did on this these two issues this
vote could easily gone the other way
the other team kind of started
floundering at the end there they ran a
very bizarre campaign I don't really
want to get into the ins and outs of our
local fight and why we won but thank God
we won but it was a weird election here
in Pueblo 2 we uh so questions 200 and
300 were voting to ban all the voice ins
businesses but we also had questions to
be in to see which we're going to allow
we currently allow all marijuana
businesses except retail stores under
amendment 64 Licensing in the city so we
allow medical all the medical businesses
and we allow every type of recreational
business except the retail storefront
locations and that was on the ballot
down here in Pueblo this time to do we
want the storefronts in Pueblo in voters
said no and that question lost by like
1,100 votes
wow that's not much no that's one an
apartment building yeah right that's two
or three city blocks worth of votes it's
not it's not a big number it's easily
swing a bull the other way with a hard
work and focus but I mean unfortunately
here in Pueblo the entire marijuana
community had a hundred percent of their
efforts invested in two hundred and
three hundred being defeated and clearly
from these results we let to be and to
see just sit ignored and because of that
they lost by a very very small margin
was one of those the the new cannabis
tax yep then the city was asking if they
could have if they could allow stores
and if they could tax
stores at a special rate and both of
those questions failed as well
the anti-pot group theory on this is
that people just voted no on everything
and if you look at the election results
a lot of the other questions that were
asked people also voted now I'm the
public safety taxes and things like that
that were on the ballot here in Pablo
all got voted down I'm so no more money
for cops no more money for police no
more money for the District Attorney's
Office how did the cigarette tax do
failed statewide okay which is where I
voted against my own interest in that
when we voted for it I voted for it I
know a lot of people who voted for it
increasing that tax revenue would have
been good for the state but so I know
you're trying to work on the new you
want it you really want to talk about
the new medical states and the new
recreational states I know but I keep I
keep progressing great there local piece
of marijuana election news is Denver's
issue 300 Webelos issue 300 was bad
Denver Zushi 300 was good that this is
the question about allowing public
consumption clubs in bars restaurants
taverns and then clubs that are
specifically set up to be private
consumption clubs in Denver County
basically the right to consume marijuana
in public with your friends in an
enclosed space designed for that purpose
and right now it's winning but by a tiny
tiny percentage it's like fifty point
two percent to forty nine point nine or
some [ __ ] like it's incredibly close
it's one of those races that really
hammers home the point that every single
vote if somebody would have broken down
on the way to vote it could have gone a
different way yep I mean there was
traffic that night that vote changes
someone's uber didn't show up it's I
mean it was very very close and they're
still counting those with the absentee
ballots that vote won't be a hundred
percent finalized for another day or two
now okay and there's another race that's
like that that we're gonna get to hear
in a minute so let's jump onto national
news guys did your uh did your issues
win to this stuff that you voted for
locally what percentage of those would
you say came out in your favor
almost all
okay it was the National stuff that
didn't go my way
but we're gonna get to that here in a
few minutes as well but most of the
stuff I voted for everybody if we're not
everybody Republic but the majority of
voters in public to agree on okay um
which was nice it's always nice to know
it's like oh yeah you are in the
majority I'm so relieved about two
hundred and three hundred man I had no
idea how to vote when it asked me about
judges do you want this judge to retain
his position I was like what you know I
know there's an answer for that they no
one does okay and so in every state
there is a group of people made up of
not judges but lawyers prosecutors
district attorneys defense attorneys
will and probate lawyers like all kinds
of different legal professionals that
are practicing in that state kind of the
best of the best get put together and
then come up with a retain or don't
retain this Wow okay and so if you
google your state and then like judge
retention or whatever you should be able
to find that group in your area and then
they tell you judge Billy Bob you should
you should retain him because X Y &amp; Z or
you shouldn't retain him because of X Y
&amp; Z but the way it works in practice is
nobody knows so everybody just votes yes
and so judge retention rates are like
ninety-three percent right for an
acrostic I'm the only judge I've had
interaction with and I'm knocking on
wood prison jaw for this one the only
judge I've had interaction with over the
past few years was the guy that resided
over my jury duty selection and I don't
remember his name but if I remembered it
he'd get it yeah he was cool like mad
nothing wrong he that guy was polite to
me he was he treated me like the old
lady in a blouse next to my know the
judge you're talking about I'm spacing
his name but he's a really nice human
being and he's a pretty good judge he's
a cool dude
but a lot of people in my world are in
the that live in the legal world and so
I always have an earful of judge this or
this judge is great this judge is in
yeah how about you man did the election
go your way yeah for the most part for
what for the you basically just told me
that all the stuff I was mostly worried
but the tax the cannabis tax sucks
that's not cool
I don't think that we should be adding
extra taxes to cannabis it's already
expensive enough I think taxing it just
encourages more of the black market sale
I kind of figured it was gonna fail for
that reason yeah that's silly thing and
considering that the tax rate that our
retail stores pay already
I mean it's deep enough and obviously
I'm not excited about the president that
represents us now but other than that I
guess I can live with everything else
that happened the the national election
could have some serious implications for
from marijuana nationally I'm willing to
trade our shitty cannabis taxes and our
lack of recreational dispensaries and
Pueblo city limits to allow the other
states to have a jump on cannabis yeah
I'll go for that we're covered here in
public like I feel bad for the city of
Pueblo is who I feel bad for later I'm
self-sufficient so a lot of that just
kind of a lot of us here are but I mean
honestly the city's had three years but
and also they limited our plant count
yep yes in the city of Pueblo we were
allowed to grow we had a hundred square
feet that's still the rule in the city
it's the county that okay okay County
just did that is a county commissioner
rule you guys know that sounds strange
but the city of Pueblo is like a
different part of the county the county
is the outer area that's not like
[Music]
falling apart yeah so the county is a
different area so they have a little bit
different rules and they actually we did
vote on uniting them there was an option
Ono's know that that was question one
see in question one see here in Pueblo
County asked if the county commissioners
had voter approval to take our
our current plant cap of 18% property if
they could have our support going to the
state legislature and arguing to make
that rule statewide and the only reason
they put that on the ballot is because
when county commissioners go to the
state legislature and say please make
this rule if they're able to say we put
it on the ballot and a majority of our
constituents supported us bringing this
question to you and asking you to do
this the legislature listens a little
more closely and that's all question
once he did was give the county
commissioners permission to say and the
voters support us asking this of okay a
lot of people freaked out about that one
and obviously and all of them fly last
night
today when somebody asked me about
question 1c i spayed I couldn't even
remember what number it was I was
impressed that you have known as many
numbers as quickly as you have I've been
breaking down data all day looking
because there was a big screw-up you've
got data eyes you've got that like
computer screen face when he showed up I
there was a screw-up in public County
our our ballot was really really long
this year it was four pages and so when
they started running through these
ballots through the servers for the the
election department the servers got
overwhelmed because there was like just
each chunk of information for each
ballot was a little bit larger than
usual because the ballot was twice as
long and they they're reporting that
they filled up a server and that the
State Election Commission had to put a
server in a van and floor it down here
yesterday afternoon install the server
run test software on it half the evening
and fire to back up our local election
department people went home at 3:00 a.m.
with instructions to report back at 9:00
Wow yep and so we were crunching as much
data as we could last night and I've
been looking at it all day and I still
hadn't looked at one see with everything
else that happened last night it was
such a bizarre election the data is
really really weird we're seeing
demographic changes in Colorado
that we haven't seen in our lifetime the
population is growing here rapidly
people that are from here are moving
there are huge numbers of people from
around the country that are moving here
for a variety of reasons and that's
changing the demographics all over the
state in ways nobody predicted and then
nationally no one expected marijuana to
do this good everybody was hopeful but
nationally marijuana just crushed it
so I want to ask one more local just a
quick one and then we'll get off the
local stuff you guys I know we probably
bore the [ __ ] out you guys were just
local but then we're gonna talk about
well they do shout out hashtag we like
it when they like it when you ramble
we're gonna talk about new states in
just one second but on the Colorado
option yet mic signal isn't gonna kill
me I'm gonna take a DAB before we get to
the national stuff now there you go on
the the ballot was a question about
basically assisted suicide what the law
basically said was if a person is deemed
excuse me I'm gonna birth let me just
get it out of the way okay I'm better
now
way better excuse me it smells like dank
ass pizza - I apologize if that hits you
Mike cuz it was ripe so on the on the
ballot there was I'm calling it the
assisted suicide
totally fair description if you're
terminally ill and you're gonna die
within six months and I think it takes
two doctors to verify this and you can't
be mentally ill you have to be like this
I'm sound mind to say that this is what
you want we're only the third or fourth
maybe the fifth state to do anything
like this and so the law is very very
careful and meticulous about the process
for this and there was a lot of anti I
can't remember the note that the ballot
issue for this one but the opposition
campaign their main argument was if your
shitty children will euthanize you to
get their inheritance quicker was the
argument and when people were like but
the doctors part they were like well
they'll just pay the doctor more no no
not okay did you silly side note we
can't get a doctor to write an extended
play
they're not gonna risk their license for
a plant they're definitely not gonna
risk their license to [ __ ] kill you
that is not gonna it was just a silly
argument and I know everybody's belief
saw on this are gonna vary but I mean
because you brought it up I don't mind
telling the listeners that I 100%
support I had filled in that bubble yes
really strong I was in let's do that I
watched a family member a shot it's my
grandma my grandma had a stroke my
grandma was a very dignified woman
choose bad as [ __ ] she raised six kids
she worked until pretty much the day she
fell down and had a stroke she had a
solid job she took care of the family
she took good care of her husband she
did good care of the grandkids that's me
one day she had a stroke she was
paralyzed on her left side she hated
that she wanted to get up and do laundry
and [ __ ] cook for us and do what
grandma did how she couldn't do it
anymore
I swear that why I'd go visit her in the
nursing home she looked me straight now
and then look at the plug for her
machines like you're the only one that
would have the plug for me Jeff that's
what my grandma was saying to me she was
she did not want to live and she
couldn't speak she could speak there's
so many instances in this country where
for one reason or another we
significantly prolonged suffering here
for absolutely no it's almost like of
course I wanted my grandma still but I
did not want to have to have grandma
miserable right if I would if she could
speak if I would have [ __ ] held
something up say grandma unplug or plug
[ __ ] momentum she could generate with
whatever yeah member with Parkinson's
and part of them coming to terms and
kind of figuring out how to live after
that diagnosis was setting up basically
with a number of people in their life
that if the time comes that I want to go
like will you help me acquire whatever I
have to acquire to get that done
because this law didn't exist right
because their only option was to
continue to wither away while they were
a hundred percent aware of their body
collapsing around them I mean it was
it's an incredibly brutal diagnosis
this issue was closed to me and I was
glad I was thrilled that it passed with
crushed it last night it passed with
two-thirds of the vote okay
it would just win a one in a landslide
that's that's one that I strongly
supported because I'm gonna get old one
day and I don't need anybody I don't
want to be a burden on anybody
hi Kent I'm I'm a young strapping young
lad you know I'm saying I'm able-bodied
if some [ __ ] needs to be done I could
probably do it wanna be I don't want to
be a burden on somebody like the wife
has instructions if if I'm a vegetable
or a burden a harvest which you can for
other people and cremate the rest yep
sprinkle it over a pot filled yep there
you go yeah with some Sun alright so I'm
glad that one passed I'm glad you
supported that one yeah hope that wasn't
too weird for anybody yeah I didn't mean
to get into the right today on this
podcast but that's that's something I
supported when I saw it was Lee that's
an option you were doing that yeah yeah
that's that's something that needs to be
the right to live free freedom alright
so let's get to what we've been kind of
hinting at we didn't even mention the
[ __ ] elephant room we got [ __ ] the
[ __ ] Oompa Loompa is our president
now so grab by the [ __ ] everybody
that's all I got to say medical cannabis
in 2017 we've got coming out of the gate
with fresh cannabis um the first big
news last night was Florida Florida's
not medical marijuana state I'll welcome
with a club Florida that was not an easy
run for you insane amount amore was
spent together Florida welcome to the
club Florida it's about time it was nice
to see a lot of the stuff we're talking
about tonight was East Coast yeah yeah
even Bible Belt a Rhode Island past a
marijuana initiative didn't they have
one I mean mean is who I'm thinking of
Maine Maine is amazing okay right now
they're a recreational legalization
state right now that question is winning
by a tiny tiny percentage so it's been
24 hours they're still counting [ __ ] yep
[ __ ] Maine this is back to every
single vote counts they're counting
absentee ballots they're counting the
military ballots counting the fishermen
ballots and in a lot of places for no
reason whatsoever people waited till
yesterday to vote when they had
significant other onions and so I mean
people were still voting at 8 o'clock
last night and then it's at 8 o'clock or
7 o'clock or whatever the polls close
they start counting the ballots then
they don't start like it'll get it
[ __ ] funny for the most part they
don't even get a jump on it and that's
part of the reason and the history are
they [ __ ] that's part of the reason why
this stuff is so slow and it's part of
the reason why you don't see early vote
totals for votes cast anywhere like I
vote he's like three weeks ago yeah like
two days after my ballot arrived I
mailed it in tonight at the third debate
my wife had some wine I enjoyed some
cannabis we watched the debate we just
talked about a half an hour to process
what the [ __ ] we just watched and then
we went through our ballot and it was a
long ballot so it took like two hours
and there was a lot of freaking out
while we did it but I they make it real
easy in Colorado and then there was this
like two and a half three week period
where you know they [ __ ] got votes
they just won't tell you what they say
yet it's real frustrating when you're
doing election work because that's
information that you could use I was
gonna say they don't want to sway any
yeah that's part of the reason they
don't do it is because if I say Jeff's
winning over Mike by 10 votes all of a
sudden Mike's supporters have a rallying
try to get more people vote and that's I
think that's part of what we saw
nationally last night how many people
saw things saying Hillary was 85 percent
to win two or three days ago on national
media so when when is the next we got
four years to the next election when it
when can I start getting people to
register to vote again I know I just
totally tried right your idea yeah they
go immediately they could do that now
for the next for the 2020 election
Michael Franti runs for president yep
the Franti warned Michael Franti from
spearhead and uncle Warren Haynes from
government back to our Medical Marijuana
States we've got Florida congratulations
Florida yes North Dakota is that wreck
or medical medical I'm doing all medical
right now good job
North Dakota is now a medical marijuana
State Arkansas welcome to the club
Arkansas bang-on welcome dangle welcome
exactly who saw that coming
it's [ __ ] crazy um I'm 99% sure
Florida North Dakota in Arkansas all
voted Trump so we got I'm 99% sure that
Florida North Dakota and Arkansas almost
always lean conservative and they still
went medical like this is spreading in
ways that are were unheard of five years
ago yeah states that were guaranteed to
never liberalize their marijuana laws
are now doing so I mean it ending
numbers that are shocking so those are
the three new medical states um I
actually think that I might have two
missing on my list what do you have some
rec states no no no they're all here I
think I may be missing one they told me
four and I think there were five
okay so nevada nevada fa no nevada fast
arizona failed that's the one I miss in
Arizona there she is okay okay so now
for rec states recreational marijuana
any adult over 21 California welcome
with Club Callie amendment 64 crushed it
dude I don't even know if I want to get
into the amendment 64 debate I've got
friends on both sides of that battle
that live in California that are on both
sides of the industry the big business
side the small business side the last
two months saw the existing industry
pairing up with national anti marijuana
forces to fight amendment 64 or
proposition 64 in California the the the
medical marijuana existing industry and
the marijuana advocate community paired
up with projects am bucking Kevin Sabet
and Patrick Kennedy's nightmare of an
anti marijuana group to fight
legalization in California largely for
economic reasons if marijuana is legal
in in real companies can invest real
money and open real businesses and it's
really regulated and it's really lab
tested I can't grow weed in my basement
make a living anymore that's in my
basement and take it to a store shelf
and make money that way anymore I know
guys that happened to it I know a lot of
people a balloon caller made us have to
become master growers at facilities and
and always have income it's like I'm
sorry but that's the point of
legalization
we're not legalizing marijuana because
we can't get it
it's hard to find or because it was too
difficult to to call my [ __ ] dealer
on my way to work and make sure he was
gonna be around after work we're doing
it because we're sick of that
we want legal we want lab tested we want
to be able to swing by this store on our
way home just like we do for the milk
and cookies eggs and the chicken the
whiskey and the beer yep and everything
else I don't want to have to call a
friend when I want to buy sneakers like
I don't want to wait two days because
he's not answering my texts right now
cuz he's with some hot new chick so I
can buy a jacket I don't know why people
are still willing to do this at a
concert that marijuana it can be on like
the reddit marijuana forums and stuff
you see people bitching about dealer
etiquette customer etiquette constantly
that's its Lea its I would have to if I
didn't keep up with parts of the online
community that are still in illegal
states um that still have to deal with
it do you remember when you were always
wondering if the person you were meeting
up with was gonna have either the money
or the pot product they told you they
were you have to you if they were gonna
have two homies in a knife or a gun you
just never know yeah oh that's gone like
when you buy jeans you don't wander if
you're gonna get robbed when you go buy
a Big Mac you don't have to arrange it
first and then wait outside and then
hang out for two hours so you don't look
like foot traffic have exact change yep
you don't have to carry drumsticks in
and out with you every time pretending
like you're taking [ __ ] drum lessons
you can just go to the store buy your
marijuana know that it's not filled with
pesticides or spider mite eggs go home
and enjoy it and it's that's why we're
doing it and it comes with a lot of
benefit if you are a weirdo looking dude
and you're carrying around portions of
things that you need concealed a guitar
case is my favorite way to do that type
of [ __ ] out in the open [ __ ] got a
big ol guitar case filled with whatever
well mine's usually a little more
peaceful I used to put a lot of good
shoot in there drumsticks and stuff oh
yeah yeah but if you've got a lot of
drumsticks that you need like vacuum
seal and wrap real tight you could fit a
lot of them in a guitar case and it just
looks normally you can just walk around
with it like a [ __ ] hippie with a
guitar case it's no question unless
someone wants to steal your guitar or or
a chick wants you to play a song
back to the list of new wrecks thank you
this tangent is brought to you by blue
oh gee from tenneco California is now
recreational marijuana state
Massachusetts bringing up our first
Eastcote East Coast [ __ ] yep this
mass was a really really contested race
there were there's a lot of outside
money there were a lot of outside it's
high marijuana groups throwing their
their two cents and their reefer madness
at the issue there
I've spent a little bit of time in
Massachusetts one of my best friends on
the planet so I went to high school and
after high school I went on Phish tour
and then did some panic shows and 90% of
that time sitting next to me in the
passenger seat or the driver's seat
occasionally it was my buddy robbed the
dude shoutout to rob the dude and he is
in Massachusetts he's a Masshole one
summer we did a bunch of widespread
panic shows from New Mexico all the way
to Boston and we missed a couple shows
cuz the car broke but we had a good ass
time but he moved to Quincy mass I think
was kind of where he moved to
and we went to Boston and we went all
over Massachusetts and that's a
conservative place I'm a LOB's at the
time I didn't have dreadlocks I just had
long filthy hair and I was weren't a
Phish t-shirt and like patchwork pants
and I probably either had skate shoes or
no shoes because that's how I used to
roll and Abell massachusetts gave me the
like man's one big cherry creek like was
like not for sure all of the places my
buddy Rob took me to felt very uh
everything was overpriced and the cars
were a little nicer than I should be
driving and yeah I felt out of place at
the time but anyway shout out to rob the
dieter Brock I'm glad that you can get
yourself some some legal cannabis here
next year we do a shout out for mass
joining the club and bike shut up the
bike also Nevada
now they've got legal casinos legal
prostitution and legal weed
congratulations Nevada that's awesome
yeah and Nevada's law their wreck now
but their medical law really pushed the
envelope as far as what's allowed what's
not allowed okay with reciprocity they
were one of the few places you could
take your med card from any other
medical state walk into a Nevada medical
marijuana shop and purchase medical
marijuana in Nevada like I can't do that
in California with my Colorado card you
can't do that in Colorado with the
California card nice reciprocity is rare
in Nevada was the first one to step up
so I was not surprised to see them go
legal marijuana um a lot of the anti
marijuana money spent in this campaign
came from casinos I'm not necessarily
those in Nevada but that's one of those
anti marijuana funding points that's
common and that's gonna start changing
into that and now why wouldn't they want
me to get super blazed and Gamble common
wisdom is because you'd spend more if
you were drinking
yes I wouldn't I don't go because I
can't get blazed in yeah if I can if I
could just safely go to my own like
Vegas until now either if there was a
place where I could go like either smoke
a joint or take a couple dabs away from
the casino floor right for that much
last time I was in the casino they kept
bringing me a new ashtray like every
four minutes and [ __ ] smokers that was
like we're all gonna get cancer and die
together a little stronghold stabbing at
the slot machine would just get reckless
for me because there's that couple of
minutes right after you take it bad
where the world is like spinning and
you're like oh [ __ ] I don't need to be
right at the machine there I need to
check out that's part of why I go off
and dab somewhere so I can just check
out what's going on so you taking a
lunch break
yep just go [ __ ] be somewhere that's
not loud and [ __ ] happen in that you can
just [ __ ] shut your brain up take
couple dabs and then you got a slowly
reenter I would love to if I had a place
where I could just go take a couple
dad's you're smoking joint and then go
back to the tables I'd actually go back
up to Blackhawk and stuff again or Vegas
would hold a little more interest for me
write it as it is now it's like yeah I
get to go drive all my drunk friends
around so that's a nice change I'm proud
of Nevada and then the last one on the
lid the the maybe list is Maine and we
choose this one a little bit earlier the
state of Maine is currently in a very
very tight race the anti marijuana focus
in Maine have already sworn to take this
one there you know they're gonna take it
to court and ask for a recount and make
sure that the votes were tallied
correctly that's step one and then
they'll go from there
that's how close it is because it's it's
within a I think it's within 3,000 votes
total in the last news report I saw said
one of the counties that had gone I'm
under majority no vote for legalization
they found like another 2700 ballots at
like absentee ballots that might have
not been counted and so there's little
things like that that they're squeezing
through and making sure everything gets
cleaned up that could put
in the no column anti legalization
people are anti marijuana people are
already calling Maine a win because the
big bad marijuana industry didn't win in
a landslide because it's a tight race
because they can legally contest it and
ask for a recount they're putting that
one in the win column unfortunately
they're putting it next to Arizona which
belongs in their win column legalization
got crushed in Arizona yeah lost by a
good chunk of the vote my guess is it
had to do specifically with that issue
like we just group these is medical
states and rec states every law in all
the states we listed is different they
do the same thing in very very different
ways and the success of the vote often
depends on the nuances there had
Colorado's amendment 64 been worded
differently might not have passed right
I'm same thing with all the votes last
night
and I think that's part of what we're
seeing in Arizona they also had a
shitload of money thrown at they're an
anti legalization campaign I want to say
half a million from discounts higher in
two million from Sheldon Adelson guys I
usually don't I do endorse companies I
don't dis endorse companies very often
other than this [ __ ] headphone amp
I've got one that works now this one is
why I'm not gonna curse it never mind
but discount tire can eat my ass
discount tire is a place where you go to
get discount Tires just pay regular
price with [ __ ] tires because a
discount tire isn't giving you a
discount anyway they just put the word
discount in there to trick you they
contributed heavily to keep you cannabis
illegal they make tires why don't they
give a [ __ ] if cannabis is illegal or
not if you if this is for everybody keep
an eye out for who supports what um
you'll be shocked how many companies
that you spend money out money at
actively take your money shake your hand
turn around and spend the money you just
put in their pocket against you here
locally we had a number of companies
the marijuana industry was actively
supporting like by choice kinda as a
group that is it turns out have been
actively trying to dismantle us and so
industry-wide there's been shifts and
who we advertise with here who use for
trash service here who we use for
construction work here we [ __ ] shop
for meat there's a I mean a couple of
people came out actively against us and
I mean elections have consequences your
your public support and announcement of
things have consequences and this is
true in your area as well as smears pay
attention to politics this stuff affects
everything you do so we've got all of
these states that just went wreck and
medical bringing our national total to
eight full legal medical or legal
marijuana states where any adult can buy
marijuana if they're over 21 in a
licensed and regulated store eight legal
states and twenty eight medical
marijuana States
I'm one in five Americans lives in an
area where they can buy marijuana
legally it's like three and five when
you do the medical uhm and now some of
that 28 is CBD only oil laws and places
like Utah but I mean with numbers like
that those give me hope for our national
our national news because as all as you
know now or have had the chance to learn
Trump is now our president or our
president-elect he'll take over in
January and this election also gave
control of the Senate to the GOP and the
House of Representatives to the GOP and
in all likelihood that group of people
will be replacing three Supreme Court
justices in the next four years so the
shape of American politics that
landscape is all shifting drastically
under our feet
one of the reasons President Obama
wasn't able to do a lot of the things he
had campaigned on trying to do was
because the opposition party the
Republicans held a large majorities in
either the house of the Senate during
his presidency so when the president
wanted to do something the opposition
party would make it as hard as possible
that's not gonna be true for President
Trump it lists for the first two years
he's got party majority in all of
government which means Trump wanted
Trump probably get to Dewey yeah for
marijuana legalization that before last
night the picture was a lot darker on
the campaign trail some of
president-elect Trump
sorry listeners I fear conservative
that's just saying that does weird
things in my brain but president-elect
Trump has spent a lot of time working
very closely with some strong
prohibitionists politicians chris
Christie is a big Trump supporter has
been on the campaign campaign trail
stumping for Trump since he dropped out
of the presidential race himself I mean
he was one of the people that was
promising to send the army to shut us
down on day one attorney John meaning
the legal marijuana industry period from
the federal government can basically
immediately void the Cole memo and the
Ogden memo and begin doing what's
necessary to enforce the Controlled
Substances Act call Colorado up and say
hey easy either you stop all this legal
marijuana bullshitter we yank all your
road funding Colorado doesn't survive
without federal dollars no Street does
yeah that's how they got coast to coast
alcohol laws in line and that's been the
threat all along his states have kind of
crafted their own marijuana industries
in their own way like we've been doing
for the last twenty years now
that at any point someone in federal
government would yank that leash and the
entire industry we've built would have
crumbled back into the black market and
honestly with eight legal states twenty
eight medical states in an election last
night where eight of nine succeeded that
that says a lot we had Republicans and
Democrats turnout in big numbers last
night and vote for legalization both
parties were talking about whoever gets
elected job one is trying to bring the
nation back together
try to heal some of the divisiveness and
this is an issue that we're now agreeing
on as a majority population not just the
majority of Democrats not just the
majority of Republicans not just the
majority of young people or black people
or Hispanic people but the majority of
Americans agree on now I think it would
be incredibly costly for a future Trump
administration to to really go after
legal marijuana at this point yes
there's just too much support
coast-to-coast now at last night's
election had one state join RAC and
maybe to join medical that mandate isn't
there like I keep coming back to every
vote really counts I mean when we really
digest what happened on Tuesday that's
gonna be what's clear is that if you're
not participating in this you're [ __ ]
yeah the people that disagree with you
get to make those decisions
and I mean where we go from here is is
kind of anyone's guess what happens
starting in January I mean
the difference between president-elect
Trump on the campaign trail and in last
night's concession speech was night and
day that speech alone changed the
conversation nationally from oh [ __ ]
who's got a good bunker to maybe we all
survived this I mean literally in one
speech and a lot of the national media
do you think somebody grabbed him by the
collar and sent him down and was like
it's clear that for the last couple of
weeks several important people have have
been in conversations with Donald Trump
explaining that President of the United
States isn't a game it isn't a joke it
isn't funny I real repercussions
billions of lives we just gave who's
accurate someone whose accurate
accurately been described as orange
Hitler all of our nuclear launch codes
that's happening in the next couple of
weeks
I mean immediately would the when the
election results came in last night like
10 o'clock 11 o'clock at night when we
knew okay Hillary lost Donald Trump won
she's calling him to concede the race
this is real international stock markets
all over the world sort of crashing an
hour and a half later he made his
concession speech in the crash stopped
Wow the world is watching one of the one
of the things that we forget is that
planet Earth is a big idea it's a very
small place right now we're 20 hours
apart from every human on earth at most
that means in 20 hours the person that's
farthest away on this planet from
wherever you are right now
you'll be shaking your hand where you're
standing it's a very very small place we
are a leader in every way globally
and when we give the keys to a reality
TV show contestant or host or whatever
the world takes notice and it's clear
that someone's been in his ear for weeks
emphasizing this because his entire
demeanor was different last night and
and even his supporters were running him
good to run it onstage and kick the
podium down and be like like grab bricks
people of some mortar we can start now
like that's what people were expecting
and when it didn't happen and he came
off as presidential the entire world
noticed the entire world noticed nine
states voting on marijuana last night
other nations are looking at legalizing
marijuana from the government down
because they see what's happening in the
United States they see the headache of
voter put forth value that ballot
efforts and how hard it is to regulate
in tax a voter initiative law rather
than craft a legalization law from the
ground up that works well in the system
they've already got in place places like
Uruguay they're not waiting for the
voters right and there's a couple other
countries that we're watching Florida
last night they were watching California
last night they're they're watching
Maine now in thinking we signed the same
conventions the United States did that
prohibit us from legalizing marijuana
these laws have been just as destructive
here as they are there are people here
deserve the same opportunity to free of
the problems these laws cause that the
people in Colorado do and so they're
doing it themselves because elections
matter elections have consequences and
if you can do this smartly from the top
down it can go a little smoother
part of the reason this process is so
ugliness so messy and so [ __ ] slow
I'm sorry for cussing so much tonight
guys dress it out Frazee well it's
[ __ ] crazy I'm so proud of myself I
haven't thrown anything in the last 48
hours part of that's because I'm always
holding a rig but still I mean it's it's
been really really stressful and and
honestly with what we're left looking at
right now we're where we go from here is
anyone's guess a lot of where we go from
here is totally up to Donald Trump
because we honestly honest-to-god just
gave that man the the driver's seat of
the planet and where he takes us is
really anyone's guess
I mean if it's pretty clear if you've
been paying attention to reality's a lot
of his campaign promises are not at all
realistic or feasible they're Bigley
crazy yes
it's sort of like him promising that if
we elected him aliens would finally
introduce themselves but he's still
gonna be president for four years he's
still gonna point a cabinet he's still
gonna replace Supreme Court justices
he's gonna do something he's gonna
govern does he decide to to yank our
federal funding and so all 50 states
fall back in line with prohibition does
he finally crack the whip and say it's
time to legalize nationally or at least
let the states do it I mean literally
every decision is a [ __ ] coin flip at
this point no one knows we hope that
somebody's screaming look look how
popular it is it did better than almost
every candidate on the ballot you can't
come out strongly against marijuana
it would kill you but who knows he could
be sitting down with Chris Christie
right now having a scotch and a prozac
talking about how they gonna round up
all the hippies I'm one of the really
scary things that happened last night
was private prison stocks skyrocketed
yep Jess eyebrow just went through the
top of his head
I've been joking for days now that I
hope me and all my friends end up in the
same FEMA camps um
FEMA camps very unlikely that was one of
the more fun rumors about Obama's
presidency but uh
I mean it's a possibility yeah I'm the
type of people that those people are
that they do not like well it's a
hundred percent possible that a new
administration goes a very different
direction then the Obama administration
has gone and there's a reason
legalization advocates of have pushed
the Obama administration as hard as they
have for more on legalization every
chance we've gotten we've begged for
movement and we've gotten a little bit
very very little and because we've only
gotten a little bit of movement
federally the next administration can do
whatever they want they can put an end
to all of this
um with a couple of meetings a strategy
and like thirty five phone calls or
press release is really all it would
take yeah I'm sure there would be a lot
of kicking there'd be a lot of screaming
there'd be a lot of hell no we won't go
but in the end you're talking about
stoners versus drones the way to change
the laws is to participate in the system
and vote right and hopefully the people
that are about to take power caught the
mandate from last night and we're paying
attention the only group of people that
are really happy right now that I see in
my social media feeds are the marijuana
people yeah the hardcore marijuana
people know that marijuana had a huge
night last night liberals are
disappointed and confused
conservatives are really confused and
kind of shocked stoners are happy but I
honestly think that it's a little early
to be super happy for those of you in
states that just passed either medical
Iraq get involved immediately get to
City Council get on your computer when
you hear this and figure out what area
you live in whether it's governed by a
city council or a County Commission or
whatever figure out when those meetings
are and start going figure out when your
state legislature meets and what they're
talking about and if you can attend
those meetings
because if your state like if you're in
California right now those rules are
just being written all of those cities
that have been passing marijuana vans
leading bands leading up into the
election we're doing so that they had
time to write rules for 64 so that they
could pick the zoning and pick the
buffer distances and pick the tax
numbers you need to be participating in
those hearings if you want to want any
kind of say in it otherwise the people
who do care are gonna get what they want
in those laws just go put your face in
that mix go be seen humans no matter
what your job if you're a councilman if
you're a zoning commissioner if you make
the laws if you're the judge if you go
to whatever meeting it is at the end of
the meeting there's always that fifteen
minutes where everybody just stands
around in [ __ ]
maybe if you're the guy like Mike that
goes to every single City Council
meeting that he can maybe one of the
guys that are running that is on the
fence about how they feel about you
maybe I'll actually walk up and actually
speak to you because they just want
someone to talk to for that next ten
minutes till they have to go to the next
meeting if they want to blend in like
everyone else they don't want to seem
like a dick and it's socially acceptable
to just walk up and talk to the other
guy at that council meeting you may end
up putting the right bug in his ear he
may talk to you and realize man that
guy's six five with dreadlocks and his
eyes are red and he wears a red golden
green t-shirt every day but when I spoke
to him he was intelligent he sounded
like you knew what he was talking about
maybe I'm not so afraid of these
cannabis guys because that guy's
compassionate and that guy's telling me
about his friend with cancer that he's
helping take care of with cannabis he
might spark something in somebody and he
may accidentally put them on your team I
I was at a couple different watch
parties on election night and when I
stopped by the Democratic watch party
one of our local representatives in the
city was asking me if I thought eight
stores would be enough to dedicate a
hard stream of revenue revenue to law
enforcement and so I quickly turned the
conversation into production facilities
that we already allow or where you want
that money to come from because it's a
more stable revenue source and it was
just a quick two minute conversation but
it was somebody in City
men who knew me from these meetings who
just they were bored at a party and so
they came wandering over to me to chat
for your face yep and so now when
they're looking at the budget next week
and they see that our to our two ballot
questions about more money for law
enforcement failed they've got an option
that they might be able to fill some of
that hole with now that might not have
been on the table before and honestly
that's down the road for the the states
that just voted on it if you live in
California or Massachusetts or Nevada
right now your city or your county is
talking about or it's about to be
talking about zoning rules what type of
land and what type of areas in our
community do we want to allow production
facilities we want to allow growth or
extraction labs or stores how many feet
from school should they be um what kind
of labeling should we require what kind
of testing should we require and the
people that are about to make those
decisions don't have a [ __ ] clue
about any of this they know cannabis is
a weed they know that it needs water and
sunlight to grow and then I guess you
can grow it under lights and that it's
probably bad for your brain and that's
all they know yep and if you don't show
up to these meetings and and bring
reality to them they're never gonna see
it they're gonna pass rules to regulate
what's in their head um and you're gonna
get stuck with some of the rules that we
get and you're left explaining them to
people with just it's just a crazy rule
that we follow like what why do we have
to bleach our trash it's just one of
those things is bleach good for the
environment bucket it's a rule so yeah
let me talk about that one oh I ran a
big grow we had over a hundred lights
and people would climb a barbed wire
fence well this is a statewide rule
because the legislature kind of saw this
committee would climb oh and they would
put carpets old-school style like they
just do back in the day throw a carpet
over graffiti style throw the carpet
over the fence jump the fence and then
climb up a big pole above the trash can
and jump off this pole through the play
we had plastic trash can lids the giant
dumpster they weren't plastic they were
that thing
like that real hard heavy plas yeah yeah
yeah and they would smash their bodies
through it and then they'd get in there
and steal our trash bags which was look
why would we throw away weed we didn't
do that it was sticks and stems and
mainly like office trash we had an
office it was a bathroom there was
bathroom trash
there was Thai food trash because I ate
lunch there okay the people breaking
into marijuana dump business dumpsters
don't know about the rules eventually we
had dollar eventually we had to put a
stainless steel do these lids were so
heavy that it I had to get on a chair to
lift him up because I couldn't get
enough leverage from the one and they
were so heavy and they they found a way
to cut the poles the hinges off of the
ends now to get into that trash can yep
and they're on camera doing it they've
been pulled over and busted it's the
same guy that does it repeatedly but
anyway you guys I'm off for like we've
had a lot of weird rules here mainly
because when it came time to pass these
rules to write a lot of them the
marijuana community was busy scrambling
trying to start a business before the
rules got in place so that they can open
it their way if their location and
hopefully get grandfather didn't later
when rules finally did get passed the
grandfather [ __ ] didn't work out too
well for a lot of us did it um at one
point we had over a thousand marijuana
retail locations in Colorado and that
was the week before real regulations
came down the pipe for the first time um
at the same time that first regulation
set hit the feds came in and said all
right any of you that aren't a thousand
feet from the school and we're gonna
make that thousand feet as long as
possible like if there's the grand
canyon between me and you it doesn't
matter before only nine hundred ninety
five feet apart at the opposite sides of
the Grand Canyon it's as the crow flies
is what they called it or you stood by
the foot and they recently changed it
and I've [ __ ] a lot of people you know
when they changed that rule like a third
of our shops had to move or close down
and all the shops that were near like it
nine hundred and eighty feet from
whatever school
the feds said you have to close and that
was the only big closure of shops we had
in Colorado
the feds closed down about 50 of them
for being too close to schools and then
the rules being put in place closed
almost 500 um and since then like
another 150 have dropped out of the
running because it's it's just too much
of a headache
what really uh what what bothered me
about a lot of the rulemaking was it
created a scenario where guys like okay
I can use Scott reaches an example
because he's gone full circle back in
the day Scott reach from rare Dan rare
dankness opened up a dispensary I think
it was called White Mountain medicine
that dispensary was the [ __ ] example
that's what dispensaries should have
been back then but that was the Wild
Wild West when there weren't any rules
if they were what's called vertically
integrated before vertical integration
was a thing they were growing everything
they were selling they were producing it
all
they were packaging it everything was
happening in house it was all like a
one-man show basically it was not in a
couple of homies and then they started
implementing all these new systems all
these new rules all these new laws and
the guys that were putting their heart
into the grow these guys were sleeping
in the grow you know what I mean they
had cots between the rows of plants
where these guys would take a nap when
the lights went off for the 1212 cycle
they'd sleep in there they'd wake up and
sneak out and go in the other room and
work on that after they had a nap they
were killing it but all the new rules
forced cameras and so much other
[ __ ] that they couldn't afford and
so the guys with heart they would love
these plants got forced out and the guys
that own car dealerships and own
whatever other random business that it
went to business school and just saw an
opportunity in Colorado they came in and
they're like well I got money and they
bought [ __ ] up and now unfortunately a
lot of those types of folks are who are
running the cannabis industry and the
heart gaps there's doubt there's still a
weird lack of quality in large portions
of the legal market here that lets me
let me wrap up because I want to I
started with Scott reach I gotta give
Scott a shout out and finished that now
Scott owns the most high-tech most
sophisticated most impressive [ __ ]
girl facility in the state of Colorado
that I
ever seen and he is now producing once
again some of the best quality cannabis
in a very large scale and it's available
for retail purchase he does the
wholesale thing so it ends up in
dispensaries so he's back at it now I
just had to be went full circle
I'm starting to see a lot of a lot more
of the the people who were doing it from
their heart finally getting up and
running again
but for a year and a half two years
three years all of them have been
looking for money and the people running
the big production facilities are the
people that have money and not the
people that have talent and that's led
to a lot of like wow solid c-plus right
a million dollar loan oh man I had
somebody like excitedly show me some bud
that was 2.2 percent THC 7.7% CBD like
excitedly like this is on our shelf now
bro and I kind of looked at him and he
kind of looked at me and then he was
like but why are you excited you've been
asking for CBD flower for a while now
and I was like yeah that ain't it though
like I got more CBD like stuck to my oil
slick um sorry like I hate it I hate to
rush you get up above 10 get closer to
if you've got passion and talent and
skill producing marijuana you know what
quality is you've got a passion for
helping share your love of marijuana
with other people it's really time to
bite the bullet and start spending
Mondays at City Council um you're gonna
hate it it's gonna take you two years
I'm of really boring meetings that don't
have anything to do with marijuana and
I've sat through that long public
testimony sessions where one person gets
up and said marijuana is the devil's
lattice is gonna make everybody commit
suicide and then somebody gets up and
say no we're gonna pave the streets with
gold and everybody's gonna get to cute
redheads to go home with and you just
argue back and forth all night long but
if you don't go and there isn't someone
there to make rational arguments to the
people that finally make these decisions
in your area you're gonna wake up one
morning and it's gonna be a two and a
half hour drive to the pot store and
you're gonna have done that to yourself
when you get to that posture that's two
and a half hours away it's gonna be
mediocre quality and twice as expensive
is your old dealer back kind of purchase
limit so that you have to do it once a
damn week instead of once a month yep
and it's gonna be your fault for
skipping out on these meetings and for
hoping that somebody else goes down and
fights for you and that's I mean that's
my takeaway from this election is you
got a yes participate if you do not vote
in this election you cannot [ __ ] about
anything for the next four years that's
why it's something that I want to say
Mike we've been going for a long time so
let's say let's wrap it up if you got
any fun last that's what I'm giving you
the chance for buddy with rate with most
political issues we're talking about
changing what is a little bit we're
gonna raise the age or whatever from
this to that it's just a little tiny
insignificant change we're gonna give
people five more years if they commit
whatever crime most of what we're
changing is already laid out when it
comes to stuff like marijuana
legalization we're changing to a whole
new system
nothing is laid out when you're crafting
stuff for people to vote on how you
write the issue matters once it's passed
in the law and your stay and it passes
by popular vote it that feels like the
win um and it's not that's getting
invited to the game it just feels like a
win and don't get me wrong
boating on legalization as a state is
amazing I remember that feeling in
Colorado I was thinking about it a lot
last night actually but it's very much
the beginning of the game you have not
won yet right now or again I'm seeing
that a huge number of towns cities and
counties band rec sales some of those
are doing it to wait and see some of
them are doing it because they [ __ ]
hate marijuana and they don't understand
whether state legalize it
some of them are doing it because they
want a little more time to finish
crafting the rules but all of them are
doing it because not enough pro-america
lot of people are showing up to meetings
and voicing their support for allowing
legal marijuana the legal marijuana
industry in their area Oregon's a big
legalization state they've been on the
list for a minute now and they've they
they don't have nearly the access we do
here and part of that is because they
don't have the community that we have
here they don't have the activists that
we have here that are fighting for it I
mean for places like Massachusetts
Nevada Maine Florida North Dakota
Arkansas you guys need to start hitting
those meetings you need to figure out
how these rules get made in your area
it's gonna take a lot of time I know a
lot of you should be at work and don't
have time to dedicate to this but that's
kind of how I became me I was the guy
that didn't have work on Monday nights I
was the guy who already had a background
in law and politics and was willing to
bite the bullet and go to a couple of
these meetings I was like eight years
ago I like it's a long fight in it to
get to the
get wherever you are to where we are now
in Colorado it's gonna take people like
me willing to step up and go to the
meetings I'm happy for you guys to hit
me up on social media
ask me for tips and tricks if you're
having trouble finding something out I'm
happy to help him help you research it
you just got to let me know yeah and
more importantly you've got to get out
there and do it how can they reach you
you can the easiest way honestly is
through Facebook um if you send a
message to Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws that will get to me that will get
that will get to my pocket with a nice
notification you can tweet me at NEMA
Punk 15 mainly my twitter was to annoy
prohibitionists online and I have
officially been blocked by all of them
so mainly I just use that for sharing
news stories with the little
Twitterverse troll [ __ ] are a troll
from your heart bro for positive impact
rules but yeah you can get me on either
of those episode I hope we had what you
were hoping for us if we didn't yes yes
if you want to email me if you want more
details I think we went for an hour and
a half here so I love the content I love
that when you come and be on the podcast
a level and you ramble you guys send me
an email if you want to if you want to
hear more about this election if you
want to hear anything about cannabis we
talked about this a minute ago my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com i would love to hear from
you the future is let's see what happens
I'm excited don't mean to paint a bleak
picture no wood I'm ready for whatever
comes I've been born anyway hey I like
change and excitement to be interesting
I'm excited to experience the future
with you whatever happens it's been fun
I love you guys thanks for listening um
yeah oh yeah you got to go to iTunes
that's what you got to do go to
if you got I will stitch your sucks
because it's hard to leave reviews on
stitcher but iTunes is you can go to
iTunes you can go to the iTunes Store
you can search for the girl from your
heart podcast and then you can yeah i'll
turn your mic down so you can take a DAB
and cough search for the girl from your
heart podcast find the podcast you gotta
scroll all the way to the bottom click
on the little icon go to the reviews and
ratings that's rating and reviews go
there so far i've got like 36 positive
reviews was the last time I looked but
go there give me some stars you've got
the option to give me 1 through 5 stars
I am a five-star general I would
appreciate it if you click on 5 stars
I'm not begging for 5 it feels shitty to
ask you for 5 give me what you feel I
deserve but I mean I'm giving you you
know go ahead like your mics back on 5
stars of man I think he's choking and
trying to hype up the show at the same
time I appreciate it so throw some throw
some stars but the best part is type in
the comment let me know what you think
about the show if you love the show type
it in there and let me know what you
think if you hate the show type it in
there let me know what you think if you
think I should go [ __ ] myself
tell me I'll read them on the air I will
read your comments on a future episode
please don't throw me too hard but I
look forward to what you do you type in
there that's gonna be a whole lot of fun
I think that's all I've got for you hey
I'm almost at 10,000 followers on
Instagram I would like it if you help me
get to 10,000 followers my Instagram
account is Irie underscore genetics that
would be awesome
also don't forget to check out my
friends at the dank team dot-com
that's all I've got for you a huge huge
shout out I know you've heard enough
right but huge gigantic thumbs up cheesy
face smiled shout it to everyone who
voted thanks for participating Mike made
this mic turn seriously all thanks for
voting I know uh um a lot of people
voted for a lot of different issues it
matters that everybody got out and voted
thank you be ready for the next election
look I know places and around the u.s.
that are voting again in like four
months no I don't wanna start seeing
political ads again in to it it's it's
small local stuff like county city
election stuff but like there's always
something going on if nothing else in
your area you will have a midterm
election in two years make sure your
friends and family are registered make
sure you're talking about the stuff
that's gonna be on the beach your mom's
registered to vote
my mom did not vote and disappointed
that lady hey you got my still having to
say on your life register divine I drove
an hour and a half each way for two
ballots to make sure that that two
people got their ballots got a chance to
fill them out and then I drove them to a
Dropbox for that's awesome
yep just to make sure that they had a
chance to vote I wasn't there because
they were voting one way or another on
any issue as just I wanted to make sure
they got the chance
it's important that everybody gets that
chance and you should exercise that
right people exercise your rights you
don't have to only exercise the right to
remain silent you got other rights too
you guys with the podcast you've been
going for a long time
I got a piss like you would not believe
I'm over here wiggling around on my
chair it's been an hour and a half I
usually brag about my podcast bladder we
have found my limit we hammered this one
alright for sticking with us yeah Mike
thanks for hanging out you guys make
sure you follow Mike on social media
make sure you follow me on the social
media Big Shot is my ninja Spence and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the drove from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with the fresh new
episode and until next time take a fad
dab and give your mom a hug for me