welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 276 of the grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and
conversations that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic roots ban for
letting me use their music on my podcast
big shout out to Kat ku and the entire
mystic roots crew
thanks again for joining me everybody is
a frosty cold night here in Pueblo
Colorado I hope you are nice and warm or
may be nice and chill wherever you are
what time of year it is wherever you are
wherever you're listening hope you're
having a great time I also hope you got
a big fat dad lined up hope you got a
big fat joint rolled up hope you got the
bong loaded hope you got a blunt rolled
up you got something going on - you get
medicated with me on the podcast I like
to start the show off by telling
everybody what I've been smoking on let
me reach over here and turn down this
music just a little bit more what am i
smoking on today I have been smoking on
some Clementine live resin batter and
I've been taking the dabs of Clementine
I get it on the dabber and I've got this
Gotham high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract it's the crystals the diamonds
it's hard to stick that to the dabber so
I just push a little to the side and
then I stick the Clementine dab dab on
the dabber and then I dip that like a
paintbrush into the crystals and just
pick up enough kind of like just uh to
season a little a little bit there and
then the Gotham crystals of course
tested 96 or 98 percent THC I'm pretty
sure is 96% THC so the Clementine gives
you a great flavor it's a nice head buzz
I doesn't do a lot for me to get me high
but the flavor is great but those Gotham
crystals they really put you in another
place so the Clementine makes it taste
amazing the Gotham gets me super high
really great combo obviously it's got me
in a good mood it's got me chatty so
hopefully it's good podcast dabs thanks
for joining me everybody I hope you're
as lit up as I am ah something I want to
talk about um I've been trying to be a
cheap ass I've been trying to buy cheap
hash usually the hash that I smoke and
I'm not trying to brag or anything I'm
just telling you something that I
realized lately the hash that I smoked
from most of the time the live resins
and the batters depending on where you
go some places have sales some places
have specials it's gonna run you
somewhere between usually thirty five
and fifty maybe sixty dollars a gram for
top-shelf super quality hash the high
cannabinoid full spectrum extracts if
you go to some places it'll be 40
dollars a gram maybe thirty five dollars
a gram sometimes you can find it on sale
for a little bit cheaper but not much
cheaper if you're on the recreational
side it's gonna be harder to find and
it's probably going to be fifty or sixty
dollars maybe seventy or eighty dollars
a gram I don't shop on the recreation
I've got a medical marijuana card but I
know it's way more expensive on that
side of the store what I'm getting at is
um I was trying to be a cheap ass I've
been smoking too much of this expensive
hash I thought what if I go to a
dispensary and I buy some of this cheap
hash they're advertising there was a
shop advertising ten and $15 grams of
shatter and $15 grams alive resin and so
I was like I should go check this out
I'm not gonna say any strain names I'm
not gonna say any brand names I'm not
gonna say any dispensary names but I did
a little bit of shopping just to see if
there was anything out there affordable
bit so that I didn't have to keep buying
these 40 and 50 are grams and dabbing
them all day I was like I'm just gonna
go get some cheap [ __ ] that we can take
some big old fat dabs and just keep
moving
cuz there's something about a big dab I
could take a hundred little dabs and not
get as much effect as I would offer from
one big dab so I like a big dab just
something about the head rush the lung
expansion I enjoy that so I like to be
able to take a big dab occasionally so I
wanted to go find some cheap [ __ ] I was
being a cheap ass I found some $10 grams
they're acceptable for $10 grams I would
have been mad if it was a 15 or $20 gram
I found some $15 grams they're exactly
what you would expect from a $15 gram it
I can tell it was made from trim I can
tell that the material was kind of dry
and old because it tastes like Keith and
it smells like dusty Keith both of these
cheap grams they get me high but I gotta
smoke a lot of it to get any effect from
it like a quarter or a half of the gram
so I guess it was cost-effective but my
complaint is that all of this cheap hash
kind of tastes like [ __ ]
I would rather pay the extra funds and
not have to make this face after I take
my medicine and smoke my dad it's
supposed to be enjoyable when I take a
fat dab it's not supposed to taste like
pesticides or nutrients or funk or mold
or [ __ ]
it should be oh that was oranjee and
delicious or who that was lemony or who
that tastes like OG Kush but a lot of
these cheap dads if they kind of does
taste like boo boo and it's because ah
my theory is that it's because
everybody's making high cannabinoid full
spectrum extracts live resins batters
butters all these other fancy hashes and
the shatter is made from the lowest
cheapest quality trim in most situations
I can't speak for every place I know
if the girl I run we sent we are very
picky about the trim that we send out to
are actually an instruction company sent
us an email saying that they get more
returns and highest tests off of our
hash material because we pick through it
clean out the [ __ ] leaves and we it is
trim we make hash out of the trim
there's a lot of popcorn but in there
that gives it better quality and we
don't spray with any funky [ __ ] we're
mostly switching all the way over to
predator bugs so there's no spray on our
plants now it's all predator so the
plants don't taste like [ __ ] nothing's
funky but some of these other places I'm
shopping some of the other extractions
it's it tastes terrible something's
funky I think they're using the bottom
quality [ __ ] I think they're probably
using problematic buds a joke that I
used to make when hash started getting
real popular again like BHO my joke was
now that we know how to make pho nobody
gets powdery mildew anymore so I think a
lot of the powdery mildew buds that
people grow in Colorado because we have
huge battery mildew problems in Colorado
it's hard to control the indoor
environment when the outdoor environment
changes 30 degrees from day to day it
was 8 o'clock or it was 8 degrees when I
got to work at 8 o'clock today and it
was 32 degrees when I went to lunch at
noon and now it's probably back down
it's dark time it's nighttime
it's probably back down in like the 16
15 degree area so you have to adjust
your HVAC you have to get [ __ ] dialed in
and get humidity that does create a lot
of powdery mildew so I'm sure that a lot
of the products that I bought for cheap
or powdery mildew or some sign up some
sort of pesticide ridden buds that
people just had to get rid of on the
cheap what I'm getting at I know I've
just been ranting for a long time you're
like what the [ __ ] your point here my
point is remember back in the day when
you had the choice of buying what they
called schwag weed or commercial weed or
you could buy people called it kind bud
or there were different words but there
was [ __ ] weed and good weed I was always
the guy trying to convince my friends
quit buying that [ __ ] weed him buy the
good weed my theory is that if I took a
gram of and I'm just gonna be
hypothetical with numbers here if I took
a gram of $15 hash and I took a gram of
$45 hash I think the $45 gram lasts me
three times as long and gets me three
times as medicated and is doesn't it
tastes 3 times better so I feel like I
learned my lesson I tried I spent a few
bucks I didn't waste it because I got
some medicine but you should
the face I made after I took a couple of
these dad's one of them tastes like fish
oil one of them kind of tastes like
broccoli or Brussels sprouts or
something but I think I learned my
lesson quit trying to be a cheap ass and
quit buying the cheapest concentrates I
can buy and stick with what I know and
what I trust but something else that I
was gonna mention is it seems like
Shatter is being pushed out of the
market so that they can make space for
all of the fancy the acronym
concentrates the high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extracts the high terpene
full-spectrum extracts the batter's the
butters and of course some places are
carrying rosen's but I see shatter kind
of becoming kind of the old school stuff
like how a lot of us look at the bubble
hash and stuff like that like the old
hash at the old guys smoked we look at
it like that's hash old guys smoked
pretty soon that's what shatter is gonna
be and I'm gonna be an old guy smoking
shatter it's really interesting to me
the way things come and go from this
industry so quickly now before it was
legal it took a long time for things to
evolve and travel around the world and
around the country if you were doing if
you're doing dads in California before
the internet before legalization it
would have taken years for people in New
York to catch on how to do dad's the
same now with legalization in places now
with the internet you could do a DAB in
California on Facebook live and teach
your buddy in New York exactly how to do
a dad and you guys can teach each other
the same lingo and now you're saying the
same [ __ ] on both coasts both doing dads
all this new [ __ ] is just across the
country instantly and now with
legalization we're able to do so much
more learning so much more testing so
much more R&amp;D and we have are indeed
ourselves up to the top with these
crystals with all these batters and
butters tour we have are indeed
ourselves so quickly that shatter is
becoming an antiquity I think it was
2010-2011 maybe 2009 when I took my
first dab that was my first dab out of a
rig and I'll tell you where that was in
a second but the first time anybody gave
me any BHO was a friend of mine just
gave me a little piece of parchment with
some snuff folded in it and a little
sappy stuff folded up in there and he's
like give that a hit when you get home
and so I went home and I scraped it into
a brand new pipe that had never been
smoked out and I just put it on the bowl
and my doesn't let that shut up and gave
it a hit and I was supposed to go
somewhere and wherever I was supposed to
go I remember just texting
I'm gonna be late cuz I just laid face
down on the couch and I was like holy
[ __ ] I was so high I didn't been that
high that instantly high that fast cuz I
went from I haven't smoked all day I
want to get high - oh [ __ ] I need a nap
and some food and maybe some cartoons
like just instantly so that was my first
time smoking concentrates and that was
I'm gonna say that was not smoking
concentrate smoking BHO made
concentrates I'm gonna say that was 2008
or 2009 because of the person that gave
it to me and where I was and how we were
associated I was involved with met amar
at the dispensary at that time and
that's where I met the guy and I'm
pretty sure that's where I got it so it
was like 2008-2009 is probably when I
started smoking vho and then I told you
I tell you about my first real dab I've
talked about it on this podcast I was at
the um the Denver Medical the Denver
High Times medical cannabis cup at the
Expo Events Center there's a lot of
words in that title because they had to
put medical in there ah at the Cannabis
Cup the High Times Cannabis Cup in
Denver at the expo and the Broadway
wellness booth had a booth set up and
they were giving out dabs and Daniel de
Syal so known as Big D from top-shelf
extracts was giving out dabs and I had
talked to him online we had uh
correspondent through Facebook a few
times we'd never met in person and we
saw each other's faces and I was like
dude you're the guy from the internet
he's like dude you're the guy from the
internet so I walked up and got in line
it took a dad and we introduced each
other and then I bought a dad rig from
Dan that day it was actually one of the
old-school swingarm skillets but I stood
in line and I went up and got my turn I
took a dad and I was like man that was
amazing and he's like this kind of oil
and he told me I don't remember what he
said but I was like I'm gonna come back
and buy one of those and he kind of
looked at me like yep I bet you will cuz
you look like you really like that and
so I thought about it for the next
couple hours I was like should I do it
should I do it I was like [ __ ] I can't
even quit thinking about and I went
bought my first a brick and I still have
it I still have to skill it and I still
have the little dub they call it a cough
less bong it's just a real to beaker
style bong we've got a little beaker
bass and it's just real tall and skinny
it doesn't make you cough it's pretty
nice
then I brought that home and I smoked
dads with little keV and pops and Tony
and probably Mike and myself and I
remember who else was there but I
remember we all took our first eye they
took their first dads in my basement
doing it that 70 show style down in the
basement getting stoned back then and
they think everybody went home and took
a nap I think I called everybody I
texted everybody like four hours later
Isaac what's up and they're all like I
just [ __ ] woke up from a nap dude
that [ __ ] was funny I remember that that
was like 2010 or 2011 when that first
High Times Cannabis Cup came to Colorado
I believe the medical one that wasn't
recreational before we allowed
recreational cannabis so that's the
amount of time it's now 2,000 barely
2018 dad's lasted Shatter lasted like
eight years before it started becoming
the old school [ __ ] it was all the rage
for a minute and now it's like the yeah
maybe we'll smoke some shatter if you
got some but I'd rather smoke all this
other [ __ ] first it's really neat how
it's evolving I've predicted and I don't
know how long this will be I don't know
that we'll actually see this but I think
that eventually you'll be able to go to
maybe it'll be like a budtender slash
pharmacist slash coke dispenser machine
and you'll be like oh I like I like this
much THC this much CBD this much CBG
this much cbn my cannabinoid ratios
now for my terpenes I like this much
trip inyline this much piney all this
much whichever trip I'm gonna talk about
and then your bud tinder or your
pharmacist or the machine that you're
pressing the buttons on and ordering
everything from because it's the future
and everything will be automated you
just type in your your ratios and it
basically has a bunch of it's got those
ingredients in the back and it whips I'm
up for it
it spits it out like a Coke machine and
it's like here's your grandma
concentrate custom-tailored for you it's
perfectly mixed up so that every time
you take a dab you get that perfect this
much THC this much CBD CBD CBN whichever
cannabinoids you're looking for and also
the perfect ratio an amount of terpenes
tor that it tastes perfect for you and
those terpenoids work with the
cannabinoids it'll be your perfect
tailored mix ah maybe you'll have a USB
card that you can stick into a machine
and it can bring up your options that
you've bought before so that you can
have your different variety mixes saved
on that USB card so you can just stick
USB in and it goes oh you need mix
number 3752 will spit it out for your
palm then you could just save it on a
USB you've always got your
your mix right there that it that way it
never changes that's something I not
exactly but that's sort of what I see
coming in the future you will be able to
custom tailor your own concentrate for
your own needs
what kind of mix do you think you would
make you should tweet me tell me tweet
me at GF wih podcast on the tweeter you
can send me a Facebook message or you
can email me it's growth from your heart
at hotmail.com let me know if you can
make up your own custom mix what would
you make do you know what percentage of
which cannabinoid interpreting
terpenoids you would put in there do you
know let me know what you think I would
probably make myself a really high THC
mix with a lot of limonene and lemony
flavored Terps or Beecher pennilyn and
limonene it would be really candy lemony
lemony flavored maybe a lint of orange
so maybe like some pineapple in there
oranges lemons pineapples would be
really like that flavor a super high THC
and it would just make my head spin and
then I would have another one that what
had like a real cushy chem flavor and it
would have something in there would make
me just want to be chilled out kind of
sedated kind of lazy maybe kind of
creative maybe a little bit giggly but I
would have two different opposite kinds
of ends of the spectrum from my uh my
custom-tailored concentrates that's what
I would do alright that's just big hopes
and dreams that's a long time in the
future I hope to see that day and I hope
you guys are there with me man that was
a long fun rant these dads must be
working you guys let's talk about
something more cannabis related how
about a breeding update you guys I keep
telling you about the breeding update
that I'm working on I of course in
breeding with my male its King Solomon
that isn't a rise male it's golden go
across the Daybreaker
I mentioned previously on the show that
around Christmastime or around the new
year I would be pollinating and the
pollination has happened those plants
are all filled with pollen the seeds are
forming the seeds are starting to get
hard I can see them they're large and
green the calyx is are getting swollen
that are obviously seeded the pistils
have curled up the plants are bright
bright green and the pistils are bright
red and the trichomes are developing
they look really good let me look at the
date today we're recording on why can't
I find the date anywhere today is this
the 4th we're recording on January 4th
that means that those plants have been
into flower for a
about 36 days which means they need
about twenty five more days ish to
finish up and then those seeds should be
ready they look really nice I posted one
or two pictures to Instagram so if
you're not following me on Instagram you
should check that out it's i reaiiy rie
underscore GE and ET ICS I read genetics
on Instagram check out my cannabis
photography but I'm super excited about
the Durbin poison cross to arise for
some reason I feel like that's going to
be a really good cross I see a lot of
potential in mating those two also the
star dog I feel like that's gonna be an
amazing cross and also platinum tangi is
in there I'm hoping that's just gonna
make big Spears that smell like oranges
and candy and are just coated in resin
the Platinum tangi is already a great
strain it's just kind of small and I
want to make it bigger and I want to
make something in my own that has that
orange flavor want to have that orange
to my lineup because I love orange
flavored concentrates so I'm really
excited about those three crosses they
should be finished up here toward the
end of January and I'll keep giving you
guys updates and I'll keep posting
pictures all right speaking of strains
that I bred I've got an email from a
listener that starts off by giving me a
compliment and then they asked me to
give advice on growing strains that I
have bred so I'm gonna press pause I'm
gonna take a drink I'm gonna take a
couple of more dabs I might check my
Instagram and then I'm gonna come back
and read this email and talk about
growing strains that I have bred I'll be
right back take a DAB you guys all right
podcast world I am back I am well
medicated I took a dab of some of the
cheap hash I was talking about kind of
taste like ah I don't know maybe cream a
broccoli soup or maybe some creamed corn
had sort of a vegetable E soft smooth
flavor that I don't know proof of
goddammit I bought it got a damn it got
to do something with it
anybody need a dad I got a dad if you
want to take a dad there's some stuff
all right let's get on with the podcast
you guys I told you I was gonna read an
email I printed it out I've got it right
here in my hand I'm gonna read it it
goes like this it says what's up Rasta
Jeff I'm in the Midwest also known as
Prohibition land so you can call me to
the roach which is my dude grows crew
name went up to the roach good to meet
you they call me Rasta Jeff
glad to make friends with anybody from
the dude grows crew on the email goes on
to say I heard of your show from the
guys over at the dude Rose show been
hooked ever since
I've caught up on the majority of your
episodes and I love it hey man thanks
for listening to the podcast I'm glad
I've got you hooked and I'm glad you
love the show he also says I was lucky
enough to take advantage of the Black
Friday sale on your genetics that's
right you guys the hella dank seed bank
did a really great Black Friday sale
they're doing another sale right now
making sure you check them out at dank
seed dot store you can grab yourself
some IRA genetics he says I just popped
some piranha seeds I also picked up some
morning dew and storm shadow my question
is have you ever done a show with
detailed information or tips on growing
said strains thank you for your time and
for the knowledge and entertainment I
will give my mom a big hug for you and
take it to the next level and smoke a
fat dab with her and that sounds good
man you are going above above and beyond
with that one I thanks again to the
roach 8 - the roach thanks for the great
great email that's a really good idea I
have actually thought about doing
podcasts about strains that I've read
but it felt kind of I don't know
self-centered or egotistical or
something spinning a whole podcast
talking about something that I created
but since you asked for it and you
actually sent a list of strains that you
purchased and wanted tips on I've
decided that I will start doing this and
I'll try to get through a few strains
over a few episodes I'll just do one
strain per episode and I'll probably do
I'll space them out pretty far but I did
make a few notes the strain that I chose
to start with is morning dew I probably
would have chosen a rise but since you
sent the email that inspired this and
you said that you had piranhas morning
dew and Storm Shadow
I felt that morning dew would be a good
place to start out of those three and
then we will work our way through a lot
of the other IRA genetics lineup um the
reason I chose morning dew out of those
three is because it's got the Grateful
dog which was kind of my debut strain
that was one of the first strains that I
released I had made plenty before that
but I never put anything out The
Grateful dog was the thing that I passed
out I gave a bunch of pack to those away
at the cannabis cups in Denver the first
one that was at the the Denver Mart
outdoors I just walked around and gave
tons of five packs of seeds away to
people I gave away the heart of
and I gave away the grateful dog and the
grateful dog was a hit people seemed to
really love the grateful dog the
genetics of the grateful dog is of
course the chem 91 also known as the s
BK cut cross to San Fernando Valley og
cush it's also known as the deadhead OG
but it's a little bit inbred and kind of
worked a little bit so it's the Grateful
dog FEM C because I put it out an only a
feminized version and that was crossed
to the arise which is golden goat
crossed a day breaker and I know I'm
breaking down the family tree kind of
far but I like to do that because it
explains why plants grow the way that
they do and what traits you're looking
for the golden goat of course is Island
sweet skunk Hawaiian and Romulan so
that's where you get that tropical
flavor from then Hawaiian gives it the
tropical flavor the island sweet skunk
of course gives it that sweet tangy
thing and then the Romulan is what makes
it grow so well I think the combination
of those made a really great combo the
Hawaiian probably gives it the sativa
punch that it's got I think the golden
goat is a great strain and then I bred
that to the day breaker I used to day
break or mail day breaker of course is
CEM D crossed to the Joseph og the Kim D
female was pollinated by a male known as
Joseph og Joseph og is an OG Kush male
that day breaker cross was made by our
friends gage Green genetics
I got seeds from gage green I found a
marvelous male and female of the day
breaker in there I made a breaker f2s
that's where the black cherry Kim came
from quite a few great crosses came out
of that batch of breeding but I made the
day break or I made the the arise there
then I took the arise male which is
known as King Solomon and I crossed him
to my grateful dog and the progeny of a
rise cross the grateful dog was known as
morning dew of course that's named after
a Grateful Dead song because it's got
the arise so it's the morning I kind of
thought of and then the grateful dog
which is the Grateful Dead offshoot
named after a Grateful Dead song about
morning dew so I'm fairly proud and was
fairly excited of morning dew because of
course arises as a strain I created
grateful dog was the first rain I
created and now they are put together so
it's kind of a timeline put together to
show a little bit of progress in my
breeding I
and they're two of my best uh best known
products other than the lemon Jeffrey
the Grateful dog in the Arizer probably
and the lemon Jeffrey would be the top
three most popular strains I've made so
it's fun to have them put together now
I've told you a lot about how they were
bred or why they were bred how the names
came about and what they are let's talk
a little bit about growing these plants
what should you expect from morning dew
now keep in mind that morning dew is an
f1 hybrid and there will be Fino typical
variation you will see differences in
your plants but this is basically what I
think will work for every phenotype
although there will be some outliers and
also your conditions your environment
your lights your nutrients all of those
things will play a part in everything
that I'm about to tell you if you have
LEDs or HIDs you may take you a little
bit longer or shorter flowering time if
you're using hydroponics or soilless
mixes it may take you a little longer a
little shorter but here's a basic
guideline and some things that I have
found by running a lot of seeds here are
things that I found you can expect from
morning dew seeds most of them are going
to take you about 55 to 65 days of
flowering to finish usually nine weeks
is just about right morning dew plants
are going to get medium tall and they'll
be kind of bushy if you top it if you
let it grow to about two feet tall and
then take out that main node right out
of the middle then it'll start pushing
out real nice I think it'll Bush out and
get kind of semi medium tall it'll get a
lot of heads that way that will really
increase your production when you do
that it's gonna need some supports right
before you put it into flour don't put
the supports on too early
leave the tomato cage off leave the
sticks off leave the cage off leave the
netting off so that you can put some
fans on it and let these plants blow
around also going there in super crop
stuff so that it gets a little bit
stronger give it the pop and twist I
talked about that on another episode
when you pop it or you grab it and then
you give it a little twist right above
your finger pop and it goes pop makes a
little stronger do that it will like
that but do that stuff before you put
supports on and then right before you
flour it go ahead and put your support
if it's trellising if it's a tomato cage
if it sticks it'll need that in flour
but don't do it too early because you
don't want to make it weak morning dew
is going to produce buds that its own
branches can't support it'll need some
so
two supports if you do it right so it's
gonna be medium tall it's gonna need
some supports I would top it and get it
kind of bushy um let's see I'm trying to
figure out which order we should go in
it's gonna need some cages or some nets
or sticks I think I've talked about that
so now let's talk about it's gonna be
stinky you guys this one is going to be
stinky you're gonna need some carbon
filtration or something if you're gonna
grow this in an apartment or a house
next door to somebody else or in an
illegal state if you're going to grow
morning dew I highly suggest plenty of
carbon filtration maybe something else
around the house that smells good also
that distracts from the smell it's gonna
stink also if you want to increase that
stank-ass aroma in the morning do feed
it some kelp type products it really
likes liquid karma that's one thing I've
noticed it really enjoys liquid Karma
it likes veg bloom products it likes
shine very well so feed it
kelp products and also seems to like the
pH semi low in late flour I've noticed
that it kind of it goes a little better
it goes faster it keeps growing if later
and flower-like around when it starts
purple and out you'll see the morning
dew will start to purple out and change
colors on you maybe lower the pH just a
little bit if you're going six four or
six five already maybe try six three or
six to just go one or two points lower
than you normally would and I've noticed
that the morning dew tends to like the
lower pH another thing I have learned
about the morning dew is that it can use
a little more cal-mag than most of your
plants i wouldn't do i wouldn't increase
the dosage i would increase the
frequency I would just speed if you're
doing cal-mag once a week I would maybe
do cal-mag twice a week maybe add some
epsom salts in there but be careful with
the nutrients because you don't want to
go too hard you don't want to push it
this is an OG Kush kind of a plant going
too hard with the nutrients could cause
you problems don't over water but make
sure you have plenty of water
I think Jorge Jorge Cervantes taught us
we want water to be abundant but not
excessive so if you've got like a three
gallon pot probably pour about half of a
gallon on the top of there and let it
saturate through it's probably gonna
take depending on the size of your plant
day maybe two or three days for that
water to dry up and need water again let
it get fairly dry before you water it
again these plants will enjoy that the
morning dew the grateful dog likes a
little bit of a dry period um cooler
temps will help you bring out the purple
I said that these plants change colors
later in flower
some of them will turn really cool
Purple's lower temps will certainly help
with that that helps with most plants
and the thing I said about the cal-mag
about it wanting a little extra cal-mag
most of your og style plants are going
to want a little more cal-mag it's gonna
give your leaves a really sweet serrated
look they're gonna stand up strong
they're gonna enjoy it
so cooler temps add some cal-mag
unfortunately you guys the morning dew
there are some freak-ass mutant
phenotypes in there they're rare I've
ran a lot of these seeds and I only came
across a few mutants there was one
mutant that was [ __ ] cool it looked
like I had topped it and he drew four
equal tops right away I didn't finish it
because I didn't have room for that
mutant I did not want to see what it did
I couldn't waste space on it it got big
enough to see that it was a freak I went
had to get thrown away it got cold but I
saw that there were a couple other odd
leaf shape plants in there but I
finished a lot of those and I found that
the fat early phenotypes of morning do
have this stank if you've got one with
the broader the leaf the more the stank
it seemed like and if the ones the ones
that got black when they started
finishing the ones that turned real dark
in the leaves almost a black color those
had the stank kind of like an OG Kush
dirty feet sort of make your nose
crinkle up but in a good way sort of
stink but those were also the slower
grower phenotypes they were lankier they
grew a little bit slower but they had
the stink they didn't produce as much
herb they produced uh further space to
golf balls instead of Spears but it was
such good quality herb that it was worth
it so the fat leafed one is gonna be a
smaller producing slower growing plant
but it's gonna put out the stink if you
just want some weed that you can smell
six blocks away when you light a joint
that's the phenotype you're looking for
there is a skinnier leaf phenotype it's
got fairly skinny leaves I'm not sure if
those skinny leaves are coming from the
golden goat or the chem 91 but there's
skinny leaves and you'll see it if you
get
skinny leaf when you ago I think that's
what he's talking about it gets kind of
tall but it makes just long skinny buds
and it's just coated and resin and it's
got that it's got the stink to it but
not this stink like the other phenotypes
do it's got more like the cam with some
sweet going on is what I noticed it was
like cam but it had the golden goat
background is like if you put golden
goat in a jar that had chem dog in it
before but had more it seemed to be more
of the THC dominant planet had more
trichomes it had a better just ahead
ripping high the fatter leafed one was
kind of got you high but it was more
like in the face more like in the
eyeballs but the skinny leaf one it just
made my brain spin around
it had feels like it's got more more of
a THC punch so those are two different
phenotypes you can look for I said
earlier to top him when you taught
morning dew or if you trellis morning
dew out give her plenty of time to
recover because she's kind of a slower
growing plant and you don't want to top
a plant and then put her right into
flower so if you do top her give her
plenty of time to recover from that
let those hormones move back up to the
tops let the hormones decide where
they're gonna be before he flower I say
ten days some people say a week is
enough I would go 10 to 14 days if it
were up to me just let your top to plant
recover before he put it in the flower
and that's a good idea with any strain
but the morning dew sometimes you've got
a slower growing phenotype so make sure
you give it plenty of time to recover
let it stretch back out before you
flower it or you'll just end up with a
bunch of little tiny buds at the top and
that's no fun you want to Cola up there
at the top you want to take good picture
and brag on Instagram so top them let
them recover put some cages or some Nets
or some sticks on them
it can take some bending it can take
some trails sing morning dew is also
very powdery mildew resistant we have
learned we had some plants outdoors not
myself but a friend had some plants
outdoors all of them except the morning
dew got powdery mildew on them over the
last outdoor harvest so that's something
that you can you can think about if
you're gonna grow outdoors and you get
powdery mildew maybe the morning dew is
one that will do well for you it won't
get the powdery mildew it's definitely
one of the faster finishers and it's one
of my most liked chem dog Kimi sort of
scented strains that I've made available
so if you're into something that's got
that chem sort of funk to it it's kind
of got some like dirty feet and sort of
cami and it smells disgust
delicious and I love it it's pungent
it's definitely funky there's hints of
gas in there there's fuel there's funk
there's OG Kush there's chem dog and
then sometimes because if the golden
goat you end up with these like real
sweet tropical tones that mix in with
that there's some great phenotypes in
there so that's a quick breakdown of
morning dew man to the roach that was a
really good email a really good question
I appreciate it I feel like that was a
lot of fun I haven't had the opportunity
to talk about a strain I've bred
it's something I've proud I'm proud of
it's something I've got passionate about
so that was honestly a lot of fun I plan
on doing more episodes about more
strains I'll probably do the three you
asked about first and then we'll branch
off to other stuff but dude I appreciate
that I thank you to the roach I look
forward to your next email and if
anybody else out there has a question or
something they'd like to say I would
love to hear from you you can reach out
to me it's grow from your heart and
hotmail.com maybe I will read your email
on a future episode I really do enjoy
doing the listener generated content all
right and also don't forget the morning
dew seeds are available at dank seed dot
store
all right podcast well this is the part
where I thank you for listening and then
I ask you to follow me on social media I
would appreciate it if you follow me on
Facebook and Twitter just search for the
girl from your heart podcast on Facebook
on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast on
Instagram I use my other company I use I
read genetics on Instagram i RIE
underscore genetics I read genetics on
Instagram and probably at 16 thousand
followers by now I post a lot of great
cannabis photography if you're listening
to this podcast I bet you will like my
Instagram feed if you want to reach out
to me and you're not into the social
media of course you can email me once
again that is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget that I've got a
youtube channel there are about a
hundred and forty old episodes up on
YouTube I am making more I keep telling
you guys that
they're coming if you're paying
attention I'm sure you can see that
they're slowly trickling up there
I just ties up my computer and it takes
a long time to make those it takes a lot
of bandwidth to upload them so they're
going up slowly but they will all get
there eventually I'll get caught up to
276 episodes on YouTube
also don't forget about patreon patreon
is a way for podcast listeners
to support podcast content providers if
you'd like to learn more on how to
support this podcast I invite you to go
to patreon.com/scishow spew have been
contributing four dollars and 20 cents
per month I recently learned that there
was a cannabis advocate who has a
podcast or a news show somewhere and
they encouraged their listeners to go
find another cannabis advocate or
podcast or a show that supported the
legalization of cannabis and contribute
four dollars and 20 cents to that show
and it seems like a few people listened
so thank you guys I appreciate that
patreon.com slash grow from your heart I
think I mentioned it on the last episode
but through patreon contributions I was
able to cover the cost of my website
this year my website I read genetics
Colorado comm is where I host the
podcast it's then uploaded through an
RSS feed to iTunes and stitcher and all
the other podcast services that you
heard on and without that website I
would not be able to host the podcast
for free so I owe a huge thank you to
everybody who contributed to patreon
last year and everyone who is continuing
to contribute to patreon this year
thanks to all the past present and
future contributors to my patreon
campaign I appreciate it
I'm sure everybody else listening to the
podcast appreciates it also because
you're making it free for everybody else
and I appreciate it and you guys if you
can't contribute don't feel bad there
are people who can contribute
I want this podcast to be free but there
are people who feel like they can help
out so say thank you to them
thank you guys we appreciate you I
appreciate you the listeners that can't
contribute they appreciate you all so
big huge things alright ladies and
gentlemen you can tell that my throat's
starting to burn out it's time for
another dab I think I'm gonna wrap up
this podcast I want to give you a huge
shout outs my friend Brett see and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you
[Music]