[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 277 of it
grow from your heart podcast your a
source for cannabis news education and
conversations let's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff wanna thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
animistic leech man to let him use their
music on my podcast big shout out to cat
- and the entire mystic roots crew hey
Mike are you writer of Debra I just gave
Mike a dabble Mike gave himself a DAB
and now he's a purple pink yellow if you
tried to lean into the mic and say some
[ __ ] and all that came out was a homo
wrong they fit the right spots Matt dad
hits the right spots it looks like it
hit you in the face that was one of the
spots welcome to the show Mike we are
hanging out it looks like Mike got beat
up by a dad just now are you good bro
should we leave your mic on or you want
me to turn it back off for a very good
alright alright welcome to the show
so let's start off by since Mike just
took a big dab and is talking welcome to
the show Mike thanks man
do you want to share your social media
with everybody so that they can stalk
you while they listen to your handsome
voice if you want to find me on social
media you can check me out on Twitter at
at Nemo Punk 15 or on Facebook at Pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws yeah I like
to challenge you right after you take it
bad maybe the ribs and lungs are working
we did it feel like the lungs we're
gonna make it through all this or all of
that sentence I can tell you did
congrats you made it made it ladies and
gentlemen welcome to a bonus episode
bonus bonus for putting on another
episode this is a since I numbered at
277 it's gonna have to come out before
Thursday because Thursday I think is 278
if I pay attention to the numbers
correctly so uh happy bonus episode
ladies and gentlemen it's always a good
week when we got two episodes to the
grill from your heart podcast for the
week this would be three because we got
the Thursday show the Monday show and
the bonus white Mike episode woo hey big
shot it's everybody that just hung out
with us on Instagram live if you're not
following an Instagram live I encourage
you to do so go to Instagram and search
for me it's irei rie underscore genetics
check us out you can interact with the
Instagram live feeds I actually wrote
down a couple of notes from the live
feed that will become podcast
material so come good questions yeah
yeah ask some questions leave some
comments and interact with me I do
appreciate the interaction alright I
usually like to start the podcast off by
telling you guys what we're smoking on
mic what did you just take a DAB over
there bro that was some foot loose from
apothecary some foot loose batter that
stuff was stinky oh it's wonderful
that's wonderful he's just lit he's
thinking about ways to describe it and
wonderful as all he's [ __ ] got for us
really nice body hi not a whole lot of
head hi didn't want to get too jumbled
for this week's show but can't go with
no hash that's the truth can - oh I took
a big old fat dab of glue Cinda which is
gorilla glue number four with Lucinda
Williams
it's batter from apothecary when I say
batter it's kind of like it's like you
took off a little piece of cream cheese
or cheesecake I just cut a little bit of
piece of that off and then I like to
smoke the high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract crystals but it's hard to get
them to stay on the dabber so I roll
some of the I just take the dab of the
glue Cinda and just gently roll it
across the sour Joker I can have annoyed
full-spectrum extract and it picks up a
few crystals for me I take a big dab of
that and now it does a really good job I
might was like do you want another dad
before the show does ignite become
[ __ ] good for a minute like I don't
need another dab I want to be cool but
yeah big shout out to our friends at
apothecary for the the quality
concentrates I've also got some this is
called Vishnu when I picked this up out
at stem Beach they took it out of the
original container and put it in this
container for me to ask - feels okay
first they have to send you out in a
childproof container and the other
container is not childproof so I got
this one instead I don't remember maybe
it says on here the name of the company
CRX some cr-x shatter some Vishnu it's
not bad I picked it up over at doctor's
orders at sym Beach shot it's my friends
out there doing good work Mikey looks
like you're gonna say something and you
just change your mind you're like no I'm
over here
alright we covered your social media we
talked about what we're smoking on
ladies and gentlemen if you pay any
attention to the world we're probably a
little bit late but let's talk a little
bit about the announcement that was made
by mr. Jeff Sessions that's that's the
point of the bonus episode folks is a
special show focused around this topic
if you follow cannabis news at all you
definitely heard the news that our
Attorney General Jeff Sessions has
rescinded the Cole memo which gave some
legal protection to recreational
cannabis businesses
in states that have legalized
recreational use cannabis we've said a
lot of things in just a couple of cents
there was a lot of information there
I've got a list of kind of things that
we need to keep in mind will you briefly
explain to us the cola memo because this
all stems from the Cole memo okay so
when Obama took office there was no
federal guidance on state medical
marijuana or reap recreational marijuana
laws we were just sort of operating in
the face of federal law and waiting to
see what happened to pieces of
legislation have evolved since then one
of which is the Cole memo Cole was
Attorney General for a while under Obama
and he wrote a memo basically to all of
his federal attorney general prosecutors
I think there's like 93 or 100 of them
or something around the u.s. saying if
you operate in a district that covers a
legal marijuana state here are some
guidelines for federal enforcement
don't bother wasting money if the
business is following state law instead
focus on diversion out of state
diversion to minors shenanigans with
banking rules and regulations that sort
of thing there were eight points to the
Cole memo you can pull this up if you'd
like but basically it's the the thin
little paper shield the legal marijuana
industry has been using to really thrive
coast to coast it was the federal
document the industry would look to and
point to to say we're doing the best we
can trying to comply with what the feds
want to see out illegal marijuana it's
what states that have passed legal
marijuana have used to kind of guide
their own rules and regulations it's
part of the reason Colorado right now is
really going after the medical market
it's because our legislatures have
decided that
medical marijuana loopholes are feeding
that gray and black market out-of-state
diversion and that's one of the Cole
memo points that really brings down
federal intervention this when stuff's
going out of state and so the Cole memo
was it's literally just that it's a memo
it's not a law that was voted on or
passed it's not part of any official set
of rules it's just an official guideline
basically for the federal enforcement of
marijuana laws couple of bosses talked
and said hey that employee sucks watch
him cuz no note made or there was a note
there's a note between two employees
yeah I mean dude it's but it was it's
not official it wasn't there was a note
I'm not an email kind of well it went
out in a very official way it was
released as how the Obama administration
would choose to spend federal resources
coast-to-coast there's a limited amount
of money that the feds have to do
anything there's a limited number of
people in man-hours and they can't go
after everybody who's breaking every
rule and so they have to pick and choose
and yes it would be easy for states
federal prosecutors to just round up
large numbers of legal marijuana
employees and say like look at me
they're breaking federal law but that
wouldn't be a good use of their time
their man-hours all of that effort money
courtroom time all of that could go to
things like an interstate sex
trafficking ring but instead you went
after the stores that were following
state rules like that's a bad idea it
was just a memo that said don't bother
this is why if you've been listening to
the show for a while especially leading
up to last year's election I really
really really pushed listeners to get
involved get registered to vote start
going to local governance meetings at
least start reading the politics section
of the newspaper
start getting caught up on some of this
stuff because the protections that are
in place for this massive legal
marijuana industry that we're building
coast-to-coast
are not set in stone one of them's a
memo in one of them's an amendment in a
spending bill and we'll talk about that
in a little bit but the Cole memo was
just that it was just a guidance memo
and so we've been expecting people like
me have been expecting our Attorney
General Jeff Sessions to rescind this
for months now he hates marijuana like
most people hate cancer
Jeff Merritt Jeff Sessions hates
marijuana a little bit more than most
people hate cancer you can pull up all
sorts of crazy quotes from him about
marijuana the big one that's making the
rounds right now is good people don't
smoke marijuana that's one of his like
one-liners that he said a couple of
times and has really been picked up and
reposted Colorado is a bad person
so the Cole memo basically said don't
spend money on bothering cannabis
businesses if the business is doing
things legitimately legit let him keep
doing their thing refocus your fund
energy and energy on other things Mike
decided to go with sex trafficking on
the highway yeah
no interstate not on the interstate okay
anyway Mike wants you to clean up the
sex trafficking which makes sense do
that stop busting pot heads work on
prostitution rings and the child slavery
and child sex trafficking that's
terrible
way more harm in that fix that so this
basically protected the marijuana
industry but it wasn't a rule or a law
it was just hey let's not [ __ ] with them
let's spend our money somewhere else
Mike says that there's more to that
we're gonna that we're gonna talk about
in a minute but that is the gist of the
Cole memo that sets us up to go to the
next step of what happened this [ __ ]
named Jeff Sessions gets involved in our
government and then he says no more Cole
memo [ __ ] those weed heads
is that accurate to say that but
basically came out and gave us all of
the you know he used as close to
terminology to that is he's he's allowed
to like I said he really hates cannabis
in all forms for all reasons as far as
he's concerned this is an evil plot
perpetrated
with the goal of destroying America and
he's really invested in reversing
marijuana policy coast-to-coast back to
about 1990 look that's his sweet spot in
marijuana policy no one really wants to
see that other than him and a handful of
hardcore anti pop people right they all
live in the same house so this week he
came out and said we're gonna go ahead
and officially rescind or cancel this
memo and that federal prosecutors will
now go back to following just federal
law as written when it comes to the
enforcement of the Controlled Substances
Act and quote like that was basically
his directive and this had a lot of kind
of immediate effects but not the ones
that the anti-pot crowd has been hoping
for so that's what I've got written is
what happens next the anti pot crowd
hopes that Trump waves a flag the army
comes in they kick down the dispensary
door they arrest us they detain us they
put us in FEMA camps they come to the
grow they clean up I roll a couple of
posts where they're like why isn't the
DEA arresting people yeah from that
crowd and that's that's not at all
what's gonna happen so if you were
wondering if that's what's gonna happen
next
that's not what not yeah what's gonna
happen next this is kind of an attack or
a swipe aimed at investors um
California was just about to just came
online on Monday and I think this
happened Wednesday or Thursday so uh all
of the people who were waiting to see
how the rollout of California's legal
marijuana business went before really
jumping in with both feet
investment-wise have now had somebody
from the federal government say you
might not want to and likely one of the
immediate repercussions of the this move
by attorney general sessions is that
investment in newly emerging marijuana
markets is gonna be a lot slower for
California this is a
especially kind of problematic because
of how their rollout is scheduled to
progress huge amounts of California have
passed bans on legal marijuana
businesses until the state rolls out
rules and regs and spells out what local
municipalities can weigh in on and then
the local area will pass their rules and
then they'll allow the industry and so
we've only hit that first step yet
California said here's what we're gonna
require and that's just now starting to
come online a few areas in California
have already jumped on it and said we're
gonna allow this from day one they've
already got played licensing protocol in
place other areas have decided to wait a
year to before they jump into the
rollout in all of those areas now are
gonna be facing a very different
investment market than they would
otherwise and that's sort of the point
the anti pot group project Sam their
head Kevin Sabet this is what he pushed
for and why he wanted to take some of
the money support out and it looks like
that might have already started to
happen
oh yeah wouldn't you be scared if
they're like hey you're not protected
anymore yes and no that type of money we
didn't have protection now we didn't
really have protection to begin with we
had a memo and honestly folks you guys
work in all sorts of different fields
I'm sure listeners memo means memo
across industries in the same way like
when you get a memo it's it's not like
an update to the official company
employee handbook even it's just a memo
saying like hey quit leaving your lunch
in the fridge for two weeks until it
rots quit playing Nickelback in the trim
room right
no more naps at lunch cuz nobody wakes
up on time that kind of that's memo
worthy kind of guidance and that's what
this was it was a memo it was an
official governmental memo from the
Attorney General of the United States
but
it was still just a memo and so the
amount of protection it gave us was
really minimal it was not at all
permanent and a lot of people like me
have really continued to push the
cannabis community to get involved and
really push our local elected
representatives to move our protections
into something that is permanent we need
to change federal law there's no reason
cannabis should be listed as a Schedule
one narcotic alongside heroin there's no
reason we should have federal
prosecutors worried about marijuana
period if this was legal lots of things
would be better and different but to get
that change made we need mass support
from the public and that's kind of the
other thing that's happening right now
Monday morning legal cannabis wasn't
under attack this memo was in place no
one was talking about it last week jeff
sessions rescinded a whole bunch of
memos rolling back Obama era guidance
policies on a bunch of different stuff
and this wasn't included which kind of
gave California a nice little shot in
the arm but it was never permanent but
neither was like there was no attack
going on and so there was no sense of
urgency to rally support for and in the
couple of days since this announcements
come out and that the Cole memo was
rescinded officially we've seen a huge
amount of galvanization across the
industry from coast to coast there's
been a couple of really cool things that
have happened locally with legislators
from both sides of the aisle Republican
Democrat I mean hardcore Trump voters so
like weights
you said states rights they're jumping
ship and all of a sudden they're willing
to work with people across the aisle who
they didn't want anything to do with on
Monday morning because this is an attack
on something a whole lot of us have come
to see is a great idea in watching
everybody sort of coalesce and come
together has been
really kind of encouraging this week it
has been neat watching everybody post
the [ __ ] sessions videos or a picture of
themselves session for sessions that has
been fun to see that support already
there's a couple of I'm sure there's a
petition or three on change.org already
there are a couple of really easy things
you can do
I noticed the hour slash trees forum on
reddit one of the top posts immediately
was a super easy format page for
figuring out who your local electric
representatives are in the House or the
Senate
how to contact them and then they evey
even gave you a couple of paragraphs if
you're not the type of person who wants
to sit down and write a letter to your
Congressman that gave you a real simple
lesson saying hey Jeff sessions did this
this is unacceptable
I support legalization please do this in
this to keep those protections in place
and then it's autofills in your name
it's super easy to do there's a couple
of different groups that have formed to
help bring out elected reps in different
elected officials at all levels that are
supporting legalization and most of
these people who were four five years
ago couldn't give a [ __ ] it wasn't an
issue on their radar they weren't
willing to talk about it in public and
now they're out front fighting for us
locally in Colorado
this basically means nothing practically
for the industry our industry is
established I'm sure there's plenty of
companies looking for investors to
expand and whatnot but for the most part
we're here and we've been it worked for
a while now so I actually wrote down
that I wouldn't be worried until that
one rogue cop in California starts doing
raids or the DEA starts making waves in
California I completely feel the
California would be first because
they're rolling out new laws so the
media coverage has them in the spotlight
and they are not as well established and
regulated as Colorado that was something
that I had actually written down as a
note well what I mean basically that the
process for in federal enforcement would
be the
Attorney General tells like his
assistant attorney generals to go do it
and then they contact local law
enforcement and start doing it so for
Colorado our US Attorney's name is Bob
Troyer
and he's covers the district of Colorado
is what they call his district and he
came out like five minutes after the
news that this was getting rescinded
saying this means zero change in policy
for his office so the day after this big
announcement came out he expects no
change in what he does every day
and right now one of the things he
doesn't do is mess with legal cannabis
businesses in any way he's happy to
prosecute if somebody says hey this
legal marijuana business is not fully
playing by the rules they're breaking
this ruler that rule he might take
interest then but he's certainly not
taking interest in anybody following but
following the rules to top it off our
state elected Attorney General cynthia
coffman has come out saying not only
this her office not interested about
prosecuting marijuana crimes in Colorado
when it's someone who's following the
rules or illegal business following the
rules she said she's gonna fight the
feds if they come in and try to toy with
this that's pretty awesome yep and this
is someone who during the run-up to
legalization was on board with governor
Hickenlooper saying they're not
comfortable with this decision by
Colorado voters they don't support
legalization they're worried about
possible calm consequences of
legalization and now here we are five
years later having lived with
legalization and these people are out
fighting for us that's one of the things
we didn't have before the Cole memo this
many Americans weren't living with
dispensaries weren't living with late
licensed grows weren't living with I
mean [ __ ] there's 64,000 meed badged
people across Colorado I'm not saying
every single one of them's currently
employed in the legal industry but most
of them are Wyatt's have a badge
they're not cheap then we didn't have
all that and now we do local elected
officials who were really worried about
legalization have now had five years to
see that the marijuana was always there
while we've done is change where adults
buy it and that's been really good for
places like Pueblo I just heated up that
nail and it was ready to hit but you
just brought a good thought to my head
do you think that now the government
excuse me government and law enforcement
now that they see how many people go to
dispensaries do you think they realize
how much black market cannabis was being
bought and sold that's one of the things
that cracks me up about the anti pot
community is they have no concept of
what happened before legalization I mean
out of sight was really out of my it was
known it was happening it just wasn't
but I mean all of it was there the DEA
puts the u.s. buying like sixty forty to
sixty billion dollars worth of marijuana
a year back in like ninety nine two
thousand for that area and it's not like
that markets got any smaller so if you
think of that nationally and you do the
math I was playing with these numbers at
home earlier if you take sixty billion I
in sales annually and you look at
Colorado's market we did 1.2 billion in
one year and it took about sixty four
thousand of us to get that done if you
do the math that works out to around
four million Americans coast-to-coast
who were involved in some level with the
illicit black market for marijuana four
million people I mean it takes a lot of
people to do six to billion dollars
worth of business but it was all just
out of sight it was just two guys
meeting in the back of a parking lot
real quick they're probably old friends
who saw each other on the highway and
stopped to say hello
it doesn't look like a marijuana sale
going down when someone walks into a
dispensary it's pretty clear that
they're there to buy marijuana or at
least to check out what legal marijuana
looks like at the weed store like
there's no question what it is so it's
more visible now but there's certainly
not more
I never go just a look I know people
that do though I'm I've got one foot in
both worlds and so I know a lot of
people who are still nervous about going
to visit a legal dispensary because
their profession would frown on it or
something like something similar but uh
a lot of people people that are paying
attention they see that we have far less
people trying to sell pot locally to
their friends to make site income we see
the benefit of moving all of those sales
into a legal market and no one wants to
go back to what it was like before this
a lot of us growers that were growing
before so much legalization we joke
about oh it's pointless to grow weed at
home now
it doesn't even there's no reason to
grow unless you're growing strictly for
yourself for medical cannabis if he used
to be a black market grower there's no
point in that it's gone cannabis is so
cheap at the dispensary there are so
many different things at the dispensary
there are so many dispensaries but
there's no need for a home black market
grower anymore
you got to wait for him to be there no
need for that just go to the dispensary
the doors open and there pretty girls
working there to go talk to you don't
have to go sit on some dudes couch while
he plays video games and deal with this
dirty dog you don't have to sit in a
parking lot and wait for anybody you
walk into the store some pretty girl
goes hey then she shows you a bunch of
great we need to see all kinds of good
jars of weed do everybody's theory
before we got to see it in practice was
that the taxes that everyone was gonna
win pose we're gonna jack the price up
to the point where the black market
could just easily undercut the legal
market and that work for a minute is
Colorado's market emerged but at this
point in time no one wants to deal with
the hassle I mean you might be able to
save a few bucks on your ounce buying it
from the black market but I mean your
times were some it takes time to call
set that up go over hang out dispensary
weed comes with a couple of other things
yep basically a lot for you a lot for
your basement weed is great nothing
wrong with it dispensary weed comes with
a lab test that lab test includes a
microbial and yeast and contaminant test
that tells you there's nothing
key in that herb it also comes with a
THC potency test that tells you how
strong that herb is it also comes with a
pesticide residual testing to tell you
if there are any pesticides in it if
they find any problems in any of those
tests that batch of cannabis is pulled
and re-examined and Aria reassess what
can be done with that product if he can
be used for concentrates maybe they'll
do that sometimes product is destroyed
because it does not pass these tests for
some people if you have some sort of
lung disease I don't know even know what
a lung disease might be a heart disease
a lung disease a throat disease a mouth
disease an autoimmune disease if you're
compromised in any way that lab test
means a [ __ ] lot to you yep that lab
test is way worth the extra tax you
might pay at the dispensary yep you get
lab testing you get product consistency
you get a selection and a level of
service that's just not possible with
the black-market and the person inside
the dispensary with the gun is a
security guard we've asked him to be
there with a gun right wherever else
you're going to get your herb I don't
know who's got a gun there it's I mean
it's substantially safer the I mean the
black market comes with a number of
really nasty just necessities the every
decision made in the black market is
based on economics period where does the
black market produce the product
wherever it's economical to who handles
the product whoever it's economical to
who moves you know who sells it whoever
it's economical to who does the ID
checks [ __ ] no one no one who pays
taxes no there's no lab testing when
product molds out or gets coated in PM
there's all sorts of stuff that's super
commonplace in the black market to
maintain the highest profit ratio
possible on any product that's produced
in the legal market
marijuana's grown inappropriately zone
parcels of land by people who have
passed background checks before they're
even allowed to apply for the jobs in
the industry we had a Department of
Agriculture
culture inspection yep and the lady was
impressed with my knowledge in the
Department of Agricultural culture
Department of Agriculture rules in our
medical marijuana facility if I taught
the Department of Agriculture lady a few
things and she was quite impressed uh
and it turns out my uh my certification
that I've gotten never expires
I've got like the highest thing you can
get right basically took the class that
the people that work at the Department
of Agriculture take before they go to
inspections it was a really cool little
discovery yeah yeah but there's a lot of
things that come with legalization that
one by one have slowly won over huge
chunks of the public sorry folks I
thought I'd turn that ringer off I think
you turn it back on when he thought you
turned it off um it's not just lab
testing and like where the products
grown or who gets to sell it but voters
finally get a say in all of that like
Colorado's is legal and pervasive of
marijuana market is exists anywhere on
the planet and there's still a majority
of the state whose banned our businesses
yeah a lot of them are starting to
rethink that decision because they've
seen Pueblo and Trinidad in a couple of
other places that have been like
economic punchlines around Colorado for
decades really start to thrive again
because we allow this industry it
brought a new wave of investment to
Southern Colorado and really got us back
on our feet it's really changed around
here in the past couple of years yep
there's uh one of the big anti pop
people put out a list of talking points
to all of his little disciples and one
of them is in Colorado they can't even
find construction workers the passed a
drug test and I always laugh when I see
that because it's wal slightly true I
happen to know a lot about the company
they're talking about and the reason
that company has trouble finding
employees is because they pay their
people [ __ ] and have for decades and
they've always had trouble maintaining
in employment force but right now
Colorado's work force we've got like 2%
2.9 percent or 3 percent unemployment
across the state it's as low as it's
been in forever
the only people still looking for a job
the biggest [ __ ] of
ever met or they just relocated or they
just lost their job for some reason most
of them weren't planning for it because
right now most people are happily
gainfully employed like these numbers
are as low as they've been since I've
lived here yeah it's not like every
business you go to around here you could
be high working at most of the business
around here will require a drug test
like if you drive that way in that way
it's car dealerships all those mechanics
and techs I bet you they get a pee test
yeah I don't know for sure but you would
assume like that's a forward I bet you
Ford piss test they're Texan stuff the
company the more likely it is to do it
because they get huge insurance
discounts for doing so we've got AT&amp;T
downtown I know damn well they pee test
you if they think you're doing something
stupid it's in your contract they could
pee test you whenever they want and
they've done it several of the jobs I
had before what I do now drug tested
Mike this got super random odd you've
got a lot of talking points written down
I want to make sure that you get
everything out do you have anything you
need to to loop around on that paper
because I didn't we do we do back on the
tree so there are two really a couple of
really cool things that have happened
since AG sessions rescinded the Cole
memo and one of those things was in
Pueblo Colorado we've got a county
commissioner named Sal face and this guy
I remember Sal when he was very on the
fence about legal marijuana medical
marijuana rules were just starting to be
thought about this was in like 2007 8 9
he was not at all comfortable with legal
marijuana medical marijuana I'm like a
lot of elected officials at the time he
was raised on anti marijuana propaganda
and we've slowly seen him emerge and
actually become the face of regulation
for a lot of Colorado when people think
marijuana rules in Colorado govern and
government in politics a lot of times
South who they think of the Pueblo
County Commissioners were sort of
the first set of small government people
to really get into rulemaking and I like
I remember this guy when he was against
his so it's really fun to see how much
he's evolved mainly just having to see
it all like I remember begging him to go
check out a dispensary for the first
time along with his fellow commissioners
and him just shaking my head shaking his
head at me but Friday after this news
broke Sal arranged a conference call
with a hundred elected officials from
all across the US and legal marijuana
States kind of getting everybody
galvanized and on the same page to fight
this and that was really huge
I love seeing stuff like that and
there's been a couple of those incidents
in the last two or three days where
honestly folks if you follow the press
on this you're gonna have an awesome
week this week one of the other really
cool things that happened is the very
next day
Vermont their Statehouse is discussing
legalization it looks like Vermont might
be I think the first if not the first
one of the first states to pass legal
marijuana recreational adult use no
medical card needed legalization by vote
of elected representatives in state
government rather than by a vote of the
people I'm just average voters the House
voted it yep so they're their House of
Representatives voted to approve home
grow in legal possession limits I think
it's to plants and flower in an ounce
possession limit if I remember right
they did that difference or the day of
this announcement they voted after the
new this news came out and they voted in
favor of legalization which I thought
was really cool I love that that's still
happening it's not a done deal in
Vermont they're Senate still needs to
vote in favor and then their governor
would need to sign that into law both of
the both their Senate and the governor
have mentioned or come out in favor of
this law it's not it's a dial back
version of one that was debated
got very close to passage last year and
so it looks good for Vermont my fingers
are crossed from Vermont we got an email
from a listener in Vermont who made sure
I was privy to this information and he
said I'm pulling up his email he said
white Mike may have hooked you up with
this knowledge already but just in case
he hasn't and then he sent me a good
link to it he sent me a good article so
thanks for that my friend I just wanted
to make sure that I mentioned that one
of our friends we have listeners in
Vermont dude awesome Vermont Rhode
Island we've gotten emails from I have a
question for our Vermont listeners if
you're in Vermont okay so here's my
question
I think the publication is called like
VT Diggler it appears to be a newspaper
it might just be a website for people in
recovery I can't tell the difference
from their online presence but they've
been doing a lot of op eds for and
against legal marijuana tweet me and
tell me what the hell that is would you
please like is it a newspaper or is it
just like an anti pot group website or
what is it so what's it called I think
it's called VT Diggler VT Diggler that
sounds like a troll page right I might
be this their logos weird it's like
letters inside diamonds inside circles
or some [ __ ] and so it's kind of yeah
and it's from Vermont well it's VT
Diggler is the Vermont Diggler and I'd
like to apologize to the people of
Vermont
one of our local anti-pot cooks is
started traveling to Vermont I'm some
anti pot group out there is flying her
out to spread her brand of [ __ ] eree
and I apologize for that that's
something we let export from our area
that yeah it's not pleasant sorry for
that this email also says that if all
goes according to plan this would mean
all states touching New York would have
some form of decriminalization with PA
being the exception PA gonna take a
while one of the other things I wanted
to roll back to is the Cole memo only
gave you know what little protection ur
did VY provided to recreational
marijuana it did absolutely nothing for
medical and there's substantially more
medical marijuana
and there are recreational the piece of
federal legislation that governs medical
marijuana States and this is important
guys so I grabbed a pen and a sticky pad
you're gonna sneeze me I've got like
half a sneeze cookin if you start sneeze
and I'll start ranting about something I
don't have okay so everybody's got their
pen this is called the Rohrbacher blue
Meyer Amendment and it's amendment to
the Omnibus spending the bill basically
the federal budget every year that's the
document that gives protection to
medical marijuana businesses saying that
feds can't spend money to target medical
marijuana businesses employees patients
that are operating in accordance with
state law it's substantially more
protection than we had with the Cole
memo and it's in jeopardy right now also
sessions can't do dick with this on his
own this is up to your elected House and
Senate members so please please please
hop online in Google who is my elected
representative it will take you to a
website where it asks you to punch in
your area code you punch in your area
code and it kicks you right to their
page your representative is blah blah
blah here's how you contact them click
on those links follow those links please
contact your elected representatives and
urge them to support the grower
Rohrbacher blue mayer amendment to the
spending bill the protections for
medical marijuana businesses these were
just extended for a couple of couple
weeks or two months I think
and that window is about up when the
federal budget extension was just passed
if you follow federal news you know what
I just said
if you don't basically the federal
budget was set to expire they haven't
passed the new budget and so they had to
a vote to extend the old budget and that
extended these protections which were
included in the old budget but until
they are officially included in the new
budget and that new budget is passed by
a vote of the House and the Senate
that's not official yet
so we need to urge support for both of
these from both sides of the aisle call
your elected officials email them tweet
them they know what the Rohrbacher blue
Meyer amendment is urge support please
we need these protections I know you're
not the guy to ask this question but can
you spell that for people so that they
can get it good just enough to get
Google started okay so Rohrbacher and
blue Meyer are named for the two people
who wrote it it used to be the
Rohrbacher far amendment its Rohrbacher
roh are a BAC h ER and then blue mayer
is BL um e and a u e are i think i did
their names down real quick from the
press was furiously taking notes before
that should get you close enough in
google um if you google federal medical
marijuana protection amendment it should
come up to in all of those words really
easier to spell than Rohrbacher or blue
mayer a lot of these folks are probably
in a cubicle or cutting concrete or in a
garden so getting them to do that right
now we're gonna have to kind of just
hand it right to them or it might not
happen what's the time post
41:52 but there will be editing all
right go to about 3540 minutes and hit
play and hopefully you can get that
piece that you need to google to find
your local rep there you go get a hold
of them play that into Siri or Alexa
alright looks like you got checking my
notes to make sure that we make sure you
get everything out cuz you did a lot of
homework over there fine I want to make
sure we get it all put into the show for
you I don't want to waste your material
to put all that stuff together by the
way thanks man
I I've been following the story really
closely oh yeah when this announcement
came out I was like we got it honestly
people were telling me on Instagram and
on Facebook wins Mike coming over you
got to get Mike over for this episode of
Mike on what are you guys doing what's
the talks Mike and I feel bad to kick
this back we're gonna do it Friday I had
to push it back don't feel me doing
Saturday I had to push it back I know
exactly so and children first both the
kids first up family first always yeah
specially when it's the little ones this
is a really important topic and honestly
this is a really
kind of pivotal moment in history like
politics exists on a pendulum if you
look the longer look you take down the
historical timeline the clearer this
gets um things go liberal then things go
conservative the roaring 20s and all the
liberalism and drinking and dancing and
the sexual revolution that took place in
the 20s was completely crushed by the
crash markets or the stock market crash
in the 1930s and 40s
everything reversed hard and we've seen
that a couple of times historically this
the sixties gave us the [ __ ] 80s
quick hit like disco is responsible for
shoulder pads and suits for women all
through the 80s I think marijuana has
been moving forward as a social policy
in a major way since 1999 all movements
been towards legalization there's bound
to be at least an effort in a back swing
and that's needed before the
galvanization of the country and we
decided that no as a group we're not
going to go back to that and we actually
take the next big step forward and start
changing federal law and it looks like
this idiotic move by sessions might have
actually triggered that avalanche
there's a couple of different people
talking about this that I mean man on
Monday this wasn't a major talking point
already the people who were mumbling
about maybe running against Trump in
2020 are talking about legal marijuana
protections Denver Republicans that were
in contested races right now going into
the next election cycle first statewide
elections are pissed because now their
option is come out against something the
Trump administration is doing ie their
own parties doing and maybe piss off
their base or come out for marijuana and
seem like a liberal druggie
and that's not a conversation they
wanted to have going into the next round
of elections and now that's the
conversation they're all having good
stir that [ __ ] up yep
if you're the donating type hop online
find your representatives that are
really supporting of this and send them
one of those $4 20 cent donations let
them know exactly why they're getting a
few bucks from you who who said that who
set that for to learn 20 cent donation
thing up honestly I can't remember if it
was like Russ Belleville or Tom angle or
just some putts at high times like it
could have been anybody
that's been going for a few months in
it's not just you that have started to
get a handful of those elected
representatives for months have been
getting discovered on account my patreon
account for the girl from her podcast
but I want to spread some love also if
you had to recommend one cannabis um
support group or somebody that needed
some funding where would you send $4.20
to right now if you could pick one group
he went silent and started staring at
that's not an easy question because
there's a lot of groups doing a lot of
good work on different fronts okay like
if I was only gonna make one political
donation period it wouldn't be for pot I
which is kind of [ __ ] up to say on
this show but it would go not
everything's pots not everything but if
I was gonna make one marijuana focused
contribution right now it would be one
or two places I think I would either go
for normal they're the oldest said the
longest they're the strongest they're
the most organized and the best
represented it's hard to go wrong with
normal and I would go for Gavin Newsome
if you're from the California area are
you follow politics you know who that
man is
and his next couple of years look really
interesting
and we don't have stronger ally in
politics at his level right now open on
the new I'm gonna go I'm gonna choose
normal if you guys are gonna throw down
a contribution and it's not going to be
the girl from your heart podcast patreon
go support normal the National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws
there's no RM right there so old that
you see normal on is it it's teaches
sure and the nice dreams show is it nice
dreams the Cheech and Chong one of the
old Cheech and Chong movies cheese's
normals been around five since the
seventies yeah and teaches wearing the
shirt proudly they go to the dudes
greenhouse where the lizard guy has
grown the weed he's wearing the [ __ ]
normal shirt Thera bro so that's how
long it all has been around the most
have been around a very long time and no
normal no this show no conversations
like this habits right I remember a long
time ago when I was reading High Times
and all that stuff just being a young
weed head not knowing what I was even
starting to get into
I knew that normal was the way to go so
I'm glad that you say to normal if
you're gonna send a contribution
somewhere you've already contributed to
my show or you want to spread some love
in other direction
go support your your local normal may be
the way to go if you've got a local
normal chapter go check them out
then if this is a story you want a lot
more information on hey I'm sure we'll
do it news updates as this develops
because this is definitely it's not the
first move in a dance it's it's a move
in a dance that's been going on for
decades so there will definitely be
updates on this show and updates on
pueblos for sensible cannabis Louis yeah
this is gonna be on going until all 50
states are legal and it's federally
federally legal sorry I just take a DAB
all Mike goes ranting I took a DAB with
a sour Joker I went in a little deeper
than I wanted to life raft yeah I hope
we covered all the bases this apothecary
is pretty wonderful if we skip the piece
feel free to tweet me it's at nema 1-15
or at grill from your heart podcast yeah
if you've got any input that you would
like us to mention on the show send me
an email let's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com we'd like your input on this
podcast it's a little bonus episode for
you so you're welcome I hope you enjoy
it also folks it it's so cold lately
that it's hard to think like this even
for us whew
reminding folks but spring be a-coming
let's start to getting start it's time
to start planning those projects for
next year um start looking ahead to what
you want to do if you're gonna do a
garden and if you've got questions on
that path Edison emails we've got time
to get you your show before it's past
time to get that done that's right
and this was not a plan but Mike since
you're pitching spring an outdoor season
coming up make sure you visit my friends
at the hell a dank seed bank it Banksy
dot store needs you know one thing does
fires it was pointed out to me I didn't
go Google this I didn't search this
somebody on a live feed pointed out to
me that if the hell it ain't seed bank
they have a top ten strains seven of the
top ten are either genetics
booyakasha uh I do a couple of things I
don't want to get into another kinda
step your [ __ ] up but uh I take pride in
my things I put my face on everything
it's me there's not it's a little more
stable than a lot of people are throwing
out too well that's not I was gonna
leave it at my first statement and you
started to elaborate the different
direction that I meant hey Mike thanks
for coming and hanging out dude somebody
has somebody today asked for longer
episodes so that's 50 minutes long so we
love you thank you for the support um
man you got anything else to say I'm
gonna start doing that closing stuff
Mike just rolled his eyes and looked at
the sky again is there a dry erase board
hanging from the ceiling I can't see no
I'm just scratching through the one on
my head it's this is uh I mean this is a
big story with a lot of implications I
want to make sure we hit all the bases
um a lot of people are freaking out like
some marijuana to stocks which were
ashamed of investment anyway took a big
crash after this announcement but I've
already fully rebounded cuz it took a
minute for everybody to remember like oh
yeah they call it the comb memo because
it was just a memo and that in reality
nothing has changed since nothing I go
to work every day it's all the same
alright ladies and gentlemen thank you
for listening to our long rambling
podcast hash tag they like it when we
ramble make sure that you support in the
podcast follow us on Facebook
simply search for the door make our
podcast go to
it's @g fyh podcast I would appreciate
it if you follow me on Instagram that
way you can check out my live Instagram
feeds it's Irie underscore genetics
ireia RIE yes that's Irie Irie
underscore genetics on Instagram go
check out my high quality cannabis
photography also don't forget there's a
growth from your heart podcast YouTube
channel where you can watch the videos
of the old podcasts about a hundred and
forty episodes are up there now I'm
posting more over time just takes a
little bit if you'd like to interact
with me and you're not into all the
social media stuff send me an email it's
a girl from your heart at hotmail com
you know I love listener emails I spoke
about it earlier I'll remind you once
again don't forget about patreon if you
like this P this podcast was worth a
couple bucks and you'd like to
contribute you can go to
patreon.com/scishow is you press in
there so just keep typing I will see
what the limit is we'll see if we can
blow that patreon up but I would
appreciate it if you support me on
patreon what that does is help me cover
the cost of my website it helps me buy
these little hey Mike I try not to but
sometimes I spit into the microphone
cover you think it doesn't smell it's
whatever you ate last time do you
remember the orange one that was here
for like the first four months that was
another guy the creepy mustache guy
haunts he used to spit into it a lot
it's yeah whenever we break the
microphones out I do a tentative kind of
sniff test yeah before I get up on the
other side of the recording equipment I
keep them over there and when people
leave I just pop them out and there's a
reason this show sounds as good as it
does folks and it's because Jeff's got
some nice equipment and sometimes pieces
that equipment eat it eat themselves
we haven't [ __ ] headphone amplifier
we yeah we went through had to go to
Guitar Center and get an upgrade
eventually they looked at me like what
are you doing to them they'd see your
van pulling and just get one here's two
just take two this time and when they
break bring them back so though you've
got a backup already I just upgraded
pieces that's all but yeah sometimes
[ __ ] does go wrong sometimes things
break I pay for high-speed internet
because uploading these large shows my
devices don't like hash I don't I don't
know why they fight so much I
had my iphone on my computer are you can
stick them all to the wall and use it as
a desk but yeah the patreon campaign you
guys I use it to pay for the website the
website does cost quite a bit of money
every year to cover so your patreon
contributions will cover the cost of my
website you guys were kind enough to
cover the website for me in 2017 so huge
thank you
it does cost a little chunk of money to
pay for the domain name and pay for all
the hosting I pay for a lot of bandwidth
because I use a lot of bandwidth on that
[ __ ] website every episode is
available like the last hundred episodes
I think it's available that cost a
little bit to host but thank you you
guys covered it I appreciate it so
that's what I do with the patreon funds
sorry I'm trying to clear my throat
while I talk took a big old AB it's
catching up with me patreon.com slash
girl from your heart see how many nines
you can put the challenge is on
alright ladies no but no I don't want to
get rich from podcasting I I love doing
the pie if I do get rich from podcasting
[ __ ] yeah but that was never my goal I
honestly how it started I was sitting
not how but part of how it started was I
used to hang out with Maddy and Spence
at their house and people would come
through all the time and we'd smoke and
hang out and dab and the people would be
like Rasta Jeff told me this about
plants help me grow and I would say it
and they would leave and then somebody
would come over and ask the same damn
question and mani and Spencer look at me
like are you gonna say the same damn
[ __ ] I don't but he asked me the same
question and I was like you know what I
should do I should record this [ __ ] and
then it all clicked in my head I was
like you should record this [ __ ] like I
really guy was like yeah yeah yeah get a
microphone record it make a podcast I
was already doing a podcast with another
guy about other totally non cannabis
related stuff and I was like we're just
[ __ ] start recording and do a show
about it I'm so glad that clicked in
your head yeah yeah well that's kind of
yeah so glad it happened if listeners if
you've got other news stories or other
topics you want us to cover shoot us an
email I don't know if I'll do this many
notes for your question but we'll try to
knock it out of the board for you I
guess I feel like you've been rambling a
long time about patreon or about
starting a podcast
Mike let's wrap up this show send you
home and go hang out the kid eat that
fancy food you got coming your way got
some good delivery coming yeah thanks
for hanging out with this Mike yeah man
thanks thanks for having me listeners
thank you for listening if you made it
this far I love you they all made it
this far I want to thank everybody for
again for listening
I wanna give a huge shout-out to my
friend Matthew Evans and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
it's absolutely