oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house yeah
what's up podcast world it's Thursday
and that means it's time for another
throwback Thursday episode to grow from
your heart podcast before we get to the
old episodes let me make a quick
disclaimer if I mention any advertising
any giveaways any promotions or any
contests all of that stuff has expired
there are no advertisements promotions
giveaways or contests that are valid in
these old episodes I want to thank you
guys for listening and with no further
ado here's a block of old episodes of
the girl from your heart podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 166 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated Babur if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jephunneh
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I wanna give a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots been flooding use their music on
my podcast
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew also congratulations
on that's coming up soon the entire
intro is welcome back to the show hey
thanks for driving all the way from
Colorado Springs to puebla oh my god
I did not we're doing it at the home
studio everything works beautifully I
love it it's great thank you for coming
granny brought an Easter basket filled
with turps hash everybody at the table
got a gift people that are not at the
table that are gonna be here later got
gifts she's got green crack terpenes she
has got sleeping monkey hash there is
some Panama punch on the table there's
salut dream
[Music]
I was gifted a sweet new pencil dabber
from our friend tater glass it is a UV
reactive it's clear it's UV reactive on
one in it has got like a cobalt baby
blue which is actually honestly one of
my favorite colors about me it's also
already in there Easter basket full of
treats
granny's basket I love it for coming all
the way from Lindsay blaster Co on
Instagram because he has started making
glass gnome carb caps yeah I'm starting
to dabble in the glass yeah dude you are
a hell of an artist you were a tattooist
before I knew you yeah I've been doing
art for do a lot of stuff clay sculpting
so glass is kind of like second nature
was really fun really interesting you're
doing I've seen excelling quickly so
good work
[Music]
all right let's do a podcast you guys
today is cause for celebration we should
all just gonna say we should all take
your debut guys take your dab I'll keep
talking today is the damn in granny's
one-year anniversary yes
I find it quite amazing that you have
come this far in one year
how many Instagram followers have you
got this morning it was two hundred and
fifteen thousand you didn't hear the
microphone smack against my forehead let
me do it a little harder yes almost back
to ten thousand I would give myself
credit for twenty five thousand
followers you know what I'm saying but
it's not just it's people from all over
the world yeah when I was doing the
periscope I did a gram dab first
celebration come on watch me on
periscope did you see the person came in
from Russia talking you know we're so
glad Trump is the president you know if
there would have been world war if
Hillary and I was like I know your
leader really felt that way and okay but
I think it's amazing that people from
Russia come to yeah that is pretty
amazing so you take a gram dab at 4:20
here it is 8:20 your video this morning
when you were talking about you were
excited to come be on the podcast that
was early this morning that's when you
replied to one of my Instagram messages
yep yep so it should this lady get bad
you guys she could keep up with you she
can probably out dab you she probably
has more chirps and better Terps than
you do she should open gifts too you
can't beat that it's a one-year are you
on YouTube I am on YouTube I don't have
a huge following on YouTube but I have a
very loyal following but it's like
granny's reality TV they ask a lot of
questions about my family and stuff so
they know that I've evolved and I don't
have an hour every morning to wake and
bake so if I do a YouTube once a week
they're happy to have my low presence
there
I just find it incredible can they find
you can my listeners find you just by
searching for dabbing granny yeah I
think it's dabbing on most of my social
medias are dabbing underscore granny all
right so I was on YouTube
periscope Instagram Facebook and I know
I'm liking Facebook again and people are
finding me I like that live-streaming
I like the intimacy of Facebook like
periscope my room fills up pretty
quickly a couple hundred people real
quickly Facebook might be 1015 people
okay and we can have nice conversations
I don't you know the people on Facebook
is what I like better about the Facebook
why don't ya okay I know more people on
periscope I've been doing it long I only
have facebook friends on my facebook
account it's mostly people that I know
personally that I've hung out with so
when I go Facebook live it's all my bros
it's these guys so that's a lot of fun
no not for me happy one-year look at my
friend the traveling she's got a nice
chunky dab there she's throwing a carb
cap on she's hitting the sweet rig from
our friends at elevate glass big shout
out to tour friend Becca and everybody
over at elevate glass all the lovely
elevate dolls I'm gonna share a secret
about the traveling stoner and I for
breast cancer month one of the most
painful things I've been through in a
while ladies their nipples pierced to
raise awareness for breast cancer you
guys that is some dedication these are
some badass women this is true I didn't
do it for like oh let's go get a tattoo
or a piercing that's the way I thought
about it because I know some people that
had breast cancer and I thought its
breast cancer awareness month and
somebody shared some stories with me and
I thought you know what if you have
breast cancer and you're going through
chemotherapy God daring life probably
sucks and every day is battle
just having your mammogram uncomfortable
experience or no I didn't want to get
that - I mean really I didn't and I will
share something personal
I've been married to my husband for over
40 years
almost 45 I know my husband very well I
knew he would not prove some of you or
be like cool but wouldn't every man like
their woman's nipples pierced
no my husband is very conservative about
your battle so I didn't tell him he knew
I was hanging out with Lindsay he knew
what was going on
but I did not tell him and I thought if
I tell him immediately he'll say take
him out so I waited a few days and he
knows how bad a piercing hurts so this
is how I told him he was sitting in his
chair and I had fun band-aids didn't I
travelling stoner okay so I put on I had
little brown sad face emoji and AIDS and
was kinda graphic but the round part
fits over a woman's areola perfectly and
so he was sitting in his chair and I
said I have something to tell you and he
said what oh my god I know you're not
gonna like it and he was like what did
you do now she and I lifted my shirt
there was them - sad faces looking at
get up and he said you are not 25 years
old like those kids you're hanging out
with I said
it was to raise breast cancer awareness
he said I don't wanna hear your
rationalization no I don't like it but
kind of cute wait too fast the other day
I was putting on a onesie really fast
and I was almost healed and it was like
360 I was gonna mention like you put a
lot of your life out there aren't you
like don't you want to keep anything to
yourself but I don't even need to ask
that question because everything's been
a learning experience and I'll share it
with you and hopefully you'll learn if I
did I was young and dumb once I did some
stupid things that young and dumb people
do dumb not dumb and I'll share that
with you hopefully you'll learn from the
things I say because they do have a lot
of experience behind me I'll try to
learn exactly what I do I completely do
yeah I find well being a podcaster and I
also used to put myself on periscope a
lot I don't seem to be I don't like
sitting down as much I like to be on my
feet doing [ __ ] periscope makes me feel
like I get anxious for some reason after
work right thirty minutes and I'm like
oh [ __ ] I only meant to spend five
minutes here time does get away quickly
wise but putting that much of myself out
I'm accountable for what I say I can't
fit at all because however many
listeners were listening listened and
it's on record and the pod every episode
is available like I've said before I'm
gonna sort put
old episodes even learned that the power
of your words you really sometimes have
to stop and think I because people take
things literally I'm really lucky that I
had a starter podcast I had another
friend that had kind of a comedy slash
community based podcast shot - wait
really you guys check out wait really
he's a comedian
we had a podcast together and I kind of
got to be his co-host so I got to see a
couple of dumb things on episodes and
realize oh I can't see that kind of dumb
[ __ ] like you have to figure it out but
that's how I learned was by it [ __ ]
it up that's why I was laughing when I
said I'll try to learn from you but I
mean the way I learned I have to fall in
crash that sucked because so many people
do watch me we have to be and you said
something on your social media this
morning about when you become as known
as you are you I've you way more than
myself but everybody this table has a
little bit of notice but you've got when
you get to your level of instant
celebrity it's slightly instafamous
you've got to pay attention to what you
say who you talk to and what you share
yes yes it's so much easier to get
caught up in [ __ ] when you've got
250,000 people in your hair oh just in
our cannabis community along absolutely
I catch myself in it catch myself
everybody's choosing sides all the time
in this industry and it seems like we're
all just a bunch of potheads having fun
but that's how it should be backstabbing
I don't have time for pettiness no no
we're getting too old these kids are too
old for that [ __ ] too already and I
think I think all these young people
will learn don't get just Jeff maybe you
said something shitty about Bobo Blaster
over there you know that was me granny
you know he's just a rotten person well
I'm learning that some of these kids
will take what you said to hurt boba
blaster over there might be damn good
person but you have a personal I've been
down because some girl you liked he
liked you he said she know that [ __ ]
messing up his glass business and taking
money off of their time just you know
so unless somebody's done me wrong you
can you can gossip and and talk about
somebody all you want
rest assured granny is not gonna listen
to your [ __ ] I'm old enough and wise
enough to make my own decisions about
people you told me earlier you just
trust your gut usually is a pretty good
judge of what I shouldn't do with other
folks
I think Lindsay's the same way secrets
don't make friends you guys which
happens to me a DAB so I'm gonna grab
the email here and I'm gonna take a -
did you just give us some turps therapy
some turkey Slurpee I am in that's why
they called it turkey Slurpee yeah
these lovely ladies the dab and granny
and the lovely traveling stoner here
they came because they are going to do a
food drive / new toy drive new toys you
guys new toys in packages or kids will
give you an age range I'll let these
ladies handle it while I take this stab
but would one of you ladies like to tell
me all about your food and toy drive go
ahead you talk for a while okay so we
have set up a food and toy drive here in
Colorado Springs so far we have 17
different places as drop-off points and
at each of those locations you'll be
able to get some sort of special like
deal or offer something for bringing in
either a canned food excuse me a non
expired canned food or non-perishable
canned food right something y'all would
eat no expired garbanzo beans and if you
like garbanzo beans I'm sorry
or like Jeff said a brand new toy in a
packaging any age rage honestly we don't
know we don't care you know a toys a toy
we're not gonna no we're not gonna put a
limit on it like that but yeah if you
bring in an item - one of the one of the
places that we'll list off you can get a
and each place is doing something
different so
you'll have to ask the specific place
what they're going to you know do for it
but we will will have a flier and
everything for it that will be posting
and stuff with each place that we have
so we have 17 places right now confirmed
and we have three spots open four places
yeah we decided to keep it at 20 cuz we
are going to be the ones that will be
going by the dispensaries picking stuff
up I have a warehouse to store things in
until we distribute them and I think we
picked a good organization you know we
wanted we wanted to somehow keep it in
the cannabis community but this year on
such short notice that's just not going
to happen so what we have decided to do
is I got into contact with the Marian
house and the Marian house is down on
Bijou and they feed and they clothe a
lot of our homeless community and to me
that's a lot of veterans it's also a lot
of young people moving here because of
cannabis um you see a lot of young
people down there yes so I reached out
to them they will be happy to take
anything we have and then there's second
organization that under the Marian house
is called the Family Resource Center and
they deal with families that are totally
displaced homeless families that they're
getting set up in apartments and stuff
and these are why we're saying we'll
take toys because there's children
involved in most of these cases and so
that's why we decided you know so many
people think oh people that smoke
cannabis they're bad they don't do
anything well guess what you're wrong we
love giving back to our community yes
and we want to start small this year we
just want to do it in Colorado Springs
but we're hoping to have a really big
turnout this year and be able to make it
into something even bigger for next year
whether that means we stay in the
springs and just make it bigger next
year or we you know try to do something
even bigger but we're really excited
about this and the different plate do
you want to list off the different
places that we have I'm just gonna throw
one more thing in there now we'd at
first we were just going to do
we had talked about money and stuff when
we decided no but what we are going to
do all the different places that the 20
places we're going to put a gallon mason
jar there and you can drop off gift
certificates because like I say the
Family Resource Center say we get enough
a meal together we get everything
further and this is for Christmas we get
their Christmas meal together what if
they don't have a roasting pan guess
what the Family Resource Center can say
here take this gift certificate go get
what else you need for or I think the
other thing we might want to include is
diapers diapers are really really
expensive I think we could expand you
know the toy diaper and food listen
anything that's not like expired or bad
or something we really couldn't donate
like don't be ridiculous please don't
bring us like you know go to the health
food store and get some of that Amy's
organic chili get some soups [ __ ] that
people want to eat like something that
you can actually open and consume
instead of like some green beans I mean
you can do that but who wants [ __ ]
green beans for dinner you go get some
soup some Campbell's good [ __ ] some
chunky [ __ ] certificates can be used
like we're just doing non perishables
but you need milk you need butter we
need eggs we had more time we could
probably solicit grocery stores and
stuff for turkeys but this year not this
year right next year guys yep we're
gonna make it really really huge yes
would you prefer them wrap or not wrap
the gifts for the kids I say not wrap
well let the Family Resource Center do
that I think we'll do this and then turn
it off if you want to donate wrapping
paper so that they can be wrap to go for
that but don't wrap them I kind of said
that because I want to see what's in
there so that I made sure you're
and besides out how do you know that
there's not a used toy wrap distribute
the boxes next Friday isn't that correct
Lindsay we're gonna put them out next
Friday
beyond that Friday 18th the drop-off no
later than December 16th yep okay I'm
just making notes because I want to make
sure that this podcast comes out at the
right time I'll put this out on the 17th
and we're thinking about we haven't
fine-tuned this where we're still kind
of kind of work on it but we're thinking
we could make this and do like a little
competition some of the drop-off spots
one of them being elevate already said
well how about if every place put a
little gift in there I'll throw
something in and then at the end the
person that collected the most gets the
little prize package from the 20
drop-off spots and granny goes and
spends a day with him doing something
fun at their facility we could turn this
into a fun competition should be a lot
of fun you can win on a date with granny
you know and I know some of the
dispensaries are gonna go penny pre-roll
you know I know that there's already
some specials okay so we'll go through
that the people we have like Lindsey
said there's only three spots left so if
you want to get one and fill one of the
last three spots I guess that'd be in
Colorado Springs yes you do you need to
have a place where you can collect
canned foods a high-traffic area you
gotta be able to participate with the
cannabis community and be proud of the
cannabis community if you've got any
fear or hatred for the candidates
community please don't respond to this
ad
[Music]
and we're not gonna junk up your
facility if you call and say the box is
full somebody will be there to pick it
up and your Lobby or wherever you have
the box will not be an eyesore I promise
you that and it's a win-win situation
because you get you get free publicity
on my social media that's one of the
things I was gonna say you have to be ok
with granny publicizing your area your
your facility or store wherever it is if
it's a head shop if it's a gross store
if it's a dispensary if it's a cannabis
consumers or counterculture folk
Millennials may roam coffee shop for
anything as long as your cannabis
friendly well I bet you by the time this
comes out you'll have your three slots
filled because you are a yes a higher
elevation has got to be on your list of
course we run down the list let's hear
the the 17 glass grinds I know they're
located down on the south end of town
then of course the traveling stoners
place the business green and healthy
wellness mm-hmm canna Canyon they're
over on Old Colorado the weed pimps
they're fun guys they really are they
make me laugh every time I seen it
elevate and hemp there will be a box at
both locations epic remedy there's one
down on the circle they have one up on
Academy both stores will have a box
grow life natural mistakes care givers
their downtown what's up Joey D BK glass
the family joint the danker e they're a
new dispense
can I tell you something funny about the
den Cree I think it's funny okay yes as
long as it's funny and not derogatory
you know I once managed a non-profit on
our military installation in Colorado
Springs and I was let go because of
dabbing granny nobody there ever talks
to me anymore
cuz I smoke cannabis he's got new
friends I've met while my life has
gotten much better I mean I like what I
did but bots necks I ran into the dang
Creek just cuz it was the new dispensary
and I was with one of my friends they
took a picture cuz they were very happy
to see the dabbing granny one of my
former volunteers cuz I was a volunteer
organization Gayle Gayle is my real name
you were my son's dispensary today that
was just absolutely wonderful and I said
in almost a year you're the first person
that has reached out to touch to talk to
me and she so she was very happy I was
that that anchoring kind of funny people
just just shunned you yeah but look at
the great friends I've made that's true
you've replaced them oh yeah people
somebody asked me one of my comments
today they said did you ever think at
your age you would be this important
person in the cannabis community and I
said no I pinch myself every morning I'm
like how can this be I embrace it
no security clearance to get in here it
was easy what you do Lindsay dude I
didn't do anything she got her own dad
she set herself up she hid her own now I
didn't do anything she in there
I think she's beautiful for the bikes do
not like die I talked about you earlier
did your ears ring cuz Chris said I
watched you do that dab and you just
kept going in and you didn't cough it's
so mesmerizing watch that you have Jeff
to thank for that I don't even know if
you know this you and I I think it might
have been the first time we met at the
first podcast and we talked about
coughing during yeah yeah and you said
while I very rarely caught because you
own your lungs you can tell them what to
do so when I feel that tickle and you
all know what I mean when I say I feel
that tickle huh I hear your voice in my
head
and I almost meditate with my eyes open
when I am NOT going to cough yeah yeah
all right
I've never talked about this on a
podcast I've only told like four people
in my whole life this granny was one of
them when you feel like you're gonna
cough when you feel that thing that goes
when you're walking at the mall if you
[ __ ] fall down I feel that coffee
come in and I either inhale or exhale as
hard as I can distract them like when
your dogs trying to run away at a cat
you just pull the leash and put a treat
in front of it it forgets about the cat
it looks at the tree goes Oh treat like
that
I just breathe in real hard my lungs
like that's good for me or bad for me
but it works cause it's got to be better
than coughing so hard blowing out my
face every now and again I've smoked
strange product that sounds weird a lot
of people in random places but that you
can make quality cannabis concentrates
with propane if you do it properly but
it comes out like live resin it comes
out really moist when I smoke it my
lungs feel heavy and I spit up all cough
up the next morning I'll cough up a
bright green or a bright yellow yes like
you're sick oh my god do I need once it
comes out I'm marvelous but it was wet
in your hands in the morning yeah yeah
oh we should finish our list I was gonna
keep you on the line sorry hashtag they
liked it when we ran
- as as you always say let's get back to
the podcast new-age medical I think
there's no gods
that's Bailey shoutout to Newell yes
Rocky Mountain dapper I love her tweed
leaf tweed leaf is really I'm glad
they're on board because they actually
once a month wanted to do a charity
event nobody seemed to want cannabis
money yeah that's the hard part about it
we found grow vets finally took money
but it was really really hard to find
anybody that will take cannabis the vets
always need help and it's always great
to help the vets and they'll take it so
if you ever need some more to send stuff
I've got a guy who runs a veteran
organization that will always need
contributions well she asked me again
can we do once one Saturday a month were
10% of everybody's purchase goes
directly to a charity so shout out to
Renee at weed leaf so it's pretty nice
dispensary - I love you it's not yours
actually it's not even I don't but you
do know one thing about me is that that
sense of loyalty I have it's just it
happens I do primarily shop at green and
healthy but I visit other dispensaries
and I go into other places I just have
to I cannot go to one dispensary because
of the different drops and I and you
know I've developed great taste buds for
different products I was complimenting
you earlier on your ability to shop
everywhere that I can recognize
concentrate yeah and it's I enjoy it I
enjoy being able to tell people you know
this is really good product go spend you
mounted every day in the late afternoon
around 2:30 3 o'clock you can open up
Instagram and see where granny decided
to shop today there's one or two shots
of her and the cool bud tender there
they would treat her polite I love it I
love it when you pop up so I can almost
tell where you are like oh she went to
elevate and that she has
then she took all right altitude meds
there downtown I believe there are
several locations okay well wherever
they are we're gonna have boxes in all
their locations
Emerald City wellness the pink house and
stained glass LLC so that leaves three
spots get in touch with me DM me on
Instagram dabbing underscore granny I
think those spots will fill up quickly
though and not just this Bob you'll
probably have those filled this comes
out and like seven or ten days from now
so these 710 is it'd probably be filled
up hopefully with much faith what we
need now is people to go to these
locations with a non-perishable canned
good that you would eat you guys that
you would put in a pan and heat up
yourself and sit down and [ __ ] enjoy
like a meal by yourself don't bring us a
bunch of random side [ __ ] people and you
know what maybe you're not a big shopper
that's what that mason jar is gonna be
for and guess what the cannabis
community is the most honorable
community you can drop your money in a
dispensary you will get it back you can
leave your badge or your ID behind
because we're all stoners and if we drop
some [ __ ] we hope that you're gonna hand
it to me also
lucky but I hear it's pretty pretty
often that people always get back
there's two yeah yeah with that said
though if you're broke and all you have
in your cabinet is something and all you
want to bring you want to bring
something in like yes please don't feel
like we're sitting here and saying don't
bring anything in like if you know like
believe me I've been there I was making
lobster lobster and live rats I was just
sitting there thinking like oh god three
years ago I would have been like well
[ __ ] I'm not bringing anything it may be
been one of the people that hopefully
was benefiting from our little food
drive most people unfortunately right at
that line where they don't need the help
but they can't afford to give any help
right now making decisions do I need
this or do Medicaid or wipe your butt
I'm afraid that's what Californians are
facing that's California so Colorado we
did all the things right we did it right
here we thought that we had lost we
thought that we've lost an initiative
here in Pueblo and they are recounting
and still counting and it turns out that
we may have actually won three of the
four major cannabis initiatives we may
actually get to open recreational
cannabis facilities within the city
limits as well though before too long
here Andy you want a new job that'll be
fun well both go work in a new
dispensary bud tenders it'll be so much
fun
anything to do with this was he quite
the activist for all the things that
we're going on white Mike did a lot of
groundwork and a lot of internet work
and a lot of podcast work so but yeah
cuz I listened to your podcast where I
gained so much knowledge I appreciate it
and I've listened to Mike and even
though I met him one time in person
where he was so quiet it's not that way
on the podcast
he's quiet until he gets a read on you
and knows how much of him you want to
hear enough he's he's polite like he was
yeah he was taught to speak when spoken
to and he's passionate about cannabis so
thank you white Mike continued the fight
yes we're lucky to have such a good team
like we've got growers and we've got
activists and we've got city council
representative
we've got glass makers so that we can
consume our products we've got Lindsay
over here promoting us and keeping us I
was like oh that was really friggin hot
Mike's microphone down when he starts
doing he points down yes alright so
we've got a canned food drive toys also
guys toys are rad bring some toys into
Turtles or some [ __ ] something that
you'd want to play with I understand
don't all have a bunch extra money this
will end the drop off they will in
December 10th so you've got nearly a
month from the time that this episode
comes out pretty much
December 16th December oh sorry I just
can't read my own damn writing I'm sorry
that is the six week before Christmas to
these folks make some happy kids make
some bellies happy make some folks happy
brighten up some holidays whatever
holiday you celebrate share some share
some joy help some people out the winner
gets cold and shitty here just the cold
the snow the slowness the the [ __ ]
bet that vibe makes a lot of people
depressed and sad anyway and then you
got a shitty Christmas on top not doing
well if you got kids that's just icing
on the damn poor cake so help some
people out make them make them have a
little kids know any different right
yeah yeah and if you if you don't break
them early they get a chance
so let's turn to help them out I'm
serious yeah strippers and serial
killers
[Music]
I wrote down just a one-word note and
I'm prominent wait till you get done
taking that drinks I don't want you to
the new trend in cannabis that I have
been catching on to the suppositories
[Music]
steal some of your green cracked abs to
place on my own terms
oh this is gonna do me just fine this
green crack chirps on the nice okay when
I first heard about them damn
suppositories even I was kind of
skeptical but I have a pretty sick
husband so I thought okay this is really
gonna help waning them off the morphine
and all that with this pain okay what I
have discovered is most most of you men
are homophobic you met you mentioned
suppositories and I see you visibly
squeezing your butt cheeks together
she's right
am i it's true it's accurate I don't
know why women on the other hand you
know we spit 10-pound babies out our
vaginas so what's a suppository let's
use no not me
[Music]
my husband and I brought you there 50%
to see 50% um DVDs thank you had a brain
fart and he said you stick that up your
ass no problem and I did it is at least
12 hours of euphoria is the best way to
put it you can function you can drive
you're not intoxicated but you're
euphoric I used one the night we had our
girls taken care of and it ease the pain
okay so my thought was alright now these
things are really wonderful if you are
truly a medical patient for real if
you're especially cancer patient if
you're vomiting right skip that whole
part of the body exactly and you and I
know that the divine creator did not
make our lungs to ingest irritants some
of us like to smoke we know it's really
not the best way to medicate yo if ands
or buts I like to smoke though if you
truly need to medicate there are so many
membranes in your anus using these
suppositories is a wonderful way to
medicate cannabis isn't the first
medicine they've used as a suppository
this is just the newest and it's just on
our realm so now it's what we're talking
about now it's been used for hundreds of
years I'm not certain but I'm sure
people been boosting things for longer
the best way to medicate
so the next week we'll skip ok so I I
had no problem with it I stick one up my
butt I stuck a couple of month my but by
now my husband had to have a colonoscopy
the next week and he came home he's a
grumpy after his colonoscopy using pain
is grouchy and I was like you buttholes
already stretched out try one of them
spy stories all right God if he I'm so
bad he does not listen to this podcast
he tried one and he was like you're
right my lower back pain is gone
I don't feel the nauseousness in my
belly that I feel when I take a morphine
for pain
yeah I'm swimming from that damn I might
have put a little too much Terps but I'm
not complaining
[Music]
it made my brain swim around in my head
okay should I tell the story we're
smoking on this stuff called Green crack
which is a pretty sativa dominant strain
[Music]
and I'm not a real sativa okay when you
buy this distilled hash it solvent
unless it comes in a little syringe it's
not very big glass its glass it has a
very small part where the medicine
actually comes out of the syringe like
where a needle would be I guess do you
have children you've used him for
pulling up amoxicillin or antibiotic
good to feed a baby bird it would be yes
it's probably a really good description
to put the idea it'd be perfect to feed
a baby bird if you had rodents or mites
or something like that okay so I really
do like these suppositories for
medicating and I'm not gonna say where
but about tender said Wow
have you tried that hash and I was like
No
that consumed huge amounts of caffeine
and lots of other things too many people
sticking too much hash in their ass how
much I really wouldn't suggest doing
that okay
I've given some do the traveling stoner
we can ask watched her put her head down
and blushes why did one I actually did
forea ones so I had gotten the four ones
the sample that's so long ago I never
use them and then once Gayle started
doing them was talking about them I was
supposed to go to Denver and meet up
with one of our friends for her birthday
and I was in a lot of pain that morning
and I was like [ __ ] I really need to go
to Denver like you know we have plans
and I really can't let this like [ __ ] up
our plant you know plans for her
birthday so I said to Christ I'm like I
don't know what to do he's like you need
to put one of those depositories and
then just try it the first time I ever
took one the forty ones are a lot
stronger they're like the 50/50 ones so
the first time I ever took it I was like
Gumby and I think I think because I was
in a lot of pain like I just I'm like
immediately was out of pain I don't know
it was weird but
like I couldn't really move today
very clean almost like a pumpkin
[Music]
incredible oh yeah cookies that were
about 50
[Music]
okay so second secret sash ever in
Colorado it was in May you were in
Florida you weren't here for it it was
you have literally flown out the day
before but he's looking like I know the
cupcakes pictures I was like we both
we're not gonna find Jeff in the corner
brought me on stage and gave me a to
Gram dab and then asked did he do one
with you know you we kind of fixed it
see he knows that I like to take big
dabs and we're buddies and he was on
stage and he goes I'm higher than you
because that's his thing he likes I'm
higher than you why cuz I'm taller than
him so I'm always higher you're much
taller this I'm always higher I think
you mean I was taller than yes you are
I've got a really killer picture of the
picture he's like Jeff I'm higher than
you come up on stage he's like you take
a big big dab he's like you ready for
this and stretches out to grams and I
was like oh [ __ ] I didn't know that's
what was coming and he heated the nail
to her it was white it wasn't red it was
white I was like let it cool and he goes
no just hit it I was like no let it cool
and so I like hesitated as long as I
could but then I just went in because he
was pushing it on there and I pulled the
whole thing when I blew it out and he's
like damn this guy's a champ and it was
like can you do a bigger dad than him
and people like yes they would come up
on stage and we would dab together
you kept dabbing oh yeah yeah they
couldn't finish their dabs and I would
grab the rig from that happy
and I would finish their dad for them
and set the rig down like now what's up
but honestly they only lasted for one
cent he calls it Adam does like a little
45 minutes and then goes and takes a
break walks around the crowd one of
those and I had to go sit upstairs and
eat there wasn't real food there at the
time so I ate about 12 bags of chips in
like seven bottles of water I didn't
want to do add a gram dab in that real a
thing we were in but I wanted to win so
max heated up my nail India's like let
it cross no no I because I sat down I'm
sitting right in front of the email but
everybody's different guys when you do
big dabs like Jeff and I do struggle you
start dropping it you see the
temperature yeah and I'll I hear some of
the time I can hear my up on the nail
[Music]
yeah absolutely
cuz I mean we've got the smaller ones
now I'm going to a hundred hundred
100 milligrams Ettore 100 milligrams
edibles is of THC is enough for most
people to orally consume and be just
fine I don't and then take dabs like
normal then I'm like oh but if just that
amount of edibles wouldn't have done it
but the to like kind of kind of boot its
like turbo makes your high turbo just
gives you a boost
is that cool jump I know I'm not like a
scientist but I pay attention to the
body and I know that kind of stuff I
care about physical stuff I know how
quickly your bomb is going to absorb
that much medicine and you're gonna
absorb all of it you're not gonna poop
any of it out your stomach's not gonna
destroy any of it your liver and kidneys
are gonna ruin it it's just gonna suck
all up in to you now when I do try that
high of a dosage that will be you know
for me that's gonna be even high for me
I'm not going anywhere I'm gonna test it
out we Facebook live it after after you
yeah I put on my new outfit the lady for
most part when he bought me as a gift
you have so many cool friends to give
you so many cool gear okay now you sit
here you know me am I very girly girly
does not call yourself on the last
podcast in Iowa corn [ __ ] yes but it
wasn't so bad I looked at it and I was
like really it's yoga pants it's not too
bad no anything that says US Army and
gold sequins ring it's okay try to pull
your back it's just the Victoria's
Secret's it was when I told tater that
he is I said I've never been in the
Victoria's Secret you know what he said
unfortunately I've been in many many of
them
can you say that to Jeff I think they're
very expensive it always worked for me
so why do you need something I mentioned
[Music]
all right guys let's recap seems like
everybody's high we've been going for
almost an hour a year on social media
thanks to everybody out there that seems
to like my silliness and quirkiness I'll
tell you I'm always on the lookout for
fun hats and stuff on social media so
that you can see it you guys periscope
and Facebook live because a lot of stuff
there she smokes down there's a new app
that I've been on talked with and and
this is kind of fun cuz it's just people
in the cannabis community and what the
end goal of this app is they want to be
able to have multicam users so wouldn't
just be you sitting there watching me
smoking all of us would be interact
kinda like a tiny chat sort of man that
sounds great I would love to do that so
I'm kind of helping them promote this I
think I saw talked with and I actually
assumed that it was a pothead dating
service
[Music]
they have a 25 word script which I'll
give you their business card to put in
your wallet that there's the 25 word
script and it's basically the cop says
where you been I don't have to tell you
where I'm going I don't have to end at
the end their hashtag is shut the [ __ ]
up put your dollars you shut the [ __ ] up
so they've sent me their hashtag hat and
I word and I love it and people know I
seen your hashtag STFU had
my friends also they could be was if you
want to call them 855 was but I think is
more appropriate they do have funny
social media give him a follow there was
somebody else they were saying that we
needed an August house was it my inna
you know yes we've got to give them a
shout and actually they're gonna be
working with the family joint he is cut
he's from Lee Pennsylvania everything is
made here in the United States um a
really nice you know I'm not a big email
fan but it's got LED lights um really
really nice quartz banger that's wrapped
from the bottom up consistent keeps your
nail consistently hot you told me it was
Pro programmable by your phone yes you
have to have a smartphone it's caught
it's called the cube one and there's
there's only a few you have to order
them okay okay and they're not cheap
this I know but you can use my name as a
promo there you go
I just remember that but you get what
you paid for just like if you were
buying Bobo blasters anything boba
blaster makes great a name if you're
making American products you're gonna
get what you pay for
yes exactly in August houses America
he's have you ever heard about I have
not that's what I was happy you finally
got it cuz you showed me them a while
back I should have actually brought it
with me it comes in a little box where
you can take along with you the nail
looked really cool I don't like emails
but y'all have been seeing me and I like
that I can put my clear rates on top of
that and got the lights on the top
that's fresh
Circle just wear your ring shopping at
Spencer's again what do you prefer for
hiking shoes all of our social media
stuff of course everybody knows how to
find the Devin granny on all the social
media I think if you google me you're
gonna find me watch the videos watch the
Russian comments from other people asked
if we were gonna hook up if you're not
part of anything you'll do your best to
try to create something to be a part of
[Music]
the traveling stoner remind everybody
how they can find you because I think
you promised us that by the time we
record it again you'd have a website
ready to go yes I heard that this month
so I will be launching the website at
the end of this month actually for real
this time
I have been working really hard on it so
it will be coming out at the end of the
month but for now I am the traveling
stoner on Instagram and periscope you
can find me on Twitter as the travel
stoner and you can find me on snapchat
travelin stoner without the G what's
your home address undisclosed bunker the
studio needs a name because you know how
Instagram has that little story I
deleted quite a few cuz I actually I
didn't even want to say the name of the
city cuz I have learned people wolf oh
yeah you are and if you guys found me
through granny's feed by anyway if
granny if you learned of this podcast
through granny send me a message or tag
me in something and just say hey I found
you through the diving granny so dang
give her a hug for every one of those
alright so follow the traveling stoner
she's gonna get her [ __ ] together and
get her website up usually just take
pictures a weed a real picture of me you
didn't know this you know that one hat
pen yeah the tall one where I'm holding
that tea pot yeah THC Sam and I had
photo shoot for a magazine it's this
little tea pot thing that goes on a
panas like a bubbler attachment that
looks like a teapot
no we're gonna go one better when that
billboards up we're gonna do a group dab
up under the billboard I mean I'll take
a seventy show they used to climb up the
water
in my life yes just for being awesome
[Music]
he's a photographer he works for a
magazine when somebody like Tommy Chong
Co comes to town your job is to go take
pictures and do magazine open invitation
there are three chairs here at the table
that are available one of them has got
your name on it whenever you want to
come also Brett I want to come get you I
want to get you to come be on the show
here at my house we've got this good
studio the good mics where the equipment
doesn't screw up we can be comfortable
it's quiet nobody interrupts organized
I've had some real good conversations
with CBDs he's been on a couple times
he's due for another episode we need to
get him here again I'd love to have a
Kabuki across the table talk about
certain doses of specific cannabinoids
for certain conditions so between the
CBDs and and bret with the Terps we're
talking New Age medicine yes yes and Sam
Sam and I I'd love to talk about
traumatic brain injuries with Sam
because of course everybody knows that
I've got a TBI that [ __ ] me up you
heard on the podcast occasionally I'd
just stop and start a brand new sentence
Sam is actually running this food drive
with us as well yeah we forgot to even
like but yeah Sam is also another big
part of helping us getting this food
drive she's not concrete you know we
still have three spots for people so I
did not forget you don't get too many
words I'm not super super busy but I'm
still doing them they're still available
I still do custom stuff with that as
well
focusing pretty heavily on the new glass
game yeah that's yes well a new glass
page I have no no me glass it's n om
glass and you gotta follow my normal
Instagram is plastic oh that's uh bo bo
bo blaster CEO as the same thing on
periscope and that's all I'm on yeah
that's about it I tried to I was so
happy to see him today
and I just thought of somebody else we
need to shout out
Color Me filthy artists I've just become
friends with on Instagram I think my
friends correct you can find me on I'm
on all the damn social medias on Twitter
it's @g fyh podcast is probably the best
way to find me on Instagram it would be
really rad if you follow me on instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics hopefully
by the time this episode comes out I'll
be at 10,000 followers you can find me
on Facebook the girl from the heart
podcast they think that's enough many
more of them I think that's all we're
gonna do for today I want to thank
everybody for coming especially granny
you've got an hour drive home so we're
gonna we're gonna let you sober up so
you're not medicated for the drive of
course not we may we may do a little
Facebook live video or something here
since we've got a whole bunch of cool
ass people yeah yeah yeah all right so
we're gonna wrap up the podcast ladies
Jenna thank you guys for listening
first I'm gonna say that thing more if
you want to go to iTunes and leave us a
review that would be SuperDuper cool I
will read your review on a future
episode she's got anything you'd like to
say and you do not want to do it at a
public forum on social media send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you if
you want some grow lessons if you need
some advice if you just want to see
what's up something go [ __ ] myself I'm
down send it I wanna hear what you have
to say good or bad I ain't skirt I don't
know what people are thinking
I've been do it be honest with me I'm a
blunt person
so uh that's all I've got for you this
week big shot upside to dabbing granny
until next time take a phat dab and
deeper mama hug for me
[Music]
take it on down to the show
wait
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 167 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
if you're professional grower new smoker
or a dedicated dabber if your cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff thank you guys once again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout outs my friends in
the mystic roots been letting me use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to catch the entire mystic whole thing
without coughing had to cough right in
the middle there you guys did not hear I
could have snuck that through oh man
good cops but shout out to my buddy
frosty organics for bringing some frosty
Gorilla Glue over here dude that was
delicious yes yes yes welcome to podcast
a newcomer someone who has not been on
yet but I promised him our no-till guest
is here ladies gentleman to frosty
organics on Instagram make sure you give
them a follow dude welcome to the show
thank you thank you I'm super happy to
be here been waiting to be on here for a
little bit you know I've I've been
listening to this for a few years now so
show up and I said message me and we can
have you show up in the talk about
no-till obviously today you guys
newcomers sitting across from me
this guy is visiting from re visiting
from North Carolina so he's gonna have
to kind of lean in a little bit but he's
visiting from North Carolina welcome to
show our new friend monistic Logan right
yeah I remember you're in from North
Carolina right yeah legal there is it is
this some culture shock to be able to
come out here and just drive around with
weed in the car and well honestly I've
been smoking since a very young age
so it's it's nothing weird to me is
broken for myself okay to be out here I
need to give my friends the dank team
calm that's right the dank team calm we
need some new genetics for your garden
some feminized or regular seeds check
out the dank team calm let them know
that you heard about them on the girl
free heart podcast also our friends at
handmade apparel that's my cool [ __ ]
coming up from our friends at handmade
just want to give them a shout out and
also I owe a huge shout-out to my friend
task rock yet highly educated titanium
the other day I went to the mailbox I
didn't feel good in feel worth or should
I eat something they kicked my ass
man I was not living but I went to the
mailbox and I opened up the mail and
there was a gift in the mail from task
rock highly-educated titanium I get the
new it's a quartz and titanium combo
domeless email of course domeless right
I still say domeless but it's a titanium
nail with a quartz dish with a little
protective titanium shroud I think is
the proprietary lit so that you could
carry your quartz nail with you and you
don't have to feel as paranoid like
you're gonna break it because I am a
breaky guy I like to break glass [ __ ]
and I will break a quartz nail so I've
got a quartz nail that I want to break
it is able to be attached to my barrel
style email coil I like it much better
on my flat email coil and it's also able
to be used without the email setup as
just an on-the-go nail so Big Shot it's
a task thank you
that's a sweet product I think I like it
a lot better with the flat coil I think
it's going to end up being used mostly
with a torch I didn't work for you
probably let's talk about some no-till
last time will was here and he kind of
led on a little bit about no-till
growing and I said elaborate and he said
you got to get frosty over so we've got
frosty organics over we're gonna talk
about no-till I should ask frosty a
couple of questions before we do that
bro how long have you been growing
cannabis really really growing like for
real growing I say a little over two
years oh [ __ ] you're good at it yeah
probably probably closer to three years
but uh you're like really figuring out
what I was doing and uh doing it
correctly I'd say about uh about two
years okay how long into your grow
career did you decide to go no-till
a year ok so you've been at the no-till
for like a year a year alright and
you're good at it broke is that Gorilla
Glue for you brought oh yeah it lives up
to your name my soils get at it ok this
guy thinks so you're making where'd you
get your soil recipe um there's a guy
that uh I've been falling for a while
his name is uh coop on Instagram okay
like a mask Clackamas cool when you said
cool I thought that might be who you're
talking about he's really into like KN f
li yeah Korean uh yeah we really uh
everybody I think that does no-till is
like basically based off of his soil
recipe okay we took his soil recipe and
then uh just added our own things into
it but he's really like the the founder
of no too nice okay who the founders
tell us a little about what note what's
the difference between no-till and what
most of us are probably doing most of us
are probably going to the store getting
bottles mixing shoot up in a shot glass
weighing it out into a bucket part and
mixing it up make sure the pH is right
and then pouring that onto our plants so
teach us a little about the difference
of what no-till is well no tool is just
basically kind of like living soil on
living soil is basically a super soil
that everybody's doing so everybody got
into an organic way and they're like
well you can feed you know just water to
this soil and your plants will do what
it's supposed to so basically all the
inputs in your soil is doing what it's
supposed to for you so like in nature
you don't see anything in nature doesn't
get fed with the bottle it's already in
the dirt it breaks it down naturally
because the decomposition happens from
other things in the earth and the worms
and poop yep so then that's available as
needed by the plant and the plant isn't
force-fed basically or starving for
anything hopefully yeah right okay and
so and so I was doing superstore there
for a while super soil is okay sometimes
your soil
too hot they put too many amendments in
it or maybe the amendments that are in
there for deep in Flour because you
might have put your soil together a
little bit before you threw it in the
flour you know a late in veg or
something like that you want to
transplant into your 5 gallon right for
you threw it into flour
you might start getting too heavy of
news you know or uh I guess
natural amendments being broken down and
feeding your plants too hot and it'll
burn your plants so I guess the the way
to get away from that is is to just the
natural way with no-till is to have
basically the same thing but then we
have like compost and then we have you
know worms in there I don't put worms in
there I just put earthworm castings okay
from a guy here in town named Don he has
the greatest earthworm castings ever but
it has cocoons in it so those worms will
come to life after like you know a few
days actually you know it'll have little
worms in there too you know little bitty
worms and stuff in there already so um
you know once they start getting fed and
stuff like that you just need to have
mulch on top because what you want to do
is you want to keep basically you want
to just keep your your soil very very
moist on top just because you want your
worms to come to the top and to break
down all your top dressings okay so
whenever you do a transplant from your
one gallon so usually in a one gallon
when I veg I use like some shitty soil
you know something that's very base you
know you could use pro mix if you wanted
you know I mean if that's what you chose
I used more something that uh you know
shout to Don again Don makes a base soil
for me I just put my plants in there in
one gallons
I've a Jim was just water only just for
like a month okay three weeks after that
I put them into their their new pot and
then I fed them for a week in there and
their no-till pots but their no-till
pots are already working and already
okay let's talk about what goes into
that no-till pot before we put the
plants in and how long before I put
one gallon paw into that no-till do I
want to get that mixed up
do I need some time to let it get
cooking you do for sure if you want to
make it on your own you can buy a soil
mix now that is basically coots mix plus
all the extra things we were putting in
it um for a few years you know we were
having to you know make our soil mixes
and put all these extra things and then
we started buying like a soil mix on
build a soil okay and we still have to
put extra things in it you know to make
it exactly what you want it to be rich
enough to be able to go all through
flour and stuff like that to have your
worms and your microbe life and your
beneficials really working you know and
so um after after we you know we're
doing that for a while now he came out
with a it's called a modern mix version
2.0 okay
[Music]
Malibu compost okay I've only heard good
things about those richest compost never
use them is it's hard to get sometimes
it is very hard to get all right very
very hard to get must be good [ __ ] then
super good [ __ ] Jeremy started making a
super good soil though so I've used to
soil a few times now on a few new pots
that I've had to put together on some
new rooms but all my older pots that are
like four or five rounds in I built
those like all the way up like we we mix
the compost we mix the soil we had to
you know mix each amendment in you know
one cup to each cubic foot you know what
I'm saying okay and we had to you know
had to mix it up and then uh I guess
you'd have it sit there for maybe like a
week or two but then you would just you
know put everything in there put your
top dress on there you know put your
earthworm castings in there you'd put
your uh your cover crop and stuff like
that and then I just let it come to life
and then by the time you put your plant
in there it's already working and it'll
just overtake your plant
okay so if you even put shitty soil in
there it'll overtake that right oh yeah
and you can start with old shooty
recycled soil you guys I'd like to take
my old soil that plants have already
been in and I will put clones in it the
clones if you've got a clone from me
chances are it came in recycled soil but
it was treated there are no bugs
it's been flushed it's happy look how
good your soil if you're going into
no-till so you've got it set up about a
week in advance do we want to put water
in there after we've got all the
nutrients and all the amendments in
there in the soil in there do we want to
water it a week in advance or do you
just want to let it sit kind of you want
it moist or do you want it to dry you
should water together keep your
beneficials eatin and stuff all right
back because whenever we put those
earthworm castings in there they
definitely already have a lot of
beneficials and stuff in there working
with the worms because you know just
it's so rich that that shit's so rich it
comes so fresh he gives it to us fresh
out of the compost of the world it's
beautiful all right so you can get your
pots loaded up about a week in advance
check out the modern mix 2.0 that's a
good start you might want to add some
stuff I check out sub cools ah super
soil recipe and it's gonna be similar
the way he throws a tarp on the ground
and mixes the super soil it's the same
idea what we're trying to do here we're
just using a different mix check out the
modern mix 2.0 find your own recipe on
making some no-till soil and perfective
for your plants you'll get a good start
with the modern makes 2.0 it sounds like
but your plants are gonna want different
[ __ ] you're gonna need to protect
perfect it for each plant but this is a
good start then get your plants into
there about a week after you make the
mix then you said mulch you want to keep
mulch on top to keep the worms feeding
what are we gonna use for mulch you can
use old stems
[Music]
okay so cover crop what am i growing is
cover crop lots of clover clover you
know keep bugs away so you're growing
lemon grass right there
you know it's keeping bugs I was gonna
ask about some pest management and
no-till here in a couple of seconds but
it sounds like we're there lemon grass
what else can I use to keep the pests
away on my no-till crop
eucalyptus was Mary okay you know
natural stuff like that um I don't
really spray a neem oil on my plants I
like garage oil okay has a more milder
smell and it's uh my face wrinkled up a
little bit there's something if if you
get a tiny drop of neem oil on anything
it feels like I can taste it for a week
it doesn't go away it's the most
terrible flavor ever okay so basically
essential oils will help you keep your
pests away so the lemongrass in there it
works as cover crop and it's gonna keep
some bugs out that's [ __ ] smooth I
like that it's good thinking alright so
that's the basics to get you started and
set up what else do we need to think
about we've got mulch we've got cover
crop we've got some good hot soil to
keep us cooking basically your just grow
it now right you got a water on one
they're thirsty what are we gonna use
for top dress worm castings yeah some
neem meals nice email neem seed meal
that's a lot of work that's weird yeah a
neem seed meal kelp meal biochars good
worm casting some fish compost is real
good okay good right when you transplant
get a like fresh dose of nitrogen right
to him right when they're transplanted I
feel like kelp and sea products
completely add flavors and aromas and
density a lot so okay I do a Niemann
kelp tea
every other watering do you ever fool
your feed with your teas that you make
oh yeah
oh yeah okay I mean I don't really make
teas anymore on it's just more about
just table dressings like whenever you
going to flour own malted barley once a
week yeah a lot of enzymes and stuff
like that sugars you know stuff like
that will make your buds real sweet make
them dance up and stuff like that you
know I do a lot of potassium silicates
who do you use magical 16h okay I just
make my own I just make my own
you know liquid I've been using the
bottle dosa still a baby over here okay
os a 28 so I mean I used to use
whenever I was doing super Souls and
stuff it seems like Bill Doyle gets a
lot of free shoutouts on this podcast
[Music]
question they've got a chart it's so
basic so man we can get I had one of my
basic questions here is how do we start
but you go get some modern mix 2.0 and
you get some pots filled with a new
water them and you grow some clones and
then you throw it in there and then you
pay attention and then the next time
you're gonna have to add amendments so
we've got our mulch we've got our cover
crop we've taken care of our pests
basically we're flushing the whole time
right and so the worms are [ __ ] you
know and then the beneficials come and
break down the worm poop at the end you
cut down your plant it's done do you
just dig a little hole next to that
stock and put your next clone right in
there how you getting it started again
just rip your take the rubella shake it
you want to get as little dirt out as
possible okay you don't want to add any
new soil to it you want to just keep
using the same soil over and over the
only thing you want to add is new soil
if you transplant and needed to add
something to actually transplant you
just composting okay just yeah we just
fill that hole with worm castings I love
doing that when I transplant I just put
a nice layer of casting so I'll throw
some some great white shark or something
I'll get that moving yeah okay and then
what are you gonna re amendment Riya
mend it with the second time Oh
worm castings refeeding everything huh
neem kill biochar exactly is the cover
crop gonna just keep growing is that
like
[Music]
yeah the stuff that you cut off can you
throw that into a tea and made kind of a
compost tea out of it if you're using
cumference
store anymore
no no really no I mean even if you
wanted to you know make your own you
know basically like if you want to push
your plants extra hard you can use like
cow foes and stuff like that you can
make your own calcium and phosphorus
yeah yeah it sounds like this all these
processes are super sustainable you know
like especially once you get to like a
certain level and so just that's great
for your soil anyway you know you just
like building your own little like yeah
and one of the major problems of home
growing is that when you're done you've
got all this trash you've got sticks
you've got leaves you've got you've got
dirt bottles bottles you can throw in
the trash but it's all that dirt like I
grow I used to have I would do like 20
28 7 gallon pots and that's a lot of
soil when you're done and I would have
to find somewhere smooth to throw all
that away and luckily I have a friend
who grows an outdoor vegetable garden
and I would just have him come pick it
all up in his truck and he would just
haul it off for me in the middle of the
night but if I didn't have that hookup
what am I gonna do with 28 7 gallon pots
worth of soil you guys don't even have
to worry about that your worms just
going like oh you need new dirt throw
your sticks in there oh and you're also
composting you guys running a boat
coffee bucket I mean I like to make you
know some fermentation and stuff like
that like you can make you know like
fermented fruit and stuff like that you
know stuff like that and it's just like
super benefit yeah sounds like you hang
on a little bit
[Music]
yeah I love drinking coconut I feel
super hydrated I feel like if I feed
that to the plan all that old stuff he
got a nice mycelium on his planted he
send me a message dude I think I [ __ ]
up my plans got mold on them perfect
[Music]
people freak out I see it on Facebook or
Instagram every once in a while like oh
[ __ ] my soils making shrooms what do I
do exactly what you're doing there's
just a humidity and the right [ __ ] pH
in there you're growing shrooms it's
gonna be awesome keep it going don't do
anything differently so I wrote down how
cost effective is this sounds like it's
a one-time deal right oh yeah I mean
like you gotta keep you get occasionally
buy more worm castings you have to buy
you know you might have to buy some more
demon kelp meal because I do Niemann
kelp teas just you know I just do those
every like third watering I think and
then it's top dresses as well depending
on how much you're doing but as far as
the soil goes yeah it's basically one
you're not buying seven bags of soil
every time you need to transplant twenty
eight seven gallon pots it sounds like a
lot of work but it also sounds like it's
saving me a whole bunch of work in the
long run I don't have to go to the gross
form buy bottles which are expensive and
it's a lot oh I'm paying for the water
to be shipped feels like essentially
because I read the ingredients and all
that shit's available and build the soil
on a dry form well the difference
between like potassium silicon
you're talking if you get premix
potassium silicate in a bottle it's
gonna cost like I mean ten times more if
not more than that then what the bag if
the powder comes in and you can make 10
times as much that comes in the bottle
with that it's crazy now you got me
rethinking everything I do and you can
make a gallon with 568 grams yeah easily
yeah okay man I wish I could I want to
start off just like one or two pots of
some stuff and to see if I can see what
it does next to my botanic air grow or
whatever brand I'm using my veg it's
really like they're gonna want to spread
out they're gonna want to go to where
you know they're gonna be needed that's
rad so it's gonna just move over to the
other possible only there's plenty of
things lactobacillus serum I had a buddy
that had some other plants that got some
PM on them and uh I was like you want to
get rid of that real quick you know and
he was like yeah for sure you know so we
just took some lactobacillus theorem you
spray that for three days and it's a
completely gone cuz beneficial fungi
overtakes bad fungi yeah that's a whole
lots like a farmer still about like you
know PM being systematic and stuff like
that's definitely not systematic he went
through his whole flower period and had
no PM thang so ever very nice you know
she just plants can be a real [ __ ]
sometimes in Colorado when the
temperature changes yeah and it changes
every day I was like it's too warm I
wish I had on shorts and a t-shirt it's
cold what happened I've been hoping on
Friday a little brag here I get to go
see Joe Rogan at Comedy Works Friday
Saturday Thursday changed myself damn it
Joe Rogan
Oh it'll be a good time shot it's a
comedy workshop the Baker I cannot wait
I go to a lot of comedy shows Joe Rogan
is probably one of the foam they're like
really give me super pumped so it seems
like you guys both follow the TLO book
quite a bit is a good way to get started
you recommend the TLO book from the they
made him changed his facebook page to
his real name so that's weird
check out the TLO book true living
organics what's the other book that he
did that I did not write down the name
of okay everybody went blank
anyway the rift teach you how to keep
your soil food web Rock read TLO first
cuz teeming with microbes is a little
bit overwhelming it's not really begin
information you need to have you need to
have kind of an idea of what's going on
or it's you know just go right over your
head otherwise ret LOL is a great one
and then once you get a good handle on
that you think you have an understanding
of like how organics work and you know
you want to dive a little deeper
open up teeming with microbes and learn
about the soil food web because that's
where that's where Noto really comes
into play okay the soil food web because
that's what's happening inside of your
soil is you've got a whole ecosystem of
microorganisms living breathing
excreting you know feeding your plants
so yeah definitely definitely check both
of those out any other books you two
would recommend while you're talking
about books TV with nutrients is pretty
good that's a little bit less about
organics it's for the same guys that
they're teeming with microbes I've
skimmed through that we have it at work
I've skimmed through it a couple times
it's just more yes less organic base but
if you're if you don't want to do the
full organic ride which I understand
some people don't want to do it check it
out it'll it'll kind of give you a good
a little bit better understanding what's
going on in your soil with your
nutrients and bottle-feeding and stuff
okay cool you guys ever get any of your
no-till products tested by any of the
labs I haven't yet but I want to really
soon I think me and my buddy we're gonna
go up to Springs to uh I could just show
how food-grade our cannabis is that we
don't spray no pesticides we don't use
no [ __ ] you know we don't use
bottles there's no heavy metals like you
could test it you know all the way down
and it's just gonna be a pure cannabis
right okay I'd love to see the tests I
want to see what kind of THC CBD CBG all
that stuff what's coming out on the
no-till just curious oh yeah I just
smoked him saw your products and I'm
high as [ __ ] from smoking Summa Frosty's
frosty Gorilla Glue 4 thank you the
trichomes were really short and all over
the place it didn't look like they got
really tall look like they were fighting
for space in there yeah I guess that's
just me you know the way I feed my
plants and stuff like that it was frosty
they're fighting for space in their
first [ __ ]
Gooden didn't heavily medicated on their
thank you
can we talk about where people can
acquire some of your great smokeable x'
is that something you're feel fry like
you want to mention on the show if not I
could totally hit a little bit of
editing and take this part right out oh
no for sure I'm at the can of Canyon in
a beautiful Colorado Springs yeah I
carry a lot of my product over there I
guess you could say you know I'm kind of
a co-op grower for them and stuff like
that um they carry my product there so
if you are a member there you can go
reimburse my product there but uh you
know in the streets and stuff like that
you know personally you know that's not
my thing and stuff like people from
anywhere if you're 21 and over you're
able to come to the canna Canyon in
Colorado Springs it's on Colorado
Boulevard I cannot think of the exact
address
it's like 1505 i-15 but come to the
kandy Canyon in Colorado Springs if
you're 21 and over if you've got a valid
ID and you're not an [ __ ] we invite
you to come to the canyon Canyon please
sign up join as a member sign the member
agreement you got the address beautiful
Colorado Springs parking in the fronts
kind of a [ __ ] but parking in the back
is available going to the alley
there's you got a park like kind of
diagonal in there you'll see it do it a
7-eleven if you see the 7-eleven go
across the street you're close but come
in there be 21 don't be a dick have an
ID sign up sign the member agreement
join come in hang out take a couple dabs
smoke with those chances are I might be
there might be there will might be there
frost he could be there Logan could be
there you never know I'm there taking
dabs the traveling stoner is there all
the damn time Camille is there all the
time you can see the dogs but you can
also grab some flowers that were done by
our good friend frosty here that are
totally organic that are beautiful that
are gorgeous last time I was there I
think they had some of the gorilla glue
on the shelf it's beautiful it's a crowd
favorite it doesn't stay long busy when
stuff comes around so that was a huge
challenge to the cannon cannon you guys
can write the check out to Rasta Jeff
[Music]
little parchment paper that it was
twenty seven point something grams when
he dropped it off is what it looked like
bros nowhere near 27 being reimbursed
for quickly if you do go to the club
cannabis or any of the clubs learn the
lingo please say the proper [ __ ] use the
proper terminology nomenclature whatever
you gotta do reimburse however it goes
there sometimes it feels silly but
that's the way it works so I think we've
covered most of no till and it sounds
like this is a perfect segue into
something else that I wanted to talk
about ladies and gentlemen in Denver
Colorado they voted yes to allow
consumption of cannabis in adult places
some bars and clubs will begin allowing
people to smoke cannabis in certain
sections indoors in places that means
we're going to have social lounges in
Denver very soon people are looking for
buildings to rent right now there are
already places that function kind of
legitimately kind of under the radar
those places are probably gonna blow up
and be popular or there are people out
there right now looking for property
painting the walls I've been to a couple
just like Springs I've been to a couple
that are really nice like the can of
Canyon the couches they went to a nice
place and bought brand new couches
they bought a rug that matched the paint
on the walls they got a table with end
tables that all match they got a shelf
that's the same kind of wood as the
tables like it looks like somebody
really they got they had like their gate
interior design came in help them out
there's a competitor that's looks like
they got all of their [ __ ] at the
[ __ ] the thrift store down the street
and their [ __ ] dog laid on it for six
weeks
I honestly won't let my dreadlocks touch
that cabbage
I will let my dreads down in there I
keep my dreads out of the other place
and there are other places that are in
the middle and above and below that
there are some where I won't even take
my backpack in because I feel like I
might get jacked for it yeah are so damn
loud because the band is playing
constantly they can't even be there
hope somebody doesn't don't all have to
be have to be dubstep bars one of those
things you can be like hey can we get a
permit for Saturday night so we can
allow smoking or is it just like a and
bro hypothetical now you guys this is
all [ __ ] that is going to come up stuff
okay I preach this all the time because
if you don't write these rules in your
role making old people in suits that
don't give a [ __ ] about cannabis that
don't take dabs that don't go out or
gonna write these rules that's gonna
suck so maybe you can get like like you
get around liquor license for a year of
cannabis consumption license every night
after 9 p.m. you can consume cannabis in
your facility or whatever from 90 to 93
drinks you take some dad's and hang out
socialize nobody ever gets in a fight
well my thought too is what about like
if you bring your own like dabs to these
places the way it's gonna work with our
marijuana Enforcement Division system
that's mostly the way it's gonna have to
work as a bring your own cannabis system
I'm sure they'll cut the loop out the
loophole out of that one pretty quickly
because they've seen how it worked with
a seen how it works down in Colorado
Springs with the loopholes so I feel
like they'll probably make it so it's
like all right there's no no
reimbursement is not a co-op this is you
can bring I think they'll make it pretty
clear that is like there will be no
money they'll have to have a they call
it a Barcade is a theme so I just stand
there like I like supernovae at Springs
I can play some Street Fighter and all
you [ __ ] drunks are spilling beer on
me honestly I I would like a beer but
unfortunately I don't know how to have a
beer I like to have about 20 or 30 beers
so I just don't drink at all it's a lot
better for me because my money or my car
is drink a lot of shots
there's no drink at all but I can smoke
like the best of them so I wish all my
friends are at supernova drinking and
doing the ganja gourmet can go back to
the ocean or County to County there's
the Clean Air Act so you're not supposed
to be able to smoke in places but if
that's why I was saying you could get
that yearly liquor license that cannabis
consumption license it would probably
break that give you that rule override
somehow just imagine like by the third
or four
Cannabis night at the bowling alley bowl
night at the bowling alley
dude the snack bar [ __ ] crush ever
let's do this all the time
everybody was peaceful there oh my god
everything would have been better we had
so many fights in there because we
served tons of alcohol and you turn on
music music girls and alcohol and people
involved in quite some time yeah good
kids hanky b he post pics of that little
kid dude i get tired of seein people's
kids on [ __ ] daughter because yeah
anything else that you want to say on a
podcast since you've got a whole lot of
people listening to you go organic if
you wanna smoke you know turpis you know
the taste is smoothest cleanest cannabis
that you can consume you know go organic
if you're trying to heal somebody for
trying to get rid of cancer or if you're
trying to take care of people that have
conditions like Crohn disease Crohn's
disease or possibly an autoimmune
disease or anything that you're trying
to take care of you don't want to give
people
[ __ ] medicine you want to give them
quality medicine that is actually
medicine into their bodies they just go
get pharmaceuticals they'd go to the
pharmacy and get some pills and get some
poison yep please let's not poison
people that's not a very stupid [ __ ] on
our plants if you're growing the bottles
I'm not hating on you I grow a finals
you guys I like to use botanic air pure
blend Pro I use veg bloom I've done
plenty of that organic as [ __ ] stuff my
lifestyle in the way that I learned how
to grow I'm really comfortable with the
bottles these guys kind of inspired me
to step outside the box you may see me
do some some attempts at some no-till
stuff but we're not hating on you if you
are drawing with bottles do me one favor
and flush leave for at least 10 to 14
days I think 20 days if you've got a
longer strain go ahead flush for 20 days
if your leaves start looking a little
bit yellow you're doing it right don't
get mad at some yellow leaves at the end
that means a plant is using up the
nutrients that it needed and it is now
time to come down look outside what
happens leaves change colors and they
come off your plant is saying it's fall
time to the end you should cut it down
and take care of it alright that's what
I think just one more thing as I say to
anybody that is like hasn't started I
meant to say this is the last one
anybody that hasn't started growing yet
and if you want to get into growing and
you think you eventually do want to get
into organics and you think it might be
smarter to learn with bottles first
don't I would advise you just go ahead
and jump straight into organics because
it's two totally different things yeah
the the styles of grow you you know
you'll learn how to grow with nutrients
and like okay cool I must wish to
organics and it's an it's entirely
different you learn you start from
scratch if you have to buy so much
different yeah it's it's so much
different in it so if you want if you
know you want to do organics just go
from the get-go just go no till because
it sounds like no-till it's gonna cost
you a little bit more to get started
versa you're gonna have to buy worms
you're gonna need worm castings you're
gonna need amendments you're gonna need
modern mix 2.0 you're gonna need to get
a head start on yourself but I think if
you're buying something like advanced
nutrients or mills yeah
yeah so just get yourself some no-till
and you're ready to go you only have to
buy it once after that first harvest
you've paid for that richer and richer
and richer yeah round thirties gonna be
the best round ok be like you know like
like the like the I guess like the
forests are like like the rainforest you
know like the biggest plants in the
world are in the rainforest it has the
richest soil in the world so you know
basically your soils gonna be like
reinforced yeah its undisturbed out
there nothing [ __ ] with that except
nature so much humic sand things things
die and things recompose go ahead
definitely with compost will there ever
be a point when I have too many worms in
my pot because it just is
self-sustaining yeah they regulate
themselves deer they multiply relatively
quickly
they also yeah they regulate okay hello
I think the Rebbe actually gives a nice
little set up on how to make a worm farm
so that you can make your own worm
castings from the worms as well oh yeah
so you can get that going you can be
fully sustainable do the worm castings
in your garage because it does kind of
stink a little bit what yeah yeah and
I'm a vegetarian so I'm throwing in like
avocado peels and apple cores and the
tips of the strawberries gonna be super
rich my plants loved it when I was
feeding them and stuff they were
yeah yeah excellent all right man I
shouldn't even tell you how many people
listen but within 24 hours of releasing
this episode about 5,000 people will
download and listen to this between
iTunes stitcher and my website plus I'm
available on like seven or eight other
podcasting applications that I don't
even pay any attention to so a lot of
people gonna hear this so I appreciate
you guys coming and helping out the
growers glad to get you guys on people
love to hear this type of stuff this is
definitely information people need to
know because this is sustainable I
always talk about into the world
scenario you guys are gonna grow I'm
gonna be rating hydro shops it's not
just basically anything you have to do
top dozen amended it a little bit
differently depending on what you do but
you know it's good yeah like you said
into the world oh no like no till you've
got a sustainable garden out front
you've got everything you need you guys
be growing weed bottles remind everybody
how they can stock you want social media
so they can check you out and give you a
follow you can follow me on instagram at
frosty organics that's really the only
place i am you probably don't know what
I look like unless you know me he looks
like me ten years you like people to
follow you want this my new friend Logan
Graham listeners will love all of that
[ __ ] they're a bunch of looks oh they're
gonna love the wire wraps right there I
like that Logan juice box make sure you
check out his work sounds like he's got
some cool [ __ ] going on alright mr.
burfoot remind us how we can stalk you
[Music]
you found them through the girl from
your heart podcast I would appreciate
that by the time you listen to this
episode I will be at 10000 Instagram
followers I would like it if you would
follow me if you're not already my
account is Irie underscore genetics
check it out there's some cool cannabis
photography on there I think these guys
once again for joining me ladies and
gentlemen
if you want to know anything about
no-till if you want to know anything
about cannabis if you have something
you'd like to say about the show
something you want to tell me ask me
anything if you want to sponsor the
podcast you got a product you'd like me
to review if you want to tell me
anything it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you go to iTunes go to the iTunes store
type in heart podcasts find the podcasts
a little icon with my face on it click
on that go to the ratings and review
section give me a five star review type
in a little rating let me know what you
think about the show and I will read
your review on a future episode I would
love to know what you think of the
podcast
ladies and gentlemen Saul I have got for
you this week almost an hour so you guys
say that's episodes are too sure I hope
you guys enjoyed this longer episode I
hope you're in your cubicle getting some
[ __ ] done a hooker at the warehouse
getting some [ __ ] done to this extended
episode thank you for listening I want
to thank everybody for joining me
big shout out to Maddie and Spence out
there on the farm on the mountain out
there on the coast I love you guys and I
miss you and until next time take a phat
dad and get on with her
[Music]
where I be free from push and shove like
[Applause]
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 168
the girl from Earhart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roof spin for letting me
use their music on my podcast
big shout out to cat to the entire
mystic roots crew
everybody's having a great day while
they're listening I did not put out a
Thursday episode I apologize guys
Thanksgiving I wanted to kind of hang
out for a week I'm actually recording
the day after Thanksgiving hope
everybody had a good holiday appear
already survived Black Friday
maybe you boycotted like Friday whatever
you did hope it went well for you
you guys I'm hanging out just about 45
minutes ago hey - ooh banana pudding bar
made with 200 milligrams of THC
distillate ah it says caution contains
medical marijuana for medical use only
keep out of reach of children I could
see why you guys about 40 minutes ago my
life was different to our friends at
Shumate bars it's delicious check it out
at your local dispensary alright guys
friends if the dank team.com if you need
regular or feminized seats make sure you
support our friends there's a dank team
that dot let me try that again
the dank team calm there we go that was
English brands like our MC bank they've
got mile hike an adventure of course I
read genetics they've got the dank team
calm let's see who else do I need to
give a shout-out to no more shout out
since we're talking about seeds let's
talk about my recent breeding pot
project you guys it has been time
yesterday I check the mail plants I
check the female plants they were
speaking at me bro right now I've got a
male rise plant and I've got some female
plants what's in there I have got a
grateful dog female there's a lemon
Jeffrey female there are several
cookies-and-cream females what else is
in there there's white widow and there
are some other things in there suma
there also are Rice's in there so I can
make summarize f2 seeds there's a bunch
of stuff in the room but yesterday the
male plants are huge there are male
callers the length of my arms on these
male plants and they're just pollen is
just falling out if you breathe too
heavily
goes flying across the room so I didn't
want to drag the whole planet across the
room to where the females were so I
could offer few select branches that
were quite large carried them over to
the male plant the female plants and
gave all those male plants a nice shake
there was a huge cloud of pollen in my
grow room for quite a while I taste like
pollen everything tastes like pollen
around me my whole mouth was just coated
in pollen I had to take a fat shower I
had to clean everything up there was a
lot of pollen in the air so in about 50
60 days we're gonna have some new seeds
some new creations it's gonna be some
great stuff happening I'm excited for
that so let's see what else can I talk
about we talked about that I'm just
making I've got a check list you guys
cuz I get stupid high let's see what did
I do I don't want to brag a couple of
days ago on Friday night I got to take
my lovely date Jenny Beth to comedy
works to go see Joe Rogan was the
headliner there was a comedian named
Doron Horton that opened that dude was
[ __ ] hilarious you guys I'd never
heard of or seen him before when he came
on stage he walked in made a presence
and he crushed for like 30 or 40 solid
minutes and then he wound down and he
looked at the crowd and he was like I
think I'm done and he said ladies and
gentlemen Joe Rogan and Joe Rogan came
out and crushed guys Joe Rogan just did
his new comedy special for the year and
when a comedian records their special
the way they do it they kind of record
that special and they throw away that
material once your comedy special comes
out on Comedy Central or Netflix or
wherever it goes see so seems to be the
new [ __ ] but once your comedy special
comes out you throw away that material
you don't perform that anymore and you
work on your next hour and then at the
end of the year you want to put out your
whole new special of our material then
you do that all over again and that
keeps the commedia on his toes but Rogan
just put out a special so he's only had
a couple of months to work up new [ __ ]
maybe a month and he was here doing new
[ __ ] he went for an hour and a half and
about 45 to an hour into the show he
kind of looked up at the crowd with this
look and he goes I just ran out of [ __ ]
about like three minutes ago I don't
have any more material and he just
started making [ __ ] up on the fly and
kind of joke in and he's still crushed
it he did a little bit of crowd work but
he destroyed for a comedian I love Joe
Rogan style I love the way he does
comedy and I agree with like 97% of what
he says so that's always a great show
Joe does a show he wraps up we're giving
him a standing ovation he walks off the
stage and less than 40 seconds later he
comes running back on stage it had to be
like 1520 seconds later he ran back on
stage and he grabs a microphone and he
said sit the [ __ ] down
ladies and gentlemen Dave Chappelle is
here or he said you guys Dave Chappelle
is here and me and my date looked at
each other like what cuz what that's
what probably one of our favorite
comedians both of us I've never seen
Dave Chappelle she's never seen Rogen or
Chappell I've seen Rogen before but for
Chappelle to walk out
it was awesome Chappelle was [ __ ] up
you guys Chappelle was intoxicated
luckily since I've got some friends at
Comedy Works I happened to be front row
and as you walk out onto the stage there
are a couple stages a couple seats
actually on the stage but then if you go
a few more feet those next two seats
that are in the crowd are where I was
sitting and where Jenny Beth was sitting
so Chappelle just was [ __ ] up so he
just walked out barely onto the stage so
he was on the stage and he stood
directly in front of her and I and told
jokes for about 30 minutes and Shane
smoked cigarettes and drank Corona beers
he did 40 solid minutes of grabbing by
the [ __ ] jokes and material about Trump
and the election he did some Dave
Chappelle jokes he did a little bit of
weed jokes but mostly grab him by the
[ __ ] jokes like 40 minutes by Dave
Chappelle it was hilarious big shot
after Jenny bets were gone with me she
was an incredible date having a lot of
fun with her lately so big shout out
that was a great time glad she was able
to come had to get her off work a little
bit early for that and glad it worked
out super huge shout out to the [ __ ]
traffic oh my god usually i-25 can lick
my balls but that night it was smooth I
can't believe it that was awesome
everything was super smooth that day big
shout-out to Baker at Comedy Works big
shout-out to Comedy Works big chefs in
the entire Comedy Works crew Comedy
Works has a podcast you guys it's called
how Comedy Works if you care about
comedy if you're a comedy fan I of
course am obviously check it out how
Comedy Works hosted by Wendy the owner
of Comedy Works and a comedian his
name's Rick Kearns almost famous you
know he's kind of on the cusp
everybody's really funny and he's got a
great personality so check him out let's
see where else are we on this list of
things to talk about I want to give one
more shout out and then we're gonna do a
couple things who were the podcast I do
have some real content you guys Ella
shoutout to
my friend at the spliff cast please
gentlemen there's a podcast called the
spliff cast they gave me she gave me
like a minute and a half shoutout and an
endorsement the other day and I listened
to her somebody told me hey this podcast
shouted you out and so I checked it out
and Wow that's a great show so check it
out it's hosted by a lady named bone
Ellis she's not as hyper as me and she
doesn't take as many dads as me so she's
a little little more focused if I'm too
much energy for you if I'm too hyper and
[ __ ] you'll definitely enjoy her
she's calm she's more mellow than myself
and she puts out a great show so I
endorsed that fully thanks for the shout
out thanks for the support and you guys
support my new friend at the spliff cast
all right I'm going to open up iTunes
here I've got a couple of new iTunes
comments you guys I love the iTunes
comments and the reviews I would
appreciate it if you go to iTunes if
you're in iTunes if you get an iPhone if
you got a MacBook whatever you're using
an Android with stitcher but if you've
got iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for the girl from your heart podcast
when you find you got to scroll down to
the bottom there's a little tab with the
logo at the red golden green logo with
my face on it click on that go to
ratings and reviews it would be super
awesome if he types in a radio review
and then gave me a rating everybody so
far has given me a five star review I've
got 39 five-star reviews it'd be cool if
you kept that up but hey give me what
you feel I deserve that'll be awesome
I'm going to read the two most recent
comments this one just happens to be
from bow at the spliff podcast they said
she said one episode in and I can tell
this show is solid can't wait for the
new ones and to go digging through old
ones I can't grow but in theory and you
got all kinds of delivery on the theory
thanks man
well you're very welcome I appreciate
you for listening to the podcast it's
great hearing other podcast podcasters
complement your podcast that really
means a lot to me all the compliments
mean a lot to me but she complimented on
her show she complimented the sound
quality other than me clear my throat I
apologize for that
she complimented the sound quality that
means a lot to me so thanks for noticing
I appreciate that thanks for noticing
the show overall so a big shot at the
bow with the spliff podcast our next
comment comes from dab Smith's dab
Smiths has become a good friend lately
we've been talking a lot the comment
says I got a five-star review also the
comet says great show is always buddy
you
try to do two shows a week on the rag
thanks for the good podcast to listen to
every Monday morning when I start the
daily grind I usually get the show while
I'm prepping my work for the day keep up
the good work amigo you know I wish I
could do I wish I could promise you two
shows every week sometimes time doesn't
allow it this week of course being the
Thanksgiving week I just took it off I
wanted to hang out spend some time
actually worked on my garden a little
bit I hung out with that girl Jenny Beth
I've been talking about so much my kid
oh yes I do have a daughter and I'll
talk about her a lot on the podcast she
doesn't want to be talked about I'm
pretty sure on a podcast a little bit so
kind of took the Thursday episode off I
promise you the monday episode I will do
my best to get you Thursday episodes as
frequently as I can I appreciate you for
listening I'm glad that I can make your
Monday's better that was why I put them
out on Monday mondays are generally
shitty for people who don't like their
jobs or don't have the best jobs you
little get to grow weed people that
aren't artists or musicians your Monday
probably sucks if you're in the service
industry your Monday sucks so that's why
I put them out on Monday morning I try
to make your day a little bit brighter
I'm glad I'm doing that for you dad
Smiths thanks for listening I appreciate
you guys I would love your comments or
if you've got something else you'd like
to say and you don't want to say on a
public forum you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would totally love to hear from you
guys that's what we're gonna get to I've
got an email from a guy I'm gonna hit
pause and take a drink so I can quit
that's a little bit better of course
it'll come back because I took some dads
and I ate this not blaming it on the
banana pudding bar but it is kind of
making my throat a little buttery thing
but let's get to this email let's start
off with an email from a dude who said
call him Roscoe he says hey dude it's
Roscoe I messaged you for advice which I
got from you from your episodes and it
was great stuff dude keep up the good
work I catch up every Monday at work on
your podcast and have done so for over a
year now when I came across it in fact
dude it was around that time you said
he'd put money in a pot for your curse
words so you guys a long time ago I
didn't find it very professional to use
any profanity on my podcast and when I
would drop f-bombs in other words
I would try to throw I forgot how much
money I said it would put in a jar and
we actually donated that to a good cause
but I filled up a jar with a bunch of
money you guys and then somebody's like
that stupid be yourself I hate it when
he tried to restrain yourself and so I
decided you're right [ __ ] it
and now I say [ __ ] on the show is it's a
lot it's more of me honestly it's more
comfortable and I hate trying to censor
myself
it's how I don't know maybe it's not
professional but that's how I roll then
it's me I'd rather be me than not to
tell you the truth so she's continues to
say anyway safe to say due to your
podcast and the educated guess you have
on I have successfully grown a lot of
nice bushy plants awesome I'm glad to
hear that
he also says I've saved a ton of money
thanks to you guys thanks to you guys
seriously not buying from the local
riffraff has been a weight lifted off of
me anyway I've been thinking for a year
now about doing a podcast much similar
to yours bar a few things that I've
gotta back up that's something I don't
think about he says that I've saved him
money and a big hassle not having to buy
from the local riffraff I'm 6 foot 5 and
200 pounds and I don't worry a lot when
I used to have to go buy cannabis but I
can only imagine if I were not this
stature and I didn't have this type of
bringing where I'm from and I had to go
into my old neighborhood where I'm
actually from the go buy weed I could
just imagine how that would feel to be
some of those people in the stress that
that would be I'm sure people get robbed
and beat up and [ __ ] and get sold
terrible product that isn't even weed
that's gotta suck so I'm sure I could
lift a lot of weight off people's
shoulders if they're able to grow that
is I can only imagine that I didn't even
realize that just thinking about the
people you can avoid by not having to
buy herb that's helpful anyway he goes
on I'm rambling today you guys I
apologize I'm gonna blame it on the 200
milligram schumak bar that I ate and the
[Music]
pepper together oh that's a combo you
guys I'd be feeling it he says I've been
thinking for over a year now about doing
a podcast much similar to you similar to
yours bar a few things then he says I am
in the UK and there's not really a
podcast out here for the UK people and
you have inspired me to want to be that
podcast the law is changing slowly here
the NHS are testing it for the first
time now and all the MPs want to advise
our new prime minister miss
me to legalize cannabis oh that's
awesome
there's a lot of amazing stuff in that
one paragraph I have inspired somebody
to want to create a podcast for their
further the UK for the entire UK about
cannabis because there isn't one that's
awesome I am that I'm honored that I
inspired somebody to do that also I'm
glad that I inspired you to do that
that's gonna lead me to part of my reply
to your email it's also great that the
law is slowly changing there I know some
areas in the UK have really straight
shitty cannabis laws I'm glad that
they're easing up on that I love that
the MPs want to advise the minister that
they want them to legalize cannabis when
I'm pretty sure that's the military
police I'm not sure exactly I didn't
research that but whoever when other
when other people are like hey do this
that's really helpful I want to educate
people and teach them how to grow small
secret setups and have fun doing it UK
cannabis news culture education chats
and more if not illegal to encourage on
a podcast you know I don't think it's
illegal to encourage on a podcast but
where you are you may want to talk to a
lawyer because I don't know the rules in
the UK that could be completely
different I've been told that I'm safe
as long as I'm careful and we try to be
careful here on the show but you go on
to see could you give me any advice on
doing this any tips tricks et cetera to
a successful successful podcast and he
said thanks dude much love Roscoe they
also said PS don't mind if you read it
on your podcast which is good because I
just read the whole email on the podcast
first off thank you for the email second
I'm glad that I can inspire you to do a
podcast about cannabis third thanks for
being so passionate about cannabis
because it sounds like it's illegal
there and you're risking your life and
your safety and your family and your
freedom and your finances in your future
for this planet because you're in love
so thanks for being on this team and
that leads me to my answer my part of my
reply I know that you're the right
person to do this podcast because you
have taken the effort to reach out to me
to say what should I do
so that tells me right there you are
supposed to be the guy doing this
podcast be the confident dude that you
are
when you go to make your podcast talk to
the people just like you did to me in
this email because this is comfortable
and it sounds like you're a cool person
and it sounds like you can connect with
people so do that on your podcast just
be yourself that's the best advice I can
give to any person trying to do any
podcast be you if you're fake your
listeners won't know it you won't have
any fun it won't feel good and you'll
come across a fake and people can spot
fake and they won't listen to fake and
you'll get more shitty emails than you
could ever imagine so chill out be
yourself edit a little bit but don't
take out all of your mistakes I I
stutter I say dumb [ __ ] I say the wrong
[ __ ] and I talk over myself all the time
but that's me and I've learned to accept
me and it makes a good podcast just
being me people don't want me to be
appalling I'm not the president I don't
need to come out you out here up here
and speak some perfect [ __ ] to you
did you have to grow weed so be yourself
be comfortable get some good equipment
that's something I really should say you
don't need to spend a lot of money my
favorite set up is the zoom h6 on-the-go
I use a zoom h6 and I run for Sennheiser
835 835 microphones into that I'm not
sure what's available in the UK you
could probably get that or very similar
it's a great recording device a lot of
people use that for my big setup there's
a lot of stuff happening but sound
quality is certainly important people if
when people do phone calls on a podcast
or if they Skype in I don't even listen
so get good quality so I'd really stress
on good quality sound good sound the
best you can make sure that there's no
funky noise in the background or if
you're gonna do in a coffee shop and you
want that clunky like dishes and
waitress sound vibe kind of thing go for
that if that's your vibe I don't like
that I like it quiet I talk when I don't
talk there's no noise in my background I
love that sort of feel so sound how you
want to sound to achieve your sound
figure out how you got to do that be
yourself and then find content that
relates to the audience you want to hit
which is obviously cannabis and news and
culture and education and chats so find
some people in your community that you
can get on a show and build a
relationship with what I found is the
people that come back to my show the
third and fourth time they come back
they forget they're on a podcast and
they're now hanging out in my little
recording space and we just happen to
have headphones and a microphone on and
we really get talking
about cannabis in a way that we love
instead of a way that feels podcast II
and interviewee like you guys notice
when Jesse comes back the first time
jesse was here you guys a hundred
episodes Jesse talked like this like
said like four words like okay yeah and
now when Jesse comes on you can't get
him to shut up you guys so just kind of
build a relationship with somebody that
you can get on the podcast try to find
people that are experts in certain areas
of cannabis like I've got a guy Jesse's
my outdoor guy of course Sean is kind of
the organics guy even though he's hard
to get ahold of lately was our extracts
guy even though he's moved so try to
have guys that you can have like special
like you got guys for everything in your
life you got a you know weed guy you
know you got a fireworks guy those guys
for your podcast also so that's
something I could recommend here's
something that I could talk about from
being a podcast nerd if you want to be
noticed in iTunes get at least 8 or 10
episodes put together before you launch
into iTunes because your first eight
weeks in iTunes is when they will notice
you and that's if you get good ratings
and you pop out with a lot of quality
content iTunes will put you in the new
and noteworthy category which will get
you a lot more views and/or listen so
try to get eight episodes put together
drop a lot of quality content and eight
weeks and you'll get up there in iTunes
I feel like another guy what I've
learned about podcasting I got to give
somebody a shout-out here cuz I feel
like I just turned I channeled this guy
there's a guy named cliff ravenscraft he
was known he is known as the podcast
Answer Man if you go to the podcast
Answer Man comm cliff will teach you a
lot of stuff about podcasting there's a
lot of paid content on his website he
will want you to sign up for his
podcasting A to Z courses I'll try to
get you to pay for a lot of online
courses I have not paid for anything and
I have learned a tremendous amount about
podcasting just through cliff
ravenscraft free stuff through his
Twitter feeds through his email groups
just stuff like that so you can always
contact cliff ravenscraft or podcast
Answer Man comm that is a wealth of
podcasting knowledge alright
so Roscoe I feel like I have given you a
lot of podcasting information and this
is a cannabis podcast so I am going to
try to wrangle my listeners back up
I'm going to read an email about
cannabis next Roscoe I truly appreciate
your efforts I want to know how your
podcast goes if you do get this podcast
launched or if you need any help getting
this podcast launched send me another
email I would be truly delighted to help
you get your podcast going I'll give you
all the advice I can things are gonna be
a little bit different cuz you're in the
UK some of the setup may be different
but we'll get it going we'll figure it
out between the two of us we're smart
enough to get this going I can't wait to
hear your show and also thanks for
listening and thanks for the email I
look forward to hearing your show in the
future don't put it off because if you
keep putting it off it'll just fall to
the wayside and you'll forget get it
going all right you guys need a quick
drink and I'm gonna read another email
about cannabis all right you guys I got
a quick drink it took a fat dab I'm
ready to read another email this one
comes from you know I don't know if he
wants me to say his name let's see I'm
looking I don't have any indicator so
I'm not gonna see your name but big
shout out you know who you are I
appreciate you for sending an email now
I will it goes like this it says hey bro
loving the show been listening for over
a year now first I want to thank you for
spreading the knowledge and being a
voice for the cannabis community awesome
man first off thanks for listening
second I guess I'm glad to beat that
voice for the community I guess I'm just
the guy that grabbed a mic and wanted to
do that I never thought of that put too
much pressure on me anyway he says my
question I hope you can give your
thoughts on is a term known as bud
washing I had a good friend telling me
to try it in case you're unfamiliar with
the term it's where you take your just
harvested butts that are still on the
branches and you dip or wash them in
water I read it's supposed to get dust
particles off of your herb and make it
cleaner tastier smoke then he also says
thanks for turning me on to richie spice
I heard you mentioning him on a previous
episode so I searched him out and then
he quotes some Richie spice oh man
you're glad all right you're welcome I'm
glad you like Richie spice oh you guys
I'm a hyah [ __ ] tonight this Shumate bar
is kicking in I ate this an hour and a
half I should go and my 200 milligrams
distillate will get to you plus I've had
a few dabs so kind of floating around I
like it I love it try out so I'm gonna
kind of talk about what he asked here he
said is bud washing a term that I am
familiar with yes I live in this from
Jorge Cervantes Jorge didn't do it with
just water Jorge took a five-gallon
bucket
of he used reverse osmosis water you can
use water from the hose if your water is
okay if you don't have funky ass water
you can use water from your hose to fill
up a 5-gallon bucket of water and then
Jorge was putting 25 I've seen people
put more you guys but 25 is probably
what I would recommend 25 or 30
milliliters of 30% hydrogen peroxide
into a five-gallon bucket of water not
the hydrogen peroxide that your mom's
got in the cabinet the stuff that you
buy you get it at the Hydra store
probably and get it online but it's 30%
maybe 33 maybe 35% hydrogen peroxide
it's not expensive but you put about 30
milliliters of that 2530 mils in a
five-gallon bucket stir it up real good
and then you harvest the branches and
you leave is like kind of long branches
you know six to eight inch long branches
and wear rubber gloves and dunk the
entire branch into the water and give it
a swirl like freshly chopped you want to
chop the plants down cut off all the big
leaves trim it up like you're gonna trim
it up again later like you're just
cleaning it up you're not manicuring it
you're just kind of trimming it I've
been dunk that into the water solution
the peroxide water solution give it a
good swirl so that if there is perhaps
powdery mildew on there you can knock
that powdery mildew off that is a really
good way to get powdery mildew if you
don't have the PM on there I guess that
would knock dust off if you drew it
outside and it got dusty and [ __ ] but I
don't see how much it dust is really
gonna be on your plants if you drew
indoors in a good grow environment but
I've heard of this being done by Jorge
Cervantes and I've seen it done by other
people for powdery mildew and other
problems like that to clean that stuff
off so brought a little bit of proxy 25
to 30 mils and a five-gallon bucket to
clean water cut the branches into six or
eight inch maybe 10 inch sections it's
got to fit in that five-gallon bucket
dunk it in there give it a good shake
then hang it up give the buds plenty of
space when they're hung up when they're
that way and they're just gonna drip
onto the floor you guys all that water
is gonna drip all over the floor which
is gonna run right out and then it'll
dry keep a fan in the room maybe a
dehumidifier out there pay attention to
the conditions in your drying area but
if you're gonna do this you got to pay
attention
I don't let it get to you - you made in
there a lot of people are gonna say
you're gonna soak buds that were just
harvested you guys if you think about it
cannabis plants grow outside and if it
weren't for us getting in the way they
would get wet all the damn time I don't
think that every cannabis plant that
ever got wet outside got destroyed I'm
pretty sure that a lot of them got
stronger and they got tougher if you
look at the shape of a cannabis plant it
is kind of shaped like an umbrella when
water hits a cannabis plant the leaves
push the water in an outward direction
and it spreads it out so that it falls
down that tells me that you should water
the plants around that area because
that's where the roots are gonna grow
out because in nature that's where the
water is gonna land of course you want
to get it in toward the stock but the
outward area is a little bit more--
where you want it because nature would
spread it out so cannabis is gonna
search for roots out that way because it
knows that you guys also the resin
glands on your plant will protect it
from the water you're not gonna bust
that off by just giving it a little dunk
it's not gonna come off there these guys
that make ash they're using a washing
machine and ice to pull those trichomes
off of your buds so a little bit of a
dunk isn't gonna gonna pull those off of
there if you've already got a little bit
of PM or if you had an issue this is a
good way to get rid of it it's funny
because in Colorado I make the joke that
nobody gets powdery mildew anymore ever
ever since anybody infinite or figured
out how to make BHO everybody just
[ __ ] blast it even though it's got
powdery mildew on it but I wouldn't
recommend using a hole if it's got a lot
of powdery mildew don't don't use it get
rid of that product get rid of that
material but if you've just got a little
bit of a problem like people in Oregon
this year got pummeled with powdery
mildew and other molds is will not
handle your Brown mold this will not
handle [ __ ] like that but a little bit
of powdery mildew this peroxide solution
will get rid of it yes you can't do it
if you want to get the dust and the dirt
off if you drew outside a lot of people
find like cocoons or caterpillars silk
on their buds that would be a good way
to get rid of that stuff just give it a
good dunk that way you know it's clean
just make sure you getting plenty of
ventilation plenty airflow when it dries
it's gonna dry up like normal just gonna
take a little bit longer you won't
notice a difference I'm pretty sure you
can take a bud that did not get dunked
in a bud that did get dunked and dried
properly and trimmed and cured properly
and you can smoke them both and you will
not be able to tell the difference
that's my opinion on that so yes I've
heard of this I've seen it in practice I
don't know that I have personally tried
it but I've seen it done I've been
places that have done it it's kind of a
semi common practice in commercial grows
to tell you the truth because it is
legal in Colorado to do that to Budds
drone any commercial facility all right
I think that's all I've got time for I
don't want to start another email
because I've been going for close to 30
minutes and it's hard to do a long
episode by myself I feel like I just
start chattering get way off course so
to show you guys you guys know about a
web site known as patreon you guys feel
like you want to contribute to the
podcast patreon is the way to do it you
guys a lot of people have send me a
message like hey on the website used to
have a donation button that is gone what
happened to that PayPal did not like
having their service attached to my
website that was about a podcast it was
about growing cannabis they felt like
that was inappropriate and they didn't
want to be involved so they made me take
the PayPal link off of my website so
that's gone but what we can do we can
set you up with patreon gonna pull up
the website right here I've got it
stored so that I can make sure to give
you the right link it is patreon patr yo
n patreon.com slash grow from your heart
if you go there you can find out how to
become a member of patreon how you can
sign up and you can contribute to the
podcast you can sign up and you can
contribute it's like a monthly service
if you want to contribute monthly you
can throw as little as one dollar in
every month I would totally appreciate
it I'll see you guys what that is going
for is it will pay for the web hosting
for my website
I read genetics Colorado com it does
cost me a little bit of money to keep
that running on a yearly basis I have to
pay that fee and that's what keeps the
roughly our podcast feed alive so that's
all I'm asking for I'm not trying to get
rich off the podcast I'm just trying to
offset the cost of my web fees I've
already bought the equipment sometimes
[ __ ] breaks so maybe I'll ask on patreon
for help with that but so far I'm just
trying to pay for the cost of the
website I would appreciate if you
contributed I'm gonna quit begging cuz
it already feels a little funky alright
guys thank you guys for listening to
another episode of the podcast I want to
give a huge shout out to my friend Baker
at Comedy Works also shout out to Jenny
Beth also a huge shout out to everybody
at Comedy Works who always treats me
like a king every time I go there ladies
gentlemen let me right remind you again
that I would appreciate
if you go to iTunes click on the iTunes
Store search for the girl from the heart
podcast click on it there's my face on
there click on that go to the ratings
and review section type in a rating no
type in a review that's it type in a
review let me know what you think in the
podcast I will read your review on a
future episode everybody so far has
given me a 5-star review you can give me
as many stars as you feel I deserve if
you want to be a weirdo and stand out
don't do 5 but they could be cool if you
gave me 5 like everybody else ladies and
gentlemen this shoe mint bar is really
kicking in hardcore if you want to prove
got a product you'd like me to review
that's what I was trying to say you've
got something you'd like to say you can
send me an email girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd also like it if you
follow me on the social media on
Facebook it's girl from your heart
podcast I am on Twitter it's at g f YH
podcast you guys I got to 10,000
followers followers on Instagram its
Irie underscore genetics on Instagram I
am at ten thousand and one hundred
followers now thank you to everybody
that followed me and thanks to everybody
that will follow me because I am high as
giraffe [ __ ] I think it's time to wrap
up the podcast owner thank you guys for
listening big shout out to my ninjas
pants it's all next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the drove from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a fad
dab and give your mom a hug for me