now welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 279 of the Grove
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower the good
news smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists even someone
who is just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic wingspan flooding use
their music on my podcast big shout out
to Kat ku and the entire mystic roots
ladies and gentlemen I am dad the fog
out today it is a happy Saturday
afternoon it's been kind of nice it's
been super cold in Colorado but today it
is a nice sunshiny day it's still like
50 degrees out there but that's nice for
what it is right now I am taking some
dabs of some durbin poison live resin
from CSC it's the concentrate supply
company I picked it up over at Three
Rivers it's super saucy it's got some
crystals in it it tastes freakin amazing
holy [ __ ] I smoked almost a whole gram I
picked it up last night I smoked a bunch
of dabs out of it last night I smoked a
bunch of dads out of it today on
instagram live it will be gone as soon
as this podcast stands I'm gonna finish
it super delicious Durbin poison sativa
dad's got me rambley the flavor was
amazing it's got my head spinning I
started off the day uh just I woke up
alone at home there's nobody here
there's this like lazy and bored
Saturday there's nothing going on like I
got to get my [ __ ] head woke up had
some food and got myself moving chilled
out for a little while handled some
chores did some house stuff and uh no
weight and got on Instagram live it took
a bunch of dabs with everybody on
Instagram live and that really got my
brain moving the Durban poisoned dabs
and the interaction on instagrams live
really got my brain fired in the right
direction works perfect so thanks to
everybody who's joining me on instagram
live if you guys that don't follow me on
Instagram I really think you should
it's a Irie underscore genetics on
Instagram I RIE underscore GE and ET ICS
on Instagram check me out I do Instagram
live videos occasionally and go and talk
about whatever is going on with my day I
take some dads and I ramble people ask
questions sometimes I answer those
questions
I'm the wide feed but then I'll come
back and record them and answer them on
the podcast and that's one of the
questions for today actually came from
an Instagram live people we'll get to
that in just a couple of minutes what
else we gonna talk about you guys
remember I talked a couple of weeks ago
about getting sick ever since I got sick
when I take dad's I have just been
getting rekt high like holy [ __ ] I
probably smoked half as much hash in the
past few days as I used to before I got
sick and I just had this killer chest
cold and a head cold everybody at the
Grove got it passed around everybody
around here got sick but since then I've
just been able to get stupid high just
off of a couple of dads it's been kind
of nice it's um it's kind of not also
because my friends be here's a big-ass
dad and I'll take anybody on I just
gotta sit here for 10 minutes and
figured my [ __ ] life out again
there's been getting lit off dad's
lately it's kind of nice I don't know if
it's got anything to do with when I was
sick or if I'm eating a little
differently because I got sick and you
know when you get sick you try to be a
little more healthy you start eating
better got sick I better eat more fruit
and cut out all the crap so I'm doing
that again
maybe that's got something to do with it
but holy crap I've been getting lit up
by him and getting red again and it's
pretty nice another thing I want to
mention my favorite rig got real dirty
so I switched over to an even smaller
rig I'm hitting the hitman phase 2 it's
a little tiny rig the phase 2 with the
thermal banger I really like the small
rigs you guys I see a lot of people
smoking out of big gigantic dab rigs why
there's no need for that a bong when
you're smoking a bong your turn to fill
all that glass space that that whole
chamber with smoke so that when you pull
it you get this big old blast of smoke
whoa and then you choke and your eyes
turn red it's [ __ ] awesome right you
got a big old bong rip when you're
taking a DAB I don't want to smoke a
liter of oxygen before my dad gets to me
I want to heat the nail I want to let it
get still tore it's a little bit too hot
for most people I like my dad's hot you
guys I'm sorry that's how I like it I do
it people talk [ __ ] but I'm a hot bad
smoker I'll get tourists just a little
bit too hot then I put my dab in there
then I cap it and then that dab goes
from the nail through the water poof
into my head Wow
that's just like a punch to the face I
feel like there's no need for all the
air I just need some bubbles to
percolate and cool down the wall down
the smoke a little bit before I get some
I throw because it'll burn your throat
if you don't cool it now I don't like to
smoke dabs out of something without
water and get some water filtration some
bubbles but I like straight from the
nail through the water do the mouthpiece
punch me in the head that's where I want
my dad ah you guys are smoking out of
big rigs downsize see what it does to
you get a little tiny rig see how much
better it works for you all right you
guys I've been giving you breeding
updates
I've got a small breeding project going
on I have got a star dog female add
urban poison female and a platinum tangi
female plus a couple others in there but
those are the three we're gonna talk
about right now that have been
pollinated by King Solomon which is in a
rise male arise is the golden goat
female cross to a Daybreaker male that
made a rise the females that arise have
tested as high as there's been 35
percent consistent tests there's been 32
percent consistent tests also that's 32
percent THC 35 percent THC coming from
the arize females I found a male the
poor
well I really love the shape and
structure and the aroma that comes from
that mail if flowers in a great amount
of time I makes trichomes I'd really
like this mail plant it makes great
progeny so I have pollinated the star
dog the durbin poison platinum tangi and
a couple of their select females with
this arise today is day 45 of flowering
for those plants they got pollinated
about 25 days into flower so they will
be ready uh and whatsits got 45 days we
got about 15 maybe 20 25 days until
those seeds are ready we'll chop down
the plants well first we'll cut off all
the big leaves chop down the plants that
I'm hanging upside down and dry then
we'll cut them into smaller pieces then
I'll crunch them up into a little
Tupperware dish and get all the seeds
out and then I'll grow a bunch of those
and see what I have created honestly I'm
pretty excited Starr dog is a great
commercial strain it's a great yield er
it makes a nice rock hard dense buds it
smells real good
it takes amazing photos I love the smoke
and the flavor it's got a nice head high
to it it does what I want from medicine
so I think crossing it to the arise
which also smells good tastes good it
does this I think when I smoke it arise
makes my eyes feel real heavy and I miss
that in weed a lot of the new weed
doesn't have the I hide that the old
weed had and it's got that so I like
that I think by crossing the two I
should really make some I'm hoping to
improve the harvests of the star dog I'm
hoping to put that that arise vigor into
the star dog I'm hoping to get that
cushy smell I'm hoping to get a lot of
trichomes I'm hoping to get a lot of THC
I look forward to that one a la Durbin
poison was the other one that I was
excited about him just dabbing the
Durbin poison live resin I loved the
flavor of Durbin poison you guys the
flavor is amazing but also the high from
Durbin poison that sativa head thing
that it does a lot of people if you
would have smoked as much Durbin poison
hashes I just smoked the live resin I
just call all concentrates hash if you
were to smoked as much Durbin poison
live resin as I just smoked that most
people would be kind of in like a
panicky state or like a weird trippy
state but it makes me just right I
really love it it makes me a little
talkative but I'm drinking a Dr Pepper
and having some sativa dad's I'm trying
to be talkative but I just love the
Durbin poison the Durbin poison ah it's
a little lanky in the grow it could be
better so I'm hoping to improve the
structure and prove the harvests and
take that flavor into something that I
can pass along and maybe find a cushier
Durbin
sort of a flavor I just want to see what
I can do with it I'm gonna grow a bunch
of those and then we'll see where that
goes from there of course the Platinum
tangi that's gonna make just oranges I'm
hoping that everything just tastes like
oranges and it's covered in Tri cones
Spence and Maddie from the garden of
Weeden bred the Platinum tangi that I've
got and they nailed it it's a perfect
plant it tastes amazing it grows very
well but it's small it stays short and
[ __ ] and it doesn't yield enough so by
putting the bigger rise mail to it I'm
hoping to just increase the size of that
plant is my main goal I want to bring
the orange flavor I want to increase the
resin and I want to make the plant
bigger it's my main goal there I'm super
excited about those so this is the part
where I make it interactive if you have
gotten name suggestions for star dog to
arise I would like to hear name
suggestions for that strain if you've
got name suggestions for durbin poison
to arise I would like to hear your
suggestions for that for those strains
keep in mind I'd like Grateful Dead type
stuff I like reggae theme type stuff but
anything you've got I may use it let's
see what you've got for me throw some
stuff at me you can tweet me at G fyh
podcast on Twitter you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your art podcast you can go to my
Instagram Ayari underscore genetics or
you can always send me an email
it's a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I look forward to hearing
your creative name suggestions Star Wars
[ __ ] stuff like that always works video
game stuff is cool stuff from my
childhood of course I'm a GI Joe fan
because I've got a strain named storm
shadow let me know what you think I've
got a couple of ideas but I like getting
input from my friends so that's a little
breeding update you guys let's move the
podcast forward you know what I've got
an iTunes comment that I want to read oh
and before I read the iTunes comments I
should let you guys know that they have
changed the way that you can leave
comments and reviews or ratings and
reviews on iTunes I instead of having to
go all the way to the iTunes store if
you're using an iPhone or an iDevice go
to the podcast that you'd like to review
so you're probably already subscribed to
the show right if you're listening if
not search for the show search for the
girl from your heart podcast click
Subscribe it will now show up in your
your library click on library you'll see
all your podcasts scroll down until you
see the girl from your our podcast click
on there it shows the topic or from your
heart podcast hosted by Rasta Jeff it'll
show you that you've
downloaded episodes if you scroll down
it will say available episodes
previously played best of the podcast
and then ratings and reviews there's a
section there where you can leave a
rating and a review it says write a
review right here on the bottom of that
part I'm gonna click on there and see
what happens I'm not going to leave
myself a review guys that's cheesy and
hokey but there it is there's an option
to give yourself how many stars are for
you to give me how many stars you feel I
deserve a title or view review and a
review so I encourage you I would
appreciate it if you go to iTunes click
on my podcast
scroll down leave me a review click on
the amount of stars that you feel I
deserve so far most people have left me
five stars one person left me a four
star review that's fair if you feel like
I deserve less than five click on it be
honest I want to know what you think but
after you click on the amount of stars
you feel I deserve please type a little
review let me know what you think of the
podcast if you love it if you hate it
type it right in there and let me know
and I will read your review on a future
episode and that's what I'm gonna do
right now I'm going to read the most
recent review this one came from a
person who their iTunes handle his
lunchbox 3 which I like really well but
they say I go by chronic Coby they were
kind enough to give me a 5 star review
and it goes like this
I recently started growing this year and
was recommended to this podcast by a
friend well thanks to your friend the
first podcast I ever listened to was
your show and what a great decision that
was well welcome to podcasting I hope we
opened the floodgates of podcasting I
once you get into podcasts you're gonna
start listening to a lot of great [ __ ]
so welcome to the world of podcasting
your show incorporates just about every
aspect about cannabis from state laws to
tips on growing I've done a fair amount
of research to familiar my familiarize
myself with the basics and being able to
hear you touch on them again and such a
thorough manner was extremely helpful
hey man that means a lot to me I'm glad
that you're my my podcast is paralleling
your research and that we are matching
up and I'm kind of reaffirming the
things that you read so it's always nice
to have some affirmation so I'm glad I
could do that for you let me see where I
was also I really enjoy how you keep the
mood a good balance between serious and
funny yes we got to be funny I love
comedy I hang out with a bunch of
smartass people I was raised by a long
line of professional smart asses so I do
like to be kind of funny sometimes
sometimes it just comes
accidentally and naturally in the show
so I'm glad you appreciate that I feel
like keeping it fun helps people learn I
always had more fun in school when I was
laughing and my teacher was actually
being cool and not being a dick and just
forcing useless information down my
throat so thanks for enjoying the
balance between serious and funny and
thanks for finding me funny I'm sure
some people don't find my shenanigans in
my [ __ ] funny so I'm glad that you
do the message are the review goes on to
say thanks for all the knowledge and
time you've put into the show keep on
keepin on hey you're welcome thanks for
noticing I'm glad you appreciate it
and once again welcome to the world of
podcasting I hope you were listening to
a lot of podcasts I'm gonna give a
couple of friends a shout out if you are
new to podcasting and you're looking for
more cannabis podcasts I would say
listen to the dude grows show that's a
great cannabis related podcast and if
you want a podcast that is not cannabis
related check out of course the Joe
Rogan experience here's something kind
of random lately I've fallen in love
with the podcast they haven't put out a
new episode in quite a while but the old
episodes are wonderful it's called under
the scales with Tom Marshall yes I am a
big silly fish fan I am in love with the
band of fish I've seen fish a lot of
times I love fish the music of fish the
sound of Trey's guitar the sound of
Paige's keyboards the way
Fishman plays the drums the way mic
don'ts the bass it's all just [ __ ]
magical the way it all happens to me
that is my favorite band there the guy
that writes a lot of their lyrics is not
in the band but he is closely connected
with the band he has made a podcast
about the band and I am a few episodes
in and I am addicted to this podcast I
think there are 35 episodes total I
think I'm 12 episodes in now I won't
listen to another podcast until I finish
every episode of this one I feel I may
have to take a break just did not hear
Tom's voice for a minute but I'm
addicted I love it so if you guys are
into fish and you want a podcast you
want to know a lot about fish there are
two episodes back to back where they
interviewed Trey about his guitars
hearing Trey talk about his relationship
with Paul the guy that built his guitars
and how Paul became a guitar builder and
how it all just unfolded I really made
open my eyes to even more efficient been
following fish since 1995 and I learned
a lot through this podcast so check it
out if you're a fish kid if you're a
fish fan I think you'll enjoy it
there's a lot of rambles about a podcast
but I recommend it alright
huge shot it's my friend chronic Kobi
also known as a lunchbox three thanks
for the great review and the five-star
rating I appreciate it also big thanks
to everybody who's left our rating in a
review in the past that really helps me
out on iTunes I encourage everyone else
to go
leave me a rating in a review that gets
the show seen by more people the more
people that see the show in the iTunes
feed the more people can listen to the
show the more people listen to the show
that means the more people will grow
better cannabis more people will help to
legalize cannabis just spread the word
spread the love grow from your heart
podcast all right podcast world a few
episodes back I talked about sweet leaf
dispensary sweet leaf was the chain of
dispensaries that was rated and a few of
the bud tenders were arrested actually
13 people were arrested ten of them have
actually been charged I've got an update
for you I actually found an article on
the cannabis that tells me everything I
wanted to know so I'm just gonna read
the article from the cannabis this was
written by Alicia Wallace on the
cannabis staff the headline says inside
informants loopers and the undercover
investigation that led to sweet leaf
raids the sub headline is the Denver
Police Department search warrant reveals
details of the Wang and the year-long
investigation the article goes like this
a bud tenders six months stint at the
sweet leaf marijuana center in Aurora
came with no incident no incidents no
activity recognizable as illegal or
suspicious the same couldn't be said
after that employee was transferred to
the sweet leaf location off 38th Avenue
and Clay Street in Denver according to a
Denver Police Department affidavit
obtained by the cannabis things are a
little different here an assistant
manager alleged allegedly told the
employee during his first work shift at
26 47 West 38th Avenue you'll get used
to the loopers so with the old location
where this employee allegedly worked
they didn't allow looping but when they
moved them to this location allegedly
one of the employees told them you'll
get used to the loopers now let me tell
you what loopers are really quickly in a
dispensary in Colorado a recreational
dispensary a customer is allowed to
purchase seven grams of cannabis per
transaction now that there is been a
loophole found where per transaction
means you can walk out the door
drive your car around the building go
back in the door and make another
transaction and you can buy seven more
grams now there was a
memo sent out by the marijuana
Enforcement Division saying hey
dispensaries that's [ __ ] stop doing
that now they kept doing it now that's
looping that is looping and it was made
clear that it can't be done
looping is when you just returned or a
lot of people like to go to different
dispensaries which is that's cool
because that doesn't look like [ __ ]
you're not just going back it go
different dispensary it makes you not
look so shitty but they're going to
implement a tracking system
I bet because of stuff like this let me
continue with the article and stop
assuming things the article says the
affidavit one of several file does
request research warrants in the case
provides some glimpses into the
year-long investigation of alleged
illegal marijuana sales at the
denver-based sweetleaf chain the
investigation which is ongoing zeroed in
on alleged incidents of looping in which
individuals would make repeated
purchases of one ounce of recreational
marijuana oh I said seven grams Hunt
announced I'm sorry the maximum allowed
for purchase and possession per Colorado
law several times a day so they would go
back several times and buy several
ounces no I did [ __ ] up and say seven
grams but when we originally started
recreational cannabis in Colorado seven
grams was the limit that out-of-state
folks were allowed to buy and they
quickly increase that once they realize
people were just shopping around and
going place to place they're trying to
slow that down but now they sell them an
ounce and an ounce if you were from out
of state you're visiting here an ounce
is plenty of weed for you to have on you
and just be smoking if you're smoking
more than an ounce a day you got to have
a lot of people with you you got to be a
heavy heavy smoker or it looks
suspicious and you're doing something if
you're buying four or five eight ounces
at a time something's happening so let
me continue with the last paragraph of
this article here and we'll wrap up this
update it says on December 14th police
raided several Denver area sweetleaf
locations executing search warrants and
arresting thirteen bud tenders employees
involved in the sale of marijuana then
here's the final part as of Thursday ten
employees have been charged with either
misdemeanor or felony distribution of
marijuana so thirteen were arrested only
ten have been charged
there is another article attached to
this and it says attorney for sweet leaf
bud tenders files to dismiss felony
charges
the article is fairly long but there is
a part in here that I wanted to share it
says that the the sweet leaf employees
and it lists a bunch of names who were
each charged with felony distribution of
marijuana more than four ounces
acted within the bounds
of state law their attorney Robert J
Corey wrote in a court motion filed
Thursday to dismiss the charges the
article also states that amendment 64
the 2012 voter approved approved ballot
measure legalizing adult use marijuana
sales establishes threshold immunity
from criminal protection
Robert Corey claim the Colorado
Constitution allows for adults to
possess one ounce or fewer of marijuana
in additions to actions such as
transferring of one ounce or under to
another adult as well as assisting
another adult Corey roe those and other
personal rights included in legalization
amendment 64 specifically in muna
immunizes actions taken by marijuana
establishments Corey added so it looks
like they've got a good lawyer they were
trying to get the charges dismissed a
lot of people think that this was just
kind of a wake up call by the meed
saying hey we see people doing things
this is our way to let people know that
we're gonna step in and do some [ __ ]
about it
so I will keep my eye on this I will try
to keep you guys updated on how things
unfold once again I owe a huge shout out
to our friends over at the Cannabis if
you want to read more there are several
links at the Cannabis dot co ipod
Castrol they've been going for like 20
minutes in my throat's getting super dry
my eyes are getting bright and white and
lifted up it's time for me to press
pause take a couple of dabs put some
caffeine in my head put a little water
on my throat and then I'll be right back
and we're gonna talk about airy buds and
a question that I got from my Instagram
live feed about do airy buds contain
more THC and I started talking about
Airy fluffy buds and a lot of people on
my Instagram live feed right away we're
like yeah [ __ ] fluffy buds but guess
what
your opinion may change when I talk
about it after this dab you guys get
your nail hot and get a fat dab out take
a DAB with me and I'll be right back
[Music]
all right podcaster old I am back i just
took maybe too big of a dab of some
Lucky Charms hi cannabinoid full
spectrum extract from our friends at
apothecary I got super lip from that I
feel a coughing fit coming on here just
a couple of minutes so I apologize when
that does begin before I took a break
and got way too high I teased that I was
going to talk about Airy buds I was on
Instagram live a few days ago and
somebody asked me if Airy buds contain
more THC I wrote a little piece about
that and then I was on Instagram I'm
live again today and somebody said
what's the podcasts gonna be about and I
said it's gonna be Airy buds and a
couple of my friends instantly said [ __ ]
Airy buds I everyone's allowed to their
own opinion so I asked politely
why [ __ ] Carrie buds the answers I got
were they're terrible to trim yes Airy
buds do suck the trim that is very true
the other answer was zero bag appeal
which is kind of true other than it
makes your bud your bag look huge but
everybody wants those little rocks
everybody wants those cushy tight
compacted buds everybody wants not Airy
but they want dense buds they want a
nice fat looking bag of weed they want
some cream and some purple maybe some
orange in there ah that's that's what
people are looking for not fluffy crappy
shitty trim - lookin weed so somebody
the first question that started this was
do airy buds have more THC ah maybe that
depends on the genetics that depends on
your stream that depends on the grower I
don't think more THC because it's Airy
is a thing what is possible however is
there is more surface area of an airy
bud so that may allow for more room for
more trichomes because that is where the
oils the THC are contained so there are
more put your hand in a fist hold your
hand in a fist in front of you now
imagine if I were to coat your fist and
trichomes you've got a fist covered in
Tricon dry you can be convinced that
your hand is covered in trichomes now
open your hand now look at all the space
that would have been missed by those
trichomes if we had just coated your
hand and trichomes well you had a fist
now if you've got an airy bud that is
open like your hand you've got that much
more surface area to put trichomes
another way you could think about it
make a fist spray
and with a spray bottle so your hands
all wet stick your hand in some flour or
some powdered sugar pull your hand out
now you see where all the trichomes
would have gone open your hand now you
see where all the trichomes did not go
spray your hand down with more water
stick that [ __ ] back in the flour or
the powdered sugar see how many more
trichomes you just gathered so the airy
buds do not have more THC per se they
have more surface area so I guess if you
lab tested a gram of those if you tested
a gram of hi-five buds against a gram of
fist punch buds I guess maybe the high 5
open-handed buds would probably contain
more THC per gram because there is more
surface area so that may be a thing now
we need to find out are the buds getting
fluffy and foxtail because of genetics
or because of heat and that may help us
decide if we've got good genetics that
we want to use bit fox tail now you're
gonna say why would I even want it if it
Fox tails because if it makes a lot of
big Fox tails and it produces huge
amounts of resin and huge amounts of THC
grow it and make concentrates out of it
the market in Colorado Springs is about
70% concentrates 30% flower in Pueblo
it's about 50% in Denver I do not know
but I would assume it's right up there
with Colorado Springs and the 70%
concentrate 30 percent flower range
I'm sure edibles take up some of that
business but for what I'm watching in
the conversation that I had people sell
a lot more concentrates than they do
flowers and I see that becoming the
trend people are people are in a hurry
nowadays they don't have time to roll a
joint smoked an entire joint and then
[ __ ] smoke another one to get as high
as you want to be when you could grab a
dabber heat the nail take a fat dab and
be on your way also people are much more
health conscious they don't want to
consume as much flour and also dabbing
is just I like dabbing I don't get me
wrong I like to smoke flowers but the
trend is getting to where concentrates
are more popular concentrates sell more
so if you are growing specifically to
make concentrates why wouldn't you want
Airy buds that have more surface area to
contain more THC
I don't see that to be a problem if
you're just going to turn it into
concentrate so you just have to take off
those big leaves if you've got big fan
leaves go clip those off you can start
taking those off a week before harvest
just go in there and start cleaning up
the room whenever you're in there
watering
pick one plant just strip that [ __ ]
naked keep going every day until harvest
however many plants you got I know you
may have a lot of plants I know but just
start cleaning up before harvest so you
can just pull off all those leaves and
then a harvest time you got these area
buds that are covered in trichomes so
find out if it's Fox tailing and getting
Airy
because of environmental problems is it
too hot is it stressing out is it too
dry in there does it have a problem if
you have a problem you've got to figure
that out maybe you've got a problem and
you're still getting mad THC if it ain't
broke don't fix it but if it's genetics
that's making it foxtail and it's you've
got the room dialed in and it makes
foxtails and it's making a lot of THC
that may be a hash plant that is worth
keeping and I do predict that that is
the way that you're gonna see cannabis
turning for a lot of commercial grows in
the future you're gonna see more fluffy
stuff the bag appeal right now is all
about like I said earlier it's about
little acorns everyone wants rocks
acorns tight little buds that are
covered in resin very well trimmed you
want to see orange on there you want to
see bright green in there you want to
see purple in there depending on what
you're into the purple and orange
combination looks really sharp to me I
think that really has a lot of bag of
Peel that's usually not that we don't
want to smoke I want the bright green
stuff most of the time I don't know but
it's been all about the bag appeal since
you're not going for bag appeal for
making concentrate so you can grow Airy
fluffy buds if it's based on the
genetics and not based on a problem and
if those fluffy Airy buds are producing
enough resin to make it worth your time
and energy so if you've got a strain
that's growing fluffy perhaps a haze or
some sort of a tropical sativa that
takes a long time
and it's grown real fluffy buds when
you're finished with it make a shout of
it make BHO out of it make live resin
out of it and see what percentage of a
return you get see if it's higher than
your standard return that you get on
your BHO or your live resin just see if
you get more out of it and it may be
worth your time and energy just because
it's foxtail
just because it's Airy does not
necessarily mean that that is not able
to be high-quality concentrates and if
you're not picky
gonna put that butt in your grinder
anyway and you're gonna spin that
grinder and turn it into this little
mulch eesh it you're gonna roll the
joint out of it so if it's your grow and
it's airy and fluffy and it's got like
38 percent THC who gives a [ __ ] that it
was fluffy right it might taste amazing
it might have all the trichomes in the
world and if it's just Airy who cares as
long as you're getting your weight that
you expect that you need to meet your
needs
like if you're growing medically and you
smoke 2 ounces a week as long as you're
pulling 2 ounces a week maybe that's the
product for you who cares that it's
hairy there's nothing wrong with it
other than it doesn't have bag appeal
and it sucks the trim if you're making
concentrates it's the way to go all
right I feel like I've rambled on enough
about that
ah thanks to my friends on Instagram
live first off for asking the question
about more THC and airy buds the answer
there is there's more surface area so
technically by weight there could be
there could be it's not always a thing
there's not a general rule but if it's
coated in trichomes because there's more
surface area that is very possible also
big shout-out to all my friends who had
the conversation with me a little bit on
Instagram live and made me think about
it
I appreciate all of you guys I encourage
everybody to follow me on Instagram live
that way you can be a part of the
interaction has some questions there if
you don't wanna find me on Instagram
live of course you can find me on the
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can go to Twitter
it's at g f YH podcast and you can
always email me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com ladies and
gentlemen this is the part of the
podcast where I remind you about patreon
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
is a spot where you can contribute to
the podcast if you feel like this
podcast was worth a couple bucks if
you'd like to make a financial
contribution simply go to
patreon.com/scishow contribution to help
keep the podcast alive i do host the
podcast on the IRA genetics colorado
comm website I apologize for that
website it looks like total [ __ ] right
now I've been spending my energy more in
the garden more at work more on the
podcast and actually working on the
website I am NOT the web guy I'm better
at breaking the website and improving it
so I've got a guy that does that we
haven't spent any time together working
on that so I apologize the website looks
like [ __ ] but it is alive inactive and
is where the podcast comes from that's
where the RSS feed is created our SS
feed is then sent out to all of the
other services where you're able to
listen for free it does cost me a little
bit of money to keep I read genetics
Colorado comm alive I post a lot of
content there there are two episodes
every week one of those episodes is
about three hours every week and then
the other it varies between 30 and an
hour and a half just depends on who
comes over and rambles with me but it
takes a lot of bandwidth to keep that
website alive so the people that
contribute to patreon you were covering
the cost of my website you were keeping
the podcast alive and free for everybody
else so thank you I appreciate it the
other listeners appreciate it if you
were unable to contribute to patreon
don't feel bad somebody else has got
your back in 2017 we did cover the cost
of the website perfectly we just barely
covered the cost of the website by with
patreon contributions so thank you guys
I appreciate that they were covering it
for you if you want to help out I
appreciate that I feel like that's
enough begging but I do appreciate the
love and support alright ladies and
gentlemen I'll be back Thursday with the
throwback Thursday episode I want to
thank you guys for listening to me
ramble by myself for 30 minutes I truly
appreciate all the love and support I've
been getting a lot of messages on
Instagram a lot of emails a lot of
Facebook messages I've been getting more
and more interaction from a lot of
people people trusting me with their
Gardens trusting me with advice and
guidance
I truly appreciate it thanks for all the
interaction all the support all the
words of encouragement it all means a
lot to me I think that's all I've got
for you I'll be back Monday with the
brand new episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend Michael P and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
everyone
[Music]
people say that a Scentsy party everyone
jump run like the party comes the not
eat ready they say his name is Freddy
smoke sexy long time already
[Music]
they are not in the party
Tom do Lord or Tim do later to do Lord
or him dear lady to do Lord imputed unto
Lord or Tom to lure them to did it to
Lord or them till later to do Lord or
dictated it to Lord although now you
know that it is getting late and now is
the time for me to go away eh eh eh eh
eh eh eh eh
ay-ay-ay-ay-ay my friend Tom Tom Lord or
chimney lady item do lordos him dear
lady to do though though though do you
was the mouse to go away eh eh eh eh eh
eh my friend Tim Tim Norton dear lady to
do Lord autumns you needed to do Lord
although do you are the mouse to blend
the lip lip lip lip little delay some do
no no Jim do you learn it the Lord or
Tim do you need him to know told him to
load imputed it oh good night good money
good night you could avoid goodbye you
gonna go - boy you couldn't know you
could boy you gonna know you could've or
you could really good boy good night hi
we see
you
[Music]