[Music]
well yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 28 of the
iGrow culture podcast they call me Rasta
Jeff and I'll be your captain for this
adventure in this episode Spencer and
Jesse came back and they brought our
friend Michael and we haven't talked
about phenyl hunting but we got really
bad doubt so I apologize if we were too
high to be useful hopefully we spark
some questions so please send those
questions to me via email Twitter or
Facebook and I'll answer them on an
upcoming show of course the email
address is I grow culture at hotmail com
and find me on twitter under
anti-guerrilla culture or on Facebook
just search for I grow culture it's got
three ways to get in touch with us so
please send me your questions about
phenyl hunting or anything else you'd
like to hear about on the show and I
will talk about it on a future episode
proud to announce that this podcast is
brought to you by highly educated
titanium if you're using high quality
concentrates you deserve a high quality
titanium male made in America don't
trust the Chinese male or an American
knockoff made of cheap metals trust the
industry leader highly educated titanium
highly educated products are available
at Aqualab technologies com highly
educated has a nail to fit any rig and
they are the only titanium product
endorsed by this podcast big shout-out
to task ROK you were listening two hits
from the nail by task and Linus this
podcast is also brought to you by
nature's green remedies com visit
nature's green remedies calm for gage
green genetics lapata lab Sin City rare
dankness mile high can adventure IRA
genetics and many more
trusted brand nature's green remedies is
running a special to the podcast
listeners I've been coupon codes
September 14 for fifteen percent off any
order and he always get free shipping at
nature's green remedies calm this
podcast is brought to you in part by
hydro indoor growing supplies hydro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at sixty to seventy one
beach street unit f or stop by the new
pueblo location at 618 east fourth
Street in Pueblo Colorado check out
highgrove for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor growth
supplies and don't forget to check out
WWE grow Denver calm for current store
hours and special sales big love to tree
hugger calm this episode is brought to
you in part by tree sucker com live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
sucker calm for concert and festival
news and reviews look out at the cookout
with treehugger.com much respect to all
of our sponsors for making this shows
possible I don't want to spend too much
time on the intro let's get to the good
part here goes the phenyl hunt talk with
the boys thanks for listening guys
alright what's up ladies and gentlemen
we are back we are gathered today comes
before in court Church sermon I've gotta
got Jesse back I've got fins back on the
mic and we got a new guy we got Michael
on the microphone with us tonight what's
up bro do you uh you have a twitter name
or something people can look for and
find you on or in instagram so they can
check you out water to listen in to the
show back however colorado bearded a
purse on instagram colorado bearded
dabbers in the house Phoebe Phoebe
secret what up yeah big shot up to the
whole CBD crew so we're going to talk
about phenotype everybody here is a
pretty experienced grower so well
everyone will have a lot of input I
should explain what a phenotype is the
first thing I'll take one step back we
will explain a genotype the offspring of
two parents will make genetics and that
genetic makeup is the genotype out of
that genotype there will be various
phenotypes the best way I can think of
to compare it would be when your parents
make kids they don't all look the same
your dad's probably tall your mom's
brother little shorter one of them's got
blond hair one of them's got dark hair
when they make kids sometimes they come
out with kids with blonde hair sometimes
you come out kids with dark hair
sometimes you come out blue eyes some
time to come out brown-eyed plants are
going to do the same thing and that's to
be expected there are ways to minimize
those traits or bring out traits that
you're looking for but for the most part
when you're making seeds in the
beginning the seeds that most of you
guys are able to get your hands on what
a lot of the breeders are selling you
are going to be f1 f2 s or f3s there are
very few breeders going far further than
f4 there's one guy know that brags about
f5 which is really cool really
respectable so you're going to see a lot
of variation I just talked a lot I
drivel there's a lot of echo I feel like
I talked a lot about variation in
phenotypes and a lot of f1 and stuff so
in f1 when you take to plan a male and a
female plant those are now your p1's
when you breed them the seasons come out
of that our f1 that's the f1 generation
you're going to have a lot of variety
there some stuff is going to look like
mom some stuffs going to kind of look
like the dad you're going to get a lot
of tuition then you're going to get
stuff way in the middle between the mom
and the dad you'll get that perfect
hybrid and that's a lot of times the one
that everybody's looking for I'm in a
little further you'll make an apt to if
you take if you find a sweet male and a
sweet female out of those f1's and you
breathe those together you're going to
make an f2 f2 is where you come up with
something that we call transgressive
segregation which means and Jesse smiled
when I mentioned the trippy show transit
transgressive segregation is when your
actual progeny which is your offspring
outperforms the parents so if you take
tea seeds a male and a female you cross
them and that plant that comes out is
way more badass than the parents you
have just experienced transgressive
segregation so the s2 level is where you
really want to buy the seeds if a
breather selling those seeds a lot of us
don't really let you know what we're
giving you which as level how far it is
that's kind of personal stuff it's kind
of breeding secrets but those f2s are
awesome if you can get ahold of those
that's where a lot of cool [ __ ] happens
so we're going to kind of back up a
little bit the variation a lot of us at
the table seem to love the variation we
do what is called a fee no hon we buy a
pack of seeds you grow that whole pack
is usually 10 seeds and you look for if
you're not going to breed you eliminate
the female so hopefully you guys are the
mail to thank you thanks I'm dab dab I
don't know which is that good understand
yeah but thanks for watching my back so
you got to pull those mails and then you
keep it going I'm sorry I'm trying to
catch my breath also you got this
feedback you keep the females going you
try to find the good ones you look for
the traits that those are putting off
early on you can tell structure speed of
growth bigger bigger leaf size you can
tell kind of if you get a more indica or
sativa leaning phenotype notes making
notes pacing there you go a lot of
people like to kind of jerk the stem a
little bit and smell that and they think
that that's going to lead to a lot of
what it's going to really smell like in
the end yeah sometimes now what do you
look for I like smell a really important
note spacing growth patterns of early
resin production early resin production
so you want to be that resin about day
35 ish get frosty if things are going
real well for sure okay how about
yourself over there new guy you want a
louder or quieter total oh it's just
this thing over here it has talked about
this headphone thing I'm usually looking
for Jesus Lee a shorter stockier flat
shorter stocky plants yeah but not
necessarily i usually like more indica
plants that's why i'm usually looking
for a surgery stock your plan ok but I
makes good sense yeah I also don't like
when they wave around too much is
usually when they start stacking they're
going to need to be staked up
essentially ok slightly when I supports
itself a little all right how about you
sent home for when I groceries you can
usually you know figure out whether or
not your plants going to be a full
depending like sometimes I grow plants
under a scrog net so like the lankier
plants you'll get will be better for a
strong net in my opinion and then you're
you know shorter stockier planes over
your just freestanding plants that you
can stake down and don't have to give
too much support besides that but you
know bigger
smells and then I look for like
especially if I know what it's coming
from you can look at like your leaf set
and see if they start matching parents
yeah there's stuff like that and you can
know which parent you've gotta go all
right you said something sort of
interesting that leads me to another
point doing the pheno huh running a pack
of seeds and looking for that fee know
that you like both of these guys grow
difference everybody in this room droves
a different style yep Vince does remote
dragnet I don't do any Scroggin I like
to run a seven gallon pot so those
plants you guys are worried about waving
around I've got a tomato cage on those
early on in life so they're not going to
get back around appreciate your doing
that I want that stretchy phenotype
stretchy but I mean with some high to it
I like hey look that's what I'm just
gonna talk into my damn leg you know
where you come up to it's like like that
mouth a lot better that way I always
said one get up on the mic I'm the one
over here nowhere near the microphone
get punk with it oh no you don't all my
teeth on that thing yeah some days you
are you after your wedding hey thanks
for taking good care of me at the hydro
shop the other day big shout out to
high-growth Pueblo burn was working and
she treated me well it was awesome work
store looks great everything's nice and
clean cool there's one big empty spot
now where I was shopping feel sure it'll
be refilled already is nice alright
we're talking about phenotypes and
variation some people get angry about
variation oh it's been said to talk
about s once we skipped s1 s1 is when I
do a lot of ass ones that's a feminized
feed essentially or kind of usually like
if i take my grateful dogs to grateful
dawg clones of the same plant reverse
one so that pollen on the other one in
flower those seeds are not a new it's
not a new breed it's just an s-1 I've
self it and made speeds of that same
thing so that's an s-1 I find that those
a lot of people hate on feminized seeds
but if an s-1 is done properly and I
want to hear your guys opinions because
you've been growing my seeds a little
bit do the s-1 seem to marry their
parents a little bit more than the r and
the regular brush gently I bet how many
things like s horns like I had things
like I can't remember what it was but it
came out so different but so much like
it's like our one of his original pair
here comes at the Kabletown I think it
might have been the kaepa bunch of kids
and seats I'm gonna tell everybody that
Spence is actually who threw down that
white widow female that I use in the
Kabletown cross so that I brothers thank
you we're attributed so I gave him the
first handful of seeds i made out of
that to run for me just to say thanks
but yeah i saw that in the pictures i
could see the grateful dawg even if you
knew that it was that white widow mom
you could see her [ __ ] it all yeah I've
got buddies running it now and I can
look at them from you know four or five
weeks after they've been planted and you
can see in the structure and then in the
Leafs edge like what parent is related
to yeah sure not related to but close is
leaning toward you can almost tell them
keep that one full that 1i I'm getting
good with but the shirt I've read I'm
getting real sure with that shadow to
bigger lover bigger lover is growing as
you shoot it out of some cables my boss
he makes dank water hash and grows thats
train like a pro so good work bro thanks
for doing much my seed to justice what
is a your experience with destitute it's
a compared to say it f to a speedo mine
answer ah so the ass ones come out i
would say fifty percent of them look
like mommy and then the other 50 are a
little weird I mean that's not to say
for a breeder but they say you get a
mutant some [ __ ] when you do that for
sure you're putting it's not a natural
its cousin [ __ ] essentially nothing
it's not I know I'm not supposed to say
that word of the podcast anymore but
there's no better way to put that it
that's cousin [ __ ] good as to come
out even more uniform I'm gonna remedy
maybe seventy percent more uniform I'm
not the mathematician and I didn't keep
good enough notes i guess but they're
even more uniform I if once you get into
that and I didn't realize I was doing
something unique when I was doing it I
took the same grateful dawg of the
original female and Kate kepta taken to
clone and were using that reversed
female to make seeds again and then
making another generation almost
inbreeding it and I've gotten it so far
that those come out like clothes those
graceful dog sees notice that as for
generation I think it's kind of what it
would be I don't know a lot of people
that have done it so don't know how to
label it that's more she doesn't come
out there like clones of each other
growing seeds from clause which is kind
of nice for a breeder to achieve nfm and
I see yeah for sure those aren't out of
the market yet guys that's not
you're getting yeah I haven't made
enough of them to check but yeah he go
get him eventually it would be very
popular yeah that's gonna be very cool I
don't know anybody has gotten that far
you always find a weird [ __ ] yeah and I
see that's why I asked because I don't
think I've ever grown in s2 that i know
of so you know this diver I've grown up
to like after year f4 and so but you
know if s yeah how FAR's you mate if you
don't mind me askin bx3 a beautiful
Kenya so i'm at the point i don't know
if i want to back cross it one more time
because i'm pretty happy with what what
i got from it or if I want to start in
crossing it and start making I guess
would be a f1 f2 generation you know and
so on what percentage of those seeds now
are coming out to be what you have in
mind well there's there's two different
phenotypes and I really like to boa so
he got to Leah and identifying there
were some less desirable phenotypes and
I worked them out I believe on the bx to
generation when i made the trees so
industries of just the one phenotype a
call one night stand and it's a [ __ ]
secreto sharp yeah I'm gonna get my head
on why didn't I right that I'm like a.m.
yeah he just kill Kevin and then the
other one is just the depot dog and it's
real but you know as a Kim dog
stabilization project so it's a lot like
Kim D a little bit like diesel a little
bit more more more unique thing or not
unique but different things slightly
differently kindy but a lot like it so
guys what's wrong around a lot of crazy
terms here I and my best or our bad for
a kind of [ __ ] yellow right but now
they'll catch up we inspire them to
learn stuff if you're lost Google if you
want to or just keep listening and
eventually will fill you in I may not be
this episode but all the stuff that
we're saying will sound like you'll
sound like us in just a few months if
you keep your shortening yeah and to
other people and reading books and
experience
what's your favorite girl look the mill
Frank ok perfect yes that's a start
that's progressive everything yo we have
a reliable book you go to Michael my
favorite one I don't really go to it as
much anymore but was true leaving
organics grateful yeah trail until oh
there's my pickup book if I need to go
search something if I'm not hitting the
internet I'm going to go that books
pretty reliable shut up to the red eye
if you guys need help building great oil
yeah it's a great deal we talked about
Jesse and I talk a lot about soil
building on our outdoor lessons if you
if we go too fast if you want more
specific that book will fill you in
he'll teach you a lot for myself I like
the end Rosenthal oaksterdam course
guide because thorough iron bug
explanations it's got all kinds if I
have a problem that's the first book I
go to if one of you guys is like hey bro
and I don't know the answer I go get
that one and read it an act like I know
is that available to the public that is
available as a public I've never river
on pretty soon because I women in or his
book you ever just about every acordes
looks great too yes I hate to say it out
date ideas well it's like your dad wrote
it you know it's like that generation
yeah for sure it's a great book so is
the limo oh and I don't feel like milf
ranks with the dew tour it's a robber
Connell Clark is what I think you're
thinking of marijuana botany no no no
not that far record no no this one was
written the early eighties but the title
is how to grow or in the first chapter
two how to grow a million pounds of
skunk weed or some water yeah but
they're talking about pounds UK pounds
so ah yeah yeah Mel Thomas I keep fun to
say I don't know I my google or is out
of reach right now so we'll just keep
the conversation rolling for sure my
favorite is at this point in my life is
google so you got to sort through a lot
of [ __ ] but you learn where the
reliable sources are and when you see
one of their articles pop up you know
and most of the time I think they're
probably referencing all these great
books so hopefully and guys if you read
some stuff on google read three or four
articles on google yeah yeah think about
what you're going to do go smoke a fat
joint and call one of your girlfriends
or Twitter somebody here on the show and
say hey I just got this high idea and I
want to try to trick you into my plans
yeah and one of us on the show usually
we're pretty friendly folk if you catch
us at the right time will answer your
emails it takes me a minute y'all I get
a lot of messages I grow culture at
hotmail com I grow culture on Twitter I
grow culture on Instagram and of course
on Facebook feel free to message me you
can go to the IRA genetics Colorado
website and go to the form create an
account log in there and I make it a
point to answer those questions there
personally because that is my forum I
feel responsible so log in there create
an account I'll answer all of your
questions and if not my buddy Tony or
cut proof or good roll or somebody in
there will help you out really soon
that's a good way to learn a lot of [ __ ]
be leery of information from a lot of
forums especially I'm not gonna say any
names but there's two specific one
either banned from to forums for talking
[ __ ] about people saying the wrong [ __ ]
up yeah and I'm okay with that you get
oh yes the photos yeah if you're gonna
go to stuff wrong and I say that's a
[ __ ] you banned me you're supporting
[ __ ] so ban me i don't want to pull
anyway yeah yeah every learn TV i know
about any of those website yeah I region
etics Colorado deck there's one I really
want to say its name but I'm not going
to does it look like this emotion that I
make you yeah and the [ __ ] from that
website it looks like both toasting a
joint yeah so phenotypes i should
mention i want to turn the music comes
touch feel like i'm yellin the
phenotypes just to make you guys a
little familiar girl scout cookies is a
phenotype their team known phenotypes of
girl scout cookies everybody in the room
of shake in their head we all know that
forum cut that everybody has and then
there's the platinum cut but i guess not
everybody has if they brag about having
in cali is there more yeah take their
baby more episodes is this yeah that's
why
I'll the thinman all right then what ekb
show you oh gee coz that a hybrid or is
that I think if you notice not across
it's just a joke you know of it okay
yeah it's the funky crazy-looking one if
you've ever seen did somebody saying
girl scout oh gee sexually isn't
platinum cookies or splicing that a
hybrid I think that's a high okay what
about animal cookies that's a hybrid
fiber Spokane cookies and cream skittle
see ya guys cuz you do some stuff today
ah man you got me thinking I was cookies
now I've got a little bit of girls got
cookies hidden away over there jillybean
is something super popular you always
hear about that candy store fino in the
orange fino your father's chernobyl the
golden ticket you know when you go my
golden goal from seed you're looking for
that golden goat fino though it's just
like mommy plush berry that's a great
example like there's a black cherry kim
phenotype and then there's the space
queen dominant phenotype and that black
cherry kim or no above black cherry soda
sorry by triquetra black cherry soda the
phenotype its dominance of that is very
noticeable you'll know if you've got it
about 20 days into flour you can tell
turn off the grow lights and turn on the
normal eyes and look from the underside
of the calyx and you'll see the purple
for sure yeah I do get that flows go to
coastal known phenotypes yeah I'll pj
shorts move DJ short says that he put
that flow out that he released that
clone that's in Colorado he said he left
that out to show everybody what was
possible with those seats what the
potential of flow was so that cut that
we all have supposedly came from DJ
short shout out DJ short I have learned
a lot of stuff from Dave yeah I like so
he's doing the free we'd show up more
hits than race the new episodes of
[ __ ] awesome yeah listen to that when
you guys hear a lot about learned a lot
from just listen to DJ on that show
that's great to hear that he's knocks
Canadian who's actually
from canada for so many years boot time
I'm not touching that one I didn't make
fun of anybody you got some to say it's
been to do it no y'all leaned up on the
mic like you're ready to go home and I'm
going to return to read your question so
I could thank you some cheer to say do
you when you grow out of the pack this
is why is variation happening and useful
we talked about kind of why it's
happening because we're bringing a male
and a female and now they're making
babies and we don't want all the babies
to look the same in the world that's how
plants survive so how do you find that
variation to be useful do you want that
stuff do I want you wanna she knows yet
I mean difference between is gives you
you know you know if we talked about on
a previous episode we talked about how
many is penis you should keep in a seat
pack so you know that's where you would
want to keep a couple different
especially if it's a seat pack that is a
hybrid you know something like that
where you can get multiple variations of
your parents um so I enjoy you know the
different variations like some plants
grow faster some plants you know have
more side branching rule if it goes like
that yes I branching you know some
plants grow straight up and some plants
actually the bottoms grow almost as good
as the top though yeah you know those
are the type of french certain people
look for we need stuff the clothes well
and kids well I'm saw him like who I got
my car games coming back I'm coming she
better hey I really think they did
something to the water around here or
something because everybody's clones
everybody that I know in this circle of
growers was like I don't like loans bro
my colony Monroe of my entries of clones
small triggers my games back on like
spin set but for a minute there they're
worse how was College you were all
calling each other like you know you got
some clown it we're all getting back on
it yeah what what was going on it had to
be something in the water something in
the water seems like every year this
happens about those terms good to know
and also if you guys are indoor growers
in Colorado be prepared to be [ __ ] for
a couple of months because nobody's
going to want to buy your products
because i have seen an outdoor crop in
every other yard
over the past few weeks yep it's sunny
and everyone's out playing with their
trees so yeah good luck you guys are
possible the dispensaries are gonna slow
down a little pump that's [ __ ] never
mind I can't believe I ever thought that
would happen yes I've just been through
the other day was a really big up or
girl looking pretty much so yeah yeah I
think I've seen pictures of that looks
pretty damn Califia oh yeah it's really
meet greenhouse it's a lot of really
cool fluorescent lights I said I talked
about that place on the show if
anybody's gone by and taking cool
pictures of that greenhouse I talked
about tweeting me some pictures I'd love
to see it it was my idea we went we
sought the night of Jesse's letting and
it was awesome it was really great how
often do you get to do a phenyl hunt bro
um not as often as i'd like to i wish i
could go from seed every single time but
i have some other plans i have to
maintain and you know best way to do
that is clone and run clones and you
know he's making la distancia yeah
that's again get your liable medicine
freeze the patients and that's what we
only I'm a this winter i'm planning on
growing pretty much exclusively seed so
other than just mother maintenance so
have you ever ran a whole pack of seeds
and not gotten anything worth keeping
yes me to you yes you're running you
your shops got a nice amount of feeds
going right now and I bet you've got
high hopes for that there's a lot of
different ones going on in there too so
it's very sad if you don't find a couple
of keepers of each one it's going to
feel like a lot of work for nothing
already it's looking like there's a
couples that are setting themselves
apart from the others so it's pretty
promising and how many how many days in
are those they are there in veg still so
how long is I think they're on day 23 in
[ __ ] they look good in your pictures
yes we're and they look great check him
out guys he looks great on Instagram
he's got some stylish glass and some
stylish plants then he takes the biggest
dubs what yeah oh my gad comically why i
don't know
efficient i think if this might be a
friendly the personal challenge person
that's a turn we were i was talking on
an episode it might have been the last
one that i'm going to put the gigantic
dab thing to arrest for myself because
I'm getting old on the highway oh you
know any thought that you I'm rough yeah
it takes a little bit of effort it kind
of if you uh if you do in the
mid-afternoon and you don't applying it
right you can ruin your whole day how
many times you can do a gram dab and
survive you know i said i think what i
actually said was in my lungs I realized
my lungs have so many inhales and
exhales and I think taking a gram dab
it's just like you're just using up cat
lives when you do that that was building
to bless you could have had but instead
you smoke a gram of hash that's kind of
how I feel about it or the road you're
gonna wait 30 tuberous breasts breasts I
don't waste any breath especially that
many but I mean what better way to do it
then taking the hit hash at least you
weren't breathing in concrete dust or
some you know i've done that before--not
more a be better than ask them like yeah
definitely prefer the dad and yeah why
that means it got really loud for a
second that might have been my fault you
guys want to give a shout out to this
hash that we're hitting here that it's
tasty myelin trichrome heavy extracts
yeah good work guys for sure tell you
off the Halon honey hole even shout out
suspense for bringing the Halon honey
hold out on point all right this
conversation has gotten off track
because I'm dabbed out what else do we
want to talk about about phenotypes you
guys ok I got a question I like you
super cool what is water bags feet
consider like CT find in like mostly s1
so you would say they had considered as
you don't know the parents yeah yeah
it's probably just an [ __ ] what if
well you know the parent if it you get
the seeds out of them but you don't know
what the mail was yeah I'm playing in
the fall underwater video have you ever
heard of points like all right so why we
having yeah slightly harming and seeding
the plant and then taking the seat from
there and growing that
with that that's a nice one okay that's
how soma sorry someone spilling your
beans that's how silma actually makes
feminized seeds he takes a female and
flowers are for too long and then after
she goes like if you got a nine-week
strain he lets it go for 13 in about
week center Tino start Pitts Pitts not
fallen and then he gathers that and
throws it on the next crop that he makes
her car so didn't have you jerk oh then
he says you can smoke those buds to if
you can go down most of the plant just
leave enough of it to her him out and
spit out fallen let me smoke the wrestle
even if you can't smoke it you could
definitely probably distract it there
you go yeah have you heard of his a fire
technique oh yeah I'm stressed plants
out yeah that's a little weird to me
yeah makes sense I mean I guess I
understand this theory sitting on dad
where he's coming from foot the forest
fire my man is that is more organic than
mine yeah that's a pretty hardcore do
yeah you don't want to smoke the flowers
of the plants that I have reversed you
don't want to smoke those you can smoke
is for sure if you don't want to smoke
mine i don't think i would i would
encourage it yeah yeah they've been
sprayed with chemicals that I don't
trust smoking yeah hmm kim dogs back
seat guys so don't ever doubt bag see
under the eyes in some great i conferred
I've had a dream so who crazy looking
stuff from Bad season done clever and it
could be an f2 you could experience
transgressive segregation it could
outperform its parent like that you
don't even it will because you don't
know what's parents were oh yeah I get
out of formal well a girl you know the
person who was managing the room could
every good i do it but good oh yeah
totally that's about i mean i think
people on Instagram sell packs of s ones
for 100 bucks not yeah one of those
forms side so so effective ones go for
like freaking 8 grand voyage crediting
some old seats go for ridiculous money
some of you rascal stuff in a forum yeah
really high price recently his when i
went to cali i met up with another
person through Instagram and stuff and I
had a fire the original fire OG cut from
Rascal and they said it was 20 G's is
how much is not an expensive clothes yes
that's an expensive clone what are you
down for a man's worth it though I'm
doing a little bit of a lemon cookies
from JP Wallace nice full mount lemon
cookies full melt shout out to JP
wellness I heard a lot of good things
about that place Oh since your ringer
just canceled its cool ya hear from the
springs check them out they got a pretty
good extract I'm gonna try to cut that
out of there sorry that's the torch you
guys if you're wondering it's time for
me to take it bad to let me take a sip
of something and make a dad anybody got
anything snazzy to say cheers the GUI oh
yeah snazzy we'd got anything longer to
say yeah are you working on any breeding
projects right now Jessie yes what do
you got going on in here and your
project and I am I guess and I'm really
happy with bx3 of depot dog so I think
I'm gonna make a whole bunch of feet of
it and maybe get it to the public so
we'll see I no way you can make that
happen yeah yeah all right don't let the
crosses on the depot dodge again so they
can get him excited it's a old school
Amsterdam I don't really have a lot of
heritage on it but it's a I don't know
the producer of it but it was asked in
case I believe it was a freebie from an
old amsterdam feedback but had really
really hurt early resin production and
it was a gun case so the initial reason
i used to din the cross was he was very
different than Kim D and it was very
easy to spot out the phenotypes of
remaining garter towards him so I kind
of used it as a tool to make the Kim
line more pewter so glad that Kim was
discovered yesterday s that's my
favorite do you have a restraining
Tanner town like a late
need I need it Kim for back bad can be
even so anybody out there it's got a
killing in camera here flora candy for
Jesse we can trade we can trade if
you're in Colorado you're an adult we
can do this you know oh maybe we can
find some seeds or something for you
subscribe I forgot a pretty cool girl
scout cookies cooked so thirsty for that
cookie still I've heard I've got the
gorilla glue for and I've got platinum
OG so let's talk yeah I wonder if ours
are the same target relig Liz yeah yeah
we should trade cut I'm can write
because there's different phenotypes
with others in there but yeah there's
the more sour diesel e1 and then this
one that has more that chocolate I
that's in it what is girl skipper don't
we lose that we've moved on it I a
should make girl glue we should read
those major um it is Goku be prepared
hold on let me think about it Spence no
I know it's like it's like a bugged
sauerkraut it soured of chocolate ah and
chocolate or something that sounds tasty
something else and very lanky I can
already tell advance that those [ __ ]
are lanky really yeah those are taller
than everybody else already I'm the ones
I've seen I pretty easy to point out
there real pushy and stuff ya know yeah
bushy link eNOS I'm yeah but yeah but
they're you they grow with more vigor
than a lot of the other challengers
roast lamb yeah whoa sorry damn gotta
text coming in because you thought is
not really advanced is the word it may
be an antique uh two and a half years
and in the phone world those manteca
yeah it kind of makes a lot of weird
noises all right so uh yeah that was a
good rant about finos because that
gorilla glue what's the other number
there's four and what's the other one
just for is all I've heard of there's
like a seven or a three or some [ __ ]
that worried about man we need cuts it
down once we can compare them you guys
find uh yeah try that yeah I've got a
lot of great [ __ ] for trade will be
bring in a KNG to show
colorado soon to not Dutch ang because
there's a strain that everyone calls the
tange 'that is not tangi there's almost
like any goddamn tangerines or anything
zero oranges yeah but why'd you call
that the tenth what are you doing I
think it's flo goddamn it pretty good
yeah I think it's blood quit tryin to
front um what are you drawing now bro uh
platinum cookies animal cookies Gorilla
Glue Minerva shine haze cookies and
cream I was cookie crazy cookies and
cream that won the cup and whoever took
that name cookies and cream I wanted
that that was a but it goes has anybody
ever smoked star charger or a felony a
firefighter the stocks are up to affect
bump like a sudden I figured it it is
polished don't know either way smoke
this starfighters a rare dankness or the
exact genetic fall I remember use chat
talking about that package phoebus or a
lot of my yeah oh but that and then
angels coach is what that's got going
and then I have a phenyl hunt going
right now by the way which sucks
everybody if you have timers that have
more than one program make sure you go
through your programs and make sure
there's no extra timers chillin so it's
cool you can catch it but I call it
thank god you almost flower huh did you
almost oh I was almost run coward I'm
with almost all our dog [ __ ] so I had it
like well I was my room some plants look
good so I don't really know like its I
saw a wrong timer but it was just weird
because there was no off timer just on
but I've been in my room and it's not on
I'm doing with those fancy digital
timers yeah I'm going so when you reset
your time a guy just reset it the whole
day like yeah just hit reset and clear
it out don't just try to go and re-set
everything actually hit the button
default that [ __ ] but I think they'll
be fun i've got a couple that are just
growing right through it and it didn't
matter to it so kind of happy with those
why Harley what life cycle are you
running you doing the 12
dreamtone philosophers that's actually a
good way to stress attached your plants
i was mentioning this this is a since
our fee no topic kind of got side well
here we ran out of [ __ ] to talk about i
think i stress test my plants before i
read with them i'll take a female and
put it in a real i'll take a bunch of
them like I've got four or five new
clones I'll put them in the room and
I'll run it on 12 12 for two weeks and
then about day 15 I'll turn it off for
24 hours day 15 will turn it on for 24
hours and then I'll put it back on the
opposite 12 12 so if I was coming on to
tennis before you know I'm coming on at
ten at night and I'll run that for a few
more days you know just watch them grow
they'll kind of freak out and then I'll
put it back into the normal flower cycle
and that really pisses off normal time
and you will be a lot of things start to
throw nanners and be that her mattress
we wish mulund earlier and don't do with
them if they throw those bananas on you
because those are going to be
hermaphrodites in the future though
cause you can reach your passion some
same goes for mouth but I don't want to
give away too many secrets so we'll just
leave it at that I like a yourself yeah
male stuff is all that's all proprietary
stuff that you keep on the down low well
give them that you know what people
breeding with a bunch of hard as nails
now or the females you know yeah you can
usually spot a nice firms male the top
clusters are too close together this
looks like they got fur between us it's
start to look like like a [ __ ] willow
or something a fox tail sort of turned
out Vale you can tell by that [ __ ] you
just want those big juicy balls and I
will never say that ever we'll talk
about what kind of treats we look for in
a meal on another episode gent you'll
come no we won't ah no we totally I
guess we'll maybe eventually like on
episode like 500 once everyone's listen
for a long time and loves us what you
doing over there Spencer looks dangerous
this is being a Piru alright that is
fire and plastic he just puts it down
like I already know how this [ __ ] ends
in the [ __ ] outside turn at the house
going that's up alright so we've been
going for a long we've been at it for 35
minutes you guys got anything you want
to talk about on a podcast anything
you've ever wanted to say no everyone
just kind of shakes their head and goes
nah bro we're good I just have one side
note back to the the faint no hunting
that's good because that's what
everybody came to the show for I was it
was one big thing I look for is I grow
mostly indoors so I liked I plants that
respond well to topping and super
cropping I get a nice even canopy versus
having a lot of lower growth and certain
trains really don't like topping well I
remember purple subs phenotypic
expression that is a very see no
physical expression so things like
purpling ah even some strange kind of it
because if you have an unhealthy plants
that have purple stems to right but but
i have seen healthy plants it's just a
purple booms girl scout cookies program
up and free of Ichiro see and do nothing
about it yeah girl scout cookies gets
black and gets purple and I crazy it's a
black leaf black leaf company or black
leaf society there it is why a lot of
had a couple dads mm-hmm that's a
hashtag that is a hashtag checking out
it's good it's a lot of cookie chefs you
might find some of my cookies on there
yeah things from with all of our sins
had something really great to say and
then backed up from the microphone aback
down or enough for now all right you
don't have to say it I don't know okay
the notes are done bro we said all the
stuff on my notes you're looking over
here like what can we say yes I'm you're
thinking like a press pause well you
think don't be ascared to kill your red
hair bird oh yeah did you guys hear that
Michaels taking a daddy said don't be
afraid to kill off those plants that are
not performing that server ID and when I
do free notes i should start full fino
hunts i usually do probably like a
couple feet back strap just woolen um
and it's kind of survival of the fittest
or Mises seeds I'd like to not really
like feed him too much I kind of like to
just let him
see which ones are going to do their
thing until I have to start you know
giving a food until yeah like I kill
ones that if you're if it's going to get
over grown as a seat it's probably going
to get over grown as a plant so I just
get rid of it right um and there's
nothing wrong with getting rid of that
just makes your hunt smaller more now
you can focus on other things instead of
now you have one less plant yeah like
picking players for the team you don't
want those slow runners or the guy that
can't shoot you don't want me on your
team you want a lot of spam I'll take
you take money to you when you block bro
as I'm saying stay in man right in front
of the new pieces go out both of us just
like a fish nobody we're both about 65
issue off you're wondering why we're
talking about sports on a weed podcast
advanced you doing a secret shop see you
there I should be at the secret cup I
think I'm going with little calves so
that should be a good time when I think
that September well holding seven okay
yeah that's good cuz I had something
else going on in September since you're
playing with that carb cap we're going
to give a huge shout out to the man task
ROK these are blue carb caps these new
color titanium pieces are dope don't
even know about this [ __ ] right here
yeah we got that new new the substance
coming out we're pretty recording this
one because I was out of town when we
should have recorded this so we're
pre-recording but this stuff is new and
they look good bro the color is not
coming off it looks just like the other
carb caps i like it good work brother
shoutout task ROK and highly educated
titanium yeah cuz over looks like
anodized bazooka I think that's the word
but I'm not certain take it with heat
and change the colors don't attend a
rainbow color when you'd be a little
more variation in it I believe if it was
the process I'll ask him so that way we
know since I oh yeah that's anodized I
mean I have no doubt task as uh you know
I was attacked by putting out top
quality [ __ ] so he's got a very high
quality anodization process
Lana giant puzzle is here it could just
be me but I just perform many people
that look like trash yeah I like people
like dressing up like cash cash but just
jeans and a t-shirt brother not really
an outfit or a costume ah [ __ ] here's
the good sized AB there's a big ol water
hash that oh yeah I'll take that one I'm
gonna let spins go ahead and eat up the
honey hole for me the host a little hey
guys thanks for bearing with a bunch of
potheads I know we tried to have a
phenotype discussion it feels like we
covered a lot see if we can name off any
other famous sanitizer or even some of
your own heart of gold the other room
Michael's got some starburst it's a
question but I'm growing out a grape
stomper OG and does anyone know of any
popular phenotype variation that's that
tray there's one that actually tastes
real gravy that spent loves a super
grapey phenotype my and it almost looks
when the blood start to grow their real
dense and they look furry like yeah
there's a joke yeah that's the one that
I really liked a lot of hair a whole lot
of odd none earn more crisis yeah kind
of try and kill me and just it's got a
real rigid structure it just looks real
crazy in the texture of the blood
themselves alright guys I won't be
talking so hopefully one of these guys
covers the dead air space while i take
this tab and then I'll correct the radio
silence all three of us just looked at
each other like ah hakama Jeff totally
leads the conversation for us have any
guys ever had see that she grew and
didn't take clone though and ended up
being like some really really good [ __ ]
I need Josh yeah Eddie order of my life
all of us have experienced that yeah
right off of the staff there are many
fish in the ocean but I lost a alien dog
fee no that was really bomb girl sad
about that it was when I private for you
to know it wasn't the alien dog that
that is from a very popular breeder
i recently lost my flow strain access
books everybody think everyone in this
room has that I know I'm get it back but
what am I gonna have to get up now
that's a good dad thank you I had a I
grew DNA genetic Holy Grail khush for
the scene and it was fire if you guys
are looking for a dank stinky fish
that's mostly indica it'll just set you
down it tastes like stinky gunky feet
it's harder to grow it's a [ __ ] to grow
and it will not clone i try i gave cuts
to other people they couldn't get it to
clone but that stuff was awesome DNA
genetics holy grail cush I just wouldn't
I've got a pack of it there's yeah he
just released a whole bunch of them I
think but well I had a lemon skunk that
uh from uh from arion yeah sure hit hit
hit I want to go to name him but like
there's a good phenotype that's what I
wanted to get me with oh okay yeah
Duncan voltage we had the DNA one foot I
think they're pretty much the same thing
anybody seen okay so would notice the
stupid question we show recording we're
still totally record okay I'll ask the
student question anyway but I'll
knowledge if you don't know the NC
you'll know it's over oh no I pages to a
question so oh geez are not a phenotype
they are like it would be a clue in
Jinan sorry okay yeah yeah for sure
lately I think og is just a sticker
using been three or a seat breeder for
dollar signs very well boat yeah I say
every true oh geez like two came out
I'll Chico she had the original ones
those who locker yeah from according to
the story there's a buncha turn the
phenotypes of the genotype poll
I don't know I underdog that's a good
story that I really think there's two
underdogs and both of them are pretty
well known so I you guys got it speaking
of G coolish I'm gonna shout out another
podcast it's called the Adam Dunn show
they did an episode all about og cush
rumors from the road no I went up today
i have not had a chance to listen it's
not on itunes right now they're having a
little problem but you can listen to
them they're on high too yes youtube and
I think it's I cannabis radio Tom and
you can either one yeah recorded shows
oh no I Canada Stockholm those guys
talking about a lot of great [ __ ] on
YouTube p Adam don't you yeah shadow sad
have done in many an office they
probably don't listen auto show because
they have their own but they get a lot
of cool guests on because they're in
Denver and because Adams got a seed
company that is very well known from
crowd at Denver self which seems to be
pretty well connected by look out which
is great check out Mitch shun haces new
book the cannabis aficionados handle
book I believe it's called yes correct
yeah might I had memory just pulled that
out of no way easy to remember pothead
things have you ever grown any th seeds
no not actually all the way oh yeah I
grus agents out there's a freebie okay I
didn't really like it matt davis is my
thing i've heard that called old man's
weed so there you fat look at that make
sense i wasn't ever a fan of the stage
and it won cops yeah oh yes stage i did
like it i know its acronym but it does
have a say gee I take it to it mental
probably now like it's what everybody
says that probably even a little late
but I like push in I haven't I said
nervous much as like a true cam or a
really really good sour so if some
showers but not like there's a sour
diesel cut that goes around here have
you smoked any of that I think I grew it
I can ruin iced mocha it just still
wasn't a fan of it oh I don't know I
might be looking for a different salary
in a case
I've had I worked where I work out we
have one she don't have any smoke it um
it's pretty good it's pretty very pretty
hard usual desperate they'll GE diesel
yeah yeah that's the one yeah that
you'll like that just like that that's
dank yeah when it's done well good
scopus you know actually the my friend
Josh from La Plata labs rolled a joint
of that [ __ ] one night at a party and
there were a bunch of breeders in the
room and they all gathered around that
joint yeah so for a bunch of breeders to
join your joint I don't know I was not
mine was a damn and I open to hear that
fino was more of a so good thing good
i'll actually it was during goes where
they're from so it's into loco yeah just
settle down nice shout-out lopata yeah
yeah I haven't been back in 13 years
regrettably every summer I plan a trip
over there and never happens but I'm
totally going through theatre show up
when I do get over there it's hard to do
it being an outdoor farmer yeah yeah
yeah long drive Jesse brought me some
eggs and I cracked open one of those
eggs and it almost freaked me out
because the you know he's not crazy do
it old man it was like two times three
times like really think it's supposed to
do and they taste so much better like
your eggs make me nauseous when I eat
them like oh god I can't believe I
decided to cook this preferment ooh yeah
for me Jesse's eggs taste like food and
maybe like a reals to be eating it and
then he brought me tomatoes and honestly
after eating Jesse's tomatoes I can't
even go buy a tomato anywhere I got food
in Denver the other night and it came
with fresh tomatoes and I bit into the
tomatoes and they taste like soggy mold
I am spoiled by jesse's organic tomatoes
and there's a deli downtown coach slips
it has my producer so shout out to them
flip on that food buy local produce
Atlanta but while your own veggie there
on Main Street and then I on to bingo
burger today and someone is supplying
the most bomb ass [ __ ] produce too
nice yeah the Pecos River usually does
pretty well yeah
stuff very good place to ya so that's a
free commercial for bingo burger from a
bunch of lies you're vegetarian get that
uh that mushroom burger that's pretty
tasty you eat things you know I've said
that I won't eat fish any more recently
but I may know what you got in mind I'm
just asking they have a bangin ass
bangin burger that is all like when I
ordered it I was like I ordered it and I
was like hold up I need to go ask you if
it's a fillet or if it's like a patty
yeah as I show you is just a patty like
salmon patties like no it's a filet o
they are I do talk to her on the menu
today but it's already decided what I
was going to get little green onions
avocado tomato lettuce touch those sauce
and then you get like a whole wheat
grain bun and I'm saying everybody
listening right now just got the month
I'll take it dad potato talking about
growing weed and now since just killed
everybody you've gotta tease we know
we're all the best food and purple is
you know if I had in order to eat if
you're vegetarian there's like four
spots that's what I really feel bad for
you just cook didn't register yeah makes
you just cook at home makes me want to
open a vegetarian restaurant Oh some of
us would appreciate that put a little
slower look backward over there and see
what I'm doing back there and no bother
me between bringing me place of food and
the office yeah just call the place the
office it'd be hard to in the winter and
be hard for me to have a vegetarian
restaurant because I just be so
disappointed by the Proteas yeah any
organic vegetables would be really huh
no wonder yeah yeah wonder if we could
grow some vegetables I think that's
probably one of the downsides of the
cannabis industry now if you want to
build a greenhouse there's certain
you're going to grow weed in it like 1
million dollars yeah you know it's
actually not that I'm shut my retirement
plan is but not for the cannabis and
yeah three how's the eye vegetable yeah
flowers vegetables yeah notice i feel
like the music part i can say yeah a
long time
I totally had time I was gonna say we
should cut them out and just forgot Oh
have you guys ever grown any produce
inside not inside myself look not like
actually they fully trained it through
like put it inside like to start seeding
[ __ ] but beside that no some turn it
like outside it's a little like window
side herbs and other things like that
but that's nothing that I've done real
basic stuff lettuce basil tried it
tomato plant one time and it was taking
up room so it's kept it up but I've got
some great outdoors by never insider
it's throwing an outdoor vegetable crop
for yourself is awesome when you're
eating a meal and you're like I grew
ninety percent of the stuff in this meal
right now mmm I mean how to make
tortillas man I would be self-reliant
hmm you can show you yeah sure learning
how to make it toward idea which is
looking at me like he's gonna make
tortillas it'll be over all the time
okay guys we've almost gone for an hour
I bet if I put commercials on this thing
and intro on a natural and a big shot at
the task ROK a bit I can make this a
nice even our you guys got anything
fancy to say I know about ten once but
we've rambled on for a few minutes since
then I want to give a shout out to chick
flick am gonna on Instagram I think it's
17 nurse or stuff like that oh and then
she replied to my first shoutout for the
show and what's not 15 nurse 710 I know
who you are yeah thank you let the end
of the show she's a loyal listener
actually know that person in person and
we give her a lot of girls ice I didn't
know she shouted you out on the show
that's cool what's up kick she do that
let me know that uh she's listening
she's listening she certainly is cool
[ __ ] yeah she's got some outdoor stuff
going on that looks pretty damn good
yeah I mean she could pictures of it on
[ __ ] face it's there it happens I
didn't ask all our out on that yeah I
might give her advice on that once in a
while any shoutouts over there dude
you're all looking into your phone
Spence shut up plugs let's see um shout
out to my lady she just turned toilet
has birthday I know you're sandy
you're finally old enough to go where we
can all go now we all love you and then
shout out to Ira genetics Jeff Jesse
Michael you know anybody that's you know
ever been on the show is not here or
anywhere that supports the show yeah um
thank you for supporting the show for
sure yeah yeah car keys again he gave me
a shout out and I got like four new
followers what you gonna sit here
starting to Eden yeah shadows the whole
garden of weeden career even gone way
out there all the guys bombshell the
game in other states i'm not going to
call out their states but even if i met
you once or twice in your garden of
weeden crew I know who you are still um
there are events in denver on thursday
um i'm not gonna understand bro i know
well tonight we're gonna podcasts while
they're kicking it but um I just want to
say everybody get out in the community
and start enjoying you know the
atmosphere is what's going on yeah
because Colorado is a special place like
other states you can't do what we do and
you know we've got places where we can
just go mingle and eat and hang out and
you know instead of getting drunk we're
taking dad's and smoking joints and I'm
saying so if you live here go enjoy it
if you you know if you're up to it if
not you know whatever but if you're in
the community go enjoy yeah come out you
don't have to be a certain type of
person wears a lot of Jews anybody there
and it's we're all happy people that all
like spoke bought some case amazing herb
can see what your herb can be grown like
camita grower camita breeder yeah
computer guru don't mess it up for
everyone else you got to learn how to
you know behave yourself yeah yeah we're
working high for a crazy stuff so yeah I
just kick it yeah smoke but don't try to
come take a gigantic dad and fall over
and [ __ ] alcohol in these bins don't
really seem to mesh it nothing's ever
been a problem yeah yeah
very little alcohol consumption is to
the cottonmouth most of the time but
it's usually a fruity drink if you see
it cook for sure for sure this episode
won't go out until the start of next
month so I'll be kind of busy for a
couple of times here so we're pretty
recording but look for us at events guys
are easy to find we usually post it up
on facebook or instagram when we're
going somewhere just go for it let's
hear it i was going to say it's that
Jesse grows on Instagram and Twitter so
yeah yeah i'm on twitter extras Jesse
Jesse girls OG and Jesse's wrote an OG
kinda just some stuff as a joke no other
God how did that even happen put it okay
really Twitter don't care if you he was
Twitter paintin under you so sad Jesse
grows OG yeah check out Colorado a
bearded Colorado bearded dabbers on
Instagram that's everybody Michael over
here we'll get them on the show more
because you've got a lot of good [ __ ] to
say and people are always better on the
show after the second or third time for
sure so I got a garden of weed and
honest program for sure you post a lot
of great pictures also make sure you
check out at I region etics on Instagram
I post a lot of weed pictures I've been
postin trying to broaden my spectrum of
type of pictures i post these wait till
you came remain I'm telling you the
camera will change yeah because you can
listen you can take imagine all the
pictures you can take your plants put in
those lights dad pictures you can cage
oh yeah right there's all sizes so like
if you want to get a guy that once i buy
it you're not going to see me for like a
week you can be like where are you like
taking pictures Browns won't come over
just your purchase doin yeah so yeah but
you may have convinced me to just drive
to bestbuy and go pick that [ __ ] up
pretty soon just I really want one too
summer Christmas was it was all my
wedding oh yeah is where it doesn't
write for black friday you probably
catch my first deal but the first one to
say that because i'm kind of far all i
don't think i need to run on friday yeah
move this Siberian Amir Amir cyber
monday sounds dirty okay speaking of
that I grow is a high gross supply is
about to launch a nationwide website
with the shipping department and all
that stuff and we'll have our actually I
think the prices are going to be a
little bit lower than they are in the
store but nationwide shipping and
everyone can get great deals like we get
here and I believe there'll be a
in-store pickup program too yeah that'll
be helpful and yeah the tote of soil
deal is now over you guys oh yeah yeah
about no I didn't buy one what would I
blur would we sold a couple but I never
even saw one all right I was wanting to
see it I never knowed it it was how many
gallons of oil i think it was i I said
it would fill 48-7 gallon pops I shoulda
got one alright yeah that would allow me
a while yeah but I don't need that thank
you if you got the right time to kill a
recycle what is it reuse recycle baby
reduce reduce reuse recycle yeah tote
bag it came in I really want one of
those but don't grow some stuff in it a
huge one knows great for recycling soil
and I'm gonna make a great compost pile
is not open yeah sweet all right guys we
got three minutes before it's an hour
we're gonna wrap up the show hey guys
thanks for listening everybody out there
in podcast world we've been getting over
a thousand listens a thousand people are
gonna hear all your guys's crazy voices
everybody's made changed word Michael
had no idea what he was getting into and
he came here I just wish I knew how
crazy our look but you don't we'll take
some pictures will post them up all
taken pictures enjoy buddy how crazy you
are sometimes you was a grill he doesn't
have the grill in today when he wears
the grill why people get nervous I think
it's really funny it is Wheeler's we
went to a wedding Oh maxed it out I
wouldn't hear it a wedding that a grill
story I haven't heard one I just some of
the normal people that were more gone
normal or Matty and myself and slop and
Big Mike we're walking through the crowd
and they kind of looked and they weren't
sure if we were there to steal
everyone's purse ordered we were afraid
of it
pretty funny I thought it was pretty
funny everyone says they're the black
sheep of their family but you proved it
that improved it big shout out to
everybody that we saw at that wedding
that was awesome best wedding ever we
keep talking about it on the show
because it's been a month and we're safe
shout out to bullheaded fuller and
despicable dialects and common bogey for
rocking it that night nice they really
know disorder yeah yeah glad you got to
say that finally glad to have you back
on the shoulders just just for that 30
seconds of stuff if nothing else okay I
mean at this time this has been shadowed
number 5000 it feels like I'm gonna fade
out the music and fade out the show
thanks a lot for listen there's alright
guys I want to thank you for listening
to a long episode I want to thank Jesse
and spins for coming back and I want to
thank Michael for coming and doing its
very first podcast make sure you follow
jesse grows on instagram follow colorado
bearded dabbers on instagram follow
garden of weeden on instagram and also
follow irie genetics on instagram i'm
going to work on that harvesting and
drying and curing episode for you and
we'll get that up pretty soon so now
that the show is over please go to
itunes go to the iTunes Store search for
the iGrow culture podcast find the
review section give us a five star
rating and after that type in a comment
and let me know what you think of the
show and I will read your comments on a
future episode also do the same thing
for stitcher if you can find the
comments lot on stitcher leave a comment
there and I'll read that on the show
don't forget that the podcast is
available on itunes stitcher and every
single episode is available on irie
genetics Colorado com big shout out to
my ninja spins thanks again for
listening you guys take a fat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
you
[Music]