[Music]
oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 169 of the
grow from Earhart podcast your source
for cannabis news if you're professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated Gabbar if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to cattlemen it is a frosty cold
Thursday evening here in Colorado it is
20 degrees outside but that's ok I'm
gonna stay nice and warm because the
only reason I know it's so cold is cuz I
had to answer the door for the FedEx guy
and he just brought me a box of hoodies
I've got some sweet new custom Grover
from your heart podcast hoodies you guys
on the front left breast there's the
girl from your heart podcast logo
without my face it's got these says girl
from your heart podcast it's got the red
yellow and green EQ bar like on your
recording equipment or on your
old-school stereo to let you know you're
not blowing up your levels and then on
the back it's got the podcast logo with
the EQ bars and then it's got my big old
face right on there just like the logo
you seen on iTunes just like that logo
you see on stitcher just like the logo
on the website it is the girl from your
heart podcast official logo and it is
now available on the back of a hoodie
you guys if you are interested in one of
those hoodies send me an email girl from
your heart at hotmail.com
I'll teach you how you can get one I'd
love to get one to you these hoodies of
course were made by our friends at
handmade apparel big shout outs my
friends at handmade apparel if you need
some custom printed t-shirts if you need
custom printed hoodies if you need some
hat pins made ladies and gentlemen I
fully endorse and highly recommend
handmade apparel these guys are members
of the cannabis community and I love
supporting community members you can
find handmade apparel at handmade
apparel dot biz send them an email they
will get you all the information that
you need to get your stuff printed get
started with them let them know that you
heard about them through the girl from
your heart podcast let me know your
listen
let them know that I sent them your
direction we would both appreciate that
I want to tell a quick story about why I
really why I really respect and enjoy
the company of mr. Adam hand the the
founder the proprietor the the main dude
there of handmade apparel just a quick
little rant on why I respect this dude
so much I was in the Denver cannabis cup
one time in Denver of course right and
it was at a place called the X nu Event
Center and the place was too tiny for
how many people were in the facility I
was frustrated it took me too long to
park it took me way too long to get in
the facility when they searched my
backpack they took some [ __ ] away from
me
they made me give some things away that
I plan on taking in but they wouldn't
let me take it in I wasn't gonna wait in
line again that kind of frustrated me
then when I got in there the place was
so crowded
then I literally got stuck in an
intersection of people for several
minutes and could not go left I could
not go right I could not go forward and
I could not go backward I was trapped
and I do not like being trapped so it
put me in a little bit of a shitty mood
to tell you the truth and I get out of
that big [ __ ] of people and the
first booth I come upon with familiar
faces was the handmade apparel and oil
slick booth and I looked at Adam hand
from handmade apparel and the first
thing that flew out of my face was boy
this is a [ __ ] isn't it and I
know now that was the wrong thing to say
that was the wrong mindset and I know
that because Adam had looked at me and
he said brother I came all the way from
Washington for this and look at all
these people that are here having a good
time this is amazing
and it took me about a half a second to
snap out of my shitty mood and the
students right I may have had a shitty
parking experience they may have taken
away some cans of butane out of my
backpack I may have taken ten minutes to
stand in an intersection with a bunch of
high people doing nothing trying to
figure out which way to go but he's
right this is an amazing cannabis themed
event and people from all over the world
were there smoking weed with me and my
friends so I just needed that quick snap
from Adam head and he gave it to me
politely and kindly and respectfully and
he's really kind and he's super polite
so I feel like I've been going on about
handmade apparel true for a really long
time so much respect much love to the
entire handmade true big shout out to
Adam Han and his beautiful fiancee
Jackie O at the oil slick true I support
that company I support those people I
love supporting cannabis community
members I'm going to their butts now to
move forward a little bit you guys
thanks for the hoodies if you're
listening the handmade true look
freaking great you guys the printing
came out so smooth you guys do a really
good job my I read genetics hoodie that
I am actually wearing right now I've
probably been wearing this every every
day it's cold every day that it's kind
of chilly I wear this probably for like
a year now and the printing is still
perfect the hoodies get a little fuzzy
because you know it's getting worn it's
got some fuzz marks like it's coming
frayed the brother printing is solid
still every bit of printing and I on
here is good I hope I'm sure that those
hoodies are going to look just as good
for just as long so much love much
respect I appreciate it good job you
guys look forward to doing business with
you in the future I need some t-shirts
soon we need some girl from your heart
podcast t-shirts that's what we need I'm
gonna move forward I like to keep the
listeners updated on my breeding project
you guys know that I've got a breeding
project underway just a few days ago I
put pollen on those girls you can really
see the seeds bulking up it's only been
a few days
I'm not sure how far apart those
episodes are gonna come out so I'm not
gonna quote how many days but it's been
several days a few several days and the
seeds were bulking up all the pistols on
the plants are really brown and curled
up so you could tell that pollen got in
there I applied so much pollen guys I
kind of got a little bit crazy I put
more pollen than I should have but I
wanted to make sure to have a [ __ ] ton
of seeds and it is working so let me
give you an update and a reminder of
what I bred I took in a rise f1 male
that's golden goat the golden go female
was pollinated by a Daybreaker male that
made a rise I used that arise male and I
have pollinated cookies-and-cream
white widow lemon Geoffrey grateful dog
and several other beautiful females
there's a flow plant and there they got
pollinated also and there are some
what's what else is in there there are
other arise phenotypes in there so that
I can make more of the arise f2 so here
in about seven weeks or so those should
be done and we'll get to see what
cookies-and-cream trust who arise does
and what white widow across to the arize
will do
my goal you guys that cookies-and-cream
plant was one of the most resinous
Frosty's plants I have ever grown and
the taste on it was great those that
plant made some of the best bubble hash
and iced hash I have ever smoked and it
yielded really heavy on the shatter when
we make shatter you'd get more shatter
than from any other strain but the
problem was if you wanted bud form it
made buds the size of like my thumb tip
just like the top of my thumb they're
just little popcorn balls up the stick
all the way up and down the stick just
little popcorn balls
and they're shooting to trim and it
doesn't put out a lot of weight and the
plants just kind of it just wispy to
grow it's not the best grower so I hit
it with the arize pollen because a rise
makes these gigantic huge colas and I'm
hoping that I can get those giant colas
with as much resin and as much flavor
and carry that a rise growth trait over
to the cookies and cream now theorize
females have been testing in the 29 to
31 percent THC a range so there's a lot
of THC available to put into this cross
I've never had the cookies and cream
crossed in my cross tested myself but
I've seen it test high because it's
available at kind love and several other
dispensaries so I'm hoping I get that
really high THC THC a value on the tests
that are with that cross so look forward
to that I'll post pictures of it when
those seeds are ready I will grow them
and then I'll post pictures of that on
Instagram I am i re underscore genetics
on Instagram if you want to check out
the progress there's also a whole bunch
of good stuff up on there right now also
let you guys on the podcast know how
it's going so that's my breeding update
speaking of updates I read an email on
the last episode from a man who wants to
start a cannabis podcast in the UK and
since I read that email he has responded
I'm not gonna read the whole email but
I'll just read a quick portion of it he
says hey dude Ross here messaging off
the podcast email address great show
today some great advice but I must
apologize though as I wasn't clear I
actually meant mrs. May Theresa May our
new female prime minister seems she's
okay and passionate and here's where I
screwed up you guys and I knew I was
saying something wrong what I said it
lost him it felt wrong when I said
but he said MP means members of
parliament are equivalent to your
Congress and he said I'm sorry if I'm
wrong he said I remember equivalent to
your Congress I think and I'm sorry if
I'm wrong however we do also have a
military police but they're strictly
military nothing political so what I
said excuse for the throat clearing he
wrote a message saying that the Prime
Minister was okay was boss I don't
remember what the stance was right now
because I'm talking too fast trying to
read an email but he said that the MPs
were partial were supporting cannabis
and I didn't know what MP stood for and
the American in me took it his military
police then I was just reading an email
quickly and trying to come up with a
solution quickly and I spat it out
military police I was wrong as [ __ ] you
guys MP and this students meaning stood
for members of parliament so I was wrong
I apologize for that I hope I didn't
embarrass your country hoping to
embarrass myself too much by saying that
I wasn't trying to be offensive so I
apologize and thanks for correcting me
I'd like to be corrected you guys I like
to be right if I'm wrong on something
feel free to correct me and he also goes
on to say for you to say you're
confident that I'm the right person from
how I write means a lot as I'm that guy
who thinks he sucks at everything does
not suck at everything you're gonna be a
great podcaster he also goes on to talk
about how he is acquiring equipment and
getting his computer ready for the
podcast I look forward to hearing your
show he says he's going to record a
couple episodes and send them to me so
that I can give him some pointers make
sure that you get a couple good episodes
recorded and then when you launch into
iTunes make sure that you get all of
your friends to listen make sure you
have a Twitter account set up so that
you can tweet those podcasts out maybe
start a Twitter account now and start
developing relationships with friends on
Twitter so that when you do launch
material they'll be there already
waiting to retweet your podcast that's
something you could work on but go ahead
send me a few episodes when they're
ready I would love to listen to them and
give you some guidance I will do it for
you
I would love to do it I also do a lot of
podcasts you guys I spend all day
working on plants so I've always got an
earbud in my hair just listen in to a
podcast
somebody actually asked me to mention
what podcasts I listen to here I've got
my phone in my hand I'll just grab this
and I'll scroll through really quickly
here and I'll tell you just a few of the
podcasts I list these are the random
emails you I get you guys people ask me
what podcasts are you listening to so
I'm gonna answer that I'm just gonna go
in order from the top Doug loves movies
Doug loves minis and then this ones on
here but it may get deleted real soon
it's called Julian loves music it's
really not the greatest podcast it's a
spinoff it's a copy of Doug loves movies
it's fun sometimes
of course the Joe Rogan experience I
listen to that more than anything the
Church of what's happening now with Joey
Coco Diaz the Doug Stanhope podcast the
smartest man in the world podcast the
fighter and the kid good times of Steve
Simone the Ari Shaffir skeptic tank
Burtt cast podcast with Bert Kreischer
that's sometimes it's hard to listen to
you guys but sometimes there's good
episodes how Comedy Works with Wendy
Curtis and Rick Kearns that's the Comedy
Works podcast the Nerdist truthin Eliza
there are a lot more you guys but that's
mainly what I listen to I'm getting to
the weed section I've been listening to
the spliff podcast I used to listen to
Adam Dunn show I haven't paid attention
to that one lately
the dude grows is a great podcast it's
in my feet I don't get a chance to
listen to it Legion of skanks is good
and then down on the bottom of my list
Monday morning podcast with Bill burr
and Fitz Dawg radio and somehow I'm not
sure when I subscribe to this but Dean
Del Rey's let there be talk Dean don't
raise a good comedian he's a rock and
roll dude I don't know if I've ever
listened to his podcast but is in my
feet so they lose the podcast I'm
listening to all right let's put the
show back on track a little bit and talk
a little bit about cannabis I want to
read some listener emails because when
the listeners send emails I know that
I'm answering the questions you want to
hear I'm actually getting somebody's
attention and helping somebody out so
this one comes from a regular listener
and someone that contacts me a lot this
one's from Fast Barry what's up fast
very good to hear from you again this
email goes like this
as always really enjoy the podcast I
have a few quick questions for you and
then he did really list a couple few
questions here we'll see how long these
take and then we might read some more
emails we might do a product review
depends on how much time we have
so the email goes like this have you
always grown using bottled nutrients and
why or why not um mostly I use bottled
nutrients I prefer the bottle nutrients
it's how I learned I have reached
okay so I guess this is why I've had my
best test results and my best flavor and
some of my favorite crops have come from
my trusted source of nutrients that I
have I've used so many brands I have
used advanced nutrients I've used psycho
I have used Fox farms I've used to roar
Aurora Seoul I have used routes I don't
remember I may be mixing Aurora and then
Seoul synthetic so those might be two
different things I've used the route
stuff with like the Buddha looking
bottles I have used Dutch master I have
used I have used I've used dyna-gro or
protec that's dyna-gro I've used so many
brands my favorite honestly is botanic
air pure blend pro bottles the cocoa
base grow in blue with a little bit of
liquid karma some cal-mag whatever
there's a whole line of stuff but I
prefer most of the botanic air stuff
from the pure blend Pro line and then I
added a couple other things in there
like just a couple of the things I
probably won't mention too much that's
mainly my main mix there's some worm
castings in there and I put in some
stuff to get the roots going a little
bit then I add my own you know a couple
little little proprietary things in
there I also like a product called
humble honey if I'm using botanic hair
put some honey in there but those things
that from the bottles I grew a really
great crop every plant and they're got a
super high test everything tasted
amazing and the weight was where I
needed it so I feel like I fell in love
with it it was like I hit gold and I
don't really want to change from there a
long time ago I had Shawn come on the
show and he started hyping the organic
as [ __ ] methods he started showing me a
whole bunch it was great the product was
really great I had to make too many
trips to too many different stores to
make that happen for myself for my
lifestyle it wasn't working I was
working a full-time job I was running a
hundred and something like grow by
myself and
have time to hit the worm casting store
the feed store the hydro store and then
go to big R to get tubs to mix all this
[ __ ] in it was getting a little
overwhelming for me if you've got time
to do it and you can do that go for it
but I was running a bottle drop and an
organic crop and it was kind of getting
to be a little bit tedious and I live in
a house and I'm not the only one that
lives here I'm trying to do some of
these stinky [ __ ] bothered some of the
other people so that wasn't cool if I
lived alone if I had yeah if I was the
only one ever here because sometimes you
can when I mix up a tea and I put some
fish emulsion and stuff in there and
some Bokashi and the stuff that comes
out of the Kashi bucket the leachate
that lactic acid bacteria it stinks up
the whole house you can't if it's in the
basement in the back left corner you
can't be in the top story of the house
in the top right corner without smelling
it is just rank so that's part of why
it'll do the organics at home I would
love honestly I've been reading about it
and thinking about it I would love to
make this shift to no-till organics I
would love to be able to set up some
compost in the garage put a worm farm in
the garage get that sort of a thing
going and then just use it sounds really
awesome to be able to use the same pots
for every cycle just cut the plant out
shake the roots off put another plant in
there put some compost in there some
worm castings in there and get it going
again
that sounds amazing so I have not always
drawn with bottled nutrients I've done
the organic as [ __ ] method I've done
outdoor stuff that we just did soil we
did a minted soil that's sucked we had
one summer where everything got stolen
I've had one I've had multiple summers
were everything I [ __ ] stolen and
that sucks but all my outdoor stuff was
amended soils and no bottled nutrients
at all it's fun I like the I like the
bottles I like the mad scientist feeling
of it but I also like the amended soils
and the teas because of the organic
feeling and I'm a dirty hippie
I got dreadlocks and like all that
natural sort of stuff so I have not
always grown with bottles and that is
kind of why and why not so I'm gonna
move on to the next part of your
question do I like well made bubble hash
why or why not
I love some well-made bubble hash I like
some fool melt like the Colorado extract
company makes this we take so we'll grow
we a commercial grow we'll grow plants
and take off the big leaves and then
freeze the buds like cut them off the
sticks and then freeze the buds while
they're still wet so you've got fresh
frozen buds and you take them to there
are several companies that do it but
Colorado extract company made my
favorite so far you take into these
companies and they'd wash it for you and
they keep the whole time they do it the
whole time they do the extraction they
keep your product and I think it's 55
degrees or it might be 65 degrees they
keep it the room is that cold your
product is kept on ice the whole time
the hash that comes out of there it's
sold to you it's kept in a refrigerator
at the dispensary and a lot of people
the hip kids bring a little cooler to
buy it because it's old you still cool
and the resin heads look like beach sand
in the container that's bubble hash
because that's full melt hash and we'll
take that and fold a piece of parchment
paper in half and put it in the middle
and heat up the carb cap just a little
bit and roll a carb cap out on it and it
presses it out and it makes like a
little it looks like a piece of shatter
at that point it's just a little thin
layer of hash and you can see through it
and then we take dabs of it like that
when it's pressed out and it just burns
so much more smoothly I really you can
tell by the passion to my voice right
now that I'm kind of drooling over a
nice dab of some good solvent less hash
I do love bubble hash if it's done
correctly the problem is there's there
are too many companies not doing it
correctly and it's too overpriced and it
has to be stored kept cool what I do
like they take they take some of that
hash that really nice 120 or 90 micron
bubble hash and then they press it they
run it through like a rosin press and
the stuff that comes out of that oh that
is delicious you guys it comes out white
and it looks like looks like white silly
putty or the stuff that I used to use
when I was in high school and wanted to
put posters on the basement wall but the
wall didn't take nails she's this weird
goo tacky stuff it looked like that but
the dabs out of it were so amazing to be
so
and I would get really medicated really
quickly from it it was like a full-body
high when he smoked shatter I don't
think he gets to my body as much as I
think the the solvent list does so yes
obviously I do like that then you say
you talk about your favorite strain to
breed with oh hold on phone just blacked
out you often talk about your favorite
strain to breed with breed with of to
make hash oil but if you had to pick a
desert island ten pack of seeds what
would they be
okay so I think you said that I talked
about a lot of my favorite let's see is
that you kind of stumbled on some words
or talk about your favorite strain to
breed with of to make hash oil but if
you had to pick a desert island baby so
I'm gonna take this is if I had to pick
ten seeds a ten pack of seeds what ten
pack would I pick to be on a desert
island
hopefully it's a deserted island who's
on a desert island trying to grow some
cannabis hopefully I've got plenty of
clean water hopefully I can find some
stuff to make some organic nutrients
there's gonna be fish around if I'm on
an island right I'll be able to find
some fish and make some fish nutrients a
ten pack of seeds that's really a
challenge and see this is gonna
frustrate a lot of people because I've
got a seed vault of my own that nobody
has ever had access to so probably
something like the lemon Jeffrey
grateful dog cross is a really good one
I call that lemon sorbet ten packet that
would be really cool if I were stuck on
a deserted island
grateful dog might be the one to pick
dude because it's got the flavor it's
got the aroma it's got that stank but
here's where I'm gonna go weird grateful
dog is feminized seed and I don't want
to be stuck on a deserted island with
feminized seeds I want regular seeds so
that I could breed so yeah that's such a
tough choice something i've bred
probably you know it'd have to be one of
my creations something regular something
they came from the arize might be cool
you know what dub wise might be a good
one if I were stuck and people like you
never even talked about dub wise it's
easy to grow i produces huge colas and
it's got a couple of good phenotypes
there's like a really hazy phenotype and
there's a more indica phenotype but they
all test high in THC so that would be
cool
but so if the grateful dog were regular
seed that would be my pick because then
I could get an OG Kush leaning phenotype
chem 91 leaning phenotype and then I
could get a male and then I could breed
and then I could start doing some [ __ ]
and if I had a 10 pack of seeds that's
all I need to make magic happen if you
just left me alone on a deserted island
we would have in crosses nuts with it so
if the grateful dog were regular seed
that would be my first choice the lemon
Geoffrey grateful dog is also a
feminized seed so all my favourites are
becoming feminized
the Cascade would be cool you know I
might have to say arise arise might be
the winner because it's available I
could grab a ten pack of that right now
but then I start thinking see I'm just
rambling today I kind of want to go away
old school and say like why not some old
like Brothers Grimm seeds or some mr.
nice seeds from way back in the day
because that's when stuff was really
neat way back then before we started
kind of is breeding for a lot of random
stuff the old breeders seem to have more
goals in mind they seem to have more
more foresight for their breeding now it
just seems like everybody's breeding for
a lot of hype and they're trying to jump
on the skittles train or whatever it
seems to be next
alright so speaking of skittles that
leads me right into the next part of
your question fast berry says I live in
Rhode Island and can't really walk look
hard into getting elite clones if you
were me what cutting should I be looking
out for well that's a great question um
it kind of depends on what you're
looking for honestly if you're looking
for like head stash for yourself you
might want one thing if you're trying to
grow some weight you might want another
thing if you need an indica you want one
thing if you need a sativa you want
another thing if you are trying to go
for flavor you might want something else
right now what I am noticing everything
tangi is popular strawberry banana tan G
double banana tan G there's a banana
sherbet that goes around there's a
banana split all of that like that
Crockett family farm stuff is super
popular the skittles with a Z I think
they're calling it skittles because they
can't call it skittles you know I'm
saying they gotta spell it with Z the
skittles is super popular right now
everybody's loving the skittles I don't
know what's next I wish I could / - one
of my strains was the next type but you
can't you can't just make it the next
type somebody's got to fall in love with
it it's got to be the next type so
anything with tangi in it people are
really in love with tangi right now that
strawberry banana Tandy type of stuff is
really cool if you want a really heavy
producer straight-up tangi works well
for you if you want more of an indica
type of tangi product I would say the
taffy was great
so that sort of stuff is what's really
popular right now it's hard to predict
because one day it was Girl Scout
jeez for a long time it was OG Kush all
you could sell was OG Kush if you had a
bag of OG Kush and a bag of whatever
else that OG Kush would sell first
you could buy triple the OG Kush of
everything else cuz you were gonna sell
that OG everyone wanted OG and then it
was Girl Scout cookies and then it was
gorilla glue and then it was tangi there
was golden girl for a little while
before that so it's hard to predict
what's gonna be the next type strain I
guess I hyped up a whole bunch of that
Crockett family farm stuff I could also
say maybe what do you want in your
garden you want to rise you want cascade
do you want Firefly you want morning do
you want those are all strains that I
have made and I am just trying to push
my products which I mean if you want my
stuff that'd be awesome I think a rise
is a really reliable strain so that's
something you want in your garden
let's see you said you're in Rhode
Island I'm pretty sure I know some
activists and cannabis consumers up in
that area and I'm sure that they've got
simulate cuts so get in touch with me I
will try to put you in touch with some
people and that way if you need a couple
of elites we can put some good stuff in
your hands I'm all about clone trading I
don't think people should clone hoard I
think sometimes I will keep some stuff
back because I'm a breeder and I don't
want everything out because I'm going to
breed two things and it's kind of my
magic but once I give a clone out I try
not to say hey don't give that out to
people I feel like once I've given a
clone out you that clones going places I
and I know guys that if you tell them
hey don't give this out the first thing
they're gonna do is go oh yeah they're
gonna give you the middle finger and
they're gonna make as many clones of
that plant as they possibly can so I'm
all about free trade cloning I think
everybody should have a clone exchange
I'm down to trade seeds for clones and
down and trade clones for clones I'm
down to trade clones recedes I like that
kind of stuff I think it should keep
moving I think that's how people find
the perfect strain for themselves and
their gardens and or their medical
patients I I think clone trading should
happen so if I can find somebody in your
area or if you can find somebody in your
area wherever you are whoever you are if
you could find somebody to trade clones
with I highly encourage it just make
sure that when you get home that you
treat those clones for pests and you
also quarantine them to keep them away
from the rest of your garden for a few
days so that if there
something wrong you don't go infesting
the rest of your garden alright that was
long rant I hope I kind of answered your
question on what cuttings you should be
looking for any of that Crockett stuff
any IRA genetic stuff also alien rock
candy has been real popular so if
there's alien rock candy available grab
that it's been real popular here in
Colorado lately alright so let's see
what else he has to say he said sorry
for so many questions it's just a few of
the thoughts around the old noggin the
last podcast my address is he does give
me his address so that I can send him
some stickers and stuff but I won't bust
you out and read that on the show I do
want to thank you once again for sending
me an email we've been friends online
for quite a while now and I do
appreciate the interaction if anybody
out there has a question or they'd like
to say something feel free to send me an
email it's grow from your heart a
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you yes I do have a ton of emails to
respond to I plan on answering as many
of them as I can on the show I've got
messages from Instagram I've got
messages from Facebook I've got a ton of
emails I'm working my way through them I
can only put out so much content I've
secretly been working on another project
that under wraps but it's been taking a
lot of my time so that's why there was
not a Thursday episode this week I took
last Thursday off for the Thanksgiving
holiday it was not a Thursday episode
for two weeks in a row now but I will
get those coming again once I get back
on my schedule I got kind of I got
something else going it took up a lot of
my time I'm back on the flow now so I'll
be able to put out more regular quality
episodes again again if you want to hear
something if you've got a question a
comment just feel free send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you alright I
want to take a second and tell you guys
about a service called patreon and I
recently made a patreon account for the
girl from your heart podcast if you want
to check it out it is patreon.com slash
grow from your heart patreon is patr
e o n so it's patreon.com slash grow
from your heart what patreon is is a
service that will allow my listeners to
donate financial contributions to the
podcast to help me pay for the web
hosting of this show ladies and
gentlemen I read genetics Colorado comm
costs a little over three hundred
dollars per year for me to keep up
and that is where all of the podcasts
are host there are a hundred episodes
there I am just trying to offset that
financial burden out of my pocket by
asking the listeners to contribute to my
patreon account you can contribute as
little as $1 per month and I do not
think there is a limit I think you can
put as many zeros on the end of that as
you would like so I would appreciate it
if you would sign up at patreon if you
feel like this podcast is giving you
some value if you've learned something
if you've been entertained one dollar a
month is all I ask I'm not begging if
it's something you can do that is
excellent I'm just trying to offset the
cost of my website so that we can keep
the show up for free the sponsorships do
help I've got some sponsors on board now
that really helps a lot but if you'd
like to go to the patreon account it is
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
go check out the page even if you don't
want to contribute go check out what I
did go check out what I wrote I would
love your clicks on the website speaking
of clicks on websites I'd love it if you
follow me on Facebook check out the
growth my heart a podcast on Facebook
also find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast and I would love it if you
follow me on Instagram where I post a
whole bunch of great cannabis
photography check me out it's Irie
underscore genetics I would love to see
you there
all right I want to thank everybody once
again for listening I want to give a
huge shout out to my boy hydro in Vegas
bro that mustache is rockin I also want
to give you a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I'm Jenny from the block
you know parted partner with each other
trades same you don't need a bank
account
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 170 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation dedicated to cure cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff on to thank you guys again
for joining me as always I need to send
a huge thank you
[Music]
he grows check him out is the Colorado
podcast have an Instagram now yes some
cool pictures
what's the strain you posted the other
day the Smurfs what's the cross on the
Smurfs moving forward ladies and
gentlemen make sure you go stock Jesse
while he's here also my friends because
this part of the five cast is brought to
you by our good friends at handmade
apparel do you guys my friends at
handmade apparel made me some hoodies
they have the girl from your heart
podcast logo right above the left breast
it doesn't have my face on it and on the
back it's got the girl with my big
cheesy face on there you guys look super
cool if you just didn't once send me an
email
I've gotten two emails so far I took on
a new project and I have not replied to
many emails and we'll get back to you
probably after I record so send me a
message Jesse picked up the hoodies and
made the big cheesiest smile that I've
seen
with my face on it handmade apparel if
you need some shirts made if you need
something printed stickers if you want
to make sure that Jesse will will agree
with what I'm gonna say there's another
word I was trying to
I owe you a huge thank you for trusting
me you guys listen to me and I give you
advice about your cannabis plants which
are used for your medicine to keep you
healthy
or in another way to keep your wallet
fat however it's happening I'm helping
you out and you trust me with your
financial and your medicinal investment
and your time and your energy they trust
what I say and that means a lot to me so
thank you for trusting me thanks for
sure that's it thanks for believing that
my guidance is correct thanks for
believing at me thanks for supporting
the podcast that shows coalition I
realized the other day that there are a
lot of people out there let's say I have
a question about cannabis ask Ross to
Jeff so just thanks for believing in me
and trusting me to guide you through
your garden I think that's enough
rambling for the start of the podcast
Jesse's here and he wanted to talk about
composting he sent me a message and he
said I have had composting on my head
all day I don't think compost is quite
what's in your head but it's close
here we are we're gonna talk a little
bit about composting yeah where do you
want a smart brother you want to jump
right into it with anything okay the
first note that I took was Bo Kashi yeah
yeah okay so Bo Kashi is for anyone
that's not familiar it is a grain that
has been inoculated with an e/m one
culture an endogenous microorganism yes
I think they spray like a barley okay
possibly a dairy product that's how you
end up with the em1
okay fermented milk okay so you take a
culture you collect and you mix it with
milk and it uh it ferments and that's
how you end up with what they called
labs lactic acid bacteria correct okay
and from that you can turn that into em1
and you can take the e-m1 and oculi your
crane fermented it again let it dry out
and boom you've got boshy great okay so
are you making the Bokashi are you
buying the Bokashi pre-made I'm getting
the Bo Kashi right now from Victor with
innovative organics up in Denver okay
it's really good and it's pretty damn
cheap so and he's a small local business
that is that's taken food out of the
book you know landfills oh very cool so
it's so let's teach the people about the
Bokashi bucket a little bit then since
you said taking food out of the
landfills that's gonna make people have
a lot of questions I've got a bocce
bucket I can see one from where we're
sitting so it'll be advantageous to
describe it it's basically a five-gallon
bucket with a spigot on it there's a
little collection tray in the bottom
that prevents these solid particles from
getting in the way of the spigot and
basically I fill that thing with my
vegetable scraps I don't eat any meat
product so all my vegetables scrap
the tips of my carrots the ends of my
avocados the avocado pits go in there
and they disintegrate completely stuff
food goes to waste anything I would
throw away it's sitting near the trash
can to encourage me instead of putting
in the trash it goes in the Kashi bucket
I fill it up I fill up a bowl like a
glass bowl and then I dump that glass
bowl into the Bokashi bucket because
it's much easier that way and I don't
have to open it as frequently because
bucket with a lid that seals on it it's
gonna speak it I usually put a little
late a thin layer of newspaper in there
just to prevent a good I do yeah some of
that particle stuff will clog up the
drain Zangler so you put put the paper
down and then you I just put like a
couple banana peels I honestly in there
to get started so you [ __ ] son of I used
to eat a [ __ ] ton of bananas too banana
peels in there to get it started than a
handful of the Bokashi grain because
that is a bio activator and then you
just start throwing your all your scrap
in there and then once you get a nice
layer maybe an inch or two thick then
just put a little another handful of
that Bokashi grain on there and repeat
just make lasagna basically of scraps
Kashi scraps Kashi
I think it's an inch and a half that
they say okay I put in every inch and a
half throw in more [ __ ] and don't
press it down you guys cuz it's going to
expand in there no you do want to press
you do want to press it down yes okay
all right so uh most bowl Kashi buckets
come with a little masher thing oh it's
when you push it down that it farts and
makes that horrific smell yes okay he's
also you could squeeze a shit-ton oh
[Music]
yeah have you ever tried to clean a
dream with that juice I actually just
tried it the other day Dave's work for
it no but it's pretty [ __ ] close okay
I poured
I even made sure had enough I poured
[Music]
like if that's like a hair clog that
would have done it you got something
serious all right so
you make your little is Anya then you
pack it down and then you seal it up and
just leave it in there and then after
about ten or twelve days it'll start
making juice and you can open up the
little spigot and I use a glass mason
jar to catch the juice and then I seal
it up and then I cover it with honestly
with just a rag to keep it dark because
you want to keep that away from the
light and then I put about an ounce per
five gallon bucket when I go to mix up
some nutrients put about an ounce of
that crap in there and a five gallon
bucket with my newts and I can see the
plants start up taking oh yeah much
better and it's just full of nutrients
it's all the nutrients from the plant
right I mean it's just that that's all
I'm using now in my girl that's amazing
even at the big grow we started using it
quite a bit
and it will save on trash yeah save on
nutrient money it's full of humic acids
folic acids lactic acids
it's got bacteria and fungi in it a lot
of the things that you probably forgot
about and that your bottled nutrient
company probably missed also speed up
the root zone speed up the metabolism of
your plants so this is just the Bokashi
bucket you can get that lactic acid
bacteria juice out of there so it'll
start growing this white funky foam
these big gross looking brainy bubbles
that is perfect you want that if that's
happening you did it perfectly keep that
going because once you've drained it a
few times you can drain it a lot of
times you can leave it going and keep
draining it mash it drain it and mash it
it'll go for a long time but eventually
what I like to do after I've harvested
I'll take my old dirt and pour it into a
big like a big are it's like a feed
trough for horses I think pour all the
dirt into there then I'll pour that
Bokashi bucket into there all that funk
and mix it in and mix that in with my
dirt and cover it and put a little
moisture in there and finish breads and
I feel like that stuff whatever I made
in the Kashi bucket grows throughout my
soil just go stir it occasionally and
I'll try to do it I'll try to get to
full Bokashi buckets in there before I
go start to reuse it yeah
the smell is intense we do it kind of
smells you're indoors like somebody
threw up in the bar trashcan after
drinking all day
milk ice cream and then drink all day
then threw up in the bar trash can
that's seriously it's bad you can just
green a little Mike can't be around it
white Mike it's on the podcast often he
can't he's like oh if you're gonna do
that I'm [ __ ] going off like he won't
even be here the guy's the Bokashi
people on instagram actually there's
actually a company called Bokashi they
use 55-gallon drums of the mixture and
then they use a forklift to lift it up
and dump it and I could just imagine
what that smells like just 55 gallons of
dead body Victor's doing the same thing
with the innovative organics okay oh
when you were talking about putting a
lot of banana peels in there so cool
thing about or doing this process is the
compost that the Bocage you will
eventually make the pulp itself and the
leachate from it are both they contained
the nutrients that the plants contained
and bananas for instance are super high
in potassium so if you want a custom
tune no costs Bo Kashi juice I mean you
know look at the nutrients that are in
the plant if you filled that thing with
with bananas and banana peels like
guaranteed behind guarantee case yep
yeah if you put berries that are darker
in colors we're gonna have a whole bunch
of like hue mix and stuff like that in
there I assume okay so you've got your
book Oishi bucket you got this whole
fuzzy white mess of stuff you've got
jars of lactic acid bacteria then you
said your next thing that you got going
was your worm program let's talk about
your worms
so I started
100 worms back in the summer a potential
vendor brought them in and just came to
me it was like a nice red wigglers yeah
wiggler shows 100 of them and like you
know like occasion yeah exactly
all right so I took it home and dumped
him in a smart pot full of food scraps
initially I put it just straight peat
moss in there except something they eat
and I also did I think some newspaper
then and I kept him through the summer
I wasn't like real actively feeding him
or anything but now that winters came
around I took I think it's a 40 gallon
container and filled it with all the
worm or you know all this stuff
necessary for a good proper setup of
warm bedding and I've been dumping the
Bocage a bulb in there and they go
[ __ ] nuts for that [ __ ] but I've got
so I mean I'm just
it's just cool so I'm making all my
nutrients at home basically we we tell
us a little bit about what's in your
warm bedding yeah so I use I got some
used phone books as well I think all
phone books are used I don't even know
why the [ __ ] they still make it's true
just the waste of trees yeah I shredded
them up and a bunch of newspapers I used
wood chips I have a comfrey plant at
home so that's indoors so I went ahead
and chopped all of that guys like so
they're gonna turn that up for you
turned out any useable nutrients which
that's a whole another part of my little
homestead style kinda like the comfrey
that is but I put some of that in there
and then a full bucket of bocaj see
stuff Wow
they're gonna love all that and I
figured out it so the bow cause she
stinks like hell when it's tuna
then yes so this time I put a whole
bunch of wood thick layer wood chips on
the top and then a bunch of wet
newspaper to seal it all on the trap it
in there and the smell was cool okay
that's helpful yeah in the winter like
this it's cold you guys it's probably 12
degrees here in Colorado maybe lower
I'm not a knight it's gonna get stupid
cold in my garage I'm guessing it's
gonna be in the teens
would I be able to keep my 40 gallon
worm life container in the garage right
now
you know I don't really know okay I have
a similar situation but my car just
heated it's around 65 degrees and they
don't give it like do it almost the
think I would assume that that dirt is
gonna be hot anyway because it's
bioactive in there yeah that's like the
the little warm farm I have most
definitely it creates its own heat it's
more established the big one I just set
that up last weekend so I'm sure it will
meeting up I'm not gonna like just say
oh yeah you'll be fine so okay one thing
I would for sure do this is lift it off
the floor okay so that's not that cold
your plants want to be off that cold
concrete really sucks for plants unless
it's a real fancy heated floor right
he gets so cold yes I'm cold so fast
it's a heat sink it actually stills keep
out of things that are like when you're
drunk anyway in the bathtub to cool down
[Music]
okay all right so you've got your bo
khosh you got your worms and you're
using a big forty gallon container how
well what else you is going into your
compost just kids subscribes at this
point once spring comes around and it's
not cold as [ __ ] when I get my outdoor
compost pile go and I'll be putting all
the chicken bedding in there that's
mixed with chicken [ __ ] okay and you put
like meat products in there also no boat
I mean you can invoke Oishi but there
they say you can I actually saw somebody
bocaj you people put their entire
Thanksgiving dinner there turkey like
the carcass of the uneaten turkey the
mashed potatoes they put the entire
thing in there then they showed the
process they and then they took a the
thing outside and dug a hole and buried
it and then they planted a tree on top
where they buried it so it's claimed
they could put meat in there as well
this is longer David say put feces in
there
things I'm not brave enough to do and
things I'm not gonna do for my endure
right if I had a big huge gigantic
outdoor garden I that would be an
end-of-the-world scenario oh yeah yeah
yeah what even dairy cheese and stuff
like that they say you can put egg
shells in there oh yeah I do I totally
put a yeah coffee grounds even paper I
mean it's like coffee filters newspaper
stuff like okay so yeah just eats that
right up disappears yeah you don't get a
lot of leachate off awesome I've been
putting all my cannabis scraps of him so
I've been when you've run him through if
I was to throw like the leaves and stuff
off my plants in the garden into the
open warm bin I would lose most of the
nitrogen and Patel said I would lose
carbon through the co2 that it admits as
it dries out breaks down okay running
them through the Bo Kashi bucket you
retain all of that Wow okay his permits
at first and it traps it in the plant so
then it's it's healthier food for the
worms and it makes a higher quality
product richer
yeah much richer okay if that
fermentation is what gives it that
amazing smell
yeah it's Victor's been teaching me
about wonders of bo khosh shoutout to
Victor yeah he knows what he's talking
about um he we totally get him on the
show when they say the victory round I
have to be on the phone okay warehouse
full of [ __ ] when you're a ganja
grower smells kind of funky sometimes is
it a sickeningly satisfying thing like
that smells terrible I'll take 5 gallons
of it
you know that that's gonna make fish
hydro slates
and like Bo Kashi juice remember Nirvana
and piranha or what was it piranha and
tarantula from advanced nutrients when
they made the liquids yeah oh those
things smell like the women's bathroom
at the park in the middle of the summer
it was so terrible they worked you could
feed your plants very little of those
things and your plants would just go ape
[ __ ] I admit it back in the day I used
all of the advanced nutrients product I
didn't know any better that's what I've
never tried I just yeah not to bash
anything but that's one that I would
avoid they promise you that you'll get
30 percent heavier yields which it did
it gave me probably 30% fatter yields
than any other brand I've ever used but
all of my different strains looked
smelled and tasted the exact same and
they were all about I hypothetically if
all those strains hit 30 percent of THC
with my regular regimen they all hit
about 20-25 when I used advanced
nutrients but they were heavier a lot
more of it it just wasn't and I'd rather
have I'd rather grow a pound and a half
of super dank than two pounds of me
they are extremely overpriced and I can
tell you that working with them as a
vendor and a company they are [ __ ]
nightmare every hydro shop that I've
tried to mess with has said that because
I would be like hey can you order this
new advanced nutrients product and
people just shake their head to me like
no I'll take what they send me they send
me boxes of [ __ ] I sell that stuff oh
yeah cycle right I did a side by I've
done a lot of side by side way side
track I did not prefer psycho either
psycho gave me a lot of great colors it
gave me bud density and they gave me
weight but I did not approve of the
flavor the flavor was where it was
lacking everything tasted like grape
kool-aid that seems to be how all those
multi part lines right if the bottles
look like clear with different dyes in
them it's all probably in my opinion I
don't know this for sure I should
research this they probably all come
from one factory and they just get
poured into different bottles and get
different names put on them something or
something similar
I am as a rule of thumb when you're sure
this is just my opinion but as a rule of
thumb when you're shopping for a
nutrient line try to stick with an
american-made nutrient yeah those are by
far the best quality avoid Dutch
nutrients of Dutch growers grow a
completely different way than most
Americans and the nutrients are
formulated differently and they don't
really work well with the way most
American growers grow I agree with most
of that I have seen some great results
though with a couple of those Dutch
brands might want mils if you follow
them okay okay then I can think of three
brands that I would almost buy their
products if it came down to I mean House
&amp; Garden is okay you're right though
about i I've got a note somewhere that
says to talk about Dutch the Dutch bred
cannabis to be a [ __ ] because their
grow rooms happens on a rocky mountain
in Afghanistan where the wind beat the
Sun on it so then the Dutch the Dutch
got a hold of these plants like we want
to grow them indoors I have no idea what
a [ __ ] Dutch exit would sound like if
I tried to do it we want to grow these
indoors they wanted to find the best
[ __ ] they bred it to be these really
skinny sticks that grow really perfect
buds
it's like roses like tulips that's Dutch
is all about the flower industries yeah
exactly and over here in Colorado
California the states that are catching
on we want to grow dank
robust plants we understand about full
plant health we're breeding for complete
plant structure not just tulips with
[ __ ] must the time I can pick out a
Dutch strain or duck kinetics from dot F
from touch from Amsterdam with I mean
roll a joint and smoke it you know put
two roll three joints put two American
strains and one from Amsterdam in there
and I guarantee I'll be able to pick out
though the whitewashed
just completely blended everything
tastes berries and flowers yeah nobody
structure okay I don't want to go back
and you know some American breeders are
probably susceptible and guilty of it
also probably bred because we wanted to
find back in the day we didn't have a
high pressure sodium lamp or an LED we
probably were using whatever finagled
lamp we can put together in the garage
to make some space to try to create a 12
12 flower cycle out of the few seeds
that we did get from whatever we we got
that we didn't know where it came from
but some dude told us was tie stick but
it was probably from Mexico but we
thought it was cool to tell our friends
it was Jamaican maybe tie stick maybe
Colombian may be Jamaican seeds it could
be males could be females could be who
knows what it is and they gotta figure
out how to grow that so we may have
gotten rid of the good [ __ ] back in the
day because we didn't have the right
whites we didn't have the right
knowledge we just wanted something that
finished quick and didn't climb up into
the lights
I grew for three years before I ever saw
a cloned or even made one so you just
did a bunch of seeds yeah I would kill
to have some uh yes I thought about how
many I used by Mexican schwag weed back
in the day where I live Mexican ragweed
was 450 500 dollars a pound it was
everywhere and you could get a half
ounce of seeds out of it it looked like
good healthy viable seeds I almost
wonder what I would have gotten from
them because you know those Mexican
crops were producing a low yielding
strain
remember the lime-green Christmas but
yes I grew out some seats how did that
come out it was lime-green Christmas so
it was just I guarantee that was like
touch genetics here we go yeah some Auto
flowers there's something like that it
was just it was alright wait you know 10
years ago what'll it [ __ ] head over
heels for yeah it's funny that you call
it Christmas but cuz this town is known
for getting that's amazing there's a lot
of talk about the Mexican cartels using
auto flower strains so that they can
keep stuff going year-round and we
talked about the one crop that was
busted in the forest near us it was all
Auto flowers yeah yeah that's so yeah
that's how they do that there those
girls are cookie cutter there's every
single one of them's the same I mean
there are different locations but the
way they grow I mean the cops I can tell
by looking at the pictures most the time
even the cops know you know the DEA
there's just a certain like [ __ ]
Willie and his crew were here again so
if you're ever going to bust the pickle
grow that somewhere find out what that
isn't grow just like it's a Mexican food
I think that's what gives him the first
what did they call Mexican nationals
what they label them as in the paper
like how do you know that we thought
tortillas I used to get mad when I found
seeds of my weed like good money for
[Music]
what happened through out the window on
Phish tour had those died when I was out
in California one time the first time I
was exposed to the whole medical
marijuana scene and everything kind of
changed my life actually I smoked some
OG Kush out there from my then
girlfriends
cousin it was full of seats and I
brought him back even and just over move
moving from you know over the years I
lost them so it's you find them when the
time is right hopefully oh they're long
I just know you guys to talk about my
first experience with medical marijuana
because I just I've got a cool [ __ ]
story I'm not gonna tell on this but
it's another podcast I just thought
about that I saw 4k room there was a
light down okay now that I'm a more
experienced grower like total Cali style
[ __ ] flood and drain tables
everything that's the way to do it but
the fast crank they it just blew my mind
it was like the oh man all these things
I thought about that room then like just
how huge it was and how much money they
must wake and all that how much work it
was now I kind of chuckle but yeah this
is before lights huh occasionally the
the first big yeah I try to I remember
the first time I walked into like a
giant commercial grow I had to like kind
of bite my lip and try to keep my face
freeze that [ __ ] my pants are getting a
boner
and now when I walk into big gross
people still trying to like the owner of
a girl will walk in and they peek at you
and they try to read your face and I
just try to keep yeah don't take it for
granted go check out some cool girls and
appreciate it too many hours in too many
facilities I've been in more facilities
than I care to admit been in half the
facilities in this great state let's
talk a little bit more about compost you
kind of got sidetracked don't ask a
couple other questions also I just was
what's your favorite [ __ ] to smoke
because we're talking about seeds and I
had a strain in mind that I wanted to
ask you about and I was like I wonder if
I'll mention that so it was a Pueblo
favorite what's when your favorites to
smoke I think oh you do I'm sure you do
I've got seeds of it yes yeah was at
Peapod the p90 one p90 one that's very
peapods the Kim dog dude yeah yeah I
know that I remember getting that
was amazing to the indica version I
could be completely wrong by the
Northern Lights I know it's bull rider
or pit bull which is their similar and
it's it's from stony girl seeds is who
actually put that one out in seed form
in the beginning and then now there's
another company I think it was Gold
Coast genetics maybe who I got the seeds
they charge me way too much like I need
that
I've been real I hold the seeds like
they're precious and I want to pop for
sure all right so I'm expecting company
are a good friend Lindsey the traveling
stoner of Bobo or coming over
Bobo blaster because his birthday was a
few days ago and he got a sweet new rig
from our friends rebel glass that's
[ __ ] dope we're gonna take some dad's
out of that we've got some time left I
just wanted to give you a warning let's
talk about composting because I just
told them to show up so just gonna walk
in eventually try to remember where
we're at we've got the worms we've got
the Bokashi we're talking about getting
it in a 40 gallon container
you've got your worms living in
newspaper you got ground up top some
phone books wood chunks bark type stuff
I imagine comfrey pokazhi pokazhi bucket
pulp
and that's pretty oh I threw in some
oyster shell hey guys some malted barley
seed okay Easter shell just to give
cal-mag and I was told by a warm keeping
friend that oyster shell helps poke the
worms themselves not to make them fatter
huh yeah make them eat more make them
work a little harder yeah okay so and
part of my plan with this big warm
container is to release in my garden in
the spring early summer so that I'm just
I'm building up the soil in my garden
year after year after year yeah if I can
dump I mean [ __ ] ten thousand worms or
something like that I might end up push
amazing is turn that soil all day long
yeah and if you you your dad go fishing
yeah but fly fisherman okay so no we've
got we've gotten dope-ass compost now
yeah what do we do with that do we want
to cut some of that 50% 25% with regular
soil let's let's act like we're gonna
put it into a potted plant to grow
either indoors or outdoors how much is
that compost do you want to use um if
you're building a soil from scratch I
would recommend like 30 40 percent okay
compost you don't have to use that much
that's just I mean that's ideal 30 it's
available yeah yeah if you've got that
you know you want to top dress that or
do you want to blend it in when you
start if you're building the soil I
would totally real kind of blending it
if you are top dressing I would do or to
say like a quarter cup per gallon
container okay so if you got a seven
gallon I would recommend three and a
half cups you did the odd number to
yourself I don't know what I do the yeah
yeah what I tell the guys at work
and if you're recharging the soil or
like reusing the soil like Jeff does I
would probably say like 20 percent okay
five percent maybe alright maybe even as
low as 15 it kind of depends on how much
aeration your soil has and if you want
to add any end or if or so okay
aeration is important you guys we
learned our lesson I put some plants
into cocoa and I did not put anything in
there to aerate it and those plants
pretty much gave me the middle finger
their whole lives it's super compressed
you gonna fill that up with some perlite
put something in there to kind of air it
up for sure alright you can also make
teas with your compost awesome yeah so
with compost make sure you have a
consistent temperature I've been told if
you let it get too warm you can
potentially have some funky stuff okay
and your tea or in the compost itself in
your tea okay all right a lot of people
talk crap about compost or you'll find
people that talk [ __ ] about it one of
the things they claim is as ecoli of it
which it possibly could have e.coli in
it okay but it also has a million other
[ __ ] things that are way nastier than
ecoli that don't karma wouldn't a large
percentage of your fruits and vegetables
have ecoli anyway when you purchased
them okay so would that mean maybe not
to use a compost tea as a full-year feed
well that's that's the way to get around
that right just feed it to the roots and
not the full year yeah I personally
would never use a actual compost tea for
foliar either yeah I would strictly save
that for worm castings okay yeah so
that's the way to get around that yeah
don't worry they feed it to the soil
magical happened that you : goes away
yeah and also with compost you can make
a concentrate where just take your
compost put it in a cheesecloth
massage it in water or underneath water
for about ten minutes
like you know put it in a bucket of
water just kind of rub it out a little
yeah actually what you're doing you need
it like a loaf of bread okay yeah
perverts and then that makes compost or
worm casting you can do either one a
concentrate and has a longer shelf life
than an aerated tea okay Wow yeah that's
useful something I just learned you're
taking old food scraps and recycled dirt
and putting it in cheesecloth and
squeezing it and making your own
nutrients why not do this let's not
making waste companies that do not
really support the cannabis movement or
us or our wallets let's stop making
trucks drive across the country with
bottles of water you're paying for what
would you buy whatever brand to use I
love botanic air but still every time I
buy a bottle of pure Belen Pro or liquid
karma I had to pay a truck to drive that
[ __ ] from Arizona to Colorado that I had
to pay some dude or the hydro shot with
a mullet sell it to me I probably could
have just taken some kelp and seabird
guano whatever the [ __ ] else is in that
product and I could have made my own
probably even bench less blue yeah it's
kind of environmentally friendly yes yes
I don't have to add to that truck
driving that emissions though water
being shipped the gas the exhaust like
we could do it ourselves and not only
that you're diverting food from going
into the landfill exactly so you're just
you're basically money from going right
into the same landfill yeah yeah put it
back in your drop back in your wallet
you're producing something you're not
depending on someone for that little
tiny bit of for your life you know it
only may be that part but I love you
know trying to be a producer not a
consumer you know may sound a little
weird but if there's a good feeling
knowing that my vivacious healthy green
vigorous cannabis
plants are on nearly the same diet as
myself for sure
it makes me think maybe other than all
this freaking dr. pepper I'm addicted to
maybe I'm green and vivacious and
vigorous as well keeps me going keeps me
strong alright dude we've been like 40
minutes you got anything else you want
to talk about composting before we get a
doorbell ring and we get some new
stoners showing up yeah good casting by
the way comfortable now just stop trying
to build my schedule I've got a busy
life that was all of a sudden well I
don't know I've always had a busy life
but it you know a few months ago it just
all of a sudden like really stepped up
it's good um yeah so it's good but it's
bad for my podcast and I have all these
ideals and the you know just plans and
everything and I'm just trying to adjust
into my schedule
I understand expect a kick-ass podcast
coming from me besides the Colorado
podcast are you get a new line coming
yeah excellent so mo go with overhead
and but it's going to be the high-grade
homestead I like that so and it'll be
more than just cannabis growing so talk
about gardening and chickens and all
kinds of [ __ ] stuff you'd find out a
homestead I love it I love him well if
you ever need a cannabis expert on that
show the rest of the Colorado podcast
boys to burn thanks for letting your
husband come hang out for a couple hours
and get I got him stupid high higher
I haven't really been dabbing diet oh
man there's another also takes great
care of me when I go to the hydro shop
she's always excited to see me she gives
me a big hug she's super friendly it's
great customer service so big shout out
to Bern thanks for letting me borrow
your husband for an hour to do a podcast
I look forward to hearing the homegrown
homes to high-grade homestead but I look
forward to hearing that I hope my
listeners follow you on up that podcast
nice I'm sure they're gonna follow you
on Instagram a tad Jessie grows they're
also gonna check out the Colorado
podcast Instagram page while they're at
it they're gonna go follow me on
Instagram its Irie underscore genetics
dude oh thank you for joining me on the
podcast we've been here for two hours I
appreciate that I'm gonna do a couple of
wrap ups make sure you find me on all
the social media guys I'm on Facebook
it's the girl from her podcast I'm on
Twitter its add G fyh podcast also you
know I would love it if you go to iTunes
that leave me a rating and a review I'm
sure you know how to find the ratings
and reviews by now everybody so far has
given me a five star review you know
it'd be cool if you follow suit but if
you feel like you want to be different
do what you need to do also let me
remind you about a new service I've
signed up for it is called patreon
patreon is a service that will allow my
listeners to make a financial
contribution to the show if they feel so
inclined if you feel like the
information or knowledge or friendship I
have provided you or just you want throw
some money around go to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart and what that
will allow you to do is sign up to
contribute a monthly contribution you
can contribute as little as one dollar I
honestly don't think there's a limit to
the amount of zeros you can add to that
[Music]
if you sign up for patreon you can
contribute one dollar to the show it
will charge you every the first of every
month and then that will send that right
over to my PayPal account and honestly
I'm not trying to make a bunch of money
off my friends and my listeners what
that will do that will help me pay for
the cost of my website you guys I read
genetics Colorado com
cost me about three hundred and fifteen
dollars per year to keep up there
and that is how I deliver you this
podcast I'm not trying to get rich I'm
just trying to offset that I'm not
trying to pay for that out of my pocket
not bagging either so if you would like
to go to patreon go check it out
patreon.com slash girl from your heart I
would really appreciate it yes do it and
he's a big guy he was my second
contributor to patreon that's where I
was headed next big shout out to all
three of the people who have contributed
to my patreon so far I appreciate all
three of you I'm not sure if everybody
wants to be listed by name ah so you
know who you are big shout out much love
much respect I appreciate the support
even if you can't contribute to patreon
you guys I love you and I appreciate you
just for listening to the podcast you'll
have to give me money you don't have to
give me anything to be my friend I love
you guys I appreciate you being there
and supporting the podcast I extra
especially his support thank you for
supporting cannabis you guys I had a lot
of caffeine and abs my brains go too
fast but I appreciate you for supporting
cannabis and like I said earlier I
completely trust you or thank you for
trusting me to be your cannabis guru it
means a lot to me it sounds like I need
to wrap up the show because my tongue is
tying itself in a damn knot so I think
all I have to say now is a big shout out
to my friend the Barefoot grower and
it's all next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
to teach at my high school
the maid of rhabdo great
[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode number 171 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
[Music]
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots bed for letting me
use their music on my podcast big shout
out to cat across the table from me a
repeat offender returning champion
ladies and gentlemen white Mike is back
[Music]
while you're listening to make sure you
follow them on Twitter it's also remind
everybody how they can check out your
Facebook on Facebook microphone I hope
it's just make sure you guys support
Mike on the Twitter and follow Pablo for
sensible cannabis laws check out what
he's posting there on Facebook we truly
appreciate the cannabis advocates dude
did you her granny give you a shout out
I did I did I appreciate that granny
it's uh it was fun meeting you the one
song we got to meet the communicating
and I can't wait till we run into each
other again I will get you guys here
together on this podcast it'll be a good
time right I'll do my best sounds good
to me we'll get you high as giraffe but
some of granny's awesome there's the
basket of magic the basket yes granny
and her basket of magic granny got to
meet Action Bronson the other day
Bronson so shout out to davon granny
also since we're doing shoutouts I need
to give a huge shout out to my friends
at handmade apparel alright if you guys
need any sort of t-shirt printing some
stickers some hat pins you guys I fully
endorse and support my friends at
handmade apparel check out handmade
apparel dot biz or check them out on
Facebook there is a Facebook group in a
Facebook page you guys they printed me
some grow from your heart podcast
hoodies they've printed my IRA genetics
t-shirts I have got a bright red
handmade apparel hoodie I've got a green
hoodie
I've got happens I've got stickers that
these folks made and everything is
top-quality it's made in America by
Americans it's made by dab kids who take
dabs they dab just as hard as you and I
do so I think it's great to support the
community I think it's great to support
our friends that are doing this with us
I really like these people they're good
friends of mine and they make great [ __ ]
so please support them as much as I do
handmade for all your printing needs and
get that sweet handmade apparel logo on
the side of your shirt like I've got we
could all be in the same gang that's
pretty awesome the handmade true ladies
and gentlemen go to handmade apparel dot
biz and check them out it's a stuff
printed I'm a big fan of the quality I
typically shirts that are printed with
logos and stuff the logo goes first I've
done all of my handmade stuff sure is
you know I wear if you know me I'm kind
of a cartoon characters what they call
me I've been wearing probably I have not
thrown any of them away I've been
rocking these t-shirts for probably five
years now and from the first one I have
not thrown it away the logo is still
crispy the shirt however is getting it's
getting that black shirt tinge to it but
the logo looks like it was fresh
they're sweet shirts so I think we've
given them a huge shout out big thanks
to my friends at hammy and apparel for
all the stuff they've printed you guys
they have the best rates for hat pins if
you're getting your hat pins made go
through handmade apparel I went through
I tried a lot of companies handmade
apparel was the most reliable they do
the artwork in-house and they have the
pins made so it's all one one groups you
don't have to have different people
working together and [ __ ] you up they
do great artwork I love those guys much
respect big hugs all that stuff to our
friends at handmade apparel make sure
you check my have made apparel dot biz I
think I've said that enough time
once you want to chatter about before we
get into our main topic my car do you
want to jump into let's start off with
the letter from the DEA they came out
just a couple of days ago and then we
will do if we have time for it we will
do a couple of election updates because
I know you love getting to that
listeners have asked for longer lessons
that was me clapping listeners are like
hey bro I want a longer episode you guys
I've taken on a new project I don't talk
a lot about this project that I'm doing
I've kind of kept it on the down low but
it keeps me busy for 45 or 50 hours a
week so I haven't been doing too podcast
episodes I apologize I'm gonna do my
best to get longer episodes and I know
that the episodes have been a little not
as informative I was over [ __ ] well
do you guys it's the holiday season I've
got friends I'm doing a new project my
mom earlier today for quite some time
talking about Christmas presents and
stuff and don't feel you just wrapped a
killer outdoor Grove session again yeah
that's true big shout out to Jessie for
coming and helping us do some outdoor
grow lessons I feel like I got a pack so
much info into every single episode when
I don't give a full informative episode
I feel like I'm kind of treating myself
and the listeners right there are
episodes where I've had to stop and
pause repeatedly while I take notes
they're so hyper detail that's fantastic
I've got and I know I keep saying I've
got those podcasts in the works the ones
are you're gonna have got the folder
right here my hand you get this this is
all this page gets more impressive yeah
I'm gonna do those I'm just I'm trying
to perfect them those are episodes that
are gonna be in-depth and I'm kind of a
perfectionist so when they come out like
that they're really good but on this
episode we're gonna talk about like I
pulled that background I've been
podcasting Wow in this podcast we're
gonna talk about a letter that the DEA
sent who the hell did they send it to do
they just publish it or was it actually
mailed to people this was the big
dust-up this week the letter clatter
that everyone freaked out about over a
CB d did your face just break
this story almost broke me the big
dust-up is basically saying the DEA just
made CBD illegal again and that's silly
because it was never legal right we're
gonna we're definitely gonna talk about
why it's silly and we'll talk about a
lot of details there are a lot of
different versions of this article the
main part that I want to focus on is a
quote the store is a great example of
just how fake news can be right with
different degrees of [ __ ] they can
work their way into a press story I've
read it in three or four different
locations and the part I want to focus
on is mainly quoted from the DEA
themselves so that can't be wrong and
then the the buffers around it we can
talk [ __ ] about a blot on every website
so this one I chose the one the Leafly
article looked like a crock of [ __ ] to
me I didn't like the Leafly article so I
chose to go with the article from the
Green Rush daily I shout out to the
Green Rush daily the headline is the DEA
just banned CBD and here's why and
there's a giant ad and then I finally
scroll like seven Scrolls and I get to
the article it says the legality of CBD
is no longer in the gray area in fact
the DEA just banned CBD cementing its
place in the list of schedule 1
substances CBD or cannabidiol is a
compound or cannabinoid in cannabis they
won't get you high what it does do
though is stop seizures and aid and
suffering from dilip elliptic Jesus I'm
the one that wanted to talk [ __ ] about
an article and I can't speak English
words debilitating is the word I was
trying to say I kneeled cannabinoid and
can a video but I can't say debilitating
you guys sinful especially on a phone
yeah especially after all those dabs the
dabs never help with reading aloud
that's true
I may be the exception to that rule so
why is the DEA putting it on why is the
DEA putting it on the list of the most
harmful drugs available to man probably
the same reasons they temporarily banned
the herbal pain reliever trade on
earlier this year they're both
alternatives to more dangerous
prescription opiates that are plaguing
the country the DEA action seemed to
protect Big Pharma's pocket
more than the health of American
citizens that's not the point that I
wanted to get you they're talking about
[Music]
yes just that quick somewhere I wanted
to venture into later in the episode
because I think that maybe have
something to do with it they see that if
there are pharmaceutical companies
working with it they don't want us
having that market they want to corner
that before we do so they're just gonna
shut us down like oh no no you can't
even play so now we win they just land
it on free parking by [ __ ] us but I
want to keep going the archaic spelling
of the word marijuana with an H is used
in the text in federal and the Federal
Register announcing the rule probably to
avoid turning up in marijuana related
search results oh wow is that true
no [ __ ] [ __ ] conspiracies yeah I
think this will be helpful for our
listeners yep because yeah it's that's
just how the feds spell marijuana and
this is where what a lot of the fake
news is oriented around basically
everybody has heard of CBD by now coast
to coast the is CBDs a household term
now people have seen through sanjay
gupta's specials and through YouTube
videos and Facebook posts how helpful it
can be with Parkinson's
I wish user disorders with list of a
syndrome with pain management with the
change in federal policy with the Ogden
memo and the Cole memo that led to
marijuana markets like we have here in
Colorado with her legal some of those
like Colorado's included legal hemp in
so last year the year before the feds
just like the : Ogden memos did for high
THC cannabis they put out a little blurb
in the farm bill covering industrial
been putting a definition for what
industrial hemp is and so under the
guise of that legal loophole a number of
companies both domestic and foreign
started selling TVs or CBD extract
online in all 50 states making it
available pretty much everywhere
companies like CBD life water have
sprung up that are trying to get
distribution in all 50 states
and it's under a gray market loophole
created by the farm bill it is in no way
legal the feds have always considered
every part of the cannabis plant it
doesn't matter if it's the Teva indica
have ruderalis they don't give a [ __ ] it
let me jump in right there because
that's right or am in this article and
they spell it marijuana with an H why
because these laws are based and [ __ ]
racism and that was a lot of where that
the original basis for these comes from
so when the feds write a new marijuana
law it's on the backs of all the old
marijuana laws and they keep the same
racist ass smelling I have to get
through this article to make the show
show the reason given that the u.s. is
complying with the international drug
control treaties the reason is that they
are stated reason for the change this
week is to help them comply with
international then they see before this
elaboration CBDs legality was in a gray
area it was assumed that CBD extracted
from medical cannabis was only legal for
medical marijuana patients any legal to
the rest however CBD derived from
industrial hemp was being sold across
the country as if it were federally
federally legal well apparently the DEA
is always believed any form of cannabis
extract to be Schedule one if I handed
you a CBD molecule a scientist a CBD
molecule and I said did this come from
hemp or cannabis he'd probably tell me
to go [ __ ] myself because it's the same
thing it would say it's a molecule so
the DEA claims if there are small
amounts of cannabinoids in every CBD
extract they cite this as another reason
to keep CBD on Schedule one for
practical purposes all extracts that
contains CBD will also contain
at least a small amount of other
cannabinoids however if it were possible
to produce the form of cannabis plant
I'm sorry they wrote this weird there's
an ad right here I'm skipping through it
let's see produce from the cannabis
plant extract they contain only CBD and
no other cannabinoids such an extract
would fall within the new drug code so
basically the DEA made extracting CBD
completely illegal whether it's from
hemp or not whether it is pure CBD cuz
they are wrong right there when they say
that you can't get pure CBD because I
know thinking counting I can put five
fingers up and confidently say that I
know five people but I could call
friends that can make CBD isolate is
ninety-nine point eight or nine percent
CBD that one or two percent is
atmospheric conditions there are things
like oxygen in there that they cannot
control it's you can get 100% pure CBD
lots of different places
the DEA is position on it doesn't have
anything to do with their being trace
cannabinoids in it that's just something
that happened to mumble during the press
conference so it's always been always
been illegal just like every part of the
cannabis plant is illegal federally the
seeds are illegal though the leaves the
root ball is illegal the pot you grew it
it is illegal it doesn't matter if it's
industrial hemp every year I'm just to
be safe every eighteen months some drug
task force somewhere like East [ __ ]
Texas makes the announcement that
they've just found the world's biggest
pot farm and they're raiding it today
and they didn't catch any growers and
it's headline news on Monday and it's
headline news on Tuesday and then
there's nothing about it in the press on
Wednesday and next Friday comes out that
it was a wild Hempfield
on some farmers back it's 400 400 acres
in the middle of nowhere and it was the
weather conditions that spring were
perfect for feral hemp to go nuts and
the DEA I'll spend $100,000 ripping all
of that feral hemp out of the ground and
burning it because it's the dangerous
marijuana plant it doesn't matter that
it's
while that doesn't have any tears if you
smoked any of that stuff if you
harvested dried and cured it properly
all that [ __ ] would do is give you a
headache there's an Indian Reservation I
want to say it was in New Mexico
somewhere hot and kind of miserable to
live where feral hemp was just
everywhere they couldn't do anything
about it it was an issue and they'd
found a way to basically build whole
houses with it with hemp creed and a
couple of other products and they were
doing it all on site in the feds would
show up every now and again and burn
their em down because it's dangerous
hemp I mean this happens all over the
country the DEA wastes small fortunes
ripping wild hemp plants out of the
ground that are left over from the 30s
and 40s when hemp was grown as a crop
all over the US when there's a terrible
heroin epidemic everywhere right now
like Colorado Springs is littered with
crystal meth meth is everywhere in
Springs people are driving around on
bicycles look in the [ __ ] trash cans
all over Colorado Springs Pueblo it
level is dead it's Friday night right
now you guys it's Friday night at 10:30
it's [ __ ] quiet all the people that
used to be out raging doing heroin not
all but I mean a good [ __ ] portion of
our young people are out doing heroin
right now and the DEA is worried about
[ __ ] with plants they keep us cool I
mean not even cannabis just fun cannabis
that I guess you stoned and it helped
just know if you make jeans with houses
bricks
textiles necklaces right there's an
infinite number of products you can make
with with hemp and that was part of the
the reason they they included the
exemption in the farm bill last year the
year before to to designate what exactly
is industrial hemp because everybody I
mean everybody everybody understands how
absurd our hemp laws are but as far as
law enforcement is concerned cops can't
tell the difference between half and
weed and they're pretty sure you can
grow the two next to each other so you
could heart hide your high THC plants
and among your hemp plants which anyone
that's ever growing either crop knows
how insane that is
but law enforcement across the country
still argue [ __ ] like that in federal
court well to keep the DEA noted since
all Asians like this and Saul's growing
a bunch of it's all CBD plants and it
looks like killer cannabis plants if
they told me that that was White Widow
or something I honestly couldn't tell
the difference on their plants they've
got can't very cannabis looking some of
them can be very very similar it depends
what the hemp you're growing has been
bred to do yeah and if I understand
what's doing is they're producing CBD
extract it looks like it grows just like
feel and that's the type of F you would
want for a high CBD extra production but
that I'm guessing that hemp strain would
be crap if they tried to make oil and
fiber it's not fibrous
I mean that's one of the great things
about cannabis is it can be bred one way
or the other to achieve an infinite
number absolutely of final products but
as far as the feds are concerned every
single part of its illegal the only
legal hemp or marijuana products that
are federally legal in the United States
are hemp clothing produced in other
countries are produced from fabric that
was grown in other countries silly low
friends and and I mean products that
were produced with plant material grown
in other countries everything else is at
least gray market the FDA and a couple
other national safety organizations
release the thing we even did a blurb
about it on the show about the foreign
companies selling you god knows what is
CBD extract random [ __ ] in there yep
they were testing and it didn't have a
lot of CBD in it
or maybe it did but it had a lot other
crap and you didn't want us along with
it is filler
that's what you get in a gray market you
get a lot of knockoff products you get a
lot of mislabeled products and this is
why I've been freaking out about getting
people politically active disease just
doing this for their own financial gain
do you think the pharmaceutical
companies are planning something with
CBD products um there's a couple in
Great Britain and around the country
that are already working with THC CBD
products GW Pharmaceuticals is working a
couple of different product lines but
there's still five ten years from market
okay
I'm sure the industry don't that don't
want THC and see like they would prefer
to I as an industry I'm sure they would
prefer to have control of all
medications that people can't eat yeah
but that's not physically possible they
don't want to make any better they want
to mask my symptoms and keep feeding me
a pill to make me a customer ingredients
like the one conspiracy theory you're
gonna get me to buy into anywhere but
with a decision like this this is just
business as usual this is the exact same
I mean this has been true since nineteen
forty if people are freaking out about
this decision today because they issued
it it's a owned serial number so they
can track the caesars separately and I
mean I encourage the move because
tracking [ __ ] separately is helpful
right now any anti marijuana group is
gonna tell you that ten years ago
fifteen years ago the average THC
content in marijuana was one to three
percent and they can back that up with
DEA seizure numbers and the reason
that's true is because they've been
seizing fields of [ __ ] barrel hemp
every year for decades and I mean it's
always been illegal this is nothing new
a tracking it separately helps us figure
out okay exactly how much did they waste
ripping up half out of the ground how
much money did they waste making sure
Kansas didn't get their hemp seed last
year how much money did they waste
rounding up hemp seed off the inner or
have
off the side of the highway as you drive
to New Mexico I mean it's nuts how many
people since they've got these companies
that are shipping CBD ah they're gonna
have to like the people there's a couple
I don't know if I want to say anybody's
names I don't - getting people in
trouble but I know people personally and
there are companies in Colorado that
will ship CBD products nationwide you
can be in Maine name in California and
they will send you a bottle of CBD
t-shirt how are those people that were
relying on those medicine what are they
gonna do now that's who I'm mainly
worried about they're screwed yeah but
they were always like their access was
only obtained through a gray market and
if they were paying attention they knew
that and they've been lobbying for a
different way to access whatever product
they desperately need in their area um I
would love to say come to Colorado and
we've got CBD for you but there is a CBD
drought it the only way like everybody
thinks they're gonna come to Colorado
and go to a medical dispensary and get
Heidi CBD medicine and they are highly
disappointed there is not much is
expensive because it's it's there's been
a shortage for a while you've got to
find yourself a private caregiver
squeezed out of the system now anyway or
you've got a girl yourself and then
you've got to find a CBD clone or you
got to find seeds or something high CBD
and then you've got to grow it and then
you've got to get it tested or I don't
know people focus a little bit too much
on testing when it comes to personal
medicine I think I'm gonna do an episode
on this I'm gonna write this down I
think that the medicine I think if
medicine works for you it works for you
don't pay attention to the lab testing
there's a lot of elaboration I want to
do on that but we'll see there's a lot
of stuff that lab testing brought to the
community that's just bizarre people
focus on all the wrong numbers and
that's I mean I loved watching the CBD
industry explode over the last two years
I don't take that from what I'm saying
because I think that should be available
to everyone everywhere I think this
society would be a lot better if more
people were adding CBD to their diets
regularly as a supplement
it helps with a bunch of stuff I'm a
huge CBD advocate I use it daily what's
your daily dose of CBD
right now I'm restricting myself because
the product I'm using I'm limited on
accessing anymore of it ever that won't
happen
it's gone the person that's making it is
gone and so I'm kind of making it last
so is the worst part about this product
yep and right now I'm it two or three
CBD devs a day okay um and I spaced them
throughout the day and it depends if I'm
not hurting that day maybe I only take
one maybe I'll take just a little
itty-bitty one maybe I'll just use some
of the pain cream I've got left in store
but that's not purpose I'm purposefully
going slow before then or like when I
was taking it is milligrams pills it was
50 milligrams a day morning 25 at night
I was my next question
okay 25 so 25 to keep you pain-free a
day 25 to get you sleep well just making
it easy cuz I never kind of went wild
with it because I liked it half and half
THC CBD and I didn't want to be eating
50 milligrams of THC before like I went
out and did my day so I was keeping it
225 and then adding more during the day
if I needed to okay but I can consume
human huge amounts of CBD when I'm
hurting like I've got an issue with
through the vertebrae in my back and it
doesn't happen often but every now and
then they Twain off each other kind of
like a rubber band and that feeling is
pretty excruciating and then the area
around where those two twang will get
inflamed and hurt for several days and
to a degree where I can't really bend
her work and if I feel its twang and I
eat a whole bunch of CBD likes because
300 milligrams right away it won't
inflame to the point where I'm down the
next day that's I was yeah I've heard a
lot about if you get on it as soon as
you feel it it like as soon as you feel
it get that like get that CBD edible in
you and if you can take a DAB because
dab is it's instant absorption yeah dab
is instant not just
but any inhalation through the lungs
that that makes it to the bloodstream
incredibly quickly you get relief in
seconds yep
it's it's seconds and if you eat it
you're looking at I mean half hour per
hour hour and a half two hours before
you you've got full effect of what
you've consumed the effect of what you
eat is gonna be a little stronger but
that delayed if you're taking it for
pain you can't wait two hours for your
painful to kick in right but CBD was
never legal in all 50 states
you just called that back like a
professional kiddies it was a loophole
that everybody was operating under and I
mean it was so glaringly obvious a
loophole that Chinese companies know
fall over it and obviously that was
gonna get shut down at some point and
that's not even what this was this was
this was just the DEA a serial number
for when they do seizures they didn't
even release a letter saying we're gonna
go after the people selling this [ __ ]
online it's just a reminder that all
parts of the cannabis plant are illegal
most of our community is still not
politically aware let alone privately
active but that's what we're here for
that's why I bring you on Mike because
you can remind them and you can turn
huge I mean huge segments of the
population not just the marijuana
community got this story wrong I'm
freaked out about it and they're tying
it to every conspiracy theory there is
we gets marijuana legalization like I
read a whole on a fairly reputable news
site it was an opinion piece that they
chose to publish about because they used
the marijuana with an H spelling in this
that it was that was because Trump was
elected in racism is now openly accepted
and that this was medication today was
gonna round up the stoners and the
Mexicans and this was published in a pen
and I'm reading this like okay geez
like we've come so far we just had a
huge night on election night marijuana
won big in so many places in the first
thing we do to celebrate is give
ourselves a black eye and then another
in another in another in another in
another I mean we didn't need a fake
news shitstorm this week there's enough
real news that we should be focused on
and because so much of our community
isn't aware of the legalities nationally
for this plan we all love this story's
spread like wildfire I've seen half a
dozen businesses down here posted and
it's like you're a marijuana store you
should have known this better than ever
yeah yeah the businesses the CBD
businesses that we're sending this [ __ ]
through the mail their lawyers should
have made this perfectly clear to them
that they're operating in a legal gray
area through a loophole in a [ __ ]
farm bill I mean that as far as the feds
are concerned all parts of the cannabis
plant are illegal regardless of THC
content it can be just the root ball of
a hemp plant that dried up earth was
harvested two years ago and it's still
illegal you can still be charged for the
federal crime for having it wow that's
scary
yeah and that's that's just the reality
of our situation that's why I have so
much respect for even the marijuana
business owners I really hate because
there's everyday going alright we've
talked about this alright so thanks for
listening to the DEA part we're gonna
move on to a little bit of updating
stuff of things we've talked about in
the past because on our post-election
episode we mentioned that a
it was the little bit of bad news we had
for for Pueblo for our election night
there was a election question should we
allow retail marijuana stores inside
Pueblo city was it called on the ballot
what's that we thought it did not pass
on Allah when we recorded our
post-election show it was it was failing
by like 150 or 200 votes and by the time
they got all of the provisional ballots
counted and all the ballots that were
stuck together and what not counted we
won by like 5 or 600 votes nice so we
will be able to have recreational
cannabis stores within the city limits
of Pueblo um December 27th I believe the
City Council is the Tuesday after
Christmas city council will be voting on
the final rules and regs package for Rex
Rex shops
[Music]
unfortunately I've been involved with
this for a long time so I know way more
about it than I should even the people
that are working on it right now I
probably know more about it than they do
the ordinance that they're about to vote
and probably pass on passed into law was
written by a Zoning Commission that was
very dead set against allowing marijuana
businesses in the city at all and at a
certain point they discovered that with
one or two zoning buffer rules so 1,000
feet from schools and 300 feet from
residences that they could essentially
limit the number of marijuana businesses
in the city because that's all the
property that's physically available to
make sense if they they include those
two buffer zones and to make that even
more restrictive they've decided to
limit the total number of stores in the
city to 8
for north of the river for south of the
river they've the city is preparing for
a wave of applications and they've come
up with a point system in a time line
for that application process to take
place so hopefully by the end of the
year we've got at least a couple of
recent marijuana shops open in Puebla
that'd be cool
yeah I I wish the the rules were that
we're about to pass are different or
we're different are different but that's
very unlikely I'm doing what I can to
get some of the craziness to be taken
out of them but there's only so much
change that they're willing to make
right now they're catching on they're
kind of slowly evolving this is a very
different City Council than the one we
had a year or two years ago I mean this
is a full process that started four
years ago it's been four full years that
the city has been working on this
particular set of rules and regs that's
how long I've been working on it do you
think since we had the first shop do you
think we could get just first in line
like hey no come on just play that card
okay we was here most of that part of
the city is blacked out due to schools
because the thousand-foot from schools
rule isn't just classrooms where they're
students if the college owns an empty
apartment on whatever street then
there's a thousand foot buffer around
that apartment around that empty
apartments property line yeah yeah does
the library in such kill not for not for
these this rule package like that tends
not to matter um there were several
other buffer zones listed around our
medical shops um which is why they've
been allowed with no store cap for four
or five years and we only have three
I move the stoning rules you can really
limit the allowed businesses in an area
and this is why if your area passed
legalization recently you really need to
brush up on local politics and get down
to planning and zoning in City Council
or County Commission meetings now
because these rules are being decided
for your area right now I mean if you're
not involved people who do give a [ __ ]
enough to show up it's their voice that
helps craft these rules and if it's two
people that really hate weed for one
reason or another in one person that
loves weed but is really an articulate
expect ugly rules yeah if you know how
to grow and you were all about talking
with City Council go down there
represent them tell them why they're
there guidelines aren't gonna work for a
typical girl you know I was thinking
about I think I cannot recall buying
cannabis in a Pueblo dispensary since
the legalization of recreational
cannabis that's the last time I can
remember shopping in a blow dispensary I
rarely shop in a store but I'm actually
get out to the stores as often as
possible just to see what everybody's
doing yes yes and also our good friends
at elevate glass and and so that was the
good news that we screwed up on election
right that was our big blooper from that
show yes the next thing I've got written
down you can see it it says Maine if you
want to tell us about Maine go for Maine
Maine voted to legalize recreational
marijuana the vote passed by a very very
very very slim margin statewide it was
like votes or something it was very very
close
so the anti-pop people forced a recount
costing the state half a million bucks
that recount is underway now it's paused
for the weekend they've counted all of
the cities in county areas that the
anti-pop people were sure we're gonna
give them the numbers to reverse the
vote
and the the outcome hasn't changed
legalization is still winning and the
really funny part of the story to me is
uh so in Maine the election rules if you
push for a recount and you get it the
pro side and the anti side for whatever
issues getting recounted have to send
ten volunteers every day to the recount
option office like you know it still
cost the state half a million dollars to
do this even with using volunteers from
the campaigns and the anti-pop people in
Maine can't get ten fifty show up every
day and so the the recounts taken a lot
longer than it should have
election staffers have had to stand in
and cover for anti legalization
volunteers that weren't able to make it
on time or were late several days a
couple days in a row when this first
started and it just happened again here
at the end of the week didn't have
enough people show luckily the pro pop
people have had extra volunteers willing
to work and have been willing to work
some longer hours to make sure that this
gets recounted correctly correctly and
accurately so that the recount is still
on track to finish up when it's supposed
to
but the anti-pop people were so
convinced that they had this in the bag
I'm so convinced that they had the
majority of people that they forced the
recount in a million and a half million
in taxes to be spent they can't even get
ten volunteers
that's funny come on now how many how
many things are still being recounted
nationwide um total election why there's
a bunch but it's all little stuff okay
is statewide issues there well there
aren't that many that are still counting
four full weeks right since the election
every County is a huge process because
it's done by hand and basically so in
Maine the ten people from each side pair
up and then they're given an election an
election person and then those three
people goes through the table
and you look at the ballot in both of
the the Pro and the anti people agree
that that's a yes vote
in the third guy there from the Election
Commission's there to make sure that the
to the eighth I and the pro people don't
fight nice and follow the rules I mean I
mean this it takes an insane amount of
time on election night they're just
funneling these [ __ ] throwing machine
if you can do thousands a minute or
thousands a second unless you're Pueblo
trash you're [ __ ]
[Music]
but the recount is an incredibly taxing
process but there aren't that many that
are still going I'm typically by now one
side is gone okay the vote clearly
hasn't changed we're down to just the
tiny towns or the areas that voted
strongly one way or the other it's not
gonna matter let's let's let it go and
they've conceded at this point I'm the
anti pot thing or the anti pot group in
Maine is one of the few holdouts that
are still fighting they don't have a
chance so what this means if you happen
to listen to the podcast and you live in
Maine way first shout out for listening
we appreciate it
i'm ii get involved locally cuz in a
couple of weeks when all this is said
and done and it's official and marijuana
is legal at best you're gonna be talking
to local government officials who will
be saying over and over and over again
well the vote was really close so we
hear what both sides are saying we're
gonna give the anti pot people nine out
of the ten things they want and we're
gonna give the pro marijuana people 1
out of the 10 things they want because
it was a close vote and if you don't get
on top of it now and figure out exactly
how these rules get made in your area
you're gonna be driving a really long
distance to the only dispensary in your
area and it's gonna be crazy expensive
to buy weed though if it's mean it won't
be that far then still cold I honestly
have no idea exactly how big that state
is but I don't want to drive 45 minutes
to the weed store no I don't want to
drive 20 minutes doesn't mean you gotta
drive 45 minutes home before you can
smoke that new weed yep and if there's
just give me a nostalgic feeling
remember one needs to go to the
dispensary yeah I don't have it
now I'm sorry I'm jaded but I remember
the feeling I just took a fat dab you
guys I apologize for the chokes while
Mike was on his rant there I took a
couple dabs normally you just go to the
dispensary and you'd be like oh you want
one yeah I got you I've got the hash if
you've got a dad you just don't use that
email because it's kind of quiet it to
be quiet and I use a torch there's a
torch yes Shantanu our friends at
elevate for keeping me stocked up on
fresh bangers remember that feeling when
he would go to the light I would I would
do Rob kind of a nerd I would do
research online and find out what the
hottest strains are in Denver or in
Colorado and I would go find that if it
was a Bruce Banner I'd go find where
they had some Bruce Banner what was the
strain that they had at the Denver
relief they had the biodiesel got the
biodiesel that's not from TGA sub cool I
was going to the clinic on Mexico in
Denver and I was getting the vortex wax
and I would say how much do you have of
that and they'd said this much and I'd
say I'll take it yeah they started
sending limits because the first week
they put those purchase limits in place
the girls screwed yeah thanks that was
actually when I bought my hitman rig but
uh so I remember the feeling I would get
when I would leave the dispensary with
that specific strain that I was so
excited about going to find it's like
like skip it's like almost the feeling
was a little kidding I'd get a new video
game whatever the new Zelda or Super
Mario came out and I'm like oh I got it
I gotta go home and show my friends and
you'd go home and call one of your
buddies and this is the same thing would
happen with weed you'd go home and call
your friends like bro Mike you gotta
come over here I got some biodiesel bro
you gotta come check it out and you
drive over and I try to keep that drawer
jar closed until you got here so that
when I cracked it open it was just
[ __ ] Oh biodiesel in the face and then
we grind a little bit of it up and smoke
it together to be like that anticipation
from the car to the house of like oh god
just mike meet me at the house don't
even make me wait bro I miss the dry
home from picking up weed for sure hmm
hmm when that was like an hour 20 minute
drive that was stressful like by the
time you got home that adrenaline high
Dan's on the show but that adrenaline
high from driving home reward it's like
I finally made it
I felt like an almost is more of a
reward ace to get higher used to be a
mission a STONER mission you'd have to
find do you have weed there'd be two or
three guys would be that first guy you'd
always want to try and he was my friend
bad eyes and his name started with a J
if you're my Creed I hate that guy first
all the time see if he's got that Sour
Diesel if not and try a couple other
dudes but if you gotta find out where
they are if they got what you want
and if they can meet you somewhere then
you gotta meet up somewhere do you got
to sit in a sketchy parking lot or go to
a sketchy house and then you got to get
it I always had three or four people but
on my way to work I would head up my
favorite and my lunch if I ain't heard
back I would head up the other two yep
there you go by the end of the day
guaranteed one of them would have hit me
back and then I'd go way too sketchy
parking lot yep I don't miss those days
I kind of Miss that extra high from the
adrenaline Drive and the anticipation
but I feel it every time that I do hit a
dispensary now or even when I come over
and pick up for my caregiver when I get
back in the car
there's no like where am I gonna put
this process right there's no oh man
this is dank is [ __ ] like it was the
other day when I picked up from my
caregiver the last time when I got in
the car I was like is that nope that's
my bag in inside is a proper packaging
inside my shoulder bag in the back seat
of my car is still stinking out the
whole cab back in the day this was this
is when the adrenaline really kicks in
he's down and drive home and 20-degree
well you make that meeting with the dude
as soon as that bag and money exchanges
now you're like [ __ ] I just went from
like gotta get this got to find it where
is it is it gonna happen is the deal
gonna go smooth too I gotta get this
[ __ ] home right now or somewhere or to
whoever's house we're partying in
tonight and you got to make that drive
and your heart starts going and then you
see a cop I'll give you this bucket see
a cop he could be going the other way 90
to 90 miles an hour oh [ __ ] the cops and
you gotta like check yourself and be
cool yeah so by the time you do get home
and you start getting that grin you get
a you park the car cuz you're not gonna
get pulled over once you park the car
you pretty much got home you take the
keys out you're like oh come on or
you're almost you can your hands start
doing the grinder motion I'm gonna grab
this weed out and by the time you light
it your heart is like in this special
place and that first puff just puts you
like it's like a mission accomplished
it's like you just rescued the [ __ ]
princess that princess was sweet Mary
Jane
I'm nostalgic for it but I wouldn't go
back to him for all money in the world
like there's nothing that could get me
to go back to having too much [ __ ]
I love getting I mean on the off chance
I get pulled over and I've got the car
yep I got pulled over and the cop was
ten feet from my car before he goes -
sir do you have marijuana in there
because he can smell it yep and I just
looked him straight in the face and I
said yeah probably there's probably some
weed near I'm not gonna even try to lie
and he was once I said yes that cop was
like cool I got pulled over leaving a
big production grow that I was trimming
at for a while and so like I didn't have
anything on me but I probably had think
eight or nine grams of just like
marijuana juice not oil or extract or
anything but like just the pulp from the
family stem like just in my shoes just
soaked in through the bottom and I
stopped - hi Evan
because I've been trimming for like ten
hours I was early the car no but I work
in the industry I've been harvesting all
day I understand that I stink to high
heaven and he was like what's wrong
clear-eyed and [ __ ] so let's just see
your badge and your driver's license and
your other thing you cool let me bring
your car information you give you a have
a nice night yeah um just just so you
know I can smell you like four cars days
behind you I could I knew someone in
front of me was just thinking it's like
yeah yeah sorry like sober as a judge
yes working on harvest time you can
really sell that bartender friend who's
been pulled over several times it's like
I swear to god officer what you're
smelling right now is my socks I'm sober
I just I work at a bar oh yeah I hate
that as a musician I wouldn't drink like
I quit dream I was I did drink it for
please don't don't get me wrong I think
[ __ ] plenty but I learned not to hit
the club clean and up or whatever and
somebody'd spill some beer on you or on
your equipment or whatever and here in
the car it just reeks that beer smell
maybe driving home like [ __ ] I smell
like beer terrible
[Music]
is so nice that this it was literally
the only part of my life where I was way
out of whack with legal
I've actually been kicked out of
restaurants or denied serve there's like
no why don't you guys go take a shower
and come back I had someone walk up and
they went to do the so table for three
and they went so takeout yeah yeah carry
out the skirted heifer in Colorado
Springs I wasn't gonna say the name of a
restaurant but the entire trim crew like
it was we were going we were trimming
and put down the trim to go to dinner it
was a dress that we're working a
caregiver gross so we like we didn't
have any of the like protective layering
that you wear at that facility we pretty
much sat around a table just like this
in our t-shirts and shorts and trimmed
with rubber gloves on and then we would
go smoke at a friend's house cuz it was
so dope we had a friend that lived
between the crow and downtown go stop
over there
that's the apartment getrekt and then we
drove right to the food place you gonna
eat outside
like what like no your table is outside
guys outside because inside the
restaurant but the place was filled with
families like you could see people
looking at us offended like you can
smell your weed over the burgers in the
listeners yes I'm a vegetarian this it
ever serves a quinoa burger that is
marvelous so don't get me wrong I don't
blame restaurants with like I don't care
what you do for work all day if you're
if you're funky you know from it to funk
out a whole restaurant
you probably shouldn't go straight from
work the restaurant like I don't care
what you do or why you stink some
restaurants back in the day when I
noticed before we had legal the cannabis
legalization and it was a known thing I
would show up to restaurants with my
scuzzy looking friends because I know
I'm not the cleanest looking person I
bathe on a regular basis yes but I do
look like Chewbacca's [ __ ] baby
cousin I've got dreadlocks past my ass
almost to my knees I've got a fuzzy
beard you can hear it
that's my beard I got a goatee I got a
mustache
I wore a crooked hat and a t-shirt and
Dickie's and skateboard shoes and I walk
into restaurants and back in the day and
I smell like wheat I just constantly
smell like herb if I'm growing it
smoking it whatever I smell like
cannabis I would walk into restaurants
and they would kind of roll their eyes
and be like [ __ ] let's sit these weirdos
in a corner now that the industry is the
way that it is they know that kids it
look like myself and you and Kev bro and
whoever else used to roll with me to
places they treat us like [ __ ] rock
stars now bro in the grimy Gatsby and I
would go to dinner in Colorado Springs
that waitress would be up our butts cuz
they know it's like these are weed
industry people and they get paid well
I'm gonna be super [ __ ] nicely that's
not they get paid well they get paid
well now and in the near future in the
very recent past they worked a job where
tips or at least service was a big part
of it right so when we go out to eat now
we understand that the person serving us
our food is making less than minimum
wage and that if one or two of her table
stiffs are throughout a shift she's
gonna have trouble making ends meet and
so if the service is good we always over
tip yeah yeah just as a community we
kind of take care of it I can always
when I was doing food service I could
always tell which one of my tables which
customers also worked in the service it
was I've heard every one of my food
service friends has said that before yep
you can always tell and you can tell
who's like no one and their families
worked in the service industry in a
couple of generations but you can tell
those [ __ ] too from a mile away and
it I mean it makes a big difference if
you're a server to know who to treat a
little better I love it when you take a
girl on the dinners over she starts
gathering plates and sets them at the
edge of the table you're awesome but
you're not you're [ __ ] awesome good
work Mike I don't know how we just ended
up on this [ __ ] ramp we're in a
random field yes I took a couple of
notes that I want to make sure to
mention some other bullet points let's
say let's say I am
gonna tease them because we're gonna do
these in another podcast yeah well no we
won't do this one tonight but these are
just coming up I want to talk about in
the future somebody you touched on
earlier I wrote down mail selection
somebody sent me an email about mail
selection and you talked about breeding
we're gonna talk about mail selection in
the very near future we're gonna talk
about the difference between lab testing
and how the Cannabis actually works for
you yeah and that reminds me that I want
to give another shout-out to my friend
beau bone Ellis at the spliff podcast we
talked a lot about growing we talk a lot
about cannabis culture we do it from
sort of a dudebro sort of side of things
[Music]
please don't ask me to change but if
you're not into the dudebro culture dab
kids sort of thing that we've got going
on here bone Ellis has a great podcast
called the spliff podcast and she does
it from a much more I described it kind
of like as it's learning cannabis for my
kindergarten teacher but she's [ __ ]
educated and she is learning more and
more as she goes on with the podcast she
will talk much more about specific
cannabinoid dosing for specific
conditions and she should call some of
her episodes a hundred and one ways to
use my cannabis because I'm all about
dabbing excuse me I'm all about taking
dads I'm all about smoking some flowers
I like some edibles beau doesn't waste a
thing she uses every bit of cannabinoids
she can pull out of everything and I
appreciate it that's just not my style I
know someone locally that there was the
first person I ever met that was juicing
raw cannabis like when they defoliate
take all that leaf material in juice
they toss the crunchy but when they do
fully anus the grain they juice all that
she uses the stuff that she's vaporized
she makes a tincture with coconut oil
out of that or a topical with coconut
oil out of that she makes a cannabis
lotion
she has been making cannabis products
for her cats recently like so if you
guys want a different perspective on
cannabis if you get tired of hearing our
bro culture over here
I understand some people aren't into
being called dude and bro I listen to a
podcast all the time but if you've
gotten this far and you must be into us
but a different perspective on cannabis
from a very well-educated professional
sounding woman if you want a woman's
perspective on cannabis I highly
recommend listening to the spliff
podcast from bone Ellis she does not pay
me to say that I [ __ ] smell it all you
gotta do is search for I'm gonna open up
my iphone or Eric's it's right here on
my podcast screen it is simply I gotta
get to the top yes and it took a week to
find this podcast just cuz I was hearing
split and pop and I thought it was the
split podcast this isn't a thing spliff
SPL iff the spliff podcast p OTC AST and
her name is bo bo h nellis and she's a
great host she's a cool person bo one
day i hope you get to take a DAB
together that'd be fun
i'm gonna make you take like a half
grand dad thank you chuck forever
because that's how i do but you guys you
would appreciate the show if you like my
show i feel like you'll like buzz show
she is got 63 episodes up right now nice
I am 30-something episodes in and
they're getting better and better as
they go she's really good at
recommending specific dosages of
cannabinoids and she's much she doesn't
over consume cannabis the way that I do
so she's much more on the beginner
consumer side which I'm not even bashing
anybody
I miss my lower tolerance right I was
able to do some really amazing things
with some low-dose cannabinoid changes
and I'm a little ridiculous I'm
Chewbacca's freaking cousin and I like
to over dab I like to overmedicate so if
you but that's enough of a shoutout for
Bo I support that show listen to it it's
[ __ ] great I like it so that's
something that I wrote down and then
we're gonna read an article about
particles per million and Colorado
concentrates on one of the next episodes
ppm Ross yes because they think it's
something that needs to be talked about
you got now retreated to stick around
yes let me make sure cuz we we kill our
phones - do we really try to dedicate an
hour or more to you guys when we record
this and in part of that involve us and
I have no idea
[Music]
50 degree or better swing today folks it
was nice but windy when I was outside
[Music]
you need to plan your grow for like
looking with you I leave to go to this
new project I'm going to I leave the
house around 6:30 in the morning and I'm
wearing seriously
pants with shorts underneath a t-shirt a
hoodie a jacket a hat that covers up my
ears with my dreads down to keep me warm
I get to where I'm going I take off
there's a jacket so hoody that I put on
a different hat then for launch we go to
lunch and it's nice and warm outside so
I put on shorts and skateboard shoes and
a t-shirt and tie the hair up and put a
little small dread hat on and I wear
that for the second half of the day when
I leave the facility that I'm working
with it is a little after 6:00 so then I
put on again all of the layers everyday
and it's cold it's colder than than it
was all day so I we run the full weather
gamut here I mean daily ago you get most
of the seasons daily all the new people
that haven't been here for a solid year
are sick right they're all they're all
walking around with that head [ __ ] going
on and all the growers that moved here
from far away and I mean even the ones
that have been growing cannabis one way
or another for years I just fight for
their first two years here trying to
figure out how to to control I mean
every day it's
is out of zero and then it gets to 65
zero again how do I not get p.m. in this
how do I hear my buds in this how do i
balance the humidity anywhere I watched
a guy designed like 2 million dollars
with a floor heating at one point to try
to combat some of the weather here wow
it's just fun way to do it different
people experience especially with I mean
we've never seen an influx people like
this it's crazy traffic is getting
shitty I'm getting people asking me like
how the 53 lanes up there and not do all
this to you guys I don't thank everybody
for listening to episode 171 of the girl
from your heart podcast that means a lot
that you guys listen for 171 episodes
[Music]
Thank You Clint said the same thing
today shot two Klan I keep saying I'm
gonna post old episodes I keep having
more content but I'm gonna do it you
guys keep asking for old stuff all the
emails you're sending me I am responding
to them slowly but I'm getting to them
you wouldn't believe how many emails I
get lately it's Christmastime
everybody's trying to sell me [ __ ] so I
just do so many emails it's for the
future but I'm getting to all those
emails please send me more emails I love
it I love making listener generated
content that lets me know that I'm
getting something out to at least one
person and if I'm hitting one person and
probably hitting a lot of people there's
one person spoke up from you so send me
those emails that's real from your heart
at hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you
make sure you follow mike on social
media Mike just took nearly 2 hours out
of his night he's gonna take a little
longer we may record another episode
make sure you follow him on social media
it's Nemo punk 15 on the Twitter and
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook there's a lot of cannabis news
that we simply don't have time to work
into a podcast or that
is only a minute or two my facebook page
every day my social media so check it
out please a couple more things a couple
more things we're gonna wrap this one up
patreon you guys I would love it
patreon is a service that you can go to
patreon.com/scishow to contribute
financially to the podcast you guys I'm
not trying to get rich off the podcast
this show will always be free free
freedom I bring you a free podcast cuz I
love you and I love cannabis I want you
to grow a better cannabis I want
cannabis to be legalized but what you
can do you can help me pay for the cost
of my website I read genetics Colorado
is the website where this podcast is
hosted it cost me a little over three
hundred dollars per year to keep that
website alive I am paying for that out
of my pocket right now because I love
podcasting it's something that I've
chosen to do if you would like to help
me with that a little bit that would be
sweet I don't want to beg you for it
patreon is there for that go to
patreon.com
contribute as little as $1 or you can
contribute as much as you would like you
can sign up for a monthly service to
where it can contribute one dollar per
month then every month on the 1st of the
month is in $1 to the podcast and that
will help me not have to cover all the
costs of the podcast out of my pocket
everybody that shows up for the show
gets a bottle of water I try to buy
these little microphone covers these
things here I try to replace these quite
frequently because you guys coughing to
them and they stink and I don't want
people having to share that funky [ __ ]
I've made that trip to the store with
you yes yes and if you're really dying
for old content this is a way to help
make that happen
Wow the reason it's not up there right
now is because it would like double or
triple the cost to maintain the web
hosting to go all 171 it's 171 now yeah
they go 171 deep that kind of volume and
storage cost I don't want to make that
promise yeah if somebody didn't make the
proper patreon contribution and it may
said post an old episode [ __ ] that's
the way to get me to do what you want
money talks it's Christmas time and
money talks but but I'm not trying to be
that way I'm saying one dollar goes a
long way if you don't have a dollar to
contribute I do not I do I'm not
offended I still love you I still want
you to listen I still want you to grow
[Music]
that's a good way to look at it I guess
that's all I want is that so by the time
I'm too old to fight this fight anymore
that it's taken care of enough for me to
just enjoy the ride there you go all I'm
asking for is help paying for the
website and buying these little
microphone covers and water bottles and
recom slash grow from your heart that
would be super awesome because I've got
one more super important thing that I
need to include in this episode this
episode comes out on Monday
so that means guess what happy birthday
miss JB Jenny Beth I love you hope you
have a great birthday hope everything
goes your way for this episode you got
anything else to wrap it up with Merry
Christmas folks merry holiday happy
holidays everybody I hope you have a
wonderful holiday season and hopefully
we have another podcast before the first
of the year oh well you know we're gonna
they're gonna hear from us again before
Christmas this one comes out love it
18th 19th so then that means we got
seven dollars it might be I've
completely forgot about in my world it's
not Christmas until I eat a specific
type of Christmas cookie that a family
member makes and I don't like it's just
to think of my world I went to hobby
so as far as I'm concerned it's like
August are far far away because I
haven't had that cookie yet will be
joining everybody the day after
Christmas so Merry Christmas everybody
happy holiday Happy Hanukkah whichever
one it is you're celebrating I'm not
sure what all of them are I don't want
to sound defensive but have a great
holiday season eat some good food with
your friends and family if you don't
have some friends and family go to my
facebook page send me a message we'll
[ __ ] chat tell me what's up don't
send me pictures of your food we're
gonna wrap this episode up a hashtag
they like it when we're and I I'm so
glad because dabs because dads don't
think everybody wants again for
listening I want to give you a huge
shout out to miss Jenny Beth and it's
all next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
it's time for episode number 172 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation or a dedicated someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I want to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots band let him use
their music on my podcast
big shout out to cat
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen white Mike is back
welcome to the table Mike if you guys
wanna follow Mike on Twitter that be
awesome he is at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter
know that you learned about him also
check out Mike's Facebook page make sure
you check that out because if you're
looking for the wrong head love it if
you follow me on let's see we'll start
off with on Twitter Mike's on twitter
follow me on twitter follow me @ g fyh
podcast that i read also follow me on
facebook the girl from our
Podcast and you guys I have got nearly
eleven thousand followers on Instagram
so check me out there it's ireon discord
genetics i RIE
underscore genetics Irie is a Jamaican
word it means the feel is blessed as you
could feel you know that feeling I
describe it is like you're sitting under
a tree and the weather is just right
it's kind of sunny if there's a little
bit of breeze in that grass is nice and
cool and either your significant other
or your best friend or your dog is
sitting right next to you and you don't
got to worry in the [ __ ] world
everything is just right it's feeling I
read everything is perfect so i reaiiy
regen etics it's just feeling good it's
most pleasing comfortable feeling you
could get just feeling alright
everything BRE I'm good so I read
genetics guys follow me there on
Instagram I posed to a whole bunch of
great cannabis photography I post
pictures of myself with famous comedians
those pictures of male plants not a lot
of weed growers and breeders are posting
pictures our males I put pictures of
King Solomon up there all the time I
think you would appreciate it be a good
time
so you think I covered all of the social
media outlet so if you want to contact
me there you go you can hit me up at
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you've got questions or comments or
concerns from me well answer all that
stuff will handle it Mike you got a
shitty grin on your face bro what's
going on over there oh it's just there's
so much there's a lot of I just had a
little flashback to us like how do you
get a hold of me and you had two options
are you gonna give him your address
right and now it's like well I have 36
different ways you can get ahold of me
on social media and the old-school ways
doesn't matter anymore but now there's
no way at ducking anybody like right cuz
they think they could see that you
tweeted why didn't you call me back I
see you tweet had time to text like see
you am on snapchat showing the truth the
ball might be my meeting but like if you
can tweet from the meeting you can text
me back from the meeting come on down
yeah I do have a lot of contact it shows
you this message was seen at 2:45 like
and it's 4:45 now why haven't I heard
back that was a question [ __ ]
you can't duck anybody now no social
media has got us on lock accountable if
you're on a podcast and if you're on
more than one podcast and you're out
there like a lot of people are you were
accountable for what you say because
people will point out that you've made
in discrepancies but you said this and
this bro I got the date wrong cuz I'm
high I'm sorry the first time it hit me
somebody came up to me in public was
like eh you like mic I turned around I
was like huh does the way you recognized
me from across the store by myself
oh yeah I need garden supply one time
talking to burn big shout it to burn and
there was a normal shopper in there and
he paused and he looked at me and I go
what's up man cuz he was like obviously
looked at me and stopped like what the
[ __ ] and I was like what dude and I was
cool man he's like you do have a podcast
like it's totally me brother
I recognized you by your voice it's
[ __ ] funny so yeah it's there are
people listening to recognise us by our
marvelous voices last night actually
they recognize me from my City Council
stuff because that's broadcast on live
TV and she goes I know you and I was
like Oh from and she goes you were on TV
at my grandpa's house senior citizens
down here in Pueblo that watch a lot of
local government public access
television and a lot of them really like
because I go and give city council [ __ ]
and for a while I was doing it without a
whole bunch of issues and so I've got
this weird geriatric fanbase that loves
me that's creepy but I wasn't aware of
it until I was eating lunch one day and
I had to senior citizens come up and be
like are you the guy that goes to City
Council you look like the guy have you
ever gotten are you the guy in the paper
smoking weed are you the guy in the news
of a smoke and we only from family I
have I'm from southern Colorado not
quite this southern but I have family
friends throughout the state a bunch of
people up in Monument oddly enough and
they see our city government stuff and
they see a lot of our press okay
and so they would call further up
my parents but then I would get the
phone call from my my folks so Mike and
I I happen to be the first person to buy
recreational cannabis in the county of
Pueblo Colorado when we legalized the
sale of recreational cannabis photos of
the line Jeff got to be first in are
still used all the time in national
press stories about legalization there's
two photos that were taken that day in
Pueblo they're both aerial shots and
Jeff is shopping while that photo is
being taken first so I'm in there buying
stuff I was first and so I I've got a
picture of myself actually purchasing
cannabis like the money transaction of
handing it money and then the owner of
the dispensary is a good friend of mine
so I shook his hand like thanks bro I'm
glad that I could be your first customer
I'm proud of you for having this [ __ ]
I shook his hand told him thank you I
turned around and my other friend to
work then I said thanks guys and I
grabbed my stuff and I left it when I
walked outside I was interviewed by 8:00
news stations and documentary makers and
documentarians I guess there were a lot
of cameras around me I'm really glad
that I'm a well-spoken dude because that
would have been overwhelming for [ __ ]
most normal people that was crazy but a
lot of that footage so also that day
there was a newscaster there who I ended
up making friends with and she was like
hey we're looking for they actually
asked me if I could smoke there they
like can you roll up a joint you know
what to college they can you roll a
cigarette and smoke it here with your
friends so that we can film that and I
was like actually that's highly illegal
I can't smoke in front of my friends
facility and we put a little plan
together and I was like let's go to my
house well let's all meet at my house at
one o'clock and smoke and so I drove
here with Mike join me and our friend
Wade came and we came here and kind of
put uh we did some prop placing we put
some product placement happen in there
couple of packs I region it exceeds on
the D have fun with it we do we set up
some really nice shots for them to get
in we didn't think about the optics of
it necessarily from people who aren't
from because we were used to dabbing by
them yeah we were used to the equipment
that goes with it the parts the process
the people that came over to interview
us and see this little session none of
them were familiar with superseded the
one lady there was a cameraman there was
a news reporter who was from the TV news
and then there was a write a newspaper
writer and the newspaper writer hinted
mentioned talked about cannabis that she
liked cannabis she wanted to say she was
saying without saying I'd love to
[ __ ] smoke that bowl with you guys
but all these [ __ ] right here would
snitch on me is what she was saying and
we did our best of completely hotbox
basically a suburban home yeah and it
didn't take much with three grown men
here yeah in the twenty thirty minutes
they were here filming and interviewing
people we a non-stop had a break in a
bowl in a joint going around the table
so that it one in any given moment one
of us was hitting everything I thought
that camera was gonna touch me I was
taking a dad a big dad was worried about
his his lens at one point he got really
really close you know and I was like bro
that's like you really don't want to get
any closer but that that shot that
actual shot is shown on the news so
frequently when they talk about
marijuana they show me take a big dam
and blow it out like oh I feel relieved
yeah so I'm sure that is interesting so
luckily they don't use me taking the dab
nearly as frequently as they used you
but they still use that footage
regularly that footage we saw we agreed
that that footage can be used in
anything it's like either ABC or NBC is
what news organization that was for so
it's there's now
if and so it's shown all over the nation
when they talk about cannabis and I get
messages from people all over like hey I
just saw you on my news what the hell
yeah task rock actually sent me a gift
because his email was on the news he's
like this guy right here got a email
email on the news and he sent me a gift
I thought it was pretty cool
in my kitchen this is going to be a
point to this podcast and I love I love
my friends at handmade apparel Yeah
right
right you're the second person I saw
leaving here now grow from your heart
podcast hoodie and another person left
here and a red handmade apparel hoodie
with a big white logo on it it looks a
really good honor it's I'm at that age
where I don't care what your brand is if
your logo isn't hideous and it's a
really good quality item I mean they get
you the best hoodies they can start with
I think there's a guild in there it's
snuggly it's super cozy like when you
put it on you're like oh it's so snuggly
and I'm a big dude and I feel all cozy
in it so that's weird
and then the printing quality that these
guys do my logo of course is red yellow
green there's white in there there's
black and then there's like a skin tone
and then there's whatever color they
call that for my dreadlocks that they
use
they're like nine colors and the color
of this design that they made for me and
every single color pops it all pops I
got your back bro you're cool like just
freaked out cuz he turned to look at the
hoodies and I felt the headphone cord
snag and then I heard the rig move and
that moved it for you there's no glass
village here but these hoodies look
wonderful you guys I'm not just trying
to sell you my hoodies handmade apparel
can make your hoodies hand Merril
handmade apparel can make your t-shirts
handmade American
let me slow down and say this in English
you guys because I want to get this
right for my friends at handmade apparel
can make your t-shirts and your hoodies
and your stickers and your happens they
can help you with the artwork they can
get your stuff to you in a timely manner
they're good people they support the
cannabis industry
they are dab kids they're my friends so
there's no reason why you should not
shop with handmade apparel all you gotta
do all you've got to [ __ ] English is
hard to do you guys I'm gonna take it
all you're gonna do is go to handmade
apparel dot biz and check them out tell
them that Rasta Jeff from the girl from
your art podcast sent you and they will
hook you up with the best deal possible
to get your products printed I think
they've got a 25 piece minimum so let's
charge you for 25 pieces plus a small
setup fee because they do have to make
screens too so I'm not sure if their
screens anymore now that [ __ ] happens
I'm not a printer they do they've sent
me stickers they've sent me it's not
just my stuff I've got shirts that
they've printed for other brands if they
didn't know we're coming to me that I
got from those people and all their
stuff looks quality also so much love
much respect to handmade apparel let
them know that you're listening boudoir
for our podcast I love supporting my
friends in the industry that are doing
stuff for us if you're interested in one
of these hoodies send me an email to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com they
are very limited on quantity I got 25 of
them printed I've got a lot of friends
that have been on the show that have
already picked them up Mike's gonna
leave here today looking stylish his
[ __ ] his new girl from your hire
podcast hoodie it's got the girl from a
heart podcast logo above the left breast
it just says grow from your heart and
it's got the little EQ bars and red
yellow and green it does not have my
face however on the back it's got the
logo very large and it's got the
original logo with my face and the EQ
bars on it they look sweet
shout out to handmade apparel shun I
think it was Adam hand they did it
himself I think Adam had adjusted the
art because the art I sent him was a
little pixely I was made by yeah it was
made by somebody else that's not a super
amazing graphic
but it was the right idea for what I
wanted handmade apparel took it and
polished it up it looks super dope it
looks super slick so they can handle
your artwork everything I he thinks very
open-mindedly so if he describes
something to Adam he can draw it without
ruining your idea he can put your idea
into motion if you're not an artist
which is really cool cuz a lot of
artists want to put their idea into your
idea and then put it on paper and then
there goes your idea anyway much love
mad respect to our friends at handmade
apparel let's tell everybody what this
show is gonna be about because I feel
like we've been gone for a really long
time came down the pipe for Colorado
concentrate companies yes I found this
article on leaf Lee because it was the
only place I could find with this
article after I did some searching and
it says rule changes aren't they're not
sexy and so they didn't make the press
there's no other way to describe it it's
it's not it's not something
controversial it's not something that
there was big heated debate over
we're like anti pop people and pro pop
people were fighting in the courthouse
or anything so he didn't make the press
a lot it was quiet
all right let's read the article this is
from leaf Lee I'm looking for the author
Ben Alden and this was written on
December 12 2016 of course this episode
is coming out on December 26th I hope
everybody had a wonderful winter holiday
whichever one that it is you celebrate
we're not gonna be inclusive exclusive
racist or biased or whatever we love you
all whatever gender you have chosen to
identify as whatever holiday you were
accepting I mean that's the truth goes
like this on January 1st 2017 Colorado
will raise its state-regulated limit on
the residual levels of volatile solvents
allowed in cannabis concentrates it's a
little noticed rule change that involves
dramatically increased levels of
allowable solvents among the changes and
I'm gonna read off some of the changes
they list here the legal threshold for
butane the solvent that puts the B and
BHO will increase more than six-fold
from a hundred parts per million to
5,000 parts per million
I should slow down and kind of explain
what that means um so PPA means parts
per million that means that parts per
million right that there are so if there
are a million parts in there you were
allowed to have 800 parts of butane in
there before out of a million which is
in law you probably wouldn't notice that
right if I gave you a million something
and told you pick me at 800 of them and
give them to me you wouldn't notice
you're missing no now you're allowed to
have 5000 which may start making a
little bit of a difference you may show
that up 5000 ppm of residual solvents of
butane feels like a whole lot of butane
to me
it's a larger number but without
significantly more context it's not
helpful information I know for a fact
that given the boiling points I mean
even like really really really really
high amounts of butane left and final
product all of that cooks off long
before dabbed a face right it comes off
at the nail if you're getting that much
yeah if there's anything if there's much
of anything left over in the product
it's gone on the nail long before the
dad gets to you okay with butane
but if you if it was harmful they
wouldn't be making these changes we
don't I don't think we have enough
information yet to know how harmful
smoking a concentrate made from butane
could be and that's from and I'm at a
heavy BHO advocate I probably spoke more
BHO percent of the world most of the
health rules that they haven't been able
to research specifically for cannabis
they have already researched
specifically for similar items true we
know a lot about pesticide residual
limits because of the tobacco industry
there's already something that's mass
produced that's smoked we know as a ppm
limits from some other things for I can
hailed medicines the article because it
mentions stuff like that I've pre-read I
did some research
another rule allowed residuals for
heptanes and other class of solvents
will go up by a factor of 10
xylene industrial solvents that
technically aren't allowed to be used
for cannabis extraction at all will be
permitted at concentrations of up to
2,000 170 particles per million
significantly higher than the premium
previous limit of 1 a ppm the state
residual limit on benzene perhaps the
most hazardous chemical of the group
will double from less than 1 ppm to less
than 2 ppm there's a little article here
that gives you a graph that is way too
small to read well I mean and that's a
good example of how statistics it's
gonna more than double from less than 1
to almost 2 to almost 2 like depending
on how always read the 5 dangerous those
chemicals are that can
make a difference and there's something
I want to talk about once we get rid of
the work done through the article I goes
on to say on the surface these are
staggering increases in chemicals that
at some levels have been associated with
nausea irregular heartbeat increased
risk of cancer and even death regulators
testing laboratory operators and
industry members in other states have
expressed surprises if the changes which
will apply to both adult use and medical
markets mike van Dijk chief of the
environmental epidemiology occupational
health and toxicology branch at the
Colorado Department of Public Health and
Environment will recommend the new limit
acknowledge that which recommended the
new limit acknowledge the concentrate
it's capable of clearing the regulatory
hurdles could be noticeably different
from what's currently allowed consumers
are going to feel like they may taste it
he said of these new allowed butane
levels they might smell it I'm surprised
nobody else has even actually been
interested in this he told me in an
interview just last week the guys making
these rules are saying that we are going
to taste and smell butane in our
concentrates with these I don't know
enough about how much butane that is to
know
just pert just when you break you down
for per million when you I mean if that
whole grandma hash is 1 million pieces
the five thousand that you're talking
about aren't visible like they're not
visibly visually identifiable as
separate able from the whole like we're
talking about an incredibly small amount
here it does surprise me that this
didn't make the press because it does
increase a residual solvents as there's
no other way to sound to say that to
make it sound better or worse I don't
think it seems like something that would
make the press but it was only reported
almost nowhere the only reason I know
about this rule change is because of the
labeling rules that came along with oh
yeah let me continue with the article I
goes on to say there are a few things
Colorado Department of Public Health and
Environment VanDyke wants to make clear
about the new rules here is one this
change was not a result of any industry
pressure the increased didn't come at
the behest what's that word mean the
behest I know the word means I've never
read that we requested the increase did
not come at the behest of lobbyists he
told Leafly in fact in the work groups
if we heard anything from the industry I
think we heard the other side that these
were too high he said which is an
uncommon place to be so what's going on
the justification for the change
according to Van Dyke is that the new
limits truly follow the best currently
available medical and scientific
guidance this was really a today staaan
trying to make things health based he
explained these numbers come from the
international harmonized guidelines for
residual solvents and pharmaceuticals
van Dijk is referring to a published
scientific article he cited in a July
letter to Jim Barack director of the
Colorado Department of Revenue's
Enforcement Division which is in charge
of enforcing the new standards and I
provided the letter and spoke at length
to Leafly about the coming change while
these numbers stand the test of time I
don't know he said we're open to new
data that comes out but our goal is to
make sure that we maintain the
we can the best evidence they
evidence-based regulations for health
agencies trying to do precisely what has
been asked Van Dyke said legislation
passed this year Ben is list the House
bill 16-12 61 put the Colorado
Department of Public Health and
Environment in charge of recommending
testing standards based on medical
reports and published scientific
literature but the Colorado Department
of Revenue's said the previous limits in
the wake of amendment 64 s passage it
was a fast and furious process Van Dyke
said there were times you came up with
numbers because that's what you came up
with at the time
despite the eye-popping increases he
said new limits adhere more strictly to
the latest available evidence in
scientific research there's a lot more
to this I'm gonna skim it roll it go
ahead Mike fat
that model of we picked a number and we
kind of pulled it out of our ass but we
we just went with them the much more
restrictive sounding rule to start off
with and now we're dialing it back to
more in line with reality I think we're
gonna see that in a lot of different
areas of regulation in Colorado we're
realizing that in a lot of ways we way
overdid it in some areas right I mean it
doesn't surprise me that this is one I
wouldn't be surprised in the next two
years to see a lot of different testing
rules and regulations tweaked up and
down as we learn more and we finally get
around to checking the research our
driving limit for example the five
nanograms that's just a rule another
state had in place and they just pulled
it out of their ass there's no research
at all to tie it with that but we made
that part of our law here I wouldn't be
allowed near a car five nanograms
there's a real thing I tried to have my
primary care physician run two tests on
me after not smoking like all night and
then going in the morning and she didn't
know which tests to run and so I had to
run three different THC tests and all of
them I was whatever the test result came
back I was way above five but that we're
doing that research now that research
just got flooded in Colorado so in two
years three years we'll have more
information to change that rule and I
think that's gonna happen in a lot of
places it doesn't surprise me that's
happening here with ppm limits well the
article keeps going and the guy says
actually frankly he doesn't actually he
actually says frankly we're not saying
that extracted marijuana products should
have 5000 PPM's of butane in them in
Colorado he said what we're saying is
five thousand is a health-based limit
but he then it goes on sorry I'm reading
way too fast but didn't he just
acknowledge the possibility of literally
smelling butane and the BHO approved by
the state for medical patients I think
there may be a lot of market drivers
that push those numbers lower if an Tyco
acknowledged and smell could certainly
be one of them but he repeated it's not
from a health perspective that those
should be lower but there are residual
solvents but our residual solvents
merely a matter of product taste and
quality or as scientific research still
too limited to inspire a consumer
confidence it may be a little bit of
both that's what I'm gonna jump in right
now because even if we're allowed to put
5,000 particles per minute to leave that
in there and not purge it out properly
most consumers are educated enough to go
I don't want that [ __ ] and they would go
buy so I've got two different products
of shatter on my table right now one was
a gift one will probably remain on this
piece of parchment paper until the end
of [ __ ] time is I do not want to dab
it the other however was made by an
artist who took their time and their
energy if you went to the dispensary
Mike and this dark stuff that looks like
squirrel poop was here available for you
for $25 a grand plus tax it looks like a
piece onyx it is pretty damn dark or
this golden kind of gold would you grab
all this if this was at the store would
you even buy it though see so you're an
educated consumer even know that a lot
of times you get that dark color just
because the material wasn't processed
quickly enough and it had time to age a
little bit before I got processed this
isn't I believe that that hash and if
you're listening to my podcast my friend
that makes this hash you may listen I
didn't want to mention this I think
what's happening is if you were using a
closed loop system the material is
sitting in the butane far too long he
was talking about this was his record
pool how they got more hash from the
amount of Tyrael than the amount of
material than they've ever pulled before
it's because you pulled out a bunch of
chlorophyll my friend that's why the
hash has got this dark greenish color
yes there's a lot of THC here but you
lowered your THC quantity by pulling
more chlorophyll you increased your
weight but you lowered your potency so
if you're doing it in a closed-loop
system a little quicker about it don't
leave it soaking on a soak
along its the hash version of putting a
coin in your grandeur it may be time to
clean the butane and the machine also if
you're doing this if this hash was made
open blasted what you did was you ran
too many cans you needed to stop a can
before because you're pushing it through
the tube you're pushing it's going pay
attention it should run piss clear it
should look like well hydrated peat
should be clear coming out of there as
soon as you see it coming dark through
it I will go as far as to move my can
over the grass or over the cement and
just drip it right into there and quit
putting it into my catch door people do
too bad when I open up when I open blast
into a open container I do it into a
mason jar because it's got a smaller
opening with less prevents you from
getting contaminants into it if you do
it into a big flat pyrex dish leaves and
shoot from the trees fall in you got to
do it outside bugs flying to their
[ __ ] butterfly landing the pancake
tray or the cookie tray don't make any
more that's why I feel free talking
about it it's you've been working with
with butane like that there's safety
precautions that oh it's just one way
our community keeps [ __ ] ourselves
every time I some idiot blows up their
apartment of their house trying to make
dabs in the backyard like just leave it
to the [ __ ] professionals true I
remember reading in history class about
bathtub gin and people blowing
themselves up trying to meet you in the
bathtub and I've thought how dumb were
people back then and then Here I am 35
and my contemporaries are doing the
execs
there were freaking hands there weren't
professionals six years ago back then
the professionals were us you know what
I mean like Big D was a professional
back then and he was doing it with a
[ __ ] until three years ago he was
doing it in a tube in a parking lot at a
professional business with a license
that's how it well they were okay with
that
ya know you gotta have a [ __ ]
blast-proof building and all kinds of
fire equipment
soups and all training and hazmat
material it's a way different world now
so what those professionals do it and I
think that if we legalize cannabis
everywhere well know it's definitely a
legalization in the market yeah because
because then if a lot of the places
where the the frequent BHO home cook
blow ups are happening are in
legalization states where it's sixty
five seventy five a gram on the shelf or
where there is no option and in places
where there's there's no legal accident
you gotta if you have to grow your own
and make your own you [ __ ] will
because people want to get high they're
going to do what they have to to get
high to get medicated they're gonna do
that if it's not available they're gonna
figure out a way since they just grew
some shitty weed because they can't get
the products to a proper weed now they
got to do something with it so let's
just go get some butane we're gonna
threw some cans and blow up the house
and make this look even worse is the
more likely you are to screw up the
safety precautions if it's just legal
then you can just go to the store and
get it on the shelf in Colorado you can
go I can think of four places for 20 25
35 a gram a good fire shatter the
article but I'm gonna keep reading it
anyway just because it feels like
there's more it says a knowledge problem
a lot of eyes widened when I talk to
people who weren't aware of Colorado's
new standards some consumers believe
that industrial solvents are inherently
hazardous to their health and should be
avoided at virtually any level many
concentrate consumers now opt for
solvent las' extract such as rosin or
bubble hash others don't worry as much
pointing out ah dennis is accurately
according to most scientists i talked to
that someone who smells a whiff of
butane from a Bic lighter has already
inhaled way more than they'll get in a
day of dabbing that's a great a great
comparison I like that well he's sitting
there talking about tasting it what in
the hash to 5000 ppm and I'm sitting
there thinking about refilling my torch
and when your torch gets phone you get
that little bit out that should I
guarantee you guru
more than 5000 ppm a butane in the air
around your head yeah in that moment as
it's it's blasted out excess I mean it
I'm sure it dissipates quickly but I
don't taste butane then and I haven't
just forced that through a several
hundred agree now right I agree with
that there's this guy this guy goes on
to say it's not the butane said Nick
Mosely co-owner and chief science
officer at confident confidence
analytics a kind of assessing laboratory
in Washington State the butane is really
not a huge health risk he said adding
that it takes quite a bit way more than
you get from dabbing or a vape in to
cause serious harm such as liver damage
and then there is a 1991 1981 case study
cited by the US Department of Health and
Human Services found that exposure to
10,000 ppm s for 10 minutes may lead to
drowsiness but doesn't appear to cause
systemic effects in humans the average
dab consists of about 10 milligrams to
20 milligrams of concentrate mostly at
confidence analytic set and in the eyes
of Colorado regulators he added there
these class three solvents are not cause
for concern at 5000 ppm s when the dose
of the substance is so low then they go
on to say Mosely did call the levels of
xylenes and benzene and Colorado
concerning the issue with xylenes and
benzene he explained is that the
contaminants are unintentionally there
in other words those chemicals aren't
part of the extraction process those
chemicals are sometimes used to clean
equipment and may inadvertently become
part of the final product
see that's [ __ ] that sucks I don't like
that they're also sometimes found in
low-quality solvents okay so if you
don't distill your butane properly in
other words their contaminants in the
contaminant Mosley wasn't there
contaminants in the contaminate Mosley
wasn't trying to consider to criticize
Colorado's new limits from a health
perspective though he didn't sound
especially jazzed about the idea of
finding those residual levels in a
concentrator he just meant that it
higher but soon to be a legal level of
residuals could indicate careless
extraction methods or low quality
products and see that's what a lot of
people's concern is going to be
this is gonna make extractors lazy oh I
don't have to take all this out let's
hurry up and get this out of the back of
it so we can get the next batch in the
back oven because this is gonna pass lab
tests this is gonna be able to go on the
shelves
the limits were drastically increased
but they were so drastically increased
to a number so small that it's
unnoticeable it's it's a super tiny
amount and when you think about all the
other testing and stuff that goes into
it this is a conversation we're only
able to have because it's insanely legal
here statewide we have access to product
unmatched anywhere in the US as far as
testing in labeling goes we know more
about the product we're consuming than
anyone on the planet and going through
these rulemaking hearings as part of
that like these are the limits for
anything else on the market I'm not
encouraging it extractors to push the
envelope of the upper limits that are
allowed now but if if these are allowed
for any other product that buy in a
store or a pharmacy I don't see why they
shouldn't be that's my my hash either
but I also understand the movement away
from solvent solvent made hash I get the
people that are looking for high grade
water extract a lot of people are Moz
entrain yeah a lot of people love rosin
a lot of people are haters of BHO I get
it a big part of the marijuana community
came here fleeing the pharmaceutical
industry for one reason or another and
the idea of their marijuana industry
moving towards that model in any way is
scary moving away from natural in any
way is scary to them I hate to be the
one to point out that their flowers and
that the BHO hash are almost identical
in every way except for a little bit of
solvent used in the extract everything
that's in that flower is gonna be in
that extract including all the bats
in your flower because just because it's
a plant doesn't mean it's good for you
or natural in the end for a little bit a
lot of people were under the impression
that the clear and distillate was
removing solvents but we have recently
discovered that that is not true no you
have to use a separate filter to get out
pesticides and solvents from the clay
it's getting rid of the solvents because
we're heating it high enough that it's
the pesticides that we're not getting
out I said that wrong probably because I
took too many dads there were a lot of
rumors about the clear and 99% of them
were were just [ __ ] but I do love
some well-made distillate oh my god I've
had some amazing distillate but I don't
at all understand the height for the
clear and I know people that are
obsessed with the clear that rant and
rave about it because of the hype and
not because of its actual properties I
would prefer my distillate
to come without turps and let me put my
own turps in there that's why I would
prefer I see one of the things I really
like in in my hash was the reason I'm
such a live resident fanatic was that
flavor like it's already there I just
scooped in and glob yeah I yeah I was
gonna I was gonna let you have it but I
I the actuals like taking that a
distillate dunking it that's fun for me
but that's I don't want to build it I
just want to enjoy it yeah and one of
the things I love about cannabis is the
the huge flavor profile variety and
it's more fun to me to taste with that
flower was supposed to taste like then
going to the soda factory and have them
having them do like 25 different syrups
to create that soda flavor right yeah I
get you okay I just like when you can
take some distillate I know I feel like
they kind of overdo it when they go
mixing the Terps in on their own when
they sell me the distillate it's
overdone every dish what I've had that
has terpenes reintroduced his way
overdone it yeah I'd rather be able to
do it myself and I can buy a bottle of
distillate and three or four vials of
turps and mix and match and make it the
way I want and then when I run out of
that distillate I just put the chirps
right on my shatter I've been getting
little tiny pipettes and just dipping it
right onto the shatter I do believe that
the terpenoids contribute heavily to my
high because I can dab the same shatter
and put different Terps on it if you get
different effects you tease the futures
show about lab testing and how it's
changed some things and it's definitely
helped us lose focus on the variety of
compounds in the plant that influence
the the high the experience the medical
effect and I can't wait for that show
for these reasons exactly there's so
many different parts of the cannabis
plant the influence its effect on you
and I think you're exactly right
terpenes are a huge portion huge um for
medical effect and the high you can feel
it with that 100% distillate when you go
from a ghost train hey stirrups to an OG
Kush strips that you're Dunkin and in
you can feel the high difference it's
the exact same THC the exact same but
when you add in the other stuff that
doesn't affect the high it's the non
psychoactive stuff that you know the
materia it doesn't scare people as a
Final Fantasy 7 joke they uh it
completely changes the hive I was blown
away the first time I experienced it
it's all about all about the other
pieces yes it's all about that entourage
synergistic effect or do you want to
call it I love the term entourage effect
it's it's so yeah and it's true because
like you said when I spoke these up
these ghosts right here this is like
from my dad and then a second later like
I keep getting higher but if you put the
same dab and take some of that oh gee
cush like you were talking about you
want to drool in yourself for a couple
seconds but if you take the thing it's
called para Digium you take that one I
get hyper from they all have there's
something in those terpenoids it's doing
something completely different to your
body into your mind it it just releases
different different chemicals triggers
different things but yeah lab testing
has changed what we look forward is
consumers and that's drastically
changing the the consumption experience
absolutely well I hope that allowing
more PPM's in our concentrates does not
encourage hash makers too lazy up we're
getting really good at concentrate
making here in Colorado so I hope that
people just keep getting better shout
out to the people that are encouraging
and learning and making better hash yeah
I don't think anybody was really excited
about this as far as yeah now we can
shave 45 seconds off our back up and
cook you know when I first heard about
this happening I was like oh what the
[ __ ] is happening but now that I've read
the article I think I understand a
little more and I'm not as nervous or
paranoid about the entries if there was
ever a be a to where I can taste butane
in it you can guarantee that that hash
is going away I was a little worried
when it was only Leafly was was kind of
reporting this and I was I was happy to
see the the level of reporting they did
but because they're not a hardcore news
org you see that wander a little bit the
guy I'm guessing he just said it as
something dumb during the interview and
I've been interviewed a lot at us
sometimes stupid [ __ ] slips
I save plenty of [ __ ] on this podcast
please dome a good reporter I'll skip
over the brain fart that you uttered on
the record and stick to the on topic
point and in this reporter got hung up
on that we might be talking about levels
that consumers could smell or taste and
then he goes on to say how these levels
are perfectly allowed in pharmaceutical
products if you can allow 5000 ppm of
butane in an epidural inhaler have a
puter all and hate other people with
that level of people that they reported
the taste like that would be part of the
study that he's citing for the increase
and it's not but because he mentioned
that to a reporter who's not obsessed
with keeping the story clean and factual
and he got hung up on something down the
guy said at the beginning and now half
of people that read that story are like
man I'm not buying hash Colorado anymore
- yeah - because you will know and
they're gonna be lab tests I can I see
your container you've got there's a
Panama East Coast Panama it's got the
lab testing real well on here this is
some this is from trip X and it is east
coast Panama chunk wax it's labeled
hybrid the next numbers listed on here
are the MIP which is the marijuana
infused product license it's got the
license number of who made the hash it's
got the OPC number which is the optional
premises cultivation center and it's
gotten their ID number that's where it
was grown then it's gonna batch number
so that we know which batch of plants
went into this mix by researching the
batch number we can tell you what plant
tags were in here which is each
individual plant which if they did it
that's how they track like those are the
members they used to do recall track
every Colorado we can tell you if that
plant has been applied a pesticide we
can tell you everything that plan has
been braid with fed we can tell you the
date it was cut as a clone the day it
was moved into flower we can tell you
everything about mostly everything that
about that plant if it were properly
documented by the grower and the metric
supervisor at that facility a lot of
times she tries to pass through testing
results are what's gonna reveal the
truth so I'm looking at this container
it's got test results on it ayuh shows
me how much CBG a cbgc BDA
CBD THC a THC and total cannabinoids are
on here now I assume that in the very
near future they're going to include
these particles per million testing on
those those part of these rule changes
we're labeling changes that product is
this endowment that's an old product
okay you can hash for a minute I do I
love stockpiling so that I can let you
know every time I go to dad I've got 35
different flavors usually awesome
planning and every now and then I
realized that I've had a cash container
for a year 14 months and then I make a
point to smoke real quick so it doesn't
convert any further if you need some
help let me know happy to old high THC
stuff that's had had some agent was
really good on inflammation of pain okay
[Music]
D carboxyl group it's it's a reason to
stash and a reason not to worry if he
gets a little old but yeah I'm I'm a
hoarder but this labeling isn't up to
par and it's still better than 99% of
the legal marijuana products she's gonna
find I'm sold in the US yes same thing
with the southern hash container I've
bought I've worn this label down a
little bit but a totally different
container totally different shape
totally different company exact same
information yeah and this one if you
look closely you can see that the butane
PPM's are listed on this oh nice can you
read it still um now I can I can read
that it used to be there and I actually
I believe it's triple zeros for both of
the the butane and that whatever that
next butane was nice job yeah and I see
propane that was actually 2.75 left okay
that's not much not much at all but it's
for some live resin so that's to be a
little bit expected there's gonna be a
little bit of residual solvent left in
that it's got a lot of moisture going on
so it'll hold on to some stuff so it
looks real real
um it's almost like what's like sugary
butter Plato's and I don't know if you
ever did the thing with water and
cornstarch but if you ever like
scratched your fingernail and scratch
some of that out of there it's about
that consistency I would totally dab
that stuff by the looks I loved I love
this company I don't really want to
shadow max we've done a lot of shout
outs on this show but they make some
awesome live resin and I Drive really
far to get it sometimes in Colorado
people are like but there's storms every
there are stores everywhere Nick yeah
but I Drive up to Denver to this one
place I Drive from West Pueblo not
Pueblo West with the west side of Pueblo
to the very far north end in Denver it's
like a hundred and twenty-six miles if I
Drive past at least 300 marijuana stores
yeah to go to the one with the product
that like yeah I do and have done and
will do the same thing in the future
only like there are two or three
dispensaries in Denver that I like to
really shop at yep all right so you guys
don't worry about it's not gonna be that
big of a deal if you come to Colorado to
buy some concentrates and you get these
high numbers you're gonna notice if
something's wrong
p.m. numbers freak you out like if
you're buying shatter in it shatters you
don't have to worry about residual
butane you're probably doing all right
if it's on the Shelf and they've got it
it's the store you're probably doing
okay because they'll get concentrates
that [ __ ] won't sell it'll go on sale
they'll get rid of it the first time
they'll never buy it again if the
employees our customers as well most of
the time I mean is a consumer that
doesn't really know a whole lot the one
thing you want to look out for is if you
go to a shop and they go I mean just for
example this is 50 this is 55 this is 65
oh and we have these for $19.99 be wary
at the 1999 there's there's a reason
that there's that big big discount for
that one particular thing it might be
old it might be about smooth
passed out like a friend of mine had to
throw out a whole bunch of product at
his store because labeling labels
expired and you can't just slap on a new
label that's terrible um that when that
date's getting close you'll watch it go
from full price to half price to exactly
what the shop paid for it to half what
the shop paid for it to please God let
me get any of my money back on it before
you know the first or whatever hits and
sometimes is a consumer that can be real
helpful and sometimes that just means
that's the crap that they got tricked
into by just a bit gnarly dad yeah one
thing I want to mention is something
I've experienced in Colorado and I'm
gonna quit talking funnier in just a
second but something that happens a
extraction company and we're just gonna
say that Mike and I have an extraction
company so Jeff and Mike's extraction
company we make extracts that's our
specialty what we do is we go to
dispensaries that have aggro involved in
there and their business plan so there's
a dispensary with a grow that grows
product and that product goes to the
dispensary for sale what we offer to do
as an extraction company is we will take
either your buds or your trim material
you want to give us and we would gladly
turn it into product for you for a price
there is usually I don't know how much
insider info I should give but there's
usually a deal worked out to where
there's an industry range that I run it
we run it as a company and we split it
with you 50/50 and then we get half of
the product that's done we package it
and everything and then we deliver your
portion back to the store and you put it
on the shelf for sale and now the other
way to do it is we run it and we sell it
back to your dispensary at a price and
those prices vary widely depending on
the company and the deals that you work
out and how much product you're running
the quality of the product the final
product consistency the popularity of
the companies Kim if if you're if you
were one of the top known grows and one
of the top known extract companies
they'll run the ship for damn near free
for each other
so that they can both say ran by these
companies and they both make a ton of
[ __ ] money off you usually see a
pretty pretty tight range in hash
pricing it at the shop and I mean it'll
be like a ten or fifteen dollar window
in the the cheapest one in that window
is usually a company you've never heard
right and that doesn't mean anything
other than their knew of them of that
company of that range is a company
called extracts they are not known but I
think lately they've been kicking out
some ridiculously good concentrates at a
very low price their packaging is plain
they don't have any advertising I've
seen a half dozen new extract companies
that I've never heard of before whether
the first product I see from them is
stellar incredible so I had no idea that
they were doing hash they make some of
the best stuff the first time I saw it
it was actually granny that yeah that
had it she opened it up and I was like
oh yeah there's a company down here that
they used to come into the shop I was
working out all the time
that's brand new was just getting on
their feet and I've seen some really
nice stuff from that lately it's nice to
see this much quality come on though
coming on the market was something where
I was headed with all of this is what
kid if you find it if you buy an extract
from the next rack company say you get
something what do we name our company I
gave us a name but if you buy a problem
but we are running material grown by
other dispensaries so if we buy I'm
gonna throw them right under the [ __ ]
bus if we buy some material from
Maggie's Farm and run it it's gonna come
out Brown and janky it always does I've
heard I've seen several extract
companies run Maggie's Farm stuff it's
not quality something about their grow I
think they trim with the trim machine
which will [ __ ] up your extract I think
they're using old material which will
[ __ ] up your extract their stuff never
comes out good if you run stuff for some
different things that going into a grow
[ __ ] up the X right if you run material
from kind love it always comes back fire
so it's not it's a good portion of the
hash work is up to the company that's
running your extract but a large portion
of it is up to whoever grew that
material how long the material said
around how it was stored how it was
trimmed that is a huge factor so if you
buy some extracts from a hash company if
Mike and if you buy some Mike and Jeff
extracts and it's shitty one time and
amazing one time you've kind of got to
keep in mind to go look at this little
OPC and MIP tag on here and see what the
the OPC number is because that will tell
you who grew it and it varies wildly
batch to batch with with some companies
other companies that are a little more
established I see less variety in the
end what they're putting on shelves but
for a while like a year and a half ago
you would see I mean like a plus F plus
yeah I mean in the same ship it's like
the products will be really really good
for a little while and then one guy will
quit and everything just falls apart
until we figured out what the new and
the other side of that coin is if you go
to a shop and you see a strain you like
and you take a look at the hash and it's
a quality the that looks good to you and
you take it home you hate it and you
love it and you want more go back and
get more right away yeah because just
the nature of the industry extract
companies by what's available there's no
guarantee that that strain is going to
be made available to that extract
company again or then if it does then
it'll be that quality that that same
artist or our team of people will be
we're doing the extraction in the same
way a lot of times that'll be a blend of
flowers like we the extractors will take
a minimum of usually a thousand grams to
run they don't want less than a thousand
grams out to what fits in their column
and you don't always have a say if you
had a thousand grams of something it
would be buds and it wouldn't be a bunch
of [ __ ] shake to run
so it wouldn't even happen so maybe
they're putting what is this you got
East Coast pineapple antenor that's a
real strain maybe you got some busy man
some golden time when it's when it
sounds like two names swish together for
an hour but you just put me on something
that I want to [ __ ] about I hate it
when extract companies do that it
bothers me as a medical product we don't
need extract companies creating [ __ ]
names out of their hash blends it's this
I have the same issue with growers give
it a minute
stabilize it then rename it but it's not
it's a renaming thing sucks something
that I find important there are strains
that are well-known certain people rely
on certain strains I don't know what
strain grateful dog works well for you
I've got a blue headband and I have no
[ __ ] clue I wish that company would
have put blue dream and blue or headband
so that we know what you're smoking
because if that works wonderfully for
you we can go find more blue berry or
blue dream and more headband for you but
they're just and now they're also kind
of creating confusion because what if
somebody does have blue headband as a
real flower and a real cross that a
breeder will they actually took their
time to make pills for the consumer is I
mean people are creatures of habit they
want to go to the store and they want
their [ __ ] six-pack of Corona yeah
and they want the same thing when they
go to the grocery they want to walk in
and get there there's three favorite
things just like they do it every other
store in their world and unfortunately
when you walk into a marijuana store
it's yeah I understand that you really
loved that blue tree we bought last week
it was you know a really good cut it was
real popular we're out of that now
here's where it falls in the range of
genetics
here's stuff that's similar good luck
picking a new huh and I mean you can
come back tomorrow it asks for more blue
dreaming you're gonna either but maybe
in 54 days yeah eventually there will be
more but when that will be and when it's
stuff like hash the the store has almost
no ability to call the extract company
and be like yeah we need more Sour
Diesel
there might be some Sour Diesel
available that they're about to run for
you there might not be any offered to
that extract company for years unless
they're growing the stuff they're
processing right or unless the shop is
selling the material to the extract
company there's no way to guarantee that
materials gonna be there when it's time
to read up a shipment so you're you're
kind of forced to go find new stuff that
you like which is you know good and bad
I like it because I like a big variety
if you there's so many people off there
are some people that are very in my
opinion it's too specific about their
THC and cannabis needs I think that
they're a little spoiled and they should
just smoke some dope and relax but some
people I cannot smoke stuff with the
word cush or this they can or I cannot
smoke heavy sativas it's part of the
evolutionary process where our brains
are just designed to remember stuff that
we didn't like or that we perceived is
hurtful and when it's stuff like foods
and intoxicants I mean we hold onto
those memories for life everybody's got
that one alcoholic beverage that they
got ahold of when they were 13 14 15
yeah it was water and then threw up for
a day and a half every when they can't
even see sour apple pucker or banana red
without that you took that to a personal
place didn't you know ice actually I
doubt that person were those two
references are there things would ever
listen to the show but on the off chance
they do that laughter
the other part but from for me it's
Miller Lite mg DS shouldn't be drinking
my piss anyway died it was what was
there when we were that age he had a
friend drank way too much of it he did
the infamous puke fart and I was
hungover for like five days now even
when I see the label I throw and I used
to have to go buy it for somebody in my
life a lot and that was always a fun
trip back from the store because I'm
trying not to look at what's in the
passenger seat cause it's making me
nauseous
so I felt about rum it's the same thing
with cannabis somebody smokes way too
much cush one night and it's how much
they consumed how they consumed it
doesn't have anything to do with the
strainer that it was an indica but now
every time they go to a dispensary they
make a big deal about how it can't be
touched to their bud tender or a can't
say Durban in it that no I smoked too
much Durban the first time I came to
Colorado and I was alone in my hotel
room and I ate that whole that whole
brownie and then I smoked that Durban
poison and it was just too much and I
don't want that Durban it's like dude it
was that my son can haz Cheezburger
didn't have nothing to do with let's
train you picked but explaining that
it's difficult and then when they get
there and that the one thing they found
that they really like you're out of and
I have to start the process all over
again like it can be kind of headache II
I wish more people expected it okay
cannabis market we've got to regulate it
a little bit better so we've got the
products and people want but it's hard
to remind myself how lucky we are here
the good [ __ ] sells out that's how it
goes it's a first world problem in the
extreme yeah we're so spoiled here with
our marijuana markets in the vast
assortment of products it's available in
that market I mean prices are coming
down quality's going up selections going
up it's good for suppositories now you
can take your wheat in every way I put
some weed pain cream on today before I
left the house I gave them both knees a
coat before I started getting ready to
come over for the
show we've got suppositories we've got
lozenges we've got sprays we've got
pills
we've got flowers we've got a hundred
different kinds of hash when you go to
this when you went to a dispensary a
year and a half ago open was the only
vape pen on the shelf now there are
hundreds of a pen companies you know
with hundreds of different qualities
honors the different strain options I
love the things are strained specific
now - that's so great this screen
specific edibles strain specific vape
pens that [ __ ] is so great instead of
just indica sativa or hybrid you can get
actual we move closer to the micro brew
model every day with the quality in the
selection of products that we've got and
it's absolutely wonderful and then I
look at I mean just next door to us most
of the states this around Colorado are
still under full prohibition where my
friends scored a handful of good herb
good weed like that's what they know
about it is that their friends scored it
and it's good yeah and that's the end of
the information that they will ever have
on it I don't miss those days when you
go to get some weed and they had some
weed and you got whatever was there it
was that was one of the things I like
most about working the retail counter is
watching people's faces light up like
they were just learning about Santa if I
get to watch the numbers on the scale
from my side and your side that's
awesome
yep it's so much fun watching people's
faces light up when they see what the
possibilities really are for this but
then again I read stuff like how it is
on the East Coast right now in a lot of
places and I just cringe that's why
we're here we're trying to educate
everybody so that we can legalize places
everywhere legalize cannabis you guys is
we've been gone for an hour like it's
them start wrapping up this podcast we
can go for an hour and five minutes
everywhere I don't see any other any
better way to rest that's perfect
follow Mike on Twitter 15 follow me on
twitter IG fyh podcast follow me on
facebook podcast of course check me out
on Instagram Irie underscore genetics
look at my cannabis photography it would
be cool if you go to iTunes search for
the drone our podcast you should
definitely do that photo click on the
little icon there go to the ratings and
reviews section
give me a leave me a review and give me
a rating so far everybody has left me a
five-star review there are 39 or 40
five-star reviews at this point in time
be cool be like everybody else throw me
that five-star review I'm not begging
for it don't you think I deserve go for
it I'd love to see it also patreon you
guys don't forget about patreon patreon
is a service that allows you to
financially support the podcast all I'm
asking for his help taking the cost of
the website off of my back and maybe
getting a little support from the
listeners the podcast will always be
free guys I'd love giving you this
podcast if you'd like to go to patreon
and sign up you can contribute as little
as $1 and I don't think there's a limit
to how many zeroes you can put on there
so go for $1.00 but for a million
dollars however you'd like to do it I'll
give you a shout out of the podcast to
say thank you I would love to see you
contribute a million I'll convince him
to do something
podcast about whatever you want if you
send me a million dollars if you've
talked about every million bucks
anything a million bucks wouldn't write
ok patreon.com no patreon.com slash grow
from your heart check it out
I'm not asking anybody for a million
dollars one dollar is plenty if you
cannot contribute please keep listening
to the podcast I still appreciate you
there are a few people out there that
will throw down a dollar it'll help with
what I'm trying to do I'm trying to
cover the cost of the website to keep
the podcast coming to you so that
doesn't come out of my pocket I can
cover it but I'd rather not that's all
I'm saying
if you find that you got some value from
the show go ahead and throw me a buck if
you can't do it times are tough I
[ __ ] get it I'm the one asking you
for money I can't be mad that you don't
have any extra money I get it I totally
get it but I appreciate the people that
can't contribute truly do appreciate
that because I feel like I've been going
on for a long time Mike I owe you a huge
thank you for coming to do a two podcast
with me yeah we did a good job I think
you did a great job I let you talk for a
whole bunch because you had a lot of
[ __ ] on your mind so
I guess it's been a really fun couple of
weeks and news it has been a lot of
scary news announcements but there's
been a lot of good ones too I cannot
wait to see what the future brings
dude it's 2017 is gonna be interesting
[ __ ] if not all in good ways he just
made 37 facial expressions trying to
think about these dudes masks broke the
only thing that got less likely is the
aliens making contact guaranteed if
they're watching us from above they're
continuing their policy of wait and see
for the next four years other than that
pretty much every [ __ ] other
possibility from peace on earth to
nuclear war got like five percent more
likely this year to last year so yeah
it's gonna be an interesting year for
damn sure it's absolutely going to be an
interesting year that Dan's got the
combination to the button
dude that the least confusing things so
far about Trump being elected is Trump
getting elected which is confusing in
its own right but all of the decisions
he's made sense election might have been
more confusing than America choosing do
like do you guys if you're not following
Trump's Twitter feed just do that sure
to follow just created it finally broke
down and created a Twitter feed to
follow it just to follow Trump just to
follow Joe check it out you guys for
pooping or whatever you're doing just go
give it a good follow and just like his
tweets cuz it's hilarious
don't feel the need to like them you
should be following them what you should
do though is go to Twitter and follow
the girl from her podcast you should
definitely follow I love it if you
follow me action if you want to contact
me and interact with me or if you've got
a product that you would like me to
review and you don't want to reach out
on social media send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com you
know I'd love to hear from you I am
slowly working my way through all of the
emails that people send me I am
overwhelmed by messages but keep them
coming cuz I like it I am going to get
through all of them before the end of
time hopefully I get to your problem in
your garden before your garden is
harvested that's what I'm trying to do
the email is the best way to ask good
questions yes if you've got a grow
question or a policy question or a good
question for Jeff that you'd like mansur
on the show emails the best way to do it
and I've repeatedly seen him contact and
then drag the appropriate person to
respond or the person that was requested
oh yeah I'm back on the show to get your
question answered
and that's huge what uh what other
podcaster is gonna recruit people from
Denver to come down and answer your your
organics question sometimes I Drive to
Denver for them 30 miles guys anyway
we're gonna wrap up the show it's been
an hour ten hour and 11 minutes on to
thank everybody for listening Mike huge
thanks again for coming happy to send
you home back to the family real quick
hope you enjoyed it thanks so much for
having me again you're invited back
we'll have you millions of more times
we're gonna make this podcast go a
billion billion episodes that's a huge
goal we need to get together more than a
couple of times a month to record
everybody I want to thank everybody for
listening guys and gals we're not
gentlemen children of all ages and
everything in between
I thank everybody for listening to the
podcast um who's getting a shout out
this week how about everybody I shout
out to the coming new year that's what I
want to give a shot yeah that's a 2016
being over yes to new beginnings
you guys thanks again for listening let
me give you huge shot that's my ninja
Spence and until next time take a bat
dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
all right podcast roll don't want to
thank you guys again for listening to a
long block of old episodes I would love
it if you would email me and let me know
what you think about these old episodes
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com also if you want to
stalk me on social media you can find me
on twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a fad
dab and give your mom a hug for me
you