[Music]
ocean Rasta Jeff in the house
yeah what's up podcast world it's
Thursday and that means it's time for
another throwback Thursday episode to
grow from your heart podcast before we
get to the old episodes let me make a
quick disclaimer if I mention any
advertising any giveaways any promotions
or any contests all of that stuff has
expired there are no advertisements
promotions giveaways or contests that
are valid in these old episodes I want
to thank you guys for listening and with
no further ado here's a block of old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast
[Music]
it's time for 176 of the growths in your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversations that's
right a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff Lana thank you guys again for
joining me as my friends in the music
[Music]
here at the table
thank you for joining me thank you
oh my gosh we take some also repeat
offenders are here do it she was
recovered from a DAB that she nearly
died from and gentlemen someone who's
not on the show he comes here often he's
kind of quiet but the infamous mr. Bobo
blaster goes here teaming up with me and
making me not the only dude here three
ladies that have already medicated yes
by sticking a suppository up there
I'm just gonna turn this down the music
right here right to this so yes ladies
and gentleman um at separate times don't
be dirty but I had several times this
evening these three ladies stepped into
my lovely pink restroom nobody made fun
of me for my pink restroom thank you
that is super pink in there and they
inserted and/or applied some
suppositories I don't have my notes out
where I can see them but I have it all
in my head we're gonna talk about is the
newcomer and also the provider of the
suppositories oh not you personally your
company we're gonna talk about that tell
us a little bit about the company and
tell us about suppositories and then
tell me about the dosage that everybody
was just fed my name is Shannon
obviously am French connoisseurs
genetics and concentrates is the name of
the company we're based in Denver we are
solvent list company we've got rosin
products that's kind of our main our
main products but we also carry the
ancillary products bath bombs you might
have seen them around town they become
very big but our suppositories are just
kind of that silent medication that
nobody's talking about but is so highly
effective and with the new levels of
chemicals that are allowed and solvents
are in your in your concentrates it's
just a smarter I mean if you're applying
this and you need it for medical reasons
you don't necessarily want those
chemicals and balls right so it's it's
just a much better application there's
people who want to be medicated during
the day but can't afford to be high due
to their jobs this does not get you high
per se there is a euphoric feeling it's
just that you know when you can manage
something symptoms that have been you
know killing you it's just nice like
it's a euphoric feeling scuse my throat
is right from hanging out well I did not
use this depository tonight but I have
tried one and it euphoric is certainly
one of the words I would use to describe
it none of my lower back pain was
noticeable after using a suppository it
definitely works for that 70 percent
absorption rate I mean edibles is thirty
smoking is approximately 10 so it's the
most effective way to get medicine
and you guys probably put them in say 30
minutes ago ish hardcore let's hear what
you did so that means diamond granny is
actually medicated with 100 THC and 100
CBD me and Lindsey since we've only done
one it's a 50/50 50 P AC 50 CBD but
because we do cater to medical patients
I recently helped a colon cancer patient
because that's what his thanks for
coming appreciate it
how many you got for 200 milligrams in
only 100 only hundred okay how long did
it take for the first one to kick in
maybe 30 to 40 minutes Lindsey do you
notice a difference since you don't go
as frequently yeah for sure
it definitely kicks in somewhere in the
in the 30 to 40 minute range it actually
probably just kicked in about 10 minutes
ago for me and I really was like you
also took a dad that made you coffee
they probably got your blood pressure
moving was actually start sort of in
your tummy and then it sort of just
spreads out and you can feel the
medicine happen it never got above my
chest region I never I never felt any
medication above that I've got some
shoulder pain from a car accident I
never felt it there but my knee pain was
gone my legs were I don't know that I
would want to take it the first two
times and try to go to work my job
involves me on my feet working I'm
running laps basically all day I don't
know that my legs would have cooperated
a hundred percent it might have been a
little little too much
a day's work and when we first created
these suppositories I was making 15
milligram and 25 milligram as well but I
think it just got to the point where if
you're in that much pain that you're
willing to stick something up your rear
it's going to need to be seriously
medicated like I'm not doing it just for
15 milligrams maybe for 50 I'll go for
it everybody's comfortable jumping in
that water do you see
what is your demographic that's using
your product do you see an apprehension
from males are they afraid of using your
product I get apprehension when like if
I'm giving out samples and I give out
one to one person they're apprehensive
but if I give to people they will
usually team up and be like yeah I'll do
it if you do it it's not gender specific
all right I think it kind of goes across
the board the you know and really the
only thing we've focused on this is the
symptoms you know just that sensation
but for women there's an alternate use
as well that's not highly talked about
and it makes men cringe is that monthly
mistress that comes in visits it can be
a [ __ ] and if you have endometriosis or
other things and men look at us and they
know because they've seen their
girlfriends wrench in pain but they
don't get it like girls actually if you
say that they're like it relieves that
and they are willing to use it
I'm sure Lindsey can attest to that I
know she suffers from that yeah I
actually I have a very insists which is
why I even have a medical card and you
know I've suffered from it since I was
about 16 years old
and I truly didn't have full relief from
my pain until I moved to Colorado and I
had tried CBD for the first time even
just dabs like I couldn't believe how
much that had taken away from me and
then the first time I ever took a
suppository I was in a lot of pain and
Gail had given
one of them and I was like Gumby I you
could barely move my bottom legs like I
was just like so so did you see your
bottom what you say that the medicated
feeling kind of comes in waves yeah you
might think okay oh that's it it's
peaked but no no good 10 hours sometimes
12 hours yeah and and it seems like the
medicine knows where to go
except for shoulder and neck it goes
past the heart is that's kind of like
you would have to it would have to be
applied differently because the heart's
kind of there like it's running these
blood vessels so the animals get to my
shoulders if I eat it it goes to my head
and shoulders finds the pain it tickles
the pain and massages that out and then
if there's leftovers it goes to your
brain and makes you a little high this
way I feel cannabis does or if you
consume it is very smart
actually Lindsey texted me I was I was
trying to hang out with Lindsey one day
is like you want to hang out and she's
like hurt so bad I can't even hang out
and I said did you put one of those
suppositories in there and she was like
crazy but go ahead and try that she's
like been there done that already I'm
still here bro
I mean I guess in a sense you can say it
gets you high but it's not the mental
psychosis one thing we do need to say to
the ladies since you brought it up about
monthly cycles
I recommend it all the time but we need
to let them know don't be support don't
do this
vaginally you can't well you can but if
you think about it your monthly cycle is
to flush things out so if you're gonna
insert that suppository into your vagina
you're going to flush the medicine back
out not to say you had more membranes in
your butt so you might as well go yeah I
know there was wasn't hours I didn't
have any part in it but I do know that
she had had bladder cancer something
more on the female area so she used them
vaginally and assist was going away with
chemo on the outside but they weren't
going away on the inside so by using the
suppository she was able to reduce the
ulcers on the inside she wasn't on her
cycle when she was exactly right so we
probably have all agreed don't don't use
it vaginally when you were on your
period but if you do have an ovarian
cyst maybe put it in there if you're
seeking relief and not on your cycle put
it in your butt to get the pain relief
you have agree with Jesus I kind of
agree with Gail here to be honest with
you I've only ever really put one in my
vagina
one or two times every other time that
I've used them which has been about a
dozen now has all been in my butt
because oh man there's a lot of reason
I'm gonna cut that into a sound right
[Music]
Shannen maybe we should tell them about
the size of the suppositories you know
they cringe just just gonna say that you
the other thing I really wanted before I
forget cuz I'm really stoned
I like to throw them in the freezer for
about five to ten minutes before I use
it so that way because I'm an idiot and
I leave them in when I first get them I
leave them in my bag or somewhere and
they kind of but not melt but they just
get soft exactly just like her they just
get a little bit soft and I don't you
know I don't want to have any issues any
crumble any breakage so I throw it in
the freezer just so hard knees up just
that tiny bit and then it's super easy
to answer and there's no issues with it
so if you're looking for a super easy
way to do it that is my tip for that
that is how I I typically store mine in
the refrigerator or the freezer we keep
them in the freezer at when I once they
cure and everything and I seal them so
it's definitely you know a cooler
temperature obviously it's we don't use
coconut oil and the reason that we don't
and if you if you check any youtubes or
any of those type of forums they will
all say use coconut oil well we don't
use coconut oil because there's a lot
people who have allergies to it that
have developed so
we try to avoid that we actually use
cocoa butter and beeswax and so that's
why ours are a little they stay firm or
even when they're not in the freezer
like some of the others I know because
when they're made out of coconut oil the
second you touch it it starts to melt
regardless of how you've stored it so
you know I try to be conscious of all
common allergies and things that may
affect patients especially when their
immune systems already being compromised
you said you make them out of solvent
list can you can you teach our listeners
that may not know what solvent as hashes
can you give them a quick lesson if you
need a hand we'll jump in yeah
absolutely thank you I'm actually this
one so depending on what kind of
concentrate we're making we makes
everything is done with either heat and
pressure or ice and water we don't use
any chemicals throughout the process I
mean there's solvent free which means
there were solvents used but they've
been removed for us we never this
product never touches us all bit okay
even in our grow it's it's as close to
working as you can get you know to get
certified organic cost a lot of money
and we're still new so that's in our in
our coming days or years probably when
we can truly go full organic but with
the process uh things are removed so if
it's star melt say we we make it into
hash with ice and water okay we've got a
hash guy that makes that and then from
there we press that will sift it we get
the truthful amount and we get our
different microns and then from there if
it's not doesn't meet our standards of
truthful melt then we press it into
rosin and that just is you know that
it's a ninety five percent typically THC
level about that and you know we always
have the testing on those and it varies
for our nug melt we just take the flour
it's all about how you cure it how it's
grown the strains you use are important
right we just take it and it's process
down and we just press the flour with
heat and pressure which makes a rosin as
well yeah which is becoming more right a
lot of my listeners might not know so
I'm gonna give him just a bits basically
you're taking
a really high-tech George Foreman grill
and squishing a bud and a George into a
George Foreman grill and some juice
strips out of it and that juice is very
potent I am NOT a huge fan of rosin
smoking by itself because I usually
don't like the flavor if it's done right
if it's me if you take hash and make out
of that
I don't think squishing the but makes
flavorful a lot of people are huge fans
[Music]
and that's where the differentiation is
with nug melt that means it's not being
done right okay if it's not being done
right and which means it's being exposed
to there too long to the heat or too
high of a temperature for too long you
get that popcorn it's never happened in
our kitchen but if it that happens those
get turned into ancillary products bath
bombs like weed that's not something we
would put on the shelf as something we
would say smoke this because it doesn't
taste right you know we've really worked
on perfecting the cure in the taste and
when we press it the time and it's a
science so and that's something that
we've been really working on for a long
time so I I believe there was I think we
had some note here I'll make sure that
you actually get to try it I'll prove
your popcorn you are 100% correct if it
is not done right that's exactly what it
tastes like it's not like you guys have
mastered the tech so you're taking
properly done rosin and then making that
into a liquid that's able to be put into
the suppositories correct yes
it's I have a formulation I know what
calculations to make as far as so to
make potencies and whatnot
and based on how many I'm making it's
just its formula and I just take the
rosin and in the CBDs and just melt it
down within the cocoa butter and correct
and you said something about size Gail
and you know sizes
if I said you know the end of your
pinkie that's gonna vary because
everybody's pinkies a different size so
they're - it's 2 grams is what it weighs
out in amount it's a liquid the size is
a fleet suppository guy me if you've
ever used any torque sight type of
suppositories the exact same size we're
used buying the same molds from the same
complicated the major players by fast
somebody out there is gonna argue with
us and say that water is a solvent yes
we know water is a solvent but it's not
being used as a we get that but it's
being used more as an agitator in this
situation still people are haters and so
I just want to leave my footnote we get
it water is a solvent in this situation
it's not the ice is being used is more
like a beater to break off the trichome
so don't don't get at me because I know
someone's gonna say that like the water
isn't changing the properties of it
whereas like when BHO and Pho is run
through an itch physically changes it
and chemically changes it right there
because water doesn't change the
chemical properties give that speech
because we're talking about the size of
suppositories yes
[Music]
my favorite word insertion it's not that
bad you guys a lot of dudes a lot of
people looking like really bro like they
said you're not putting a dildo you eat
all day you take giant [ __ ] so some
things not gonna affect your butt any
poop you've ever thrown out don't be
scurred but right there Jeff is what you
men say know that hole is meant for
stuff to come out not stuff to go in a
lot of yeah at first when you say
suppose it
that's my natural reaction is but then I
think I'm a logical dude I understand
[Music]
let's do this it's not so it just
literally you just put it yes you go
like like do you Lindsay no what's the
story over here I want to know what I
missed how do you how do you know how
when it's in right well if you push too
far your body pushes it down a little
it's like you don't go far enough it
falls out it's called that second
speaker muscles really you know it's
comfortably right in one spot okay kind
of you know it's there but yeah yeah
it's gonna sound crazy but I mean I'll
just say this as long as you get it
completely in you can kind of like
squeeze your butt cheeks and push it the
rest of the way without needing to get
no closer it'll kind of like itself
where it squeamish about your butthole
you can just like get it all the way in
there physically and then you can just
use your own butt cheeks to just squeeze
it in there and then wash your hands
before you come take please let me
dispose it is important since you are
possibly inserting your finger you do
want to wash your hands before you just
say that because they'll be like oh
we're supposed to wash my hands before
too you know yeah we're not all savages
wash your hands ladies and gentlemen
all right I'm gonna bring up another
thing that maybe people are squeamish to
talk about but I do get asked this to it
what about leakage okay see I'm glad you
said that because that's exactly what I
was gonna say earlier when we got
derailed and I minimize guys majorly
talking medicating here might be and if
you're 15 years old then don't listen to
us this is we are truly talking about
medicating here and it's not all gonna
be suppository talk this is gonna sound
crazy but like I mean like I don't put
them in vaginally because I am always
afraid that like I'm gonna take a DAB
afterwards and cause really hard or like
bright and like juice and like I mean
it's not like a super big like fear of
mine I mean out of my vagina
I actually don't use them that way cuz
I'm super afraid of dr. pepper and good
friends
[Music]
neither with either one of them it's
possible because it's so if that happens
like it's not the end of the world wash
your clothes wash your underwear there
should not be any leakage now I have yet
to have any any no potato tips that have
given me worse side effects then I
really couldn't say that there's any
super negative side effects that stand
out to me there's a random question if
somebody gets a hold of these and they
don't have the proper labeling and they
eat one what's gonna go wrong nothing
but it's basically 50 milligrams THC and
50 milligrams CBD is gonna be processed
and stomach so you are probably going to
get a head high and not feel a lot of
pain relief it's going to be a different
high it's cocoa butter and it's beeswax
it's but we do ask that you be
responsible Medicaid errs and keep these
products away from your children yes yes
what uh what type of kid I was gonna ask
could we use these for our pets we just
had so I'm gonna go with another
question what are what
ladies had a conversation about a
documentary where people were having sex
with their farm animals I did not bring
it up I didn't start these ladies did
this to us what I was gonna ask really
though was what type of conditions would
you recommend like if you had just a
list of conditions and if you're like
suppositories we'll fix that what would
you go for first pain in any kind of you
know symptoms that you have where relief
I would say I'm gonna say anybody can I
use my own personal best ways to
describe things I took a year and I
weaned my husband off opioids with the
help of these suppositories oh wow okay
I'm with CBDs and suppositories Kevin is
now opioid free Congrats Kevin wasn't he
he will smoke but he didn't want to do
suppositories he didn't want to do CBDs
he he's an old hippie he'll smoke his
bowls okay but at the beginning of 2016
he was on 75 micrograms of fentanyl
which was to be changed every 72 hours
40 milligrams of extended-release
morphine two times a day 15 milligrams
of immediate-release morphine five times
a day as needed so he was basically
[Music]
that's when Jen and I first met I was
like I can't do this and she was like
well I'll help you she gave me some
products she gave me those suppositories
at first he said you stick that up your
butt I said are you kidding after 45
years of marriage you're gonna tell me
that are you kidding me stick this
little pinky thing compared to something
so I said okay if I do it you have to do
it I did it he did it and he's like
you're right they're not so bad if I
remember correctly it was he and had a
colonoscopy that day so you were like
you've already had it stretched out you
might as well just go for it it's
already inflated and they work so he is
someone that is in a lot of chronic pain
I mean those look to be prescribed that
much morphine to begin with absolutely
are those the coins it looks like a
quarter what the morphine pills
um no they're actually very small okay
and then you know then the government
has gotten to the point also where
they're like oh we're gonna take all
these pills for ten years and now we're
gonna take them away from you yes and
then we have people going out onto the
streets and they're buying them and
we're getting more heroin addicts now
because heroin is cheaper than pills on
the street so guys I'm telling you
cannabis it I'll tell you if you have an
opioid addiction these suppositories
help you get rid of it cuz when you
start kicking opioid you get sick yeah
even if you try to wean slowly you get
sick your body missing it you've been
right yeah but your body doesn't know
that yet so yeah well congrats - is he
still as grumpy
yeah alright but he's gone to Vegas with
me live up to his name well do we want
to brag about that for a second are we
finished let's keep talking about why so
obviously I mean any kind of lower
extremities I would say anywhere from
you know the heart down you could you
could find relief in some way it just
depends on what your symptoms are I mean
there's because it's a one-to-one ratio
50/50 THC and CBD you're getting the
benefits of both so it it's just it's
the to catalyze each other it's just
overall beneficial I mean I the list
could go on and on but I mean for me
personally it's nerve damage
sciatic nerve issues I was almost
paralyzed in a jet ski accident so you
know it flares up from time to time and
it swells up so and that's what I use
them okay girls obviously use them for
endometriosis cancer patients use that
to relieve symptoms you know from their
cancer okay whatever it might be I mean
cancer if you're on chemo yeah you're
probably really nauseous and what are
they gonna do they're gonna give you a
pharmaceuticals they're gonna give you a
kite rail zofran there's all these pills
they're gonna give you so you don't get
sick well guess what
you don't need those pills you can
insert one of these suppositories it's
going to help with the nauseousness it's
going to help with the pain it's not
going to cure your cancer that's not
what we're saying but it will make the
quality of of what you're going through
at that time better it'll make I think
that's why that's why I'm such an
advocate for this I mean you know the
70% absorption rate is huge when you
smoke things it's about a 10% when you
eat it it's 30% so they're getting 70
percent of that 5050 and that's a huge
amount quickly lasts for quite a long
time I don't know when I take dad's it
may be good 30 40 minute buzz out of it
but well you know the lingering part
about 15 minutes of are is cool but then
you just seem to last a long time yeah
the waves go yeah the waves yeah the
waves are fun I noticed that for sure
for sure I was thinking maybe I would
take them if I had to go on a plane ride
or a car trip where I'm sitting for a
long time because my lower back and my
knees start to get mad about that so it
might be cool to have those on a plane
trip or something where I'm cramped in
the car I have that same like any time
I'm sitting for a long time and I Drive
a lot just with calling on dispensaries
and just writing the word out so I I
don't typically do it while I'm driving
just because like you said it kind of
deadened like I want to have my reaction
times but as soon as I stopped or
you know at the end of the day and
taking them further computer time yeah
it sounds perfect all right I like it
it's a good product you guys all have
the same look on your face what other
products do you carry though at CGC yeah
we also one of our highest things that
we've been been popular have been our
bath bombs they have we have three
different kinds there's a hundred
milligram THC with 15 CBD again we've
got the solvent listen they're okay
they're foaming bath bombs so they have
the experience there's actually bubbles
involved colors colors are involved not
we don't heavily color them again wanna
keep it as clean as possible but there
is a color in there of course
differentiate scents and things like
that lavender and citrus ginger and I
know granny when I offered her products
she loves herself Atlas caviar loves the
suppositories obviously you know
definitely dabs are rosin but she was
like yeah I'm not a bath person so
recently she she caught a cold and I saw
her on Facebook or Instagram on one of
her live feeds and I was heading down
this way so I just I dropped some stuff
off at one of her epic remedies one of
the local dispensaries that we do
business with and I know shops there and
we all do yeah I was just gonna say that
[Music]
I just dropped it off in texture and I
said I know you're not a bath person but
this will make you feel better and I
dropped they were wonderful relaxed I
was down with just my nose that's how
long I've done very cool I love watching
the girls on Instagram and YouTube the
[Music]
bath is more painful than it's worth
just because I know they have out there
what we need is a shower essential oils
and a few other things that bind it
together and make it pretty so naked
foam how much of the cannabinoids does
your skin develop develop that's nothing
what I wanted but I think you know what
I meant
yeah okay I've ruined everybody nobody
can find a granny and help us out
[Music]
there's no science that has I could
quote that I would feel comfortable
saying it's this kind of percentage
just from everything I mean your skin is
your largest organ right so it's
obviously when you get in a tub of hot
water it's absorbing a we know epsom
salts and those so it's just collecting
on and absorbing into your skin people
the effects that they have had is they
say that it's the best night's sleep
ever has you know I pulled my back I
took a bath in the next morning they
were able to you know I I believe in my
opinion that you know issues oils in
there essential oils as farce but
there's so all those things like they're
all made just a little bit different and
specifically but so yeah I mean it's
just those oils carry the cabinet's into
the skin all right so there's definitely
an absorption but to give you an exact
quote on percentage I have no scientific
see you think just personally do you
think somebody that did not smoke or
consume edibles or anything would they
pass a drug test from using a bath bomb
I don't know but we could probably find
a candidate to test you know somebody
that doesn't smoke they do you want to
drop a bomb on I have some curious
friends that are not cannabis consumers
that because again there's no high to it
you're not actually is there any key in
it at all from the CBD that your your
skin will absorb well yeah I mean that's
right THC one to see if they right yeah
you can buy a test at the grocery store
right I know one person that will be
down for it but I'll report back there
you go
that sounds fun if you can't find one
let me know cuz I know I'm very curious
because you said the skins largest organ
if our lungs take in so much right
hopefully hopefully all topicals I mean
they wouldn't work if it if our skin
bresenham's or pray excellent sources of
pain really especially in specific okay
do you have a topical a SAP
no that's that's out there you know I'm
not trying to recreate the wheel with
this company like our goal is to find
new inventive ways and connoisseur grade
type products but like we're not that
much more expensive than the big guys
that are doing BHO but so for a few
dollars more you can have something
that's completely clean if that's your
choice
I personally have smoked Vito I'm not
gonna be a snob like I've I'm not sick
and I don't have cancer so I can't make
that decision for somebody who might
have a more serious condition right for
me it doesn't affect me so I'm willing
to take that risk somebody else might
not want to have to take that risk so we
want to offer those people a solution so
sorry I got off point your beer going
beautifully Oh so topicals so like I
said I'm not trying to recreate it I do
have a topical that I'm wanting to bring
out I'm trying to go like I said
connoisseur great and I'm looking at
bringing out a body butter cool you
don't dry skin again yeah big effect out
here in the
it's it's sunburns and you know there's
already the topicals in the south this
will be something that not only
nourishes your skin smells amazing you
know it's that connoisseur great body
small body product so you can go to the
mall speed this to pay the same amount
of money or you can pay the same amount
of money and you can get it with
cannabis in it and it still equally has
all those effects but you'll get
additional effects if you have a need
for it that's awesome you can smell like
strawberries and watermelons so what
type of price point do the suppository
go for if somebody wants to think about
doing this I know you're not the
dispensary you're the distributor maker
so I want to say right around $16 that's
very affordable okay yeah exactly it's
all about what kind of what do you need
the medicine for like you know for
somebody who doesn't have pain buying a
topical why would you buy a topical
that's a South so it's all about
application and what you need it for in
my personal opinion is where you're
willing to spend your money do you know
of dispensaries in the Colorado Springs
Denver area where people can grab these
absolutely one of our favorite
dispensaries oh yeah for sure I actually
just swung through there right before we
did the podcast and I picked up a whole
bunch of dabble products from them we
grabbed it was so funny we went in there
earlier this morning and we walked in
and shout out to dusty in there because
dusty was like drop happening later come
back I was like cool so I just picked up
a syringe and I think I grabbed like a
Oh I grabbed a New York City diesel
shadow from them
you look like it looked it looked pretty
good in the container which is why I
scooped it but man when you open it
it is that's it right there it look
honestly like I would compare it to a
very well known and this is dabble no
yes no this is craft actually and I
would that's the first thing I said when
it came out I said oh and it tastes so
good dusty and everybody in there always
hooks us we are we're also the pen
market is huge the you know the vape
pens so we're gonna have a solvent let's
pen out soon so you wanted to know where
we are
yes man in the Springs area and again so
what I want to disclose before I give
you this list is not everybody carries
all of our products so you're gonna want
to contact if that's your suspensory and
ask um hey do you have their rosin or
their suppositories because some of them
carry some of it but not that may have
changed this will be all money so you
got a couple days right so a wellness
here in the Colorado are in the Springs
area the 64 store cannabis air tweed
leaf and grant farms stained glass is a
huge supporter I really like working
with them mindful elevations obviously
epic remedy we already talked about
enlightened care and I think that's
green meds is it just the Green Cross I
don't remember what green meds and then
we do have one partner that we're
working with up in Fort Collins and they
are just doing amazing things up there
and that's natural alternatives in the
Denver area we've got live green which
is patients choice on Colfax affinity is
on Colfax be good carries our stuff up
in north
Greenfields is another one and there
they have all these downtown akimbo the
and kind love the people the quality the
[Music]
best clones I've ever seen yeah we've
got a great team we're still small
company but we've got a great team Brent
our grower does a great job in the back
you know two owners majority owners are
really just doing a great job running
the company and I'm just happy to be
part of all of it and be able to to meet
people like you guys we're glad to have
you on to teach people about
suppositories do you have a Bible a
place where people can buy it by any
chance we do not yet
but please if you're in the public area
and you have a dispensary that wants our
product go in and ask for it I will make
it happen if but we I need you guys to
ask for our products and and that will
help me and I'm gonna go only a wreck -
we just went wreck not too long ago okay
but on the wreck side bird were limited
because
our grows not quite establish it on the
REC side for that first harvest so we're
only working on ancillary products being
bath bombs and suppositories can be made
so if anybody needs them on the wreck
site - of course happy to fulfill those
needs to start making the request you
guys don't have it on traveling stoner
and dab and granny and I'm not popular
so but on my Instagram there is a list
of all these dispensaries that you can
find that they've shouted out for me and
been so helpful to help promote for me
you brought you brought great content we
already following the traveling stoner
in the Davin granny but if you're not go
follow them find those lists of
dispensaries there are recreational
dispensaries on the list so if you're
coming from out of state if you're
coming from another country if you're 21
and over you can get these products you
can take the bath you can drop a bath
bomb in there you can get a suppository
you can put that where the Sun don't
shine you can see what we're talking
about you need to tell your dispensary
who to contact my Instagram name is s
serendipity 93 it's you know it says I'm
that I'm the CDC manager on their
marketing manager and whatnot so if they
can di mean they can Instagram me they
can call me directly whatever they need
yeah I'm definitely accessible they have
questions get in touch if you guys heard
that hissing sound that is not a deadly
Cobra that is a can of butane refill
over here needs a DAB I think you just
gave
I had to take a macro of it because he
just gave me the most is it a tourniquet
he put a piece of shatter then he dipped
it in the CBD and then he just coated it
in distillate and I'm like watching him
and I'm like is he gonna stop playing
jessalyn on it is he gonna stop playing
do it
this is ridiculous yeah most people
would be mad at us for this yeah we go
to prison for Kentucky Texas so granny a
minute ago you started a hint started to
hint to us I can't even talk I'm still
so high shot it to the Debs but anyway
I'm gonna get you talking about your
Vegas trip and I'm gonna take a dance
who is invited you and the grumpy
grandpa to Vegas this is something I'm
very excited about because anybody that
follows me on social media knows that my
husband is very sick but he's getting
better now that we got him off them damn
opioids and he's on cannabis he's much
better and he's come out of that
zombified pharmaceutical trance he was
in and beta glass labs out of
Philadelphia called me well two weeks
ago
and said granny you know what champs is
and I said I do I kind of would like to
go and they said well we'll fly you and
grumpy grandpa there together and I'm
like you're kidding me they said nope
we'd like to have the both of you come
out we'll put you up in a hotel that's
why I talked it over with my husband so
I hung up and I asked Kevin and he said
I feel pretty good even if I have to
stay in my hotel room I think you and I
can take a trip to Vegas nice very nice
so shout out to bata glass labs for
making this trip come true you're gonna
see some great glass and what did you
say it's been like five years since you
guys have taken any kind of vacation
because he's been so sick this is
amazing perfect time I've had lots of
good things come your way been doing
things correctly I believe you reap what
you sow I'm not out there to make money
I'm out there too while I'm out to
promote a lot of young artists that I
see here in the springs I'm out to help
educate about cannabis and I'm out to
have fun while I do it I think you were
achieving all three of those goals this
year things are coming to fruition
though and that's kind of cool like okay
guys tonight here we sit like I said we
had all those products on the table
something we didn't say shout out to
Clyde side edibles from Glasgow Scotland
all the way from Scotland
I got a care package yesterday of
edibles and t-shirts from Glasgow
Scotland
now I opened them up and everybody was
like God tell you what they're edibles
are pretty darn good that chocolate
marshmallow thing looked amazing it
looked very dense but man it was amazing
it wasn't heavy it was good I'm just
glad that it was only THC we joked about
some of us maybe be having possible
other I've still got these little
chocolate not chocolate EES hard candies
they are pineapple chunks made with Sour
Diesel cannabis they're 50 milligrams
per bag two point five milligrams per
cube the cubes are small oh and they
remind me of semester land I got on fish
so I was very apprehensive to eat these
I did not eat any all of my friends a DD
fen seemed to be okay they smell good
but they look those little squares look
very suspicious to me I mean that you
would be eating th the edibles and you
know I gotta say they have really big
balls in Scotland because not only did
they ship this to her but they had it
labeled right in their sweets and
t-shirts so then I said to him well I
want to know what does the said third
true Scotsman like me nothing its balls
in the wind
so these edibles were made by a dude not
wearing any underwear
[Music]
we should probably send him back a care
package I am not messing with something
from Glasgow Scotland it sounds like it
now these guys have a like it's like a
six foot bong if you're on Instagram
yeah you can tell the whole story too if
you can't okay
um if you're on Instagram you will see
this big six-foot bong and I will say it
looks kind of appealing and it's metal
and crystal and it's called Stanley kind
of like Flat Stanley it's supposed to
travel around to different weed people
and um I had messaged this company not
knowing anything about him saying well
Ken Stanley come to my house to review
and they said yes he could and then a
couple months later they said granny
wheat we can't secure Stanley I said
what do you mean you can't secure
Stanley
they said well we'll get back to you so
a month ago they say to me granny custom
grow 420 has Stanley and he won't
respond to us he will not give Stanley
back so custom grow is holding Stanley
hostage he likes Stanley he's not gonna
give Stanley back well that probably is
no big deal if your company here in the
United States I just go fine customer
zero 420 these guys are in Slovakia
which is the former Czechoslovakia so
there's no chasing I can't find custom
girl 420 but I'll tell everybody this
story we can tell everybody that follows
all of us on Twitter and they listen to
this podcast to send a message to custom
girl and be like returned Stanley this
company was so nice they sent me their
second bong which is called T OTE oh
it's very big it is an blown
Czechoslovakian crystal Bohemian crystal
how tall would you say it is from the
table well that's 24 inches tall
probably easily easily because if I
stand up the mouthpiece is right where
I'm staying and I pretty tall Jeff yeah
you are a tall lady so they sent me this
bong and I really liked it but I was
gonna get a bong shipped from Slovakia
only damn and Granny only Devin Graham
how does that I've seen the video on
Instagram it's real bubbly
that perk is like so it's just a shape
of it for us you told us how it looks
kind of like a big crystal liter 2-liter
bottle okay you bother and then there's
this metal perk that and it's all done
on the lathe they have a video up where
you can actually see them making it cuz
I know people are like ooh I don't want
to smoke on the middle I'm an old hippie
you smoked out a way worse yeah and
guess what I still use a bit like not
out meet you
don't bring your hip way toward me I
can't get you can't get your bow hot
enough to fill your lungs it's gonna
light the hem quick with the lighter and
then light my ball with the hip flick
and then shake that's too many damn
things get a lighter and smoke a ball so
it's like a three litre bottle with this
perk and then there's this great big
tall piece that comes up off the top
that you fill with ice gives hella rips
but it's not really practical
I mean it's heavy so once you put it
down somewhere it should States oh okay
it looks really heavy it's not and that
crystal is thick so I mean I think it's
kind of cool I got a bomb they should do
to you from Slovakia yes that's awesome
and then they thought I spoke Slovakian
cuz I was trying to be nice and I
googled simple Slovakian phrases and I
cut and paste and they replied with a
paragraph and I was like oh no I don't
speak Slovakia nice people they really
are shout out too long bong official yes
big [ __ ] I think bong is amazing I don't
say bong very much anymore actually
maybe the next time we say I'll have to
take it apart but they're screws to take
some assembly is required I'm wearing at
canna Canyon Bonner it sounds fun
please do please do right now on my
Instagram I got a really nice giveaway
going on with freaky smoke shop here in
the Springs have a email a rig that
Lindsey and I have been smoking out of I
I took a titanium pencil and I
sign the bottom it says peace davon
granny 2017 and there's a few other
Gibby's give a few other what do you
call them
I just wax why it's some more swag to
give away I think we all might be
medicated yeah when I can't even think
those simple words it's bad or is it
anyway so that is the giveaway and then
the one thing I want to say is I reach
250,000 followers on Instagram I've
surpassed that even though you'll be way
past I'm at 250 torti but that just
amazes me so I am going to be doing a
hell of a appreciation giveaway one of
the things that I know betta glass Labs
is gonna donate one of their palm breaks
to me and somebody I absolutely adore
here in the springs pop tea glass has
already blown a piece just give me for
the giveaway I bet I can get a few other
nice little glass blowers here in the
springs to give us some nice things so
just be keeping an eye out for my 250
giveaway and then of course I've got to
thank my sponsors gabato who's 420 and
I'm back to reppin mega Tok and I
actually like smoke and concentrate out
of it I'm done I'm gonna give a shout
out to elevate always elevate glass yeah
beautiful ladies and gentlemen elevate
dolls I think those dudes are dolls I
know I asked him what do I call you
what's up turtle hey maybe we should
shout out a few companies that we've
been getting our CBD from because some
of these companies even you people in
states that aren't legal you can order
CBD and so far they're still delivering
I can direct you to Empire wellness.com
I think anybody that sampled their CBD
tonight they're Terps are wonderful
they're good people they've helped me
get medicine
patients all dank distillate dad's here
in Colorado he he is still shipping
nationwide Trinity terpenes they're
still shipping nationwide and phyto
family they're still shipping nationwide
allegedly I believe even oh and in John
Ramsey what's his company in in infinite
CBD he still the time they want to get
CBD out to everybody shout out to all
the CBD warriors one thing I will say is
we've got a lot of great CBD
manufacturers I don't know extractors
whatever but then we also have a lot of
[ __ ] we have these CBD Wars where
they're all fightin and scratchin at
each other I won't deal with this I will
not endorse just one company I will
endorse them all yes they've got to be
nice to all our followers you can
probably speak yeah and I go over I get
the more I'm like well this is stupid
we're all doing the same thing let's
just chill out and be nice to each other
and do that there's room for all of us
us patients and consumers out there none
of you are going to go out of business
right absolutely I can smoke all of this
hash on this table guaranteed I needed a
provider for more have you tried that
one yet please do some of these
companies in their packaging are just
amazing this package is what else comes
in a package this size like toothpaste
almost yes the pad the product that
comes in it is
I'm trying to find something what else
is this nothing else is this sighs
nothing else is this small with
everything okay that's better
all right that makes more sense but it
wouldn't be consumer friendly so the
packaging so much garbage is what I call
it this is all landfill material unless
you recycle and I know a lot of people
that don't and you know what if your
trash company isn't gonna help you it's
hard to recycle let's let's admit it I
know you compost don't you I do what I
can but I can't compost everything yes
when you talked on your podcast about
some of the things and I was like yeah
but you don't smell it at all Jeff's
home is very pleasant oh it's a dude's
house it could use a accuse of cleaning
but you have a pink bathroom I want to
give a shout out to all my triplet
friends everybody's my friends at
handmade apparel yes I know I'm supposed
to do an ad for handmade apparel if you
guys need some printing done please do
please use me as a reference as well
about both of us if you need his
t-shirts if you need happens if you need
stickers I need some stuff printed you
want to look sharp how dope her the
colors on those hoodies you guys meet
they still look brand-new actually looks
in the back
[Music]
this is one of the original I region
etic shirts the very first batch printed
by handmade and it's probably it's just
now starting to kind of start weird like
it's crackling but it's like one of your
favorite concert t-shirt yes I bought a
lot of these shirts and I think most of
the extra extra larges went to me you
guys really should order one of your
girl from your heart these are these are
[Music]
Chris and I went camping for my birthday
we went January 2nd we got in the car
and we want camping and it was snowing
it was snowing it was 20 degrees that
night and I I warm the girl from your
heart podcast sweatshirt all night with
like probably like two layers underneath
it and that was it and I was so warm all
night like I was not I don't know issues
yeah super cozy hoodies so that's a
double advertisement right there you
guys shut it or friends and handmade
apparel check hands handmade apparel dot
biz and also if you need a hoodie grow
from your heart at hotmail.com you look
sexy in it it looks like what's that
girl from your heart
it's podcast bro we do we tell everybody
that when we go place yeah that's pretty
rad yeah and we tell people thank you
but the back is the best cuz you got
Rasta just it is super cheesy it just
makes you smile they gave me a really
friendly deal because of what it was
they're like dude we want to do this we
want to do this and like go for it since
we talked about all the other companies
that we were supporting yeah well I mean
I can let you guys know that my website
will be up and running at the end of the
month so my blog the blog portion of my
website will at least be up and running
at the end of the month the end of which
month food thing that's funny well I've
actually been working really hard on it
and it will be out at the end of this
month because I have nothing else that I
am working on right now this is the only
thing I've been working on didn't even
open look because we had so much to talk
about on the show my organic natural how
was the food drive you guys how did that
go do you know I actually the day that
they picked everything up I was at my
sister's wedding in Georgia so shout out
to granny and Sam and Bailey and
everybody else that Kat was helped Sam
Bailey and I and then the people at the
million house but when we pulled up in a
new hall and those people were on the
dock and I opened it up and she went
and I got out of the truck and I came up
and I said I wasn't going to tell you
until I got here but this all came from
the cannabis community and she goes
where did you get all this food and I
said all the food and there's toys in
there there's money in there and it all
came from dispensaries I'm getting my
hair in your face it made me so happy
and she was like you guys really made a
difference so we had a u-haul truck from
ceiling to floor front to back full food
toys there was some brand new kids hats
gloves lots of new toys yes and then
when I spoke with the lady I was so
impressed with this program and it's all
through the Marian house Catholic
Charities if you're not religious I
don't care do you know what I mean by
guerrilla chefs those metal show yes
yeah they had several of those different
categories and they have a lot of
displaced families they're trying to get
back on track the parents have to take
parenting classes which I think that's
good that's good because if you're young
you know I was young and dumb once do
you need help and we get a lot of people
coming here because of the cannabis
community and they don't have a plan
they don't have a solid plan in place
and sometimes kids get supper anyway
these guerrilla chefs have brand new
toys and if it's kids birthday they get
to come in and they get to pick
brand-new toys that's pretty awesome
they had so many brand new diapers you
can go down there and get if you need
diapers people you can go down to the
Marian house and get diapers there's no
questions asked diapers irks so I just
felt yes we did make a big difference
thank you for bringing that out okay
that seems like an eternity ago it was a
while ago but thank you for doing it
because of the smile on your face right
now is priceless
yeah really happy know that we helped
little kids faces when they little kids
know they can see it their parents don't
tell them but they know we live in a
thing and we are getting
it's not gonna be cool present and
they're like oh my god I got a
five-dollar dinosaur that made my day
and kids have to be punished for sure I
want to give a big shout out to Bailey
too for being a part of it and actually
I put up that post tonight that we were
doing the podcast and she comment on
she's like yes I've been looking for the
neighbor
yes she helped granny and Sam without
any questions asked on a day off and you
know she only she's a budtender at Rocky
Mountain medical over on Garden of the
Gods and you know she probably only gets
a couple days a week off and I'm sure
she has conditions that you know make it
hard for her to stay mobile sometimes
the last time they sent her home from
the hospital with a walker also big the
THC Samuel yes Samuel Sam has a lot to
talk about Sam was just out on the west
coast started down in San Francisco with
JD maple s'en these are all heady
glassblowers guys started down in San
Francisco worked his way up spent the
night with Derby homes and the Holmes
family and ended his trip with Bob
Snodgrass 85 in the school bus I mean it
was pretty awesome
Sam has on the show and he's the perfect
person for that like he just I love him
now when I say these are heady
glassblowers I don't know if any of us
sitting here can probably afford any of
these pieces
and I love you Sam hunt summon Sam text
me that he was at Derby homes in' and we
Sam and I have come to know the Holmes
family and he said with a carb cap and
the carb cap is beautiful so gorgeous
but I'm telling you guys that wasn't
like a five ten twenty thirty dollars
hundred no it's a beautiful die crow
it's peach its peach and then it has
these two green Leafs on it is a
gorgeous car Kevin it's a directional
flow like it is a Trinity it's signed
leaked gorgeous piece but these glass
blowers yeah that's a car sitting on the
Shelf right there absolutely we're gonna
get him on the show Sam and I both have
been survivors of head injuries a couple
more than me I was a youth but that
allowed everybody brought stuff to the
boxes again for this
honest to god this is what cemented my
relationship with epic remedy we had
lots of people that took our boxes but
this is what epic remedy did epic remedy
didn't care how many cans of new
food you brought in they gave you a
dollar per can off your product that you
were that's awesome yeah and after a
week I was like rants he's the owner
you're taking a hit and he goes I don't
care it's the holidays were giving back
to the community so shout out to Rennes
and epic remedy and back that dispensary
was in the poorest neighborhood of all
the dispensaries that was over in pikes
peak park over on circle and fountain it
is one of the poorest neighborhoods that
of any of the dispensaries but they
collected the most food yes Gail had to
go over there countless of times like
honestly we ran the thing for like about
three weeks right I was there probably
twice a week three times a week she was
going over there and picking up not just
like a box pool palettes like she had to
take the truck over there in the entire
truck was like every time I will get
like pictures and I just got back from
epic remedy shout out to uh seventh
floor when epic remedy called me the
first time and I Drive a Silverado so
the entire back of my truck was full of
food and I thought what am I gonna do
Steve said you can you have my warehouse
so he let us store all the food out
there for three weeks then when I did
get to you ha his whole crew loaded the
truck up so shout out to the entire
seventh floor vapes crew cuz they they
were phenomenal
what are we doing next working on
another food drive or something yeah
have to do something we'll talk about it
on the next episode when we bring granny
on again brainstorm Sam's coming up with
lots of good ideas too yes Sam's a
thinker kids head never stops he's like
me just bring keeps just spinning you
guys check out THC magazine finest cover
on a magazine ever yes we've got the
best style I don't know what that
whatever prints not the users glossy
it's available in Barnes &amp; Noble across
the nation so like anybody anywhere can
get it now I see you smoke blunts smoke
blunts so your friends can't be sitting
on the couch you got Ally broom on the
couch for me we're gonna break in all
these heavy pieces that I know he gave
you a quote Bronson's quote of the day
but it's still funny just know Bronson's
okay he's he's got this thick Bronx
accent what did you say and you just
kind of looked at me and I said say it
again call you people from New York say
sausages sit down with them again I hope
you get to be on the alien shows I
believe the traveling stoner and Bobo
just did an episode yes can I please
give a shout-out to daily bong
shut up to daily bong yeah daily bong
just had Kris and I on
wanted season two and it was actually
really funny because like we get there
and like you know he did he had messaged
me like honestly he messaged me a month
ago and he was like hey I'm think you
know I'm gonna be coming out into
Colorado and I'd love to get you and
your man on there I just really like
y'all's vibes and I was like that'd be
awesome we'd love to be on it I knew
about the show because of metal Damian
um so he he's on the show all the time
because it's filmed in Miami and so I
said yeah absolutely so then he messaged
me at the beginning of the month and
he's like oh I'm gonna be out there on
the 15th and 16th and I said Coolio so
we get there and I really I just watched
the show so I know that the way the show
goes is you sit in front of a really
bright light you wear sunglasses and you
smoke either like a joint or a blunt or
something and he asks you questions and
you just answer I mean like the
questions are you know in the bottom of
the of the like screen so I just knew
that we were gonna get asked questions
and honestly he had put up a picture
that morning and he had tagged a bunch
of people so I didn't really know how
how it goes so he doesn't let anybody
like be around each other when they get
taped and if you're on the same episode
and like you can get be in the same room
so we get there he goes oh your episodes
all about relationships and I'm like I
Stoneface I'm like you picked the wrong
couple what I mean like if that's what
you were looking for out of this you it
was really funny because it was like the
newlywed game style kind of like we
didn't even stay in the room with each
other and he asked us pretty much the
same questions and like to see how we
answer him and it was pretty comical to
be honest with you like I'm super stoked
our episode is was to come out at the
end of March where episode 4 of season 2
so he um text me yesterday did he back
here at the end of January and asked
would I maybe come up so I'm asking if
maybe you guys will take me yes
absolutely
daily bomb check daily bong shout-out to
them because they it was so much fun to
be honest with you he asked just like
I mean just I don't want to spoil our
episode so I'll tell you what's been on
other episodes and it was really funny
because I I was at the can of Canyon a
couple days before so you're gonna spoil
somebody else's up to season one it's
already up it's on YouTube okay yeah so
I was at the can of Canyon the other day
and I was showing Camille like the day I
was like yo look at what I get to go
into the other day like I'm kinda me
said she was the only person I don't
even tell granny like granny called me
on the way up and she said what are you
doing and I was like okay I'm going do
this really cool thing but I was showing
Camille this never is really funny
because the question was ice cream or
anal and the amount of like guys that
chose ice cream was insane like it was
so fun yeah and it was just mind-blowing
to me and me and camera both like I
can't believe how many people are saying
ice cream right now like this is
actually insane to me
maybe they thought they had to receive
instead of give like so some of the
questions are like what's your favorite
strain you know like so yeah it's just
really funny because he just asks you
these like question he doesn't ask them
in a certain order like there's no like
what's your name
where you from like it's not like a
gradual thing it's what's your name ice
cream or anal what's your favorite
strain like you know what I mean like
it's so back and forth like that so
would you just actually I can see it
right here so I think the cookies from
you guys at CGC Terps ac/dc Terps as
well smell amazing
[Music]
smells like your just because I'm brave
and I'm very curious what it actually
tastes like but it tastes good right
[Music]
white crack OG smells like green crack
what do you think the white is White
Widow
the white the white the white probably
yeah yeah I don't get me on that rant I
hate that extraction companies do that I
think that it should say the white and
green crack don't have the knowledge or
front like I have knowledge because I
have friends like you guys that pass it
on to me somebody might walk in there
they may be in the white is perfect
because we don't really know what can we
talk about sure you took a gram of
distillate yes some green crack in your
Brown crack and it made you bounce
around all day I guess for cleaning the
house or or just use a normal
suppository higher syringe a one thing I
will say about these syringes they're
good for cooking oh yeah yeah you wanna
put a little a little distillate in your
food like meatballs and spaghetti sauce
cocoa with some distillation oh I have a
different way make hot cocoa summit bars
Caleb did you see my picture the other
so awesome I've made I had some s'mores
hot cocoa made cold milk nice and creamy
I took a 200 milligrams Shum it s'mores
bar and great Oh marshmallow cream oh my
gosh I drank that all 200 milligrams
yeah they're made with pure distillate
good candy really good candy I'm I go
through these phases where I do and
don't do edibles and I think one of our
good friends may have just messed up my
edibles case I was back on the horse for
too long the next day like I feel really
good when I eat that wolves but the next
day I feel slow-motion and I'm a very
productive dude and I can't a little bit
but it's more it's more my body I feel
like I'm just weighed down my legs how
much are you eating way too much too
much yeah first time was your own fault
second time we didn't realize how much
that cake was really we tried to do [ __ ]
likes you know they were super polite
they all have learned that I'm a strict
vegetarian and they put bacon on the
cake and there was a specific section of
cake with no bacon and so they were
super polite about it they were a
trivias and fed me so I was like I'm
gonna eat this and it was super tasty
but by the next morning when I was still
high when I woke up wasn't what the [ __ ]
did they put in that thing and it was
TNT extractions and yes
not the extension cord Dwayne as well
both of them they're always together so
you probably you probably have you
probably just you know don't realize oh
yeah
but yeah it's shout out to them because
that cake was superb and the bacon that
they may owe his really good and the
hash that they make the bacon we're
sorry you're involved here and for you
listeners out there I know you hear them
silly ass
[Music]
and do too many - too many suppositories
you're gonna fall asleep you're gonna
wake up tomorrow you're gonna have a
weed over like Jeff's hungry so contrary
to the [ __ ] you hear on some of them
new shows on TV
you're not gonna overdose on cannabis
the only way you can die from cannabis
is if a ton of it falls on your head and
kills you and that's if you're eating a
pound and it lodges in your throat I
mean but who's gonna really or if the
cops kick in your door and kill you for
having it that way that's the problem
with cannabis police are more dangerous
than cannabis
jello is more dangerous than cannabis
all right you guys we've been going for
an hour and 35 minutes this is one of
the longest bodies yes there's no reason
to stop at the Contra conversation got
natural and wonderful is like I'm gonna
let this keep going but you look
exhausted over there
[Music]
they're so good you just we've talked on
the show that we need to buy edibles
that come with like package and package
B and a is medicated B is not so that
you can eat one of a and then four or
five of B to be alright because we find
ourselves we're actually looking at
doing one of our edibles being okay
lower THC yeah so we bring something
I'll offer something else so it's gonna
be a high CBD don't know exactly what
those are yet to be announced soon come
yes cannabis industry is always evolving
I love it I love how every week there's
something new we didn't have what's the
new thing V hi terpene what's the HTS
fer q hi terpene full-spectrum extract
[Music]
how he explained it to me
it's like drip sauce it's so it straight
sativa to the dome oh hell yes he called
it without the sugar okay it kind of
makes sense it's not like evil laughter
yeah well she got is just she got just
the the crystals by themselves and then
the sauce in its own file okay so she
got like just the top layer of turps it
just comes off in its own the vial just
like lemony skunky unbelievable miss
a bunch of people listening to them
check out my Instagram and that's the
traveling stoner on Instagram in the
mornings yes so yeah you can follow our
grow our Instagram we've got a gross
okay so like your commercial girl you
can actually check the progress that CGC
black label okay that's kind of giving
us a hard time on our concentrate side
so I'm still working on that but you can
definitely follow us and get in touch
with us through the tools just just
block them in this way if I control if I
need to bring it come on
[Music]
we can follow
yes absolutely I mean life as well but I
do all right
[Music]
thank you for helping thank you for
having me thank you traveling donor for
always putting things together I'm here
to help get everyone together one
yes this podcast is not out of reach
some people have told me they like dude
I'd love to be on your show but I don't
know what I would do you would come and
you would talk it's not that hard I've
got a chair I've got a microphone and
you just run your face we're gonna do it
without a microphone anyway so come let
me know what you've got to say if you
want to be on the podcast and you're not
crazy I mean you've got something
interesting to talk about send me an
email to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'd love to get all kinds of
people on the show open up the audience
open up the members the what are you
guys the guests open it up just teach
more learn more do more better podcast
come be on the show I'm gonna talk about
patreon and they were gonna wrap up the
podcast I would love it if you guys go
to patreon.com/scishow five cast you
guys the podcast will always be free
free freedom free cannabis lessons free
love I do it from my heart I can't shut
the [ __ ] up about cannabis this is my
way of putting it I love weed I love you
guys but if you want to throw a buck or
two my way you can go to
patreon.com/scishow to
patreon.com/scishow artists you can
throw down one dollar a month or you can
throw it on as many dollars as a month
is you would like what that will do is
it'll help me pay for my website I
region etics Colorado calm it is a
little costly to keep that website up
and that is where the website the
podcast is hosted so just help me pay
for that a little bit if you can if you
can I would appreciate it if you can't
do it I still love you high five big hug
fat dad's we're still gonna be friends
but there are a few people out there
they can certainly afford to throw a
buck or two my way I would appreciate it
we'll keep the podcast going we'll keep
it free forever for everyone so
patreon.com/scishow or from your heart
it's all I'm gonna say about that once
again check out handmade apparel dot biz
thank you everybody for coming gonna
wrap up the show big shout out to
everybody we always in the show with one
big shout out who's it going to this
time somebody throw me an idea
silence bigshot at the silence Brett
Brett from Evo labs I see him he's so
happy to see me and it's so genuine and
like I just love Brett and he is so
positive he wants to spread the most
positive messages about cannabis he's
just a good guy and it gave me a fat
sack of weed for my birthday that he
grew some lemon skunk diesel like he
knows me so well he gave me a fats and
he's like this is for you for your
birthday I was like you see unanimous
decision big shout-out to our friend
Fred from people I make sure you follow
on Instagram it's underscore Mary's
motivation Brett from evil a big shout
out better and it's all next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 177 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff wanna
thank you guys again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my podcast big shout out to cat
coupe and the entire Mystic Krewe huge
audience you guys the podcast was ranked
number 963 on stitcher stitcher hosts I
think they brag that they have fifty
thousand podcasts available on their
service and the girl from the heart
podcast was recently ranked number 963
overall listening on stitcher I wanna
thank everybody for listening also on
stitcher we were ranked number 80 in the
society and culture category so we were
in a top 100 section on stitcher makes
me super proud thank you guys for
listening for supporting the show iTunes
doesn't show me a lot of stats or
anything
iTunes doesn't give a [ __ ] so I don't
know where i stand on iTunes but on
stitcher we are crushing it big thanks
to everybody
also big thank you to everybody who
listened to the episode with solvent
list Shannon and dab and granny that was
a great episode also Lindsay and Chris
were here yes they did put some stuff in
there but I got a couple of messages
that said hey bro as soon as you guys
started talking about putting things in
your butt I checked out one of my
friends said that he was getting some
mental images and some visuals and he
did not want to contaminate his brain
like that so he listened to about three
minutes of the show and checked out I
apologize if that was too much for you
but thanks for everybody thanks to
everybody they listened to the podcast I
appreciate it
also big thanks to some unless Shannon
and dab and granny for coming and being
on the podcast I look forward to having
both of those ladies on the podcast
again and you know we will get the
traveling stoner and boba blaster code
back on the show real soon shout out
kids I hope you guys are doing well
let's see where else am i hand made big
shot it's my friends at handmade apparel
that's right this podcast is brought to
you by our friends at handmade apparel
if you need shirts hoodies any type of
clothing
if you need stickers if you need hatpins
any sort of creative custom artwork I
recommend my friends at handmade apparel
that's right check out handmade apparel
dot biz they make all of my gear they've
made my IRA genetics t-shirts they made
my girlfriend heart hoodies they make my
region etics hat pins I trust love and
support my friends at handmade apparel
checking out handmade apparel dot biz
let them know you learned about them
from the girl from your heart podcast
tell them Rasta Jeff sent you they will
take great care of you
alright I am pulling up a message on my
phone here but other things to get to
the message you want here we go my
friend Mountain smokes a few episodes
back in episode called follow your nose
and I talked about Sour Diesel and
Hispanic folks I felt like I may be a
bit racist calling about calling out the
folks of Latin descent for liking Sour
Diesel but I felt that was something
that I noticed and my friend Mountain
smokes
on snapchat sent me a message she said
oh my gosh the Sour Diesel bits so true
being from Gunnison County another
heavily populated area Sour Diesel has
always been growing in the basements and
it was by far the most popular strain I
sold their spot on that she also says
also love the podcast once again and yes
follow your nose so very true so thanks
for the message and big shout it's my
friend Mountain smokes on snapchat make
sure you follow her on snapchat she's a
cutie she smokes cannabis she's a great
cannabis activist and she is learning a
whole bunch and becoming very
knowledgeable and she likes to share
that stuff with her viewers on snap so
check her out and follow her ladies and
gentlemen I'm gonna get right to an
email I've gotten a long email here
about powdery mildew and I feel like I
can really give some help so I'm pulling
up the email while I while I talk where
is it here we go alright the email goes
like this yo love the podcast a longtime
listener hashtag love it when you ramble
shout out to white Mike why Mike you got
a shout out bro hope you heard that you
guys will get Mike back on the podcast
real soon he'll be here he's got a young
child he's got a wife he's got a wife he
can't be on every episode but we'll get
it back pretty soon
shut up bro I hope you're doing well the
message goes on to say anyways I will
keep this short I work at a commercial
scale cultivation site and we have been
fighting powdery mmm
do for a year now and would love some
help we have sprayed [ __ ] everything
and I'm starting to tap out it's indoor
and it's in the desert any thoughts and
then he signs it thanks and then his
name I'm not sure if he wants everybody
oh he does he says PS you can see my
name we out here
so thanks Matthias five eight five on
Instagram it's ma th hi u.s. five eight
five on Instagram follow him if he wants
you alright let's talk a little bit
about your powdery mildew situation
there are a lot of things we can spray
and things we can do to help treat and
correct this problem but what I'm mainly
concerned with is why is it there how
did it show up in the first place and is
it going to come back since you say
you've sprayed [ __ ] everything it
makes me think that you have issues with
the room obviously there is not enough
airflow you're not getting rid of the
old air you're not bringing in enough
fresh air possibly there are temperature
fluctuations there are a lot of things
like that that are going to be causing
problems are you running a hydro grow or
a soil grow if it's hydro you've got a
lot of water in there you're gonna have
to control the temperature if it's hydro
you may need to get some chillers and
cool the water because that'll prevent
the water from becoming a vapor which
becomes humidity which promotes the
powdery mildew if you're running with
rock wool cubes you may need to let them
dry a little more if you're running soil
you may be getting the soil too wet how
much water is in the grow facility
itself do you have water available to
evaporate to make condensation in there
that's gonna help you get powdery mildew
too much moisture too much water you
said you're in the desert so too much
moisture too much water the outside is
hot the insides real moisture treating a
bubble filled with humidity in there and
that's going to contribute to your
powdery mildew so you need heavy
dehumidification in that room you need
to get that old hot stale air out you
need to get some fresh air in you need
some ventilation hopefully you're
treating the air that's coming in that's
something we should talk about you need
to get that old stale air out stale air
out of course but there's fresh air
coming in that fresh air coming in does
need to be treated you need a filter and
also they make a UV light that is very
good at killing powdery mildew it will
kill any spores that come in they make a
light it goes over your ducting so the
duct
the intake ducting comes in and then
this light shines through the ducting
and everything that passes through that
duct is basically killed so I would use
HEPA filters on all of the intakes and I
would use the UV lighting on all of the
venting and ducting if you can if you
can pass all the air through one thing
and run a UV light over it that would be
ideal they sell things called clean
lights they're UV lights that are
designed for gardens they're mostly used
in like the strawberry industry because
strawberries get a lot of powdery mildew
on them they sell handheld versions of
these lights that you can actually walk
around the crop and shine this light
over the entire crop and you just run it
over I just basically want to illuminate
every inch of the canopy for about a
half a second to two seconds so you just
wave your hand waving my hand over it
right now like you guys can see what I'm
doing but it's basically the same motion
you make when you're watering you know
you just move your hand around back and
forth like a windshield wiper you do
that with this light and you walk over
the canopy and just make sure that the
light shines on every leaf and that
light kills the powdery mildew it takes
several applications of that light to
get rid of powdery mildew if you already
have it but if you're persistent with it
that will help so the room needs to be
corrected there may be some water issues
you may need some equipment some
dehumidification you need some air
exchange temperature control is huge you
can't have huge swings huge temperature
swings in the night and in the day are
going to cause powdery mildew issues so
that's what I think about the room let's
talk about the plants how far apart are
your plants are they touching if the
plant leaves are laying on top of each
other in that little space imagine if
before a sitting in a room and I just
put my hand on this sounds disgusting to
me but what if I just put my head on
your leg in my hot hand I'm 96 degrees
or whatever I am my head is just sitting
on your leg in about twenty or thirty
minutes there's gonna be a hot sweaty
spot there just from our body parts
touching and getting warm there's gonna
be a little bit of sweat in there that's
sweat that those plants create will
cause powdery mildew right there between
those two leaves and it'll start
spreading from there rapidly so
something you can really help deep
foliate heavily when I'm in a large
commercial facility we spend days just
defoliating sometimes it'll be
defoliation day you guys get super
stoned on your break because when you
come back all you're doing is pull
and leaves for the next eight hours just
pluck every leaf with the PDL out of
that room if you're I'm not sure if
you're the manager if you're the boss or
if you're the owner but if you were able
to pull every leaf that you can out of
there those leaves are where the powdery
mildew happens get it out of there so
that's what you can do for the plant
spread them out kind of take off all the
big leaves put some air on them fan them
around if the powdery mildew can't
develop because it's blown around too
much it can't develop if the humidity
doesn't stay stagnant the powdery mildew
will have a harder time developing so
let's talk about you said you sprayed
everything I pet your plants look pissed
off they got powdery mildew and you're
spraying them with stuff and they're
trying to fight the powdery mildew and
then they're getting [ __ ] sprayed on
them frequently but they're getting mad
I bet you're getting frustrated as hell
stay positive bro we're going to beat
this [ __ ] I'm curious what you've
sprayed because sometimes your sprays
are going to add more moisture it's
gonna add more humidity I've sprayed
commercial rooms thinking yeah I just
got rid of powdery mildew and I came
back the next day and the powdery mildew
is actually thicker drove me [ __ ]
nuts
so like I'm saying you got to fix the
room you have to spread the plants apart
if you've got a bunch of water on the
floor squeegee and shop-vac that [ __ ] up
get rid of that extra water so let's
talk about sprays what have you sprayed
I'm really curious um there is a product
called big-time exterminator that I have
heard works wonders on powdery mildew
it's organic and it is okay here's
something I should mention in Colorado
we are very limited on products that we
can use a lot of people will say go get
a bottle of Eagle 20 and spray that [ __ ]
right on your plants Eagle 20 will get
rid of your powdery mildew it may take
one application it may take two
applications but your powdery mildew
will be gone for 30 days maybe 45 to 60
days guaranteed I personally do not like
Eagle 20 there are a lot of deadly
dangerous shitty chemicals in there that
we do not need to spray on our plants
that we are going to call medicine to
give to sick people I do not recommend
eagle 20 in Colorado Eagle 20 is
completely banned we are not allowed to
use it in a recreational or a medical
facility that is regulated by the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
is a banned product I like that some
products are banned it keeps us safe it
keeps our growers safe
it keeps the consumer safe
we haven't done enough research on a lot
of these chemicals to know what's going
to happen to us if we smoke it and a lot
of these things affect your body in a
way that say I spray my plants with evil
20 today and we let them flower we
harvest them we cut them down that's
probably you know 50 to 60 days they let
them dry you smoke it there's probably
still evil 20 on those buds when I smoke
it I don't think I'm gonna notice
anything right away I may get a funky
taste my throat may burn but that's it
but I'm thinking that in like 10 years
is what I'm gonna notice the [ __ ] up
from that I'm gonna get a twitch my left
eye is gonna pop out I'm gonna talk
funny I might get a limp or even a
bigger fear maybe it does something to
my DNA or my RNA and my I'm not I don't
plan on having any more kids but maybe
you do maybe it'll [ __ ] up your RNA and
your DNA and your kids will come out
with three arms or three eyes or one
foot or 14 toes you know so we don't
know enough about what these these
chemicals kill mildews and they kill
bugs so it's doing something
biologically or something it depends on
what kind of chemical you're using but
it's doing something and it could be
getting into your body and [ __ ] up
your body by smoking it so we need to be
really careful I know I got way off
topic just kind of want to rant there
but if you want a spray eagle 20 go in
there hit that shoot with eagle 20
problem solved you got a little bit of
time to figure out how to fix the rooms
and then hopefully you can fix it again
and not ever have to use the Eagle 20
again I don't recommend that [ __ ] you
guys at all at all at all things that we
are allowed to use in Colorado a product
called big-time exterminator it's mostly
citrus oil or citrus it's citrus
something I think a citrus oil mostly
citrus oil extract it sounds like smells
like oranges it's kind of nice like
lemony smell orange II smell citrusy
smell to it I mixed that up I think I
put I did whatever the bucket says
there's an ingredients on the bucket go
the heavy route mix it up with some
water spray that right on the plants and
that stuff should calm down the powdery
mildew you may have to go for a few
applications of that that'll take care
of your powdery mildew another product
that I have seen work on powdery mildew
is 30 percent hydrogen peroxide I saw a
guy put 50 milliliters of hydrogen
peroxide in a five-gallon bucket and
sprayed that directly he adjusted the pH
and then sprayed that direct
on to the entire crop and you could
kinda see the hydrogen peroxide
breakdown the powdery mildew she sprayed
the entire crop and then he went ahead
and sprayed the entire room sprayed
everything down everything smelled like
hydrogen peroxide it smelled super clean
in there it took several applications I
think he was going at it daily but by
the end of a week the powdery mildew was
gone so you can use PM wash you can use
hydrogen peroxide you can use oh sorry I
didn't say p.m. wash there's a product
called PM wash which I haven't used it
but I've read great things about it the
PM wash should wash the powdery mildew
off of your plants so peroxide PM wash
and Big Time exterminator are three
products that you can buy you can order
them over the Internet you can probably
buy them at your local grocers those
products I'm told will get rid of your
powdery mildew I have seen the hydrogen
peroxide do it I've seen the big-time
exterminator do it it'll take multiple
applications you have to be persistent
you have to pay attention to the plants
they're gonna need a little bit of love
after this if you're gonna spray them
for several days with the products like
big-time exterminator or hydrogen
peroxide
I recommend give them a day of rest and
then spray them with push from our
friends at veg bloom they do not pay me
to talk about their products but push is
an amazing product it's a foliar product
it's a little hard to get it's a little
bit expensive but oh my god it's worth
every penny and if you're gonna do this
much damage and this much beating up to
your plants I think push would be really
helpful another product I can recommend
is a product called stylet oils silent
oil is not allowed to be used in a
recreational or commercial facility in
Colorado but I have used it myself and
it did take care of everything
a stylet oil is an oil that coats your
plant and it will not allow the powdery
mildew to grow on the plant it will not
allow fungus gnats to gather on the
plant it won't let mites get on the
bottom side of the plant nothing wants
anything to do with styling oil the
problem with styling oil is it strips
the cuticles off your plant leaves and
it leaves them really vulnerable and
they look a little leathery they get
kind of sad at you about it if you're
going to use styling oil I would if your
plants are small enough I would dunk the
plants into a stylet oil diluted heavily
don't go straight into the oil sorry let
me say that mix up some styling oil I
cannot think of the dilution
recommendations but it is
on the bottle go light dunk the plant
into the stylet oil get every leaf in
there give it a good wiggle pull it out
set it back in the grow area turn off
the lights let it dry give it about an
hour let all the plants dry after you've
dunked everything and then go back with
the sprayer and hose off every single
plant the stylet oil will dry and coat
and then you just want to kind of rinse
off the excess and all of your powdery
mildew and bugs should be removed within
the first application styling oil will
[ __ ] your plants up if they're not
strong it's gonna beat the [ __ ] out of
them maybe test a couple of plants
because it does beat your plants up
heavily but it will work I had almost
forgotten about the stylet oil where are
you located man I've got a huge bottle
of JMS silent oil that I do not think
I'm going to use if you're near me we
can work out a deal just [ __ ] I want
to see what happens when you use it
let's see where am I now another thing
that we can talk about our friend frosty
organics was on the podcast quite a
while back and he talked about lactic
acid bacteria spray frosty taught us
that he can make his own lactic acid
bacteria spray and apply it to the
plants and he says that one application
will remove his powdery mildew issue I'm
not sure how well that works I have not
tried it myself but I do trust the [ __ ]
out of frosty organics so if you want to
learn about lactic acid bacteria and how
to treat your cannabis plants with it
you can google lactic acid bacteria and
then powdery mildew and then there will
be the word Clackamas in there Clackamas
is a city in Oregon there's a guy named
Clackamas coot who is from that part of
Oregon who wrote an article about making
lactic acid bacteria to treat for
powdery mildew if you google it it
should not be too hard to find
as something else I want to mention in
professional horticultural applications
and environments what is commonly used
for powdery mildew is a product called
potassium bicarbonate it's available in
several different forms from what I read
they say that it makes this up very much
like a baking soda in water and you
apply that to your plants as a foliar
spray and that disrupts the pH on the
surface of the leaf which will get rid
of your powdery mildew and it is a
horticultural standard it's what they
use in large greenhouses for large
production so potassium bicarbonate from
what I read it's like it comes in a very
powdery form that's like baking soda
they say it's available in other forms I
check that out maybe that's something
that'll help you out if you're in a
commercial girl I'm not sure if that
will be legal so make sure you check out
all of the laws I don't know where you
are I don't know the rules so everything
I say needs to be researched before you
apply it another thing that people are
gonna recommend for you for your powdery
mildew issue people are going to say to
hang a sulfur burner in the grow and run
the sulfur burner for an hour or 45
minutes every few hours or something
like that everyone's gonna have their
own recipe I highly advise against this
you guys I do not like a sulfur burner
there was a dispensary in Colorado I
will not call them out they were in
Denver they were a very very well known
dispensary they had a very well-known
breeder working with them who actually
left and started his own thing that
facility was having a powdery mildew
issue and their solution was to run a
sulfur burner the results were for about
six months every time you would shop at
that dispensary everything would have at
first it was a flavor of sulfur it would
smoke it need like why does this taste
weird and it was sulfur II once somebody
would say I think there's a sulphur
burner your brain would go oh yeah it
totally tastes like sulfur so it was
really strong at first and over a few
months it faded out but you could taste
it for a long time they've gotten rid of
the sulfur burner they've corrected
their problem now it doesn't happen but
that's why you don't run a sulfur burner
in there it will make your plants taste
like [ __ ] so don't do this whole 4
burner that's not something I would
recommend something that you can do that
may help you
I'm not sure if you're using mother
plants or if you're taking plants taking
cuts from your vegging plants or how
that works but when you were taking
clones
I recommend dunking them I cut my clone
from the mother plant I put them in a
cup with water and a small bit of
nutrients and then I carried that cup
filled with cuttings to another area
where they are trimmed up then they are
dunked into a solution and then they are
dipped and then stuck into either the
cloner if I'm working at one facility or
they're put into plugs if I'm at another
facility or they're put in a rock wall
at another facility just depends on
where I'm working and who am working
away from what I got going on but after
the cut I like to dunk the freshly cut
clone and trimmed up you cut off the
leaves you trim off all the extra then I
dunk that right into something I will
change my eye product up sometimes I use
vanish sometimes I will use the what's
it called the big-time exterminator
because I wrote down BTE and I can
always forget that stands for a big-time
exterminator sometimes I'll mix up the
hydrogen peroxide just depends on what's
available and what I'm treating for what
I think may I may be at risk for but we
know that powdery mildew is the problem
here so mix up a little bit of hydrogen
peroxide in your water I just use a
five-gallon bucket I mean anywhere
between 30 and 70 mils of hydrogen
peroxide usually seems to work for me
cut the clone dunk that right into the
five-gallon bucket a hydrogen peroxide
give it a nice hefty shake and then put
that into the dip and grow or the clone
X or whatever you were using wherever
the hell we are
and then stick that right into the the
cloner whatever I'm going into and then
I know that I killed all of the powdery
mildew so that I've got a fresh start so
that that clone can root and have a
healthy start then as soon as it roots
and it gets put into its first pot I'll
spray it with something and then every
I'll spray it once a week with something
and then if I see powdery mildew or
here's here's a hint a little bit before
powdery mildew starts you will see
little tiny bumps pop up the leaf may
start to just get a little bit bumpy I
don't even know how to it just looks
like a little pimple or a war or
something funky coming up on the leaf
but it's real small so if you start
seeing that then it's time to start
treating for powdery mildew extra-strong
get out your UV clean light get out your
hydrogen peroxide get out the PM wash
the big-time exterminator the lactic
acid bacteria the
seem bicarbonate something like that get
it out there start treating those plants
because you're gonna see the powdery
mildew but if I see that that's when I
start stepping up my game going a little
bit harder one more thing I should
mention is the powdery mildew could be
on your clothes you're carrying it
around from the flower room to the
bedroom to the mother room to the clone
room it's in your air-conditioning ducts
it's in your HVAC system it is
everywhere it needs to be taken care of
it needs to be treated if you've got
those silly ducts that have the
insulation inside of them tear that [ __ ]
out of there I know that could be a
multi-thousand dollar job for your
facility but all of that insulation
inside of there is harboring harboring
that was a hard word to say the
insulation is harboring powdery mildew
and it will eventually be a place for
bugs to hide out once one gets in there
just takes two and those bugs will start
a party it'll be disgusting so you could
have the powdery mildew under close make
sure everybody's changing clothes
properly I bet you've got a grower that
has a private grow at home and he's got
powdery mildew also and as soon as he
starts getting rid of powdery mildew you
get it worse and then as soon as your
facility starts getting it cleaned up he
gets it worse and you guys are just
passing that [ __ ] back and forth and
it's never gonna go away
so start changing your clothes get some
dedicated clothes dedicated shoes a
dedicated hat if you've got long hair or
dreadlocks get it wrapped up get it in a
hat get it covered up you guys I'm
always going and REE tucking my dreads
cuz I try to keep everything covered up
I don't want dragging my dreads long
around the grow think it's gross I need
to be picking up bugs or leaving a hair
in the flowers just just keep your
dreads in your hair cover it up if
you've got a big man book beard or if
you've got a hipster beard cover that
[ __ ] up too I just try to be clean you
guys another thing I really want to
recommend I did work in a facility that
was riddled with powdery mildew I won't
call them out on a podcast most of my
friends and listeners know who the [ __ ]
I'm talking about the place was riddled
with powdery mildew they fired a grower
I took over I walked in and I said we've
got bugs and powdery mildew to start
with and they're like yes we do help us
I tried to get rid of it you guys but
being Emmy deregulated I understand the
struggle that my listener here has it
was a pain in the ass everybody in that
grow got sick because of the powdery
mildew the mildew is gone you guys it
took two or three crops
two or three crop cycles to get rid of
it but the
Romilda was actually done we got rid of
it in a hundred light facility that PM
was gone you could not see it you could
not smell it you could not taste it it
was cleaned up so they did their job
they got rid of it but everybody kind of
got like a scientist sort of thing
everybody showed different symptoms but
everybody could agree that it was
messing up their noses their throat and
their eye region so wear a mask if
you've got a ventilator or respirator or
even one of those just shitty little
paper Asian bird flu masks just wear one
of those when you're working with the
powdery mildew because you don't want to
get sick from it I tried to deny that I
was sick from the powdery mildew but
once it was gone I felt better and I
could tell that my allergy problem and
my throat thing was happening because of
that powdery mildew that's what was
doing it so please take care of yourself
if the plants are bad powdery mildew E
you have to think about if you want to
release that product to the public
because you don't want to be responsible
for making people sick so that's a moral
thing you're gonna have to think about
yourself something that they do allow
here in Colorado they will let you blast
the powdery mildew buds the marijuana
Enforcement Division has decided that it
is safe to put powdery mildew buds and
trim into a tube and run butane over and
turn it in to Pho a hash dabs
shatter wax it turns into distillate
eventually it gets put into edibles
eventually so yeah they're deeming it
safe so if that's what you want to do
with it do that that's the best I can
recommend with it but honestly if it's
coated in powdery mildew think about
this my friend Doug is getting old and
Doug's got a lung problem and when Doug
smokes regular cannabis he coughs
but Doug smokes cannabis that's got
something on it he coughs a lot and gets
really sick Doug is smoking because he's
sick and trying to prolong and save his
life we do not want to give Doug powdery
mildews and mycotoxins and funky [ __ ]
for his lungs to kill him more quickly
I love Doug I [ __ ] want him here
treat everybody like Doug okay everybody
that's getting cannabis is my friend
Doug in my mind we all have to take care
of all of our patients like they are
Doug
all right dougie was a real dude but I
kind of exaggerated his story Doug's not
that sick you guys just wanted to use
him as an example because he's a good
dude all right I hope I've given you
some information that kind of teaches
you how to at least control and harness
and get rid of this powdery mildew I'm
not sure what you can do where you are
so you can spray any of these products
that you choose to spray you can D
foliate things that I fully recommend
you do are get the old air out the fresh
air in dehumidifier do some filtration
also space out the plants a little bit
make sure they aren't touching each
other and then control temperature
swings you're in the desert and you're
putting a bunch of water inside of a
building you're making it excuse me
you're making a big Tupperware dish and
it's you're making a giant comb dome is
what you're doing in there so you need
to evacuate the humidity and get that
out of the room don't be afraid to throw
away some plants if they're starting to
get too bad I know that sounds terrible
in a commercial production facility I've
been there before trust me I have dealt
with what you're dealing with some days
it makes you want to punch yourself
straight in the face but I did an
episode a few episodes back called stay
positive and if you didn't have powdery
mildew it wouldn't be getting so many
hours should be too easy
wouldn't be a challenge wouldn't be fun
anymore so you got to go through some
struggles and that way when those issues
are gone it's gonna be like your [ __ ]
prison and the coolest damn facility
ever and you'll appreciate it that's
what I think stay positive don't pull
your hair don't put yourself in the face
keep growing and dude if you have any
more questions please send me an email
if anybody out there has any questions
about growing cannabis about smoking
cannabis about anything cannabis related
I would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I'm easy to get a hold of
I'm trying to catch up and answer all of
the emails and do episodes about all of
them but I honestly get so many that
it's hard to keep up but I'm getting to
your email a lot of people have asked
for episodes about beneficial insects
and pesticide manage our pest management
and identification of problems in the
garden I am working on that that's going
to be a long episode I may do it in
multiple parts I've got several pages
written already I'm still working on
that one I've got an episode coming up
about seasonal effectiveness disorder or
seasonal affective disorder since it has
been winter time here I want to talk a
little bit about that because I've got a
bunch of great stuff coming up a lot of
it has been listener inspired material
which I truly enjoy brain
to you has it been going for 28 minutes
I'm gonna wrap up this podcast I want to
thank everybody for listening big shout
out to my friends at handmade apparel
once again if you need t-shirts hoodies
stickers hat pins any kind of swag
printed up custom designs with super
high-quality printing and high quality
clothing make sure you visit my friends
at handmade apparel dot biz I would love
it if you follow me on the social media
I am on Facebook it's girl from heart a
podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast
and on Instagram you guys I post so many
photos to Instagram my phone is way over
loaded with photography right now so
instead of deleting the pictures I just
go shoot a bunch of them to Instagram
about once every two hours or so
whenever I sit down and take a couple
dabs I try to shoot a new picture up to
Instagram while I edit this podcast and
listen back I'll shoot a couple pictures
to Instagram follow me on Instagram it's
Irie underscore genetics ir i underscore
genetics it's my seed company i am a
seed breeder if you're aware of that i
regen etics colorado is me make sure you
check out our Instagram lots of great
high quality cannabis photography you
could see what I'm doing there once
again if you have a product you'd like
me to review or if you've got something
you'd like to say or if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast send me an email
grow from your heart at hotmail.com let
me remind you about patreon patreon com
is a service where you can go and you
can financially contribute to the
podcast I'm not trying to get rich I'm
not begging for money I'm just trying to
offset the cost of my web hosting so
that I can keep the podcast coming to
you for free this podcast will always be
free free freedom I'm simply asking
people to help me pay for my website so
that I don't have to pay for it out of
my pocket there are a few people that
are able to contribute
I truly appreciate it thank you if you
can't contribute I still appreciate you
I still love you thank you for listening
to the podcast if you can't contribute
financially one thing you can do to help
me out you can go to iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart podcast find the review
section type in a comment let me know
what you think about the show and I will
read your review on a future episode so
far everybody has given me a five star
review give me as many stars as you feel
like I deserve and I will truly
appreciate it you guys that's all I've
got free this week I was lucky enough to
get to see Maddie and Spence for a
couple of minutes at the canna Canyon
the other day they came to Colorado to
visit they invited me up
I got the hang out take some dad to take
a picture with Maddie I sure did miss
those guys so big shout out to Maddie
and Spence and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
if malware stick
see
[Music]
if you turn up be empty if it is
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for up so number 178 of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to create a new
grower if you're professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Ross -
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me as always I need to send a
huge thank you shout out to my friends
in the mystic roots bank letting me use
their music on my podcast just coming in
for a quickie I'm gonna release this on
a Thursday you're very welcome for
Thursday bonus episode before I get to
the main topic I want to do a little bit
of bragging I want to give a huge shout
out to my friends at organic organic is
a medical marijuana dispensary in the
state of New Mexico they are located in
Albuquerque if you are in Albuquerque or
a New Mexico medical marijuana patient
be sure to visit my friends of our
Gattaca because I bred a strain called a
rise arise is golden go to Daybreaker
these guys have our Gattaca got some
seeds and they grew the arise and the
arise has been testing consistently in
the high 20s to low 30s their most
recent tests tested at 32 percent THC
was 35 point 8 4 percent THC a and 32
percent THC it was tested by my friends
at steep hill lab congratulations and
big shadow and much thanks and much love
to everybody at org antica shoutout to
everybody that's [ __ ] amazing that
means I've got a screen currently I hold
the highest THC a test it's deep hill
labs with the arize I did not grow it
but I bred it means a lot to me it means
there's a lot of potential in the arize
and a lot of potential in the strains I
crossed with the rise mail alright so
big shout out to everybody there also
shout out to my friends at handmade
apparel that's right if you need some
t-shirts hoodies any sort of clothing
printed I highly recommend our friends
handmade apparel that's right handmade
apparel top is they are members of the
cannabis community they are smokers they
are dabbers they were putting together a
really cool event right now it is the
borrowed Derby
it will feature dinner and auction and
bar oh I cannot wait to see how it goes
I'm really proud of my friends at
handmade apparel if you need something
printed if you need stickers made if you
need hat pins made please contact my
friends at handmade apparel dot biz if
you were my facebook friend they are on
my facebook it's handmade or Adam hand
check those guys out truly appreciate
they look super sweet they printed my
eye region etics t-shirts they look
super sweet they have printed the secret
t-shirts they printed my hat pins
because these guys have put in a lot of
work for us and I will continue to use
them because I support and respect much
love to our friends at handmade apparel
all right this episode sure I need to
quit rambling I need to quit bragging
let's move into the main topic of this
podcast because this podcast is about
something called seasonal affective
disorder also known as sad also known as
winter depression I want to talk about
winter depression and feeling sad and
ways that some cannabis may help us out
with this um why do I want to come up
with a podcast about sad because lately
I've felt this funk in my head
I blending it on this weather I'm a
California person I'm from Southern
California I grew up right near the
beach boy oh yeah that was [ __ ]
stupid right but it's okay cuz I meant
it I'm seriously from the beach I grew
up 20 minutes from the beach I used to
go to Bolsa Chica beach I used to go to
Huntington Beach I used to go to Seal
Beach
I used to be all over the beach bro
lifeguard stand 23 at Bolsa Chica Beach
used to be the spots where the waves are
rippin it's where the kids could go do
whatever we want swear the I was a young
kid is where the older kids can go smoke
some dope even older kids are drink beer
nobody gave a [ __ ] what we did I'm a
beach kid
I missed that constant sunshine I miss
just that vibe I live in Colorado now in
about October November ish it gets
[ __ ] cold and it gets really dark the
days get really sure it feels like I
feel like the days didn't get as short
in California when the winter comes the
day's feel shorter in Colorado that just
could be baby being older or not being a
kid but it's [ __ ] with my head you
guys
these dark cold winter months you can't
go outside and do what you'd normally do
it's a little slower you got to get up
early for work you got a defrost the car
joe rogan put it best joe rogan said
there are states that are called he
calls them the [ __ ] states because when
you get in your car to go to work in the
morning you spend three or four minutes
sitting there going [ __ ] cuz you're so
cold your body can't do anything stomach
muscles tighten up your brain starts
twitching your neck gets all stiff and
you just gotta wait for the car to
defrost and so that you could drive to
work that [ __ ] sucks snow drives me
crazy I don't like the cold I don't like
the snow it feels to make me it seems to
feel like it makes me weak and slow down
it makes my bones and muscles hurt I'm
dealing with it I'm not enjoying the
winter I've got a lot of good friends I
do a lot of cool [ __ ] so don't let it
slow me down but I do feel it in the
back of my head gone bro something sucks
and it's just this seasonal
effectiveness disorder I wanna talk
about a couple things that winter
depression comes along with and then
we'll move into the cannabis part of
this I did a little research says it
usually lasts from fall to spring ish so
if you're feeling a little funky from
fall to spring this is probably why
especially if you live in these winter
colder climates some symptoms of this
seasonal affective disorder include
depression just basic depression it's
not your classic depression if you are
feeling like hurting yourself or
somebody else or if you've got problems
like that if you're thinking about
starting to drink alcohol or take pills
hurt yourself or cut yourself or break
something or be an [ __ ] to people
please get some help nobody's gonna
judge you nobody's gonna hate you we're
gonna love you we're gonna treat you
right if you wanna hurt yourself if you
want to kill yourself please call me if
I can send me a Facebook message
we'll talk call a suicide prevention
hotline call somebody I don't we
probably don't know each other too
personally if you're embarrassed to call
somebody hit me up I don't know you
I won't broadcast your business we'll
talk about why you won't hurt yourself
and we'll fix that [ __ ] that doesn't
need to happen so if you're really
depressed please get some help but if
you think you've got some winter
seasonal depression we can help you with
some cannabis suggestions another
symptom here would be some laziness just
low-energy
lethargy no no desire to get out of bed
you just want to lay around put some
blankets over you maybe plan your phone
and not do a damn thing losing interest
in life that's sort of the effect of the
winter depression
um a lot of people have no desire to eat
when this winter depression comes on but
oddly enough the internet says that
people will seek foods like
carbohydrates and such during the winter
which is odd for me because I always
like carbs I like pizza and pasta and
[ __ ] but it says that you're gonna seek
out carbohydrate type salty foods if you
were experiencing seasonal effectiveness
this order it says you're gonna be
agitated and irritable which I am there
that's partly how I'm noticing this I'm
partly I feel more tired I feel grouchy
I feel [ __ ] annoyed and I'm pretty
sure that it's mostly just this seasonal
effectiveness effectiveness order
another thing that the internet said
that I totally relate to and this is
kind of what inspired me to want to talk
about this because it's part of where we
are in this new generation this new part
of life
they said the seasonal effectiveness
disorder comes with panic attacks and I
think there's a reason for these panic
attacks that we're getting now as humans
we are too attached to our computers and
our devices and as humans we have become
completely lazy and complacent in the
winter I think that there's something
inside of me that gives me this trigger
to go hunt and gather food and build a
fire so that I can keep the family warm
through the winter but now we all have
jobs that don't require most of us have
jobs that don't require that sort of
stuff I work in a grower I put a grow at
6:00 in the morning I do grow stuff I
leave there at 6 p.m. I come home I play
on my computer I live in a house I Drive
a car my food all comes from a store I
think that as humans we were supposed to
we were designed and built to be out
there hunting our food we should be I
should be out there chasing down deer or
Buffalo and killing that [ __ ] and
dragging it in and then skinning it and
cleaning yes I'm a vegetarian but I'm
saying this this is part of why I think
humans are [ __ ] up because we're not
doing this there's something primal in
us that makes us supposed to do that and
in the winter that primal instinct to
survive becomes even stronger because
it's harder to survive and in the
environment where I am it's even harder
because it snows I'm not saying that I'm
in the worst conditions but I mean we
get snow and it's [ __ ] cold and if
you don't have shelter and food
want you will die out there so our
inside our instinct our natural design
is to be hunting and gathering and
you're supposed to be using energy and
adrenaline and that anger that you feel
you wouldn't feel that if you were
throwing a spear at another animal so
that you could survive you wouldn't have
time to be angry you wouldn't have time
to be depressed you'd be letting out all
that anger through adrenaline through
hiking through stalking an animal
through or maybe through gardening if
you were a vegetarian back in the
whatever times I'm talking about maybe
you had to spend all of that energy in
the garden and we're not doing that [ __ ]
anymore
we're sitting on computers and we're
playing video games and we're driving up
to a window to get our food I think a
lot of that is kind of what's causing
the winter depression for a lot of the
males I'm not sure if this affects women
the same way I'm not trying to be sexist
I just know it's a testosterone thing
maybe women want to be hunters and
gatherers also maybe women suffer the
seasonal effectiveness disorder for the
same reasons but differently I'm not
sure this part is my opinion the panic
attacks and the hunting rent is all my
my own opinion here but I think we
should be using our energy and I'm gonna
start talking about now about things
that we can do to help ourselves with
this seasonal effectiveness disorder I
already talked about being active
exercise get out there and do something
I hypothetically saying I feel like we
should be hunting we should be chasing
down an elk or a deer and then we gotta
kill it with either spear or a bow and
arrow a recurve bow and you gotta go
drag that [ __ ] back to camp and then you
got to skin it you got to get everything
out then fire I think being around a
fire makes me feel really good like a
campfire something inside of a campfire
really fixes me especially in this cold
weather so get out there and be active
build a campfire go camping go hunting
if you're that type of person be
physical something I can really
recommend to get you out of a seasonal
affective disorder kind of a funk is
join some sort of organized martial art
or fighting be physical use your body I
think a lot of what's causing this is
pent up body energy from the winter so
get out there and use your body go join
a Brazilian jiu-jitsu class go join a
martial arts class go be a
Resler if you're not into that go do
some yoga just use your body use some
energy I think it'll really help you out
so now let's start talking about before
I get to smoking cannabis honestly go
for a drive
put on some music and go for a drive
that always fixes my head when I'm a
little bit funky ah
put on your favorite music some reggae
whatever you're into if you're into some
metal put on some metal turn it up a
little bit to lime just go for a drive
that'll fix your head but I wanted to
say go for a drive before I start
talking about consuming cannabis because
Michael flip out if I say smoke a joint
go for a drive it'll make you feel
better so let's talk about other things
cannabis this is how cannabis can truly
help with the seasonal effectiveness
disorder I think that's smoking sativa
dominant cannabis either flowers or dabs
are going to help fix your mood I've got
a short list of strains here that I've
experimented with personally that I have
found to help uplift my mood and not
make me too anxious or jittery and still
allow me to function and get my job done
and still be like a normal person would
still have a nice buzz and nobody could
tell how high I am so on this list
number one on this list is Jilly bean
Jilly bean has always put me in a good
mood
it's uplifting it makes me walk with a
nice little pep in my step it puts a
grin on my face Jilly bean will wipe out
any anxiety depression it'll calm me
down and put you in a good mood
the next one on that list is tangi yes a
lot of people are gonna say jelly bean
and tangi are the same thing they're
very similar strains they have very
similar qualities they taste very
similarly they grow similarly I think
they both put a smile on my face the
next brand on my list is tangerine haze
from soma this is actually sohmas New
York City Diesel but there is a
phenotype that tastes very tangerine and
orange II that tangerine haze is always
been I used to call it my morning
breakfast smoke I'd be like I need my
morning oranges and I would smoke some
Selma's tangerine haze or his New York
City Diesel known as tangerine haze so
there's a group back in the day known as
a devil's harvest crew and they grew a
bunch of stuff and they found a very
orangey phenotype very orange phenotype
of the New York City sour
sohma's diesel and they passed that
around and called a tangerine haze
that's where it got the name and I found
the same phenotype out of a packet
grew it and I loved it and it always
used to put a smile on my face so I
think those top three that I listed are
very orangie very citrusy very sativa
yet very light strains when you smoke
them when I smoke them I don't get super
high I can't get high as [ __ ] off either
of those three strains but I can catch a
really killer smiley buzz so something
in that orange chirp is really helping
you fix your mood the next screen on my
list you guys is Cindy 99 shout out to
the Brothers Grimm seed company Cindy 99
has always given me a nice smiley
cerebral uplifting buzz it's just a mood
changer it gives you a little shift I
like it it's easy to grow I think it's
available again in seed form from our
friends at Brothers Grimm you can
possibly pick that up at the dank
team.com I'm another one that's always
uplifting and puts me in a good mood but
is sometimes too much for some people
this one may give you a little panicky
if you get a little jittery in too much
sativa this may be a little too much but
the jack herer has always been a good
strain for me it changes my mood it
gives me energy
it keeps me upbeat and it makes me
social but it can drive your head a
little crazy if you're somebody that
gets too talkative when you smoke too
much cannabis Jack may not be the cross
for you if you need to get social if
you're going somewhere and you're like I
gotta go talk to people maybe some Jack
will be the one for you another screen
that is always uplifting and puts people
in a good mood and you guys are gonna be
surprised that I say this because I've
made plenty of jokes about it but Blue
Dream Blue Dream is always a good strain
for putting you in a good mood for
changing your vibe it's not one of those
strains that makes you like want to curl
up into a ball when you get to high
because I've seen people want to do that
blue dream is you can't get to - blue
dream and it's a nice mellow buzz that's
why I make fun of blue dream I call it
stripper weed because it's that's how
high strippers want to get strippers
doing if I got high as [ __ ] like I do
strippers just want to get a little
buzzed you know spend on the pole I'm
just joking but that's why I called
stripper weed so basically any kind of a
haze cross you guys most of what I've
mentioned has a haze in it also Jack the
Ripper Jack Herer and Jack the Ripper
have a lot of the same parents Jack the
Ripper is a cross of Jack Herer I
strongly recommend some Jack the Ripper
but like I said about the hair it could
be a bit much for you you guys could
make some people's head spin if you're
not an experienced smoker so if you're
trying to beat seasonal effectiveness
disorder and you are able to take a
strong heavy sativa dose and you like to
get kind of whirlwind high grab yourself
some Jack the Ripper it's available at a
lot of dispensaries it's a great tasting
cannabis it has a great high to it and
it's usually pretty easy to find because
sub cool is a very popular breeder since
we're talking about sub cool I'm gonna
mention vortex I used to get some vortex
it was waxed but it was kind of there
was a different texture of wax from a
dispensary in Denver and I loved the
high from it it made me it gave me
tunnel vision high to where I couldn't
pay attention to anything except what
was right in front of me but it also put
this stupidest smile on my face I really
love the way that vortex made me feel
again vortex if you were not an
experienced vortex made my heart race it
made my heart was going but I love it
there's something about being too high
like that that I really really enjoy um
another strain that is good for the
seasonal affective disorder is the lemon
Jeffrey that's a golden goat cross -
it's actually lemon skunk crossed a
golden goat i bred that one it is one of
my favorites to smoke it has been tested
in the 30% range for THC it is
definitely a head changer something
about the orange and lemon Terps the
limonene Terps really create like a good
mood a good vibe so I think things that
smell like oranges smell like fruit
smell like lemons are usually going to
be uplifting positive vibe kind of
strains I think most of the haze crosses
and the tangi and Jillybean crosses are
usually going to be good to put you into
a good mood so those restraints that I
can recommend for smoking if they are
available where you are if smoking isn't
something for you and if you're not
getting the desired effect from smoking
edibles may be a better route to go body
chemistry is all different so if you're
trying to fight depression or seasonal
affective depression maybe you need high
THC maybe you need CBD I would kind of
stay away from the indicas what happens
to me and I have
go in history because now I smoke so
much and my tolerance is so high and I'm
older and I'm more used to being high
out of my mind when I was younger and
was new in cannabis when I would smoke
sativas I would get that real
psychedelic high and get talkative sort
of like I am now I'm just [ __ ]
rambling and talking about everything
but then when I would smoke indicas I
would go in my head and get quiet and
that's when you just sit in a chair and
you start thinking too much and I would
kind of sometimes you could drive
yourself crazy thinking too much when
you're already in the seasonal
effectiveness disorder kind of head
state smoking an indica that's gonna put
you into your own head and make you
think may [ __ ] you up a little more than
you need it may cause more depression it
may cause self-doubt it may cause
confusion it may not be the thing that
you need so I would go for some sativa
edibles or CB CBD edibles but I would
definitely stay away from the indica
dominant stuff because I think the most
reliable cure for seasonal affective
disorder is to smoke a joint and go for
a hike find a nice safe hiking spot roll
yourself up a nice joint of your
favorite strain either the Jilly bean or
some lemon Jeffrey or whatever you can
find that fits in the list that I talked
about it's yourself a nice sativa joint
roll it up take one of your best friends
with you take your dog with you get a
bottle of water go for a walk smoke a
joint and fix your head
keep in mind you guys it's okay to feel
this way everybody's gonna deal with
some [ __ ] in their life it's all right
to feel kind of funky once in a while
just don't be a dick try to deal with it
properly and pull yourself through it
hopefully when the spring comes you'll
start cheering up again hopefully by the
time 420 rolls around you'll be in a
good mood and then summer is coming back
and then it's time to get in a good mood
again hopefully you can figure it out
not go through it again next year are
you guys that was my quick talk on
seasonal effectiveness disorder I hope I
was helpful I hope I could guide you in
the right way to select cannabis to keep
you in a good mood hey even if you're
not suffering through some seasonal
depression all of these strains would
probably put a smile on your face keep
you social if you have to go to lunch
with somebody don't really care to go to
lunch with if you've got to do a chore
you don't really give a [ __ ] to do try
smoking one of these strains and just
might put you in a better mood for doing
it all right you guys want to thank
everybody for listening to his short
podcast this was right at 20 minutes I
appreciate you for joining me for a
Thursday bonus episode ladies and
gentleman if you have any topics you'd
like me
to talk about on the show send me an
email it's girl from your heart at a
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I would also appreciate it if you
follow me on twitter it's @gf yeh
podcast I want to send a huge shout out
to my friend bone Ellis and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
all right podcaster all I want to thank
you guys again for listening to a long
block of old episodes I would love it if
you'd email me and let me know what you
think about these old episodes the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to stalk me
on social media you can find me on
twitter at g f YH podcast and you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the grow from your heart podcast I hope
everybody out there has a great weekend
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a fad
dab and give your mom a hug for me
you