yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends in the mystic leaps band for
letting me use their music on my podcast
big shout out to cash - and the entire
mystic roots crew
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure you
noticed I did not mention an episode
number at the top of the show I'm not
sure if I put out Thursday content or
not that's right I have ran out of
throwback Thursday episodes and I'm not
sure if I'm going to put together a
quick Thursday show for you so since
this came out on Monday if you did get
Thursday content you're welcome and if
you did not I apologize
by not stating a number at the top of
the episode I do not create any
confusion and I also get to dodge all
the internet trolls do you want to tell
me that I did something wrong so thank
you guys for joining me no matter what
episode number this is you guys I am
dabbing on some concentrates I want to
tell you about I have got some sour Clem
for my friends at apothecary and it is I
don't say this word often but it's
[ __ ] amazed balls this concentrate is
one of my favorites I've grabbed in a
little while this batch is super nice it
is sour Clem batter they take their
ambrosia which is their proprietary
texture it's got crystals and terpil
liquids in it it's really nice but I
prefer the batter
they take the ambrosia and then they
simply whip the [ __ ] out of it to a
battery consistency it looks like a
little bit of a bright orange cheesecake
or bright yellow it's yellow goldish
orange cheesecake or cake batter is the
texture honestly inside this little jar
but the smell coming out of here the
aroma let me hold it up to the
microphone maybe you can smell it
through the mic is that coming through
your speakers because it is delicious it
smells so it's sour clam which tells me
it's probably Sour Diesel and Clementine
the Clementine comes through strong with
that sweetness but there's the sour
comes through also it's like sweet and
sour dankness it's got a hint of that
dryer sheet sort of smell and I'm sure
you've heard me explain the smell of
dashes dryer sheets before but that's
true petaline is the the terpenoid that
smells like that it's a really it's a
good thing it smells like somebody
wrapped a Sour Diesel nugget in a sweet
dryer sheet smell it sounds like it may
not be the most pleasant but if you
could smell it it is so great you guys
this is amazing so the texture is nice
also it's a it's a slightly firm
Cheesecake batter is the texture over
here so what I like to do with it I like
to take the sour Clem batter I like to
take all of the batters
the truth and I like to dip it in the
high cannabinoid full-spectrum extract
crystals so I've been taking the sour
clam and I put it in the extreme oranges
crystals and that is a super great dad
that's why I'm in such a good mood
that's why I'm all rambling I hope you
guys are in a good mood also I hope
you're listening if I'm rambling I hope
you're listening is that some [ __ ] it is
now it's my podcast can make up words if
I want to all right you guys thanks for
joining me before we get too far this
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at the Hell a dank seed bank that's
right if you need to add some seeds to
your lineup I highly recommend the hell
a dank seed bank at dank seed dot store
they've got all the fresh I read
genetics drops so check them out at dank
seed dot store I'd speak in a dank stuff
I recently found out that the crew at
rare dankness listens to the growth from
your heart podcast in their facility
while they're working I don't know if
they're listening in the grow I don't
know if they're listening in the trim
area I don't know if they're listening
in the package area I don't know if it's
being played in the retail area but
wherever it is being played I am honored
thank you guys the rare dankness
facility is the most impressive most
well thought out most well-designed and
most well-run facility in Colorado in my
opinion to the best of my knowledge
there may be something bigger better
badder shinier out there but I don't
know what it is I haven't seen or heard
of it yet so somebody pointed out to me
so I can be [ __ ] amazed but they're
listening to my podcast in that facility
and that means a lot to me it means a
lot because Scott is a pioneer Scott is
a leader in the industry and if his crew
is listening to me that means I'm doing
something right because they've got all
the knowledge they need at their
fingertips Scott is a weed wizard Scott
is every bit as qualified to educate and
talk about cannabis as myself if not
more Scott used to be on the forums
Scott's wife used to be on the forums
and I used to read their posts and learn
from them I'm sure they were reading
mine and learning from me as well but I
was learning from Scott and now Scott is
Scott's crew I don't know if Scott's
doing it personally but Scott's crew is
listening to my podcast and Scott's grow
so that's an honor to me that means a
lot to me I'll quit gushing and rambling
about it but huge shout out to everybody
at rare dankness if you guys are ever in
Denver make sure you check out the house
of dankness they were voted the best
dispensary on the planet by High Times
Magazine so drop in see what they've got
going on all right you guys I've got a
couple of emails I would like to read
the first one goes like this what up
Rasta Jeff I just dropped 20 dollars
into the patreon account hey guys that
is a good way to get me to read your
email right away on a podcast just a
hint anyway he says thanks for all the
grow info and entertainment on the G fyh
podcast one quick question I remember
you talking in the past about mixing
different pest control applications with
other beneficial additives can you
review some of your best practices keep
twisting them dreads and smokin the
bread thanks brother then he signs the
email chef dho of cut of cush culinary
in Los Angeles so chef dho is correct I
have talked about mixing different
pesticides and different beneficials
into a sprayer and applying them at one
time that's called the tank mix um that
is very doable very reliable it's
actually a common practice in the
agricultural world if you're really
working on keeping pests out of your
garden the best way to do it is through
multiple modes of attack which is using
different types of pesticides that will
attack in different directions if I stop
on your foot and punch you in the nose
and stab you in the stomach all at the
same time you're not sure which to block
so if you come at your pests the same
way they're not gonna want to come
around you need to hit them with
multiple modes of attack and figure out
the ways to develop the least amount of
resistance the way to do that is to mix
multiple things into a tank and spray it
at the same time now you can mix a lot
of different products you just have to
be careful and make sure that you're not
going to cause a chemical reaction so
before you mix anything into a tank okay
let me let me back up before you even
start playing with pesticides read the
label carefully on every pesticide you
are going to use
read the application rates read about
the personal protective equipment that
is required that stuff is very serious
ask Elijah Elijah was exposed to a
pesticide and his whole body broke out
in hives and he was itchy and he had a
fever and he looked uncomfortable and
scared that was a very minor exposure
we don't know what the long-term effects
of that exposure was it happened
immediately he touched the pesticide the
[ __ ] grew on his skin it went [ __ ]
crazy we don't know if something's gonna
come up in the future from that he
should be fine
but he could have problems and we do not
know it so please be very careful with
personal protective equipment where
everything requires pants and long
sleeves and gloves where at least that
wear eye protection as soon as you go
before you pick up a bottle you should
have eye protection you could not have
the lid on all the way and shake it and
put that [ __ ] right in your eye you
haven't even thought you were gonna
unscrew the bottle and you've already
[ __ ] got stuff in your eyes wear eye
protection please wear extra personal
protective equipment you can't go too
far what's extra goggles a respirator a
bunny suit extra gloves how can that be
a problem cover-up excessively if you
need to so no matter what you're mixing
use the proper personal protective
equipment also read the label of
whatever product you were using read the
application rates read what to do if you
get it in your eyes read what to do if
you swallow some of it see how dangerous
the product you were working with is see
how toxic it is see what kind of
problems it could cause you maybe if
you're alone in your gardening let
somebody know that you're going to apply
these pesticides and that maybe if they
don't hear from you an hour in an hour
somebody should check on you do
something like that just to be safe
I seriously know a guy who was mixing
his nutrients and got a product in his
eyes and had to call 911 he had to
unlock his phone with his thumbprint and
have Siri call 9-1-1 and come to his
house and help him and the first thing
they wanted to know was what did you get
in your eyes I was the first question
they asked and he said it's the bottle
on the counter so have the bottle if
something goes wrong don't put the
bottle away have the bottle out to where
if something does go wrong that you can
get the proper help I don't want
anything bad to happen to you but if
something does happen we want to be able
to help as quickly and effectively as
possible so have the bottle where it is
findable if you're mixing several
bottles leave those out until you're
done until you're I know it sounds weird
Lee Miller done I want you to make a
mess but leave them out so you're done
in case something goes wrong somebody
could say maybe he was using this pile
of bottles right here just trying to
help yourself out so read the [ __ ]
label you guys that's always super
important use the proper protective
equipment now if you're going to mix
pest
sides find the application rate if it
says use this many milliliters per
gallon pour yourself a half a gallon of
water into a container use half of that
or half of the dosage pour it into there
mix it like you're supposed to give it a
couple of minutes to emulsify let it get
in there now if you're going to add
another pesticide or another fungicide
apply that and half the rate that you
intend or at half of the dosage
recommended on the bottle or half of
whatever you're gonna use per gallon put
it in the half gallon of water mix it up
see if those two things do anything if
it makes gas or bubbles or sizzles or if
it burns your lungs arise get rid of it
I don't know what you're gonna do
hopefully you're doing this outside but
get rid of it safely you don't don't
want to apply that [ __ ] to your plants
you've only got a half a gallon to work
with maybe a quarter gallon is smarter
for this but I don't have a quarter
gallon container but be careful test it
before you mix it together in a large
batch you can probably mix most of your
common pesticides together but a lot of
them are oily and it's gonna get really
thick if you go mixing a bunch of things
what this listener is asking about
mainly he said remember me talking about
mixing different pest control
applications with beneficial additives I
know what you're talking about I will
mix evergreen or a Xamax and I will also
mix push from hydroponic research or veg
bloom it's veg bloom as they're
accompanied and it's made by hydroponic
research I all mix push in there with my
pesticides um I will do and now this is
where you have to read you have to read
the program or the product label and see
if there's something in your sprint your
one product that is going to destroy the
other product let's talk about powdery
mildew this is a very good example that
I can come up with off the top of my
head powdery mildew
early in Flour I would spray powdery
mildew with cease and double nickel
those would be my two go-to products to
take down powdery mildew cease and
double nickel this is great information
write this down if you'd like I would do
45 milliliters of cease per gallon and
45 milliliters of double nickel per
gallon and I would spray it and I would
use kind of an aggressive I use a paint
sprayer and I would put it at sort of an
aggressive setting and try to hose the
[ __ ] out of the plants and knock that
p.m. off and also be straight and leave
so what the cease and the nickel are
doing is they are beneficial bacteria
that will leave a layer on the plants
and disrupt the growth of the powdery
mildew these beneficial bacteria do not
harm the plants or people and they won't
cause the problems that the powdery
mildew will cause and they will not
allow the powdery mildew to colonize on
your plants so you're applying bacterias
that are helpful and they will destroy
the bacteria we do not want there okay
now later in Flour you're gonna if the
powdery mildew gets thicker you're gonna
want to use a product called zero tall
zero tall is it's a mixture of basically
vinegar and hydrogen peroxide and it
smells like dirty feet and [ __ ] and
a gym and it's disgusting but it
dissolves powdery mildew on contact it
has to touch the powdery mildew but it
will dissolve it it will destroy it
unfortunately it also will destroy
double nickel the beneficial bacteria in
double nickel would be destroyed by zero
tall but the beneficial bacteria in
cease will not be destroyed by zero at
all so you can mix cease and zero tall
in a sprayer together and apply them but
mixing nickel and zero tall together
would be a waste of your money so those
are things to think about when it comes
to mixing pesticides and fungicides now
the zero tall you spray that on the
plants and it basically destroys the
powdery mildew that's there and since
it's a vinegar and basically hydrogen
peroxide it's not exactly what it is but
it's what it smells like and that's
basically what it is since it's those
two products they dissolve and dissipate
and break down and disappear very
quickly so then you can destroy the
powdery mildew with the zero tall and
the cease application and then you can
go back in a couple of days and you can
actually apply the sea
and double nickel again to colonize and
help keep down the powdery mildew if you
feel as you've knocked it out with the
first zero tall application if not go
back with the zero tall maybe increase
it a little bit but not too much
I do the zero tall and the c s--
application again and hopefully you can
get that powdery mildew under control
but those are things you can mix
together see some double nickel you can
mix those together ah double nickel and
zero tall wouldn't work for you see sand
zero tall that's gonna work well for you
other pesticides that I have had good
experience tank mixing together have
been things like venerate ah double
nickel and push that is a very good
spray for preventative for almost all
insects I also like I'm trying to give
away too many of my secrets here but I'd
like to share some stuff okay here's a
good example of an actual spray that I
would apply to veg plants that has a lot
of products in it but will work for you
I would do
should I tell you how many milliliters
sure 15 milliliters of Evergreen 50
milliliters of push from veg bloom
30 milliliters of venerate 45
milliliters of double nickel and 2 mils
of cal-mag per gallon now I know that
sounds like a lot of products but you're
gonna be hitting pests from multiple
angles and then spray them again in a
few days and actually switch out the
Evergreen and switch that for a Xamax
and then drop the venerate and switch it
for botanic garden max and that way you
were hitting at every angle and then
you're switching so you're not getting
any resistance and that's gonna take
down just about any bug infestation in
your veg plants now we are spraying
pesticides we have got there's evergreen
in there which is a whatsit pyrethrins
we've got venerate in there which I
don't even remember the active
ingredient in there we've got the double
nickel which is a beneficial bacteria
which will prevent powdery mildew and
also pisses off spider mites but then
we're adding the push the push is a what
did you call it a beneficial additive
the push is a beneficial additive the
cal-mag is also a beneficial additive so
we're mixing those in right on in with
the pesticides when I was a new grower I
would want to spray multiple things I
was like well I want to spray my plants
with this I don't even remember what
product it was but I was like I also
have to hit him for pesticides which
means I have to hit him today and
tomorrow with the full of your feed I
didn't even realize I could just tank
mix all that [ __ ] so it took a long time
for me to realize you could just mix it
all into one tank mix it up maybe put a
little Coco wet in there to make it
stick to the leaves a little bit better
and then just blast it on the plants all
at one time now something you will need
to think about ah some oily products and
sulfur products will cause you problems
don't spray all of the plants right away
maybe mix up a small batch with a pump
sprayer with a hand sprayer and then go
spray one or two plants with your new
product and see if you're gonna destroy
anything because it is plant sensitive
in his grow room since it if I don't
know the health of your plants that
you're starting with so be careful makes
a test batch spray a test plan
spray your plants in the dark if you've
got one plant that you're gonna test
spray pull it out of the grower area get
it away from the whites spray that plant
by itself make sure you wear all the
personal protective equipment that you
need and I highly recommend that you
write down exactly how many milliliters
of each product that you used and write
down the date that you applied those
products also since I'm on this trip
think about what you're spraying I only
apply products that are approved by the
Colorado Department of Agriculture and
the Colorado meb I have a personal grow
that is not part of the meed grow that I
still use those practices in any
personal garden that I help with that I
run myself or that I set up I encourage
everybody to follow meed and Department
of Agriculture guidelines because that's
what we're going to have to do in the
future anyway so I guess to make a long
story short yeah you can tank mix a
bunch of [ __ ] together just test it
first and test it on a test plant before
you spray the whole garden you guys I am
NOT some sort of cannabis wizard or weed
genius or ganja guru I have simply tried
a lot of [ __ ] you would be amazed I post
pictures of great things on Instagram I
post pictures of my successes I talk
about and brag about my wins I don't
share my losses my losses [ __ ] see
I'm gonna leave that one right there I
don't share my losses and my failures
with you guys so you've got to keep in
mind for every three cool things you see
that I post there were probably 10 or 20
things that I [ __ ] up and that's how I
learned how to do those 3 cool things so
don't be afraid to expand your knowledge
by [ __ ] up a little bit if you make
mistakes and you learn along the way and
you are making mistakes because you're
trying new [ __ ] you're not making
mistakes you just haven't found the
exact way to do what you were thinking
of yet so if you're learning to ride a
skateboard and you're trying to do a
kickflip you'd have to learn how to
ollie and get that board up off the
ground and then once you got it up off
the ground you gotta learn how to flip
it and then once you get it flipping you
gotta learn how to get your feet back on
it and land it up those first hundred
kick flips are gonna suck and you're not
gonna know what you're doing but you're
not failing you just haven't got there
yet
you got a land one
and then once you land one now you can
do kick flips and now you just got to
perfect it
so start throwing them kick flips in the
girl you guys quit skating in straight
lines cuz your grow is never gonna look
any different it's not gonna get any
better your skills aren't gonna advance
you're just gonna be doing the same old
thing forever start throwing some kick
flips you're gonna crash a couple of
times you're gonna fall down you're
gonna get a bloody me but you know what
Falls what happens when you fall down
when you're growing weed you kill a
couple plants if they're all my way you
gotta buy more dirt if I can try it
again
it doesn't hurt nearly as bad is when
you crash when you're skateboarding
that's my pep talk for today you guys
alright let's continue with the podcast
I've got another great email hey I want
to see a huge thank you to my friend
chef dho of cush culinary in Los Angeles
chef you threw down $20 in my patreon
account thank you dude I appreciate your
support if anybody else out there would
like to send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
also if you'd like to check out the
patreon campaign just go to
patreon.com/scishow
need help and it goes like this first
off thank you for all you do for the
community you've helped me in a lot
you've helped me a lot in my pursuit of
good wholesome natural medicine okay now
for my question dude first off you're
very welcome thank you for listening to
the podcast I'm glad
ah that I was able to help you in your
pursuit for natural wholesome medicine
so the question goes like this I have a
real problem when it comes to anxiety
what strains would you recommend for
dealing with this affliction I've had
folks tell me this and that but I really
don't trust what they've told me I've
done some research myself but I just
wanted to know if you know anyone
personally that battles with this and
what they use any help would greatly be
appreciated
thanks again in advance and then he also
says you answered an Instagram question
for me once before hey Senor Smith I'm
glad I was able to help you out on
Instagram thank you for the email and
I'm glad I'm able to get this
opportunity to help you out again
because this is something a lot of
people deal with anxiety seems to be
sweeping our nation or community or
world everybody is getting anxious and
why not because the world is getting
[ __ ] crazy right now I understand why
people are anxious I'm anxious you asked
do you know anybody personally that
battles with this and what they use yes
me dude I am anxious I am a nervous
[ __ ] wreck sometimes I know why it's
cuz I've got a brain injury ah and also
some things in the past to give me
anxiety
I've got anxiety so I know how to talk
about this before I get into
recommending strains for your anxiety
let me save it
not all people have the same body
chemistry not all strains work the same
for all consumers I like really strong
sativas for my anxiety but I've got a
traumatic brain injury and sometimes I
feel like the thoughts start on side a
and just will not connect to side B and
somewhere in the middle there the
[ __ ] telephone line is just crossing
and the information is just not getting
to where it needs to be and it starts
making me anxious and I get weird and so
I will smoke a dab of really high THC
really strong dabs and I will feel that
tangled telephone wire in my head I'll
feel that [ __ ] unravel and all the
connectors go hum now I know where I'm
supposed to be going and all the
information can travel down the right
pipeline so for me it's things like
lemon Jeffrey really helps out a lot
almost anything lemon flavored the lemon
Terps really seemed to work well for
that and orange Terps ah extreme
tangerines screamin tangerines extreme
extreme oranges tangi ah Jillybean those
are things that really work for me
I've got a very dear friend who I don't
want to call them out and say their name
but somebody really close to me has an
anxiety issue and they smoke the
Clementine and the Clementine is what
they say stops their anxiety from
happening now those are strong sativas
that seem to work for me and somebody
else
I'm not sure your body chemistry
some of those sativas are going to give
people anxiety and if something if you
smoke Jillybean or lemon Jeffrey or a
Clementine or something in that realm
and it gives you anxiety then you're
gonna have to try something at the
opposite end of the spectrum I would try
LA Confidential cataract cush ah
something in that room kosher cush and
those are all three from DNA genetics
but they're the opposite end of the
spectrum there gonna be more sedative
more chill you out more relax you more
put you on the couch kind of weed what I
think about smoking the sativas and the
limonene and the Turpin alene Terps
they're so uplifting then it just
changes my mood to where I can't even be
anxious I'm just in a good mood and my
mind is firing so fast that I can't
stick to an anxious thought that's just
fresh like oh good mood well I was
anxious oh no I'm not I'm in a good mood
I'm so high off this lemon Jeffrey dab
that I'm in a good mood and so that it's
just motivating and uplifting I feel on
the lemon Jeffrey Jillybean tangi
Clementine a lot of strains like that
the fruity orange II kind of things work
with my anxiety
some folks are gonna need that indica
stuff and I'll repeat those strains I
said kosher cush I said what else did I
say cataract cush
and LA Confidential are the three from
DNA genetics that I think would work for
you if the other end of the spectrum
doesn't work now you've got another
option if the sativa and indica 's don't
work for you you can try CBD you can
find CBD isolates or you can find CBD
heavy flowers strains that may be heavy
and CBD are Tora Bora and Pennywise
those are two really popular CBD strains
also there's the ACDC which is really
popular for being a CBD strain I'm sure
there are more out there things evolve
everyday but you can get CBD isolates
you can get CBD flowers you can get high
CBD concentrates you can get CBD
teachers you can get CBD everything you
can imagine just make sure it's coming
from a source that is reputable and it's
actually CBD and not some imported
Chinese fish oil because you don't want
to take random chemicals from other
countries get some quality [ __ ] but so
those are things I would recommend and I
know that that is not a direct science
or a prescription but that's the thing
about cannabis and that's the thing
about our bodies and that's one of my
favorite things about medicating with
cannabis is when you go to the doctor
they say you've got this condition you
take this pill this often at this rate
and they think it's gonna work based on
everybody else's body and yes most of
those prescriptions will work at that
rate at that dosage at that interval
because they've done science to figure
that out cannabis doesn't work that way
the thing about cannabis is we cannot
you can't kill yourself with cannabis so
you are able to be your own guinea pig
and find out your thresholds you can
find out I need six dabs every 22
minutes and I need to smoke a sativa and
you can administer your medicine to
yourself and you can perfect your
regimen and you won't kill yourself and
you can stay pain-free or anxiety free
or whatever free and you can be happy
that's one of the greatest things about
cannabis the downfall to that is I can't
tell you smoke a quarter gram dab of
jellybeans every two hours you're gonna
have to dial that in yourself which
means unfortunately maybe you're gonna
go smoke some lemon Jeffrey and it's
gonna [ __ ] you up and give you the worst
panic attack and I'm sorry if that's
what has to happen
but remember that and then don't ever
smoke limit Geoffrey again if that's the
case then smoke LA Confidential and see
if it helps see if it is if the LA
Confidential makes you lazy or lethargic
or maybe it makes you creative and
psychedelic and puts you in a good mood
but you're gonna have to try a couple
things at the opposite ends of the
spectrum and see what works for you I
wish I knew your body chemistry better I
wish I knew exactly what to recommend
I've believed that in the future once we
figure out what we like I know what I
like I know my favorite Terps I know how
much THC I like I don't know exactly but
I mean I have a good idea of what I like
from the labeling that I've experienced
and from the consuming that I've
experienced I've got a good idea of what
works for me
I believe in the future we'll be able to
go to our dispensary and we'll say hey
can I get a gram of this concentrate you
hole you'll hand them a card and he'll
hat it'll have your mix on it it'll say
like ninety-seven percent THC with two
percent tur pennilyn and one percent
limonene and then he's gonna give you
this perfect homogenized dab and you
just feel like that's exactly what I
needed but still to get there you're
gonna have to experiment and figure out
what you like and what works best for
you so like I've keep repeating I don't
know the exact prescription or
recommendation for you I would start off
by smoking flowers of multiple different
strains just take one or two puffs I
don't know how experienced you are in
cannabis but I would definitely start
light smoke a couple puffs of one strain
pick one and stick with it for that that
session you know what I mean go buy a
bag of jellybeans buy a bag of lemon
Geoffrey buy a bag of LA Confidential
buy a bag of cataract cush smoke them at
separate times so you can tell exactly
what each one is doing do your normal
day if you go to work and then come home
and take off your shoes and take a poop
and take a shower and pet the dog after
that routine happens smoke your ball
then do the next thing
routine tomorrow do the same exact thing
smoke your bowl compare the two effects
see if the jellybeans made you giggly or
paranoid and see if the LA Confidential
made you lazy or paranoid see what
happens
write it down if you're able if you've
got a partner ah that you can trust
they will take notes for you a lot of
times I think it's cool cuz your
girlfriend or a lot of times your
companion will want to be involved and
they like taking notes and things so
that
they can that's a way you could bring
them in on this is have them kind of
observe and take notes about your
progress and see if they feel like you
were nicer or better to be around or
maybe they had to talk you down and help
you out or something but it may be fun
to have somebody around to take some
notes for you
alright senior Smith I feel like I've
rambled a lot about your email but I
don't feel like I've answered your
question directly I apologize that this
is not something I can just answer
really directly this is gonna be based
on your brain chemistry your body
chemistry which flowers you choose it's
gonna take some dialing in so if you
want to message me try the strains that
I recommended and if those don't work
for you or if they're not available
message me what is available in your
area and I will talk to you personally
and we'll see what we can dial in to get
rid of the anxiety because anxiety is a
[ __ ] and nobody should ever have to
live like that
alright senior Smith thanks again for
the great email I look forward to your
response let me know if I helped you out
at all ladies and gentlemen once again
if you'd like to send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to answer your questions on a
future episode before I start wrapping
up the podcast I do want to give a few
shout outs I should owe a shout-out to
John B Adam K Steven P and Zack s also
let's not forget chef dho of cush
culinary in los angeles shoutout to
everybody for the support thank you I
appreciate you ladies and gentlemen I
would appreciate it if you follow me on
all the social media check me out on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast find me on Twitter at
G fyh podcast and on Instagram I use my
other company name I use I read genetics
it's i reaiiy are ie underscore genetics
I read genetics on Instagram check me
out there check out all my fine cannabis
photography if you'd like to contact me
and your not into the social media you
can simply send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I've said
that a lot of times this episode I want
your emails grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also since the throwback
Thursday episodes are all caught up
they're gonna
are falling out of the feet as well so
I'm putting up more episodes on YouTube
go to youtube search for the girl from
our podcast 155 inch episodes are
currently there more or coming soon you
guys I'm releasing them as quickly as my
computer will produce them let me remind
you about patreon one more time check
out patreon.com/crashcourse am ii
chanclas and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me