[Music]
[Applause]
yeah what's going on podcast World
welcome to episode number 29 of the Agro
culture podcast I'm your host and they
call me rosted Jeff thank you for
joining me for another episode in this
episode Clinton Adam come by and we'll
talk a little bit about cannabis and a
whole lot about comedy so I hope you
like that before we get there I'm proud
to announce that this podcast is brought
to you by Highly Educated titanium if
you're using highquality concentrates
you deserve a highquality titanium nail
made in America don't trust a chinese
nail or an American knockoff made of
cheap Metals trust the industry leader
trust Highly Educated
titanium Highly Educated products are
available at aqualab technologies.com
High educated has an nail to fit any rig
and they are the only titanium product
endorsed by this
podcast this podcast is also brought to
you by Natures green remedies.com visit
Natures green remedies.com for gaag
green genetics llata Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Aventure iy
genetics and many more trusted Brands
Nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code September 14 for 15% off
any order and you always get free
shipping at Nature's green remedies.com
this podcast is also brought to you by
our good friends at hyro indoor growing
supplies hro indoor growing supplies has
two locations to serve Colorado visit
the Denver store at 6271 Beach Street
Unit F or stop by the Pueblo location on
618 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
check out hyro for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor grow
supplies the show is also brought to you
by our good friends at tree thug.com
tree thug.com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree Thugger
[Music]
docomomo make the show possible I don't
want to spend too much time on a long
intro so here's the part where Clint and
Adam join me hang
on all right guys we are here we're
hanging out with Clint and Adam I think
everybody knows Adam he's been here a
few times Clint has been here a couple
of times uh he was a non-smoker the
first few times he was on the show but
now Clint has converted to the dark side
Clint is now a pot smoker so
congratulations welcome to the team hey
thanks for you guys that do not know
Clint uh he is a comedian or an aspiring
comedian he's just a silly open micer
that's right uh he's actually been
hosting the Open Mic at a local bar
called Phil's radiator uh when is that
and how has it been going bro uh every
Tuesday every Tuesday every Tuesday
about 9:00 p.m. and um come out it's you
know it's just a place to try out new
new jokes you know it's I think it's
great um we've been getting mixed
reviews as to who's coming down and
stuff but I I think it's starting to
blow up it always takes a little bit to
get stuff going in this town where is
Phils Phils is uh peblo Colorado uh C
Street and Union yeah Union and C or D
whatever it is down yeah right there
you'll find it go downtown it's the spot
with the nice outdoor patio uh do you
guys do comedy inside or outside right
now inside um it's just they got to
stage and stuff oh nice what time do we
need to get there to sign up if we want
to be on the stage if you want to come
be a comedian uh try to get down there
by 9:00 and even then I'm not going to
hold you against the Kohls if you're a
little late we'll get you on it's it's a
good time have you performed at Phils
yet Adam oh no I've not performed at
Phils uh not yet I went down there last
week and just saw the show and it's it's
a cool place man cool um good beer and
Adam's got dreams of uh doing some
standup comedy he's done a couple of
shows unfortunately I didn't make it but
I've heard he's uh it's all right he's
shocking is what I was told
uhoh I guess that's better than
shitty yeah for sure it starts with the
same letters though so they may be may
have been being nice to you buddy hey no
I I've heard what your act is we're not
going to go into it here if you said
that on a show that is shocking bro uh
that's big balls so if you guys want to
hear some guy with big balls talk about
funny [ __ ] go see Adam the next time he
gets his big balls ready to perform
somewhere oh boy yep now you got to go
do it yeah that's what I got to go do
Phils radiator Phils radiator Tuesdays
Tuesdays 900 p.m. it got all like
monster truckish on awesome brag Tuesday
Tuesday Tuesday Adam and I and another
hot friend uh Monday night I am so
pumped yeah so it'll be the night that
you guys are listening to the show
probably we are going to go smoke
cannabis with Doug
Benson yes we will be getting Doug with
high we're not on the show but we are
going to be doing actually getting high
with Doug it'll be fun yeah Doug Benson
[ __ ] lit yes uh if you guys are
listening to this on Monday this will
come out Monday the 15th uh Doug Benson
is at Comedy Works in Denver tonight the
last I checked it was not sold out uh
Doug Vinson is well worth your drive to
Denver go check it out I will be there
uh there will be a smoke session
somewhere and uh it'll be your chance to
smoke with rosta Jeff it'll be a good
time if you show up and Doug Benson who
is [ __ ] hilarious hilarious my
favorite weed comedian probably the most
popular weed comedian oh definitely I
mean you listen to one of his podcasts
almost every week and and then I watch
the uh the other one just about every
week so we have two different tastes you
know what I'm saying but we still we're
still right there yeah uh Doug Loves
Movies is one of my favorite podcasts
shout out to Doug Loves movies I guess
go listen to that one when the show's
over you'll love it movies and pot
comedy and then if you only have a few
minutes for a podcast Doug Loves minis
is great uh it's a perfect short little
show uh I listen to it when I take a
shower he does about 15minute episodes
that's long enough to throw hit play
jump in the shower clean your ass get
out dry off and get dressed got about 15
minutes for a guy perfect love it so all
right so Doug we've promoted you we need
you to start promoting us going to say I
just we just went on for like a minute
about Doug Bon we're just we're just
pumped top of the episode we've been
going to Comedy Works quite a bit and
man there is nothing like a good show at
a good comedy club that Comedy Works has
it freaking correct you went to we
bragged on the show about seeing Joe
Rogan Clint went the night before us and
sat front freaking Row dude really I
don't know how that happened they let
your hairy ass up there that was they
weren't filming that night yeah they
just let us up there of course they
wouldn't have let my ugly ass up there
dude when they were filming uh they
would put decent looking people up front
but then a sexy young lady and a guy
showed up and they no had no problem
telling those people sorry you have to
move and they would rece you and then
this girl in like a tangerine or Melon
colored shirt with giant boobs and a lot
of makeup and you could tell she was
they go oh front row and they just
walked her right up to the front row and
put her in the front like they had no
problem making people move Dan Rainey
and uh Matt Chapman were at the show and
they kind of got put up towards the
front but then they slowly moved them
back to our SE they mov five times Jesus
I sat they sat me down we got to in line
kind of early like maybe 30 minutes
before the doors were supposed to open
so we were in line pretty early and
that's they just let us in and then the
group ahead of us was like of six dudes
and there's only seven front row seats M
so so like they had already had most of
that so they're like all right you guys
go to the back and I don't know if it's
like an ideology of like they're going
to want to talk more cuz there's six of
them yeah you know I'm going to be
talking louder there's only two me and
my buddy Riley we go up and we thought
oh second row that'll be cool and the
guy goes hey there's two more front you
guys want front I go yeah I think I do
yeah yeah and then that's a cool place
to be front row like I'm really hoping
we get there good on Monday Joe Rogan
does a a beard joke and it felt like it
was directed at me uh I I did you guys
get that joke too I don't know I don't I
did not get a beard joke he did a
Grateful Dead joke and I felt as if you
were staring me directly in my eyes
telling this Grateful Dead joke and I
didn't say that to anybody but on the
right home the girl I took with me said
he looked you straight in the face when
he said the Grateful Dead joke yeah was
like yeah he was talking about Duck
Dynasty beards and oh he might have
mention Duck Dynasty yeah yeah but that
yeah yeah sorry I mimed part of his joke
I really don't want to give it away be
on Comedy Central here not that long we
got to go to that show [ __ ] him and I
were in the taping dude see and I I
didn't want to be in the taping honestly
you know I would rather not next time it
was stressful uh you couldn't go take a
piss and I didn't have to piss but just
telling me that I can't go take a piss
now I have to piss it's like you're just
like I can't well suddenly I need to pee
yeah now I'm going to be sit in I had to
pee the whole time he was on but I was
like I'm not leaving no food or drink
service during the entire show they came
took our beverages everything you know
the Comedy Works they have a menu
hanging from the chair in front of you
they took that they took the pen uh they
made everybody take off their hats yeah
it was no logos like I said they were
moving ugly people to the back of the
room like definitely intense back row
they sat me under a camera like the
camera was right above my head that's
why that's why I feel like a couple of
the jokes Joe was looking me in his eyes
telling them to me because gave him
right yeah the camera was above my head
and it made it feel instead of talk to
that machine he could just talk to me
and it felt a little more natural cuz I
was high and laughing my ass on dude
yeah see I was just laugh it was a good
time I'm sure is a fun place man like
it's just yeah we went for a walk after
and uh it was fun having I had a lady
friend with me and I had Adam with me
and it was fun cuz a dude walked up and
recognized me he's like hey man are you
that guy I was like I am rosta Jeff from
iy genetics and we talked about seeds
and stuff yeah he ever get a hold of you
and you know I don't think so okay well
you're listening out there brother Phil
was his name so what's up Phil if you
contacted me yet uh hit me up on
Facebook send me a direct message I'm
taking Flyers with me to Denver Monday I
don't care what you say okay all right
we've only got a couple few left we may
need to go to Kingo and get some printed
all right we got with me uh we need to
give tony hinchliff a big shout out I
don't know if we talked about Tony
hinchliff on the podcast we've talked
about the The Joe Rogan show but Clint
got to go to so I'm re excited yeah Tony
henchcliffe nailed it dude that is one
hell of a comedian it was really but you
could still see yes he's been doing
comedy for a while but you could see uh
another step when you watch Joe Rogan
not to say that Tony hinchcliff wasn't
great because that's that's what I like
seeing I like seeing guys that are
better than me because I can go oh I'm
not the big fish in the Little Pond I'm
a little fish in a little Pond quit
being a like get better but that's what
I get to see like when we bring guys
down and they're they've been doing it
for like 5 years 8 years 10 years you
get to see like oh that's where I want
to be but it was stage but seeing Tony
HED cliff and I don't know how long he's
been telling jokes I know he's 30 he
said yeah um you listen to The Joe Rogan
Experience well yeah that but he also
said it when he was talking about being
did he do his uh knit cap bit Yeah he
was he was like I'm a 30-year-old man in
a knit cap a nitat yeah but you're right
yeah I listened to him on Tony uh or on
the Jo Joe Rogan um but it was it was uh
magical live dude I don't know I just
put my [ __ ] [ __ ] in the microphone to
do that it was weird I'm sorry I turn
this way um no uh but Tony henchcliffe
was on par yeah definitely [ __ ] he's
got some really good jokes but and I
mean not only that but you say Joe Rogan
killed it I mean as a comic to be up
there for an hour Jesus yeah you know
and I me and him talked about it
afterwards you know he was really
nervous you could see the nerves at
thees thought but then the lady heckled
him I heard about that you told me as
soon as she heckled him he came out of
the like nervous thing went away and
he's like what [ __ ] and he kind of went
off on her for a minute and when he came
back to the set he was on point from
then on I think that Heckler kind of
helped him out kind of helped him and it
brought the crowd and him together
before before that there was a a barrier
between the performer and the crowd
because called cameras yeah yeah that
tension in there affected our laughter
and his performance but once that
Heckler all of that we became one yeah
that's uh does Tony henchcliffe and you
guys can laugh your asses off if you
want does Tony henchcliffe slightly
remind you of Ina Luhan yeah he's got
the look The really mellow calmness you
can't shake him nerves of Steel just
kind of feels like his you know he's
kind of always up here you know hold his
hands and slightly a hipster I don't I
don't know what I I I looked at him and
I I didn't think that he
felt like like he was having fun he just
like his sense of humor is so like yeah
it's kind of like this and so it just it
wasn't I wish he'd had been having more
fun while he was telling his jokes they
did invite him back for a weekend so we
got to pay attention to when Tony Hench
Cliff is coming to comedy work go to
that yeah I'd love to see I'd love to
see more than how he probably did 20 did
about 15 when we saw him i' say yeah so
I'll let's talk of Comedy I guess I'm
going to keep going uh Sunday night I
went to the Oddball Comedy Fest the
Oddball comedy tour with Hardwick uh
that was amazing was he like headlining
it was he the no he was actually second
uh Lou CK headlined there were nine
comedians I think there were Brody
Stevens was the host and he said nine
comedians he must have been one of the
performers that he counted cuz I can't
think of who the other the others were
it was uh Brody Stevens Whitney Cummings
Chris Hardwick Demitri Martin um
Hannibal
baress uh Sarah Silverman I'm gonna
forget somebody because I'm on the spot
Mark
Marin uh did you say Louis already
somebody and then Louis CK who was
before yeah Jo Rivers
it might have been Jones that set was
quite stale I'm going to Google it
because I feel bad missing somebody on
that list where's that losing Price Is
Right theme when you
need I'm looking for it I really want to
get it right cuz I feel bad um we read
the list I mean Red Rocks seems like I
haven't been down there yet but it
definitely I saw the picture posted and
sorry as who I'm forgetting how did you
forget aiz whoa cuz you're so
little no aiz was great uh I think
everybody got 15 minutes but I think
Louie may have gotten it seemed like Lou
did 30 minutes and if you're a comedy
fan uh we've gone on for a minute but
you'll get this part every single second
of Louis set was calculated he knew
where to where to breathe he knew where
to take a couple of steps I don't think
and I'm not a comedian but I I've paid
enough attention to you guys I'm friends
with all you comedian guys and I've paid
enough attention to what you say and so
I get it now and I could feel every
minute of him he crushed it dude always
be crushing was Louis's motto that night
[ __ ] awesome he was killing it dude
on it I I need to see him now yeah now
just just to see his mannerisms but
you've performed you know so it's it's
also performance you understand like
when the singer does it in this note it
sounds a lot better than this note
that's like one octave higher or
whatever being the drummer my thing is
to play less if I overplay as a drummer
then you sound like you're insecure when
you learn to get older and play less
notes it's when you sound better and I
think Louis has learned each note
perfectly Lou I and honestly not to
sound like an [ __ ] he was one of the
comedians I was not most excited to see
yeah haven't you seen him before no I've
never seen Lou CK perform before I've
never seen any of those guys perform
live before was so I got to see n the
world's best uh Aziz was good really
high energy uh stuck to the same joke
basically the whole time told like a
story with a lot of taglines and a lot
of callbacks so that was cool Hardwick I
was being
this affects my podcast hosting uh I
listen to Nerdist often uh I watch at
midnight uh I've followed Hardwick since
the freaking uh singled out days so I
know he's from Denver I know how he used
to play in a band with Ferman called my
Harden ferm so they come out he comes
out at Red Rocks and he puts his hands
up in the air in the there and he's like
red rocks and I could see the
15-year-old boy in him that's wanted to
do that since the first time he touched
a guitar I was like that was his dream
just he's he just [ __ ] his pants I
could see it that's [ __ ] awesome yeah
and I kind of got to share that with my
friend Chris Hardwick through podcasting
and that relationship that I feel that
stalker relationship that you feel like
you have with all the celebrities follow
now I I did feel like that with Joe
Rogan like I felt like this is my buddy
performing yeah and and I've known him
and then I wanted to like as he was
walking off the stage I wanted to shake
his hand and stuff but I was just like
also like he's he's not a guy you know
and that's a weird thing to like have
this relationship with people that like
is a one-sided relationship yeah but I
could see that like I would probably do
the same thing with Hardwick it's just
be like I felt Pride for him like one of
my buddies just crushed it at Red Rocks
cuz he was awesome he did a great great
set his set was uh man he's kind of a
pervert dude he did uh he he did a joke
and I don't want to blow his bit but
half of his bit was about [ __ ] your
mom that's funny like yeah yeah and for
Hardwick to go that route at Red Rocks
was it was funny for me that's pretty
great uh Dimitri Martin did his thing
Demetri Martin he surprised me how funny
he was my date that I took with me she
loved him that's who she went to see so
that was good we got to chuckle at that
uh DJ Trauma is a killer DJ by the way
he's the one that ran music uh between
The Comedians and then we took a
15minute intermission this was about a
30-minute intermission I believe if you
do comedy for too long you burn out your
funny oh yeah yeah so they gave a nice
intermission and we stood up and danced
for a few uh Hannibal baress was great
he did his thing uh he made a joke about
Colorado having the ugliest crowd and
then he said it looks like y came from a
hike and then he thought about it he
goes you probably all just did and then
he made a joke about who was the white
guy that broke down out here and decided
let's build a venue we can do shows here
because Red Rocks is kind of in the
middle of nowhere yeah uh Louis CK Crush
like I said Mark Marin was good his
closer was solid but you could tell he
was frazzled and didn't know what to do
with 15 minutes Marin's used to 45 to
whittle Marin down to 15 minutes is kind
of like you got to give him time to get
out on the stage and sit down at the
edge of the stage and get pissed off
about something and then he gets into
that Mark Marin thing he didn't get time
for that in his 15 I didn't feel he was
good his closer was hilarious like I
won't blow anybody's bit on purpose but
his closer was great Sarah Silverman
surprised the [ __ ] out of me uh her set
was great but she is funny like she is
naturally funny you could just
tell Whitney Cummings [ __ ] yells her
set at you like I'm Whitney and my jokes
are funny so you're going to laugh
punchline like and it's what it feels
like the whole time it feels like you're
being barraged with jokes she was funny
but it was a bit [ __ ] too much for me
you're just saying the way she delivered
them could have been better she forgot
she had a microphone and she had to yell
she was she was Roman style like and I
felt that way about her TV shows like
when she's on TV she doesn't feel like
she's speaking she feels like she's over
projecting to me too much uh and then
Brody Stevens needs medication Brody
Stevens was the host uh Brody take your
medicine buddy I love you I respect you
dude you need [ __ ] calm down Brody
Stevens [ __ ] harness that [ __ ] bro
like I don't know man maybe you smoke
too much of that good Colorado weed but
at that show you were [ __ ] losing
your [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah I'm not I'm not a
huge fan of Brody Stevens yeah it's just
not my thing but personal preference
there well it's just like anything like
I'm I'm so glad that there's some people
that don't like my comedy because if
everybody liked it it'd be like wow that
was that was that that's not right
everybody's as [ __ ] up as me that
doesn't make any sense nobody wants
another Dane Cook I keep telling my mom
that she doesn't want to hear it but she
doesn't [ __ ] listen to me so your
mom's going to come see your comedy H
she wants to that's going to be funny
it's going to be hilarious I want to
tape it I'm not going to have the camera
pointed at you at all it be her reaction
the entire time see and I haven't I got
I make sure that nobody's coming to my
shows like familywise like they don't
know when I do stuff they that that
would be terrible they do now CU they
listen to the IG gr culture podcast
Tuesday nights 9:00 radiat downtown P
Colorado it's free to get in right if
free to get in it's free whereever you
want smoking weed what what he's
grounded grounded you're done speaking
of smoking weed this is a podcast about
consuming cannabis growing cannabis and
cannabis education we should probably uh
talk a little bit about cannabis got a
little ranty especially but I think our
listeners enjoy getting a little inside
of our heads and a little bit of our
world and knowing what's up with us uh I
like like I said that Chris Hardwick
talk uh they're my friends now they know
what I'm doing they're 29 30 episodes
into being my buddy we've spent 30 hours
together now absolutely we're Bros yeah
and sisses I guess what do you call it
we're not if you're a lady out there
you're my bro I don't know what else to
call you right now you're family you're
awesome thanks for listening to the show
just as much as all the dudes uh I have
a female friend who is encouraging me to
do an all an episode All About Women in
cannabis I don't know what to do I told
her to research it for me and help me
out if you guys have any ideas for women
in cannabis it feels sexist a guy doing
a show all about women in cannabis so
anything I come up with I feel like it
be gender biased and it'll be weird so
ladies send me some stuff so that I can
do a ladies podcast I I want to satisfy
the listeners and if you're asking for
it that's what we got to do I'm ranting
again so women in cannabis yeah that's
uh just the trimmers right oh man so
Clint is a comedian we should remind you
and these are
jokes but that that one wasn't I wasn't
even going to open my
mouth know I'm actually going to give a
shout out to miss Green Thumb Jessica
you're a badass girl or I'll Stand up
for you one of my favorite female
Growers I was going to say do you not
know any kind of people from Denver that
maybe could travel down and you know oh
yeah we can get people on the show uh
yeah definitely but I we're going to do
like an hour and it's easier for yeah
we'll do a report on it instead of
bringing them but I'll talk to Jess and
get some info from her CU she's a badass
badass female grower she grows as good
if not better than myself I'll give her
that credit she grew some Kong that was
amazing follow Miss green Thum on
Instagram I'll find out the proper uh
the exact Instagram address and I'll
tweet that [ __ ] out so you guys can
follow her CU she's a great grower so
Clint came I had Clint here Clint is uh
he used to be a nonsmoker now he is a
new smoker it's fun he took two Puffs
off of a bowl earlier dirt weed and uh
obviously did not come from here I
brought it in myself I felt bad about it
immediately but uh I saw him get plenty
high off two good puffs of some some
swaggle weed it wasn't really swaggles
but it was not the D it was that bed you
smoked it I mean it's not it's not rosta
weed it's not iy looks looks similar to
that stuff that was in that bag over
here the other day he's on the smoke
team now so you know he's joining us and
now he's got some questions I do one of
his main I wrote down the questions
because we got blazed and I didn't want
to forget them and he knew he looked
into my eyes and he goes Clint's not
going to remember anything yeah so one
of the questions Clint had was storage I
do cuz I don't know you know I I my
little bag of weed is my plastic [ __ ]
up my
weed well I hate to Dish your weed that
you got but that's fine to keep in a
sandwich baggie but when you upgrade and
you get some quality weed from somebody
that's a good caregiver that likes you
and doesn't want to see you smoking that
[ __ ] anymore uh keep your little to go
portion in a baggie maybe but keep the
rest of it in a jar uh I store usually
you know most people have like a quarter
to an out of weed maybe an e of weed I
keep it in a glass jar your glass jar
size can depend on the size of your
stash I use baby food jar I was just
going to say Adam uses a baby food jar
to 98 because if you go to Walmart
trying to buy a jar for number one we
live in Colorado a and there's no jars
for number two they're $6 for a jar
that's the same size and the same price
you know yeah and you get baby food yum
you know hey I like peas and carrots
carrots and peas peas and carrots all
right so butchered weed in a jar uh
hopefully when you get it it's not too
dry it's not too wet hopefully it's at
the right Point uh if when I dry and
cure my own weed guys you keep asking
for a drying and curing episode that's
coming Jesse and I are putting that
together we're putting a lot of thought
and work into it that should be episode
30 is the drawing and curing episode so
be patient that's coming you got about a
week till that's out yeah chill out God
yeah wait your turn I'm just kidding
thanks for listening and being patient
if you are uh listening to this next
week I got a big show coming up uh
September 22nd at Phil's radiator we're
bringing uh Ron Babcock through and he's
a professional comedian who's been on TV
before like he's been on HBO he's been
on Comedy Central like does he do weed
jokes I I don't think so he in Colorado
he has to he will that night well he's
from La three at least coming from La
he's going to hit Phil's radiator Monday
it's only $5 like it's I'll come down
yeah it's the 22nd it's a good he's and
he's going to do as long as he wants to
do I'm goingon to do maybe 10 minutes
Paul's gonna do 10 minutes Paul Rosales
is really funny Paul Garrett Waller is
GNA be on that one Jarrett Waller what's
up you giant [ __ ] huge huge jokes he
might guy yeah he might do a fat guy
joke he might he might not he will he
will um and then uh John bueno's on that
as well oh John Bueno I hope he wears a
fancy sweater yeah yeah he probably he
looks so good he was rocking Mr Rogers
last week was he's a [ __ ] killer he I
just derailed to plug without asking at
all no that's cool I caught you doing it
and I like I like the natural flow of
this show that's what we expect out of
Clint just ruin show we expect out of
Clint I know where we are cuz I took
notes uh and and we let you get nice and
high so you're not going to ruin
anything I'm the captain of this ship uh
I'm going to start something called the
uh what what what I'm going to start
something called the uh the the cuss jar
here pretty soon every time I say after
starting on episode 30 every time I say
the word [ __ ] I will donate a dollar to
a charity uh I had a conversation with a
guy on Instagram today and uh he asked
me to donate to a charity and I will
find out the charity that he was asking
about and I'll donate a dollar uh
starting on episode 30 every time I say
[ __ ] in a podcast each
episode however many times you say [ __ ]
you have to donate to a different
charity that way you're spreading it
around maybe well hopefully I don't say
[ __ ] more than like six or seven times
before
mys because after I start I'm going to
throw down the dollars on the table and
watch themen so it's going to get
expensive last one you only had two I
believe yeah so hopefully I can get to
zero and hopefully this guy's charity
doesn't get anything out of me
but but yeah I don't care what your
charity is no I'm uh we had a good
conversation I made a new friend today
on Instagram he started off mad at me by
something that I posted and I turned him
right around once I explained what I
meant and made a friend with the guy so
shout out Dr green thumbs it's not there
are so many Dr Green thums on Instagram
you won't be able to find which one no
uh but uh that dude uh I'm going to
donate to his charity if I say [ __ ] on
episode 30 so anytime after this episode
The FW cost me a dollar uh I'll start to
once I keep screwing up I will increase
my my value for the FW like five or
we're also not going to keep track so
you have to tell us yeah people no
people tweet me I actually definely no
that's fine just we're not going to keep
track so Dreadful Jay has been tweeting
me somebody else has tweeted me so they
remind me I said compilation of you
saying [ __ ] over
so we've just said [ __ ] like 14 times in
the past 5 minutes so hey me and Clint
are allowed you're not yeah I don't
remember putting up any money maybe I'll
make that a guess stipulation too so you
guys got maybe we'll all start matching
dollars every time somebody says it then
we all got to match you know I'm below
poverty level right you know that I
would just be doing it just to be a dick
to Clint works at a steel mill so [ __ ]
is in his daily vocabulary and Adam is
from the south and you know yeah he he
knows like six words and two of them are
[ __ ] yeah and the other one is yeah yeah
shut
up oh we're talking about storage so
you're saying baby food containers cin
yeah baby food that's just what I use I
mean I literally got tired of going to
Walmart and there being none you know
after you drive to both Walmarts on
either side of town and you're like do I
really want to go out the West no I just
98 cents you know you scoop it out you
clean it out leave it let it dry and
then yeah it's it's good in there and
that's that's perfect for an e you know
especially like a fluffy eight that's
that's but you got to wait until you got
to make sure your weed's dry enough to
go into a jar I was about to say that's
where I derailed you I no I'm I'm on it
bro I'm getting good at this podcast
thing when my weed when I'm curing and
drying my weed I'll leave it a little
bit extra moist for my personal so that
I almost have to open yes I do smoke
flour still people don't believe that I
still smoke weed I do it's not always
dabs but I'll leave my weed a little
moist where I got to open the jar and
take the buds out and set them down for
10 or 20 minutes before I can actually
roll a joint with it and see yeah that's
just my personal if it's a production
crop for my patients I'm a caregiver and
the herb that's going to get delivered
to guy later on tonight uh that stuff's
dry it's been cured and it's dry it's
ready to go into his jar he'll keep uh
he's getting a half so it's probably
going to go in a mason jar it'll be
sealed up and he'll just he'll probably
pull out a little baby food jar worth
for himself every couple of days when he
needs it and he hides the Mason jar away
from the family and has that in a safe
place and keeps his jar in his pocket um
and that will also if your weed is
really dry that may bring back some of
the the moisture in the Christmas to
good topic if your weed's really dry I
see a lot of people trying to put fruit
and [ __ ] there don't do that you're
going to bring pathogens and molds uh it
doesn't take a lot of moisture to start
molding up a jar if you leave it in
there long enough uh this company does
not pay me [ __ ] but I do highly
recommend a boova or a BEDA humida pack
uh it's a great product uh if your
weed's a little bit too dry or a little
too moist even you put the proper Bova
humida pack in with your herbs and it
will properly uh moisten your herb to
the moisture content that is desired um
isn't it like 67 or whatever I don't
remember exactly it's one of those
numbers I'll go to the B website right
now and'll it's one of those numbers
I've seen it around
um it's the humidity the perfect
humidity should be around 67 or 76 it's
somewhere in between there I got it's
like the same thing as a hum there's
also yeah well exactly there are
humidors for marijuana specifically I'm
not going to mention the name because I
don't want to give them a plug either
but um they're they're shiny metal
they're cans they got a blocking seal to
them so it's and they come in all shapes
and sizes that's if you're you know the
High Roller you're the the pro uh I see
people use them to transport cannabis
for uh uh the Cannabis cups and stuff
like that yeah they'll basically have
four or five of the big pound storage
ones and there's three of them in a
backpack and they're loading getting on
an airplane wo you know and it's
completely you know No One Ever Knows
because it's completely sealed yeah you
know still scary as [ __ ] that has your
package your humidifier package that
he's talking about that keeps it all at
the
same um same humidity uh and I it
doesn't really uh tell you what it keeps
it at it says that it keeps it within a
certain range of uh ambient humidity so
yeah uh they have so many products out I
didn't know they had so much stuff so
you guys go check out the Bova website
boa uh shout out to Coral reefer she's
actually the one that introduced me to
the boa products uhhuh you a big fan of
the coral reer over there buddy go on
move along all right so if you're going
to keep your weed longer than uh if
you've got some herb that is dried and
cured and you know it's not moist enough
somebody hates the word moist a lot of
people hate the word moist you know your
word your weed why would they hate the
word sounds sticky you know so if your
weed's not too damp and you're not
afraid to get mold in it you can put
your Herb in a vacuum sealer bag and
vacuum seal that [ __ ] uh vacuum sealers
aren't too expensive the bags aren't too
expensive uh seal it up label it Mark it
uh some people DJ Short says to put it
in the free at this point that's what my
dad always did he put it in a brown
paper bag and then stick it put it in a
bag put it in a brown paper bag and
stick it in the freezer because that way
none of the light would get into paper B
so I was going to say that also keep
your jars and stuff in a dark place when
you're not smoking them if you have the
opportunity or if you can get an opaque
jar to keep the lights out a large
quantity you know if it's if it's an
eighth or quarter you're good and yeah
if you got if you got an ounce or
quarter pound keep that out of the out
of the light you want that right on I
feel really good about that question now
that took a lot longer than I was
thinking it would what about um
in jars if you keep stuff in jars for
longer than I do obviously so would you
go in there once a month and kind of
dump it out and no once it's uh once I
feel like we're going to do a whole
episode about drying and curing once
that process is ended once drying and
curing is done you can put it in your
jars and just leave it it's almost
better to leave it because every time
you open it you're introducing oxygen
and you're changing the gases that are
in the plants the plants are actually
releasing ammonia and
chlorophylls I I haven't studied for
this part so I'm going to say wrong [ __ ]
and a lot of people are going to correct
me
gases and you're exchanging those gases
and if you quit introducing more gases
the decar oxolation and the changes will
stop happening starches will quit
becoming sugars everything will stay
right where it is all right it's like
opening uh cool like uh opening a food
product you get it just gets stale
eventually because to change same thing
will pretty much happen with your weed
yeah I I've talked about this on the
show before I like mine a little bit
drier because I put mine through a
grinder and still get the KE off of the
the bud onto the know my my grinder so I
like it when I bring it home I I'll sit
it in the jar and just leave the the lid
half on half off for 12 hours and then
put the jar you know the lid back on
it's still moist inside the butt a
little bit but it's that outer stuff is
flakier and I get you know Dr I like it
a little more a little more sticky you
get a little more flavor out of it when
it's a little stickier I think still you
don't let it dry out so much and then
your joint Burns a little bit better
there you go I gr culture you got a
question answered Clint came over and
asked a great freaking question after he
got high that was nice yeah uh he also
asked since he's a new smoker I did he
asked so I hope we wrap that up how to
store your weed put it in a jar baggies
are cool but the baggie has uh static
electricity and it's stealing all your
[ __ ] and all your [ __ ] sticking to it so
keep it in a jar a nug jug of some sort
all right uh if you have to be sneaky
they spell skunk proof bags that are
smell proof they also at hyro peblo they
offer a duffel bag style bag and a
backpack that they claim is smellproof I
have not tested it by putting any
product in it but they claim such and
they're they're decently priced so if
they work that's worth it there's also
stash cans and things like that that you
can get you know of course you've seen
them yeah yeah but that's hiding that's
more being secretive here yeah I'm not
really looking to keep it secret I can
you know keep it well you already got it
like a little case that's that's all you
yeah you're doing good we saw what
you're working with yeah uh so his next
question was a normal new guy question
how am I going to pass my P test working
sucks right everybody yes working for
guys you with me ladies you
listening working sucks if you guys want
to tweet all that uh that stuff at at
tall Clint and not not at Agro culture
you can go ahead send your comments to
at tall Clint ladies it's me I don't
care no I meant but no I get you watch
us
work um anyway work sucks but I like my
job unfortunately my job does not like
people that smoke marijuana and it sucks
cuz I like my job and if I could quit I
would but it's just got to eat life's
expensive I got I got I got three women
asking me for money all the time and I
got a family but
I'm um no
it's Jeff's cracking up guys if you want
if you want somebody to come crash your
podcast invite a comedian just destroy
this I love it anyway we need to loosen
up and have more fun on this show it's
always be real tight reading news today
on the news there is weed
stuff I like that we got somebody here
to dis what's that character's name I
don't know but he was good he needs to
stick around let me ask you this are you
worried about them popping random drug
tests or are you worried about getting
hurt and them wanting you to pee in a
cup for workers man comp those are the
two times that I can get UA they I mean
like randoms
are I don't know with anybody that's got
com from a weed smoker that's dealt with
this you know time and time again
randoms it's just the dice that you're
rolling brother I've got a solution this
is the iy genetics only Surefire way
that I think I know how to get past a
drug test that has worked for me
multiple times when I was a heavy
smoker uh I actually went 63 days
without smoking cannabis at one point
and took a p test I was trying to get a
badass job I was promised to kill her
job 63 days and could not pass I was
still hot I was drinking cranberry juice
I killing the water still had aot test
my family was mad at me like you [ __ ]
it up you've been smoking pot and I was
like honestly I went to Reg on the rocks
and didn't smoke weed like I quit from
the 4th of July I puffed down and then
for 90 days after that or 63 days after
that I didn't smoke and still could not
get this job that I wanted and I told
them I was like I haven't smoked in 65
63 days and they're like sorry you still
didn't I was like can you give me 30
more days and they were already hiring
for the position so it's was gone [ __ ]
but so the next time I needed to take a
p test I could not risk my PE even going
in the cup honestly so your best bet is
to use fake piss because they are not
checking for fake piss or piss they're
looking for THC Crystal math opiates
ecstasy whatever in our case hopefully
guys if you're listening to my show
hopefully the only thing they're going
to find in your pee is some [ __ ]
medicine some cannabis but that's not my
spot to judge uh so they sell a product
that is straight up fake piss it is
designed to be fake piss it's usually at
some kind of a head shop around here
there's a couple spots you can go you
guys all know where they are if you live
around here yeah yeah there's two spots
I don't endorse either one of them they
got to work out a sponsorship if they
want me to say their names yeah start
paying us Mr money so you go there and
uh you get this fake pee and it's got a
thermometer on the side of the container
the bottle has a thermometer on it it
should come with a it's a glove warmer
for the winter you crack the thing open
and you put your glove you put it in
your gloves and it warms your hands in
the winter it comes with one of those if
it doesn't you got to go buy one so what
I do this is how I sure fire past more
than one drug test I get this product
and I microwaved it for 7 seconds and my
microwave and that made it a little too
hot so I took a sock and I cut the sock
off and I stapled it to the inside of my
boxers to where it looked like it was my
dick swinging I put that uh warmed up
bottle of microwaved fake piss in the
sock um I could tell that it was going
to be warm enough I I went too long in
the microwave the thing got down you
need it between 96 and 100 degrees is
where you need it to get that's where
your body is so I let it cool down you
got let me intervene here I just used
the heater in the car and and a plastic
IC bag in my boxer line you know it's
not probation it's not jail no one
should be watching you piss they should
be going they should be taking you to a
lab and you should be going into a
closed area where you can pull out your
dick and go woo right but they wash your
hands and check your pockets well that's
what I'm saying in the Box are line you
know what I'm saying so I got this
swinging swinging sock with a fake pee
in it that's been microwaved and I've
let it cool now I've driven around long
enough to let it get to the right
temperature because you got so much time
to get there hopefully if you're you're
a union worker would assume they're
going to send you to a lab you get a CP
you get yeah you get a couple minutes to
go drive by the house or 7-Eleven even
and hit the I got a piss and run into
7-Eleven and use their microwave or
crack have that so you're going to if
you're working a job where you might get
P tested you need this [ __ ] in your
locker or in your truck or somewhere
close if you can carry this fake piss in
your cigarette pack you're a [ __ ]
genius it's a small bottle you don't
need a lot it's a little tiny bottle so
you got fake P keep it in your shirt
pocket do something uh so you get hit
with this P test you go you're driving
maybe take another car to drive you to
the gas station say I got a pee man or
can we stop and get a pack of cigarettes
go in there and hit that microwave for 7
Seconds do whatever you got to do to
warm that piss up to the proper
temperature if you got that glove
cracker use that wrap it around it put a
rubber band around it put it between
your legs and squeeze when you feel your
legs getting too warm that shit's
probably right at the right temperature
H yeah so and you got that little bottle
it's tucked inside of a sock it's
strapped inside your boxers girls you're
going to have to modify I don't know
what you're going to do you're going to
look like you got a dick if you follow
my method maybe it'll help you out don't
wear a skirt or or or do or do so uh
pull out this little bottle and just
stick it out of the pee hole of your fly
and stick your hand in there and stick
your thumb out so it's like your dick
because if they're standing behind you
or something you're going to have to be
smooth stick your thumb out make that
look like your dong fart uh always fart
during a p test if someone's watching
that's just mandatory fart do that so uh
I squeezed the bottle the first time I
did it into the little sample cup and it
went when I let go of it cuz it tried to
suck in more air so tip it up so that
you don't make a bong sound when you're
[ __ ] doing that or fart right at that
point if you can time it you got to be
careful so and then stick that thing
close it back up screw the cap on stick
it back in your underwear [ __ ] don't
wash your hands leave the cup there like
you're supposed to and hope that you
just put enough of the right temperature
fake piss in there so that fake piss
worked for me more than once right on
yeah fake piss don't trust my friend I
won't say his name he had his girlfriend
pee in the cup and that's how they found
out that my buddy was pregnant M yeah
yeah um definitely don't use females
piss
but I have
I've never used my own
piss ever he's got kids I don't even
want to ask any questions yeah so we're
not trying to mask it we're trying to
replace it yeah cuz they're not looking
yeah there's plenty of things you can
drink eat or whatever to take and all
they've done is upset my stomach and
give me diarrhea and by the time you get
to the lab you got a pee so bad that
your pee is clear and they go oh this is
diluted we can't even test it yeah yeah
yeah yep so if it comes through you and
if you smoke like Adam and I do uh I dab
at least a half a gram a day a day could
honestly probably quit for 15 days and
you would maybe fine but don't you know
it's technically 30 days the thing is is
I don't want to quit smoking weed though
and I'm and it's just a random that's
going to come up you know and so I don't
want to quit if I wanted to quit I
wouldn't have started then you should
you should definitely get prepared I
mean that's that's one of the best best
options that I've heard and then I would
just keep hand warmers on the ready like
I'd start wearing shirts with pockets
and like you know don't touch me you
know one day you're standing there
talking to your boss there's just this
big are you my pocket protector is not
working
today my nipple peed all over me that's
funny that's awkward there's got to be a
joke there oh there's definitely a joke
there yeah but I don't take your jokes
all right good don't take my jokes
because I wouldn't tell it anyways I
like your jokes that's why I'm not going
to use them anyways we've gone uh 40
minutes 41 minutes you guys want to uh
you want to do one more question you one
more question I got one more but I bet
we could go on for quite a while about
it if we do it it'll kind of make it a
long question I want to know what it's
about well the question was what kind of
lights are you using for each phase of
growing all right that could be really
long or it could be really simple yeah
so quick rundown I've I've been oh guys
I know but I know I started off doing a
bunch of grow lessons and we got
sidetracked because Jesse came over and
started doing outdoor grow stuff uh we
started talking about all kinds of other
stuff we kind of lost track of the grow
lessons I promise to get you caught up
on those there's just so much [ __ ] going
on that it's hard to even catch up we
get sidetracked just stay tuned it's a
busy season it's such a great year to do
a podcast there's been so much cannabis
news and stuff to talk about that's true
it is a busy season yeah uh Jesse will
be here in a couple of days and we're
going to work on finishing up the uh uh
drying and curing episode so that'll
definitely be fun but what kind of
Lights do I use that's where I was uh
for seedlings and stuff that's just
starting simple t5s are fine um a lot of
guys correct yeah yeah fluoresence T5
fluoresence uh t5s are the little skinny
bulbs so they name them t5s are the
skinny ones and t8s are the bigger ones
it's just what size they are uh so I
keep my seedlings and my clones under
t5s until they're good and rooted um
depending on which room they're going
and what I'm trying to do with them
sometimes they'll stay under t5s until
flower if I'm just doing a three gallon
pot of a little plant and the reason why
you run t5s is not only because of the
heat but because it's it you can get
them closer to the plant right you can
put them right on the plant and they're
more energy efficient uh than a big
light and I don't think that the plant
really needs a th000 watt light when
it's a baby you could just give it
enough just and that spectrum they sell
two different color bulbs if you get the
blue ones uh those keep your plant short
and squat uh and that's what we want for
veg and until your plants are 2 and a
half three feet tall that's plenty of
light don't keep them too crowded in
there give them plenty of space with the
t5s but yeah it's definitely helpful
I've seen people flower with t5s I have
too uh it's not impressive but if you're
in Tennessee where you're not supposed
to be growing weed and you can't get a
big light build that's going to be
better than buying weed off of some food
on the street I've seen some people grow
some pretty dank stuff you know with it
um so to start I like the the t5s uh
once they get a little bit larger I will
throw them under uh I go straight to the
thousand watt metal Halli for vegging uh
I've got a nice veg room with thousand
watt metal halides in there keep them
kind of close to the plants uh the hux
uh I think it's the blue I forget which
one they make for it's the hux lights
they make for vegging the blue one
that's awesome for vegging uh hux makes
a high press sodium that is red uh
that's super awesome for flowering I
like to switch to that now with your
when you step from the t5s to the bigger
lights uh how just give us a range on
like how far you want to keep them you
know I as far as close as you can get
them within uh you don't want them you
don't you kind of want to get them as
close as you can without burning the
plants but there is a range around 1,000
watt light bulb that is unusable light
for the plant it's just too intense and
it's the wrong Spectrum so you have to
back up about a foot and a half 2 feet
from the bulb okay is probably your best
bet right but only the tops of your
plants are up there so the bottoms of
your plants you gota there's a lot of
factors to keep in there but about a
foot 18 inches to a foot is probably
about as close as you really want to get
unless you've got some amazing cooling
you know if you've got really well
ducted and ventilated lights then you
can get them 10 8 in but sometimes that
that burst of light coming right out of
there isn't what the plants really want
that will kind of stress the plants and
change the flavors and kind of do a few
things that if you want a certain effect
that's how I achieve one effect when I'm
trying to do something is light stress
the plan a little bit but I don't want
to tell too much about that so I'm
vegging under the t5s I'm moving to the
uh metal halides and then I go to high
pressure sodiums to finish a long time
ago I tried an experiment using high
pressure sodiums and metal halides and I
honestly get the best flavors using a
mixture um the different spectrums yeah
yeah using like the blue and the red I
got four uh High Press sodiums with a
with a one metal H right in the middle
of the room and all the plants in the
middle the room were a little more dense
had a little more flavor uh I learned
that by running uh the old reflector
called the Grilla it holds two bulbs I
put a 600 uh sodium and a 400 highight
in there and everything in that little
tester Hut came out dank some of the
pictures of headband on my Facebook are
actually from that Hut and it was
amazing yeah I've seen those pictures of
man super dank is that his headband
yours I did not make it no okay sorry
trying to plug your [ __ ] well nice try
uh uh actually I got to talk to Dr dank
today or Mr dank today the creator of
the Golden Goat o we had a little
conversation on Facebook that was kind
of nice CU I did not create Golden Goat
a lot of people try to give me credit
for that Mr dank created Golden Goat I
simply put it into seed I femin I
reversed a female made a male out of it
and put the pollen on another female
made seeds out of it yes so it's a it's
a dank cut so I made seeds out of the
Golden Goat if you guys want to give
credit to the guy that made it thank Mr
dank he did that not me uh thanks Mr
dank for letting me use it he actually
gave me permission to put it into seed
and he said all he wants seed though
yeah yeah there you go I thought
everybody deserved good genetics that's
part of why I started making seeds so uh
I usually do fluorescent Halid sodiums a
lot of people will ask about LEDs I used
to knock an LED light but my friend
Nancy kills it she is killing it with
Bounty Killer yeah she's running ceton
too and they both look Frosty and dank
and all pretty much all of her stuff is
on I was just about to say she's running
a lot of stuff that's from other Growers
not even me that looks amazing just as
well
uh what's the one that she's got is it
DB Cooper that's just giant nugs it
looks really nice yeah yeah n's doing a
great job with the grows shout out Nancy
bwell talking about women Growers you
know I mean always get her to write
something a little yeah I'm going to
make a not prob she's probably a well
spoken individual that could probably
you know put a paragraph in that you
could read yeah there we go support
those women Growers I don't care what
Clint says hey I was just making a joke
no I like it I like that you got to have
an approach as a ComEd and one time
Clint told me go on the chauvinist route
and I believed
him I got a little misogynistic yeah
there was no uh no denying that you were
good at it oh it's it's the it's really
easy and that's why I don't like it yeah
is because it's for me it's easy to
write those jokes
yeah fun it's just not fun it's just an
easy
target I'm saying women are easy targets
that was the uh I'm staring into my
computer like how do I fix this I just I
just took it this direction almost on
purpose anyway it was yeah yeah all
right guys uh you guys got any uh I'm
going to let Clint do some plugs Clint
has a lot of [ __ ] to plug tell us about
your Facebooks your Instagram your shows
how do we call you to cuss you out or do
we email you to send you hate mail yeah
um best way to get a hold of me is
probably Facebook or Twitter find me on
Twitter it's tall Clint and uh Facebook
find the wild cousins we've been doing a
lot of shows we probably have about one
showcase a month and you know this one
this one's a little rough cuz it's on a
Monday so it's just but he's just
passing through and somehow we booked
him that's uh Ron Babcock and he's he's
funny look him up he's a funny guy I
think I'm free that Monday so for five
bucks down I'm going to try for yeah
like a professional comedian coming to
peblo like it's not like oh it's unheard
of but it's like you guys are going to
miss it and I don't want anybody to miss
it like oh I didn't even hear about that
you know what I heard like one of my
favorite bands baroness have you ever
heard they're like a metal band um
one of my favorite bands and my buddy
Paul who does comedy with me told me
yeah we had them back in like 2000 come
through and play some House show they're
[ __ ] huge they're like a huge band in
metal and they're just like I missed it
and that's that's why you miss it though
is because you don't know it's happening
and there's not enough to do in P where
you guys can be like oh I was doing this
and it's like well that's fine during
the fair but you don't have anything to
do right now there's something going on
down there every day it seems like
though you know it's hard to just
distinguish what's good and what's not
well that's why I'm inviting you to this
for five bucks you can come and watch a
professional comedian you can watch me
be a [ __ ] piece of [ __ ] and then uh
Paul and John are there too and they're
funny so you got two out of four at
least that'll be a good show no I have
faith in you guys you guys we talk a lot
of trash about you uh open micer
comedians but you guys are getting there
you've been at it for quite a while and
you're getting there you guys are funny
now giveing for a year you know the
comedy scene here has uh definitely
blossomed and evolved in quite a nice
way yeah yeah for sure there's another
one opening so that's pretty crazy it's
going to be fun it's we're we're just
getting there comedy heals the world
guys comedy and cannabis they go well
together I guess that's a good way to
end this portion of the show Adam you
got anything to plug um overgrowth
go.com on Twitter 420.com Adam will be
here when I do the intro and exits to
the show so he'll get to say a lot more
cool stuff for the show Clint dude
thanks for taking a night out or a
little bit of time out of your night you
got to get to work pretty soon we kept
you for longer than we should have I'm
doing well Budd thank you cool cool
thanks for coming uh you're welcome back
when you have more questions more stuff
to say whenever you need anything come
by you don't have to just be on the
podcast to drop by either come by hang
out we like you at the table we do need
to yes all right guys we're going to
wrap up this portion of the show right
here and I'll be right back to do the
[Music]
closing all right that was another
successful episode of the igro culture
podcast before I say goodbye I want to
give a big thanks to Clint and Adam for
dropping by make sure you follow those
guys on Instagram and Twitter it's @
overgrowth goov and at tall Clint also
go follow my friend Jessica it's Miss
Green Thumb
msor Greenthumb on
Instagram now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for igro culture find the
review section give us a five-star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode and don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes and Stitcher and
every single episode is archived on iy
genetics colorado.
all the music in this episode was from
task and Linus make sure you check them
out at task and less. bandcamp.com
big shout out to Highly Educated
titanium a big shout out to Ryan from
tree Thugger tocom I want to give a big
happy birthday shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening to the
igro culture podcast take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me
[Applause]
hey y stubs wake up
buddy you're going to miss
7 ah [ __ ] it more for
me the F's bright I'm cing out my
dabbing up my brain falling out my head
again if you hadn't heard well I'm all
about my medicine peace to my crew yeah
I'm calling out 710 CA all the way to
the UK they got my nails sticking to
they do like a t we the CR CR like a
Brule not a fan of all your water
me we come long but we're not looking
for another I'm sick of all
this me it's for my please keep your
blunt RS to yourself man and even these
days I think smoking joints is bad I get
some spoil by the oil which ANS my pth
but not as spoiled as you lovers of sa
who keep telling me the butter was crap
huh it's a civil war my brother brothers
under attack I'm in my house with the
clubing the back bring [ __ ] I love Shad
as a matter of fact I don't discriminate
I hit it when that is packed I hear the
fear but the pressure from my stronger
I'll hit the butter and w't live another
year longer fre and I'm a near goner
doing three pointers from across the
table like a
beer you see that jump shot nothing but
nail hey yo pass me the rock man I can
do this [ __ ] all day lay uh-huh uh-huh
oh here we go again uh-huh uh-huh yeah
you ain't [ __ ] with that oh you
thought we was
done I heard got the well your boy pass
got electrical Nails Inc and sometimes I
get a bit ahead of myself while eating
Ed it's better for my General Health and
our ship's leaving and we're raising the
cell we'll see you later you hat will
have to hate on yourself because my team
is going places and well I want to see
my name in the stars and my ugly faceing
the now I can do it I'm an overachiever
I go and get it like a golden retriever
cutting down trees any T always roll
with a beaver spread it wide like an
open receiver so come hit it I'mma show
unbelievers that they had to be wrong
don't start you left your battery on we
done finish i d dises my sanity's gone
then pass out my
family I've been working lots trying to
get my own place no I haven't I'm lying
through my Stone Face sorry y'all but
I'm growing at my own pace slow L St
coming over with the colde we're taking
hits to the D St sits on the throne
making hits from the home base me myself
I'm an entrepreneur concentrate
connoisseur clean my rig and I'm
clocking the sewer we came here just to
better the game we Innovative and we
never
the even WEA R TN remember the
name came here game we're Innovative and
we're never the same we run [ __ ] even if
the weather is rain tnl y'all remember
the name and we out
Bobby water sucks Gatorade is
better