rhasta Jeff you bad [ __ ] yeah
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for a Thursday episode of the girl
from Earhart podcast I like to call
these Thursday episodes the Thursday
quickie these quickies are brought to
you by our friends at the hella tanked
seed bank make sure you check them out
at dank seed dot store ladies and
gentlemen it won't be a quickie unless
we get started right away
so let's get on with a girl from your
heart podcast all right podcast roll
thanks again for joining me for another
Thursday quickie before I get too far
let me apologize I know that my voice
sounds like [ __ ] I'm a little dried out
my voice is a little rough I do
apologize it's because I smoked a whole
bunch of joints with our friend Baker it
comedy works shout out to Baker had a
great weekend up there at Comedy Works
we'll talk about that in just a second I
like to start the podcast by talking
about what I've been smoking on of
course I was smoking flowers this
weekend I'm not known for smoking a lot
of flower I'm known for smoking a lot of
concentrates this weekend I smoked dog
waltz and star dog flowers groan and the
Three Rivers commercial grow grown by
myself and my grow team shout to the
whole grow staff shout out to everyone
at the grow but also I've been dabbing
on this lemon og live resin from our
friends at the garden of Weeden and it
is amazing you guys I'm gonna crack open
the jar and give it a smell and try to
give you a nice description um it smells
so it's lemon og it's got a very lemon
smell to the top of it as soon as you
crack it open
it smells like sweet lemons sweet sour
tangy lemons it's got a very strong
lemon smell now often want to talk about
lemons I talked about that dry lemon
smell like a lemon head candy or like
the country time lemonade dry powdered
smell ah this has a a wet lemon smell
and not in a bad way like the juicy
lemon smell it kind of smells like a
Jolly Rancher like when you put a Jolly
Rancher in your mouth and it kind of
makes you drool from that lemon flavor
it's doing that same thing to my tongue
it's kind of giving me the lemon essence
Jolly Rancher candy wanted rule now I
want a Jolly Rancher candy real bad ah
that's what it's doing to me so it's got
that lemon smell to it but then once you
get past that
sharp punch in the face of lemons
there's this hint of like cushy gas eNOS
earthiness at the bottom of it
it just blends really well with the
lemons the lemons kind of mute out the
gas eNOS but the gas eNOS brings out the
lemons I think and it is very well done
so shadows my friend Spence shadow so
the whole crew the garden of Weeden for
hooking me up with some delicious lemon
OG concentrates here alright now that
you guys know what I'm smoking on let's
get some business out of the way this
episode of the podcast is brought to you
by our friends at the hell it dank seed
company that's right if you need to add
some new genetics to your garden look no
further than the hella tanked seed
company you can visit them at dank seed
dot store alright you guys I owe
everybody listening to this podcast a
huge thank you this podcast is available
on iTunes the podcast is available on
stitcher the podcast is available on my
website since i'm talking about my
website let me apologize i know it looks
like [ __ ] i am not a web guy it exists
that website right now is mainly used to
host the podcast i know it needs a lot
of updates i simply don't know how to do
it myself and if I did know how to do it
I don't know if I would have the time so
I apologize for the shitty looking
website anyway the podcast is available
on iTunes stitcher my web site and it's
available on dozens of other random
podcast hosting sites now iTunes and
stitcher and YouTube are pretty much the
statistics that I pay attention to I
look at my website sometimes but you
guys don't listen on the website a whole
bunch it kind of looks like iTunes and
stitcher are the most used services and
ladies and gentleman I was blown away
when I checked my statistics on stitcher
last week because the show in the month
of February has already reached over
90,000 downloads on stitcher alone I'm
going to reach over 100,000 downloads
for the month of February I haven't paid
much attention I don't think I've hit a
hundred thousand downloads in one month
before on one service that is amazing
that's tremendous it blows my mind thank
you guys for downloading and listening
to my podcast thank you for all the
support I never thought that this little
show was gonna get listened to by 90,000
people
that's overwhelming that's uh no you
know what it's not overwhelming it's
inspiring I'm not overwhelmed I I love
it
ah I've been overwhelmed before and this
is a different feeling oh this is
inspiring this is motivating I never
thought that a large football stadium
north of people would download my
podcast and listen so all 90,000 of you
that downloaded the podcast on stitcher
this month it'll reach a hundred
thousand I'm confident that I will reach
100,000 downloads on stitcher this month
to all 100,000 of you thank you and also
if you're not listening on stitcher if
you're on iTunes if you're on pod Bay if
you're on podcaster if you're listening
wherever thank you
I truly appreciate it and I am blown
away that this podcast has gotten this
far you guys were almost a 300 episodes
I was stoked to make it to a hundred I
was blown away to make it to 250 300 is
really gonna mean something and I see no
end in sight anytime soon you guys so
90,000 downloads on stitcher that's what
I wanted to brag about holy [ __ ] we're
gonna hit a hundred thousand downloads
on one service this month you guys thank
you
if you guys keep listening I promise to
keep bringing you quality content
alright now let's move forward a little
bit I want to talk about what I did over
the weekend I know I get to keep coming
on here and bragging about all the cool
[ __ ] that I do sorry I don't mean to
brag but I gotta brag this week any guys
I got to go see uncle Joey I got to see
Joey Coco Diaz at the finest comedy club
on the planet that's right Joey Diaz was
it the comedy works he was there all
weekend he did Friday Saturday and
Sunday night he sold out two shows every
night I got to go to the early Saturday
show so Saturday I drove up to Denver I
find a nice parking spot over there at
writers Square I head into the comedy
show I get myself some pretzels and a
root beer and I get all set up the
comedy show comes on the hosts at Comedy
Works that night was Aaron Urist who is
always hilarious the opening act was a
comedian named Elliot who I am spacing
on his last name I knew it until I
started recording I'm gonna press pause
and find it hold on oh you guys I can't
find his name anywhere he's his name is
Elliot he is a regular at Comedy Works
is a very tall guy and he was very
hilarious if you get to see a tall guy
named Elliot at Comedy Works he's
[ __ ] great I recommend him
anyhow Aaron nearest opened Aaron's
always reliably funny Elliot I've seen a
couple of times
always reliably funny but after Elliot
set is when the party really got started
you guys I listen to a podcast called
the Church of what's happening now which
is where Joey Diaz gets to do most of
his ranting but he's joined by a
producer named Lisa at Leal so produces
the good times podcast with Steve Simone
he used to host his own podcast he was
part of another podcast with Johnny Rock
called life in neutral anyway Lee has
been a podcasting engineer and producer
in LA for quite a few years now
he's also becoming very well-known in
the podcasting world and the comedy
world because he hangs out with Steve
Simone Joey Diaz Ari Shaffir Joe Rogan
he's in that comedy realm so of course
the dude has started writing and doing
comedy if you listen to his podcast that
he's on you know that he's very new into
comedy and he's only got about seven
minutes of time total well I happened to
be paying attention to him on Twitter
and on the podcast and they kept saying
that Lee was coming to Denver with uncle
Joey now I didn't know if he was gonna
come to stand up or if he was just gonna
come hang out and Friday night he did
not do stand-up so I didn't expect
anything but Saturday night after the MC
and after the opener they brought out
mr. Lisa at the Flying jus to come do a
few minutes of comedy he did about three
to five minutes I tried not to watch the
clock too hard but I did try to pay
attention he did about three to five
minutes and I could see how visibly
nervous he was but he was [ __ ]
hilarious that dude crushed it for how
new at comedy he is and he's just a shy
nervous person in general so to see that
dude talk about doing comedy one day on
the podcast I went and did my first open
mic too he talked about I did three
minutes the other night I just got to
see this guy make the biggest level up
in his life Lee just jumped levels Lee
has now performed at The Comedy Store
Lee has now performed at comedy works
he's been on stage and crushed at the
two best clubs on the planet so shout
out congratulations to Lisa at and also
holy crap I was so excited to see Lee
come do comedy he crushed it he actually
pulled a move that I don't think he
realized how smooth
was one of the oh one of the acts before
him told a joke and I'm gonna kind of
ruin the guys material but I won't ruin
it all he invented a new name for giving
a woman blue balls and he calls it
flooding her basement all right that's
just a quick premise Lee actually came
out on stage and talked about himself
for a minute and then said look at me
I've never flooded anyone's basement and
for a comedian to pull something back
like that is gold so he's on the right
path it was [ __ ] hilarious I was
super excited I did not realize that
lee-sia
is about the height of a bar stool that
dude might be four foot two or something
that is a short little man holy crap I
was amazed to see how tiny he was but
Lee did about three or four minutes he
crushed it then he did the honors he
shifted from his material into alright
ladies and gentlemen you know I'm from
the Church of what's happening now and
then he brought out Joey Coco Diaz who
is one of my top five maybe top three
favorite living comedians that I've ever
[ __ ] listened to Joey makes me laugh
until weird parts of my body hurt Joey
makes me laugh until weird parts of my
head hurt I wasn't sure what part inside
of me was giving me a sharp pain but I
was laughing so hard that I almost
wanted to just stop laughing for a
minute I wanted to like oh how do I snap
out of this because it was uncomfortably
painfully hilarious I was laughing my
ass off I didn't have to pee but I
thought I might piss my pants from
laughter it was so good so he introduces
Joey and you guys when Joey walks out on
stage he comes out with the most
tremendous energy he just walks out on
stage and he just looks at the crowd
like what's up [ __ ] and he does this
really cool strut move this guy's 53
years old he's Cuban he's from North
Bergen New Jersey so he's got this East
Coaster vibe to him and he comes out on
stage and he struts and he grabs the mic
and he goes what's up you bad
[ __ ] and that Club [ __ ]
erupted you guys I have seen no [ __ ] 50
over 50 shows I've seen Doug Benson 20
times at comedy works you guys I have
been to over 50 shows at Comedy Works no
problem maybe closer to a hundred shows
at Comedy Works and Joey Diaz gets that
place roaring like
nobody [ __ ] else the only person they
got close with Chapelle and it's a
different thing the thing that Joey Diaz
brings it feels like the roof is gonna
come off the [ __ ] building he'll have
you in stitches laughing he'll tell a
punchline and you'll be crying laughs
and you're holding your gut and then
he'll throw a tag on to that just one
more little and so then I did this and
then you're like oh [ __ ] it can't go any
further
and then he'll then he'll make another
one and then I did this and they're like
oh god damn it Joe you better stop and
then he'll let it go and he'll just
pause and stare into the crowd cuz he
knows I don't have to say anything
they're [ __ ] laughing their asses off
I'm paid to make these people laugh I'm
gonna let them laugh and then as soon as
the laughter starts to kind of you know
people laughing hahaha and then you get
the you do that weird inhale noise
laughs oh like you're gonna settle down
and you're not laughing anymore okay I'm
done huh as soon as people do that noise
he grabs the microphone stand and picks
it up and I'm gonna do it he picks it up
about three or four inches up off the
floor and just smacks it on the ground
and he goes ha and when he does it it's
like the [ __ ] troublemaker kid at
school just got caught doing something
but doesn't care he's like I'm gonna get
detention whatever it was worth it cuz
you're all laughing at me he does that
and it's it's cheap it's a cheap-ass
comedy move but it's genuine it's if it
were disingenuous I would call him on it
it is just Joey's way of going ha look
you bad [ __ ] we're friends and
we're laughing together it is so [ __ ]
funny when he does it
so he'll hit you he'll tag you again
he'll tag you again and when you finally
think you're coming out of that water
and getting there
he'll slam that microphone stand on the
ground go ha ha and then you're busted
again I [ __ ] laughed so hard at uncle
Joey Joey told Joey tells some filthy
jokes maybe that's why I like him Joey
has a dirty mouth and a dirty mind but
he's honest and that's part of what I
love
but anyway Joey told a nice long story
that was tremendous and people were
offended and people were disgustingly
laughing or like I can't believe he just
said that [ __ ] in front of 250 people
uncle Joey that [ __ ] you might want to
keep private and everybody's laughing
and he's making this face that he makes
he opens his mouth and shakes his head
so that his bottom jaw flops back and
forth and he looks at you like ah it's
funny and it's really really is funny
but then he goes it's Saturday night you
[ __ ] you want to hear
knock-knock joke
for that man to realize that we were at
our limit and then just try to push us a
little more as just so it's so amazing
the way he works a crowd Joey brings
energy that nobody else [ __ ] brings
so I get to see Joey again unfortunately
there was another show afterward so we
didn't have the regular outside smoke
sesh that we usually have things had to
be a little more contained so it wasn't
a big party like normal however I did
have a very good time shout out to all
my friends at Comedy Works to take very
good care of me
you guys I keep saying it and they don't
pay me to say this at all I pay for all
of my Comedy Works tickets I pay for all
my food there they don't sponsor me in
any way I just [ __ ] love it
I recommend that everybody wherever you
are go see comedy at a comedy club go
support live comedy go support a
comedian go see what it's like it'll be
one of the funnest nights you've had in
a while alright you guys I feel like
that's enough bragging about my weekend
enough talking about comedy let's
actually read an email that has
something to do with some cannabis all
right podcast world this email comes
from our friend Ben Osborne and it goes
like this he starts off right away and
says feel free to use my name and the
name of the company that I work for if
you read this on the podcast hey Ben
thank you that makes life so easy ah
this one's from Ben it goes like this
dear Rasta Jeff let me start by thanking
you for everything you don't know you've
done for me
almost two years ago I decided to get
into the cannabis industry as a grower
I've had terrible luck growing anything
throughout my life killing just about
everything I touched I felt that with
proper knowledge and enough effort that
I would be able to be successful in my
grow my love for cannabis is a very
strong driving force I think you know
the feeling yes sir I certainly do know
that feeling he said after all it saved
my life I was hired at the clinic about
a year and a half ago as a tremor
as of about three months ago partially
thanks to the knowledge that the podcast
is bestowed on me I made it into the
grow Hey Dude congratulations because I
always talk about everybody having to
start off as a trimmer and you were
proving exactly my point you got hired
as a trimmer you showed that you knew
what to do you showed that you could
listen and show up on time and now you
worked your way up and you were in the
Gro congratulations dude I'm glad you
have made that step level up then he
also says Ross to Jeff thanks to you I
am able to communicate with the people
on my team with confidence that I would
have otherwise lacked dude that's pretty
cool I'm glad that you're able to use
the knowledge and information that I've
given you and communicate with these
people and I'm sure that when you said
specific words and said them in a
certain way that they realized hey this
guy knows what he's talking about and it
got you some respect in the grow so man
I'm glad that worked for you and I'm
proud of you for jumping up so quickly
I'm gonna continue with the email it
goes like this now the main reason for
this email I recently went to the grow
off awards party in Denver we won first
place in yield and flavor this year dude
congrats that's that's a huge award if
you won best yield and best flavor
that's a good job congratulations the
email also goes on to say Philo's
bioscience had a display with the
Philo's bioscience galaxy and i'll say
that again you guys
Philo's ph yl o s bioscience galaxy the
Philo's bioscience galaxy and he said
you were the first person I thought of
this is a website that shows the genetic
ties between cannabis strains it holds a
lot of information aside from genetic
ties such as breeder name and novelty
score the website is Galaxy dot Philo's
bioscience com they mentioned that this
isn't anything exclusive anyone is able
to get in touch with them and add
genetics to the database I have the
contact information of a representative
if this is something that you're
interested in adding your genetics to
thanks again for everything you do for
our community IRA has been one of my
favorite terms since my trip to Jamaica
in 2004 so I shall really use it for the
first time with someone that can
appreciate its meaning always Irie Ben
Osborn hey Ben thank you for the great
email I appreciate it if anybody out
there wants to send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com send me an email maybe
I will read your message on a future
episode now let's talk about the Philo's
galaxy yes I am very aware of the
Philo's galaxy because my grateful dog
is actually part of their website Colin
Gordon from the ethos collective was
kind enough to get my sample of grateful
dog into their database so I read
genetics is actually included in the
Philo's bio science galaxy I really like
the website I think it is great one of
my favorite parts about the website is
an algorithm where you can put in a
strain and it can show you strains that
it has not been bred to and strains that
it is genetically very far from it would
be good breeding ideas this website
knows what genetics are making up each
strain and it can tell you so it
recommended to me that I breed Girl
Scout cookies the forum cut to my
grateful dog because they were so
genetically far apart they did not have
any similar parents that it would make a
very unique cross so it recommended that
to me on the website which I found to be
very amazing because I had already made
that cross and it was [ __ ] tremendous
and I call it Burning Spear and it
already been done so I guess I need to
send a Burning Spear clone to Philo's so
that they can get it in their galaxy and
show that it's been made so that's one
of the great things that the Philo's
galaxy does I kind of think of it as
like an ancestry.com for cannabis it's
kind of like a a family tree for the
cannabis plant and I really like it it's
a really great website it's really fun
if even if you guys aren't breeders if
you were just interested in cannabis
cannabis genetics and you want to nerd
out a little bit on cannabis I
definitely recommend you go check out
Philo's bioscience just poke around once
you get into the galaxy you'll start
clicking and you will be there all day
so Ben thanks for the great email thanks
for giving me the opportunity to share
Philo's bioscience with my listeners it
is a great website cannabis genealogy is
very interesting and once you start
looking you'll start seeing all the
strains you're familiar with and then
you'll see what they're crossed with and
then you'll want to know what those were
crossed with and you'll be there all day
so Ben thanks again for the great email
ladies and gentleman I look forward to
your emails once again the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you let's do a
couple of quick shout outs I owe a huge
shot it's my friend Roger s also won our
and Kelvin Medina huge shout out thank
you guys for the love and support all
right if I don't start wrapping it up
soon this will not be a quickie so let's
get this show wrapped up ladies and
gentlemen make sure you support me on
social media find me on Facebook simply
search for the growth from your heart
podcast find me on Twitter it's at g f
YH podcast where else am i I'm on
Instagram it's Irie underscore genetics
I are ie underscore genetics on
Instagram also make sure you check out
the youtube channel there are a hundred
and sixty videos up on YouTube I'm
trying to get more coming that is very
time consuming be patient with me
I'll get them up there for you also
don't forget about patreon if you feel
like this podcast was worth a couple of
bucks you can go to
patreon.com/crashcourse a little bit of
funding keeping all these microphone
covers fresh takes a little bit
sometimes equipment takes a [ __ ] on me
and of course this MacBook is starting
to slow down and piss me off so it's
almost time for a new MacBook that's
what the patreon contributions will be
used for so I definitely appreciate that
thanks to everybody who's helped me out
on patreon in the past thank you for the
support
alright ladies and gentlemen it's not
gonna be a quickie if I keep rambling on
so I'm gonna wrap up the podcast I want
to give a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]