yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for a Thursday episode of the
girl from Earhart podcast I like to call
these Thursday episodes the Thursday
quickie these quickies are brought to
you by our friends at the hello tank
seedbank
make sure you check them out at dank
seedot store ladies and gentlemen it
won't be a quickie unless we get started
right away so let's get on with the girl
from your heart podcast all right
podcast world I am back with another
Thursday episode I like to start these
shows by letting you know what I am
smoking on today I am dabbing on some of
this lemon og live resin from our
friends at the garden of Weeden I
scooped a little bit out of the large
container I've got a fairly large
reserve I scoop some out of there I put
it into a smaller container and then I
opened up some of these lemon Jeffrey hi
terpene full spectrum extracts from our
friends at apothecary and I dumped the
high terpene extract into the live resin
and I gave it a little stir and I've
been taking dabs of that it tastes
tremendous the high goes straight to my
brain it feels amazing
it's like fireworks and skyrockets for
your brain I like it
great combination so that's what I'm
dabbing on let's keep it quick let's do
a quick update on my most recent
breeding project if you've been paying
attention you know that I've been
working on a blueberry cookies reversal
project I have a blueberry cookies plant
that smells amazing
I have reversed it I took the female and
turned it into a male it produced pollen
I put that pollen on several elite
females I put it on the Durbin poison I
put it on a rise I put the pollen on
more blueberry cookies I put it on
platinum tangi Strawberry Fields and
lemon skunk I'm trying to breed a bunch
of candy flavored sweet and sour Terp
sort of things I'm hoping I've created a
big bag of candy so those are just about
done you guys they are at day 60 right
now some of the seeds in the very tops
of the plants are just about finished
the seeds that the lowers are taking a
little longer to finish of course
they're almost done I will start
chopping those down here in just a few
days so I've got some new creations we
will need some new names soon once
things are tested so that's an update on
the breeding projects I'm gonna let them
go
63 to 65 days that's usually just about
perfect for the strains I'm working with
so they'll be cut down depending on my
schedule and how my life goes in three
to five days and then we'll have some
new stuff to play with
alright so that's an update on the
blueberry cookies breeding project the
blueberry cookies but in there it's in a
three gallon pot it's under a small
white and that bud is as big as my
forearm I am amazed at the size of Cola
that plant put out especially for being
seated that is tremendous
alright let's move forward and keep this
Thursday quickie going I got a message
from somebody on Facebook and they said
when you guys go eight to nine weeks of
flowering are you considering that from
the twelve twelve switch or from when it
actually starts pre flowering just
trying to get a better timeframe on
finishing so this person is asking when
we say that a plant will take nine weeks
to flower are we counting that nine
weeks from when we see the first signs
of Bud set or from the day we switch the
light cycle from whatever our veg time
is over to our 1212 flowering time that
nine week flowering period or whatever
your package of seed indicates that is
from the day you flip your timer to
twelve twelve if you were on a 24 hour
or an 18-6 or a 19-5 whatever your veg
cycle was the day you flip your timer to
12 on 12 off that has now become day one
of week one of your flowering period so
if you're gonna go sixty-three days that
starts now not from when you see bud set
that starts from them the time you flip
so mark your calendar eight to nine
weeks from there and start paying
attention that is day one of flower week
one of flower start adjusting your
nutrients to that schedule start
planning your flowering you're flushing
your harvest everything will go around
that date now something I've got to
mention as a responsible grower a
breeder and educator do not let those
numbers printed on the package dictate
too heavily when you cut down it is a
good guideline it's a good idea but each
plant is going to be different if you
get ten seeds out of a package and five
of them are males and you cut them down
you've got five females left you may
have one phenotype that ends or finishes
at the end of week eight it may be day
56 and that one is ready to cut down you
may have another one that needs to go
all the way to day 60 you may have
another that needs to go to day 63 there
may be one that [ __ ] around and wants
to go to day 70 so you're going to need
to pay attention to each individual
plant start flushing 10 to 14 days in
advance of your anticipated harvest time
but don't hold too hard to that number
pay more attention to the trichomes on
the plant get yourself a scope a
magnifying glass
get yourself a 420 scope or a dope scope
or a jeweler's loupe or something from
the gross store or something on Amazon
that will magnify your trichomes at
least sixty to a hundred times you want
a 60 X or a 100 X magnifier at minimum
so get yourself a light or something
with a light in it and LEDs so that you
can see what you're looking at and a
nice jeweler's loupe or add oaks go up
or a magnifying glass or something you
can get in there and look at the
trichomes and see the trichome color and
the trichome development you want them
to start becoming amber I've got a scope
that hooks up to my computer it's a
dynolite scope I think it cost around a
hundred bucks and I got it on Amazon it
plugs right into my computer it was kind
of a [ __ ] to get it installed to
installed on my macbook it took me a
minute once I got it figured out it
works like a charm
every time I plug it in so get the Dino
lights go plug that into your MacBook
Jerry the computer into the grow room or
carry a plant near your computer and
press that magnifier whatever you're
using press the magnifying glass the
magnifier the dope scope your 420 scope
your Dino lights go pressed up against
the plant and see what your trichomes
look like check in several places the
top is gonna be a little more done than
the bottom in most cases check on the
top you're looking for twenty to thirty
percent
amber trichomes the trichomes are those
the crystals those mushrooms grown off
the plants those skinny stalks with
round bulbous heads
that's a trichome they're gonna start
off clear they're gonna get kind of
silvery then they're gonna get milky
white then they're gonna start degrading
and turning it's gonna look like you
sprinkled dr. pepper on them you want
about thirty percent of them to look
like they've got dr. pepper on them
when you look in the screen you're
probably gonna see depending on how soon
did you've got your stuff and how many
try comes on your plants you're gonna
see between ten and thirty try comes in
that little view on your viewfinder on
your magnifier so if you've got ten you
want three of them to start turning
amber does that make sense
thirty percent twenty to thirty percent
amber trichomes is what you're looking
for when you harvest the number on the
seed pack is a good idea but they don't
know exactly which phenotype you got
they don't know the temperatures in your
grow room they don't know what kind of
grow light you're growing with there's
so many variables that contribute to the
finishing time of a plant that it is the
numbers on the package are simply a
suggestion and a guideline and
unfortunately quite often a sales pitch
why not tell you that this plant is
gonna be done in eight weeks when it
could really take ten weeks but who
knows because I've already got your
money unfortunately a lot of breeders
will do that stuff and back in the day
that used to be a very easy way to
increase sales
you can't do it so much anymore and it's
not something I would do but it can't be
done so much anymore because we're much
more accountable now we're reachable
social media makes the breeders very
accountable anyway that's not something
I would have done but it is something
that has been done people would just
print hey this flower finishes in eight
weeks and you grow it and it ends up
taking seventy days and you're sitting
there going what the [ __ ] or a lot of
people just cut it down early and then
they thought man this plant sucked it
wasn't very good and it was because they
didn't let it go to its full potential
so don't be that guy don't cut plants
down early
hopefully the seeds that you have are
from a breeder who had some morals and
actually wrote down a realistic time
frame on their plants I try to give a
two-week time frame on my packaging or
on my strain descriptions if you ask me
how long will this take I will say eight
to nine weeks or nine to ten weeks and I
try to keep it realistic and I've grown
enough of my plants to know how long
they're actually going to take maybe
some of the other breeders aren't
growing enough of theirs and maybe they
think it only takes eight weeks I don't
know but don't hold too fast to what
that says pay attention to each plant
pay attention to each phenotype the
beauty from grown from seeds is that you
can find something unique you can find
that one maybe you want something to
take maybe you've got cycles that take
eight weeks maybe you've got cycles that
take eight or nine or ten weeks maybe
you can find a plant that fits perfectly
into your system so you could dial it in
perfectly that's part of the beauty of
growing from seed so you get to find the
one that you like you get to find the
one that grows smells tastes and smokes
the way you like but also you get to
find the one that works the best in the
grow room for you as the grower so
that timeframe goes from the time you
flip your lights to twelve twelve that
is day one of that's when you should
switch to your bloom nutrients that day
is what you should base your anticipated
flush time off of that date is what you
should base your anticipated harvest
time off of that day is what you should
adjust your nutrient calendars off of so
day one is when you change your timer to
twelve on and twelve off all right you
guys if I keep rambling on this episode
will not be a quickie make sure you find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your heart a podcast check me
out on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast if
you want to follow me on Instagram and
check out my cannabis photography you
can find me at Irie underscore genetics
also don't forget that eight hundred and
sixty-five videos are available on
YouTube if you want to check out some
old content go to youtube and search for
the grow from your heart podcast don't
forget about the patreon campaign
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast I would appreciate your support
don't forget you can email me if you've
got a product you'd like me to review if
you'd like to sponsor the podcast or if
you'd like to ask me a question that I
would read on a future episode you can
send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I love all of the listener interaction
ladies and gentlemen I will be back
Monday with the brand new full-length
episode I want to give a huge shout out
to our friend cannabis clarity and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
absolutely
and make the ganja Pro under sunshine
[Music]
[Applause]