[Music]
foreign
what's up ladies and gentlemen welcome
to episode 30 of the igro culture
podcast you know who it is they call me
Rasta Jeff thanks for thanks for joining
me for another episode
this podcast is brought to you by our
good friends at Highly Educated titanium
if you're using high quality
concentrates you deserve a high quality
titanium nail made in America don't
trust the chinese nail or an American
knockoff made of cheap metal trust the
industry leader trust Highly Educated
titanium
Highly Educated products are available
at aqualabtechnologies.com Highly
Educated has a nail to fit any rig and
they are the only titanium product
endorsed by this podcast
[Music]
this podcast is also brought to you by
our good friends at
nature'sgreenremedies.com visit
naturesgreenremedies.com for gauge green
genetics La Plata Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Adventure irie
genetics and many more trusted brands
Nature's green remedies is running a
special for the podcast listeners type
in coupon code September 14 for 15 off
any order and you always get free
priority shipping at Nature's green
remedies.com
this episode is also brought to you by
Hydro indoor growing supplies I grow
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 6271 Beach Street Unit F
or stop by the new Pueblo location on
618 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
check out hi girl for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
growing supplies and don't forget to
check out
www.higodenver.com for current store
hours and special sales
biglove to tree thugger.com this episode
is brought to you in part by tree
thugger.com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree thugger.com for
concert and Festival news and reviews
www.tree thugger.com
[Music]
all right guys Jesse came over and we
pretty much wrapped up the uh flushing
and harvesting and trimming section of
the outdoor lesson so I'm not going to
waste any time let's go ahead and get
right to that
all right podcast world we are back
we're here to pretty much wrap up the
outdoor groceries and Jesse's with me
how's it going bro pretty good how how's
it going everyone we're both dabbed out
so we're gonna have another one of those
episodes uh grab some pins of paper guys
you guys uh might want to take notes for
this one I was told that people are
writing down [ __ ] that I say that kind
of scares me oh wow yeah I was at a grow
store I was at Hydro indoor growing
supplies and I was just there to pick up
a couple of small random items and a
lady at the counter turned around and
she said Jeff I know you know the answer
and she made me come over and shop for
her a little bit and honestly the
solution that I gave her I learned from
our good friend Jesse uh what what was
the uh problem she was trying to figure
out it wasn't a problem she just wanted
to know which uh which bat guano to use
late in the bloom season for sure which
one should she have used uh the Jamaican
that's what I told her bro gosh I'm so
glad I was right I told her Jamaican
late in the season and I learned that
from my buddy Jesse nice awesome so I
hope you listen to the podcast because I
told you that you should and now we have
proven that you're right and now I've
also admitted that I was only 90 sure
that when I told you that at the Girl
store
burn knew what she was talking about
though uh shout out to burn you do a
good job at the hydro shop it looks
great I appreciate it yeah yeah guys go
to hydro Pueblo place is awesome yeah we
we got uh some some big news coming up I
I can't say it yet but uh it has to do
with a really popular new lighting
system so I don't even know the news yet
I'm gonna have to grill Jesse here in a
second find out what's going on yeah uh
what else oh we gotta we gotta sell on
the
um
was it Black Label yeah Black Label
Black Label nutrients are they 50 off
um
10 10 above cost ten percent above cost
so whatever check it out guys whatever
they paid for these nutrients they're
gonna sell them to you for 10 above that
but after that it will no longer carry
the line of products yeah it's nothing
wrong with it it's just not a big seller
for us it's a small shop also you can't
carry every single line in there we uh
we replaced it with some Botanical
products and we already sold out of the
stuff we stocked in today so I recommend
Botanica strongly to everybody that I
teach how to grow so that could have
some small factor we're going to carry
every product they have awesome thank
you them and general Hydro products guys
if you listen to this show I don't talk
a lot about the nutrients I use I try to
keep a lot of my uh that's kind of stuff
that I like to let people experiment on
their own Botanical doesn't pay me
anything go to highgro Pueblo support
their new uh their Adventure is it
Adventure their new business venture and
stalking their store with Botanica it's
what I recommend it's what I use I
promise I've talked about grow uh
feeding recipes and [ __ ] and all of it
is included Botanicare uh pureblin Pro
grow the soil based formula it smells
almost drinkable really and for your
nutrients to smell like you would almost
there's I know there's chicken [ __ ] in
there so I don't ever think about it but
well we got that stocked in now so it's
Cannabis Cup winning nutrients right
there yeah awesome I've always um I've
used the uh um
NC oh crap
sn91 or something okay yeah yeah it's
more their commercial line yeah yeah
that's that's good stuff yes you get
what you pay for they seem to pay
attention to what we're trying to do and
they're also good to the environment
they don't seem to be real dirty yeah I
like that liquid karma is a good product
you can add liquid Karma to any feed
regimen and it will help you out uh
they're um the pure blend tea yeah
that's good stuff vitamino is a new
product that they're putting out that is
a good product we got that now too uh
full decks and a foliar spray
good product and ogt uh see none of
these we're not getting paid for any of
these free commercials we're doing right
now it's just this is just from our
heart that's what we do it's what we use
it's high quality products that work
yeah I wouldn't uh we don't talk about
[ __ ] on this show yeah all right so
uh it is time to talk about the end of
the grow season sorry that music was
kind of distracting both of us let's
focus a little bit outdoor season's been
fun uh nobody's stolen your [ __ ]
hopefully you didn't have to shoot
anybody
um I'll accept one guy I'll accept that
one guy yeah hopefully you got to
harvest everything hopefully you didn't
get that frost on it that one night
uh it's coming up guys if you haven't
cut down yet you're a week or two away
maybe three or four weeks at the most
right yeah either that or you're
prepared for the Long Haul yeah you got
yeah you've got a greenhouse covered and
you've got a heater out there so if
you're just out in the backyard it's
really time to get your [ __ ] together
uh it's time to flush flushing is
important even if you're good this is
something that I've always wanted to
touch on on the show let's talk for a
we'll give it however much time this
takes we'll talk about flushing very
important yeah flushing as you're
feeding all of your cannabis plants you
were pouring even if you're using
Organics you're pouring stuff into the
root Zone that is staying in the soil
and your plants are feeding off of that
uh you don't want to smoke whatever
you're feeding your plants you don't
want that taste in your buds at the end
you don't want nitrogen you don't want
phosphorus you don't want potassium in
your buds tasty oh yeah yeah so the
plant actually takes up nutrients
it puts the nutrients where they want
and then yes your plants do spit out the
excess nutrients through the roots again
it basically shits them right out I'm
keeping this real simple what we need to
do now is flush the toilet we need to
get that poop soil out of there we just
want clean dirt for sure and if you're
recycling your dirt this is a good point
this is where you actually start
recycling your dirt is that the flush of
an indoor plant so this works for the
outdoor we want to do this to every
cannabis plant you ever grow before you
harvest it uh 10 to 14 days before you
cut down that plant
water the [ __ ] out of the plant water it
as much as you can and from then on out
only give it clean water just clean uh
PhD if you can but this is the end so
just give it a lot of Clean Water a
water in real well go ahead I'll let you
jump in on a container plants so it's a
20 gallon container I'll give it 20
gallons of water
and that's I I want to see you know
pretty much you'll have
I don't know from 17 gallons of water
come out probably yeah you know run off
that's I drag a seven gallon pot to an
area where I have a drain and I will
pour about 15 gallons of water through a
center gallon pot and repeat it you know
this is yeah just keep pouring water you
get get however much water you can fill
that pot with pour it in there let it
drain through it'll pour out go back in
a couple of minutes pour another pitcher
or a bucket or whatever you're using
pour more water in there
if you can set the hose in your plants
on your pot plants water them until
you're afraid that it's over watered up
you're not too worried about killing
them at this point it is the end of the
season you won't over water them they're
Outdoors that water will go somewhere
you want to get all that nutrients off
there the indoor container plants
Jessie's perfect on that just water that
pot as much as you can if you have to
it's kind of hard to get a plant
somewhere if you're working a seven
gallon pot you need to get it kind of up
off the ground so it'll drain properly
yeah a shop vac is your best friend
there you go if you don't have adequate
kind of where I was headed or uh set
that foot a lot of you guys are grown in
the basement and you got a dedicated
bathroom set that sucker in the shower
put it up on two cinder blocks under the
pot so that it doesn't go anywhere and
that creates a lot of drainage space
that water will pour right out of those
bottom holes of the pot if you've got a
three gallon pot set that put a couple
of cinder blocks in your garage maybe
where you can get some water going or if
you've got a cool backyard where your
stash is kind of hidden you don't want
to don't show your pot plants to your
neighbors and be real careful about
bringing bugs in but this is the end you
got to flush them real good always 14
it's 10 to 14 days with nothing but
water if you had any nutrient burn
problems get in there maybe a week
before you can I don't think you can
over flush
yeah no the only thing you're going to
do is kill it I mean it's going to run
out it's going to be starve to death you
drown the roots because you're giving it
you know 15 Gallons every day right
that's uh you know this is
um flushing will help your plants burn
better
uh they'll dry and cure better they'll
smoke they'll smoke better they'll taste
better they'll smell better have you
ever smoked pot that uh it almost tastes
like you just stuck your tongue in a
light socket like it leaves that burnt
[ __ ] on your tongue that probably had
not been flushed I feel like I can name
the brand of nutrients Sometimes some uh
I've I can taste worm castings a lot of
times in people's weed I can taste
Advanced Nutrients honestly if you
overdo a couple of things in botanic
hair I can taste it if you overdo it and
don't flush it Lucas formula always has
its own
um that's you know I think GH always has
a um it brings out the limonene smell I
think a candy lemony lemon head candy
yeah smell when you use GH I think so so
if you've got something that you want
that is a lemon strain and you want to
bring out that lemon uh feed it the
General Hydroponics also I don't say
this a lot this is kind of a secretive
thing that a lot of us know that one of
those things that you have to like read
a lot to learn stressing the plant with
light strap gas and heat will bring out
limonene so if you're trying to Lemon up
your lemon strains drop that light a
little bit too close around week six of
ripening and you'll bring out the
limonene terpenoid I've heard you say
that that'll also stretch your plants a
little bit so you're going to have to
adjust on that your top leaves are going
to Brown up uh sometimes we're not grown
for pretty plants sometimes sometimes
it's what you got to do uh Girl Scout
cookies is gorgeous right up until about
week eight and then she's so damn ugly
she just goes Mom I'm done well she's
pretty up close she's tall man did you
get the taste her head oh man my girl's
got cookies bag is in another room so
I'm teasing you check out this uh girls
uh Gorilla Glue number four nugget I'm
gonna reach
oh nice I actually haven't seen anything
that's a lot of glue the finished
product of the Gorilla Glue everybody
around here is passing that looks like
an old uh skunk nug or some uh or Cola I
should say yeah that's that's a nice
shout out to uh elbow he does not listen
to the show I don't think but I'll get
him too and he'll hear this
that's well done he did a good job with
that nice Gorilla Glue number four I
don't know if it's ready yet is it
smokable uh it's a little little it's
moist hey there's a nice little crop for
when we get to curing there we go some
people hate the word moist so I had to
throw in moist out there because you
know it does that all right we've kind
of ranted on about flushing the point
here is flush your damn weed we we can
tell the people that can tell can tell
and they're the ones that you want to
impress if it's Hydro uh flushing is
even more important
um
don't really talk about Hydro growing
very much and there's a reason for that
but um I have zero experience in Hydro I
run an easy cloner that's about as far
as I get I've seen uh Sparky weed from
hydro weed uh or from Hydro systems yeah
you're constantly if you've got a res
full of nutrients you're constantly
pumping that plant it's very important
actually
um it's important throughout the entire
growth cycle every couple weeks you
should be flushing
um and using one of those flush products
clear X I was just about to ask how do
you feel about those flush products uh
not necessarily for dirt in my opinion
um but uh for for Hydroponics you needed
to help flush your medium off so and
those things break up salt is mainly
what they do cool they're uh
they're all like a sugar of some like a
sucrose or something so I didn't know
that yeah I never researched what they
are yeah I don't know exactly how it
works I'm dancing all over the mic on
Jeff
I'm gonna get them honed in I'm turning
myself down so that I can turn you up
and it'll make us sound even
I am super [ __ ] stoned so I'm not
getting you very well on the computer uh
talk talking to the mic real good for me
for a second hello really stoned come up
kind of hard I need to come up good
enough we'll keep you going yeah I don't
know how to turn just you up anymore
without making it weird we'll do it
we're cool because if he's too quiet I
apologize we're High yeah sorry so
flushing your plants really good is
really important you want to impress
Jesse and I with your weed and the only
way you're gonna do it the only way
you're going to win a Cannabis Cup is by
flushing your weed yep also you don't
want to give sick people weed with [ __ ]
in it that's not what a caregiver does
it's not what a compassionate person
does it's not what a responsible person
does you're on the other team and you're
growing that weed that should be illegal
you're on this reason that makes
prohibition happen if you're growing
weed that has not been flushed
exactly what he said the look on your
face is like [ __ ] you think about that
yeah not even which side you're on not
even sick people like you know it's you
just don't want to put that in anyone's
body right that's horrible thing to do
to someone
all right so you flush your plants now
it's time oh we're going to talk about
de-leafing
um
after you flush a few days before
Harvest time you want to get in there
and take off the fan leaves all those
big leaves that are in your way if
they've got what's called a pedial
that's the stem that reaches to the
large there's some other people
pronounce it differently you can tweet
me and argue me that's just how I've
read it so you anything with the PDL you
can reach and cut off chop all those
leaves off clean those things out of
your grow room don't just chop them and
leave them on the floor those bring bugs
feed them to your chickens if you've had
a clean grow room you can possibly juice
those if you're into it yeah throw those
right in there with your kale and your
white people smoothie
all right so get in there cut off all
those fan leaves
um you can cut off some of the outer
Leaf if you want but you might want to
save that if you're making hash just
decide how much trichome is on that if
there's not a trichome on it you can
take it off right now like you mentioned
Girl Scout cookies they always have a
little uh PDO coming out of the nug yeah
such a long one too I you know depending
on how far it is like you said with hash
um some of them are a little closer I'll
keep that one on there just because I
see that little little bit of resin on
there and I can get greedy with resin
we're resin Farmers bro that's our goals
um but yeah if it's very long I I've cut
that [ __ ] off you know coming out out
of the bud so clarify that a little bit
I found a knob that'll turn everything
up a little yeah nice all right so uh
cut off all those fan leaves now while
you're flushing you've got a few days
now you know you're flushing you know
Harvest is coming you've taken off the
fan leaves Now's the Time to prepare the
harvesting the trimming and the drying
area you need a space all right let's go
back real quick okay I like that one
more thing
um
how do you feel about like the sweet
eating agents molasses and stuff like
that oh I use this [ __ ] out of molasses
um with my outdoor stuff
um
the first I start flushing really early
um like I actually I started two plants
flushing this week
um
uh I give them two molasses feedings uh
before I actually start flushing and
it's just lasses but it's it's pretty
heavy so I know what's going into my
plants and this is uh so try to keep it
basic because I don't want to steer
anybody wrong I want everybody to learn
the right steps but I do sort of
something similar I feed them enzymes
carbohydrates and molasses at the end
for sure so they'll get some hydrozyme
has the enzymes I prefer and they'll get
the molasses and uh sometimes maybe some
Yucca extract and coconut water
that's Yucca extract and coconut water
and sukanet
and hydrazyme on that last flush yeah uh
day so I've got 14 days that's like day
14 that's uh really strong that and then
from then out I flush but I don't
overfeed I feel like I don't over feed
yeah and I've got plenty of space to
flush properly like I can I drag a plant
to a watering area just [ __ ] hose on
it until it's flushed so that's worse
yeah it's actually just I converted the
old bathroom that was in the work joint
and dinner just the flushing spot so the
guy's got a pee with no stalls my
building doesn't have indoor plumbing so
ouch yeah uh guys if you have all that
stuff that you're taking for granted
you're you're way ahead of the game
sometimes yeah
there are guys that have been growing
since before we could talk about growing
you had to go to the hydro shop with
your hat down in your face dude I've got
dreadlocks to my ass like rent a car I
get looked at like that guy grows weed
even if I'm not at the hydro store so
yeah Colorado is awesome all right so uh
we flushed we've used some sugars and
enzymes and some coconut water and some
Yucca extract you don't have to use them
all at the same time
um you can use these differently the
sukanat may need a little while to break
down so you may need something to help
that happen the enzymes are going to be
good uh
so we have de-leafed uh we're preparing
the dry space right is that where we are
yeah yeah
um very very important Yeah clean up
your drying and trimming space any dust
dog hair hippie hair
uh all the crap that's on my table I
think it's just a bunch of dab resin to
tell you the truth but all this all that
[ __ ] is going to end up in your weed
that you're cleaning up and once again
that's just as important as having a
good flush you don't want crap on your
weed you just spent
70-day flowering cycle plus however long
we took to veg that stuff plus if you're
doing a Fino hunt you're risking you
know you got to tell which seeds are
good or if they're Outdoors
you know that's that's a big plant too
yeah yeah put a lot of work and nervous
nights into it
and have a nice secure area while we're
at it I did not write that down but have
a nice secure area and think about this
if you're making concentrates every
piece of dust and hair in particulate is
going to end up in your concentrate
somehow like even if it you're blasting
butane over it you're gonna blast dog
hair juice into your hash essentially
you know what I mean I don't know
technically what you're getting but you
know that's what you're gonna find in
there it's all gonna end up in your
concentrates you're gonna need so in
your trimming area your work area cover
your table get a plastic cloth you guys
use rubber gloves when you're handling
your plants when they're growing when
you're chopping them
for God's sake please uh you you've seen
how you do fingerprints when you commit
a crime you're doing that to your plants
you're leaving oils and hippie goop and
human goop and Cheeto stains all over
your plants wear some rubber gloves our
oils actually
um
affect the plants for long-term storage
and plants that have been handled with
bare hands uh break down faster in my
experience that makes sense okay I think
a BHO dab you can
decarboxylize a BHO dab enough uh with
your fingers oh yeah yeah I think by
Rolling BHO around in your fingers you
can decarb it enough to be edible like
processed is Delta 11 THC by your liver
that's how well that's like cannabinoids
yeah imagine so if you can do that by
Rolling it in your hand imagine what we
can do to a trichome on a plant you can
pressure it ruin it kill it yeah it'll
even weird oils that are fighting when
you said decarb relaxing I was thinking
of d-waxing and all that stuff floating
oh man yeah
somebody asked me what is de-waxing we
need to get a hashmaker over to say more
technically what it is but I'll explain
it on a later episode
nothing to do with explaining that so in
your trim room you should have comfy
tables you should have some good music
uh everyone's gonna argue over the music
Sorry put on the agriculture podcast
episode one and hit play uh
um I actually like to put up stand up
comedian shows oh that's a good idea I
listen to Comedy I honestly listen to a
lot of Joey Coco Diaz and Joe Rogan yeah
listen to a podcast when I'm trimming uh
one of my favorite podcasts hasn't
posted an episode in quite a while I'm a
little annoyed what's up Adam Mill
where's my new podcast buddy
all right I'm dabbed out we got to keep
on track here we're getting uh into the
show I like it preparing the area the
area gloves comfy chairs good music uh
let's go back to dry area Okay preparing
that drive your dry area yeah
um dehumidifier yeah humidifier yeah
fans possibly possibly a fan or two
um heater and or air conditioner
possibly we're gonna need to keep it uh
between 60 and 70 degrees you can go up
to 75 degrees if you need to if it's you
know in your bedroom or something you're
gonna be all right don't stress but keep
in mind though that heat is
um one of the biggest enemies of a
dragon plant yes and also you want it
dark yeah light I know it sounds weird
you've had all kinds of light beating
down on your plants for months but now
we want it dark we want those to stop
growing and degrading we want to kind of
suspend the animation right where we are
it protects the the trichromeds yes yes
we want to we picked them at the right
maturity we don't want them going much
further we also want our humidity at 40
if we can uh not much more than that if
you go any lower you're going to dry too
quickly if you go any higher uh of
course you risk molds and it's going to
take too damn long to dry if you're in
the Dirty South do the best you can good
luck yeah Us in Colorado it's funny that
you say that because in the South you
read stories they're like so when you
harvest your weed you got to dry it for
20 days and I'm like what the [ __ ] 20
days and then you read in Colorado
you're like so cut it down five days
later you got dried buds you're like oh
yeah they must be must be in Colorado in
February it really varies from region to
region yeah and even like what's side of
the state you're on humans dry out in
Colorado yeah yeah so so you got your
fan you got your dehumidifier your
humidifier try to have if you can afford
it if you can do it put a carbon filter
and a blower in your drying room yeah
harvesting plants stink
very much sorry guys I'm choking on a
dab over here uh harvesting plants
your neighbors will smell it ten times
more than you you've been around them
every day you're so used to it you're so
comfortable with it I've had plants uh I
had just gotten done trimming and didn't
have any plants on me and somebody came
over and they're like damn dude I can
smell your plants from the garage and I
was like I don't even have plants at
this house what's going on it's just me
reeking of trim so I've had lady and
Loaf and joke always tells me I smell
good oh yeah I'm just coming home from
work the people at Lowe's know what I do
yeah yeah you see me and they're buying
weird [ __ ] smelling like dank all the
time the restaurant owners always love
me yep and no he's hungry so you got
that carbon filter also you need a
hygrometer that just tells you what the
humidity is and a thermometer they sell
a great one at high grow indoor growing
supplies yes yes also that is something
you can get at Walmart anywhere in the
nation Lowe's has uh remote control uh
thermometer hygrometers you can set the
unit in the room and then you can carry
the thing around with you and whatever
you're curious you look at the thing and
it tells you you don't have to run to
the grow room and look my dad has one
um it has a chick on it
um and uh he seriously got this at
Lowe's or Walmart
um but when it's hot she's in a bikini
and when it's cold she's in a coat and a
scarf and everything all bundled up it's
hilarious that's a great the mother I
can see your dad smiling at that one
I'm gonna put more heat on your mic
there we go all right so uh we've got
yeah the road the rooms are looking good
we've got a place to harvest we got a
place to dry now you need a spot to hang
your buds or your whole plants depending
on how you want to do it we'll talk
about that in a minute
uh set up a hanging space with plenty of
space between your plants if you have a
small crop you can use a coat hanger put
two plants on one coat hanger if they're
little like three gallon plot kind of
guys if you've got uh
five gallon pot hopefully you've made
enough pot to where you need a one coat
hanger per plant any bigger than that
we're gonna need little hanging lines
from the ceiling uh I use hemp twine and
freaking Hooks and just put hooks in
each end of the wall and run some twine
across some of you guys may not have
space fishing line works good too yeah
fishing line is perfect uh any kind of
string to hang it up you just want them
you know I've seen guys take chicken
wire and make a big cylinder out of it
and that way you got a bunch of hanging
spaces at different layers that's
basically what we do at the farm okay uh
tomato cages work great too yeah recycle
that tomato cage uh you know a little a
long time ago I harvested a crop and
dried it in the hydro Hut that the crop
grew in just took out the light flipped
the crop hung it upside down right
inside there kept all the blowers going
kept the carbon filter going beautiful
crop that was awesome worked very well I
wish I had the space to be able to do
that yes yeah yeah
it's moving yeah
um avoid the drying racks if at all
possible yeah a lot of people were
talking about those online the other day
when I was talking about drying uh those
put a dent in your they make a flat side
on your weed they make it take taste
longer uh when you start squishing the
bud together like that you're messing up
your trichomes and your flavors you're
trapping in air trapping in chlorophyll
you're trapping in moisture which is
what we try to get out raise chance of
mold
um
it centralizes a whole bunch of humidity
um and I've always felt the mesh damages
the bud yeah just shaking around and
stuff like trying to poke through the
mash and then you always end up with I
have to put uh something underneath
those to catch all the stuff that falls
out there's so much that falls off I
always wonder what should I do with this
although that was a few years ago I know
what to do with it I know but I quit
using those so I was like you make BHO
I'm not sure where you came from
um it is useful for if you have gigantic
plants
um all the the larf and the little buds
that you
end up with inadvertently you know so
always seems like you have a pile of
that stuff no matter how hard you try to
fight it don't be mad if you chop a butt
in half on your first trim session
either that happens that always happens
occasionally
all right so we've got the rooms built
up we're wearing rubber gloves
um let's see have everything done before
you chop down don't be scrambling around
yeah be relaxed this is really when this
I've seen a lot of good crops
go right up to the point where it's time
to put scissors to them and that's when
somebody [ __ ] them up or right after
you put scissors to it and trimmed it
and then put it all in a tupperware
while it was wet or hung it out too long
to dry yeah like this is where it counts
you guys if you've spent 60 days 70 days
on a flowering crop let's do the Harvest
Right This is where this is where this
is where the patient's real this is
where the money happens my aunt in a
highly illegal State Grill crop when I
was younger
um and she didn't know how to handle any
of this and of course there was no
information this was the 80s she stuck
it in a black trash bag and then hung it
in her basement and
there were swamps in the area of the
country she lived in and uh or not her
basement but her attic
um and needless to say uh it created a
whole bunch of mold that sounds
disgusting yeah a horrible waste of a
summer's work especially in this Locale
oh yeah rescue time your life for moldy
buds terrible
she was a crazy one so be prepared be a
Boy Scout when it comes to Growing your
crop you should always be thinking two
weeks ahead in your pot plants because
anything you do today you're not going
to see it for seven to ten days probably
anything you've messed up on in this in
the season uh here's your chance to you
know make a little ride of it but that's
a good point yeah get on it so so I
guess this is the time where we are
going to get the plants and harvest them
right
yeah okay uh we should also Branch out
to uh dry trim and wet trim a little bit
before we get too far uh the way I'm
going to talk about how I harvest a
plant I'm gonna hypothetically have a
three gallon pot I'm gonna drag that
three gallon pot with my three foot tall
pot plant over to a nice area where I've
got plenty of space I'm just going to
chop the whole plant
the way that I do it I chop the plant uh
just just above where the first nodes
pop out so that I don't have a lot of
stick hanging off the edge chop that
boom it's unnecessary water flip the
plant upside down I use a fuzzy stick it
looks like a pipe cleaner just wrap that
[ __ ] right around those bottom two
nodes so that I got a nice hanger and I
leave some hanging off and then I tied
that onto wherever it's going to hang
from different situations at this point
I hang in different areas so we'll say
I'm using my main dry room uh just hang
it from the dry line that hangs up there
boom it's hanging in there I myself dry
trim so I've got a plant that's been
flushed de-leafed
um my rooms are clean everything's going
properly now I've just got this giant
wet plant that is mostly little leaves
and just donkey dick buds hanging upside
down in my dry room temps are perfect
so if we were gonna wet trim
this is where uh wet trim and dry trim
would Branch off a little bit right yeah
I believe so okay I just want to keep
everybody on the same page sometimes we
uh we go too fast because we've done all
this and sometimes people are like you
skipped like four days worth of growth
so I just want to keep it all so if
you're gonna wet trim
the difference between white trim and
dry trim is obviously you let your
plants dry if you're going to dry trim
and then you get in there and take the
leaves off what trim you would do it
right now you've cut the plant down you
got to hang it up now it's time to get
in there and chop everything off you
trim it into the bud that's going to be
smoked at this point right uh you don't
have to go as close as you look like you
want to because those little leaves are
going to shrink up into the butt a
little but still do a hell of a good job
getting in there uh Jesse said earlier I
definitely prefer dry trimming Jesse and
I agree that you say dry trimming we
agreed earlier that some of those
Southern States we were talking about
with a lot of humidity you guys may want
a wet trim because you need to get those
leaves off of there and kind of speed up
that dry process here in Colorado
there's not a lot of humidity sometimes
it gets super dry we're trying to slow
it down we need to slow it down we leave
those leaves on so we're going to talk
about mostly about dry trimming this is
wet trim is basically uh I cut the buds
off of the sticks or I have a good hand
sized Bud more in rubber gloves I try to
hold on to just a stem and then I spin
that bud in my hand and just slowly clip
off all of the leaves you can trim it to
your preference if it's going to you if
you're trying to put it to Market you
got to trim that [ __ ] close it's got to
look good take off if there's not a lot
of trichome on that leaf take it off if
that leaf is sticking out take it off we
don't we're not Leaf heads we're
potheads we want to smoke pot not leaves
yep so that's basically wet trim I have
some patients that they don't want it
trimmed at all but they're old school so
uh so I guess you should leave it on the
Sticks no I should say that leave it
kind of on the sticks don't cut it into
two smaller parts because you need a way
to hang it uh you know how the branch is
a branch and then there's a little node
coming off where your buds grow say one
of those little Branch Parts as a little
hook and then you can hang that in your
dry room because after you get done
trimming these buds you want to hang
them up so they don't get a flat spot in
your cure Rack or your dry rack you want
them hanging
so trim them up hang them up
and then let those dry uh they those wet
buds need to dry after they've been
trimmed until you grab them and bend the
stick and the stick should pop and snap
it should just go crack right on you and
that'll be obvious when it happens so
depending on where you are that should
take between five to maybe 15 days just
depending your location and they dry
from the outside in so
um
work the [ __ ] I'm stoned uh we're in wet
treatment still right yeah so like I
mean the outside of the bud is going to
be dry before the entire Bud is actually
dry right don't know
you know get too happy and jump the gun
there yeah it's really going to make a
huge difference uh just slightly wet
buds to dry buds to
properly cured buds this little so
Jesse's learning how to use a straw here
on the podcast
[Laughter]
the the cough wasn't that impressive the
look on his face was like did I just
cough from a straw yeah you did bro yeah
all right uh yeah wet trim I don't do
that so let's talk about dry drip uh
guys dry trim I prefer it it's easier uh
dry trim you're gonna hang I hang the
whole plant I've heard uh people
chopping the brand I've grown I'm
talking about a three gallon pot here so
I'd hang the whole plant some people
chop it into smaller pieces uh if you
can get it into just branches that's
cool I like to let the whole thing hang
I feel like it dries up just the right
speed here just because of where we are
for for indoor plants I totally agree
all right so you're growing those big
outdoor plants you've got to chop them
into smaller parts yeah outdoor plants
with three levels of cages around them
that's not really an option yeah you
can't even get out of the cage and also
I told somebody to cut down the whole
plant and they said I grow a scrog so
you guys are going to have to cut out
branches so we'll just go with this
we'll go we've got a bunch of branches
now uh we're cutting off one branch at a
time we hang those they dry
uh however long it takes just kind of
sort of similar to the wet trim we're
gonna let them hang until
right before they snap when that first
part snaps now it's time to get to work
because your stuff's gonna dry slowly
and you're going to catch up you're
gonna get a little behind in trimming
but you'll catch up yeah especially if
you got a lot of work to do hopefully
you got a lot of work to do yeah had
that thousand watt light remember oh
yeah yeah and the 52 ounces we're trying
to grow outside
foreign
ounce per week is all we need that's a
flashback to an old episode yeah I hope
you guys remember that because I got
where we're headed uh so we got these
dried plants you talk you chopped your
plants down you hung them you let them
dry now you've cut off a stick go to
your drying area and you got your stick
uh pretty much just take your thumbs and
just knock those little dried leaves
right off uh put them get a little
container and have that or you can just
knock the leaves right into that
container because you're gonna make some
sort of concentrates out of that
hopefully or food or something with your
gloves on with your gloves on keep your
gloves on please I don't want to eat
your skin Flakes and your fingernail
dirt so you got these Buds and I kind of
hold it
I don't know I kind of I'm just
picturing the way I do it it looks like
I'm playing Nintendo I got my thumbs
just going and I'm just knocking leaves
off and he looks like he's playing snake
on a Nokia phone yeah texting on the
iPhone that's pretty much what you're
doing you're just holding that thing and
just knock the leaves off you don't even
have to
you can see what you want to take off
once it's dry so trim it to your
preference this little triangle leaves
it stick out I'm actually trimming this
bud that's sitting on the table with my
fingers these little triangle leaves you
can just pluck those right off and then
pluck that off and you can see where the
bud is and where the leaf ends if you've
done it right
oops I use scissors but it's the exact
same process yeah some strains uh Girl
Scout cookies and Yeti uh-oh no scissors
necessary you just roll that around in
your hand and those dried leaves fall
right off yeah and then uh so these
dried nuggets they're pretty much dry I
throw those in a bin and then when I'm
done I jar them up uh that's kind of how
or the Cure process starts for both of
these plants once those sticks are
snapping on your wet trim take the
leaves off
throw it in a bin and they're ready to
go into jars when you're done trimming
everything the dry trim now that you've
knocked the leaves off you got that in a
bit now we're ready to pretty much go
into jars and uh that's kind of where
the curing process would start don't you
think yeah have we skipped anything
I'm sure we have but I'm really stoned
me too me too um
do we want to get into curing on this
episode or do we we've gone 35 36
minutes do we want to get it get into
the Cure or do we want to save that for
another time yeah let's do a little
homework on that all right guys we're
gonna wrap it up I want to thank Jesse
for coming we're going to hang out and
leave the mics on for a couple of
minutes you got anything you want to say
while we're on there
um
the story
I have this uh never mind I'm not even
gonna explain it on the air attention
deficit disorder is that what you're
going to talk about no no
stuck in the old school I don't like
talking about certain things but there's
no reason not to so nah I see yeah you
try to keep well you got to keep the
family life and the podcast life
separate for sure I understand
understandable yeah shoot we're saying
hi to the lady at the hydro store for
sure hi baby
uh dude really thanks for coming you
make the shows uh people listen when you
come they feel like you're an authority
and you remind me of [ __ ] that I would
skip wow that cracks me up but have I
told you we're getting close to 1500
listeners per episode that's crazy isn't
that crazy that's crazy this little
podcast from this little town is
actually making a difference we're
helping people make quality medicine
dude and that's what the goal was that's
what's up oh here's something I want to
talk about I like it I'm gonna get a dab
going uh dude would you pass me the new
dabs a Golden Goat for sure another
paper oh yeah that one there you go dude
this is these dabs are the craziest
looking dabs he said he tipped it when
he was putting it onto the thing so it's
got this Ripple look to it it's really
neat it looks like uh
like the floor of a golden uh pool or
some [ __ ] yeah yeah it looks like uh
I could see a rapper wearing a shirt
with this print on it like it's got like
a Slick Rick sort of look to it I could
see a couple looks staring at that for a
couple hours on actually you know it's
just some kind of some kind of weird
things yeah
sure not to Garden of Wheaton we're
talking about your hash bro it's dank
good work what's up homies
big love to everybody at the Garden of
Whedon
um I need to give while I'm thinking
about it a special special super shout
out to my friend Doug Benson and also
Comedy Works uh we had the time of our
lives Monday night I don't want to brag
too much but look at uh the Facebook
pages and the Instagrams and the
twitters there's like 100 pictures of me
smoking and dabbing with Doug Benson oh
even know the stories you can tell so
it's coolest cool as hell hey uh custard
I said we need to bring up look I even
just stopped myself something from
saying [ __ ] cuss jar there's only this
is only a rule that applies to me but if
the guests want to participate they can
the cus jar if I say the f word the F
word's the only one that counts in this
Kush jar uh if I say the f word you guys
tweet me and remind me every time I say
it on the podcast starting on episode 30
that's this show don't go back in time
and cost me money every time from now
forward that I say the f word on a show
it cost me a dollar okay after a few
episodes if I quit saying if I don't
quit saying the f word I will increase
my donation amount I'll crank it up to
five dollars and then after I'm not
committing to any amount of episodes I
want to see how I do because if I do the
worse I do the more money I have to pay
because it'll hurt me more a dollar
doesn't hurt my feelings but it reminds
me five dollars you go damn that was
five dollars ten bucks you start going
this is getting expensive so we're gonna
increase it slowly I have a charity
um that I have in mind that I will tell
you who it is it's a friend on Instagram
we had a long conversation and he does
deserve the donations it's not an
organization it's actually a person who
needs help it's a sick child so we will
help that kid out every time I say the f
word here's a buck for you what the [ __ ]
there we go you got a dollar coming your
way just to get it started
that makes me want to make you cuss so
right that was kind of a smart-ass way
to do it but it cost me a dollar and it
was well worth it I get to send this guy
a dollar for a sick child [ __ ] yeah
there you go I'll still occasionally see
us so and we're gonna start charging the
guests a dollar two just for that one
[ __ ] that doesn't count you can see that
one all you want [ __ ] yeah what kind of
rambling
I got a big dab here I owe a huge shout
out to my man task Rock I really
appreciate my brand new blue Highly
Educated carb cap isn't that stylish Bro
[ __ ] Yeah it's blue I didn't mean to do
that actually
so uh I'm gonna wrap up this part right
now
all right guys that pretty much wraps up
episode 30 mostly wraps up the outdoor
grow lessons I want to send a huge thank
you to Jesse for taking time out of his
Grow schedule to come and help us out it
seems like the listeners really
appreciate that so much respect and much
love to Jesse make sure you guys follow
him it's at Jesse grows OG on Twitter
and Jesse grows on Instagram give him a
follow we'll appreciate that now that
the show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for igrow
culture find the review section and give
me a five star rating after that type in
a comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode also read all the
stitcher comments Stitcher just recently
updated and it is a lot easier for me to
find the comments so go to Stitcher
leave your comments there give me a five
star review and I will read your
comments from Stitcher as well the
reason I like good reviews and good
ratings is because that helps us move up
in the ranks which just gets us which
gets us seen by more listeners which
gets more people growing quality product
which gets less [ __ ] product out on the
street so we can improve everybody's
Garden by making the podcast a little
more popular
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes Stitcher and every single
episode is archived on I
regeneticscolorado.com
I want to give a big huge shout out to
my ninja Spence I owe a huge shout out
to my buddy Doug Benson shout out to the
crew at Comedy Works thanks again for
listening you guys take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me