yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the glow from your
heart a podcast
[Music]
what's up podcast world it's time for
episode 300 welcome to the show what's
up dude sup guys
ladies and gentleman me on the podcast
awkwardly and highest oh my god
welcome to the show we got Kevin right
in front of me welcome to the show bro
sweet what's up been here in a while man
thanks for coming back well thanks for
coming bro he's good to have you thanks
for having thanks for dabbing with me
brought a sweet new rig or shot some
great Terps yeah made a hell of an
entrance indie thank you brother
also to my left a regular a regular
visitor a repeat offender I like to say
cracker Mike is here welcome to show why
Mike what's up everybody
guys 300 episodes dude yeah that's crazy
business excited for a policy told me in
a long time yeah well welcome to the
show guys ah we got a couple things I
wanted to highlight 300 episodes and
four years I think right around the date
that the show comes out we'll be four
years of podcasting also that's lined up
pretty well then also in February we had
10,000 downloads on stitcher that's
awesome lots of landmarks going on a
hundred sorry I wrote down ten I gotta
have more zeros hundred [ __ ] we're o or
a comma here we'll just change it there
you go a hundred thousand there we go
you guys in February we got a hundred
thousand downloads on stitcher there we
go the celebration sounds yeah sorry
folks right before we hit record I
suggest we all take another dab and that
might have been unnecessary yeah I
wanted to hit one more bullet point and
then we'll talk about what we were
smoking on because I always start the
show talking about what we're smoking on
but we got one more thing we got to
celebrate ah Kevin today on the day that
we were recording is 20 months alcohol
free yeah I said 20 months right right
yes start of the show already 20 months
congratulations brother day I'm proud of
you and that means a lot to me I know it
means a lot to you but I means a lot to
me that you did that right on yeah yeah
it was just a decision I made and
fortunately enough I was able to just
make it and do it
I still hung out with all the same
friends I still went to local shows at
bars and things I didn't really shy away
I was on a pool league so that was all
at bars Wow
you know I've had free drinks offered to
me by close friends and whatnot and it's
just something I don't want it's almost
like tobacco or cigarettes or something
it's just something that's not appealing
it's something I just don't care for and
don't want anymore
good job and I was able to make a bunch
of even more positive changes in my life
so you know it's it's awesome I was able
to get my own car my own place to live
you know have a pretty stable life now
which is much better than it was I was
ruining all the relationships that I had
so completely around and being able to
earn most of those back even with the
people that I hurt the most and was the
closest with is something that I'm
really grateful for and I'm proud of and
I'm just gonna keep going on the same
road and keep building and continuing
life but now you're on a podcast I got a
hundred thousand listen so now you got
some accountability bro
that's cool a hundred thousand people
are rabbit or Nate accountability I got
my own I'm not gonna try to steal your
thunder but I quit drinking a long time
ago also and that point when it doesn't
even become a thing yeah just when
someone's like you want a beer and
you're like for a long time they see if
you want a beer that's a [ __ ] yes
yeah I want seven hold frosty I want
dark beer I want them in my hand and
then I want them in my mouth and then
just hand me another one that's how it
used to be when that feeling goes away
it's just like it's kind of release you
don't have that pressure on your body
your mind your brain kind of drives you
crazy just wanting something that's one
less thing to desire congratulations for
the good job yeah you got my respect
welcome back appreciate it have you back
on the crew back regime you never went
away just sometimes we gotta yeah that's
all I can do and I'm just gonna keep
forward with the positivity from here so
hell yeah appreciate it
do you want people to follow you on any
sort of social meet I'm only on
Instagram right now it's elevated
concentrations all one word
pretty some
so if you want to come check it out I
got drum pictures and ash pictures and
positive pictures and just cool stuff
that I post every now and then I don't
over blow nothing up but I got some cool
stuff I'm trying to say yeah you say
over every day so it's not a lot of
content but it's cool concentrations
check out his hash pictures I love I
love local stuff Ken's been a part of
the the Colorado hash community since
the beginning we've been yeah our
cannabis there you go all of it yes
spread the love yeah we used to go hang
out at the Rhino district we used to go
hang out at Adams place for sure the
events together a stick with me all over
the place met some cool people so
alright cracker Mike since I let Kevin
snake how can these people find you on
social media so they can stop draw me
the two places to do that best our
Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
Facebook or nema 1-15 on twitter emo
Punk 15 on Twitter you guys he tweets a
lot of good stuff he retweets a lot of
good stuff following there's we've been
retweets Lou yeah yeah but make sure you
check out Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws because that's where all the Wonder
have their opposition is growing and all
they're getting bad [ __ ] you guys it's
fun lately come follow me
yeah support Mike just don't when you
find out who when you realize who his
opposition is it's another Facebook
group and they are several dozen now but
they're not educated in cannabis and I'm
trying to be nice Mike I'm trying to be
nice I'm not trying to release the Irie
army on these people I can't be polite
to them and speak factually don't call
them names don't stoop to their level
play like an adult don't speak
emotionally speak with facts and
knowledge and just come and come at them
with respect and care for the cannabis
and the knowledge you're trying to
spread yeah you represent myself and
represent Mike you represent Kevin you
represent represents the industry and
the plant and exactly the patient's one
of the things about our community that I
always kind of shake my head at is we
should not always represent ourselves
well
No yeah a lot of people currently they
show me hatred because I'm a dreadlock
white guy doing a cannabis show like
yeah you're everything we're against and
I'm like I'm all spoken and I'm talking
about I'm gonna do my thing there's
there's ways to disagree and have a
conversation without it being an
argument yes so please do that if you go
interact with mics uh Facebook rivalry
there so I said earlier that we're gonna
talk about what we're smoking on but
apparently we smoke so much of it that
we don't know what the [ __ ] anymore
we started off where did we start off we
started off with some keV tell me about
the the rocket extract that Rockstar
douches what we started with and it gave
me a nice I hiya made me nice thirteen I
should shut out it's got a little bit of
a CBD level in it so it's kind of pretty
nice after a while and then next was
some sour strawberry from garden a weed
in which is quite delicious much love in
respect to everybody in the garden of
weeds good friends good family good
people
amazing extract artists great
photographers huge members of the
community that we need that we love and
respect and support all the way through
to sure on the label or anything where
the flower came from exactly but who
ever grew it was fantastic so this most
recent batch of garden of Weeden sour
strawberry whoever drew that material
was shadow garden of Weeden once again
miss you kids let's hang out more
frequently I go see them occasionally
not often enough so then we shifted into
Mike brought some Sour Diesel live resin
from CSC concentrate supply company it's
just straight fuel they open the jar and
keV goes that's gasoline
like I don't know like a kid licking a
window you can smell right now is
gasoline good job I didn't get one of
those no I just didn't grab one of those
I could have I chose to smoke some
Skywalker batter and I've been talking
about the Skywalker banner for a minute
so everybody knows what that's like
then we upped our game ah that's when
everybody went full art art
we grab some of these Clementine high
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract
crystals that are they're calling it the
diamonds there were two maybe three two
and a tiny piece in here that were the
gram so it's high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract chunks there are
two half gram chunks in this container
we took medium sized dabs and coughed
our faces often then giggled for about
ten minutes and then we had to take a
little break and then we decided to
record and it feels like we may have
taken too short of a break I've got that
like weird my face feels strange I'm
like looking around the room like is
this where we are it is where we are
then after that I thought I'd get stupid
I've got some gorilla glue they're
calling this the ambrosia it's got some
big crystals in there some big THC
crystals and a lot of Turkey sauce I
took a nice sized abyss these guys made
fun of me because when I dabbed it my
face turn different colors Mike's
looking concentrates right now yeah it's
a little diamond sauce right yeah like
geez how much came in that container
originally that's a gram I just took one
tiny that's just a Grammy well it looks
like three from here I know to me I'm
like damn it I wish there was way more
in that container number four that's
because one Kevin brought up the theory
of it it's like nachos I'm calling it
the nacho if it's stuck together it's
one dab dude you just took a miniscule
dab of this Clementine high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract Dimond crystal
imagine what would happen to you if you
dabbed that thing I know that's point
seven and that one right there's
probably point four point two I'm gonna
say that's point six I don't know I'm
just guessing probably point six of a
gram I'd say point six and point three
or 0.6 and point for I would cough til
next year
Mike you're gonna cough just looking at
it
that's impressive I'm done with you that
sounds like the theory of the dude who
sells the diamonds yeah I don't remember
whose page I read that on but I read it
on somebody's was the profile so you
guys it's like notch it no because then
someone's gonna come to your house and
just dab all your chatter I remember
nachos Brothers is like the edible
episode where you were like this is what
I eat and I was like because somebody on
vacation is gonna be like Rasta Jeff
said this so we figured you'll we'll
split it and you know don't eat edibles
or dab like me unless you're experienced
you guys that that will lead to disaster
and naps and I have to add a disclaimer
to the front of the show ladies and
gentlemen we are not professionals but
we do play some on podcasts we
professionals get paid that's where that
line gets drawn all right then yeah all
right speaking of getting paid champions
for me at the start of this episode
which is good because we're gonna take
dad's and just start getting to the to
the fun part of the show ah
if you watch the YouTube videos and
don't forget to watch the YouTube videos
you guys the girl from your heart
podcast YouTube channel ah there are 200
YouTube videos up now which means that
there are a hundred episodes in the feed
you've got 201 through 300 in the feed
and then you've got 1 through 200 on
YouTube you can listen to all the
podcast episodes right now which is
pretty cool I think I'm kind of caught
up for a minute I still need to make
more videos but here's what I'm getting
at all the old episodes have other
people's music in it and YouTube hates
me for that every time I post new video
it's like copyright claim copyright
violation and they're not doing anything
to me they're just saying I can't
monetize the page and they limit things
and advertising for me they don't put me
in other people's like up-and-coming
videos I don't get as much play because
I'm using other people's copyrighted
[ __ ] so if you noticed at the start of
the show I played a brand new track that
was produced by Rasta Geoff with
GarageBand you'll hear some new music
coming up that's why there's different
music I'm trying to not piss off YouTube
so much so starting with episode 300
there will be new music it'll be I
probably have to stop using other
people's music unless
unless you've got music that you have
produced and you would like to hear on
the podcast and you can give me full
permission to use when I put it up on
YouTube and they flagged me and say hey
you can't do this it's gonna piss me off
so don't put some music up there that
you can't give me full copyright and
permission to use so if you've published
it on iTunes or YouTube I probably can't
do it if you would like to make me a
tract or make me some music I'd love to
play your stuff on the show I just
there's a lot of artists out there that
would like to get their stuff exposed
send me a message bro from your heart a
hotmail.com love to listen to your
tracks see what kind of music you got
I'll put it in the background I'll play
it at the start a plate at the end see
what you got that's a good idea I'm
curious what that just did to your inbox
yeah I love it I love what my inbox
explodes that's one therefore you're
supposed to get your message box filled
with stuff it's not supposed to sit
there interact with me guys I love it
send me some music I want to hear what
kind of music you got for me of course I
like reggae it doesn't have to be reggae
well-produced if you're gonna send me
something to start a show in let's
enunciate that it doesn't have to be
reggae that's true but if it's an intro
track it's gonna kick in the door like
wow what if it's Rasta Jeff it's just
gonna it's gotta be [ __ ] it's got a
hit
can I show someone out please do
mark LeBlanc or project 432 I've seen
project four three two I've seen those
guys at the black sheep a couple of
times yeah they open for other acts I
think I saw them open for Morgan
heritage one night yeah I'm good man
pretty decent Bros with the drummer mark
LeBlanc so listen and in a word or
whatever I'll make sure I share this
with them if you guys have a dub track
they got all kinds of extra stuff I can
layer all of the voicing over it of
course I've got mics and editing gear so
just give me some some backing tracks
and I'll do all the work you got
something like 45 seconds long something
about two minutes long and then
something like ten minutes long but I
would use all of those in certain spots
yeah if you're listening go check out
project four three two they're they're
pretty good man they're pretty new
they've
a little over a year and they're doing
some big things so the drummer is pretty
good drummers pretty hot he's been
through a lot of bands he's been
drumming since literally he was one
there's a picture of him youngsters so
they're young dudes yeah so they've got
a lot of young cat energy yeah they
don't have the same that old break a guy
energy they cut youngster reggae energy
it's different mics roll on his eyes no
I'm just trying to picture young reggae
revolution versus my idea how hard it's
been not just [ __ ] get up a little
pokin right now and I know dude if one
reggae songs been flagged by YouTube's
how are the rescued by Mike's not a fan
of reggae
no it's not that at all just us so you
got the Pope Boom Chicka Boom Jack see
if that got get flagged in one song then
they catch it in all of them ouch all
right Mike trying to stab at us you guys
this podcast is not gonna be one of
episodes where you need to get out
notebook and take a bunch of notes
apparently this is gonna be one where
Kevin and Mike and myself get really
high and hash tag they like it when we
ramble now we're gonna teach you about
what it's like in the studio when we all
bake this bug
yeah you guys are kind of just joining
us don't be afraid as long as I can keep
talking everything will be okay I'm not
afraid no one else the sauce your sauce
devolve into giggles four I don't get
afraid of really anything dab related
taking more dabs not not anything dab
related wait till Jeff turns the [ __ ]
your headphones you're hittin it turned
off Mike's mic because I knew he was
gonna cough and he thought he went deaf
the sound in my headphones went to and
when I realized that I explained I'm so
glad that's not the weed and I wish I
had been recording but unfortunately it
was one of those beautiful moments but
yes one of those fun side effects the
[ __ ] all the anti weed propaganda I
sit through every day is like every time
I get a good hit and it rings my bell a
minute I'm like oh is this the weed
psychosis I've heard about am I finally
gonna see some [ __ ]
and now I just get a little higher than
giggle for a minute and come back down
you haven't gone crazy yet from the weed
yeah they say you can't OD on cannabis
but I've been trying you know I'm sorry
this is a point to think where you might
be able to with all the new distillation
stuff but if you took like a big 2-liter
something like drank it of like
distillate probably would get pretty
sick
I'd imagine we've please don't do that
if you've got a 2-liter a distillate no
let's kick it the original equation was
something like 45 hay bales worth of Bud
in like an hour was what it would take
to even approach a lethal dose and when
they did the conversion like they were
probably working with five or seven
percent THC herb I've been pondering and
if you got pure enough distillate in a
big enough batch of it like it's you
still got to get it into the person and
get it absorbed at that point like if
you try to drink a two liter a
distillate about your third gulp your
body's just gonna vomit up four cups of
dislike yeah but that's just a little
coating I don't think my body would even
let me well it's like trying to swallow
a mouthful if anybody would like to
donate a cup of distillate we'd like to
see Kevin
it's for science bro for science so two
cups on this I will keep my throat clear
and keep talking [ __ ] research
purposes I got I'll put up the iPad with
the fisheye lens for this [ __ ] and if
you do don't blame me it's a bad idea
we're Friday do send us music don't
drink
distel holy crap do's and don'ts of the
pie Gemma's just gonna giggle for the
whole show now would you dad question
you looked in the table in awe and had
no idea for a moment where did this come
from
I'm pretty sure his mouth to guess
alright let's get serious for a second
on episode 300 we have done four years
worth of podcast 300 shows we had a
hundred thousand downloads in February
Kevin hasn't consumed alcohol in 20
months there are so many things to be
grateful for Mike's got a healthy
healthy kid sorry Mike I'm trying to
include you in all the celebration here
I didn't know if I was supposed to
mention that so I hesitated at this
point though we're so far past 12 weeks
yeah well congrats on the new one ah
numero dos are coming so having me on
the podcast we're gonna we're gonna get
Mike a small setup with a microphone
that he can plug into his computer so
that we can Skype and do shows together
like that so that he can have a kid on
his lap because I can get away for an
hour to a night I just can't leave the
[ __ ] house is the baby monitor s to
be able to blink behind the microphone
yeah yeah we got you there bro we'll set
you up with something I can't drive
across town to [ __ ] feed a kid a
bottle or change a diaper once we get
another MacBook to replace this thing
that's going super slow we will
get you a microphone and just plug it
right into your computer I'll teach you
how to use a program all you got to do
is open up Skype we'll talk on skype
we'll record you will do the same thing
you can ramble with me on skype just
like you can from here boom sounds like
a good way to produce a [ __ ] load of
content and you can probably smoke
cigarettes I could you can't do that
here
cigarette free zone yeah I have a
tobacco friendly office so it's true
we've got I've got a lot we all have a
lot of things to be grateful for I'm
grateful for all the people that
download listen support talk about share
what's vibrating who is that damn mic
your phone is like a dildo race yeah
just the five great feature on the new
phone I haven't learned all the bells
and whistles yet hey [ __ ] you 300 shows
it's the first one I think I've
interrupted with a cell phone so I've
got that to be grateful for
all right I'm grateful for all the
people that support the show people have
been supporting on twitter facebook
instagram through patreon quite a bit
people are reaching out I get private
messages on all of my social media they
say hey dude
thanks for the podcast people tell me
that I brighten up their day people tell
me that our interactions ah helped them
with their life they just changes their
attitude their approach to life
apparently I'm the only person that some
people interact with which is kind of
neat I'm kind of know I'd rather not go
out in public and deal with a lot of
people sometimes it's just it doesn't
seem like that once you know me that's
one of the community character traits
yeah yeah I was Eve more ofter than
there's a grower for so long that I just
became a hermit and didn't want to do
with other people because then they were
probably snitches or thieves or cops or
a problem if they weren't somebody that
I already knew so it kind of made me
weird you're right but I get a lot of my
social interaction from the social media
people that listen to the show and
interact with me so you guys mean a lot
to me also and I appreciate that
and all the support we do put a lot of
work into the show it sounds like a
bunch of dudes just sitting here getting
stoned today yes it is uh two hundred
and something other episodes is me
putting a lot of work into this podcast
they do a lot of research
I've got you guys can testify for this
show there's a notebook in like three
days of planning yeah yeah just just to
get these guys here like is an
orchestration just to get three growers
in a room together and it takes a lot
i've got notebooks here you guys i've
got notes and days worth of content
prepared and stuff there is a lot of
work that goes into this so for everyone
to reach out and say hey we love the
show thank you for what you're doing
throwing down on patreon all that means
a ton to me I appreciate it I'm grateful
I'm trying to express gratitude as
clearly as possible four years holy
that's that's awesome I remember when
you were talking about the idea of doing
it and how excited you were about like
doing this concept and sharing cannabis
news and just grow tips and whatever
could just knowledge and your love for
the plant and Industry and patience and
it was awesome to see that from the
beginning and to have you still here
with the same passion and love for it
and even more so have developed it into
a semi comedy podcast as well and have
made it a super fun time along with
getting all of the information across
and sharing the lives of your friends
and fellow cannabis industry people
which is amazing you're spreading a lot
more than yourself which is awesome
because a lot of people just kind of get
their self and their idea out there and
you do a lot more than that you you
thank you Mike for most of another show
that I caught advertising print if you
wrote them an email and said I have
spider mites they'd say buy this product
and you would hear him talk about that
product through the entire episode and I
felt that that was kind of shitty but I
didn't want to do that yes I do
advertise things you guys but you notice
I've got two advertisers on this episode
you haven't heard anything about him
you're the one at the start of the show
you'll hear one later two brief
advertisements I'm not gonna bombard you
with them the whole show people that
want to support me they want their
product known we're not gonna crush you
with it I tried to put out like Kemp
said I tried to put out a genuine show
this I don't have a filter
I couldn't keep [ __ ] back if I wanted to
I don't think so I just come out and
express myself and I think it's
hilarious that people have started
saying that my show has got a touch of
comedy to it because that
wasn't what I intended at all when I
started no it wasn't it was to spread
information and knowledge and what's
happening yet within the industry so
people could experience it and
understand the first hundred episodes
Sam I can keep the first a hundred
episodes are me reading a script like
because I wanted to be so I didn't want
to make any mistakes I'd yeah the the
magnitude of my advice to people cuz
they trust me you know I mean I'm going
out there saying I'm the guy to listen
to
I'd better get it [ __ ] right I don't
want to make however many people listen
to that episode they may ruin their
garden yeah so I didn't but I don't
remember I was gonna go ahead Mike I
keep telling you off so I'll let you one
of the things that I mean it was it
wasn't there as much in the beginning
but there was still a good Pete part of
this and it's grown to be a bigger part
of the show over the years but like it's
highly educational but it doesn't feel
like school yeah class feel like you're
sitting there trying to learn stuff but
you learn a whole bunch that's not
because I wasn't a good student because
school was like that but I had a few
teachers that knew that about me
shout-out to the good teachers teachers
that are good cuz all three of us in
this room are bad [ __ ] students we're
[ __ ] here Mike's a Genco kid like
Kevin's a tattoo kid I'm [ __ ] Rasta
Jeff like we were the kid that were
sneaking off gettin high together we all
went to different schools at different
times but if we knew each other you
would have snuck I would have been
suspended for smoke and weed together
all the time yeah yeah so we were bad
students if we had good teachers I would
have gone to school more I had a few
teachers a band teacher that saved my
whole school [ __ ] thing without him I
would have quit going to school he was
like man Nene you have to be here you're
gonna [ __ ] your life up cuz he knew that
I would just show up baked for that
class and he's like I'll give you five
band classes a day and I got to be in
like jazz band orchestra concert band
marching bands recess band basically but
just be here whatever we had good
teachers make a huge difference so yeah
make it easy for people to learn there's
a really directly my teacher but he was
a professor at one time you I think you
know I'm ray Grayson oh yeah no red beer
a rainbow he did a lot for me and my
young childhood
all the way through my life as far as
education wising and how much I am into
the sciences and math and how I can
understand it and everything he did hola
did he ever kick your ass at chess big
sheepish grin once my grandpa taught me
to play chess and Ray would have just
destroyed my Gramps and I have nothing
but respect for my ground makes lunar
calendars every year oh fish anybody all
right runs across that name or whatever
ray Greeson he's a super cool dude he
still does he works all winter on the
summer he goes and follows the rainbow
family yeah he comes usually back around
this area in the wintertime and be cold
run into him he usually I'm on his
mailing list for the lunar calendar so
cool I should be getting that at some
point pretty awesome it's like a little
spiral
the weird the most published story I've
heard in a while all right
I remember what I was talking about
earlier when I was talking about all my
sounded scripted I used to write [ __ ]
out like because I didn't want to screw
anybody up so they were used to research
different topics you'd like I want to
write a show on blank I know enough
about it to do a show and you'd still
spend two weeks now and now I'm so
confident that I've gotten wrote the
three hundred episodes dude I can sit
here I could tell you about anything I'm
not shy I'll tell you everything you
want to know about my life now in the
podcast I love it because it gives me
I said accountability earlier I can't I
can't talk [ __ ] now I have to rethink
everything I'm about to say I've said
things that I've exaggerated me like no
wait wait I might be wrong I like maybe
I'm wrong in that maybe I'm exaggerating
maybe I don't remember that story right
and I have to like think about it cuz
I'm like well I'm being recorded I don't
want even [ __ ] I have to get the
details right right now and it does
something and it also makes me a better
speaker and a better communicator but
I've gotten really comfortable I did I
got to give a shout out to somebody else
do I can't overlook this since I'm doing
shoutouts and given
gratitude
respect to people Wade Ridley what's up
bro I don't know if you listen to his
podcast I don't know I don't know what
happened whatever [ __ ] fell apart there
is our friendship our podcast we went
separate ways
I got no animosity to you or for you
against you with you whatever however
animosity works I don't have any of it
toward you there we go ah I did a
podcast with a guy named Wade Ridley
I was called 7 1 9 the blocks I was ah
hired I guess to be the producer I was
supposed to sit here and run the
microphones and keep the show working
and host a place for the podcast to
happen I have a big-ass mouth it
couldn't be quiet and Wade likes my
opinions and we didn't have a guest one
time so it was just him and I and I
would talk a lot I guess I was his Lisa
at if you will ah and Wade and I did
approximately seventy five episodes of
the seven one nine the blocks podcast
together he kind of taught me sort of
how to podcast he let me embarrass
myself it out together yeah he let me
embarrass myself on a few of his shows
before I had my own so that was cool
shout out to Wade ah bro we're cool if
you ever see me high-five me I got a DAB
for it we'll be alright
I gotta say the same thing I haven't
talked to you for a minute bro and if
you're listening dude like it would be
cool to reconnect and see what's up I
don't know exactly what happened I
probably have a good idea I was a
[ __ ] so but I mean it would be cool
to link back up with you man you were a
big part of my life and did quite a few
things that were pretty awesome for me
too so hope you're doing well bro yeah
shout out to Wade Ridley got me
podcasting also shot at the John Doe
radio what up Tim Martin was oh dang
Wade was the other dude for smoking weed
for the news right yeah yeah you guys if
you would here's here's a brief history
lesson then since Mike just linked all
of that reef it was on the news like a
month ago to my head yeah so I was on
seven one nine two blocks Kevin brought
so I went to high school with not Wade
but I was in the same I drink beer with
the same people as Wade he worked at a
bar that I used to go to we're the same
age
he worked at Phil's I used to go to
Phil's I'd get shit-faced we knew each
other we'd hang out we knew all the same
people we got along but never like hung
out you know I mean we all like we were
all we're friends in that
yeah and Carl grunt like we had so many
things yeah but we had nothing against
each other we'd high-five movers we
walked by but we didn't he'd never been
to my house and [ __ ]
then keV was like hey man I've been
hanging out with Wade Ridley and I was
like men bring him to the house like
just [ __ ] bring him by seems like a
cool guy
I've always liked his vibe we've always
gotten along so Wade and I started
hanging out and Wade and I loved hated
each other like we agreed disagreed on
so much [ __ ] but we were adults and so
we could have great disagreement
conversations and Wade loves to play
devil's advocate just like I do so we
would both just troll each other and
does it would get hot down in the
basement we'd have to come up here and
smoke dabs and calm down to be like bro
that's we can't have this conversation
on the couch down here we got to go in a
bigger space and get like fresh air and
be a little further apart from each
other cuz this is getting weird
like sometimes we want to punch each
other but we'd like man this is good
it's what we're asking for you know what
I mean so we started a podcast together
he started a podcast and I was like that
needs love dude and he's like what would
you do and I was like I've got all this
gear I would plug all this gear out of
there all my sound equipment and he's
like oh like heal it up and yeah so he
started the podcast and then uh [ __ ]
we're doing a lot of podcasts I would
talk about cannabis occasionally and he
would feel like he would give me this
vibe of that's not what I want to be
doing like he would kind of rush me
through it but then cannabis became
recreational legal in Colorado and I was
the first person to purchase
recreational cannabis in Pueblo Colorado
at the greener side on the south side at
stem Beach it's now called doctor's
orders
it was the greener side my buddy Hank
used to own it as a first person to shop
there wait and I I got to be on the news
for that so Wade came here after so I'm
like back every news station in Colorado
picked a dispensary kind of at random to
do what Jeff did the day marijuana first
became legal in Colorado like every
every news channel had they're the first
customer yeah um and it was cool that
you were the one down here for our right
KOAT
I don't remember yes KOAT
five-and-thirty I'm pretty sure pretty
sure Michelle San Miguel was the
reporter that helped me out so I met up
with Michelle right after I walk out and
then we talked she interviews me and
then I come home and I call wait
where are you bro we should record about
this and put it on the podcast and he
came over here he goes I got a better
idea
let's go down there and so we drove back
to the greener side and Michelle San
Miguel was still there and she came up
to me and she said hey do you have any
of the weedy bought earlier I was like
no it's at home she goes we want to
watch people smoke and I was like oh
it's illegal to smoke out here and Mike
and I kind of looked at each other and
mike is Mike's a little more
level-headed than myself Mike's a little
a boor of a different thinker I got
caught up in the spirit of the day I'm a
rebel
I'll cowboy the [ __ ] up I'm I I'm down
to break the rules obviously and I
looked at what it was an insane day like
doors a dude driving by throwing weed
and planted people yeah just Brockville
4x4 plants and he'd pull up and honk in
half the line would run up to his truck
and come back like what do I do now and
then run her plant to that car and then
try to reform a quarter mile long line
it as best they could from many people
people were certainly smoking bowls and
joints in that line and security guards
are walking by going please put that out
guys and they just walk away
they just they'd have to do their job
until you not do but they didn't do [ __ ]
the helicopters overhead getting footage
it was crazy oh man yeah there was a
chaotic day but Michelle San Miguel was
like can we film you guys smoking
somewhere and I looked at Mike and Mike
just came of it yeah dude I don't see
why not
and I was looking for guidance like tell
me why we can't go smoke weed at my
house and let the news film it yeah no
reason why not so I was like yeah my
house here's my address and then she's
like we'll give you like an hour we'll
be there in an hour so we drove here and
everybody put on and I read genetics
t-shirt I think everybody got all decked
out and then we cleaned up the table and
put some props on the table you know
like put the right products in the right
places and did what we need to do and
the news came here and filmed us filmed
me taking a big old dab on the news and
filmed smoking a joint and filmed filthy
Wade and his filthy mustache smoking a
joint they've got a scene that they like
of me hitting the pipe and then the
scene of you hitting a dab apparently
they love ya I used to run into that
reporter it's City Council and she would
bring it up at least three or four times
a year unfortunately she moved away and
got assigned to another area but she was
fun any time she had it
I said headed any time she had related
questions you just call me she's like
hey I need to interview somebody about
this who would you send me to and half
the time I'd be like oh that's a Mike
thing just go straight to Mike don't
even call me about these types of things
here's Mike's number and she would text
me hi I've already taught or I already
texted Jeff he said this is a you
question yeah a lot of the political
stuff I just wave right over to Mike so
anyway
Michelle San Miguel comes here we smoke
and then that ends up on the news it is
part of the ABC World News or something
the bacon player yeah they can play it
whenever it's been yes but it was one of
the major news organizations they own it
and they play it on their [ __ ] all the
time when they talk about cannabis so
Mike and Wayde and I are seen worldwide
movie role now yeah all right but Wayde
and I talked about that a lot on the
podcast on the seven one nine the blocks
podcast and that kind of before Wade was
like nobody wants to hear about we
nobody wants to hear about weed but now
that it was legal and it was
revolutionising revolution it was a
revolutionary topic I can take myself
out of holes pretty good it was a huge
topic Wade would give me some space on
the podcast to talk about it and then he
got bored with it he didn't want me to
talk about it as much and then his
relationship and I and the podcast he
kind of quit doing that podcast and it
kind of fizzled and he moved to Kentucky
and then I started doing my own show I
was like we had both shows at the same
time and he didn't want to do my segment
so I just sorted doing a whole weed show
and that's kind of how we came to the
podcast so without wait I don't know
that I would be doing a campus podcast I
had talked about it there I think there
was enough bad information and that was
pissing you off at the time to the
degree you were outlined in a book for a
while yeah and there was no chance to be
putting out a book because I've got a TD
and it changes so much I was getting
ready to be like dude I'll ghost write
that [ __ ]
well me what to say I would go to
Spencer in Matty's house all the time
the garden of Weeden crew and spins well
they would invite me over and then we'd
get high as [ __ ] and I didn't want to go
home because I didn't be here a home
alone and Mady and Spence and the dogs
are there but Spence would get high and
want to go play with this plants and
Maddie would just be sitting there
sometimes they'd have other people come
over and this guy
Micke kept coming over and asking me and
Maddy apologize she's like I'm sorry he
has so many questions I was like I like
it he's making my brain spin he's making
me think and I love that about the
podcast it makes me a better grower but
Nick kept asking questions and then Nick
left and Travis came over and asked the
same [ __ ] questions and Maddy's like
god I'm so sorry it's the same [ __ ]
question I was like you know what I'm
gonna start recording this like and then
I was like no wait I'm really go I was
kind of a smartass joke I was like I'm
just gonna put my phone out and just
record it and then the next time
somebody asks I'm gonna hit play but I
was like no wait I've got a podcast like
I can just go to a podcast and that's
gonna what a lot of what started it so
the book idea and you're right people
pissing me off on the forums I saw
people telling people to use coffee
grounds to fix nitrogen we had a bunch
of conversations of bad girl information
then I'd bring up a bad dab information
and we can't let three people who were
fronting for the entire community
continue to do that [ __ ] right other
voices alongside them absolutely so
that's sort of how this podcast started
at number one ended up to 300 I want to
drop a clip that goes this is sparta
right now the the accountability piece
like
when you told me how many downloads you
got in February about [ __ ] I was like
cool I think I've done my last show for
a minute
I kept refreshing that that's a lot of
zeros yeah yeah yeah I do other social
media and some of what I do
kicks you out viewer metric and that's
just I never saw this show reaching that
many people I can't believe you stuck
with it this long
like my when I first started I was like
I'd like to get a hundred episodes and
when I hit a hundred I was like well
that's easy
I'm just getting good at this I felt
comfortable now like around 75 I think
73 63 ish whichever the uh there's a
perpetual grow and there's a dry and
cure episode I was like I'm [ __ ]
positive drag here 36 I've had to look
it up so many times you're right in the
rain I was getting a rhythm then and
then when I got the new intro song and
then I'm gonna write a name down just
cuz I have to give a shout-out to
somebody I don't want to interrupt us
there's a lot of amazing shows you know
who made me a huge hugely better
podcaster you guys if you're trying to
start a podcast and this is really
really you're trying to start a podcast
if you're trying to improve your podcast
if you want to know more about
podcasting there is a guy named cliff
ravenscraft the pug yes that's for me he
is known as the podcast Answer Man ah
he's changed he's rebranded himself he
listened to his shows we're driving
places far dude that guy tonight he
didn't get it the first two shows but I
buy the third one I was like oh now I
[ __ ] get it I could hear it in the
podcast yeah it made me a better
podcaster it made me a better producer
it made me a better social media manager
it improved it just made me the way that
cliff ravenscraft this is since the ad
he told you you would hear later right
right yeah go check out cliff
ravenscraft sorry he he just he'd taught
me a different way of thinking in
different ways of approaching things and
I I'd like it he just opens up your eyes
and it's free there's so much free
content he's got so much paid content
I've never paid for any of it Florent a
ton I could only imagine what I'd get
from the paid content but podcast Answer
Man com cliff ravenscraft is the podcast
Answer Man he'll teach you so much [ __ ]
about podcasting you'll see where I got
a lot of my ideas and inspiration
I owe him a huge shout-out I don't know
that he'll ever listen to this but I've
got to mention him because without that
dude this wouldn't be here alright
gratitude it's what I've got read down
the biggest word of my pages gratitude
and nacho theory alright you're thirty
scares me my throat's dry I'm gonna take
a drink
what are you guys about drinking debs
rambles yeah is gonna say let's ramble
about something then get some dabs going
we've been going for a little bit here
we can get silly again it took us a
minute to get back on earth do you have
a favourite show you've been on keV or a
favorite podcast a moment at the moment
I asked when we were talking about who
was on the first episode I got thinking
about why I knew that offhand and I
recently went back and listened to a
couple of throwbacks and just started
with number one again I kind of feel
like a bag of dicks for not remembering
that you weren't on number one alright
I'm always here if I've been on more
episodes than any other guest by a mile
44 is preoccupied I think I really liked
the first one because it was just really
just informational there's one where you
guys pretend to be excited about having
been at the cup when the couple is just
a brutal experience and there's a minute
where you're like so we're gonna talk
about the cup next week and then it goes
into the next show you're like so we
were at the cup
big events are challenging there yeah
they are it's fun but it's they are
theirs we've invented the way to do
things so much in Colorado but we
haven't got the cannabis consumption
friendly event down - no we [ __ ] it
all up I think the first few events we
nailed it and then we got legalities
excuse me we got legalities involved and
it ruined everything yeah but that has
to happen at some point
yeah you can't throw a regular party for
more than eight people my thing is those
events have I don't know how many people
went remember the candidate the last
cannabis cup at the expo the small place
yeah where that traffic jam of people
happened where you couldn't walk
anywhere they were just stuck you were
like physically stuck was that the one
that got reamed because of the [ __ ]
huge crash the next year yes that's
exactly yeah those events are
challenging because you have to park
three miles away
you got a park and then walk with all of
your gear I've got and I'm not trying to
sound like a [ __ ] but you've got your
product that your whatever your vending
you've got your product then you've got
your dab rig you've got whatever else
you're bringing it's Colorado so you've
got a hat sunglasses a [ __ ] jacket
like you got layers of clothing because
it's Colorado you got a backpack it's
just challenging to get from the car to
the thing and then there are so many
people you got to stand in line forever
then the events are super crowded and
then it's challenging because Kevin and
I have a different approach to the
events than most consumers we aren't
your average consumer were there to see
other industry folk and Indian consumers
and this sounds egotistical and it's
weird for me to even think about it this
way but consumers are there to see us a
little bit they want to come talk to
Rasta Jeff and I love the social
interaction but after from [ __ ] noon
to 8:00 at night your voice starts to
sound like this and you're like will you
shut up because I want to check my text
messages and eat a sandwich
throw a big concert or whatever that
never sounds worth a [ __ ] and every time
I see a cannabis themed concert and like
I'm a fan of some of the bands that
always do them but I see the line of it
I'm like dafuq why and he's mid 90s
hip-hop ends most of the time it's
already 4/20 can't we just have some
good music they're getting better like
they're getting bigger name better acts
now and there's another event that's
actually booking top acts at our current
right now shoutout to to our friends at
the chalice festival they don't pay me
to say any of that but revolutionising
cannabis festivals Charles is doing a
race shoutout to dougie Doug he's doing
everything right I don't care if he
loved her he glass alright I think that
dougie does [ __ ] well like Doug he's a
good businessman love him or [ __ ]
hate him he's he's killing it he's doing
it what are you doing
it's perfect I got a dab right here of
this gorilla glue number for the
ambrosia shake in one of the islands huh
yeah it's just so gorgeous folks yeah I
wish I take some pictures of it but I'm
gonna just smoke it I think it's
probably the weed talking but you know
in the movie where they do like the cool
3d map of the [ __ ] island that
they're gonna go to that's kind of what
it looks like in the jar like there's
this beautiful sea of [ __ ] Terps and
then there's just these [ __ ] gorgeous
little island chain of icebergs icebergs
sure it'll icebergs in there to see how
this things about to like your ship I
was thinking more like full of life
rather than sink your ship but both are
eggs a little bit of both yeah the way I
do it yeah they're more ice then dream I
would you also describe these as piss
yellow thanks when you said ice I get so
nervous around people they don't know
what dabs are cuz they gotta be like
what is he [ __ ] doing if you want to
hit this on camera or in not heavy
consumption company you really need a
hat with giant bold white lettering on
it says this isn't cracked Mike can you
tell him about patreon while I take a
DAB are you capable jeff has a patreon
account you should hit it up that was
good
tell him what it is patron slash girl
from yarn tell my patreon.com slash girl
from your heart is a way for the
listeners to help contribute to the show
you can contribute any amount of money
it to the show that you like from a
penny to a lot of pennies we encourage
people to donate four dollars and 20
cents to any cannabis related anything
just to let them know kind of which
community you're coming from but if you
wanted to help cover some of the costs
and expenses of the show and now we're
not talking about the hash I'm talking
about microphone covers and earphone
cables and that kind of stuff you can
hop on man and help Jeff out yeah he's
trying to save up for a MacBook people
so it's a whole lot of patreon
contributions but the patreon
community's been killing it the the
community's just been absolutely
wonderful lately so
keep the love coming and we thank you
very very much that's good Mike that's
pretty good for adlib minute guys if you
go to paid spot an ad before yeah you
build it that's why just did you Brad
I'm all stressed I'm all stressed you
guys if you go to patreon.com slash go
from your heart I've made promises
excuse me I've swallowed and said I've
made promises at the same time I've made
promises if you contribute certain
amounts I have promised to do certain
things for you go check that out also
I've made specific goals I'm not just
begging for money with no goal I put it
up there clearly what I'm gonna do with
the finances so if you'd like to help
out I would appreciate it yeah I got you
dad Mike you can't be like for Deb's
patreon.com slash core from your heart
is what I was trying to see you guys
thanks for the love and support thanks
to everybody's help me out you guys if
you can't contribute to patreon please
listen to the podcast it's free for a
reason some people can contribute thank
you if you can't just keep listening
your listens mean the world to me you're
supporting cannabis that's right you're
supporting our efforts if you can't
contribute and you want us to support us
more than just listening tell a friend
or 17 tell all your friends just blab
about the show retweet it share it
alright guys I'm off on a ramble now I
just like a big old dab some gorilla
glass is so impressed with the where the
shows gone now he kind of at the bottom
of the nail a little better yeah bottom
where the floor meets the wall right now
he's just trying to clean off the layers
so brother it's gonna taste good that's
that is the taffy so it's the LA Fe and
the
Tangie I think I just have the gorilla
glue number four part of it came out of
my nose oh yeah it kind of burns but I
feel like I get so high when it comes
out of my nose those are burns cause it
burns
there's something good and bad about it
it has burned all right this would be a
good time to read that ad I was talking
about it feels like we've got some some
dead sorry about all the coughing Oh
should I just turn down your mic do you
remember what number you are three all
right Mike has turned down cab you're
still live so don't say anything too
dumb I'll try not to you never know with
this care all right check this out you
guys this podcast is proudly brought to
you by our friends at pol grow systems
PL grow systems putting you in control
check out this read they gave me guys I
[ __ ] love this they know their
audience they know who I am they wrote
this okay this is straight up from them
you've just taken a nice bad dab and you
get that burning desire to check on your
grow room but you're too stoned to move
PNL grow systems the minder lets you
check on your grow room environment from
right there on the couch simply log in
and get the information you need and
that's no exaggeration you guys
plpl grow systems sent me a unit to set
up their website is great you open this
package you go to their website you sign
up you created an account you register
your device you put your device in the
grow room it will tell you live readings
of your temperature and humidity and
more and you can log in anywhere there
are other devices like this I'm not
gonna bash other products there are
other devices like this that I've talked
about that I've used and they're great
but you can't log in from anywhere and
view them with the PL gro systems unit I
can be over at Kem's house and dab it on
the couch I could be a bit Liberty Point
eat and launch and I can login and I can
see what's going on to my grow in real
time which for a guy with OCD like me
for a guy that loves his garden like me
it's really helpful so I think their ad
is great because it's accurate how many
times mics get enough to just leave mics
like [ __ ] this I'm so high I'm going
home how many times have you been
somewhere and you're like I kind of want
to hang out okay let's get real how many
times you been hanging out with a fine
ass girl just [ __ ] it beautiful you're
like oh tonight might be the goddamn
night
and I need them look at the temps and
the humidity and you can make sure
everything's cool in there check the
moisture sensor make sure the plants are
moist
if everything's cool we probably hang
out for a little longer then he could
relax and enjoy yourself but if you
don't have a kill growth system unit you
can't [ __ ] log in and check it out
you're gonna have to go home it's gonna
be freaking out the only thing getting
wet tonight are the plants that's a good
[ __ ] hand shadow to our friends at pl
grow systems uh I support them they
support me you should support them as
well thank you guys for the support I
won't do any more ads in this episode
you guys that is it but make sure you
check it out P&amp;L gross systems have
their website right here I'm trying to
get my iPad to light up but it was
really far away so I had to reach for it
and their website is pl grow dot systems
check them out let him know that roster
Jeff sent you please alright no more ads
you guys I promise I promise ok have
you're awful quiet Oh not bad not bad
and they're funny i watch i watch
youtube videos all the time and you
can't get through like five minutes
without getting an ad it's kind of
[ __ ] YouTube kind of decides where
they throw that ad that you I think I
know but it's all you know it's
frustrating what I hate though is I
watch fish videos at work cuz I'll just
put on YouTube and go type in a fish and
then just let it play fish eye dude fish
plays like 15 minutes song yeah in about
eight minutes is where you get like your
huh and they'll go you'll be like we won
this episode you're like what did what
just happen it's like a tide commercial
with new Tide Pods you like snow [ __ ]
your Tide Pods get out of here happens a
lot or they die they play on the reggae
Channel they put McDonalds commercials
and I'm like that's poorly aimed like
Rastas aren't gonna go eat McDonald's
it's highly unlikely you should put a
vitamin cottage or a sprouts commercial
on here or something you might have got
me whoever pays man that's the truth
well I guess you're right
Mike's back you okay I walk back into
just a podcast bro how was your day
getting better every man I since the
right approach did everybody get a good
dad mine came out of my nose and I can
still feel it still Gotham perfect
cabbed you get stoned over there do you
need a dabba Skywalker you just be a
patient over there
a Skywalker dab if you sure I'll take a
Skywalker dab I couldn't really decide
what Colorado problem oh this one's
gonna be a combo cuz we finished off
this Skywalker you're gonna get a
Skywalker taffy a scaphoid AB let's
sounds worse than it is
sounds like jealousy to me like you want
another big dab I'll give you one bro
you ready sir huh need a minute lungs
are still fluttering
you're still sweating like actively he's
just thinking about he's sweating I
think that's a drool I think that's
drool keV you're just drawing for the
coming man all right it's a little taffy
a little Skywalker you got you a torch
you got a real pretty rig shadow to our
Frank camp bowls glass with the dope rig
yeah I really like the banger it's like
three times this thick is anything I've
owned it's just a super thick version if
you go to the store and see the super
thick one that's the one Kev's got yeah
they just had the regular one the last
two times I was shopping I guess yeah
get yourself a bubble cap that's what I
think people have been digging on the
core reactor banger I it doesn't I'm
it's not hot enough for me I take too
big of a dab for it I feel like I know
people are gonna say that's [ __ ] but
I want my dad's hot it's for cool dabs
it's not designed for a hot dab I do
cool dad yeah it looks like it's for
cool dabs and a large supply for a lotta
butane
you're supposed to heat this bottom part
to keep that big piece in there hot yeah
but as soon as your dad hits it it
really cools it off super quickly when
you put a puddle in there I put a big
big big dad's lately I don't know why my
dad size is just so cabs over there
heating the nail until it's going to
reshape itself I think yeah I'm good bro
I'm just cleaning it all right
burning off that muck yeah do that every
now and then give it a good clean make
that turf taste good well then you know
go in right now hot and her t-bird three
two one red means go red means go Mike
you ask Kevin what his favorite moment
on the podcast was do you have any
favorite moments of the podcast episode
100 is a serious standup okay Wow who
was here for that one was that garden
okay this this place was packed yeah
sloppy and Joe were sloppy joe we're
sitting over there in the corner dry
davon dried to having they take a dive
out of the email and no water in it saw
he's like you trying to kill me
yeah I shot it too sloppy holy [ __ ] I
remember one saw he used to rap in the
basement at the garden of Weeden house
in the garden weed and getting weeded
and now sloppy is legit on tour with ICP
like sloppy came a long way yeah yeah
slops on tour with ICP go check out
shampoo shampoo sloppy or something
similar
sloppy nine one nine dead god that's all
sloppy's brand and stuff I'm sorry guys
I can't keep bugging
I'm gonna sound like an old guy right
now but the youngsters change their
names and their handles and their rap
names so quickly that we had to pick one
and own it well I think he's a youngster
and it's been an evolution we've got to
watch him evolve from one version a slop
to the next to what he's become now
which has been a blessing to watch one
of your friends go from rapping in the
basement at Spence and Maddy's I
remember when Maddie was like my buddy
slop he's moving out here in a little
while you're gonna like him you guys
will get along and sloppy cam and I like
it's [ __ ] cool like I totally get
along with sloppy like he's down his
[ __ ] and then he's like I'm a rapper and
I was like everybody's a rapper and then
he started rapping and putting out beats
and I was like I dudes got it going on
he can actually do some [ __ ] and then he
tried this new thing and then I was like
god it's coming together and then you
started putting out videos and I was
like it's coming even more together and
then one days like guess what dog going
on tour ICP and all these other names
that I don't know but I mean I'm like
as ICP and I like these you're doing
something bro he's got a guy in his crew
that wears a giant foot or giant toe
costume that's getting real famous also
yeah shot at the sock [ __ ] you just
marry killed yeah we are old like the
same time I'm essentially smoking future
weed it's a weird dichotomy here I'm
Colorado it's a great time to be alive
one of our buddies rob was like are you
smoking those weird crystals sure yeah
the the crystals are no it's it's a
different high it's like 90 something
percent THC and it really hits you
quickly can mess up a good podcast real
fast
I haven't soured do sold in a while and
this is a new gram honestly so I'm not
super familiar with the ride on this
particular gram so I can't say how much
is which but I feel like we need a
project smoked himself and do it do
something mode yeah we should do
something that I look down I'm like
you're talking to a microphone right now
we take some of that tour get something
done finally
oh that was the Skywalker leftovers and
the taffy on top of it good yeah it's
the batter garden of Weeden made that
also ok I'll be alright don't worry if
you guys need more bottles of water let
me know I've got to back up over here
just raise your hand to show ya it's a
tube water bottle kind of show we can do
that occasionally Mike covered patreon
so that's fun I covered the other ad
that I talked about though it was good
you did a good job dude
it's not at all prepared for that out it
wasn't two of them so episode was 100
was your favorite
anything else stand out for you
there were a number of grow episodes
that I remember anticipating like I knew
they were gonna get recorded cuz you
would tell me like oh so-and-so is
finally emailed me back we're gonna set
up a show - it's gonna get recorded on
Wednesday - it's gonna drop on Monday
- like furiously taking notes because
that was this step I was gonna be doing
in a month right like that kind of [ __ ]
that I really enjoyed in going back and
listening I got to kind of relive some
of that nice a lot of fun on the show
I've had a lot of fun I've laughed a
couple of times - I've had to stop
recording one of my favorite times now
that I'm thinking about it I smacked my
elbow on this chair and I turned to get
up to do something I guess I hit myself
this week so I was getting to get up and
I hit my funny bone and I was still
recording and I just sat back down I was
like mother I just hit my funny bone I
just talked myself through it and I just
left the mic on and I put that in the
podcast and I was like that was kind of
funny there's a some of my favorite
moments or mistakes I've made a dumb
[ __ ] that I've said and I'm just like
I'm not even gonna edit that whatever
I'll just keep going because it I've
edited some I've stopped editing that
crap out now because I'm a human and I'm
gonna stutter and stumble and say some
dumb [ __ ] and I like to show that I'm
kind of human a little bit when it's to
clean it feels overproduced and if I
wanted that I'd still have an am/fm
radio perfect yeah he'd listen to our
bell probably not that sound like the og
podcast remember you'd be driving home
from a concert late at night you might
he lived in Denver I had to drive
[ __ ] two-and-a-half hours from Red
Rocks back in the day and the only thing
we didn't have podcasting and [ __ ] back
then I'm old you guys I'm sorry it or I
was on Phish tour I used to travel
around the country and go see fish from
place to place and we had a tape deck or
a radio in the car and once you listen
to all the tapes in the car you like
just put on if it's night time if it's
like 10 11 12 o'clock at night cruise
the a.m. channels and find George Noory
and art bell and put on some coast to
coast I feel like that was the og
podcast right there that's kind of where
that [ __ ] kind of got started I've never
spent enough sound on the road to have
to go to am
oh man no I just learned a new thing
about you that makes me see different I
don't think there was that much
difference between the age of my age but
apparently and includes some am
listening in our 20s my brother Bradley
got me addicted to Coast to Coast AM
radio these guys talk about aliens and
[ __ ] conspiracies
that's what does it to be you'd be
driving you can get this all across
America yeah yeah you can call in a talk
to women contribute talk about goes
[ __ ] my trips you can always catalog
the tapes or maybe some books on tape no
we did no I don't like 20 shows a
widespread panic tour at summer tour
2001 we needed something to listen to us
yeah I thought this was all the drugs
but apparently there was plenty of a.m.
yeah I would imagine the mix the drugs
of a.m. together yeah that's there was a
stirring element I didn't understand
previously and apparently it was
listened to fish all night and then and
radio god it wasn't politics I am so
into politics it's like semi
embarrassing talk radio is that one
family member used to love talk radio
shows about politics on AM radio in it
near at this point in the world and at
my age I should be way on top of
politics and I would get an F in a
political sciences class right like they
can't you're not alone yeah I'd get a
[ __ ] a in Instagram I'm currently
watching our city devolve into Obeid
about a research study that I'm the only
person who's read but there's a lot of
people trying to debate it so I've given
up on trying to get like the masters to
do [ __ ] correctly it's all about bro
science now nobody cares what science
says it's what bro science says it's
what with it what it feels like
o or what you see oh and that's
everybody gets a trophy no one who
[ __ ] like that's what I studied in
college was like how this [ __ ] gets done
and why it gets done and who does it and
what rules they follow like that's what
I studied and so to see shake it butcher
like this like I've kind of given up on
humanity this week I'll be back next
week folks problem
let's uh turn this boat back around
before mike has everybody you committing
mass suicide on the podcast I want to
get back to gratitude my gratitude
[Music]
shout out to all the people that use the
hashtag I like it when you ramble
hashtag I see those and I [ __ ] love
hashtag yeah I was just at hashtag - but
shot it's all the people that support us
on the social media that is really funny
guys to put out an episode and then
within hours to start getting comments
about hey that episode taught me this or
hey needed this that shit's really cool
so all that interaction the people that
like to just listen to us ramble that's
really fun there are a couple of people
that said I was depressed or bummed or
whatever and hearing you talk about
whatever put me in a better mood that
[ __ ] means a lot to me like that is
really cool rescue in your garden
putting in a better mood that's awesome
I'm grateful for that
there we go I turned it back around Mike
you can't crash my gratitude ship don't
poke the bear I wish you could have seen
his face is like Bucky I'll crash this
thing for good you brake levers in that
speech you just gave which I liked by
the way and agree with most of it but
there are a couple of points I'll turn
this podcast right around that's another
thing I should say a lot of people tell
me about how they look forward to Monday
because of my podcast people that have
yeah Monday can kick a person's ass
Monday [ __ ] us up and we love our job
most of the time Monday's so [ __ ] up
when people have a [ __ ] up Tuesday
they describe it as having a second
Monday
like that's how [ __ ] up mondays are
but have no fear cuz Rasta Jeff is here
to fix outlets even being me sometimes
the podcast is like I will go to bed on
Sunday like man [ __ ] I ain't ready for
Monday but at least the shows coming I
walk into the office at work and Mike is
listening to my podcast sometimes in the
office sometimes he was on it it scares
the trimmers yeah sometimes I need to go
back and listen what the [ __ ]
know of how many listeners happen to be
listening tonight that Oregon's screwed
up a bunch of their ID checks the first
time I won't repeat what I said but it
wasn't my proudest moment on there I did
not edit that out
I might have told you just told me you
were gonna and then I listened like a
month later and I was like mother [ __ ]
that's why people been sending me word
tweets I usually listen to the show and
I follow the topic stream so if it's one
I'm really looking forward to I make
sure to listen to it but if I wanted I
damn sure listen because sometimes we
get really high and I I say some silly
[ __ ] we can be gettin high and saying
some silly [ __ ] shot up to bone Ellis
what above we miss you Bo get a show
going we miss you yeah we do we do we do
I miss your Twitter interactions you
guys uh if you want to hang out with us
more if you like what I if you like
listening to the podcast you can find me
on Instagram wife I've been on Instagram
live a lot lately you'll see what I'm
dabbing you can see what we're doing I
hang out you can throw out questions and
I will answer them right there on the
Instagram live I actually put episode
number 299 was a chunk of Instagram live
clips put together so if you enjoyed
that let me know I'll put out more of
that type of stuff to throwback thursday
episodes are gone you guys there's no
need to do that I threw them all back I
caught us all up everything's up on
YouTube so it's just gonna be
straight-up
normal episodes I'm gonna try to do two
a week we're gonna do Thursday quickies
and Monday full-length episodes and then
occasionally I'm gonna put out those
Instagram videos so I do plan on bring
any more content you guys we're at 300 I
have no plans of stopping there's no
reason better gear yeah just keep
getting better at it you guys are
listening more the interactions are
going crazy yeah I want to go to 500 now
I want to go to a thousand I'd be I
think Joe Rogan's is one of the only
podcasts that I listen to that's made it
to a thousand episodes you qualify that
with that you listen to right there's
only a few and my favorites lists that
have a number more than a couple
okay Logan's like it almost 1,100 which
is Kevin Smith's guy like 40 podcasts
and I listen to a couple of them and
some of them that are [ __ ] years
rogon does three shows a week on average
and they don't know how he does in
[ __ ] three hours long because he gets
[ __ ] up on caveman coffee and alpha
brain and just [ __ ] his the topics
are amazing like he brings on the
coolest [ __ ] people some of his shows
have been really really good I end up
watching for the guest yeah that's I if
you walk through the trim room at work
that's the number one agreed-upon
comedian and podcast is Joe Rogan
they've just been we kind of hit a spot
where we were tired of giving each
other's [ __ ] over the music choice and
so they've been doing just it's sort of
like Pandora for comedy yes and you get
three to six minutes per artist it's
never like a long bit or the first half
of their DVD or anything like that it's
just one or two fifth oh this is [ __ ]
great that day flies I love walking in
and trying being a comedy nerd I love I
pride myself in being a commentator I
love to walk in mid bit if I'm passing
through because it's on the way to the
men's room or the front door if I'm
passing through the trim crew I'll stop
and be like who is this
oh that's Mitch Hedberg live at this
place 1992 or whatever you know I don't
know Hedberg dude but [ __ ] I can tell
you how that chapelle off of this
recording
let's Rogen off the Rocky Mountain High
recording trying to name him or whatever
and the tremors always laugh at me I
gotta make a note in garage banks I just
saw something that I don't like it's
okay just gonna be do we listen to a lot
of newer like R&amp;B and rap and I don't
know any that [ __ ] but when they switch
to Conway I was like oh [ __ ] this bill
burr ever forever and they all look at
me like how the [ __ ] you I use a fun
little changeup this way because Bill
burr is a savage all right you guys my
throat's starting to burn out odd do you
guys want to keep going you want to take
some dabs and start wrapping it up
Hazzard what are you doing on time oh
all right I'm down to keep going I'll do
some editing and make this podcast not
as rambly I say that check my phone and
see if it's true right I'm gonna press
pause real quick and make a correction
in GarageBand just want thinking about
it
gone here
alright guys we are back we are well
medicated we are well hydrated I've got
a big fat dab of the taffy the taffy
that ruined Kevin's life I got some of
that on the dabber here I'm gonna heat
up this nail and take a fat dad ruin to
me we took a little break to get a drink
we took a break to fix a technical issue
with the computer and the mic here we
are back on track as we took a break I
remembered that I wanted to talk about
the strain episodes that we've been
doing those are a lot of fun I was
mentioning how much fun I have I felt
that it would be very egotistical to go
online and do a podcast about something
that I bred and hype up my own [ __ ] that
felt kind of weird but once I did it
everybody responded so well ah those are
a lot of fun you guys I have a lot of
fun doing those so look forward to more
of the strain report episodes coming
from me I'm not gonna do them too
frequently cuz I'll run out of them
there's only so many to do but maybe as
they create more I can try to catch up
and do backlogs and stuff but yeah the
strain reports those have been a lot of
fun Mike I'm gonna take a dab will you
ramble for me I'm trying
what what strand reports coming next
what we got to look forward to ah I just
did once I haven't planned the next one
yet
good times keV what are you looking for
with the podcast over the next hundred
episodes I mean just a continuation of
because I'm not really a grower per se
so I'm curious too I don't know where it
can go for where it needs to go from
here I think what he's doing is spot-on
I like letting the thing I'm hoping to
see is more guests I don't think I'm
alone there and I don't mean more me
right there's more people it's hard it's
it is hard we need to find a better way
to do guests like well we need a studio
that's better located yeah being in
Puebla is rough you tell people pueblos
and they take two steps back and check
for their wallet like attend them to
come down here like now including this
private neighborhood I can go to places
it's just I'm consumed by the current
project we're working on
that's got me overloaded and sometimes
I'm not sure when I'm gonna get to
record who's got a everybody I want you
to get on the show that's also true for
ya so no I know I know why it is like it
is so I was gonna say I just like
letting the show kind of evolve I do
have plans and ideas but it's doing its
thing perfectly you know I'm not gonna
take too many sponsors so you won't get
too many ads oh we support the holiday
theme company or who the vendors are
because that's kind of a symbiotic
relationship there I always plan to
share what I'm smoking on stay honest
keep the people up to date and one thing
I've noticed is in early episodes I had
different ideas on some things I've said
do full your feet do not follow your
feet do follow your feet okay now do
follow your feed now don't like I've
changed my opinion an idea and I'm glad
that people have still respected me
because I've changed my opinion I'm
gonna keep doing that I'm gonna keep
giving the most updated advice that I
can give when I learn more and I'm not
gonna I'm gonna try to not be too
prideful and too egotistical to say hey
I've changed my idea now this is the way
I would do it now because there are
things I'm doing way differently now
and I have ever done before that's
that's a big part of the reason I think
you're the level of grower that you are
is because you didn't learn away and
then sweep to it I watched so many
people fall into that rut like sort of
like it was a cookie recipe and then
they would struggle with different
genetics because it didn't like to
follow the recipe right um and just
watching you learn several different
systems over the years has been fun I
mean it shows in the herb I've managed
three large commercial facilities ah
technically two because one wasn't very
functional I left because it wasn't
functional I've managed three large
facilities and I've ran countless small
home grows and I've consulted on
hundreds of home grows
yep I've been in enough grows I've ran
so many plants bit I was doing the math
on it I think last year
they threaten to kill people for the
number you bout to say politics but
mister are you saw that story yeah I
brought it up in front you are trying to
kill us for having too many plants yes
the numbers are large it's not like
anything you've got don't worry but the
past where you live in like how many
pounds and we can disclose this number
how many pounds last year do you think
our production facility produced many
pounds of cannabis we produced last year
out of that facility
whenever I see on the news that like
they busted a house and it had this many
plants and it had this many pounds and
it's worth this many millions of dollars
I always convert that to like the
product that went through the room that
day right in chuckle so there was that
approximately we're gonna say 700 pounds
of cannabis plus however many pounds of
trim in one year in my first year at a
facility I ran another facility for
approximately a year and my first
harvest there was 321 pounds so I've
produced over a thousand pounds of
cannabis in two years
fair I'd like to say I've got a little
bit of experience right and then in the
process to learning too that I only post
my good pictures to Instagram I post my
successes the way that I learned the
most was my fuck-ups I would if I had 10
close to teachers Mike saw me grow buds
that were the size of NFL footballs
stacked on top of each other but when we
cut him up the middle
they were moldy it was an 11 ounce plan
all moldy up the middle white rhino buds
the seriously properly inflated NFL
football it was gorgeous
Kevin looked at me like oh you got junk
no and that's when I stopped when I
stopped literally shopping with any
other provider caregiver was the day I
saw you take that find it throw the
entire thing in the trash bag and go
that that wasn't [ __ ] with that it
was all moldy but but no I wanted other
places where people will like cut around
it but now I know not to grow football
sized butts I have I have taken plants
and fed them
oh it says to give it 50 mils of this I
give it a hundred and see what happens
and done that like we have done
everything we can to torture a plant on
purpose here that's kind of that's how I
have gotten good I wasn't afraid if I
had 10 plants I only need 9 to finish I
got one I can experiment with so if I
was gonna do something weird just pick
one and pick an experiment for this grow
and if it dies you got none you only
only plan on living 9 only fun on having
9 live to the end be ready to kill one
play with it the best thing about your
crop of weed that you're growing right
now is it's not the last crop of weed
that you're gonna grow God willing I
have some faith most of us are able to
grow again most of us are like we're in
Colorado most of a lot of people in
California Oregon a lot of people are
gonna be smart they're gonna follow the
rules
now they're gonna be the screener be
careful right now the markets changing
really fast and as it changes
who's doing the growing this changing
very true very true there was a thing
that came through here when legalization
when medical happened everybody went to
the gross torn I bought a grow light
mm-hmm then a year and a half later
Craigslist and
yeah nothing but grow lights everybody
had gross [ __ ] for sale because they all
buy all the fancy equipment that the
gross store will sell you and they say
go do this and you'll be able to grow
and they go home and they can't grow for
[ __ ] because they didn't listen to a
podcast I didn't buy books they didn't
do their homework but they don't realize
that it's that it's like getting help
that has me when people ask me like what
what's the most important thing I can
have in a grow I'm like the [ __ ] book
yeah like it's a hundred percent the
knowledge some time and dedication it's
not just gonna be walking there once a
day and look at it and leave you gotta
[ __ ] take care of things there's work
to do every day when I see people
looking for like I want to be able to
have it hidden and it needs to be the
size of a kitchen table is smaller and I
need to be able to just look at it once
or twice a month and I'm like then go to
the weight store yeah all right or if
it's only that important to you checkout
love for the plant those guys have a
micro grow master a camo micro grow
there's three beautiful micro grows but
like it's the hands-off ignore it
component that I don't understand at all
yeah no matter how much monitoring an
auto shoot you have you have to be there
you have to know if there's a spider
mite if there's powdery mildew you have
to defoliate you have to put trellis up
you have to work the canopy into the
trellis I like to pop the stems I just
call it popping them I grab them I would
grab here and I'd grab here I guess
that's about a half an inch of space
between my fingers and turn and it goes
it makes that noise I like to break all
the plows start there sound effect and
work my way all the way up the plant and
then I'll start with the lowest branch
and work up each branch every branch
gets all popped all the way up about
every four to six inches apart I'll pop
each plant a hundred times if it's a
decent sized plant pop pop pop pop pop
will leave there with our hands bucket
looking all calloused up on pop day but
there's work to do every day
you got a trellis imp you got to pop
them make sure everything's working if
you got an auto water system how do you
know an emitter isn't clogged we get
clogged emitters we get clogged filters
pumps burn out [ __ ] goes wrong
fans burn out molto helps burn out yeah
light bulbs never burn out at the end or
beginning of a cycle it's always about
week six when everything's big emotion
[ __ ] obnoxious and you got a move
get up there oh yeah shit's gonna go
wrong oh and it needs that attention
every time I've seen somebody try to do
I mean even like a four day vacation I
bet it's just everybody gets tackled why
don't you go do this and I'm like are
you gonna come here and take care of the
plants there was the old video that I
saw on YouTube and I'm pretty sure it
was so cool in his first sentence to the
crowd is shut up we all have to get home
in a day and a half the entire room they
didn't even laugh they just went clip
yep because all of them immediately got
the joke understood why it was made
realized it was true for them too and
wanted to hear what the man had to say
yep because just when you're in charge
of a crop every time you shut that door
the clock starts it's like well Mike and
I run a large facility when we drive
away I look in the rearview mirror like
is anything on fire is there any smoke
coming out so I've only got like 12
hours to leave here before [ __ ] starts
going wrong and we come home and record
a podcast and go take care of our family
life take a poop of shower and some food
get back there make sure nothing went
wrong when it's on that scale and it's
not like other industries where they've
been doing it for a hundred years and so
the industrial version of what you need
is time tested and and updated and so a
lot of our [ __ ] we have to do on our own
and it the start of every day is go find
a little broke and most days nothing
broke but the day you don't check
everything broke everything yep you
gotta see how it goes in and I watched
family members that grew every time they
would come up to Denver and visit for a
day and a half their [ __ ] would die and
so it got to the point where we were
like hey we've got tickets to a game and
they were like [ __ ] off every time I
come up and visit for two days I come
home but no livelihood and I have to
start from scratch it's why people don't
realize they got to give me like a solid
week in advance if you want me to do
something Saturday you should have hit
me up last Saturday because I have to
get the plants on the right rhythm to be
gone overnight Saturday because if I
water on Friday
and I can't water I'm Saturday before I
leave because then they're gonna be too
wet I got a water I'm right before I
leave for whatever we're doing Saturday
night got a water we're gonna be gone
overnight Saturday gonna leave in like
noon Saturday and then get in the car
and [ __ ] go so I can be back Sunday
before they start getting to drive in
that with that's what makes me ripping
in my hair every time I hear somebody
like well it's just wheat anyone grow it
and I'm like no people tell me that just
try to force me to grow weed because
everyone I'm like no I can't
yeah anyone can also make hash bro I've
run into this at every level from like
serious business owners that have
invested millions - newspaper reporters
and city officials and police and
friends and it's just oh it's easy
anybody can grow weed and it's know like
it's an acquired skill that takes years
and years and years of training to even
get close anyone can do grow weed but I
mean depends on what your target is it a
lot of people are just growing weed at
home do it and they're throwing some
light they got a an affordable light and
they're doing it they're satisfied with
the product which that makes me happy
but to grow to make a profit or product
on a commercial level on a reliable
scale that's when you start getting into
a lot of nuances if you want to figure
out dial in a strains nuances and trying
to your things properly like anybody can
just throw some seed or a clone in there
and they can make it happen and if
they're satisfied with that that's cool
I'm proud of them and I want them to
smoke that and love it but if you want
to take it to the next level it's gonna
take some skill it's gonna take some
learn it's it you can teach I would say
can teach probably 60 to 70% of this but
40 to 30 to 40% you're gonna have to eat
beside me
every day for a couple of weeks to
figure it out like there's [ __ ] that I
can't even teach you through this
podcast through a video you got to come
touch the plants a trade more than an
equation yeah yeah you're gonna have to
look like to tell you how much exactly I
want to foliated we have to stand back
from the room and I have to show you
like the whole room instead of one small
section and then I'm like I know it's my
view of aggro is way different from
other people's I think it's fun like
teaching new people how to do it our
scale because you don't especially with
that task it's not something you can see
until you're done with it I have to
teach people say we're defoliating a
table we've got our average for average
room so room a is 40 lights room a is 40
lights and it would take two or three
dudes an entire day to properly do
foliate for a week to defoliation the
way that I want it for proper light
penetration if we put the right people
in there if we put the wrong people
there don't tell him to move around it
would take four hours to do fully one
section really heavily and the rest of
the Grove would just be leafy so I've
got to tell him to listen to a song and
every song move to another table listen
to a song and every song move to another
table because they're not used to such a
large growth they think they're gonna go
in there and defoliate that room left to
right yeah and I tell them like just
walk around the table like just kind of
always be shuffling up into the layers
right and just work your way like a
typewriter dude you're eating a piece of
corn yeah I don't want
Table one to be naked and Table three to
be super furry so just start give me a
level one manicure a level to a level
three and just work your way back and
forth it's hard to get people yeah
because they think they're gonna go in
there just like their home grow that's
one light I can leave this in like an
hour there are 40 lights in here if it
takes you an hour to do the one at home
that's 40 in here Plus these are much
beefier plants cuz we got kavita's and
curve oh [ __ ] it charge really tall
ceilings
yeah ridiculous HVAC and Rasta Jeff Tech
and trellising all day so they're beefy
plants in there it's gonna take you
quite a while to reach in and trellis
all that [ __ ] that middle
it's hard for me to reach I'm six five
gonna let imagine what it's like for the
unresponsible prototypes the bottom I
know how are their reach is that why
they're in the dirt yep only only metric
[ __ ] Oh God only metric certified
people know why that's funny all mics my
tags are in the dirt you guys plan on
all you [ __ ] plants are [ __ ] three
feet tall the tags not a happy place to
be so if you work in a metric regulated
facility wherever metrics in like
Washington and Colorado most legal
states have adopted it so if you work
with metric and you've got those stupid
[ __ ] metric plant tags that are
supposed to be affixed in such a stupid
way I'd find that to be obnoxious I wish
it would hang so that I could read the
tag instead of have it anyhow
ah here's a thing for you to do I had
somebody helpfully recommend we do it
the other way walk find your metric or a
compliance person mike is my personal
[ __ ] this is really funny this is really
funny I want you to walk walk out of a
grill room with a perplexed look on your
face most of you have it already because
you've been in the girl room and even
smoking dads will [ __ ] date and the
lights are brighter like huh find your
compliance person or your metric person
and walk up to them and say hey why
don't any of the plants in room a have
tags on them and just don't say that you
know so all what if they like they're
like five things that have to absolutely
happen in a girl you have to have a
badge on if you don't have a badge on
you gonna know numero uno ya gotta have
a visible badge above the waist at all
times these are either a visit I feel
weird right that I can see it like
that's how close I keep that badge when
I go if I leave if I leave I take it
with me if I go to other dispensaries to
shop I take it with me because often
times you can get a tour if you're me
and they're like you got your badge like
yeah come on back like if you don't have
it you're [ __ ] you just missed your
chance for a tour but it brings
opportunities sometimes and you also get
a discount
in the industry but number one you got
to have a badge number two where am I
getting plant tags like number two or
number three is every plant has to
Colorado pretty much - as plant tags
yeah you got to have a black tag maybe
badge license on the wall plant tags but
waste accountability you gotta weigh the
[ __ ] waste yeah that's things that
people [ __ ] up on all the time we just
listed both components of my job yeah
yeah keep track of plant tags and making
sure all the waste and then and then
Mike does all the weighing and packaging
and it's like yeah like 99 percent of my
job is first part that people would be
like man I just want to go wait weed all
day Mike's like I gotta weigh the
[ __ ] weed all day like it's literally
that's what I'm doing all day tomorrow
for eight hours I will be putting weed
on a scale and writing numbers down yeah
absolutely for eight straight hours but
the number two thing is those plants
have to have a tag when I cut a clone
off of a plant I have to find that tag
and write the strain name onto a piece
of paper the mother plant that tag
number that the clone came from and then
how many clones came off of it and the
date and then that sticker has to go
with my clones at all times then once
those clones are put into a medium of
anything they come out of an EZ cloner
once they're rooted Mike has to
immediately take this Lippman list is
made when the clones are cut goes into
the computer as clones as soon as
they're put into dirt Mike moves them
into another section the computer called
vegetative stage and then they get these
tags every single one of them has to
have a tag Mike Lohner holds a hundred
and eighty clones and for those of you
who don't know about this particular
task in detail each tag has to be filled
out by hand
so Mike writes chem for chem for chem
for chem for chem for chem for I do
about 40 clones of each stream because I
want to fill the rooms with chunks you
know this seems to be the Simpsons were
parts at the chalkboard I never
understood how much that skill like in
grade school would come in handy later
in life I was I was that kid I did it is
Matt but now it's like [ __ ] Sour
Diesel Sour Diesel Sour Diesel
[Music]
my favorite is uh when you write gorilla
glue and nobody can read what the [ __ ]
it says yeah golden goat we like what is
soldier cloak what a soldier cloak we do
we get some new genetics here no we just
got an [ __ ] they can't [ __ ] right
you got it right and sharpie and if you
use a fine point it's not legible unless
you've got the tag pressed to your face
which is fun cuz sometimes they fall
into the dirt which is covered with
nutrients and sometimes they get sprayed
with sprays which are full of sprays so
you don't want that [ __ ] in your face so
you gotta use the fat Sharpie which
[ __ ] dolls after like to cook to
tanks so you wind up [ __ ] right with
like a goddamn paint brush and I can't
write for [ __ ] to begin with in my
[ __ ] y'all don't even get me started
Jeff too late I like it anybody who
fills up that tags is 100% with me
promise to you thanks for joining
why don't we get you see the labels I've
got over there bro like for my for that
those labels they come out of that
normal printer not compliant from what I
understand we can't just print those and
stick them onto that pretty sure the
stick is non-compliance s might be cuz
the stuff that's written on the front of
that in the back of it like I'm I would
have to talk to someone above me about
that okay I've never seen another
facility do that so my idea may be
non-compliant you may be correct because
we could just buy the printer in the
right tag my guess is that anything you
stick isn't gonna hold right because of
the wet and moist just yeah now they
make plastic ones it'll be perfect or we
stick them on the outside of the [ __ ]
plan either way either way I'm cool with
it metric tags go in there walk out of
the room with this look on your face
like what the hell happened then walk up
to your compliance person metric person
and say what happened all the tags in
beanie and they're gonna have a little
they might pee themselves just a touch
just depending on their anxiety level at
the moment they might pee themselves a
lot depending on how long metric has
been spinning around likes to give you
the wheel of death you try to use metric
and it just shows you on the screen just
spins the cursor just goes mmmm not
today [ __ ] it always happens it
nine times out of ten metric will freeze
when you've got a delivery driver
waiting to pick up and you're just
waiting to print the manifest because I
know people would say why don't you
print it before they come because if you
put a driver
and a car license plate on a manifest in
print it I [ __ ] promise you a
different driver and a different car
will show up one of the two will not be
every time and you have to reprint you
cannot it's it's a Colorado regulated
thing after reprint you can't wait it
out or if it's gotta go back to the
internet you got to adjust it in the
Internet then you got a permanence you
just wait from the show up because if
they say Kevin's come in at 4:00 in a
Honda I guaran-fucking-tee you Mike
showing up at 5:00 in a Nissan that's
[ __ ] the medical marijuana industry
that's how it goes no it's gotten better
but yeah we've got some drivers that are
actually pretty punctual and we pissed
them off because we take a long time and
actually I like it when they're on time
and stuff it looks much better for this
industry then one dude shows up way
early and that ain't cool the other dude
same time every week every day every
pickup I love that good yep consistency
that's how you make me happy at work and
you guys if you are one of the drivers
and those little silver Sprinter vans
that's doing pickups and dispensaries ah
bro you guys you look like Hedy wooks
no nothing against the head he looks
Kevin Love you bro I got my hat pens - I
got my grassroots hat I got my baggy
pants I got my [ __ ] Merrill's I'm
[ __ ] - what the [ __ ] out I got
dreadlocks down to the floor don't you
guys when I see that paired with work
equipment when I see that look in that
van I'm a good person but I start
thinking like some [ __ ] Ocean's
thirteen [ __ ] how to give that [ __ ]
van in my garage like and you guys
you're kind of you're totally
identifying who you are and what you're
doing this is it's legal now
yes but [ __ ] are still
[ __ ] you don't have to worry
about the police but you have to worry
about thieves and be safe please I know
that sounds like the old man just preach
to you but when you're all worked out
and that Sprinter van I know what you
got and I'm a good person but that
doesn't mean that everybody who has made
that correlation cuz you see you see him
in Denver in the right lane lost his
[ __ ] looking at their GPS going where's
live well and just [ __ ] there's
driving a Sprinter van dreadlocks and
[ __ ] hat pins and a hoodie [ __ ]
leaned up over the steering wheel high
as [ __ ] like you guy can spot him I've
seen a couple of them when I've been out
I Drive dinner frequently and you got
the Sprinter van
with the [ __ ] refrigeration in the
back so you got concentrates or you're
picking up and it's obvious and you're
not an armored truck and you've got more
[ __ ] in you than an armored truck would
we kind of keep that in mind you guys
let's try another if you're on the other
side of that token hey there's a bunch
of a [ __ ] hit yeah maybe if you're on
the other side of that token is what
your [ __ ] hippies driving around in
Sprinter vans cuz tip me out that's all
I'm saying commission as we come out of
the shadows we need to remember why we
did some of this [ __ ] we did the shadows
like I remember how good it felt to be
free here and how much I wanted to walk
about to everybody be like you know what
I like weed and that's all and then just
log off that's because it was felt like
it was there was so much [ __ ] heaped
onto it for so long and when we finally
got to the point where like as a voting
population we said [ __ ] prohibition
we're done with that [ __ ] weeds legal
here like regularly go get it at a store
legal like that was before we went
overboard with the rules and regs and
[ __ ] but like I remember how good that
felt and I remember why we shed a lot of
the stuff that we had during the
Prohibition days but do now they're
busting like 30 guys a week who were
just growing a hundred plants in their
shed and every one of these
[ __ ] they bust them and they're
like what were you thinking and they
were like I thought it was legal I just
want to [ __ ] slap these people like
you're ruining it for the rest of us
what aren't you getting like I get that
it's still thirty five hundred a pound
if you can get it all the way to New
York but [ __ ] your profit like you're
ruining our dream quit it quit it
yeah all right Mike
or at least be circumspect about it like
they used to be whole magazine articles
about not getting copper your landlord
and we got people showing up renting
house [ __ ] kicking doors down I had a
friend who used to manage a grow store
and he told me that one of his favorite
things to do was when kids would come in
and be all high
marijuana card I want four lights I want
a filter I'm gonna go hard I'm gonna go
blow up the whole basement they buy all
this [ __ ] and they pay cash for it and
he'd smile and hand him a bunch of boxes
that say grow light ballast carbon
filter and he'd smile I go there you go
and they'd be like can I get a box or
something you'd be like nope good luck
have a good night
just carry that [ __ ] right out to their
car and you're like I thought you were
bad dude I thought you're [ __ ] gonna
go hard because it's legal and now that
now that you're thinking about it you
got to carry four lights into your house
you don't want anyone to see that [ __ ]
it wasn't just for the police that we
went through all that [ __ ] like
there were articles about hiding from
your landlord because sometimes
landlords get pissed and throw your ass
out in the street and if you're growing
wheat illegally they can do that without
batting an eyelash regardless of what
landlord tenant laws in your state I
don't like to talk too much about stuff
like this but it's a reality when
medical marijuana first became legal
here there was a guy Kevin shaking his
head you know who I'm talking about a
guy named Eric Wagner who had a medical
marijuana grow in this neighborhood and
three guys kicked in his front door and
murdered him for his medical marijuana
grow so people forget that it's worth a
lot of ativan it was worth thirty five
hundred dollars a pound it was $300 an
ounce easily on around here and once you
got it out of here it was way more it's
four thousand on the East Coast five
thousand on the East Coast back then and
they knew people east the people that
shot him and killed him there's uh one
of the sheriff's up north I want to say
how paso or were one of those might have
been denver racked up like eleven
homicides that they could tie to exactly
that string of events people who want
weed but don't have money for weed find
out you have weed shoot you and take
your weed and then take it back to
wherever they're from and sell it at the
ridiculous price that weed sells were
there um there's still plenty of that in
Colorado because it's still commodity
you're basically posting on Facebook hey
guys look at all this jewelry I just
bought yep yeah by the way I don't have
a safe it's just in my spare bedroom
just because it's legal in Colorado and
we are
kind of soft you know what I mean we're
we're soft not everybody around us is
super soft and we've gotten soft and
comfortable the people here's what I
think I'm trying to say did I have that
edge anymore because we're not it used
to be it used to be a gangster business
it used to be a thug business the people
that used to grow and have cannabis and
produce that much of a valuable product
had a gun had some street cred it had
some homies knew how to throw down knew
what to look for heads down the street
it's legal and then people that had no
business in that kind of business got in
that business and didn't realize I've
kind of delved into the black market
like doctors lawyers were setting up
businesses like our friend that we used
to have the dispensary with he had no
business dealing with some of my other
people I was a middleman for people that
he should have never been involved with
but he was because of me
well there were a lot of people that
came in the door in those days looking
to move product that that they never
could have moved safely in any other
market I'm not again I could have robbed
some of those [ __ ] people I could
have said boo I'm sorry it had no
business being in that sort of market
yeah your 14 year old Kevin looks like
your cousin Kevin looks like Omar from
the wire - you know most of these people
who's just [ __ ] nuts they come in
terrified they all look the same they're
[ __ ] clutching the messenger bag that
held two quarter pound jars and they'd
come in hugging it like it was a baby
but they were trying to football carry
it and they'd go purchase and then
they'd look around the waiting room to
see if anybody heard every [ __ ] time
and if they tried to sell that by the
ounce to their friends even they were
gonna get a gun in their face real quick
yeah yeah that's just how the market
used to be people forgot that people got
soft complacent and who let their [ __ ]
be see I see it I'll be driving and I'll
see somebody making a delivery to a
dispensary and they open the back of
their truck and there's so much product
right there it's like what are you doing
dude you're not even
barely paying attention like a random
dude with a brick in a dream could have
your [ __ ] fit in 30 seconds do it fast
guy with some Nikes yep that's all it
takes
didn't you see Ninja Turtles to sugu the
used up one box in how fast was that
truck empty and your highest [ __ ] then
downtown Denver leaving the roll-top
open like come on now
pay attention all right you guys want to
take more dabs and start wrapping up the
podcast we've been going for quite a
while there's gonna be some editing done
on this episode yeah we're gonna edit
this down to something listenable
instead of just fully rambles let's take
some dabs I almost used my actual bic
pen as a dabber here on accident I'm
glad I paid attention to that along oh
we've got two hours of stuff on the
screen but I would say we've been going
for an hour give or take Mike nodded his
head who remembers the time I tried to
write with my dabber no I picked up this
day for them to write with this yeah I
was gonna say I finally matched him out
I almost just took a DAB with my actual
pen there was a story where they tried
to say kid died from weed and he
actually died from smoking plastic PEZ
dispenser and yeah that's how that
happens is people try to dab off a bit
past different [ __ ] that's like when
people get drunk and drive into people
and they smoke the joint before they
left the bar but they also had a hundred
and seventy two beers and like oh they
crashed and died because they smoked
weed [ __ ] 172 beers like look at his
credit card tab come on but it had to be
the weed because alcohol is completely
safe and okay you could buy it at the
bar we'll have to get me back for a mike
goes [ __ ] off for a while show a
couple data points that email lawyers
have asked for Mike they want an episode
on how to be active in their area and
just more Mike rambles oh yeah we can do
that you guys can send me watch it to
Mike you have yourself here's a dabber
would you like some of my fine
concentrates or would you like some of
your Sour Diesel or
trying to figure out how many more I
want to take before I leave and thinking
I want to go for King Louie dab the King
Louie there's a dabber here is I
definitely don't need any more jewels
rig here is a carb cap that works with
that rig it looks like you need L
torture reno l inferno there you go so I
work with sharpies all day and none of
my hash is labeled so I've got to keep
it in the [ __ ] packaging there's so
much required labeling that like we
haven't gotten around to doing the
useful labeling yet that's my my wants
yeah this is a little more than I need
to but I think it's gonna be a good time
keV I will pass you this torch as soon
as I get done with it and you can dab
with us and feel free to help yourself
to anything keV lit up a little Phase
two hitman shout out to Big D that was a
kind of a sort of a gift from Big D
there may have been a trade involved but
we'll call it a gift doing well man he's
doing great
he's doing great no he's doing well he
is well I hope so
trying to be grammatically correct was
it he not quite great I know he's always
been an amazing dude he's always been
the first one was grammatically correct
you're just so how you thought you had
to change it yeah I just trying to not
sound like a [ __ ] because I'm smoking
a bunch of dope dope [ __ ] I gotta go in
kind of hot cuz this is a big crystal so
here I go sorry about all the silence on
the podcast you guys we're taking dad's
dad with this please thanks for joining
us not that it sounds like a [ __ ]
bastard a big gorilla glory keV with
that [ __ ] quarter inch dick banger
we shouldn't dab all at the same time
next time hold that tastes so good two
minutes yeah calves nail is super thick
takes a long time bag gorilla glue and
you let that cool and hit that it just
sorry a temperature yeah that is so
delicious oh man and it's just the high
is coming over my head it's uh kind of
got my highs going right now I feel like
I'm pulling my beanie down that is super
nice making me twitch a little bit there
goes Mike in a coffin to the mic mic on
the mic I'm gonna turn him down just a
little bit you guys you don't want to
have died what's up keV you look scared
I'm not scared I'm not scared waiting
waiting to see what you're gonna do to
yourself with that dab oh it's gonna
hurt it's gonna hurt in such a good way
I love those dabs it hurt it's awesome
yeah but that like I have it right now
are you it's like I gotta breathe
properly err I'm not gonna breathe right
I enjoy that it's like an adrenaline
tattoo similar but not as no I don't
know some people might find it as
intense I'm a big dude and I take giant
dads and I've been doing it for a long
time if a normal non Dada connoisseur
totally long-lasting yeah just getting
like they do that arm thing to swirl
their arms around they trying to curl up
into a little ball and look at me like
would you just do to me yeah I've given
you those dab several times it's my
pleasure my friend
like you gonna be okay turn your mic
back on I'll be good
all right oh you sound fun yeah as soon
as I turn his mic on he looks at me at
cops huh you know I'm still shaking it
off you guys that was not a beer that
was a mountain dude that you're a lot
like a Hank Hill beer I wanted to hear
the king of the hill song John Redcorn I
hope you listen to the podcast big
mountain fudgecake keV that's a huge
debuted nice work I like the way that
that rig fits in your hand like a goblet
like that yeah pretty smooth
it's got a little handle on it it
doesn't resemble a cognac sifter but
it's got that perch to it so one of my
favorite episodes one of my favorite
things that's ever happened on a podcast
was not on this show was on seven one
nine two blocks we talked about
Siegfried and Roy the flamboyant
entertainers from Las Vegas who one of
them was attacked by a lion we spoke
about this lion attack tiger it was a
tiger actually you got eight so long ago
you don't forgot to add well I'm glad
you corrected me because it's a huge
part of what I was gonna say I've just
been [ __ ] up things on this podcast
the whole time we got waylaid which is
fine with me ah
we ended an episode of seven one nine
the blocks and everybody said goodbye we
all said are we love yous and I was like
alright peace and love we're gonna in
the episode and Kev goes shout out to
anyone who owns a tiger tiger we talked
about Siegfried and Roy by their pen on
that episode anyone's a tiger that's
always gonna be golden Alliance I think
that was [ __ ] awesome
[Music]
somebody just sent me a is this a gift
yep they just sent me a gift of the
Spartans
and the 300 number on there somebody
knows with certain iuck janeth people
send me 300 I they know people know
what's going on alright ladies and
gentlemen uh you guys wanna start
wrapping up this podcast Kevin - yawning
over there like that oh shut up - the
bedtime kid Oh Mike's gonna be in
trouble sorry get you in trouble Mike
hey Mike's worth Mike's family thanks
for letting me hang out and steal your
husband well thanks let me borrow your
daddy for a minute he did a very good
podcast so give him a high five good job
Mike
hearing you use that word refer to me
[ __ ] my head yeah I'm good you were a
good husband and a good father Mike it's
okay no I was referring to like no I was
the relationship with my son no I got it
I'm not calling you daddy big guy
awkward I'm ready to get I'm all down
with weird every day you thought you're
done with having to make edits Jesus no
I'm gonna leave that in your [ __ ]
crazy that's good that's gold ladies and
gentlemen thanks for hanging out with
this this was episode number 300 I don't
know what you expected I don't know what
I expected but I know what we got and I
[ __ ] had a good time I hope everybody
here at the table had as much fun as I
did absolutely thank you any time dude
any time you want to come be on a
podcast let me know we will keep the
listeners updated on your sobriety here
if you ever need support with that bro
you call me and call Mike any time I
think you already know that appreciate
it for sure I don't think it's gonna be
necessary but you know whatever you've
been tested and you've won two other
cannabis only guys that you know
probably there's like 11 reasons to call
you you can call for reasons other than
sobriety your podcast word Mike you can
come be on the show whenever yeah
whatever here is way more often if I
could get away so I'm trying to build
this into a more structured schedule but
we'll see how that goes
lol yeah with children that's what I
said is those of you that have kids
understand those that don't have kids
you'll find out soon
yeah all right podcast we'll make sure
you stock everybody on all the proper
social media elevated constant
concentration
elevated concentrations for Kevin find
white Mike at Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws on facebook he's Nemo punk
15 on the other social medias that start
with an at you'll be able to find him of
course find me on Facebook search for I
read genetics on Instagram I use my
other company name it's IRA underscore
genetics I invite you to follow me on
Instagram because I do Instagram live
feat I go talk to my audience you guys
can throw me questions I will answer
them live right there it's a lot of fun
I've made a lot of new friends kind of I
stay at home a lot I don't like to go
out so that's kind of my my social
interaction find me there hang out
you'll love it also find me on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcasts don't forget on
YouTube there are 200 videos available
you can see the old 200 episodes on
YouTube check it out I think you will
enjoy it if you've got a product you'd
like me to review if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast or if you've got
something to say and you're not into all
the social media stuff you can send me
an email it's a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you once again don't forget about
patreon Mike did a good job earlier I
want to remind you once again
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
it's a way to financially contribute to
the podcast not begging just looking for
support need a new macbook SOS almost
though it's going slow you guys it's
kind of scary it did eat itself twice as
often as it normally does today so yes
those of you that have been contributing
double thank you right now cuz that
money's going to a real word because
true without the MacBook there is no
podcast so thank you ladies and
gentlement the end of the episode I
usually do oh you know what we didn't
mention we're gonna talk about things in
the future I'm gonna breed more lemon
Jeffery seeds that's coming in the
future but I want to give a huge shout
out I usually do a shout out to one
individual person I want to say all the
stuff about I'll be back on Thursday
check out the mini episodes of you back
Monday with another fresh episode thanks
to all the sponsors contributors the
guests everybody and then usually I say
huge shout-out to a specific person this
time if you hear this shout out thank
you for the support 300 episodes there's
no reason to do 300 episodes of a
podcast without a loyal audience that
would be schizophrenia or some [ __ ] if I
kept doing it with an audience you're
just a crazy person with
yeah with a lot of fancy expensive toys
yeah that's what I thought as well so
you guys you are proving that I am not
completely insane so thank you for that
but honestly dude 300 episodes thank you
that means a lot to me you guys have
been outpouring support my social media
explodes my email explodes the YouTube
channel has been getting views and
comments the podcast has been Kenny been
getting downloads on all platforms it's
unbelievable this little show that
started here at this kitchen table is
making a difference and I didn't know I
can even do that I wanted to put out
some advice that was true and I'm making
a difference so thank you it wouldn't be
a difference without you guys actually
doing it it's uh I love that we're
achieving or you're achieving the goal
you set originally in such a fashion now
like I never saw it getting this big and
or going this long and to see that how
many people this has helped it's just
[ __ ] awesome better weed
coast-to-coast thank you for all over
the place not just coast to coast world
worldwide we're getting people that
listen in the UK people in Australia
people all over the place listen to some
of our sponsors are located their home
bases are in other countries so we've
we're doing it all over the place so
thank you guys cuz you guys bring more
audience like Kev's people are gonna
listen your people are gonna listen
that's awesome thank you some
interesting people in my world have been
like don't you go on a show from time to
time can I get that info yeah yeah then
they're gonna share it with some
interesting people as well yeah so thank
you guys everybody that listens to the
show thank you like I said earlier I
would just be schizophrenic or something
if I didn't have an audience so I
appreciate it
I wouldn't it would be kind of strange
to do this without all of your support I
love you guys thank you for listening to
300 episodes I promise to keep
delivering you quality content as long
as this computer and this production
equipment works and my brain and my
throat will all function properly
I'm gonna keep putting out podcasts as
long as my promise is to keep coming
over I'll keep having them on
- same with you bro you don't even have
to have dad's just show up good just
show up just be like hey I'm ready asked
if you get an idea also you guys I love
doing the listener generated content
when you send me emails and you say hey
Rasta Jeff my plants are doing this my
grow room is doing this I need some help
please help me out Bell it's me know
that I can help somebody and I'm sure
that if you're having that problem if
one dude in Texas has a problem that
means that a dude in Iowa Alabama Kansas
and Louisiana probably have a similar
problem and they just haven't bothered
to email me yet
or they were going to that's why I like
the email show so much it lets me know
that I'm hitting a target instead of
just blabbering maybe this is a good
idea like it lets me know I'm actually
getting my idea out to at least one
person and like I said if one person has
that problem a lot of people we had a
hundred thousand people listen to an
episode I had to have helped twenty
thousand people with the proper thing
that week maybe I don't know somebody
learned something that's what I wanted
to teach you guys right keep you going
keep you gardens growing strong make
everybody grow better cannabis safer
cleaner cannabis so that patients and
recreational smokers can stay healthy
and enjoy the product the way it was
meant to be holy crap I'm rambly from
those dabs let's wrap up a podcast
ladies and gentlemen shout out to
everybody that listens to the show until
next time take a phat dab and give it a
mom a hug for me
[Music]
you