yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for a Thursday episode of the
girl from Earhart podcast I like to call
these Thursday episodes the Thursday
quickie these quickies are brought to
you by our friends at the hello tank
seed bank make sure you check them out
at dank seed dot store ladies and
gentlemen it won't be a quickie unless
we get started right away
so let's get on with the girl from your
heart podcast welcome back podcast world
it's time for a Thursday quickie let's
get on with the show I like to start
these episodes by letting you know what
I am smoking and it's a sad sad day I
just finished this container the last
container of the skywalker og live
batter from garden of Weeden quick
moment of silence to this empty jar
was a trusty jar it was a worthy jar and
it served a great purpose and now this
jar is empty and it will be retired to
the graveyard of empty hash jars
Skywalker oh gee I'll miss you that was
some good [ __ ] you guys
I bet Elijah has got a small tear in his
eye also hearing that it's gone we used
to dab the [ __ ] out on that Skywalker it
lasted a little bit there was a lot of
it and now it's gone
alright guys this guy Walker was
delicious it's obviously got me in a
good mood I'm nice and high having a
great day before we get too far I want
to make a correction in the last episode
if you listen to number 300 thank you
but I said that art Bell and George
Noory and coast to coast may have been
the og podcast I know that that wasn't a
podcast but it was what I thought maybe
the first type of show to have that
platform that long extended platform to
break the basic AM radio kind of a mold
but then when I was listening to the
podcast and editing it came to me that
there was somebody else that I should
give sort of a shout out some tribute to
and it's ironic because he did kind of
pave the way for podcasting and he was
never a podcaster he actually despises
podcasters I'm talking about Howard
Stern Howard Stern was a radio DJ that
broke all of his own rules who pushed
the limits who ended up with his own
show who ended up with his own TV show
who ended up with a movie after him who
is still on Sirius XM making tons of
money basically doing podcasting so in a
way Howard Stern may be the og podcaster
and I think it's funny that Howard hates
podcasting but it makes sense to me
because he's og he uh he had to bust his
ass and get on the radio and fight with
radio politics and business politics and
if you know anything about the radio and
if you know anything about Howard Stern
you saw the stuff he had to battle to
become Howard Stern I was able to go buy
some toys and plug them in and just run
my mouth into a microphone and post it
to iTunes and hope to get listens it's
so much simpler now so I understand why
how he despises podcasts but he is kind
of the og podcaster because he set the
standard he broke the mold
he showed us that we can do different
things so shout it to Howard Stern even
though you despise podcasters I think
you're the og of podcasting you
definitely change radio and broadcasting
so we oh shout out to him I'm gonna keep
going or this is not gonna be a quickie
holy [ __ ] I'm talking of today this
episode is going to be about adapting
and adjusting as a cannabis farmer now
being a cannabis teacher an educator I
come on my podcast and I try to teach
you guys how to grow cannabis in the
best way possible how to take care of
your garden the best way possible
sometimes that's hard because there are
no instructions everything I say is
basically a suggestion you can follow my
suggestions and it should work 9 out of
10 times it will work but I don't know
your grow room I don't know you I don't
know what's going on I the only if you
ask me a question the only info I have
or is those two paragraphs you sent me
and you may have left some things out
there may be things you didn't even
think about mentioning there may be
something that I can't see because I'm
not in the grow room that you don't see
because you don't know to look for it so
helping you guys out everything that I
say is kind of just going on the fly by
what you're telling me now you have to
be able to adjust and adapt to not
having real instructions but two
suggestions I don't know what strain
you're growing every strain is going to
require different treatment
I do recommend specific pH ranges and
feeding ranges but I try to give a range
because each strain is going to want
something different that strain may want
something different in a different grow
room if you've got an LED light you may
have to grow differently than if you've
got an HP S light or if you've got a
ceramic metal halide light everything
that we're reading in the books
everything that we're reading on the
bottles all of the instructions should
be taken as suggestions when it comes to
growing cannabis it's kind of like being
a doctor doctors are always practicing
we were practicing growing cannabis
because each plant we see is like a new
patient your body chemistry is different
the next guy's body chemistry is
different we could how many people do
you know that can smoke weigh more or
weigh less than you and get way [ __ ]
up or
and you're like what's going on how come
in that's because our bodies are
different our plants are just like that
you're gonna have to adjust and adapt to
each plant to each environment to each
situation different strains are gonna
want different feeds OG Kush &amp; Sour
Diesel and super Silver Haze they're
gonna want completely different feeds
environments they want to be treated
completely differently you're going to
have to adapt now sometimes the
different stages of your grow your
plants are gonna want different amounts
of water you're gonna have to adapt and
adjust maybe you're used to giving this
plant a gallon of water maybe you see
something wrong you're gonna have to
figure out do I need to give it a gallon
in a quarter or three gallons adjust and
adapt don't get stuck into your routines
and patterns because the bottle says the
instruction book says they don't have
your plants they don't have your eyes
take all of the instructions as
suggestions when it comes to growing
cannabis I said each different strain is
gonna want different things each
different phenotype of that strain is
going to want different things possibly
a lot of times you'll find a phenotype
that is this is kind of a typical thing
when you get seeds one will be taller
and skinnier one will be shorter and
more dense that's kind of a phenotypic
expression showing mommy and daddy
they're gonna want different things and
you're going to have to adjust and adapt
now when I run a Fino hunt the first
time those plants all get the same thing
for the sake of science so that I can
see what I've got so that every plant
gets treated the same I have a dialed in
basic feed regimen a good light schedule
and a good room so that all those plants
get with a good basic treatment that I
know works so I run all of those plants
under the same conditions in the same
environment and I can see what performs
ideally in the ideal conditions then I
can select the keepers though two
possibly three keepers out of that
usually out of a ten pack I find one two
three that I like to keep and run again
then I will I have seen what they do I
know they are keepers I know I can use
them I know that they grow well I've
seen them girl once I took plenty of
notes I paid attention to which one
stretches I paid attention to which one
stays Squa now I can adjust and adapt my
grow to grow those plants properly so
you can't always follow what it says on
the bottle you can't always follow what
it says on the internet you can't always
follow what I say nine times out of ten
I'm going to steer you the right
direction but you have to keep in mind
that I'm human and I may make mistakes
you have to keep in mind the only
information I've got to go by is what
you have told me and also whatever I
give you the advice I give you you're
going to have to adjust and adapt it to
your garden you're gonna have to use
your best judgment you're gonna have to
use your eyes you're gonna have to use
your nose you're gonna have to use your
sense of touch hell maybe even use your
sense of taste use all your senses what
do you got you got eyes ears nose mouth
and touching so use all your senses in
there get in there and smell it look at
it taste it touch it listen to it I
don't know if there's anything to listen
to if your plants are making noise
you're doing something wrong listen to
the equipment either way you guys you
know what I'm talking about adjust and
adapt pay attention to what's going on
maybe the book says give it a gallon of
water you pour it in a gallon of water
and that plant went crazy you're going
to have to adjust and adapt think about
it go pick up that pot is it too heavy
is it too light does the plant look like
it's too dry or too wet you're gonna
have to think about it you're gonna have
to adjust and you're gonna have to adapt
let's talk about things like I talked
about popping the sticks we call it
super cropping when you grab a portion
of the stem and you grab it another inch
above that and you twist opposite
directions and it makes this noise your
sticks will make that noise it's a good
thing as long as it doesn't tip over
sideways if you're twisting it's perfect
don't break it just twist it you want it
to pop when you're working with let's
say Blue Dream Blue Dream has tight node
spacing it grows really long strong
branches blue dream you could pop this
[ __ ] out of it all over the place and
it'll be just fine
Ghost Dog is kind of stretchy she gets
kind of tall you have to be careful
where you crack her because if you do or
too much she'll start getting kind of
droopy and get mad at you you've got to
adjust and adapt same strains Ghost Dog
and Blue Dream Blue Dream supports
itself like a champ Blue Dream you don't
need a lot of netting a lot of stakes a
lot of trellising it's a good idea
because the buds are gonna get big but
if you don't have them the buds will
hold themselves up that plants robust
Ghost Dog you better have
three layers of trellising because
they're gonna start tipping over at week
five those buds are gonna get floppy
they just can't support themselves
you're going to have to adjust and adapt
because you've got different strains
it's not always gonna be science you
guys plants are nature they've got a
life of their own don't try to fight it
and don't get sucked into your routine
get sucked into the plants routine be in
the rhythm with the plants just because
you get to the grow at 8:00 in the
morning doesn't mean those plants need
water at 8:00 in the morning if they're
not dry let them wait till noon if
they're still a little wet maybe let
them wait till 3:00 don't force-feed
them if they're not ready because it's
on your schedule all right you guys I
feel like if I keep rambling this
episode will not be a quickie I want to
give you a huge shout out to Jade and
also a shout-out to Maddie
E and while I'm giving shoutouts don't
forget about the hella dank seed bank
4/20 sale that's right if you need some
new genetics for your garden
check out dank seed dot store and check
out their 420 sale you can get four
packs of I read genetics for a hundred
and twenty dollars plus two free five
pack so make sure you check that out
also huge shot it's my friends at pl
grow ladies and gentlemen please follow
me on social media stalk me on Facebook
it's simply the girl from your heart
podcast find me on Instagram it's Ayari
underscore genetics I RIE underscore
genetics on instagram check me out on
twitter it's at g f YH podcast and on
youtube there are 200 videos available
on youtube now you guys I got 200 videos
up there please subscribe to the YouTube
channel check out the old episodes on
the videos I would appreciate it if
you've got something to say or if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast or if you've
got a product you'd like me to review
send me an email let's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you know I would
love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen forget to check out patreon
patreon comm slash grow from your heart
big shout out to everybody that has been
helping me out on patreon ladies and
gentlemen I'm gonna wrap up this
Thursday quickie I will be back Monday
with the full-length episode I look
forward to joining you then I'm gonna
give a huge shout out to my friend
bagsied Jessi and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]