yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
davor if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast welcome back podcast world
it's time for episode 304 of the girl
from your heart a podcast thanks again
for joining me ladies and gentlemen I
owe a huge thank you shout out to
everyone who has supported the show on
patreon thank you with all of your help
I was able to grab the new MacBook I
have been trying to get ladies and
gentlemen I'm recording this episode on
a brand new MacBook Pro at the 15.4 inch
monitor I've got the i7 processor it
took me about three or four hours to get
this thing all set up and ready to rock
I played with it yesterday and now I am
here recording a brand new episode on
the brand new machine that I could not
have done without you so thanks for your
help everybody I truly truly appreciate
all of the patreon support thank you
alright usually I like to start these
episodes by letting you know what I'm
smoking on today I am taking dabs of
gorilla glue number four high
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract I just
opened up the little mini jar and this
gassy funk this sweet gassy chirp just
hit me right in the face
it's a gassy and funky and it is
delicious ladies and gentlemen it's got
me in a great mood it's got a really
heavy face hi I feel like my head got
slow it was like putting cinder blocks
on my brain anyway great concentrates
tastes great smells great and the dabs
were super super smooth I felt like I
took a little tiny dab and got a whole
bunch of smoke remember I was talking
about I go through those phases where I
can smoke super heavy and I don't get
lit and then I go through phases where I
can take a little tiny dad and I get
super wrecked the past few days have
been those phases where I could take a
little tiny bed and I get super duper
wreck that's been pretty nice kind of
saving on the concentrates that way
anyway let's move on with the podcast
ladies and gentlemen don't forget about
the hella tank scene Bank 4/20 sale
that's right
a dank seed dot store you can get four
packs for five packs of IRA genetics
seeds for a hundred and twenty dollars
plus you're gonna get a free five pack
of cactus cooler cross to arise plus
another free five pack it will be
selected by the hell a dank seed bank so
make sure you check them out at dank
seed dot store the sale starts on April
13th and it goes through 4/20 so check
them out and restock on I read genetics
eat there's a lot of new great stuff up
on the website make sure you take a look
they've added a lot of great new
breeders also you guys I read genetics
is not the only breeder up there of
course I would recommend my brand there
are tons of other great breeders up
there I would highly recommend everybody
on the website also this podcast is
brought to you by my friends at pol grow
systems
ladies and gentlemen I'm not gonna give
you a long drawn-out ad I support pol
grow systems I like what they do
I like their product they're easy to
communicate with their tech support is
awesome their website is awesome that
people are great they are supporting the
cannabis community and I support them
and I recommend that you support them as
well you can find them at PL grow dot
systems check them out check out their
unit called the minder I highly
recommend it I think I do everything
highly but this one I do a little extra
high all right shout out the pl grow
in the last episode I mentioned that I
was going to go to Best Buy and pick up
the MacBook and I would let you know how
that went let you know if I had to act a
fool let you know if they were nice and
polite so here's how the whole story
goes we'll start from the day I went to
go buy it I walked into Best Buy
and I was like hey I've got this picture
of this computer on my screen I'd like
this please and I'm like oh give me a
few minutes I'll find that for you you
went to go find it and he came back with
a bewildered look on his face and he
said sir I hate to say this I can't find
that computer in my store and I was like
well I've got money I'd like to buy it
now if you've got it just to encourage
him you know like maybe he thought it
was just browsing or something to sort
of know I've got money I will take it if
you can find it I'm gonna look around
for a minute so I looked around and him
and another guy came up the other guy
can't claim to be the inventory manager
he's like sir we cannot find that
computer here but we can order it for
you so they ordered it in from another
store and they also gave me a pretty fat
discount for making me wait around and
having to look for it so I got a nice
deal they ordered the computer they told
me it would be here on Thursday
Wednesday night at 8:55 I got an email
saying hey your computer is available
the shitty part about that is the store
closed at 9 o'clock and it's about 20
minutes away from my house so it was
kind of just a big tease they're like
hey your computer is in here you can
come stare at it through the window if
you'd like but that's the best you can
do tonight so I do wait till the next
day of course I had to work all day I
kept saying it's I would like to leave a
little bit early I would like to leave
just a little bit early but I I'm the
manager I can usually make that happen
but fate was just not letting it happen
everything needed my attention so I had
to work a little extra late that day but
I did get off work and I did make it to
Best Buy and here's the part you guys
want to hear I walked into Best Buy and
I said hey I'm here to pick up my
computer and she said you have an ID and
I showed her my ID and she turned around
and she picked up a box off of the
counter and she set it down and she said
have a good day sir and I walked out
with my computer there were no problems
there were no issues I did not have to
act a fool I got to high-five the guy on
the way on I drove home and played with
my new computer so I got the new MacBook
you guys it took me a little bit to get
some things set up there was one uh the
tascam software did not want to install
but we got tech guy Tony over here and
Tony helped me out shout at the Tony
thanks for coming over to on such short
notice bro and we got it running so the
new MacBook is
in action ladies and gentlemen big
thanks and a huge shout out to everybody
who contributed to the patreon campaign
you guys covered probably half if not a
little more on the cost of this new
machine so thank you I appreciate it I
hope the show sounds good I'm sure it's
gonna be easier to load the show and it
will be easier to make videos and now
I've got two machines that I can make
youtube videos on on which I can make
youtube videos sorry I'm trying to be
nerdy with my English and now that means
I can speed up my production process
we'll get caught up in less time so
thank you let's move on with the podcast
ladies and gentlemen I have got an email
from a friend of ours it's kind of a
long email I'm not going to read the
whole thing on the air a lot of it was
just kind of a personal thing to me he
asked a couple of questions that don't
need to be read on the air but there is
part that I want to put on the show so
I'm gonna start from the beginning and
then we'll get to the part I want to
talk about it goes a lot like this Ross
- Jeff what's up it's been a while since
I've messaged you I'm still listening
every week and I'm still supporting you
in all you do hey good to hear from me
man and thanks again for supporting me
he goes on to say thank you again for
being such a great resource I'm emailing
you to ask you a question and maybe a
favor God knows you don't owe me
anything and you have no idea who I
really am but I'll try to keep this
short and maybe let you know where I'm
coming from he says if you refer to my
previous previous email I'm from
Albuquerque New Mexico and a big fan of
the podcast and your art recently I have
acquired my medical marijuana card in
New Mexico and I'm fully legal what a
difference in feeling it is what a
difference in feeling it is to walk out
of a shop and know I'm not a criminal in
the eyes of the law and that is such a
huge feeling I remember that the first
time I went to go buy medical marijuana
and I walked out of the place and I was
like dude you just walked out to the
weed place loud and proud with weed and
everyone knows that's the weed place and
you're walking to you and I had to like
call myself down and think oh yeah it's
the weed store and you got a weed card
in your pocket you can do this it is
such a great feeling it's almost surreal
the first couple of times
and then that first time that you're
driving and you got your weed in the car
and the cops get behind you and you're
like oh [ __ ]
and you go oh wait never mind and all
your worries go away because the only
thing I used to do that would get me in
trouble is have some herb in the car now
I'm totally golden alright the email
goes on he says I had never cared much
for being legal and always feared being
on in the system or on some sort of the
list I'm also not your stereotypical
stoner nothing against my stoner bros
but I do not fit the mold and people
generally assume I do not partake
contrary to this belief however I am
highly knowledgeable cannabis and I have
consumed countless hours of content and
research I've been a closeted activist
and a literal closeted glower grower for
a very long time Rasta Jeff you have
inspired me I am 33 and I money and I am
a new father and I'm a full-time
employee of the local university after
going through some complications with my
son's birth and having a small
interaction with child services
I've become fully motivated in becoming
a positive face in the cannabis movement
hey thank you for uh for joining us so
strongly I appreciate that thank you for
becoming a face in the cannabis movement
we need more articulate ah strong-minded
people like yourself joining this
movement so thanks for jumping in with
us he also says nothing negative came
from this interaction but I came out of
it with a better understanding of the
laws point of view I've held myself back
and I feel I have kept my talents and my
heart to myself and I am ready to
fulfill my destiny so to speak so here
is my question I said I had for you he
asks what qualifies someone to be a
master grower I mean he also says for
lack of better term um bets I kind of
want to jump off on a rant right there
in Colorado the term master grower is a
huge joke it's one of the most cringy
terms or words or phrases you could
throw out in the cannabis industry right
now anybody that's been growing cannabis
for quite a while before this medical
marijuana movement
cringes at the phrase master grower
technically
master grower simply means that you are
the boss of the cultivation facility you
were the lead grower it is another term
for lead grower I wish everybody would
just change their badge from master
grower to lead grower or cultivation
director or a cultivation manager or
something just a little less douchey and
egotistical sounding is calling yourself
a master grower is like saying that
you're the black belt that you have got
all of the knowledge that you were the
champion that you get a head kick
everybody that you know all the forms
all the tricks and a lot of us are not
masters I am the most qualified
most experienced grower at my facility
which makes me the cultivation leader or
the cultivation director but a lot of
people so technically it's a position
technically it's a title it's a stamp on
your paycheck position
master grower culturally and societally
it is more of a joke nobody takes you
seriously if you say I'm the master
grower so that's just something I want
to touch on here in Colorado the phrase
master grower is kind of a joke but you
don't mean it in that way you're asking
what does it take to be a master grower
and then you even said for example or
lack of better term you just want to
know what it takes to be at that level
and he says I refer to myself as a
humble green thumb and I'm not very
outspoken about my talent but the proof
is in my pudding I'm grounded in
caregiving and I follow exactly in line
with your thinking so what do you call a
guy like me all right I call a guy like
you a cultivation manager a cultivation
director now if you want to be a master
grower and the terms and the not douchey
terms in the terms of a blackbelt grower
as in the terms of a cultivation manager
what you need is cultivation experience
you definitely need cultivation
experience you have to be able to look
at plants and say that plants too wet
that plan is too dry that is powdery
mildew that is spider mite damage those
plants are too close together those
plants are too far apart that light is
too close to those plants you have to be
able to identify what's going on with
the plants what is going on with the
room you have to identify things on the
fly every day at a rapid pace you have
to be able to think and adjust and adapt
you have to know you have to keep track
of 20 different rooms and know how much
water has gone in each room for the past
couple of days you have to be able to
manage people you have to have an eye
for detail you have to have a passion
you have to be there and you have to
give a [ __ ] that's what you need to be
the master grower it sounds like you
possess all of these qualities don't be
in too much of a hurry to call yourself
a master grower keep calling yourself
the humble green thumb because those are
the best master growers the humble green
thumbs are the guys that should be
running the large facilities you know
what to do you can go to certain pace
where you work fast enough but you don't
rush through anything you get everything
done without screwing up you don't drag
your feet you can lead the other people
to keep them going at a fast pace you
can make a plan you can make a schedule
and you can encourage your team to do
what needs to be done in a timely manner
and keep it fun and have everybody
motivated and Curt and encouraged and
still get all of the [ __ ] done and break
a sweat and at the end of the day
everybody is proud of what they did so
it sounds like you could do that that's
what a master grower needs to do in a
large cultivation facility it's
basically the same thing that any other
boss needs to do in any position plus
you have to have specialized skills for
your industry which is cannabis
knowledge now you have to have knowledge
all the way through the process you have
to know how to cut a clone and you have
to know how to get it all the way to the
store so knowledge of the full cannabis
grow cycle is necessary knowledge of how
to identify and manage pests is
necessary and diseases all the plant
stuff also you have to be able to pay
attention to electrical HVAC plumbing
also you have to manage employees also
you have to communicate between the
employees and ownership and whoever else
you may have i've got contractors in the
grower or in the grow on average three
days a week if it's not an electrician a
plumber um
maybe an HVAC guy if not the Department
of Agriculture or the Department of
Health there's somebody coming in to do
something you have to be able to
communicate with all different types of
personalities
you have to be able to give instructions
you have to be able to deal with
employees that kind of don't follow
instructions properly you have to be
able to correct things you have to be
able to document things you have to be
able to give praise you have to learn
how to separate your dab time and your
work time and your friendship and your
management from your co-workers because
once we go to lunch I take off the
nametag and we're friends we're gonna
take some dabs we're gonna hang out even
if you're the employee that [ __ ]
everything up all day when we go to
lunch
we're friends we're gonna be cool you
have to learn how to keep that balance
you have to be able to discipline your
friends you have to be able to fire and
write your friends up when the time
comes so those are things like any job
they are going to be part of being a
master grower but the way you are trying
to be qualified it sounds like you were
doing it you love the plant you have
passion you have an intention for detail
and you care about what you're doing and
it sounds like since you work with a
university you are able to communicate
and through the email you sent you can
certainly communicate so that's
basically what it takes to be a master
grower you continue to be the humble
green thumb and you will find a position
as a master grower I'm gonna keep
reading a little bit of the email and
then we're gonna cut it out short
because some of this was just for me
like I said he said what do you call a
guy like me I call you a passionate
grower I call you highly qualified I
call you somebody that respect as a
grower he goes on to say I have worked
with both small personal and large
commercial grows I have listened to
every girl from your heart episode as
well as all of the cannabis growing and
culture podcasts available on my iPhone
I follow and watch with all I follow and
watch all of the very best no-till and
sustainable growers I have found
and then he goes on to say that he's got
all this cannabis knowledge and skills
but nothing to show for it except for a
few jars of quality medicine and his
Irie feelings ah unfortunately a lot of
people fill feel that way in this
industry and when you're trying to get
into this industry
you can't bring your product to the
dispensary to show at least in Colorado
it's illegal to show up with product you
can't come to an interview with product
you're in New Mexico you've got
different rules there you can probably
bring in your product I don't know but
if you can't and you feel like you don't
have anything to show for it
a lot of these jobs are not hiring based
on your gross skills and your outcome a
lot of them are hiring based on do you
fit with the team does your personality
work can you be on time did you we asked
trick questions in the interview to see
if you can catch on see if you can
follow instructions we ask questions to
we're kind of milking information out of
you the first and fifth question we're
the same question you just didn't
realize it you answered them differently
and we started writing notes like that's
the kind of [ __ ] that goes on an
interview scape keep that in mind so
we're trying to check out your
personality we're making sure you mesh
with the team that you're responsible
that you're honest that you're reliable
and those are the things that you need
to bring to the interview um and this is
everybody I'm not just saying this for
the guy that sent me the email this is
for everybody if you're going for a
cannabis related interview
don't wear your Bob Marley t-shirt don't
wear your Cheech and Chong t-shirt dress
for the position you are applying for go
in there and look like you've already
been hired dress nice comb your hair I
know I've got dreadlocks and [ __ ] right
do your hair make your hair look good
make yourself look presentable brush
your teeth
clean up your shave if you got a
scraggly a shave just tighten it up a
little bit just try to look good look
presentable you aren't about to
represent this person's business the
customers that come into the business
are going to be dealing with you the
plants that are grown by this business
are going to be grown by you you've got
to be a trustworthy reliable person that
can represent our company so you can't
bring your jars to the grill you can't
bring your product you can scroll
through your Instagram and show us it
doesn't impress us show up and kick ass
in the interview that's what you can
bring all right there's more to this
email it doesn't really need to be put
out on the air so I'm gonna keep that
part to myself
dude if you want to be a master grower
you already are you just don't have the
title because you don't work in a
Colorado facility you have from what I
can tell by your email it sounds like
you've got the qualifications the way to
actually earn that title would be to
started agro don't be afraid to take a
trimmer position don't be afraid to take
agro tech position I started in my
position as a Gro tech I was the bottom
there was a trimmer and then there's
grow Tech's and then the hierarchy moves
up to my position my 90-day review I was
promoted to cultivation director or
master grower so go somewhere prove
yourself don't be afraid to start at the
bottom and you can be promoted to master
grower now one thing that a master of
anything would do is keep learning if
you go in there and you start as a
trimmer you trim like a maniac you're on
time for work every day you follow
instructions you volunteer to help when
there's more work to do you get promoted
to grow tech you become a good grow tech
one of the growers gets sick doesn't
show up
now you're you've got his position now
you are hanging out with the lead grower
the master grower all day every day
working hand-in-hand with him
don't be mad that you can't get his
position because it's taken your job now
is to absorb everything you can about
commercial production about cannabis
cultivation on a large scale absorb
everything you can be present don't be
angry that you're not getting the
position you want be present and be
excited about the free education you're
getting while you're getting paid you're
becoming a better grower you're building
your resume one thing you should do
while you're in these facilities is
write down everything you learn if you
learn a new piece of equipment a new
tool a new method a new trick a new
technique a new idea write it down add
it to your grow journal add it to your
resume if you can drive a scissor lift
now because you worked in a cultivation
facility put that on your resume if you
can drive us is her lift or a forklift
it makes you much more hireable for my
facility because we get deliveries we
need the forklift if there's a guy that
can't drive the forklift or there's no
that no one there they can drive the
forklift that [ __ ] stays on the truck
and the truck drives away and comes back
when it can so if you were able to
operate a forklift you're much more
hireable all the scissor lifts we got to
change bulbs the guy that knows how to
use the scissor lifts we call him in he
gets extra hours you can drive that says
you lift put up the bulbs so that kind
of stuff helps right
everything you do and then you will get
to be the master grower in a facility in
this email he mentions our friend
mentions that he was offered a job but
the place does not grow from their heart
so he's going to be patient and try to
find himself a job that meets his
standards I applaud you for that I
applaud you for not compromising your
standards just for employment in the
industry you want to work in that means
that you're gonna grow from your heart
that when you do find a facility that
appreciates your heart and your care for
the plant that you're gonna give them
your all so be patient keep looking
until you find a facility that does work
for you I do have friends down there at
organic ax and Albuquerque I don't know
what I could do by pulling strings
because honestly the only thing I know
you buy is your screen name in your
email but go to organic ax and say hey I
listen to the girl from your heart
podcast I've heard great things about
you I email with Rasta Jeff is there any
way that I can get an interview just
walk in and ask dude you walking in
and setting it up on your own is gonna
look way better than me trying to set it
up for you so go in there hit them up
say hey where can I work when do I start
and tell them the stuff you told me man
that's how you become the master grower
shout-out to my friends at org antica
also hey guys I should add that a lot of
what I said applies to any position you
were trying to get in any job if you're
trying to get a cannabis industry job
you get those jobs just like you get any
other industry job you need to go apply
don't sit at home on your computer and
try to find a job on Facebook or on some
website get up
get cleaned up look sharp put on some
clean clothes drive your ass to the
place where you want to work and apply
there talk to people go make contact
with humans there's no way to make an
impression online unless your resume is
super dope and they see we see so many
resumes but honestly we think the super
dope ones are fake so go there let the
people see who you are
you may not if you fit if they see you
and they say man this looks like a
person that would fit in with our crew
they look like they'd probably go hang
out with Jeff after work and they look
like they probably listen to the same
music as Mark show up make yourself
known if you're not noticed if you don't
show up and make yourself notice you're
just another resume
you're just another email you're just
another piece of white paper with a
bunch of letters on it show up talk to
somebody talk to a manager show up ask a
who does the hiring and if they're not
there if they're not available ask for
their phone number or their card find
out when they'll be there again go back
ask for them
speak with them shake their hand when
they come out from wherever they are say
hey uh whatever hiring person hey Ross -
Jeff I know you're busy I don't want to
take up too much of your time
my name is this I'd really love an
opportunity to work in your facility
here's my resume shake their hand look
them in the eye smile get the hell out
of their face be seen be noticed
do not waste their time because
everybody that has a manager title and a
dispensary or grow they're [ __ ] busy
they've got [ __ ] to manage get them your
resume make eye contact now you're in
that person's brain okay you've you've
planted a little seed now call back in a
couple of days and ask for that person
hey give you my resume the other day we
shook hands I wanted to see if you had a
chance to look at that and they're
either gonna be cool with you or not by
now you're either bugging them or not
and if you're bugging them [ __ ] them you
don't need that job you weren't gonna
get it anyway if you're not bugging them
and they're happy with you they're gonna
talk to you about it they're gonna say
yeah look it over talk to my other
manager about it we'll call you back in
a couple of days
got to beat him to the punch in a couple
of days you'd go to the store where you
found them
and hit them up again hey manager guy
was wondering if you got a chance to
look at my resume and talk to your
manager because I'm really interested in
getting a position with your facility
there are so many resumes there are so
many phone calls there are so many
messages you've got to go and you've got
to push the button to yourself you guys
so in this industry if you want a job in
any position you've got to go get it
they're not they are online they're
being advertised online if you just want
to be another click if you want to be
another whoever at whoever comm go for
it or you can walk in there and you can
shake somebody's hand and be remembered
people don't forget you if they see your
face I couldn't tell you any of the
email addresses on any of the resumes I
read this week that's coming from
somebody that does the hiring and firing
and as a manager I don't remember any of
the email addresses but I remember
everybody's face that shook my hand and
said hey can I have a job I don't have a
job for you
but when I do I remember your face
alright so this email wraps up and I got
off on a long rant thank you guys for
listening to my rant I love it it's fun
thanks for the supporting the show he
goes on to say thanks again Ross and
Jeff for all you do even if you can't
help me out I still love you and I will
give my mom a hug for you hey much love
and respect in return I appreciate it
hope you're doing well down there in New
Mexico he says growers love and then he
says PS you do not have to read this on
the air I'm just reaching out there was
some of it that was worth reading on the
air some of it was personal so I used
what I could my friend thanks for the
great email you guys if you'd like to
send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to get your emails so I can
answer your questions alright I've got
another email here
let's get right into this one also this
one says Ross - Jeff I'm a new grower in
SoCal and I really enjoy your show hey
Thank You Man I appreciate that
he goes on to say on your next seed
discussion could you also cover OTO
flowers I'm really interested in doing
OTO flowers outdoors to maximize the
number of harvests per year what do you
think and then he also says thanks for
sharing your awesome knowledge and being
a positive force peace and then he
signed it with his name he knows his
name he didn't say if he wanted me to
say it or not so dude thanks for the
email big shout out you know who you are
anyway he said on your next seed
discussion could you also cover OTO
flowers I really don't grow or mess with
OTO flowers I don't have a lot of
experience you said you were interested
in doing OTO flowers outdoors to
maximize the number of harvests per year
what do I think I think that everything
I know about OTO flowers that is the
perfect reason for OTO flower seeds a
lot of people hate on feminized seeds a
lot of people have hatred for OTO flower
seeds I believe that everything has its
application and your purpose is the
perfect application for OTO flower seeds
you can maximize your number of harvests
outdoors because you don't have to have
a veg time so it's beautiful I think
that your intention is going to work
perfectly with OTO flowers you're gonna
get what you want um there was a large
bust in southern Colorado just about 45
minutes south of me there's a National
Forest and a cartel had set up an
illegal grow in that National Forest
they were growing cannabis on a large
scale and when they got caught it was
not the right season for cannabis to be
flowering
the pictures that they showed were
straight-up flowering plants and fields
of plants in different stages
and me and my we'd head friends were
sitting here watching the news and
looking at the pictures gonna wait a
minute how did they do that because it's
if you know about growing cannabis it's
an annual plant you put it outside and
it flowers because of the Sun cycle
because of the night cycle so all of the
plants are outside how are some of them
flowered this far how are some of them
flowered this barn how are some of them
still in veg and then it dawned on me
they're using [ __ ] Otto flowers and
they're just plotting different size
plots so they've got a perpetual grow
happening with Otto flowers on other
people's property on the national forest
land so yes it is very very feasible and
that is a very good idea that is a very
good application that's honestly the
best application for Otto flowers is to
run them outdoors so that you can
maximize the number of harvest outdoors
I hope the Otto flowers work for you I
hope you're able to maximize your
harvests I hope you're able to get some
high potency Otto flowers the only
downside to Otto flowers is that you
have to keep buying new seeds hopefully
the cost of not having to veg them and
the opportunity to maximize the number
of harvests offsets the price of having
to buy new seeds for every run because
that's the only the only catch there is
if you weren't running Otto flowers you
could just cut clones and put more out
there but they need have to veg them and
you have to have space and you have to
have a mom plant so what you're doing is
perfect I have no problems with your use
of Otto flowers and I'm usually kind of
a hater on Otto flower seeds so dude
thank you for the great email and thanks
for the opportunity to teach my
listeners a very good application for
Otto flowers you guys quit hating the
Otto flowers because this is gonna work
well this guy is going to get more
harvests next year than you it may be
Otto flower bud but he's going to have
more of it and he's gonna have more
frequent harvests and it's all gonna be
outdoor sunshine bud and he's not gonna
have to have a veg space so good hatin
on the Otto flowers you guys this guy is
gonna kick some ass with Otto flowers
this season alright but there's a whole
year [ __ ] not even the season his season
is all year you get one season so don't
make fun of the Otto flowers anymore you
guys we found a perfect application here
on the show
hey dude I know my answer was super
short and I did not give a lot of
details but you uh you asked if this was
gonna work basically and yes this is
gonna work beautifully you have got the
perfect idea for Otto flowers so yeah
it's gonna work man
good idea all right let's move on to
this next email this next email comes
from somebody who's very smart because
they said right away if this makes it to
the podcast please don't read my name
but I will read the subject it says
happy st. Patty's Day from Ireland
ladies and gentlemen we've got listeners
in Ireland a big shout out to everybody
out there in Ireland listening to the
podcast I do not know the rules on
cannabis in Ireland although I would
assume they do not tolerate cannabis
they don't seem like they take much
[ __ ]
seems like a place that if you fall out
of line you will quickly be put back in
line so be careful if you're growing
consuming or possessing or even talking
about cannabis in Ireland
let me know if I'm wrong I'm really
curious what's it like what's the
temperature on cannabis there anyway the
email goes on it says many
congratulations on 300 episodes hey
thank you I appreciate that
he also says I've listened to them all
most of them twice thanks to the
throwback Thursdays hey that is
commitment that's dedication thank you
and I apologize you've had to listen to
me for a lot of hours I'm sorry you've
had to hear my voice drone on about
nothing for so much the message goes on
to say I am a chef and I work alone so
you keep me company during prep hey
thanks for hanging out man anyway the
email keeps going and he says I'm not a
grower given we are deep in prohibition
land the first few steps on the road to
medical have been taken in Ireland but
nothing approaching freedom yet but we
really enjoyed the grow episodes in
particular he also says I'm currently
smoking some UK cheese but missing the
quality of flour I enjoyed in California
he said they were smoking orange aka
from harvest off mission in San
Francisco and Green crack from kind love
and Denver where our favorite flowers we
tried
that green crack from kind love is a
great product I actually know the
consultant that set that grow up and I
have got this same clone of that green
crack in my garden at Three Rivers and
it is a great cut so that is quality
product kind love is one of my favorite
dispensaries in Denver if I were going
to go shopping so I'm not bashing kind
love they are kind of a premium
dispensary they've got some of the
higher prices but they've also got some
of the better products if I'm looking to
spend money for cannabis for a concert
and I haven't had a harvest in a while
kind love is one of the few places I
consider shopping also of course Three
Rivers because I grow that product but
if I'm looking to spend too much money
kind of love is where I go anyway he
says we didn't get around to dabs yet
too much gear to sort for tourists yeah
I totally understand that the next time
you're in Colorado let me know I've got
all of the gear you won't have to sort
any of it and you won't feel like a
tourist you'll feel like you're right at
home we'll go to some cool places we'll
take some dabs you will have a good time
but the email wraps up saying anyway
I'll have a smoke and go annoy my mother
for you best of luck and big hugs to you
and yours hey my friend from Ireland
huge thank you for the email huge thank
you for the support I really like
hearing from my friends in other
countries it's neat to know that
somebody in Ireland is listening to my
podcast right now it's even more neat
knowing that you were unable to
participate in what I'm teaching you
can't grow it's probably hard to consume
there you're taking the first steps
toward medical but it's extra neat to
know that you're listening even though
you can't do it I'm saying you're kind
of living out the dream vicariously
probably a little bit but you're still
enjoying the show even though you aren't
able to practice what you're being
taught which means I'm entertaining you
and keeping your attention enough to
keep you here even though you can't do
the stuff that means a lot to me so
thank you for the huge compliment I hope
you go annoy your mom for me that sounds
great and when you do get some dabs take
some giant dabs there or when you come
back to the states send me a message and
we will take some fat dabs together hey
thank you for the great email and
again for the congratulations on episode
300 I appreciate it and I will keep the
episodes coming you guys there's no end
in sight I just bought a brand new
MacBook I'll probably buy some new
upgrades to the audio equipment pretty
soon also there is no reason to stop
this
all right podcast world we ripped
through three good emails I'm trying to
get through this stack of emails that
I've got I do have more cannabis
cultivation lessons coming for you I
just make promises that I will answer
emails for people so I've got to get
through those as promised I love
answering the listener emails because it
lets me know that I'm hitting my target
I know I'm helping at least one person
we're improving somebody's garden so I
love the emails you guys keep them
coming
once again the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen I do have a whole bunch of
great cannabis cannabis cultivation
stuff coming up I do have some things
about building a drip system I've got a
whole bunch of great stuff written down
I've got a vapor pressure deficit
episode coming up we've got a 420
episode coming up pretty soon there's a
lot of great stuff coming from the
podcast I know I've been reading a lot
of emails lately I'm trying to catch
them up there are a lot keep them coming
I will keep reading them I hope you guys
enjoy that format let me know what you
think of the show you guys you can find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your heart a podcast on
Facebook you can find me on Twitter it's
at G fyh podcast make sure you follow me
on Instagram I do a lot of Instagram
live videos where I go live and I answer
cannabis cultivation questions we hang
out we take dabs we get way too stoned
it's a good time on Instagram
I am I reenter score genetics i RIE
underscore GE and ET ICS I read genetics
on Instagram please follow me there if
you've got something to say or you've
got a question or you've got a product
you'd like me to review or you'd like to
sponsor the podcast or if you'd like to
communicate and are simply not into the
social media you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you know I read the emails you know I
will reply I may even read your message
on an upcoming episode ladies and
gentleman by the time you hear this
there should be about two hundred and
five ish videos on the YouTube channel
make sure you go to youtube search for
the girl from your heart a podcast find
my channel click Subscribe and whenever
I put up a new video you will get a
notification iTunes and stitcher are
able to hold
100 episodes I'm going to try to have
all of the episodes previous to that up
on YouTube it's hard to keep up now I've
got two devices it shouldn't be a
problem
please check us out I'm also going to
get all of the new episodes up there as
soon as I get caught up then we'll stay
current you'll be able to see everything
on YouTube
also don't forget about patreon I've
talked about patreon earlier in the show
patreon was a huge contributing factor
on how I was able to get this new
computer a little earlier than
anticipated my old MacBook was taking a
poop I asked my patreon friends to help
me out you guys stepped up I've got the
new computer the podcast will keep
coming
uninterrupted thank you if you guys
would like to contribute
it is patreon.com slash grow from your
heart you can go to patreon.com/scishow
Oh from your heart and you can learn how
to sign up to financially contribute to
the podcast you can keep the podcast
alive you can keep the podcast free for
everybody else and I would appreciate
your support if you're unable to
contribute to patreon
please keep listening to the podcast
this podcast is free it is from my heart
it is my gift to you I've been blessed
with some skills I've been blessed with
a big mouth I feel the need to share
this this is what I need to be doing
this is coming out for free I want you
to have it there are a few people that
want to contribute thank you I needed to
make a way for that to happen and
patreon is the perfect platform for that
so thank you thank you to everyone they
contribute to patreon thank you to
everybody that listens to the podcast
thank you to everybody who supported me
through 304 episodes this show means a
lot to me all of the interaction with
you guys mean a lot to me cannabis means
a lot to me so thank you we're making
cannabis better we are legalizing
cannabis we're making sick people feel
better we're improving the world
together with this podcast so thank you
ladies and gentlemen I want to thank you
again for listening I want to remind you
to be good to one another
I'll be back Thursday with a quickie
episode and then you know I'll be back
Monday with the full-length episode I
want to give you a huge shout out to my
friend concentrate 4:20 and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]