you
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
davor if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast welcome back podcast world
it's time for episode 305 of the girl
from your heart podcast this is gonna be
another Thursday quickie episode thanks
again for joining me I like to start
these episodes off by letting you know
what I've been smoking on all day
instead I'm gonna tell you what I wish I
was smoking on on Sunday I stopped at a
dispensary in Colorado Springs called a
cut above it was a medical dispensary
they had about 75 ish concentrates on
the shelf to offer they also had some of
the best flowers I've seen in a long
time
but what I was there for was
concentrates I'm not joking there were
probably 75 quality concentrates to look
through before I made my decision I was
about halfway through and I stumbled
across something called Starchild og
I've done an episode called follow your
nose talking about whatever jumps out at
your nose is probably gonna probably
gonna be good medicine for you I smelled
this starchild OG and something in my
brain my nose and my body said Rasta
Jeff just buy this there's no need to
look any further I said a gram of that
aside of course I'm stubborn I looked
further and I found some of this super
sour lemon live resin from olio it
smells and tastes amazing but this
Starchild it had this Durbin poison Jack
Herer super Lemon Haze kind of a flavor
going on to it and an aroma and it was
saucy it was high cannabinoid full
spectrum extract crystals floating
around in high cannabinoid full or high
terpene full-spectrum extract Terps
so it was crystals and
just floating around and a tiny jar
together and the aroma just kept
punching me in the face
unfortunately it disappeared very
quickly I smoked that gram Sunday with
keV Kevin and I destroyed that gram we
enjoyed it but it disappeared very
quickly so I've been thinking about it
wishing I had more I came home today I
was gonna take some dabs after work and
I picked up my dad rig and it was a
little mucky I was like maybe I should
rinse that thing out so I wouldn't took
it to the sink and ran some hot water
through it as soon as that hot water hit
my rig I could smell that dryer sheett
Turpin alene Jack Herer Durbin poison
smell throughout the entire kitchen area
it was overwhelmingly perfectly amazing
it was like some sort of aromatherapy
candle had been lit like somebody had
some potpourri or somebody sprayed one
of those little things in the room it
smelled so good it made my mouth drool
it made me wish I had more of those dabs
so the Starchild oh gee that's what I
wish I was dabbing on right now that
stuff was amazing somebody told me it
was actually snow Lotus from Bodhi I'm
not sure if that's accurate whatever it
was shot it to a cut above that was some
delicious extract the high was amazing
the color the consistency the flavor the
aroma beautiful concentrates
unfortunately I bought the very last
gram that they had when I was there so
unless they've got more next time that
was my last shot at bat so the Starchild
og was delicious wish I had more the
kitchen smells like it right now even
though I don't have any I do have a nice
clean rig and I've been dabbing since I
cleaned the rig I've been taking dabs of
the pre 98 bubba kush ambrosia batter
from apothecary it has got sort of a and
I know I say this a lot earthy coffee
cushy sort of a smell to it plus a hint
of chocolate so it's earthy cushy coffee
chocolate maybe with a little like a
sweet thing in there also the pre 98
bubba kush I'm smelling it again
I think I described it accurately earth
coffee chocolate and cush so I'm dabbing
the pre 98 Bubba cush batter I'm getting
decent-sized dabs of the batter and
putting it on the dabber then I'm
getting some bobblehead high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract crystals and
dunking that batter into the crystals to
pick it up like salt and pepper on my
dab so I got a little bobble head
crystals on the dab and the bobble head
is 398 bubba kush and headband ran
together so those are pretty nice dabs
lots of flavor from the batter the
bobblehead concentrate is 98% total
cannabinoids so I'm getting a lot of THC
in my brain when I take a dab of that
I'm getting a lot of cannabinoids a lot
of flavor and the batter gives me this
nice long punch that I really enjoy so
super great dabs today I'm glad I clean
the rig that's what I'm smoking on
thanks for joining me let's move forward
with a podcast ladies and gentlemen
Saturday night I got to go see Chris
Hardwick at Comedy Works in downtown
Denver and holy [ __ ] what a fun show I
had a great time let's start from the
beginning April Richardson the host and
producer well not the host the producer
of The Nerdist now known as the identity
podcast I remember how to say it
identity i Nerdist changed the name of
all their stuff but anyway Chris
Hardwick changed the name of his podcast
listen to it he'll tell you why anyway
April Richardson opened she was pretty
funny ah she makes fun of herself a lot
she's a very unique looking woman so she
uses that to her advantage
miss Jenny Beth was my date for the show
the the comedian April Richardson was
from Georgia Jenny Beth is from Georgia
they had a connection that was fun of
course we were sitting up front so when
the comedian comedian I think that's
what you call a lady comedian when she
said she was from Georgia
Jenny screamed like woohoo cuz they're
both from Georgia and now they made
friends it was pretty cool to have her
kind of come perform right in front of
Jenny for a few minutes so that was a
good time then Miss April Richardson
brought out a guy by the name of Mike
Fuhrman and I knew Mike Furman would be
there because I saw a guitar on stage
when we walked in that was a huge hint
that mike phirman would be there mike
phirman is one of Chris Hardwick's best
for
from a long time ago they go way back
they used to be in a group called hard
and firm together that's right chris
hardwick mike phirman they made a group
called hard and firm where they would
sing really good shitty songs yes I said
really good shitty songs musical comedy
is always terrible unless you're in the
mood for it unless it's hard and firm or
maybe wheeler Walker but usually it's
not good right but these guys pull it
off they're cheesy white guys and they
nail it so ah Fuhrman comes out and does
quite a bit of good material quite a bit
I don't wanna ruin any of it because it
was all great go see it if they're
coming toward your area go there you
guys I drove two hours to go see the
show you have no excuse to not go go see
it it's [ __ ] hilarious
so mike phirman does a a nice set then
he of course brings out the legend Chris
Hardwick Chris Hardwick comes out and
did I don't know he must have done a
solid hour hour in ten minutes and he
killed the entire hour in ten minutes he
uh so he asked the people on stage on
that side he was just having he does a
lot of crowd work he interacts with the
audience quite a bit so he asked the
people over there he's like hey what do
you do for work and the one guy's like
I'm a geologist and he's like cool and
he made rock jokes and he asked the next
person what do you do for work and the
person sitting next to that person said
we're all three geologists so all three
people in that row are geologist Chris
Hardwick is like dammit Denver you're
allowed to hang out with other people
then he walks to the other side of the
stage and he's gonna interview people
over there and he's like sir what do you
do for work and the guys like I'm a
project manager and he's like sounds
good are you sure you're not a geologist
hahaha and then he asks that man's date
what do you do for work and she laughs
really hard and turns red and says I'm a
project manager so on one side of the
stage we've got geologists on the other
side of the stage project managers and
Hardwick is saying to himself damn it
down or not to himself out loud
damnit Denver date other people you
don't have to stay in your box then he
looks at me and he smiles and he says
you and he sticks the mic in my face and
he says what do you do for work sir and
I proudly said I am in the cannabis
industry and I said it just like that
you guys I didn't embarrass the cannabis
industry I didn't embarrass myself I
didn't say a girl weed bro
cuz everybody knows that when they look
at me I got dreadlocks red eyes a
crooked grass roots hats and a veg blue
t-shirt I grow weed I tried to say it
professionally and I said I am in the
cannabis industry
and he goes yeah no [ __ ] I could
probably tell right he made a couple of
jokes and he walked around the stage and
goes on about it for a few minutes then
he makes a joke about how the geologists
the project managers and myself should
get together and start a business right
because we got the guy that breaks up
the rocks and the guy that grows the
dope and the guy that does the project
managing and the hard work made some
jokes on that then he came back to miss
Jenny Beth because she was sitting next
to me and said ma'am what do you do for
work and of course Jenny Beth told the
truth she said I am in the cannabis
industry and the crowd and Hardwick went
[ __ ] wild I thought it was pretty
damn funny it was hilarious he made fun
of us for a couple of minutes then he
walked away then we were on a date I
took the girl on a date so I looked at
her and I gave her a little kiss after
Hardwick made fun of us cos honestly
Jenny Beth has a huge crush a crush on
Hardwick and I don't know if I'm
supposed to say that on the podcast but
hey no hiding [ __ ]
Jenny's got a hat has had a crush on
Hardwick since she was a kid she said so
ah I gave her a kiss because I took her
to that show and I was like look what I
got to do babe Hardwick in her
interacted with you fun date we win so I
gave her a kiss right and hardly goes oh
they kissed how sweet and I went oh how
sweet Hardwick cuz he was right in front
of me I'm front row at comedy works ah
and then he goes oh my god there was
probably some marijuana lipstick or
something involved wasn't there and I
said absolutely dude and then he got
real like serious and he came and stood
right in for anybody goes hey somebody
told me there's marijuana suppositories
and he did the little finger motion like
like you know like suppositories and me
and Jenny Beth like yeah and he just
laughed he's like oh my god they know
about it and they're proud of it
and they're like have you tried these
and me and Jenny of course cuz yeah and
he's like oh my god and then Jenny did
the finger motion back to him they're
like like if you're gonna just insert
one and someone's bum boink she did that
motion and Hardwick just will have to
put his hand on his face and did the UH
shaking my dead damn head laughing he
did that emoji uh he was just [ __ ] it
was funny so we got to see Chris
Hardwick you guys and I'm [ __ ] humble
bragging because it was a great [ __ ]
time ah so Hardwick did his set he
interacted with the audience quite a bit
he goes into the audience he sits on the
audience's lap he I interacted with a
kid named Ian a lot embarrassed the [ __ ]
out of this kid the kid was purple he
may have pissed himself a little bit it
was a good time if you get the
opportunity to go see if Chris Hardwick
go do it
so Hardwick does his set then he's like
would you
his mind if I bring out mike phirman
again cuz that's his best friend and
Furman came out and they did another 20
or 30 minutes together of crowd work and
like improv comedy and then at the end
I'm not gonna ruin it I'm not gonna tell
you what it was about or what they said
or anything but they sing a song
together
it was very very unique there was a
video in the background that matched
their theatrics were beautiful I thought
I was gonna break something laughing so
hard
and it was [ __ ] hilarious so you guys
go see Chris Hardwick
go to comedy works if you go to comedy
works tell him Ross - Jeff sent you and
have a good ass time and be a good be a
good comedy guest don't heckle go enjoy
the show all right I saw Chris Hardwick
it was fun you guys I had to brag on the
podcast come see a comedy show with me
all right um really quickly let's talk
about something that somebody asked me
on Instagram live I do Instagram live
videos where I will answer cannabis grow
questions I'll answer all kinds of weird
questions we talked about all kinds of
random [ __ ] on my Instagram live videos
so join me on there I'm Irie underscore
genetics on Instagram I read genetics so
somebody asked me was actually Banksy
Jesse asked me to explain the difference
between f2 and BX
no I thought of a really easy way to
explain this f2 so let's say you take
let's just pick a strain we're gonna say
a rise so you've got a rise you've got a
handful of a rise seeds you making a
rise male and you making a rise female
now let's back up a step I'm gonna
correct myself and back up a step let's
say you're certain that these seeds are
F once that you're arise seeds are f1
this is the only way that this works
well for my example these are rice seeds
or F once I made the seeds I gave them
to you you've got seeds that you know
are f1 okay so you've got a no rise f1
you find a male and a female that is f1
when I cross Daybreaker to golden goat
Daybreaker and golden go I cross them
they made new seeds that's an f1 okay
that's a rise that's the f1 you got some
of those from me then he found a male
and a female that's a male f1 and a
female f1 okay
if you cross those
you make f2 okay if you cross from the
same handful of seeds if you cross the
male and female from the same batch
batch ah filial generation you are now
making F twos
filial generation F 2 and if you take a
handful of F twos and you cross those
together a male and a female you're
making F 3 and so forth but they have to
come from so the male-female F 1
pollinate each other they make this
handful of seats you take these handful
of seeds you find males and females you
breed them together you make F threes
those seeds that come up you breed them
together you make F fours now so a B X
would be if I took the arise F 1 seeds
that I have and bred them back to either
the golden goat or the Daybreaker that
would be a B X so in the most disgusting
terms to say it F 2 s our brother and
sister [ __ ] F threes or brother and
sister [ __ ] continuing continuing
filial generations our brother and
sister [ __ ] B Xing is parent [ __ ]
okay that's [ __ ] disgusting to think
about it that way but now the idea is
clear in your head and there's no
confusion on what the difference between
an F or a B exit so if you want to make
filial generations forward you just keep
using batches of the same seed that come
out of use so you got your male and
female you breed them I like this little
thing where you make more seeds you put
the male and female together again you
make more seeds you just keep going
forward and the reason to do that is to
stabilize across with a rise I would
like to get them all into that one
phenotype that is real squat it grows
that one squatty bushy phenotype with
the giant Cola it's got a lot of resin
on it and it kind of smells like gassy
ice cream and I know that's a really
weird description but it's like it's got
a smoothness to it and a gas to it at
the same time so I'm gonna find and I've
done a couple generations I just don't
release a lot of things yet I keep some
things to myself you got to find the f1
it looks like what you want it to be and
find another male it looks like what you
want it to be and breed those and then
you'll make the f2 s and then find the
f2 that grows like you want it to be and
then find the male that looks like you
wanted to be and breed those and then
every time you go you should get it
closer and closer to making clones
basically when you grow from
by the time you get to f4 or f5 you're
gonna be growing basically clones from
CDO throw out ten seeds and they're all
gonna look very similar very similar
almost clone like so that's why you
would want to move forward with a filial
generation with brother and sister
[ __ ] now why would you want to do ABX
that's a really good question here's a
really good example golden goat is a
clone only stream there is no male of
golden goat in existence the person that
made that put out the best golden goat
got rid of the rest of it honestly I
don't know what he did but that's never
been released nobody's got access to a
male golden goat other than the guy that
made golden goat whose name is mr. dink
a lot of people like to think I did that
that was not my creation a guy named mr.
dink did that so there's no male golden
go but perhaps a lot of people would
like golden goat seeds I know they would
because they asked me for it all the
time
what's the best way to get some golden
goat seeds without [ __ ] up gold and
go too much you would have to take a
golden go female and pollinate it with a
male plant that is not golden goat so
now perhaps I did that with day breaker
and I made a rise alright so I've got a
golden goat today breaker which wouldn't
have been the best idea my intention
here wasn't me
to make a bx but this is just a good
example golden goat today breaker made a
rise now if I wanted to get golden goat
closer to golden goat seeds I would take
a male a rise that looked a lot like
golden goat that had those long skinny
shitty leaves and then I would put that
pollen on the female gold and go and now
I have just back crossed it and the
reason I'd want to do that is now I'm
going to make seeds that have two so
there's golden goat right here that I
just pollinated plus there's golden goat
and Daybreaker and this other one so now
there's two chances of getting two out
of three chances getting golden goat
style
dominant phenotypes I'm gonna see a lot
of golden goat rates out of that 66%
hypothetically hopefully if I do it
right hopefully about 66% so then I
would grow those and out of that batch
of seeds I would find the best-looking
male the one that looked like the golden
goat male closest to gold and go and I
would use that and I would reap all
innate that gold and go female and those
seeds are gonna be very close to
so that's why you would do a BX you're
trying to make a strain that is clone
only into a seed form people say
couldn't you just reverse it and make
feminized seeds yes you could but a lot
of people do not want feminized seeds
they would rather have a B X so that is
the difference between making f2 f3 f4
is and so forth versus back crossing
your genetics I hope I taught that
correctly I hope you learned something I
hope you had a lot of fun with me ladies
and gentlemen
thanks for hanging out with me on a
Thursday quickie I will be at the dude
grows cup that's right
the dude grows cup I will be there
hanging out look for me I'm easy to find
I'm a tall white guy with dreadlocks
you'll recognize my voice if nothing
else don't be shy walk up introduce
yourself tell me your real name if
you're on Instagram tell me your
Instagram name let's hang out let's take
some dabs
I want to see what you grew I want to
smoke someone what you grew I'll share
with you you share with me maybe I'll
have some seeds in my backpack you never
know I hope to see you guys at the dude
grows cup ladies and gentlemen don't
forget about the 4/20 sale at the hella
dink seed bank that's right the hella
dank seed bank dank seed dot store if
you buy four or five packs of ira
genetics you'll get a free five pack of
cactus cooler cross to arise plus
another free five pack they will be
chosen by my friends at the hella dank
seed bank so make sure you check out the
4/20 sale at dank seed dot store also my
friends at PL grow systems are running a
4/20 special you guys use coupon code
420 and you'll get 20% off this offer
runs from April 16th through April 23rd
sorry I had to make sure I read that
correctly
April 16th through April 23rd and check
out PL grow dot systems for all the
information that you need there you guys
PL grow systems they keep my grow they
keep me comfortable they keep my mind at
ease they keep my grow regulated and
that's something that myself a guy that
runs from grow to grow from place to
place that wants to go places on the
weekends it wants to have a social life
that is recording a podcast and can't
look at my girls right now the peel Gro
minder is something that really helps me
out so make sure you check out PL Gro
dot systems use the coupon code gfy H
420 and you'll get 20% off once again
that runs from
April 16th through April 23rd of 2018
I've got to include that because
podcasts last forever now ladies and
gentlemen make sure you follow me on all
of the social media check me out on
facebook check me out on instagram check
me out on twitter if you've got
something to say and you were not into
all of the social media you can send me
an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com by the time you listen to
this I will probably have 215 ish videos
posted up to YouTube I've got the new
MacBook and is increasing my video
production speed drastically so make
sure you check out the YouTube channel
simply search for grow from your heart
also don't forget about patreon if you
feel like you'd like to contribute if
you feel like you would like to
contribute that makes sense yeah do that
if you feel like you would like to
financially contribute to this podcast
you can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart you can
contribute to the podcast I did get the
mac book patreon didn't completely cover
that that was a little bit of Ross to
Jeff but patreon helped out tremendously
and made it possible if you'd like to
help me cover the entire cost of the mac
book and keep that going you can go to
patreon.com/scishow to keep the website
alive I'll also use that funding to
upgrade some of the equipment over here
that's going to crap sometimes I have to
replace this headphone amplifier quite
frequently but anyway patreon calm if
you would like to support the podcast
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back Monday
with a fresh new episode I think that's
all that I've got for you this week who
are we gonna give a shout out to ladies
and gentlemen I wanna give a huge shout
out to my friend Brett from the dude
grows and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me