yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write of here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Roscoe
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart a podcast welcome back podcast
world it's time for episode 306 of the
girl from your heart podcast I like to
start these episodes off by letting you
know what I've been dabbing on today
today I'm taking dabs of jet fuel live
resin full-spectrum extract from Green
Dot labs this stuff has been amazing
I've got a little tiny jar with a little
bit left and when I crack open this jar
the aroma just fills this room this
whole room is filled with a skunky funky
feely gassy sort of a smell I guess you
would call it jet fuel I opened this jar
and the smell that comes out is like
kinda smells like you were kicking a
skunk in the ass all day and then you
tried to rinse that aroma off with some
diesel fuel then you threw those hot
shoes in the car and the Sun all day and
then you've got in the car and that
overwhelming fuel II skunky smell that
hits your eyes and kind of makes your
eyes burn it makes you squint that's
what this smells like and it is
beautiful I love it it is fuel E it's
skunky it's disgustingly beautiful and I
can't get enough of it
the texture and appearance are all so
beautiful it is perfectly golden and
clear what I like about it a lot is the
amount of crystals or chunks and the
amount of liquids or turps it is not too
runny and too saucy for me I don't
prefer the really liquid concentrate
I prefer the chunkier so this is
probably 70% chunks and 30% crystals
which is just about right for my style I
really like it I was able to get a big
fat dab on the dabber I really
appreciate that when I took the dab it
gave me the most intense cottonmouth
I haven't had cottonmouth like that in
quite a long time that was kind of nice
it tasted really well the cottonmouth
had a pleasant I tasted just like the
concentrate it also gave me a nice eye
high and also I found myself standing in
the middle of the kitchen for no reason
after I took that dab I had a drink and
I have eaten I wasn't hungry or need a
drink or anything but I took a DAB and
the next thing I knew I was just
standing in the middle of the kitchen I
think that's a good sign
that means the concentrates are working
when you're not sure why you're in a
different room alright ladies and
gentlemen thanks for joining me that's
enough
talking about hash let's move this
podcast forward let's cover a little bit
of business and then we will get to some
emails
it is 4/20 time that means it's time for
the 4/20 sale at the hella Danks seed
company that's right a dank seed dot
store you can get four or five packs of
ira genetics plus a free five pack of
cactus cooler cross to arise plus
another free bonus five pack of ira
genetic seeds for a hundred and twenty
dollars during the 4/20 sale the sale is
going on now and it ends on 4/20 so
ladies and gentlemen go check out dank
seed dot store and grab yourself six
five packs of ira genetics for a hundred
and twenty dollars that's right if you
buy four or five packs for a hundred and
twenty bucks
we're going to give you a free five pack
of cactus cooler to arise plus another
free bonus five pack of ira genetic
seeds make sure you check that out
they're also running a bunch of other
great sales on the website they've got a
bunch of other great breeders a bunch of
great brands and a bunch of great deals
so make sure you check them out at dank
seed dot store one more order of
business before we get to some emails
you guys my friends at PL Gro are
running a 420 sale also that's right
from April 16th till April 23rd of 2018
you can use coupon code Z F YH 420 and
you will get 20% off off your P o grow
systems minder unit that's right I use a
minder unit and my grow and my person
will grow
so I can look at my phone and I can see
what the temperature and what the
humidity are in my grow and I don't have
to stress out about anything I can just
look at the phone ago Oh everything's
cool and just keep on recording I don't
even have to get up I don't have to walk
anywhere I don't have to open any doors
and just do it right from my own phone
right here while I'm recording shelling
out so make sure you guys check out PL
Gro dot systems make sure use the coupon
code gfy H 420 and you will get 20% off
of your order and that offer does expire
on April 23rd so jump on that very soon
ladies and gentlemen I think that's all
the ads for this episode let's move
forward with the podcast I have got
great news if you used to listen to a
podcast called the spliff podcast that's
the spliff SPL iff and it is the podcast
P ot CAS T the spliff podcast hosted by
bone Ellis if you were a fan of that
you'd probably probably been missing the
show she's been gone for quite a while
but I've got good news
BOE is back in podcasting she put out an
episode a couple of days ago and it was
wonderful it was so great to hear Bo's
voice as soon as I heard that intro
music I got a smile on my face I hit
play and I heard the little guitar piano
family and I was like ah there she is
she's back those drums come in and then
she's like hey everybody it's so good to
hear her voice um I love Bo's podcast it
is a completely different style of
podcasting than what I deliver it is a
completely different format it is
cannabis-based yes but she has a
completely different approach to
cannabis than I do she talks more about
the effects and more about the
California scene and also she's a woman
so there's a different approach just in
the tone of the show um I've got this
dude voice right I've got a lot of
energy she kind of talks like a
kindergarten teacher and I say that with
all due respect though I love your show
I love it because it feels like my
preschool teacher or my kindergarten
teacher sitting on a little stool in the
class while I'm sitting indian-style and
she's like gather round class today
we're gonna learn about cannabinoids and
I love it and today we're gonna learn
about terpenes and I [ __ ] love the
way beau delivers her podcast I love her
product so big shot at the bow I'm glad
you're back you guys if you're not
listening to the spliff podcast you're
missing something and you should give it
a chance
all right I think that's all we've got
before we can get into some emails I've
covered all the business I said shout
out to bow yeah you guys let's get into
some emails I like to answer emails from
my listeners if you would like to send
me an email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com send me
an email I may read your email on a
future podcast so this one goes like
this also you guys when you send me an
email let me know if you want me to say
your name on the show or not because
oftentimes I don't know if I'm supposed
to say your name and I'd like to if you
want me to say your name I'd like to
give you a shout-out but I don't want to
call you out and get you in trouble also
make you uncomfortable or anything like
that so let me know and I will follow
your guidance all right let's get right
into this email I apologize for that
microphone sound here I'm trying to Mike
out of my face so I can read this email
goes like this hey sir I oversee 288
plants in a drain to waste hydro
commercial grow our feed schedule has us
adding a and B every single day we are
not allowed to change the schedule we
must follow it to 80 but for my own
personal grow should I assume that I
need to add a and B every single day add
a and B until the plants tell us it's
good then possibly every other day all
right if you're growing in cocoa I would
recommend that you just keep giving it
nutrients every day cocoa does not hold
on to the nutrients they fall right
through there's a lot of science I could
go into on that with low cation exchange
an ionic bond but we're not gonna go
there that's just too much talk to
confuse people um
nothing sticks to that cocoa so you do
need to use a and B every day I would
also use some sort of a booster um
you're gonna need cal-mag in there if
you're in flower you're gonna need a
bloom booster you're also gonna need
maybe some epsom salts once a week so I
would do a and B every day and then I
would make a list of the boosts that
you're gonna use like if you're gonna
use a bloom booster a sweetener I like
some carbs some enzymes some silicates
maybe a root inoculate maybe some
cal-mag and possibly some epsom salts I
would make a list of that stuff and on
day one feed at the top of that list
you've got your a and B plus your
cal-mag on day two you've got your a and
B plus your enzymes on day three got
your a and B plus your bud booster and
just go down that list and I'm gonna get
to the bottom go back up to the top and
just cycle through that list and then
that way you can add some other things
to it instead of just the a and B and
that way you're not overdosing them or
over feeding them anything if you want
to mix a few things in there you can
makes what they need but I would give it
a and B every single day if there's not
nutrient if there are not nutrients in
the soil or in the cocoa the plants
can't eat and if they can't eat they're
not producing to their highest level as
long as you are P aging everything and
you're not getting a salt build-up and
you're not over feeding you should be
able to feed a and B every day now there
is a second part of the email that I
need to address he says also the ph
window i usually work with is five point
eight to six point two we are told that
we must and he put must in capitals so
they [ __ ] mean it we were told that
we must fluctuate by point one every
single day is it a benefit to hit every
ph point or just keeping pH at six is
good to go
I would stick with 6.3 or 6.4 you're a
little bit too low at five point eight
to six point two I would come up I would
go six two at my lowest and six five at
my absolute highest but I would rather
be at six point three or six point four
we mix a lot of nutrients at my large
facilities I run two grows for three
rivers and we mix 150 about 200 another
180 ish like 350 450 500 something
gallons there's 500 something gallons of
flowering nutrients mixed in one room
and then easily 500 gallons mixed in
another and we get the pH to six point
three or six point four whatever we
designate we dial it in on the [ __ ]
money
so it's not that hard you have to have a
pH pin and some patience and a bottle of
pH down it's gonna start off too high
put in a cap full give it a good stir
test it see what happens now start
putting in drops until you get where you
want it go slow and get it to six three
or six four don't overdo it
all right now I would move the pH up
that's the first thing I would do now
you're told that you must fluctuate by
0.1 every single day why I want to know
why they think that why why do you need
fluctuation plants love consistency we
are building automated systems we're
building all these things on timers
everything is attached to a timer
everything has got some sort of a
schedule we show up at a certain time
you eat breakfast at a certain time you
get lunch at a certain time consistency
is key I'm not sure why we would change
the pH by 0.1 every single day there is
no benefit to that in my opinion I don't
see the reason I would adjust it to the
proper pH where the plants can absorb
the nutrients and everything worked well
on purpose every day why would you
change that so without trying to go too
far into pH I kind of want to I don't
have any notes on this I wasn't gonna
rant on this this is a side rant this is
a general idea of how pH works
certain nutrients are available to the
plants at certain pH levels so if you
drew a like a half circle chart I guess
we'd go the other way to go up you've
got an up graph a graph that's a half
circle so it looks like a sunrise right
you got the sunrise a half circle going
up some nutrients are absorbable at pH
around 5/8 some nutrients are most
absorbable at pH around 6.8 we have
found that almost everything will be
absorbed right around 6.2 that's where
you can get everything you may not get
one nutrient the best you may not get
the other nutrient the best but you'll
get everything efficiently everything at
six point two six point three six point
four that's when you start getting at
all if you go too high some things
aren't available if you go too low other
things are not available everything is
efficiently available around six three
that's why we lock it in there now also
here's what's gonna happen your plants
are going to go from freshly water we're
gonna call that freshly water that's
heavy right that's as wet as they're
gonna get now your pH is gonna be at one
state now when you leave they're gonna
start drying up and as they get drier
the pH is going to change the pH level
in your Coco in your rhizosphere is
constantly changing based on the amount
of moisture based on the temperature the
amount of oxygen that is all affecting
your pH inside your rhizosphere that
stands for potential hydrogen so think
about if you've got your pot let's find
a vessel if this is your pot this is
where all of your cocoa is you stick a
meter in there there's so much potential
hydrogen now watch if I add this pen I
have already changed your amount of
potential hydrogen because
you had if this was a hundred percent
full of hydrogen not anymore because you
have to deduct for the pen so every I
should have put something wet in here so
that it could dry if I spit into here
we've just changed the pH now as my spit
dries up you can see the amount of space
disappearing that my spit is taking up
so the pH will change the water is going
to do that the moisture is going to do
that the pH is going to change in your
rhizosphere constantly so you make it at
6-3 and as it fluctuates it will do that
point one adjustment for you as time
goes on I hope that made sense the way
that I did that um I took a container
dropped a pen lid into it you can't have
as much hydrogen in there because now
you're taking up space from the lid
right so that's what the oxygen does
that's what the water does it changes
the pH in your rhizosphere I hope that
makes sense the way I said it so no
there is no benefit to changing your pH
every day consistency is key in a large
scale grow man congratulations on the
position in a 288 plant drained away
system that's cool I'm glad you were
able to get yourself into the industry
yes you do need to feed a and B every
day and I would work some other things
into there and do not fluctuate your pH
so much and try to get it closer to 6-3
that's what I would do all right I know
that you're not able to change that in
your commercial grow maybe you can just
put this podcast on and put it on repeat
and maybe the people that are in charge
will walk by and they'll hear that and
then ask them why do I want it to
fluctuate I would ask why are you a
person that asks why don't be afraid you
look like you're trying to learn just
like hey why do I want to do it
differently every day something that I
like in a large facility is to train
everybody to do everything the same way
every day because I'm off for the next
two days I will not be there but I need
to know that the things are happening
the same way that they would if I were
there I just need to know that it's
happening so we train everybody to do
everything the same every day we take
notes we write it down we use Google
Documents I know what everybody fed
every plant today because there's a
Google spreadsheet that says hey I gave
room a this I gave room B this we try to
keep track
so I don't see why you would want to
vary and deviate keep it [ __ ]
consistent so much better alright dude
thanks for the great email you guys once
again if you'd like to send me an email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I would love to answer
your emails ask me some questions
alright here's another email this person
does not say if they want me to use
their email or say their name or not
anyway the email goes like this top of
the day to you Rasta Jeff question for
you which way do you personally prefer
to trim wet or dry and would you mind
explaining why I love the plant however
I personally do not use these days I
grow for my family and friends I
appreciate your time and advice your
podcast contains a plethora of knowledge
and I enjoy tuning in thanks for all
that you do wow that's a lot of great
stuff right there first of all you are
welcome thanks for noticing that I do a
lot of stuff thanks for the compliment
thanks for the email you're very welcome
first he says or they say I don't know
if this is a man or a woman or both
since its 2018 they say question for you
which way do you personally prefer to
trim wet or dry
I prefer after many years of
experimenting and wasting a lot of time
I have learned that I prefer dry trim
dry trim is it's easier it's more
efficient it's less time-consuming it's
less of a pain in the ass and in a
commercial environment it's more uh it
makes a lot more sense and I'll explain
that I just want to make sure I cover
the whole email
I love the plant I love the plant too
and I'm glad you're on our team you say
however I personally do not use these
days you grow for family and friends
hey that's cool you're not even
consuming the product but you've got a
passion for growing it that's awesome
everybody needs a good grower then you
say you appreciate my time and advice
then you're very welcome I'm glad you
you sent me an email to say thank you
and then you say the podcast contains a
plethora of knowledge and you enjoy
tuning in dude that makes everything
worth it so I'm glad you were getting a
plethora of knowledge keep tuning in now
let's talk about why I prefer wet or dry
trim wet trim is kind of a crucial thing
that's like we cut down the plant if
we're gonna wet trim it we got a [ __ ]
wet trim it now is the time you got to
go you're under the gun there's no
mistakes there's lots of pressure
you can't stop until you're finished you
just have to trim and then it's kind of
it's super sticky it's kind of a pain in
the ass also yours it's so sticky I like
dry trimming the way that I like to do
it is just before harvest I will go take
off all of the big leaves all the leaves
with the pea deol they get snapped right
off the plant several days before
harvest then we continue flushing then
on harvest day cut down the plants and
hang them upside down now you've just
got plants hanging upside down they will
start to get crunchy want this once the
stems pop once they start popping when
you bend them crunch then I will put
them into bins I will cut the main part
of the stick out and then I'll leave a
bunch of stick in there but I'll put
them into big Rubbermaid or Tupperware
bins ah they are 2 feet long by a foot
wide and about 18 inches tall those are
the Rubbermaid bins I like to use I can
fit a couple plants in there maybe 3 or
4 plants the size I grow them so I put
the dry plants in there I cut out a lot
of the big stick but I leave some of it
because there's moisture in there that's
gonna come into play so I have excuse me
I have plants that kind of kind of snap
now they've gone into these Rubbermaid
containers then I will put the lid on
them it's a good idea to wrap them in
butcher paper just put one good wrap of
butcher paper around a bevel absorb any
excess water that wants to come out
that'll help you so lock him in there
seal him up then once a day just go in
there and open that container and let
out all the funky air spin him around so
where the buds that were on the bottom
are now on the top leave him open for a
few minutes and close them again now
you've got dried buds that are basically
just drying and curing now you can go in
at any time and get one of those
Rubbermaid containers and just carry it
out to the table and to start trimming
you can dry trim that product whenever
it's gonna stay in there dried and cured
in stasis forever
until it gets ridiculously dry but if
you seal it up and put it in a room with
humidity control we keep it in a room
with a dehumidifier and a humidifier on
they fight each other all day but we
keep that room 50% humidity constantly
you'll hear that dehumidifier click off
and two seconds later here comes the
humidifier like yep it hit 52% and then
they battle and then a real good
to 49% the other one will come on so
it's constantly 50% in that room but
that's what keeps our buds at just the
right squishiness just the right texture
we keep them in the container sealed but
a little bit about moisture exchanges
you can't keep they're not all airtight
so we keep them in that room and they
get perfect so we cut them down let them
get to where they snap once they snap we
put them in the containers then you can
just open them up and dry trim them
whatever you can cut the buds off the
sticks and you can trim them up by hand
you can hold the button your hand and
knock this the leaves off with your
thumb just use your thumb just like
you're playing a video game or just use
a little like it's little thumb scissors
then just knock the leaves off it's not
nearly as sticky it's not nearly as
messy it's not as much of a pain in the
ass you won't go through as many gloves
and also as you're dry trimming you can
take those dried buds and just throw
them right into the bag because that's
ready for retail ready for packaging
ready for whatever you're gonna do with
it and then you've got this little pile
of trim that you can turn into whatever
you're gonna do with that and you can
weigh that finished product
as soon as you're done trimming it so if
you're paying your trimmer by weight if
you say hey I'll give you this much per
pound then he's got dry trim he's just
pulling it off trimming it up throw it
in a bucket trimming it off throw in a
bucket trim it off throw in a bucket and
then at the end of the day you can put
that dry product on the scale and you
can see how much they actually did trim
with wet product it's wet you don't know
how much is there that [ __ ] can dry up
30 50 75 percent maybe 80% depending on
how soon before harvest it got watered
so I like dry trim it's less of a rush
it's less of a fiasco it's less of
there's less pressure you don't have to
just you're not under the gun as much
there's not as much of a deadline with
the dry trim you can just seal them up
in containers and as long as they're
sealed they're gonna stay the way that
they are you can just trim em up when
you need them so maybe maybe you don't
have anywhere for that product to go
maybe you don't have a patient that
needs it maybe you're not hustling it
maybe you're not flipping it maybe you
don't have time to trim it you can just
sit there dry it as long as it's sealed
up you can just sit there with the
leaves on it so that's partly why I like
it and it's just less messy it's wet it
is not as sticky it's not as much of a
pain in the ass so that's why I prefer
dry trim it makes more sense to me Mike
and I used to wet trim for hours and we
would be at it all night wet trimming we
would start trimming afterward
for whatever is you can't trim during
the day when everyone's around you gotta
wait till the night time when people are
kind of low key because it [ __ ]
stinks and then you gotta be in it for
hours so we'd start trimming in the
evenings and we'd go until sunrise and
then try to go to work the next day a
half exhausted we wore ourselves out wet
trimming we would be super sticky we
would over trim because you trim it and
that blood dries up and it shrinks and a
lot of those leaves you trimmed off what
it just shrunk up you wouldn't even have
seen it anyway so yeah dried trim is
better in my opinion in most commercial
applications that are doing dry trim
because it's such a rush there's such a
deadline that's such a fiasco to do wet
trim so dry trim is the way to go in my
opinion once those buds are dried and
trimmed up you can already weigh them
also so that feels good it's a nice to
know it's like chip chip chip chip chip
chip chip two pounds cool I did that it
just feels good I said two pounds don't
don't kill yourself if you can't trim
two pounds in a day one is good I hope
you could do two I hope so
but one is cool all right you guys I'm
getting off on a ramble here hey thanks
for the great email you guys start
including if you want me to say your
name on the show or not in your emails
because I would like to give this person
and the other person a great shout out
because they did send me wonderful
emails but I don't want to get anybody
in trouble um with your job with your
community with your wife with your
girlfriend your boyfriend whatever
trying to be respectful so if you want a
shout out let me know and I will hook
you up you guys if you want me to read
your email on the podcast all you've got
to do is send it to me it's a girl from
your heart a hotmail.com I've got a huge
stack of emails I'm working through if
you'd like to get your email to the top
just go to patreon.com/scishow Oh from
your heart everything you need to know
will be right there all right you guys
don't forget it's about the 4/20 sale at
the hella Danks seed company also don't
forget about the discount code at pol
grow systems I'm gonna open that up
again and make sure that I give you the
right coupon code cuz I don't want to do
it wrong it's GF wih 420 at PL Gro dot
systems make sure you check them out you
guys I hope everybody has a great 4/20
ladies and gentleman I would appreciate
it if you find me on all of the social
media check me out on Facebook search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Eirene on instagram i use i read
genetics it's i RIE
underscore genetics I post a bunch of
great Canibus photography I do Instagram
live feeds where I go and hang out with
my friends and answer cannabis
and take dad's today I was on Instagram
live with Gavin granny we were talking
about podcast stuff and dabbing and
answering questions for her audience
that was a lot of fun shout-out to
granny I love you everyday I miss you
let's get together so Instagram live
yeah follow me on Instagram check out
the cannabis photography check out the
live feed that's a lot of fun also I am
on Twitter you can find the podcast it's
at g f YH podcast you can find my
Twitter simply search for Rasta Jeff 420
it's real easy to find I always retweet
all the podcast stuff so you're probably
following me anyway ladies and gentlemen
if you would like to interact with me
and you're not into social media if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast or if you've simply got
something that you would like to say you
can send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you know I would
love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen I upgraded to a new MacBook I
think you can hear it the sound quality
recording is easier editing is easier
it's a lot more fun also it has made it
a lot easier to produce the YouTube
videos there are about 250 videos
produced and on my YouTube page I have
only released about 230 ish but they are
coming much more quickly now so I will
get caught up way more soon way more way
sooner than anticipated I was doing
pretty well right up until that point
with the English ah but I'll get the
videos caught up you guys thanks for
being patient if you want to watch old
videos and see the old content go to the
YouTube channel go to youtube.com and
search for the girl from your heart
podcast you will find me go check out
the old videos I would appreciate that
ladies and gentlemen I like to remind
you about patreon if you feel like this
podcast was worth a couple of bucks you
can go to patreon.com/scishow from your
heart and you can learn how to
financially contribute to the podcast I
mentioned the new MacBook earlier about
half of that was covered by patreon
contributions thank you
I couldn't have upgraded I don't know
that the podcast would sound as good as
it does without your help
so with patreon contributions we were
able to cover the new MacBook I also
like to cover the cost of the website
with the patreon contributions I have a
website where I host the podcast that's
how I'm able to get the show out to
everybody for free there are some people
who are able to contribute to the
patreon campaign I appreciate you
it's patreon.com slash Grover
go check it out if you contribute at
certain levels I do offer certain gifts
go look there may be something there
that you're interested in you never know
if there's something you think I should
put on there is something I would offer
for a contribution let me know how else
I can help you out and we'll see what we
can do all right you guys I think that's
all the rambling that I've got for you
for this week I will be back Thursday
with a throwback Thursday episode
tomorrow is the dude grows cup so by the
time you listen to this I will have gone
to the dude grows Cup in Denver I will
be back Thursday to report on that event
and let you know how it goes I will let
you know what I got to smoke on do I got
to hang out with I'm sure that's gonna
be a ragin good time I've got a couple
other things in Denver that I'm gonna go
to that I'm not sure I'm allowed to talk
about on the podcast if they give me
permission to speak on it I will
certainly share everything that I can
you guys I'll be back Monday with the
brand new episode thanks for hanging out
with me I made it through the whole show
without taking a break or taking a drink
I'm proud of myself I'm proud of my
throat I'm proud of you guys for hanging
out with me and hanging in there this
has been a lot of fun I truly do
appreciate each and every one of you for
listening to the podcast
I appreciate if you're listening on
iTunes I appreciate you if you're on
stitcher I appreciate you if you're on
youtube or however you're listening
thank you thank you for supporting
cannabis thank you for supporting the
podcast and thank you for supporting me
I appreciate it I appreciate each and
every one of you you guys I am a rambly
tonight so I'm gonna get out of here
before I make this a long podcast I want
to give a huge shout out to Mitzi shore
and until next time take a phat gab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]