yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode 307 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
my friends call me Rasta Jeff thanks
again for joining me ladies and
gentlemen this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company that's right if you
need new genetics for your garden I
highly recommend the hell a dank seed
company you can find them at dank seed
dot store the hella dank seed company is
running a 420 sale that's right you can
get four or five packs of ira genetic
seeds for a hundred and twenty dollars
and you're also going to get two bonus
free five packs of ira genetic seeds
that's six five packs for a hundred and
twenty dollars at the hell a dank seed
company this offer lasts until April
21st so check them out at dank seed dot
store also ladies and gentlemen our
friends at pol grow systems are giving
us an excellent deal for the 4/20
celebration that's right but running a
4/20 special with coupon code GF wih 420
you will get 20% off your order
that offer does expire on April 23rd
make sure you check out PL grow dot
systems to learn more about the minder
unit it is a great device I highly
recommend it all right podcast world
that's all the advertising I've got for
you today you know I like to start the
podcast off by letting you know what I
am smoking on I feel like I've smoked a
little bit of everything over the past
weekend I smoked flowers I smoked dabs I
smoked a joint with dabs inside of it I
smoked every kind of concentrate I could
imagine I think you might be able to
hear it in my voice but it was great it
was worth it but today let's talk about
what I've got in my hand right now I've
got some white lightning number seven
sauce from our friends at olio
it is olio sauce I'm cracking it open it
smells like banana runts
like the banana
shaped candies that you get out of the
little quarter thing at the bowling
alley or wherever you get them it smells
like banana runts with another sweetness
on top of it maybe maybe a hint of lemon
maybe on top of the banana run too
lemony banana run this concentrate it's
going quickly there's one good crystal
left in here once again with olio I
really appreciated the amount of sauce
which is the Terps to Crystal's which is
the high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract the ratio was beautiful
about 30 percent Terps 70 percent chunks
it's really easy to dab that way it's
not a pain in the ass to get on the
dabber I don't feel like I'm wasting a
lot of the juice great concentrate from
our friends at olio I highly recommend
that the white lightning number 7 sauce
delicious kind of tastes like banana
runts if you're into banana that's a
good thing if you're not into banana
this might not be the thing for you
alright shout out to our friends at olio
great concentrates and I said I've been
smoking a little bit of everything let's
talk about why I went to an event called
the dude grows cup let me tell you a
little bit about what the dude grows Cup
is there is another podcast hosted by my
friends the dude and Scottie real what's
up guys I hope you're listening I they
threw an amazing event this weekend
anyway the dude gross show the dude bro
shows the podcast that's the name of the
show the dude and Scottie real are the
host and co-host guru is the producer
there's a couple other cats that are on
quite frequently I'm always gonna miss
names I feel bad cuz I'm a pothead and I
forget names but shout out everybody
from the dude gross show and the dude
grows crew so these guys on the dude
grows podcast decided that they're going
to throw a cup and this year was their
third cup so they've got some experience
and they're getting really good at it
this was a great event so it is a cup
growers grow flowers their pot and they
entered their pot into this Cup and then
a bunch of folks were invited myself and
a lot of other people I don't have a
good head count on how many people were
in there it was at a place called
cultivated synergy and it was perfectly
crowded it was crowded enough to look
like a big crowd but not so overcrowded
that you were shoulder-to-shoulder
bumping into people but anyway a bunch
of people came everybody that grew their
product came there were at least 30
maybe 40 entries so the way
work these people grew their product and
they entered them they turned them in in
a jar and then these jars were all wind
up across a I would call it a bud bar in
one section of the building the back
wall of the building just had a long bud
bar setup and there were bud tenders
behind that bar packing bulls for you so
if you walked up and you said hey can I
try sample number one the person behind
that bud bar would pack up a bowl of
sample number one for him just a small
one II Bowl they're a bunch of fresh
pipes laying around and people had pipes
for days so you just walk up and say hey
can I get a fresh sample of number one
they'd pack up number one for you take a
little hit of it see what you think of
it blow it out and get back in line and
go try sample number two and then get
back in line and do sample number three
and just work your way down the table
and there were 30 to 40 samples so if
you wanted to smoke all of them you were
gonna be there for a little while cuz
you had to stand in line between each
one and also you want to take a second
between each puff you don't want a smoke
example one smoke sample do how you
gonna tell what happened sample two is
gonna be the only one you notice maybe
maybe sample one's all you noticed but
you didn't know two sample - see what
I'm saying you can't do it that way so
you gotta take a minute anyway so they
were all lined up people were you take a
smoke then once you smoke all of the
samples you want to try then it was time
to vote and they gave us tokens that
said the dude grows Cup on them and they
were just little wood tokens and he
would place those in the corresponding
jar numbered - which sample you like so
if you like sample number one or number
23 or whatever you would go ahead and
throw your count your a little token
your coin into jar number one or jar
number 23 to show that you had voted for
that strain and we were given three four
or five tokens I don't remember how many
tokens there were but yeah you were
given tokens to vote with that's how you
vote it and then they just went through
and counted how many votes there were
for each one and then they did announce
the winners at the end of the night I've
got the list of winners right here first
place at the dude grows cup I don't know
what they grew I just have the names
first place Oh should I start at the
bottom let's start at fourth place I
almost [ __ ] that one up fourth place
you guys was a friend of mine was a
friend of the show was a friend of the
dude gross crew fourth place was a very
respectable very honorable very polite
very friendly young dude my friend Moby
dill won fourth place at the dude grows
cup and I cannot remember the name of
his entry however you'll hear this jar
pop open
that is a little sample of it he gave me
a nice sized nugget it's lemon Jie
crossed to something and he he either
called it Colorado pucker or a lemon
pucker I want to say he called it
Colorado pucker and it's lemon G cross -
something I can certainly see the ugly
lemon G structure I'm not dissing your
grow lemon G is ugly to grow you did a
hell of a good job of it just the way
this bud is shaped is obviously lemon G
and it smells too high hell of lemon G
greasy lemon funk
oh I'm just I just keep smelling it over
and over this is amazing as soon as I
opened the jar it kind of punched me in
the face it's almost overwhelming this
whole house is gonna smell like that
lemon turf for quite a while now
Mobe dill much respect bro great grow
fourth place if that is 4th place I can
only imagine what 1st place smelled and
taste like I may have smoked that I may
have tried it I'm not sure anyway we're
gonna keep going
let's see second uh third place third
place was an entry by a person named
Jaron so shout out to Jaron second place
was a person who called themselves
Gwen Green thumps a shout out to Gwen
green thumb and then first place winner
at the dude grows Cup was a person who
called themselves bin ski and I've
actually heard a lot about Ben ski going
around the industry lately that is a
name that people are saying so shout out
to Ben ski for being first place with
the flower competition at the dude grows
Cup so let's talk about the couple
little that I told you what it was I
told you who won I told you how it
worked
people grew flowers they entered flowers
we smoked flowers we voted they
announced a winner that's basically how
a cup should go it went smoothly in that
aspect without a hitch nothing went
wrong in my opinion
I got super lucky and found a really
nice parking space otherwise that could
have been kind of a pain in the ass is
that a lot of stuff to carry but nothing
went really wrong nothing was poorly
planned this year I think everything
went fairly well so and I had a great
time one of my favorite parts about it
is there were two or three different
podcasts there of course it is a dude
gross event it's hosted by the dude
gross they invite me the girl from your
heart podcast I go up there and hang out
and then also I met a couple other folks
that have podcast shout out you guys
I honestly I'm gonna forget a lot of
people that I want to give shout outs to
because I got super lit and I had a
super good time and I didn't write down
names and [ __ ] but I'll try to do my
best to remember but
ah my favorite part is that all these
people get together all these podcasters
come together and we just all hang out I
get to meet people that listen to the
dude grow show I get to people listen to
meet people that listen to my show I get
to meet people that found the dude show
through my show and people that found my
show through the dude show it's just
such a good time to get the community
together people that message me on
social media and on through email and
however they contact me mostly social
media right I get to meet them and
actually shake their hand and give them
too big of a dab and watch them turn
pale and try not to fall over because
they're not from Colorado they don't get
to dab like that and I'm spoiled and I
like to spoil them so that's what I love
about it it's such a good time cuz we
get people from all over the country and
a lot of the events are a bunch of
younger kids and it's uh the music's too
loud and it's just it's a little
obnoxious and it's mostly like a like a
trade show like an RV show everyone's
just trying to sell [ __ ] and their way
of selling you [ __ ] is by having hot
girls and loud music that doesn't happen
at the dude bros cup there are plenty of
beautiful ladies there but they are not
vending anything they're just they're
hanging out smoking dad's there they're
part of the crew they're not there for
advertising the music is at a very
acceptable level I don't have a headache
my throat's only burnt out because I
chose to talk way too much I never
stopped talking I met so many cool
people and a lot of the other events the
music's so loud that when I come home I
throat hurts the music is at a great
level this is a little bit of an older
crowd it's not the super young crowd
it's the next level up so I kind of
enjoyed that aspect of it it's super
comfortable I don't have any worries
leaving my backpack sitting on the table
and turning my head a few times I don't
feel like someone's gonna rob me I
really like that so it's a great event
the venue is awesome cultivated synergy
is great at hosting events like this
shout out to cultivate its energy for
taking good care of us I really enjoyed
the event I got to meet a lot of my
friends I got to meet so one of our
friends actually there was a huge
snowstorm east of here right before the
event and our friend I'm not sure if he
wants his name said but one of our
friends was trying to come in and he got
snowed in and had to post pictures of
himself stuck at a hotel saying I'm
gonna miss the dude grows Cup and the
community felt bad were like [ __ ] dude
that sucks everyone's messaging like man
we hope to see you there bro like Oh
you figure it out and then I met the
dude gross cup and this big guy walks up
introduced and introduces himself and
he's like what's up bro this is me and I
was like bro I thought you were snowed
in and he's like dude we saw Cara's
going on the highway and we got in the
[ __ ] car man I was like hell yeah so
they got to make it so a bunch of my
friends got to make it to the cup a
bunch of people that I see on the
Instagram Y feeds made it to the cup a
bunch of people I message with it was
really cool to shake a bunch of their
hands um I don't want to leave anybody
out so I'm not gonna say a whole bunch
of names I just want to give a huge
shout out to the dude and Scottie dude
thank you guys for inviting me to the
cup I had a great time your event is
awesome ladies and gentlemen if you can
go to the dude grows cup next year it's
gonna happen next year I invite you come
take some dads with me do not do this
what happens a lot of times as I get
messages on Sunday saying hey bro I saw
you last night at the cup I didn't want
to say hi you looked busy
I'm not busy I'm there chit chatting and
bullshitting and taking dad's with my
friends you're my friend but in say
what's up I don't want to butt in you do
want to put it just be polite and say
hey I'm going to interrupt I want to
meet Jeff I want it dad with Jeff come
say hi shake my hand don't feel bad I
get super lit everyone else is super lit
the conversations just come and go
you'll say one sends and then your
attention drifts off to the next
conversation you try to keep up come say
what's up to me don't be shy I want to
be your friend I want to meet you also
so um I love the interaction you guys it
was great meeting a lot of people come
say hi I don't even remember what the
[ __ ] I was saying but I do want to talk
about something that I did enjoy I never
caught the young man's name there was a
guy sitting across from me at this
little bar area and we're taking some
dabs and he pulled out some bordello
chatter and some Clementine chatter I've
been growing bordello at Three Rivers
for quite a while and we've made some
chatter out of it we've had a couple
other companies make chatter for us and
it's come out pretty good but this dude
made some [ __ ] bordello chatter that
brought out the the sweetness to the
bordello there's this undertone of
sweetness and he brought it out so nice
so dude whoever made that bordello
extract if that is you good job my
friend that stuff was delicious it was
so nice I was ah it might have been like
the first or second dab I took when I
got there and I was carrying my bag and
I'd been parking and
been driving for quite a while and you
know when you run into an event you see
everybody it's like tense for a second
should I just wanna put down my bag and
relax and so I put down my bag and my
cooler and I got chilled out and I was
kicking it then I took that dab and then
just put me in like chill like all right
now it's time to be at the dude bros cup
mode so everything was just just chilled
out it was perfect I loved it
all right so shout out to the dude with
the bordello chatter I never caught your
name dude uh thank you thanks for the
great dad
message me if you hear this let me know
who you are and maybe we can meet up and
take some dabs I'd love to try some more
of that bordello it was delicious all
right ladies and gentlemen if you can
attend the dude gross Cup I highly
encourage you to do that next year make
sure you go check out all the samples
make sure you vote make sure you hang
out I got super lit I walked in I met up
with some friends and hung out in one
area for a little while we took a bunch
of dabs then I realized there was a
bunch of space at that little bar area I
went over there set up my dad area and I
just hung out met a bunch of people uh
then they wanted to do the prize
giveaway at that area so that's when I
drifted off to another area that's when
they did the awards you guys they gave
away so many prizes that night if you
had raffle tickets if you got in on the
raffle you were able to win so many cool
prizes if you go next year get in on the
raffle because you will win something so
many people leave early that all the
people that stick around that's who wins
everything so stick around win some cool
stuff I was gifted some cannabis a
friend of mine who I cannot remember
their name like I said it was a cannabis
event I've got a traumatic brain injury
I meant a lot of goddamn people I was
gifted some flowers called [ __ ] if
you gave me the [ __ ] flowers
you're my new [ __ ] hero this [ __ ]
smells so good oh my god I can smell I
don't know the cross I know there's some
star dog in there
that's why it's called star [ __ ]
there's star dog in there for sure I can
smell the star dog either start a killer
or star dog it smells like star dog to
me I don't know what the cross is good
[ __ ] job whoever drew this weed
yeah it's called the star [ __ ] and it
is Rasta Jeff approved I completely like
that weed it's super dense it smells
like star dog it's got great green and
bright orange colors to it it is the
density gets gets my attention and the
aroma is kind of like old school weed
it's like weed used to get in California
it's got a little bit of chem it's got a
little bit of skunk
going on to it super delicious weed good
job whoever gave me that alright so
that's pretty much my wrap-up of the
dude grow show you guys not a lot to uh
to highlight it was a great cup
I got lit I saw a bunch of great friends
that's what I was there for um
definitely worth the drive definitely
worth the ticket price if you go get
there early because parking in that area
is kind of a [ __ ] I got super lucky
somebody pulled out of a spot and I was
like oh man you got to dive in there and
be aggressive in Denver so yeah go to
the dude grows cup and also listen to
the dude grows podcast that's right
wake-and-bake with the boys roll up some
weed and get high that's what I think
you should do shut its my friends at the
dude grows once again I shout out to all
the people that I met shout out to all
the people that I got to hang out with
I'm not sure who wants their names said
or not so I don't want to get anybody in
trouble but I want to give you guys
shout outs it's kind of weird it's kind
of a [ __ ] weird weird level they're
weird boundary but uh my friend Matthew
I'm not gonna say your full-name had a
great time hanging out with you a whole
bunch to the roach mangled remains good
time I don't want to forget anybody so
I'm gonna stop there you guys had a good
time
shout out to everybody that I hung out
with shout out to my friends at new
millennium for taking care of me super
big shout out to uh al gringo de Mota
dude that super lemon haze that your
friend GRU was amazing if you would have
entered that you probably wouldn't get
had a good chance of winning that stuff
was super nice anyway you guys that's
enough names I don't want to get anybody
in trouble I also don't want to forget
anybody I don't want to leave anybody
out feel bad shout out to all the people
that introduce themselves that walked up
and shook my hand shout out to everybody
who had good conversation with me shout
out to everybody that I saw that I
dabbed with I had a great time I
apologize that I'm no good with
remembering names when I see your face
I'll remember you I will high-five you
one thing we need to do is get nametags
we need to write hi my name is and you
need to put your real name and your
Instagram name on there because first
owners and everybody's got to [ __ ]
names they gets to be a lot to remember
like I was talking to a friend on my
Instagram live video and I didn't even
realize who I was talking to because I
was like what's up Instagram handles 710
for 25000
and I'm just talking to him like he's
some random dude like he's asking
questions and I was just like kind of
being kind of vague cuz what he was
asking was I should be vague about that
if I didn't know the guy and so
eventually he's like hey you know that
it's me right and he told me his real
name and I was like oh [ __ ]
dude I didn't realize that was you
because it's hard to keep up with all
the Instagram names and real names so
that's one thing that I would add those
little hi my name is I would have those
tags with your real name and then your
Instagram name or whatever you're known
as or whatever your company is so mine
would say hi I'm Rasta Jeff and I region
etic so that people would be like that
is Rasta Jeff just so there's no
question just so you guys can't say I
wasn't sure if that was you
you guys I'm six five and I have
dreadlocks and a [ __ ] a girl from your
heart podcast t-shirt I'm taking gram
dabs
I'm pretty easy to spot don't be shy
come say hi alright there's one more
quick thing I want to talk about before
I start wrapping up this podcast let me
find this little screen shot that I took
I thought this was entertaining I work
for a Colorado marijuana Enforcement
Division regulated business and let's
see who published this document the the
Med yes the Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division has passed out a
big criminal enforcement division from
the Department of Revenue and where this
came from which is a part of the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
they pass out a paper that says 4/20
reminders and it says 4/20 reminders in
the middle and then it's like a bubble a
bubble a cluster chart I don't remember
what they call these like when you're
supposed to get ideas in school and you
make a circle and you write podcast and
you make notes coming off it you make
another circle and it says talk about
weed another circle comes off and it
says talk about education but they made
one of these in the middle of says
reminders and I'm gonna read you guys
the reminders that they have issued to
the dispensaries the top one says no
sales to non patients and persons under
21 years of age most vertical IDs equal
under 21 so what that means is no sales
to non patients if you're a medical
marijuana dispensary you cannot sell
sell to anybody who is not a registered
patient with a current active card and
valid ID um and persons under the age of
21 if you are a recreational store you
were able to sell to anyone with a 21
and up ID if they're not 21 and up you
cannot sell to them they also give you a
hint most vertical IDs equal under 21 so
if you've got a vertical ID the
was the long way that probably means
that you are a minor you are not buying
cannabis all right
there's another bubble and it says no
public consumption it is violation of
state and local laws and person could be
subject to criminal charges so they're
just reminding you for 4/20 to remind
your customers no public consumption the
next one says visitors and limited
access areas visitors must be escorted
by employee five per employee which I
thought was four so that's an increase
um if you're going to take people that
are not badged and not employees into a
cultivation facility they must be
escorted by a key badged employee you
must have a key badge you can't have a
support badge if they have a key badge
or an owner badge and you have to escort
those people through the facility and
you cannot do more than five people at
one time so if you're gonna bring a band
through if you're gonna bring fortunate
youth loves to go through grows I think
there's like five or six of them you
could bring five of them per person so
you gotta have two people to have the
full band going through there probably
to escort them if a rapper comes through
if Wiz Khalifa comes through by himself
one person can escort Wiz just
one-on-one but you have to have one
person for every five visitors that one
person has to be a key badge you guys
don't have to worry about that I'm just
telling you the weird things that the
media is reminding us of that's because
people come from out of town they know
that celebrities are gonna fly into
Colorado and oftentimes when that
happens you see pictures of said
celebrities on social media and grows in
Colorado and a lot of the grows it's if
you've been to a few of them you can
recognize them like I can scroll up
there and be like oh that's that grow
that's that grow just cuz I've seen them
a lot I know who does what
so the meb sees that and they're like oh
look this bunch of rappers is in this
grow and here's one guy with the badge
and they can see that [ __ ] so be careful
if you're doing that also if you have
this is not on the paper but if you have
visitors in there don't let them touch
product and don't post pictures of
people touching product because visitors
cannot touch product that's illegal
all right I'm gonna continue with the
bubbles the next bubble says no free
product you cannot giveaway marijuana or
marijuana product to a consumer for any
reason so that means no free [ __ ] no
free you can't say buy two of these get
one free you can't do that you can say
buy two get one for a penny but you
can't do them for free there are
loopholes around everything but no free
[ __ ] sales limits one ounce of flour is
equal to 80
ten milligram servings in edibles or
eight grams of concentrates so if you
are an out-of-state shopper or if you're
shopping recreationally and that's just
a recreational thing that's not a
medical marijuana think this is
recreational one ounce of flowers is
equal to 80 ten milligrams serving
edibles or eight grams of concentrates
so that's how they do the math on
deciding how much you are allowed to
purchase so if you're coming from
out-of-state and you want to meet reach
your limit that's the conversion that
you have to do to break it down you can
either get eighty ten milligram servings
of edibles or eight grams of
concentrates those are your limits all
right so I'm gonna continue on with the
little bubble here's the red bubble it
says no consumption on premises a
license II shall not permit consumption
of MJ or MJ product on premises so no
marijuana consumption on site a lot of
people think you can go to the
dispensary and smoke weed there a lot of
people think we're at the gross smoking
weed there no you cannot smoke weed
anywhere regulated by the marijuana
Enforcement Division everything is on
camera from a thousand different angles
there is nowhere I can go in that
building to pick my nose or scratch my
ass that will not be on camera other
than a restroom every square inch of
that facility is on camera
probably from two angles they want you
on camera from two angles at all times
all right we'll keep moving that says
hours of operation no sales before or
after 8 a.m. to 12 a.m.
unless restricted further by local
jurisdiction some of the places around
here I think are forced to be done by
9:00 I think the rule is I'm not certain
on that I don't shop at a dispensary a
lot to tell you the truth guys I only go
to one and it's in Colorado Springs they
are regulated they're forced to close at
nine o'clock and Springs
and their medical only so the bubbles
continue they say check ID must be valid
government-issued ID so you can use your
military ID you can use your normal
state issued ID you can use your
passport
but you have to have a valid
government-issued ID it cannot be
expired advertising it just says follow
appropriate requirements for advertising
you're not allowed to have sign spinners
you can't do that kind of stuff product
limit centers can only have patient two
ounce allowance that's right if it's a
medical marijuana sinner the amount of
product you're allowed to have on hand
is based on how many people are signed
up as
for you as their provider for that
facility so you're only allowed to have
your patient 2 ounce allowance you can't
overload because it's 4/20 you can't
have extra inventory on stock because
you plan on running through it you're
gonna have to have a driver at your grow
or wherever your product is stored ready
to transfer that product and on demand
whenever you run out of a jar or a few
pounds of something and you can take a
five pound delivery you got to have a
guy bring you more so you can't have
extra on sight just because it's 4/20
then the last bubble says licensee may
refuse sales example to a person who is
impaired they're just reminding you that
you've got the right to refuse service
to anybody should you so choose if
somebody walks into your dispensary and
you just don't feel right you do have
the right to refuse service to that
person if you think they're a federal
agent if you think their ID may be fake
if you think they're intoxicated if you
just don't want to sell to them because
it doesn't feel good in your heart you
were allowed to say no all right so that
is a little bubble of a little memo of
bubbles sent out by the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division to all of
the businesses just to remind the
businesses how to keep themselves out of
trouble for 4/20 of course we did have
one facility experience some problems
and they got themselves in trouble so
they're trying to help us out and make
sure that doesn't happen anymore ladies
and gentlemen I hope you enjoyed this
episode of the podcast my throat's
starting to burn out it's Thursday this
was supposed to be a quickie I feel like
I went kind of long by myself anyway so
thanks for hanging out
this episode is gonna come out the day
before 4/20 so I want to wish everybody
a safe and happy 4/20 ladies and
gentlemen smoked a whole bunch of good
cannabis but take care of each other
don't do anything stupid
don't get yourself in any trouble
alright ladies and gentlemen make sure
you follow me on all the social media
check me out on Facebook search for the
girl from your heart podcast on
Instagram I use my other company it's
Irie underscore genetics make sure you
check us out there I like to do a lot of
Instagram live videos follow me join it
on the live feeds also find us on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast if you've
got something you'd like to say if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast or if you've
got a product you'd like me to review
you can send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
to hear what you've got to say also
check out YouTube until further notice
I've got about two hundred and forty ish
videos up on the YouTube channel search
for girl from your heart podcast
I heard that YouTube is cracking down on
all the cannabis channels hopefully I
survive also don't forget about patreon
if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast go to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information that
you need is right there ladies and
gentlemen I hope you have a happy 4/20
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode I'm gonna give a huge shout out
to the dude and Scotty real and the
entire dude grows crew and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me