they'll welcome that cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dapper if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the holiday exceed company you
can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the wrong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart a podcast
[Music]
what's up podcast world it's time for
episode 308 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me it
is the post 420 episode I hope you guys
had a great 4/20 joining me at the table
across the table from me is our good
friend or repeat offender white Mike is
back thanks for joining me dude yeah man
what's up everybody
Oh Mike how are you doing wow man it was
good for its money was it good for you
yeah yeah I feel a little dried out
still yeah I'm a little dehydrated I
feel like I've been yelling and
screaming but it's just from the dads
and all the flowers that I smoke I don't
smoke a lot of flowers I'm dull just
feeling a little half human half jerky
right now half jerky you've always been
a little jerky huh
I've been on since the dude grows Cup
last week I've been smoking heavy I
haven't stopped since then luckily we
have cool employment so at 4:20 on 4/20
we were able to take some 420 smoke egde
yeah I just rearranged our break
schedule that was pretty nice that was
the beginning of a smoke-filled weekend
I haven't stopped I went I went to the
dispensary on sometime last week
Wednesday I think yeah went last
Wednesday and I bought hash about
concentrates for the rest of the week
plus I bought a stash for 4/20 I burned
bright of course my throat is shot on
that I burnt right through that it's
gone I had to go shopping again today we
just got back from the dispensary just a
little bit ago so that's a great segue I
like to start the podcast off by letting
you guys know what I'm smoking today
that's gonna be a challenge because I
just got back from the dispensary and I
think we've taken a dab of almost
everything we bought I've got some Mendo
breath and broza which tastes phenomenal
it is set me back in my seat we haven't
tried that one I haven't tried that one
this is our Pez ambrosia uh super-sweet
pezzi candy kind of a grapefruit
with a cherry aftertaste be Clement I uh
the Clementine tastes amazing doesn't
get me high but the Clement eye
Clementine and Clement eye or two
different things
the Clement eye has that Clementine
deliciousness but it's also got another
thing in there that does get me high so
that's beautiful then the one that
[ __ ] me up the one that made me want
to just go lay down on the couch or
maybe even on the floor might have been
okay was the
the louis xiii ah this battery will do
the dude I took that Dad and I was
talking and in the middle of my sense I
was like brother lately
whoa did I melt him I done like I felt
that like that girl in the on the couch
and the [ __ ] old commercial they just
melted that's what it did to me yes I
finally found that weed that did that
unless you got me to lit so uh yeah the
King Louie the thirteen batter from
apothecary farms that stuff was awesome
I liked the flavor of the Mendo breath
better but the high on the Louie was
pretty phenomenal then ladies and
gentlemen if you listen to the podcast
often you've heard me talk about the
Starchild og that I got from a cut above
they've got more it's back I went and
got some dude it is so delicious now
it's almost but yeah but the the jar
that I bought today is almost gone now
Mike and I have been over indulging on
this it's wonderful would you agree with
the citrus dryer sheett sandalwood
peppermint flavor yeah okay this hint of
peppermint no it's a lot it's got that
candle store kind of yeah that's a lot
of sense and flavors all at once but the
dryer sheet in the candy were out front
yes yes and that dryer sheet thing that
it leaves on your mouth that cottonmouth
flavor I I enjoy that flavor that dryer
sheet that's uh Turpin alene is what I
think that terpenoid is that gives you
that flavor I really enjoy that it comes
in you find that in Jack Herer a lot you
find that in the trainwreck I guess cuz
that's what this Cross has trainwreck in
it that's probably where that came from
I love it great flavor we haven't tried
it yet but I've also got some of the
Green Dot labs black label white Durbin
nectar this is the white crusted urban
poison I'm excited to try this one a
little bigger I just know so many things
that I had to save one for later
that Green Dot is kind of the the fancy
one we wanted to do a slightly more
coherent show so we slowed our roll a
little bit I just a little the Green Dot
is a great product it's worth the money
but I prefer a different consistency and
everything was on sale for 4/20 so I
grabbed some of the Green Dot
label it's gonna be like my uh my secret
stash my spoil myself stash the after
podcast dabs when you want to get a
little goofy and not have to pay
attention to anything right so that's
what we're smoking on today Mike really
seemed to like the sour Pez when I gave
him a dab of that I was really nice but
then the which one was it that really
made you choke up a lot of the mindo
breath was definitely the other Mendo
breath was a cougher yeah that one made
you choke up a whole bunch but I think
everybody enjoyed all the dads so great
work to a cut above and green dot and
apothecary mantra bronze spinner yeah
it's been a great 4:20 it's been a hazy
and Daisy 4:20 Mike do you do anything
exciting on 4/20 no just a lot of
consumption a lot of consumption it
didn't go anywhere skip most of the
events it's easier that way yep
it's uh everything's real crowded I
didn't stocking up for a while so I got
home and I was like well I have all my
favorite flower and a bunch of live
residents just enjoy it let's just enjoy
it speaking of things to enjoy I don't
know I'm trying to find a segue this
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at the hell at Bank seed company that's
right if you need some new genetics for
your garden I recommended the hell a
dank seed company you can find them at
dank seed dot store the hell a dank seed
company perhaps a new I read genetic
seeds also shout-out to my friends at
pol grow systems you can find them at PL
grow dot systems is what I think that is
I may have gotten that completely wrong
I apologize
Google pol grow systems you'll find them
check out their product called the
minder I highly recommend it much love
much respect to Pio grow systems you
guys I'm able to go to events like the
dude Rose cup I'm able to go to Civic
Center Park and take dads with my
friends in the wind and rain and try to
enjoy 4/20 I'm able to go to reggae
shows and I can check on the garden with
my phone by using the minder unit from
Pio Gro systems that's right I can tell
you what the temp and humidity is in my
room at all times I don't have to walk
to it I don't have to stress I could be
in my underwear on the couch watching
Bob's Burgers and we could check on the
grill room it's that easy peel grow
systems make sure you check them out
much love and respect all right ah the
list of things I want to talk about I
got my weed card renewed that time too
early actually I was having problems I
can't
Early's way easier to fix them too late
that's the truth I can't wait they won't
let me pay for it because I'm not
thirty days within the expiration date
yet so I've got to wait a couple of days
here before I could pay for it
would you that's fine with me I'm
getting I'm buying I'm on free time
right now but uh so the hardest part
about getting my weed card renewed was
getting the [ __ ] appointment yep I
had to call several times and they kept
saying we're booked and I was like well
what the [ __ ] like we're booked and I
was like can you just give me a date
further out and they're like no what
happened was the main weed doctor for my
area has retired the guy that Mike and I
go to can I say his name is that fair
yeah do you do that dr. Bruce rhymers
has done he's retired from the cannabis
industry he's not writing marijuana
cards anymore doesn't surprise me he's
been doing it for a minute for at least
five or six years that I've gone to him
we we yeah so he's made plenty of money
he's retired but there was a new doctor
there and I had to kind of reintroduce
myself and meet the new doctor but the
hardest part so the hardest part was
getting the appointment then they said
we've got this day at this time and I
was like what are my other options
there's like no you're coming [ __ ]
Wednesday at 10 o'clock or 11 o'clock in
Colorado Springs we will see you there
or no doctor for you and I was like oh
[ __ ] okay so we go there and I didn't
get stuck in the elevator this time the
last time I went to that building the L
I got stuck in the elevator and they
almost canceled my appointment because I
was 20 minutes late I called them I was
like hey I'm stuck in your elevator and
they're like you don't miss your
appointment and I was like no I'm Steve
will you help me I'm stuck in the
[ __ ] elevator I'm like we don't know
what to do just don't miss your
appointment and I kind of threw a fit
when I got in the office I was like hey
yeah I was stuck in the elevator like
you should feel bad for me like you
shouldn't just [ __ ] my appointment I was
here like I was trapped like I could I
wasn't just drinking off in the basement
I was stuck so you let me have my
appointment but this time there they
said it's gonna be a minute because the
the state is updating their computer
system we're no longer gonna have these
cards that we print it's going to be
attached to the barcode on your ID so
you're no longer than I have to present
a card you'll just walk in with your
Colorado ID they will swipe that just
like they do at the bar it'll show that
you're old enough that you're a patient
and it'll let you in so the day that I
went was the first day they were
activating this new system which meant
the computer was all [ __ ] up and
everything was taken for you so my visit
I sat in line for at least an hour maybe
two I just playing with my phone
chillin they have you fill out the
little application
stuff online I just hit refresh because
mine I'd already been all filled out
before all my information is still the
same refilled everything out then the
doctor came and explained what happened
to Bruce he's like yeah he's been in the
weed industry since the 70s he was like
a big part of legalization where he's
from and he did all this and he's like
but he retired so I'm the new doctor my
name is this how many times have you
seen dr. rhymers and I said this is
probably my seventh or eighth time with
medical alternatives renewing my card
and he goes oh okay just signed for my
paper
she's like there you go here's your new
renewal and that was pretty much all it
took and he said this is gonna take 24
hours to update because the website is
down but check this in 24 hours make
sure all your information is cool and
you'll be legit and so [ __ ] went
about my day I went shopping a
dispensaries in Colorado Springs since I
was up there anyway high five everybody
leave and go shopping 24 hours later I
go to check everything everything was
legit all my new stuff was updated
everything was cool and it allowed me to
print off a new card but it won't let me
pay for anything yet I've gotta wait I
think six more days until my old card is
30 days expired yeah I know it's gonna
be within 30 days I'm not even 30 days
from expired yet you got to jump on it
good yeah yeah well who's renewing his
always like the doctor's appointments
always been a bigger circle and often
times yeah the doctor's appointment and
then back in the day you would get your
card renewal and then have to mail it in
and then they'd have to review it and
send it back to you and that could take
six to eight weeks and if there was a
problem with it now you're looking at
another three to five more weeks and so
it's taking you 13 weeks 14 16 weeks
just to get your card and then you
couldn't shop you wouldn't be able to go
to the dispensary yo and I go through a
little bit of concentrate to where if I
couldn't shop at a medical dispensary
would probably put me in a pinch so I've
got to stay on top of that I've got to
stay on top of that yeah I got ahead of
it especially being in the industry
those are something that I always stay
on top of his my my weed car to my badge
stuff like that
gotta stay on top of that so I got the
weed part of a super easy um they do not
do extended plant counts like they used
to do back in the day you could say I
need an extended plant count and they
would say what hurts and you'd say I
don't know what does 250 bucks worth of
pain look like what is [ __ ] 24 plants
cost and they would say okay well then
there you go
here's [ __ ] money here's plant count
I'm gonna write this down on your
paperwork
be okay Mike shaking his head that's how
it used to be Mike we're not gonna play
games cuz it's not like that anymore so
it doesn't matter there were a lot of
doctors [ __ ] I was trying to remember a
doctor's name the other day and I
couldn't remember just popped in my head
I know his [ __ ] name right now anyway
there were one a daughter walking in and
they had a it was like the drink menu at
Chili's yeah they just had a little
placard at the end of the dot on the
doctors desk that was like regular six
count ninety-nine like twelve count
I remember once 150 yup 24 catch every
hundred oh yeah it went up to five
hundred count and I was just like that
is the shadiest [ __ ] you just pay more
money you can get more
fill out the little pain graph and we'll
give you more plants some doctors didn't
give a [ __ ]
some doctors were pretty tight on it
some doctors would not give you more
some doctors would blatantly advertise
we'd love to give extended plant counts
they would talk about it that's not a
know has been putting the screws the
whole system for four years now there
are lots of new paperwork's I'm not sure
because it was the first day of a new
system so I said lots of new paper will
also they've raised the part of missed
it I figured we would have brought up by
now but haven't touched on specifically
is it's attached to your driver's
license now so when you're asked license
registration and insurance that
information is coming up on the screen
usually you're a medical patient
possibly is that a HIPAA violation to
put that up on the screen there's got to
be I don't I'm not worried about it
myself but that's got a concern someone
could be considered one the thing I
don't like about it is now that just
drastically increases the the likely so
the cop comes up doesn't suspect a thing
the the the word marijuana never leaves
the cops mouth doesn't smell it doesn't
see it doesn't think about it goes back
to the cruiser runs your [ __ ] come back
up and now that's all the conversations
about because that's what came up on
your ID right and maybe they can turn
this from didn't signal that lane change
or you know speeding to a DWI or DUI
that's more money for their jurisdiction
change the whole story just because it
flagged that you're a weed patient you
know
we'll stop it uh and just a brief thing
I'd like to have faith that HIPPA
protects me from that but but like I
said all right so there's a lot of new
paperwork lots of new questions you have
to fill out a whole bunch of stuff it's
like going to a real doctor for the
first time even though I've been to that
doctor several times or that office at
least it was like going to a whole
brand-new doctor you have to put in to
ask about your diet I asked about my
exercise asked about a whole bunch of
stuff so it felt a little more legit
than it did in the past there was a lot
of weird questions that I was like what
like and you glad to started making
check marks whatever ah lots of
questions I was gonna say extended plant
counts are not gonna happen anymore you
have to bring in actual paperwork with
your qualifying condition it has to be
current there were people in there with
stacks of paperwork and this doctor
would not give them extended plan
accounts he's like no I'm afraid of
those this doesn't qualify I think you
should be like cover your needs with the
plants you can grow basically it doesn't
there's no point in an extended plant
count anymore like the the state of
Colorado capped a household plant count
at 12 yeah
state water there's a couple of specific
property zone designations for like
homesteaders like dig your own well
generate your own power raise your own
chickens type properties but the days
who can have more than more than 12 but
the days of renting a house and throwing
two hoop houses in the backyard and if I
can go on hog wild with $4.99 or been
over for a minute alright
yep that everybody that was doing that
and saw it coming so the last year it
was allowed they went hog wild hog wild
[Music]
lots of negative press in industry wide
black eyes were generated and they heat
to extinguish medical from Colorado just
quadrupled so doctors are under strict
supervision card holders are under
substantial more scrutiny
it's they didn't even wanna close here
in five years always shocked they did
not want to even talk about and hear
about extended play no once when you'd
bring it up I didn't even say I didn't
care I was like but if you're going for
an extended planet count right now show
up with terminal illness
documentation and documentation that you
live in bfv like otherwise it ain't
happenin and otherwise it's probably
useless because yeah would your capped
anyway yep
right now the the sheriff in the county
north of us is going hog-wild busting
every grow he can and some of them
they're like mm plans 4,000 plants and
some of them it's like 106 plants and
the news reports those the same and it's
like dude that's dude had it got caught
with his Cologne erful like calm the
[ __ ] down
oh because every clone in that hundred
site cloner counts as a plant god damn
yep that's a major grow that was
millions of dollars in flowers that were
growing in there yeah most of the time
they just it like if you've got a
cutting in a cloner they they assign
that as a street value of twenty five
hundred dollars it's just if anyone's
got 2500 bucks for a cutting I'm in come
get some cuttings all right um so ya
know extended plank counts doctor visit
was super easy everything was pretty
chill everything all the payments happen
online they take cash at the doctor's
office it's very affordable very
affordable you get a pretty generous
discount for being in the cannabis
industry so if you have a Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division badge
wear that to your appointment when you
go see the doctor show it to the lady
when you check out say hey do I get a
discount for this they should give you a
deal it should help you out at least a
little bit it did me plus I've been
going there for like I said that's
probably my eight ish time getting a
card from that guy I've gone did that
doctor there's four different office
spaces
yeah they move around they move around
so frequently but yeah so they gave me a
pretty fair discount it was very
affordable uh overall it was a super
easy fairly friendly visit not not no
not a lot of [ __ ] drama or that
challenge answer yeah well back in the
day it used to be different because you
have to fill out everything by hand they
would give you a blue pan and if you sit
for hours yeah yeah everything would
have to yeah for four hours just to see
the doc everything would have
in a blue pen and if you [ __ ] up
they'd have to give you a new paper
because you couldn't make any
corrections on it so you just be writing
super carefully and then all there would
be so many ridiculous questions and
there's always people that [ __ ] it up so
all the people that work there we're
tied up fixing everybody's errors all
the time used to take forever now it's
all on a computer so you just go make a
bunch of clicks it's pretty easy it's
pretty easy all right
one thing I want to touch on it's still
happening so I'm not positive I'm not
sure of the final outcome I don't have
any awards I don't know if anything has
happened but at the time we're recording
this the 420 High Times Cannabis Cup
celebration in San Bernardino is
happening yeah it is going on the reason
that's a big deal is because Thursday
there was an announcement made an
announcement made that High Times was
denied permits for their event in San
Bernardino the event was denied permits
for several reasons for changes in laws
then they were saying they were going to
let them hold the event but there would
be no consumption because of the change
in California legalization then whoever
is in charge of running the dispensaries
and medical marijuana centers and
marijuana centers in California issued a
statement saying that anybody attending
this event would be under scrutiny by
that division High Times went so far as
to have security guards at every
entrance checking people and only
allowing them to bring in their a legal
allowed amount of flour so people are
only bringing in an ounce of flour or
eight grams of concentrates or something
like that back in the day people would
bring in a backpack of flour and start
hustle in it people would bring in
concentrates and sell it this time high
x was only allowing tax ID businesses to
be a part of their event so you had to
have a real business license you have to
have a marijuana business license to set
up so you signed up with your
application you put in your your info
you turned that into high x then you set
up your booth so the people that are in
charge of the marijuana control I can't
remember the name of their division I
should have written that down sorry
those folks are threatening to walk
through the cannabis cup at the time I'm
recording it hasn't happened so far it's
gone off without a hitch
but this is what happens when we go from
the wild wild west so I was good sing
but they're letting people in through
these gates and they're checking
everybody but the vendors that have
products that are allowed to come in are
coming in through a back gate and able
to set up so they've got product this is
how they're making sure no illegal
cannabis sales are happening there right
yeah kind of weird Mike's role in his
eyes it's we're stuck in this awkward
spot where we're trying to host an event
that's like 50% football professional
football game 50% Burning Man and we're
trying to do it a hundred percent in the
football arena venues and the only way
to at this point to get the events that
we want to attend where there's
consumption where you can go around and
sample different people's products you
know enjoy yourself just like you would
at the Great American Beer Fest we taste
a Colorado or any of those other events
to actually get that event off you
really need to go to the middle of
nowhere and allow open consumption
events like my dream would be to bring
one to this a 4/20 event to the State
Fair down here it's the perfect space
there's plenty indoor there's plenty
outdoor they could do it so [ __ ] when
High Times was looking for the venue I
recommended the State Fair and they
basically laughed in my face the State
Fair and High Times both were like yeah
right which is dumb both of them can
make a fortune there right there's
plenty of parking there's plenty of
indoor and or outdoor buildings because
places for concert yeah yeah there's
three different stages endless square
footage for vending young booths of all
kinds like when I could never happen I
could walk there right in this art
there's plenty of indoor outdoor sea you
can have all the consumption you want
and never have a building full of smoke
it I mean it's it would be so easy to do
it's stupid yeah but it'll never happen
for lots of reasons like in Colorado
licensed cannabis businesses can't give
away at anything period and so like even
if they go to an event and only hand out
t-shirts and [ __ ] they're still kind of
pushing it they're supposed to sit there
and charge you a penny for
even for the t-shirt yeah why okay just
so that they're not give giving anything
away is its product and there's some
legislature at some point will like but
drug dealers give out free samples to
hook patient you know it's always been
the catch yes it's like no we're just
wag just like the record people you know
buy the CD here's the t-shirt get
excited right it's so well Friday when
the cannabis cup was setting up a lot of
people were missing there were a lot of
empty booth space don't slam about a
third of the booths showed up the event
went on Friday people came in the
concerts that were scheduled for Friday
night happened to the bands performed
people smoked out and had a good time
and watched these bands nothing happened
Saturday things would not went off
without a hitch we were far into Sunday
I haven't checked any news yet because
we've been Mike and Ivan together and
I've been on the road and doing stuff
Mike and I've been hanging out
podcasting and taking dad's and the
story go well past this weekend event
right but so nobody has raided or shut
down or walked through the cannabis cup
as far as I'm aware and they're well
into the Sunday night concert the events
have happened or the awards have
happened by now so Saturday people
started setting up Friday half the
people are third of the people showed up
Saturday people actually started coming
at setting up Sunday everybody was there
swerved from the callee connection was
on instagram live talking [ __ ] he's like
[ __ ] you to all these people that didn't
show up you're a bunch of [ __ ] where
cannabis soldiers since when do we need
permits to be cannabis warriors when do
we need a permit for this let's get it
on so ah I want to give a huge shout out
not just to swerve but to everybody who
still has that cannabis warrior [ __ ]
spirit this isn't we're getting too
comfortable
a lot of the suits and the bureaucrats
and whoever you want to call them are
taking over they've gotten involved it's
there
we're losing the passion all of those
people were the people that were scared
to show up those were all the people
that didn't do it there's a lot more to
risk now like absolutely you can't start
over by getting a job at Home Depot and
just sucking it up for six months and
saving your money and going to get into
lights and a [ __ ] fan and getting
back to it like if you [ __ ] up now and
you crash out you're out millions
millions Esther's absolutely in half
every
paycheck you weren't from now - you die
is gonna go to pain those [ __ ] off
right but I just want to give huge
respect to all the people that didn't
push out that showed up and said hey
they're trying to shut us down watch us
watch me do it because that's what I do
because I'm a cannabis soldier because
that's where we are that's where our
heart is
I just have a lot of respect for those
folks I respect the other folks too in
the same way but take a lot of soldiers
doing what they do to get us to where we
want to be I think everyone in the
cannabis community wants to at least
have the option to attend a 4/20 event
or it doesn't even have to be a 4/20
event but that we can go consume at like
if I go to a baseball game I want to be
able to go to the smoking section
take a couple hits off my bowl put it
away grab some nachos and go back to my
seat and it shouldn't [ __ ] be
earth-shattering that that's a desire
yeah like half the [ __ ] there in
line getting beers one of my earliest
memories it's part of the reason I'm not
a big fan or organized pro sports is we
were in line to get nachos and [ __ ] and
dude in front of my dad turned around
and just up and did four beers over me
and my brother like dude didn't mean to
he was out 24 bucks or whatever but we
got to enjoy the whole game soaked in so
like six and eight in like you know six
an eight-year-old likes beer now
Terry was just miserable you're sticky
but like that's a hundred percent cool
and it happens at every event everywhere
why can't there just be a little section
for me to go toke out like I get no one
wanted me to smoke in the seats don't be
a dick and light up and you don't be a
[ __ ] Rob Corey like I won't dab right
by your kids if you have me a little
section I'll go there yeah
probably won't leave there yeah let us
go off to a side thing I mean there's
within reason like if I can't take a
water bottle into a venue I don't think
you're gonna get away with AD a breaking
the torch the like a vape pen for
concentrates or a [ __ ] joint or a
bowl look we've been using enjoying
these at concerts for all of our lives
the idea that we just make a space for
that so we don't have to do it on the
down-low why is it [ __ ] nuts if I had
a box seat and uh Folsom Field in
Boulder right those
expensive they're 120 bucks a person for
a box or you can rip the whole box for
like 3GS or something like that you get
that box and they bring out a little
fridge with [ __ ] in it and then you get
free food and drinks and [ __ ]
those are semi-private what if should I
be able to bring my rig in there and
take some dabs in there
should you yes are you probably not I'm
sure plenty of people have and I've had
that idea before like I would love sorry
this is the torch II guys here I
apologize recent couple of events that
I'd love to attend and I've thought
about like you know it that events worth
taking the time putting that money aside
getting a box you know get 8 or 10
friends together put that planning
together and I mean if you take it to a
breaking a torture or something where
you're vaping rather than burning you're
not gonna offend or annoy or even tip
off the people in the boxes on either
side of you but for us to get to a point
where this doesn't happen to have has to
happen half on the down-low like a lot
of people are gonna have to stand up and
fight like no one understands how many
of us there are no one understands how
the community operates what we like what
we don't like I mean a third or more of
Americans believe the propaganda we got
in there like a third of Americans are
us a third or in the middle and don't
really give a [ __ ] and a third or
against this that's just how it works
and unfortunately most of us have I mean
we've survived by staying hidden and
that's good advice in a lot of places
keep it quiet or end up in jail perfect
ramp mic I just took the biggest dab of
some men Rapha dad sit across a total my
gosh that was so awesome here well he
better are actually you started heating
that up I'll get you a little dab mike
is right you guys we do need a lot more
a lot more fighting a lot more soldiers
but this is what happens when you get
legalization when you regulate something
we are going from an unregulated market
where people would bring their backpacks
and just hustle it out to a taxed
regulate it oh I'm trying to kill Mike
I'm giving them away too big of a dab to
a taxed regulated market we kind of
voted for this we kind of asked
for this we talk about it as a consumer
I want it like I want the but I'm buying
to have a prior or part of its price be
lab testing yes I like knowing that my
[ __ ] doesn't have mold or yeast or heavy
metals or pesticides so what I was
getting at is when you guys are voting
and setting up the rules and regulations
for the legal cannabis in your area what
you've got to do is include somewhere to
consume put consumption in your rules
that's what we missed here that's what
they write in Colorado for the last year
has been consumption and we're not gonna
win for another four or five years like
Mike said there are so many places where
we can gather Colorado was a beer state
Colorado loves beer
there's beer everywhere we can gather
everywhere you can go to the State Fair
and buy a big-ass beer and walk around
the State Fair and drink of beer there's
kids there like Mike said at the [ __ ]
baseball game he got beer spilled on him
he was a kid it's unfair so you're gonna
have to write back into your rules that
there is somewhere where you can suit
consumed we can buy cannabis we can grow
we can gift we can share we can
everything but ship and transport export
cannabis or you can do it all
Mike's gonna die I'm gonna turn down
your mic but we can't consume it anymore
you're not allowed to consume cannabis
anywhere you've got to go home even if
you were from out of state you can't
consume in your hotel you've got to get
an air B&amp;B is the only way you can do it
and you've even got to ask the air B&amp;B
people can we smoke weed in your house
and a lot of them before you even rent
it it will say no cannabis right on the
page when you're trying to rent so that
makes sure that when you're writing the
rules in your area I'm gonna get your
mic back on for you Mike
make sure that when you're writing the
rules that when you're setting up the
legislation for cannabis in your area
make sure that you include some sort of
way to consume maybe you allow some sort
of smoke clubs don't let don't make it
to where we're allowed to smoke weed in
the park at 4:20 don't do that be an
adult make a designated area if you want
it to actually pass it has to be smart
something like Jeff's talking about what
have to be is this state rule it would
have to allow local municipalities to
opt in
or define exactly how they wanted it to
play in their area but honestly I see
this evolving sort of like bars in Utah
you've got to be a member or I mean
maybe following the sex club model where
it's way the [ __ ] out in the middle of
nowhere and it's only word-of-mouth
there's no advertising but like the
community needs a place together yes and
we don't have that now at all there step
stomping down on events hardcore right
now think about man I wish and this is
the wrong audience because these people
all agree with us but just think about
this you've got your local bar right and
we're just gonna say it's a biker bar
because that's really good for people to
visualize you got this little janky
shanty biker bar with some [ __ ] loud
ass rock and roll band I was probably in
it playing in the backyard too loud at
midnight playing [ __ ] mustang sally'
or seek-and-destroy way too loud with
motorcycles I'll wind up around the
building all night long right or or you
could have a little 420 friendly Club
right a bunch of Volkswagen buses
outside a bunch of people just chillin
listenin to the Grateful Dead inside
smells like nachos they don't get a lot
of press so if you're not me you don't
see a lot of air if you're not like me
you don't see a lot of it but right now
the anti pop people their message is
that the high potency products of today
cause mental illness and psychosis in
like all the mass shooters it's cuz they
smoke weed yeah already this [ __ ] the
Waffle House dude from today they're
like yeah he visited Colorado when he
wasn't wearing pants it must have been
the weed like and yeah I chuckle because
anyone in the community knows it's
insane we've been at the concert with
1500 people smoking pot in a concert
venue that holds seven or eight thousand
1500 2000 people have sent their puffs
in if consuming marijuana just caused
people to pop off wait a [ __ ] notice
yeah yeah that's what keeps us from
popping off that's what keeps us melting
what keeps us in our place but
people that have never been part of our
community in I mean I lose sight of it
too because I'm such a so engrained into
the community like it's I I get up I
it's part of my breakfast it's what I do
all day at work it's what I do when I
get home
like I eat sleep and breathe it yeah but
a lot of people don't like there are
people that eat sleep and breathe
football or advertising or newspapers
that don't know any really know anything
about our community and when they see
[ __ ] like high potency weed causes
psychosis they go oh kind of makes sense
and there's not a voice for most people
opposing that and so just I mean getting
out and just finding those people and
being like hi I like dabs do you see
that I'm [ __ ] normal and I show up to
my job five days a week and I do a good
job while I'm here and it's just Ana
toxicant that's different than alcohol
that I enjoy it's not anything
miraculous are scary or frightening like
please don't outlaw me like that's a
hard conversation to have in parts of
the country where everything's illegal
but if you want [ __ ] to progress like
little by little you have to start
breaking down assumptions and prejudices
and this starts by being like hi I like
weed I'm completely normal we can say
that this Mendo breath is some of the
best concentrates on the planet right
yeah like I'm not saying that this would
win the best concentrate but this is in
the category I mean this would be the
fun part about being in Colorado is I
can confidently and honestly say that
right now at the table that I'm sitting
at some of the finest concentrates in
the history of humankind yeah yeah and
it's I'm we're not brown this my point
isn't bragging right now I have got I'm
bragging a little there's 12 grams of
hash on the table different flavors
different vendors different brands
different consistencies we've got oh
there's more over there Mike brought
some also oh we've got concentrates
we've got the best concentrates did this
green dot [ __ ] white and urban this
could win it
this [ __ ] star killer star child
could win an award mindo breath award
winner all of these could do something
this [ __ ] King Louie put me on my ass
we probably took six dabs before we
recorded like reasonably six days each
because I thought there's there's seven
containers here we tried almost all of
them right in front of me and then
there's D we tried this one for sure we
tried we didn't try this one we tried
almost everything I bought today we
tried so we've had two four six seven
we've had at least seven dad's ah you
feel like going crazy yet no just
chilling to say that all the time I go
oh is that the wheat psychosis that I
always hear about yeah I could go for
it's not a thing it's if you if you
really dig into the research what
they're talking about is when you get to
the hospital you've had way too much
weed and you're freaking out and you
insist who your friends take you to the
hospital
these you're definitely having a heart
attack did you get to the hospital and
they're like you know what year it is
and you know like yeah and you tell them
and they're like okay how long have you
been sitting in this office and you're
like oh man like half an hour 45 minutes
and it's only been like four minutes if
that's just you being baked yeah that's
the effects of the intoxication but
that's when they say that you're crazy
that's not being able to accurately
gauge time as part of being psychotic
yeah okay and so like it could it's part
of a mental illness and it's it's one of
the reasons that doctors are able to say
oh we see weed psychosis all the time
and it's like well you see being high
yeah
like I can't keep track of time if I
take booze drinks either I said take
booze drinks and sometimes this [ __ ] can
get pretty extreme because we've got
some amazing [ __ ] right now and every
now and then someone who's never smoked
weed before it's like I want to take a
really big dab like I see him doing
YouTube and so they go to the dispensary
they buy a torch they buy a rig they buy
grandma hash they go home they try to
take a half gram dad they cop for five
minutes they lay down on the floor they
sit back up and they freak the [ __ ] out
but it's no different than when you were
a teenager and you drank too much and
then threw up all over your cousin and
then blacked out and now you can't drink
sour apple pucker no more
it snowed [ __ ] different but because
this community hides so well it just
plays out so [ __ ] terribly in the
press I'm just checking the labels on
some of the concentrates do I grab today
that one is 92% THC mm-hmm this one
they're all crinkled up because the way
they stick them on the jar but total
cannabinoids that one only says 78 total
72 here we go 95 percent this is Bill
Lucinda Williams hi cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract the job Allen was
so sexy we took pictures it was
basically one giant diamond that way to
Graham and it's 95 this 1% total one
giant suck in space rock so we're
smoking the [ __ ] the concentrates the
the weed pills a hundred percent THC
Sativex
sativex no that wasn't the marinol was
what I was drugged ribbon all or
whatever the [ __ ] maranatha back off is
marinelle's the trade name but SATA fax
is a if it's the one I'm thinking of
it's the whole plant extract they just
got fp8 well the next step of FDA
approval cool yep no that's a good thing
yeah I think that one was from the UK
yep that's from out of Great Britain
nice I'm paying attention GW
Pharmaceuticals Oh we'll talk about if
you've watched like the CNN we've one
two and three specials and a couple
other documentaries you've seen the GW
Pharmaceuticals Garden in labs we have a
link to that garden you yeah anyway Mike
I wanted to give you the opportunity to
talk about all the drum stuff going on
we've been recording for quite a while
if you want to go I'll give you good 10
or 15 minutes
I don't need nearly that long all right
okay so everybody's excited I think
Trump came out Pro weed is how its kind
of being thrown around in the community
and that's sort of what happened but did
never trust somebody who's that orange
and who says this amount of [ __ ]
yeah
I don't even I've never heard Mike make
this noise it's good news but it's not
that good a news and you never know with
Trump how much this is [ __ ] and
panders like makes promises right or the
guy in the van like how sweet is the
puppy at home you never really know to
get back to the dudes house right so
he's saying that he's gonna be on our
team
well it's there's some run-up to this
story like when Jeff Sessions started
really screwing with legal marijuana
states and really started threatening a
crackdown of some sort a lot of
politicians said [ __ ] off and and did
some things to counter that one of those
things was Colorado senator Cory Gardner
um put a hold on a bunch of nominees it
was like it's part of my job to approve
these guys if you want to screw with my
state's voters having approved
recreational cannabis I'm a screw with
your nominations how do you like me now
and it's been a stalemate kind of going
back and forth between a couple of
different senators doing stuff like Cory
Gardner was doing and the current White
House administration over legal cannabis
and it came to a head last week the long
or the short version is it Trump seems
like he really wants to fire somebody
but to do that he would need Gardner to
approve the replacement and so to get
Gardner to start approving people
replacements in other appointments he
said that our Trump said that he would
support an amendment similar to the
Rohrbacher fire amendment or the rubic
Rohrbacher blue mayer amendment that
protects medical marijuana basically
that amendment says the feds can't spend
money to go after legal medical
marijuana as if it's following state
rules Trump said he would support a
similar amendment covering recreational
and throw the way to the white house
behind an amendment like that on one
hand if Trump is serious and Senators
submit that amendment and it makes it
through committee and it makes it to the
floor and it gets voted on and it gets
approved by the house and then it lands
on Trump's desk is part of a larger bill
that would provide protections for
recreational marijuana there's a lot of
steps between seven hands yeah I mean
late steps a lot of [ __ ] has to happen
before this is anything other than a fun
idea but on the upside it was definitely
a yank on Jeff Sessions leash saying
like this is wildly inappropriate a
terrible way to spend resources do
something more interesting and that
annoys less people
one thing Trump can do is read a poll
like whether you like him or whether you
hate him he's clearly at least employing
people who can read public opinion very
very well and everybody agrees that
legalization and liberalisation of
marijuana laws is very popular right now
so to see the Trump administration have
a Jeff Sessions going after us was
surprising seeing him walk it back was
not surprising I'm definitely keeping a
close eye on where this goes a couple of
senators have said they'll go ahead and
submit that amendment to protect
recreational marijuana like we do
medical because they've struggled to
pass a federal spending bill the
opportunity to slip that [ __ ] in there
is probably still there I honestly
haven't been following this as closely
as they should those of you who like me
on the podcast know that I've got a kid
I'm about to have another kid and so
I've been kind of busy and slacking on
my responsibilities but I did want to
get on and say something about peanuts
like a chump
they're called priorities and you've got
him in order it's okay
earlier in the live feed somebody was
like can can Mike do a state-by-state
breakdown and how the non legalization
states are faring and I was like I could
I can't right now
give me like a week I'll start writing I
do more than a week right now honest am
so behind on that I've been running two
facilities instead of researching yes we
are running 77 and 83 is what we call
them if anybody listening would like
further clarification or has specific
questions feel free to tweet me at Nemo
Punk 15 or hit me up on Facebook it
Pablo for sensible cannabis laws I'm
happy to interact with you on those
platforms and answer your political
questions political weed questions so
how long you said it's got to jump
through those eight hoops before it
actually lands on his desk how do you
have a timeline for that and I'm gonna
take a DAB so you can happen and
relatively quickly like in a matter of
weeks or it could take a year to like it
just governments like that
um I mean this guy's got a lot of a DD
and it doesn't have anything to do with
this bicker his ego so it could get
pushed aside right well and that's the
thing like if this was something that
President Trump decided he was gonna
make his number one issue and he was
gonna spend most of his time focused
right now on making sure that marijuana
legalization happened or something it
would still take him at least the rest
of it this term to make it happen just
with the amount of steps that have to
happen for it to go from something that
people want to make happen to something
that is there's a lot of steps a lot of
steps you guys I just took a really big
dab of really potent marijuana
concentrate still don't feel like
[ __ ] anything up that was big
I might [ __ ] up some ice cream if you
got some Ben and Jerry's that she would
be in trouble
hmm but that's the only thing I feel
like doing any harm to I hadn't moved
one of my feet in like an hour
oh you feeling all right over there this
will help this is the sour Pez live
resin ambrosia
it tastes like grapefruit and cotton
candy at the same time kind of weird
it's a [ __ ] honey it is very chirpy I
tried to get you a nice crystal and some
turps but I know you choked at
everything so I didn't go too hard you
guys well I heat up this dab nail I'm
trying to get it a little further from
the mic so I can talk ah I want to thank
Mike for keeping us up-to-date
politically I know some people get
[ __ ] bored of hearing about the
political rants and the politics but
that is a huge part of cannabis activism
what's going on being informed and
staying aware is really important some
of you guys might not care a lot of you
really do care so I appreciate it when
Mike comes on that stuff with us it's
super important y'all like when I hear
people say that like they don't vote for
this reason or that reason like I want
to slap them like you would a little kid
who was like yanking their sister's hair
like there's a lot of times you asked me
to edit [ __ ] out of the podcast is that
gonna be one of the things no it's just
our democracy works because people
participate in it and the reason
cannabis consumers get [ __ ] on by so
many different segments of society is
cuz we haven't participated in the
system since the 60s get out of the
system [ __ ] the system became one of our
cornerstone values and it costs us a lot
we never had an organized group fighting
for protections or rights or anything we
had exactly the opposite we had an
endless number of groups who made a
career out of demonizing our community
we're villains in almost every way
politically and that's because of our
non participation I need to take this
port is any colder for far too long our
representatives were Cheech and Chong
and that that didn't I love Cheech I
love Chong
much respect they did a lot if it was
them not their characters in the movies
it would be different but it was their
characters in the movie right and that
they didn't there was the exact
stereotype that we did not need that was
what made people say well look at those
burnouts look at those stoners that's
why we don't want it legal so for far
too long we had fad until the people of
our generation I'm gonna kill you Mike
just because that's obnoxious Mike you
okay bro I'm gonna call nine-one-one
already gave me two thumbs up
and so our generation came along and I
think things started to change with
maybe the kids right before me and then
our generation and then the people after
us they feel so entitled it's like we
want legal marijuana so they just went
out and [ __ ] tried to make it happen
and it seems to be working in a lot of
the places so it just took time from
people to wake up and then social media
really helped with the activism and
waking of people because a lot of
cannabis consumers advocates speakers
we're better off at home who don't do so
well going out so being able to speak
our opinions from the comfort of our own
recording studio really helps us out we
made it
having like we had to hide for our own
safety and we preach dropping out and
getting out of the system and [ __ ]
Babylon and that allowed groups to pass
all sorts of rules so that if we dared
to stand up and identify ourselves as
parts of this community we'd risk school
funding housing opportunities job
opportunities freedom opportunities
freedom yeah
the Grover's would be arrested the
activists remember reading about grow
houses getting busted when I was like
six and eight we're people that were
growing under [ __ ] stoned
streetlights in their basement people
cropping out way back in like 92 94 and
if you look at the numbers and do the
math like people's best guess is like 35
to 60 billion dollars in herb gets
purchased coast-to-coast Wow and if you
that's about the size of the cosmetics
industry and so if you look it I mean
just think about that for a minute
how many places do you see cosmetics
period like eyeshadow lipstick all that
[ __ ] Walgreens Target Walmart [ __ ]
everywhere this stores where I go and
then you've got the places where I gotta
take my daughter whatever it's a massive
industry it's everywhere it requires
thousands of companies tens of thousands
of employees a massive amounts of light
trucks and boxes and people and shipping
and now do that with weed so you can
kind of do the math and weed in your
area and figure out how many individual
hey bro oh so you'll take you out source
our diesel cool that'll be delivered in
like how many of those transactions have
to take place if you've got a hundred
and fifty plant a house grow how many of
those house grows are required to supply
80 percent of the demand Coast the code
which is estimated what we're producing
coast-to-coast and 20% import now it
used to be the other way right and
slowly the demand for domestic grown is
pushed out the import market but when
you look at all of that commerce
shifting that into a legal market is
freaking out all sorts of things and one
of the opportunities we have right now
is there's this little window where
people who weren't real deep into the
black market can stand up and fight
right now without risking too much like
I was one of those people in Colorado
was on the cusp and I remember agonizing
over can I be the person who stands up
because the odds that you get hammered
down when you're the first one to stand
up are huge and in pueblo the only
people talking for us were really bad at
it talking for the community and they
needed someone who could put a whole
sentence together to stand up and speak
for legal cannabis and I attended
meeting after meeting where no one
showed up and was able to do that and
finally I broke and was like [ __ ] it
like maybe I have to get really creative
for employment from here on out and just
know that I'm never gonna work for
anybody who does a Google search first
because just stand up and speak about
legal cannabis and the need to legalize
it in any way mark she was a target and
that's still true in a lot of the
country and so to have the balls to
stand up in a place like Alabama Georgia
Texas yeah and really fight right now I
mean it takes like soldiers a good word
it takes a set of balls that takes the
skill set it takes dedication but you
need to be doing your research you need
to know how the process works you can't
go and propose that the people you're
talking to do [ __ ] they don't have the
power to do please don't take them
marijuana
it's just it's not a it doesn't go over
well is weird like when people come and
talk to him about a restaurant they say
come to my restaurant they don't just
show up with food it should be the same
way with cannabis go tell them what
you're about let them know where to come
to check out and find out more
don't just show up and be like here's an
eighth everybody yeah but I've seen it
I've heard about seeing it it take your
time if you really want to get up and
fight you don't know how contact me yeah
Wow how can they contact you Mike lots
of ways you can hit me up but on Twitter
at Nemo punk 15 or on Facebook at Pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws it's the best
way to do it cuddle off for sensible
cannabis laws on the Facebook everybody
hearing this is gonna try to find me on
Instagram which one of these days I'm
gonna learn how to work Mike's not much
of an instagramer that's more that's
more my thing Mike thanks for coming
keeping us up-to-date politically I
appreciate that dude yeah thanks for the
some of the rants you guys that feels
like it was a lot but I'm really baked
right now and my ability to judge times
a little hinky well hey it's what are
you psychotic you fallin in about
psychosis
it's called cannabis news education
rosacea and I feel like we got all three
today there was news there was
edumacation and there was lots of
conversation so I think we nailed it I
think we did pretty well if you didn't
like this episode of the best part what
did dad next if you didn't like this
episode the best part is there will be
another one Thursday so he'll just get
the lesson again Thursday maybe I'll say
something you like on that episode and
if you liked it hey thank you I
appreciate you for hanging out um I want
to give a huge shout out to a couple of
friends of mine the dude and Scotty
what's up gentlemen every episode the
dude and Scotty give an award or a
shout-out they call it - they name
somebody the executive producer they
just say this person is called the
executive producer for this episode two
times now I've been titled the executive
producer the post
dude grows cup episode Scotty gave me
the executive producer title he's like I
ran into Rasta Jeff big tall dude with
dreadlocks with always has a smile on
his face and a positive attitude which
lets a huge compliment it's kind of what
I'm aiming for try to have a big smile
try to be chilling having a good time
Scotty it's always fun hanging out with
you so thanks for the
the executive producer title I think I
gave Scotty too big of a dab he got a
little bit rekt at the dude grows cup
but that's what we do so with the cup is
for that's the truth but when you're
hosting in your that lid it's a
challenge I'm sure hi everybody
who I'm not going there so shout out to
Scotty real for the love and respect for
giving me the executive producer
position it's always good to see you bro
it's always good to hang out it's always
good to take a DAB let's do a podcast
together also on the same token shout
out to the dude there was a grow
competition called the Adam Dunn show
Invitational I'm sure a lot of my
friends listened to the Adam Dunn show
podcast and also the dude gross podcast
I hope but the dude from the dude grow
show actually placed in the Adam Dunn
show Invitational yeah
so that's super cool to see one of our
grow gurus actually place in a contest I
think that's pretty awesome
so how it should be shout out to the
dude shot at the Scottie real shout to
everybody in the dude grows crew since I
have been hanging out with the dude
grows crew more and since I went to the
event my Instagram live feeds have been
much more full the dude grows crew comes
in and hangs out there getting a lot
more interactions so shout out to all
those people and big shout out to
everybody excuse me sorry for the throat
clearing hold on big shot to everybody I
did turn off the mic that wasn't me this
time yeah everybody that comes to and
hangs out on my Instagram live videos if
you're not checking those out on
Instagram I those yes its Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore GE
ne T ICS I read genetics on Instagram
make sure you check me out I do a lot of
live feeds I go talk about growing
cannabis consuming cannabis I take a lot
of dabs on there because it's not a
podcast I get loose I'm just chilling
there's no headphones there's no
microphone it's me and my dad rig just
people asking questions about we I write
down some of the questions and they
actually make it here to the podcast a
lot of times I just answer [ __ ] on the
fly it's a lot of fun so make sure you
check me out there you guys I think you
would enjoy it but shoutouts all my
friends that was the point shut up to
Scottie and shout out to the dude
alright yeah
wrapping up this podcast um I would
appreciate it if you follow me on all of
the social media find me on Facebook
it's I know it's not I read genetics
it's the [ __ ] girl from her [ __ ]
okay follow I read genetics also more
should the more clicks the merrier so go
find all my stuff on Instagram just
stalk me Facebook Instagram on Facebook
search for the girl from our podcast on
Instagram find I re underscore genetics
on Twitter there are a lot of options
you can find me on Rasta Jeff 420
check me out you can find the podcast
it's at G fyh podcast you can find I
read genetics it's I read genetics lots
of stuff to click on there if you've got
something to say if you'd like to
sponsor the podcast if you'd like to
send me a product to review if you'd
like to not a question yeah if you've
got a question if you've if you want to
know something and you're not into all
this social media stuff if you're not
hip on that you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to see what you've got to
say ladies and gentlemen I've got two
hundred and forty two videos on YouTube
now or you did this last my check
YouTube is going and chopping down a lot
of cannabis related pages fortunately
for me my videos don't have a lot of
cannabis happening it's just audio it's
a picture of my ugly mug and audio maybe
I'll slip through maybe they'll let me
live maybe they'll let me keep going if
I were a different type of channel they
wouldn't take me down why do they want
to take down the cannabis channels the
the Internet is doing there's a little
like smut purge personal ads on
Craigslist disappeared oh the personal
sections gone when I walked in you were
listening to a show who mentioned that a
popular message board for escorts in LA
is gone now yep shut it off on in his
podcast I love that [ __ ] podcast
there's a couple of different social
media platforms that are purging
cannabis or gun-related and I don't say
those two it's just both of those
purchases are happening and it's
happening for a variety of reasons it's
unfortunate but at the same time were a
community
operates in the shadows and as such were
subject to getting [ __ ] on regularly
step out of the shadows yeah if they
thought they were gonna receive some
sort of backlash for deleting the
content we enjoy in produce they
wouldn't be doing that I just got a
message from somebody sitting me a
youtube link that's funny youtube link I
hope my channel is still there alright
guys find me on youtube search for the
girl from our podcast we watch the old
videos while they're still there start
with number one it's on a shared
playlist start with number one and watch
as many as you can before YouTube Yanks
them down I will keep producing them and
I'll put them up but I can't guarantee
what YouTube will do we'll figure it out
from there if YouTube [ __ ] me over um
also you guys don't forget about patreon
on patreon.com slash girl from your
heart if you feel like this podcast was
worth a couple of bucks and you'd like
to contribute you can go to
patreon.com/scishow from your heart all
the information that you need will be
right there
you can sign up you can contribute to
the podcast what I do with those
contributions is I pay for my website
I've got a website where I host the
podcast that allows me to give you the
podcast for free there are people that
are able to contribute to help me out so
that I can keep the show coming for
everybody for free if you can do so I
would appreciate it if you can't I still
love you
keep listening keep smoking keep hanging
out keep following me on all the social
media we're still friends they're just
people that want to contribute I'm
giving them a way to do it and thank you
thank you to everybody who wants to
contribute big thank you to everybody
who has contributed and thank you to
everybody who will contribute in the
future when the time is right for you
the time may not be right by now you
might win the [ __ ] lottery or
something and then be like oh now I know
what he means I got five extra bucks I'm
gonna go contribute you'll know what I'm
talking about when the time comes if you
can't afford it dude I still love you I
understand we all don't have five extra
dollars some of us don't have a [ __ ]
spare dollar so do what you have to do
some of us are just trying to medicate
and get by don't worry about it
someone's got your back this struggle is
real don't sweat it that's the truth I
shout out to everybody from patreon the
MacBook that this show was being
recorded on is going so slow that it's
[ __ ] frustrating you guys I did use
some of my own personal funds but I did
use a large portion of patreon funding
to buy a new MacBook I've recorded
several episodes on the new MacBook Pro
I've made a lot of youtube videos with
it
I cannot believe
how much faster how much more quickly it
made life better did it made life better
I can edit I can [ __ ] edit I don't
know Mac we'll go move it and spin
around I can edit now I can do multiple
shows it's so much easier so this metric
needs a new MacBook yes yes if you guys
work in metric you'll know what I mean
but anyway thank you guys for the
contributions you did help me get a new
MacBook Pro things are going much more
smoothly I appreciate all of your help
thank you thank you thank you I can't
say it enough I know what it's like to
reach into your pocket and help somebody
out it feels good and it takes some
effort so thank you I appreciate that
um you guys I think that's all of the
rambles I have got for this week Mike do
you got anything to say before we say
goodbye to these fine people
he's got the blankets look on his face
lots of rants keep the questions coming
yeah keep them leave you wondered why I
took the rant that way 50% of the time
for this episode tonight it's because of
the Facebook live before the show
oh the Instagram I feed him to Graham
live yeah not Facebook left that's how
high I am that's all right
once those are over I forgot them people
were like hey remember you said this and
like yeah I just go so fast and those
I'm fielding four and five questions at
a time right and so my brain is firing
in a really weird way and once it's over
I go into like a weird recovery mode I
have to watching the lag in person is
funny cuz I've got the feet up in front
of me and I see you in person so
sometimes it gets a little hinky I feel
like when the show when the live feeds
are over the little the driver inside my
head has to go put all the files back in
the folders and put them back that was
so many files at once like yeah I just
kind of decompress after those for a
minute take a couple more dabs and wipe
it off all right you guys I want to
thank everybody for hanging out of
course I'll be back Thursday with uh
I've been calling them quickies but
they've been normal fully [ __ ]
episodes lately once I get talking I
just get going but I should be back
Thursday with another episode I wanna
thank everybody for hanging out I want
to send a huge thanks to Mike for coming
and taking time from his family from the
wife the baby the dog the new baby
that's on the way you've got a lot to
think about so thanks for being here
wasting time with my ugly ass yeah man
um I think that's we all we've got for
this week hey I've got a super important
shout-out this week you guys I want to
give a huge birthday shout out happy
birthday bro I mean it from the bottom
of my heart I hope you have the greatest
birthday hope you
a great time hope everything goes your
way hope you're taking fat dads I hope
you're smoking fat joints whatever
you're doing you got a big smile on your
face cuz you're a good [ __ ] dude and
you do dessert you deserve it so huge
birthday shout out to my friend bagsied
Jesse and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me