and what's that podcast world it's Rasta
Jeff it's time for another episode of
the girl from your heart podcast no
music I just wanted to get right to it
it's Thursday I usually try to put out a
Thursday quickie episode this one may
not be so fast I've got a lot to talk
about so let's get right to it you guys
I like to start the episode off by
letting you know what I've been smoking
on today today I've been taking dad's
actually just finished off the jar of
Starchild og from our friends at a cut
above in Colorado Springs I picked this
up at the Fillmore location it smells
kind of like dryer sheets uh I really
like the way it smells it is delicious
it's kind of got a Jack Herer sort of a
smell if you're familiar with jackets
also got a trainwreck kind of aroma I
really like it super sativa head buzz
gets me talkative makes my head spin
great podcast dabs also I've got some
sour Pez ambrosia
from our friends at apothecary you guys
know I like to get the apothecary
concentrates when you open it up and
give it a smell it smells like a
lemon-lime kind of a candy it smells
like a sour Pez then when I smoked it on
the way in the inhalation tasted like a
lime Rhine like if you had scraped the
inside of a lime and like that and it
was pleasant but it was really tart and
it was surprising I was like oh [ __ ]
that's a lot of flavor and then on the
way out
it was just straight-up grapefruit
citrus I'm smelling the jar again I'm
picking up more of the grapefruit now
that I'm smelling it again closer to my
face but limes and grapefruit you guys
this one was really unique the sour
peasant Broza
from apothecary both of these obviously
super sativa because my head is going my
eyes are wide open and I'm ready to
ramble ready to get into my main topic
let's jump right to it I was on
Instagram live and somebody asked me how
do I feel about people breeding with my
seeds of course I do have a seed company
I'm Huayra genetics I make seeds those
seeds are commercially available on the
internet which means that people are
getting ahold of them which means people
are growing them which means they're
finding select males and select females
which may be great candidates for
breeding now who would I be to say do
not breed with those great plants I
invite you to breed with the plants that
come from my seeds I will
please do that there are people breeding
great projects with things that I've
made there are things that came from my
Capleton there's a whole seed line that
came from my Capleton there are guys
breeding with my black cherry Kim I'm
sure that there are things I don't even
know about being bred with my stuff I
can't be mad about it
I did not invent cannabis I did not
invent the seed stock that I started
breeding with I was gifted clones I
created a nice clone library for myself
by gathering clones from friends and
when other dispensaries would have
clones for sale I would go get them and
I got clones through various other means
that I won't mention here on the show I
had a nice clone library and then I got
bored with just growing from clones and
I wanted something different that not
everybody else had so I started getting
seeds and then I started buying seeds
and getting addicted to buying seeds off
of the internet so my breeding stock
came from seeds I bought off of the
Internet I kept buying those seeds and
I'd find great stuff but then I was like
why do I keep spending money on seeds
and throwing away mail plants I could
learn how to breed myself so I started
studying breeding then I built a
separate little breeding area for myself
and I used one of the male's that came
from a seed pack that I bought and I put
it put the pollen on clones that I have
gotten from friends and plants that came
from seeds that I'd bought on the
internet so I was breeding two clones
and seeds by using a seed that I had
purchased so I can't be mad at anybody
if they want to use my seeds for
breeding I should be honored if they
find one of my plants that comes from
one of my creations good enough and
worthy enough and impressive enough to
continue its genetic line I should be
proud of that the only thing I asked for
is credit when you write down what the
genetics are put that you used whatever
of my Cross you use storm shadow [ __ ]
scarlet begonias write it down and if
you're gonna write this down make sure
you write it down properly when you
write down genetic crosses ladies first
so if you use a female star dog plant
and a male arise you will write star dog
X arise and that's your one plant if
you're gonna cross that plant to
something else you'll put star dog X
arise and Pinta parenthesis so it'll be
parentheses star dog X arise parentheses
then you'll put an X on either side of
that depending on if that's the boy or
girl if that one's gonna be the girl it
would be parentheses star dog X arise
CAES X then your boy plant whatever
that's gonna be so make sure that you go
ladies first when you're writing down
genetics I hope I didn't over make that
too complicated there hope I didn't
overcome placate that for you guys but
still ladies first when you're writing
down genetics so it doesn't bother me at
all when people breed with my genetics
because I am breeding with other
people's genetics even when I'm breeding
now I have to get other stuff I have to
outsource other things because if I just
keep breeding with everything that I've
already got it's just gonna be a bunch
of inbred stuff I've got to pull other
male plants out of somewhere I've got to
get other female plants out of somewhere
or I'm just gonna be doing a bunch of
cousin [ __ ] and I'm gonna make a
whole bunch of the same seeds before too
long
so I have to have breeding stock that is
not all mine so which means I have to
use other people's stuff and the way
that I honor them and show them respect
is I clearly label what I used in my
crosses so you can see what I'm using
and that's how I don't piss off the
other guys and it keeps it fair and I
ask you to do the same if you breed with
my stuff you've bought the seeds they're
yours like can a car salesman say hey
now when you drive off with this car
please don't take it to the east side
eat some [ __ ] you and go to the east
side it's my car he's if he says when
you buy this motorcycle please don't
drive it down dirt roads you're gonna
say bro dirt roads with this motorcycle
all day don't worry it's mine like
that's how I feel about my seeds if you
buy my seeds and you want to breed with
them have a good time
those are yours you paid for him just
give me some credit if you do breed with
them and when you post pictures tag me
in it that would be cool also alright
so that's my rant on how I feel about
people breeding with my seeds I may have
done that rant on another episode but
that leads me into another thing we were
talking on another forum and somebody
said that OG Kush stands for ocean grown
another person said that OG Kush stands
for original gangster I heard a lot of
silly things I would like to give my
opinion and I would like to start a
conversation and hear what you think I'm
gonna go the long route and not tell you
right away what I think o G stands for
but that's how all it's gonna be the
punchline so a long time ago there was a
website and on this website
this website is gone so you couldn't
find it if you wanted to now it was shut
down a lot of the people were rated a
lot of people that were a part of this
website were rated by the DEA and their
local authorities for growing cannabis
this was huge a lot of people were a
part of this website there are now
prominent members of the cannabis
industry a lot of people that were taken
down would have been dominant members of
the cannabis industry if they weren't
rated because of this website many years
ago this website was home to a lot of
cannabis growers breeders and
enthusiasts and activists a lot of these
people were growing at home and breeding
at home a lot of these people had gotten
seeds from around the world and brought
them back to the United States and we're
growing them in small home grows that
were fully illegal at the time there was
no medical marijuana at this time maybe
California was thinking about it a lot
of these growers were growing and
breeding at home because that was what
they had access to was those seeds so
people were here's part of where I think
the og cush name came from
I think somebody acquired seeds from
from cush but where's cush I want to say
cush Mountain I want to say cush Valley
but I'm sure that those are dispensaries
anyway people got seeds from cush
probably from soldiers who traveled
overseas and came back with cannabis
seeds and said these came from cush
either the cush mountains the cush
valley wherever they were the word cush
was involved in these seeds they were
delivered to somebody maybe they brought
them back themselves and were on this
website that I'm talking about
I think they grew these seeds I think
they bred with these seeds I think then
they took a handful of these seeds and
what I think what was happening on this
website is a guy like myself that could
breed would breed seeds and send them
out to five or ten maybe 15 or 20 of his
friends I honestly don't know exactly
this is a theory those guys would work
the seeds and then send them back or
pass them around
I think that somebody was really
narrowing something down and breeding it
with a couple of people and a group in
different locations through the mail
seeds were being passed they'd go to one
guy he would breed do it and do his
thing and then he would send seeds back
to the original guy plus more people who
would then breed to it and I think that
out of all of this breeding is where the
og cush came
is from some of this breeding project
they came off of this website and if you
guys haven't caught on by now if you're
og you know what I'm talking about
the website I'm talking about is
overgrow comm I personally don't think
that Oh G stands for ocean grown because
a lot of it was not grown near the ocean
and I also don't think that og was
original gangster because a lot of the
circles that had the og cush originally
were not the gangster types they were
more hippies and they were more more on
the hippie side of life than the
gangster side of life we didn't start
hearing it be associated with Original
Gangster until be real and dr. Dre and
all those guys started talking about the
chronic and the OG Kush so I really
think that it came from overgrow dot-com
overgrow the government is a website
dedicated to cannabis dedicated to
cannabis growing dedicated to cannabis
rebellious Ness it was the home for weed
and unfortunately it did lead to a bunch
of trouble you guys we are carried away
nowadays with our internet freedom back
in the day people got raided because of
this [ __ ] that they did online so keep
that in mind there are people that paid
the price for us to be here and a lot of
them lost everything because of overgrow
calm so that is my theory I think that
OG Kush was some seeds passed around
from overgrow calm and it was a breeding
project happening in different locations
through the postal service I think that
some of the stuff that came out of there
was OG Kush and that would explain why
there are different phenotypes and
different names of OG Kush the Tahoe og
and the whatever og and the whatever
we'll say the Tahoe and the [ __ ] e we
got Florida and Tahoe California I'm not
sure what part of [ __ ] Florida the
creepy is for them I'm sure someone's
yelling into their [ __ ] device right
now saying it's from this part of
Florida but you got the creepy and you
got the Tahoe they're very similar if
you smoke them if you get them near each
other
you got the triangle very similar yet
very different they're all similar and
all different they're all og cush is
because they probably all came from the
same seed stock and have been kind of
bread somewhere along the line with the
same parent and/or grandparent maybe
they're all different F generations
maybe they're cousins
but I think that that's got something to
do with it it's because of the website
it's because of the mail I don't think
it's ocean grown because how you gonna
ocean grow if you're not if you're in LA
it's not ocean grown you're too far
you're you're [ __ ] Smaug grown all
right and it's not original gangster
because the people that were doing it
weren't the gangster types I don't think
they would have named it that so my
theory is it came from overgrow the
website I'd like to hear your rebuttal
I'd like to hear your opinion I'm
curious send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail
calm you can find me on Facebook just
simply search for the girl from your
heart a podcast if it's easier for you
to find me on Instagram search for Irie
underscore genetics also there's the
Twitter you can tweet me at my tweeter
it's at Rasta Jeff 420 or you can tweet
the show it's at G fyh podcast I would
love to hear what you think oh gee and
og cush stands for I'm gonna stand
behind my statement I think it's over
Gro that's what it was all right you
guys thank you for listening to me
ramble it's been just about 12 minutes
no intro music no outro music just me
talking this time hey thanks for hanging
out I really have a lot of fun doing
this podcast I really have a lot of fun
doing the Instagram live feeds that is a
great time thanks to all my friends that
kind of helped me name a strain today I
played a little game on Instagram live
where we wrote down strained names and I
let people vote on when I crossed out
the ones we didn't like of course my
vote supersedes all your guys's votes
but I think we're gonna have a good name
for star dog to arise and I owe a lot of
credit to my friends on Instagram live
for that so if you're not following me
on Instagram please do and check this
out it is a lot of fun also speaking of
videos on YouTube I've got two hundred
and forty two videos up I think now I'm
slowly making the videos YouTube has
been cracking down on cannabis channels
I'm not going to put up a whole bunch of
content for it to get taken down let me
see what happens in this wave of
destruction that's happening through
YouTube right now all of the online
services Instagram Twitter Facebook
periscope they have all sent me a new
Terms of Service Agreement to sign so
things are changing on the internet
right now they're trying to clean up all
the smut it sounds like they're trying
to get rid of weed
in dirtiness and I don't want to fall
victim to it on YouTube so I'm just
gonna kind of lay low for a minute and
once it kind of chills out I'll start
putting videos up again I'm caught up on
what I wanted to do so I'm okay for
about 35 more videos I think which will
be just fine ladies gentlemen thanks for
hanging out thanks for listening don't
forget about the patreon campaign that's
right if you'd like to contribute to the
show financially you can go to
patreon.com/scishow um your heart all
the information that you need will be
right there I do owe huge shoutouts to
my friends roberto tyler and angel thank
you for all of the patreon support i do
appreciate that ladies and gentlemen
thanks for hanging out with me thanks
for listening to a thursday quickie
episode thanks for all the love and
support you guys everybody has been
sending me a ton of emails my instagram
has been blowing up the patreon has been
staying steady I do appreciate all of
the love the support and the
interactions it means the world to me
I'll be back Monday with the full length
episode I can't wait to hang out with
you guys again ladies and gentlemen I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friend el gringo de Mota and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me